-For my understanding, there have been some discussions and misunderstandings in the group,
of how a proper follow up should be given. And I would like to ask you to clarify how a proper follow up should be like?
-Ok, I'll give you my idea of a proper follow up.
A proper follow up is one that gives first of all an overall impression of what is going on before and after the treatment.
It's an overall impression.
I'm better in this, this, this and I'm worse in this, this. I am the same, whatever is the general state first.
So we can get an impression of the subjective feelings of the patient. What are her subjective feelings?
And this has three parts. One is the mental-emotional part which is of very great importance and interest,
the second is the energy level and the
third is the local symptomatology.
So in this order a proper follow up should be given; mentally-emotionally, I'm the same, I'm better.
Energy wise I'm better, I'm the same, I'm worse.
And local symptoms you can also say what it is there for sure.
If you had a little pain in the ear at the day 17/11/98 it's not important.
Unless this pain is until today. From November
I have a pain in my ear which stays here.
Otherwise the practitioner, the one who is going to take the case, you're going to take the case you're confused
and you give much more importance to a symptom that does not have any importance.
And then you misguided and then
you give the wrong remedy.
A patient who does not give a report like this,
he can misguide anybody even myself.
I can be misguided because I tend
to believe even though I'm very careful
in observing, there are individuals who believe what they say.
So if they believe what they say, I also
believe. If somebody is trying to trick me,
I understand it immediately and I don't say anything. I will not say you try to trick me
but I will try with the same words of the patient to prove, later on, that this is what you're saying,
this is what you're saying, these two
don't go together, something like that.
Because it's not nice to tell
somebody you try to trick me.
The desire to trick you is that now I'm with
the doctor, let me get the best benefit.
So I have also this, this and that. Can
you do something for this, this and that?
But this eagerness to cure certain ailments may lead you into a kind of a relapse of the whole case.
Because instead of waiting, I give you a remedy which is wrong because
if I have to wait and I give a remedy, the remedy is wrong. We have to wait, you are in the process of curing
and we have to wait, placebo, you give placebo yes. But if somebody does not give this overall impression
of the progress of his case and the progress should go from above, downwards.
From Mental, Emotional, Physical. Here we have a lot of problems finally. We can have a lot of problems
but we may still have to wait with severe
things which are happening here.
Especially we have to wait when this process is correct and here is not so severe the situation.
So imagine somebody comes there and he says, I had a pain in my neck and then I had a pain in my lobe of the ear
and then a little pain there and he gives you 1000 pains which are going all over, what are you going to think?
And he doesn't talk about the energy, about the mental-emotional; the patient does not understand
the process of cure and then you may have to ask the patient, wait a moment how do feel in mental-emotional?
That means your fears, your anxieties, your depression. If the patient has come originally for depression,
is going to complain with a lot of physical symptoms, if your treatment is correct.
This is the most successful treatment; otherwise your treatment was not correct. It was a placebo effect,
I feel a bit better and then back again etc. etc.
It has to come down here. And when it comes down there,
there are complains. But these complains you have to decide, is the remedy clear, yes or no?
If it's clear ok, I'll give you a remedy. If it's not clear, but I feel pain, say 'it is not clear I can't give you a remedy'.
This is how strict you may be. Oh I go
to acupunture. Go to acupuncture.
I go to chiropractors. Go to chiropractors.
I don't care what are you doing.
What I care is what I know is correct and
you must do. You must sit there and wait.
That is for me the correct thing to do at this moment.
There is no way that you have a big depression here and you won't get a spasm over there.
So it is to the detriment of the patient if
he does not give you the right information.
You try to trick me is like tricking your own self. What is this? That is why the best follow-ups come from simple people,
not intellectuals. Simple people say, yes this is better and now I have this. You say, my God the case is clear
because there is a kind of clarity and purity in these levels but we have learned 'if I tell him that I have this, this and that,
he will try harder, he will give me a better remedy and then I will be cured'. Forget it, there is no such thing.
You just say the truth what is there and then
let the Homeopath who knows what is doing.
The problem is how many Homeopaths all
over the world know what they are doing?
Perhaps you are the only group because you listen to this theory.
All the other Homeopaths all over the world, they just throw remedies. Throw this remedy, throw this remedy.
I can prescribe remedies in 5 minutes but you will be missing all the essence, all the information.
You see, real cure is a magical thing. Something which is beyond our ability to handle it.
You say, I will cure you. Who are you? I know Homeopathy. You see the most clear case and you fail.
And you think it's clear and you fail. I say ok now what? Watch yourself, go to the mirror look at yourself and say,
I will cure you. Wait a moment. Homeopathy is a discovery. You discover this magic, this individual reaction of each person.
You observe and you discover. Sometimes
it's a very tedious process.
If you want to learn Homeopathy
you put a lot of effort. This is no question.
A lot of effort in studying, in watching, in observing, in waiting, you put a lot of effort.
You can't say, I'm bored with this case.
This case you're going to discover.
You wait until that magical moment when you discover that which makes the case clear, there is a magical moment.
And if you do this process, then you are going to discover a treasure of symptomatology.
You will discover that Sepia has multifacets. This can be Sepia, that can be Sepia. Ignatia, the Calcarea carbonica.
I told you many times students of mine, oh why did you prescribe that remedy? Because I have listened to many Pulsatilla cases
and I have seen that Pulsatilla is not only the
one who is easily lead and easily persuaded.
It's not only that, it's something else as well. When did I discover it? When I listen to the case.
Yes, if I dont' want to listen of course. If you are
a very busy practicioner you don't listen. If you become too soon,
too famous, people will start coming one after another. Now you are greedy either to get more money
or to get more fame and then you prescribe. These things I have done, I know the psychology,
I know everything which is going on. 40 years I'm observing myself and I'm observing the patients.
What I'm telling you is not stories from another planet. They are stories from real experience.
But in the back of my mind was, George you are missing a lot. In one hour I had scheduled five cases.
And I will see the case is better.
I am much better, ok, placebo, next.
So I gain a few minutes from the next case that was a new case and maybe I had a problem.
And sometimes I was stuck of course and instead of finishing at 9-10 o'clock in the night,
I would finish at 1 o'oclock in the morning.
So this discovery, this new attitude and
I know where can I get a new attitude.
You have a typical case of Nat-m, worse sun, aversion to fat and desires salt and has headaches.
Ah, Nat-m, go. If you do this, you missed a lot of the inner complexes of this person because you see
a typical case of Nat-m and you don't investigate. You just give the remedy and you let it go.
Here, you have a treasure in front of you and you let it go because now you're going to discover the new symptoms
which belong to that particular individual. And then you discover that Nat-m has also this and that,
that fear, that anxiety etc. etc. That is the time when you sit and investigate and you listen.
The Nat-m can become very hypochondiacal.
Talk, talk, talk how do you know this? Because you have listened some time, one time or another.
You didn't listen one time in order to say Nat-m is hypochondriacal that means you listened to 10 cases
which are hypochondriacal. And they bother
you with little symptoms here and here.
You think is it Nitric acid? Hypochondriacal anxiety, Kali-ars is not an anxiety, it's fear. I'm going to die.
Nat-m is hypochondriac.
This, this, this, that... placebo. Why?
Because before she was in depression, now she has this little, this, that, placebo.
But you listen and you discover oh, there is a hypochondriasis, still belongs to Nat-m. Wait, placebo.
And then it comes a kind of a balance eventually.
What I planned to talk to you today is miasms.
Definition. When we say miasm, what do
we really mean? We have this word to specify something I think,
something misunderstood in each
one of us. What is a miasm?
We can say that a miasm is this energic
complex net. It's a net, like this.
This is one miasm. Then put on top of it another miasm, you just twist a bit and you put a complex net.
And put another complex net, you twist a bit and you will see almost, all the holes are closed.
When all the holes are closed, that means 5 miasms, then we say the case is incurable. Why?
Because there is no energy that goes through those holes. The energy produces symptomatology.
You close the energy totally and then you have
a state of total "adynamia", total weakness.
No symptomatology, no indications. The organism is totally blocked as far as energy is concerned
and is going to go down and die. And this
cannot be found in any physical system,
it's not on the lymphatic, is not on the nervous, is not on the reticuloendotheliac, is not something which you will find
its physical counterpart in the different systems of the body. A net like this may have affected one, two or three
or all the systems of the body. This network, this complex network that blocks the defensive energy of the body,
because we're talking mostly about energy condition, can be taken away with 1, 2 or 3 remedies.
You can take away what we call a miasm not only with one remedy; you may need 3 different remedies to take out,
what we call a syphilitic miasm or a sycotic miasm or a tubercular miasm.
You see this is another net, you see how it closes. And this is another net and you have this, a very unfortunate situation
in which if you put these nets in another perspective,
this is what you're looking for,
for the first miasm, these 3 keynotes.
To take away the first miasm, the first layer. Layer and miasms are similar ideas. The only difference is that
a miasm may need in order to take
away, 3 layers, 3 remedies.
So an individual who needs 3
remedies for the first layer,
3 remedies for the second, 3 remedies for the third, is a very difficult case to treat.
Now what are the qualities of this complex net.
We have some parameters to define the miasm.
First parameter is when can we call a symptom complex, when can we call it a miasm?
When it has at first, origin.
It has a specific origin and this may be bacteria, microbes, virus etc., chemical substances.
Because we're using very complex chemical substances today, we can create a miasmatic blockage in the organisms.
And these is one of the most dangerous things we're doing to ourselves today, concerning the overuse of chemical drugs.
So it has a specific origin and
b) it can produce a specific set of symptoms.
Now if you take these two factors, you put all the infectious diseases here. What is the third factor that you need to have
in order to call it a miasm, not every
acute disease can produce a miasm.
You need a third factor in order to have the
idea of a miasm. Which is this third factor?
-The family history? Hereditary?
-Genetic disposition I think.
-Genetic disposition, yes but all these have an effect. The genetic disposition etc. What is the effect?
The effect is that they have the ability, the miasm has the ability to pass from one generation to another.
It has the quality, the capacity to transfer
its network into the next generation.
This is a condition, absolutely
necessary that we have a miasm.
So passing this to the next generation.
If we accept this kind of definition and this kind of conditions for a miasm, then we may say that we have more than 3 miasms.
Hahnemann had an idea and the idea was correct. What was his idea? Something was blocking the case.
He would say, I will give Rhus tox to somebody and he will come back again and again with symptoms of Rhus tox.
During that time the organisms were strong enough, so they had very orderly symptomatology.
So the patient will come back with Rhus tox. And then when I gave a Calcarea carbonica to such a case, the person was cured.
What does that mean? He, therefore thought, I gave a deeper remedy to counteract a miasm.
That was an original idea, like a raw idea which comes first. This idea has to be thought out, put into practice, observed etc.
and eventually you have the real truth revealed. Like in the beginning, I said, the conception can take place in phase one
when the organism is totally in a state of satisfaction and equillibruim. That's a raw idea.
Now if this idea is going to be put into practice, some gynecologists who are dealing with in vitro fertilization etc.,
they will try to find the parameters how to recognize these living cells which are in phase 1.
And if they can recognize it in the microscope, they take this, this is good and fertilisation
instead of being successful 10-15 %, will be 85 %. This is a raw idea which may have or may have not validity.
It will have a validity after it has been put into practice.
In the same way, Hahnemann's
idea of the miasm was a raw idea.
Now some contemporary Homeopaths took this idea and made a kind of dogmatism out of it.
The idea is this. It's not dogmatic idea. We have 3 miasms and then how do you explain the fact that
when you have Tuberculosis in the family, you give Tuberculinum to the patient and the patient is cured. How is he cured?
Oh, Tuberculosis is a mixture of 2 miasms. Or something like that. What is this? That has nohing to do?
If it's a mixture of 2 miasms, Syphilis and Sycosis, that means you need sycotic drugs, you need syphilitic drugs
before you can solve a case of Tuberculosis or of tubercular origin. But what practice shows is,
when you give Tuberculinum this miasm is going away. All the tubercular miasm is disappearing.
And further than that it was a misunderstanding that we could find the remedy of a person
because we understood the miasms. This is totally wrong. If somebody tells you,
'I found between Merc. and Nat-s., I choose Merc. because I saw the syphilitic miasm in this case'.
There is an english word but it's not to be
said in front of ladies; I would use that word.
Because actually what you do in a case of Syphilis where you use Medorrhinum. What is this now?
You say the Syphilis has produced sycotic or the sycotic symptoms of Medorrhinum are syphilitic.
All kinds of twisting thinking is going on in order to justify certain things which are not explained and not justified.
Therefore this idea I will know the remedy,
if I know the miasm, is a wrong conception.
That came originally not from Hahnemann but from followers who misunderstood the theory of Hahnemann.
And why Hahnemann was stating all these things. Hahnemann was correct when he said,  there is a blockage
because this net of the miasm is an
obstacle, is a blockage that has to go out.
And it goes out with what? With the correct remedy, maybe two remedies.
This is the one thing. The other is: do we have
a specific set of symptoms for each miasm?
And we say, we have to have this. So therefore if I know the specific set of symptoms, is it more easy for me to find the remedy?
Let's go from experience and see
what is the psoric miasm.
And the psoric miasm as the word says,
is a miasm that comes from skin eruptions,
from suppressed skin eruptions producing what?
Producing inner states similar to the itching.
You will be surprised for instance to see in some cases that a skin eruption that is very itchy,
produces a state of restlessness and anxiety which never leaves you in peace.
It produces a similar inner state. Have you been really ever having a skin eruption that is itching?
You will see that you go to sleep and then you start scratching and scratching and you turn and you turn and you turn.
And that is an anxiety state or a restlessness state which is, in the same way that you need to scratch,
you need to scratch your brain. Or if it's going into the lungs this itching, then there is constant irritation
of the lungs all the time. But ok, you say you have the psoric miasm. What is the remedy?
Does this help you to see the remedy?
Very few cases are clear cases where you will say, now I treated this case with syphilitic remedies,
she started with Aurum, went to Mercury, took Syphilinum etc. and now is coming with symptoms of psora.
This itching, this restlessness, this anxiety has developed. Very few cases.
And you will see from the cases we treat how much more complicated are things, even with cases which are clear cases.
Let's take the case where we prescribed Ignatia 50M and then it came to Sulphur clear and then Calcarea carbonica clear.
What is this miasm?
Ignatia you have
to say belongs to what miasm?
And then because of this problem, those who brought up these theories for those who are interested,
they said Ignatia oh, Ignatia is syphilitic,
is sycotic and is psoric.
Sulphur, what is Sulphur? Oh Sulphur is primarily psoric, primarily syphilitic and primarily sycotic. What is really going on?
I had a student of Ortega here in Alonissos
and I presented a case of Medorrhinum.
A Medorrhinum which is very introverted, it cannot talk at all. It will not communicate, it's totally antisocial.
The words cannot come out. They cannot
stay with a group of people unless they drink.
If they are drunk they can communicate,
they can go out of the house etc.
I presented this case and she was down in the class and I said, what is this case? You tell me.
She was the best student of Ortega. She had in her mind this prejudice. She said, this case is a clear case of Calcarea carbonica.
I asked the other students. Some of them said this is a case of Medorrhinum because it's better in the sea
and desires unripe fruits and things like that
and because they were some other indications.
She said, it's a clear case but the remedy which cured this case was Medorrhinum unfortunately.
It doesn't matter what your ideas are and
your preconceptions or even prejudice.
Because if you have some prejudices you are going to have a problem with Homeopathy.
If you can become somebody who does not know anything when you see a case, my God I don't know anything.
If you have that state of feeling that I dont' know anything, then everything that the patient says
will be impressed upon you and then the anamnesis from what you know, eventually will come.
If you go with the idea that I know this, I know the miasms, immediately you cut down the possibility of information to flow in.
You have a preconceived idea.
Forget about finding the remedy.
You have to be like a blackboard on which nothing is written and the patient is going to write the symptoms.
And you receive all the symptoms and then you make an analysis and then you make a synthesis.
In the same way, the idea of the miasm
a lot of misconceptions have taken place.
The itch has a similar inner state. The
Syphilis also has an analogous inner state.
From conventional Medicine you know the stages of Syphilis, if they go in they can affect of course the vascular system,
it can affect the nervous system and it can affect the skin. So there are certain stages which you know.
Syphilis will follow. But what is the mental-emotional state of the syphilitic patient we don't know.
The only thing we know when it has affected the nervous system and then in the end of the nervous system
you see a distraction of the mental faculties, after you have seen the Tabes dorsalis, the paralysis on the nervous system,
then eventually you will see the distraction of the central nervous system as well. But before that,
there are some distractions that have been done on a subtle level with Syphilis which are interesting to study.
For instance if we had the possibility, that the Universities had students working in different subjects,
and we had a hospital, I could give them research projects that we could find fantastic things and to put in order
again back in order what is today a confusion in Medicine.
Then Syphilis is creating a state in the organism which is self-destructive and in order to prevent that self-destruction
because it is an organism that goes
into the body and wants to kill everything.
You intervene in that process and you save the patient, but the idea is to destruct and to distort and to kill.
So the organism in order not to die finds ways out. And what we see is perversions in thinking,
perversions in feelings, perversions in sex.
So a lot of perverted sexual practices which are happening in certain nations, I would say,
who they were under the effect of Syphilis, are due to great exposure to primary syphilitic infection.
Alcoholism, the use of drugs, when I say drugs
I mean the narcotics, is a syphilitic perversion
but these perversions in sexual issues
they take a lot of distorted expressions.
And depending on how strong the syphilitic tendency is there in the body, so bigger is going to be the self-destruction.
Why do we say Aurum is a syphilitic remedy?
Because it has this idea of self-destruction very strongly. In the same way Platina is syphilitic.
These are remedies which have all kinds of perversions and self-destruction.
So as an idea we may say Syphilis has self-destruction and perversions. And this is a theme, a general theme.
And it comes from the actual facts of this infection. Now if you go to sycosis, you have different facts.
In Gonorrhea for instance, which we're mostly talking about, we see as the immediate reaction
of suppressed Gonorrhea, we see condylomata.
That means the organism under Gonorrhea
infection has the tendency to bring out an eruption, a hard tumor.
It's like a volcano. It cannot retain it. It has to come out to the surface. That's the idea.
But when you see self-destruction tendencies together with condylomata, which is going to go first?
What determines what is going to go first are the symptoms. What are the main uppermost symptoms,
keynote symptoms on which you're
going to base your prescription?
If you don't know the theory of miasms at all, if you don't understand anything, still you can be a very good Homeopath.
If you understand the theory and you know the theory, it will make you a better philosopher but not a better healer.
You see your enthusiasm when I say, I' m going to talk about miasms, why? Because in your mind you had the idea
that if we know the miasms then we can
more easily find the remedies. Forget it.
I can tell you it can misguide you and you can give the wrong medicine. I have seen it again and again.
I say why did you give this remedy?
It's a syphilitic case so I thought of Mercury.
I said, Mercury did something? No. Ok, give Medorrhinum, see what happens with Medorrhinum.
We have an explosive character, we have an expressive character in Sycosis, that is true but they say, for instance,
Natrum sulphuricum, what is this remedy?
Sycotic, syphilitic or psoric?
-Sycotic.
-Mostly sycotic. They say, mostly sycotic.
Ok, take a Nat-s patient with an asthma case and try to show me where is this explosive general attitude, expressive.
It's not expressive, it's a remedy which is very composed in the mental-emotional, very unexpressive I would say,
but you need Nat-s, why? Because of the 4am aggravation. If you think that this is a case of Syphilis,
you will never give a Nat-s but you see the 4 o'clock aggravation etc. No, no it's a syphilitic case and will give
Syphilinum or will give Mercury. Again you go to tubercular miasm. It has a kind of overall picture.
What it this overall picture? First of all cachexia, it doesn't allow the person to develop properly.
Secondly you see easy infections,
especially of the respiratory tract.
Repeated infections of the respiratory tract together with a kind of cachexia, it has to give you the idea of Tuberculinum.
But in Tuberculinum you have to have the grinding of the teeth, the desire for fat, desire for pork etc.
Little things like that which will give you the clue.
What is the general idea of cancer, of cancerous miasm because you have found out many times when a person says,
my mother died, my father died, my uncles died from cancer, you give Cancerinum and many times
they will say that this was an excellent remedy for me. That means it took away a complex net
that was blocking the case due
to this hereditary predisposition
and then you find out more or less
what was taking out from this case,
what was the general indications and then that's how we came to know the symptomatology of Cancerinum.
And this is how we found out that Cancerinum has both types of people. One who is suppressed but nice
and the other which is angry and loose and just doesn't care who is going to kill around.
There are these two types of persons in Cancerinum. The one that is like a "bulldozer" they will go around the house,
their own environment, children they don't care, they don't care about parents, if they hurt them, if they don't hurt them.
'Just give me money, you are my mother you have to give me money. You are a bad mother'.
And then the mother says, 'ok take money'. 'Buy me a motorbike. I can't go to school walking, it's half an hour'.
He sleeps up to 10 o'clock, wake up, leave
me alone, wake up you have to go to school.
The mother says, 'I'm afraid because he will hit me'. That type can be a Cancerinum type, this explosive.
This is where we have the final stages where it destroys everything; the cancer destroys the body totally in a very short time.
-So you are saying it's not influencing your praxis and you never mention miasms anyway. But Hahnemann says that
when the best chosen remedy is not working with the patient, he was looking for the possible miasm,
Tuberculosis in the family which he treated with a kind of priority and gave a remedy for that. If there was Syphilis
in the family, he gave a syphilitic remedy,
so you didn't find anything like that?
-No. There is no such thing. You may do it and still you may be effective sometimes but there are no rules
on which you can base a prescription
concerning the knowledge of a miasm. There are no rules.
If you say at a certain moment, let me give some nosodes and some people do it as a regular practice, they give
Medorrhinum, Syphilinum Tuberculinum, they give Psorinum in the beginning of their treatment.
And they claim to have some effect. Of course, these people who need one of these nosodes will be affected.
What about the others? They have
taken deep nosodes for no reason.
-But you have a case which has had Tuberculosis before and has 1-2 keynotes of Tuberculosis.
-Yes, if you have 1-2. But let us say, you have a case which had Tuberculosis and you see a case clear Calcarea carbonica.
What are you going to give?
Tuberculinum or Calcarea carbonica?
Actually one of my students in Athens when she came first, she came with Tuberculosis and still was there.
You could see in the X-ray.
It was a case of Calcarea carbonica.
I gave her Calcarea carbonica and the whole thing disappeared. It cleared up and the whole organism
started developing again in 2-3 months. If I had this idea? Another case I remember of Syphilis.
Syphilis that was positive after years of treatment with penicillin, still was positive after the test.
And this was a case of Calcarea carbonica. I gave her Calcarea carbonica and the test became negative
and the woman felt much better.
Now if I had this idea of Syphilinum, why?
But from the very beginning I mistrusted because when I saw her, I did this one time, two times.
You have to observe, it doesn't work. Then something else happens and what is this something else?
It is these things here, the 3 keynotes. If you have 3 keynotes of Tuberculinum, you give Tuberculinum, there is no question.
With tuberculous idea plus 1,2,3 keynotes, you give Tuberculinum. On the other hand if you do have more symptoms of Sulphur,
you have to give Sulphur, nevermind what you know about the family.
I know that my father had Syphilis; it does
not matter, still Sulphur will be indicated?
Calcarea carbonica will be indicated? You give it.
I try to take you out of the frame of mind which is set on certain things.
Why do you think I do not give you indications
of what to do in different pathological cases?
Do you think I don't know?
I know very well and I know that if I put together 5 remedies I can make a specific composition
that will affect most of the individuals
that have that particular pathology.
But if I do that I will become very rich I can assure you because all over the world they'd be selling
these GV composite for rheumatic, whatever and then I would be very rich but I would have destroyed Homeopathy,
the possibility to really cure, to really regenerate a generation which is going down the gutter and there is no hope.
It's going to be degenerated more and
more. And if I do that what they will do?
They will go to the pharmacy and say, give me this rheumatic or give me this rhinitic or give me this headache pill
and they will feel better and they can go on.
But this better needs the second remedy and needs the third remedy
and when is the time for the second
or the third and what follows the first remedy?
And why after the first remedy it has to go to Sulphur, there are reasons. And I'm teaching you that and I don't
want to teach you easy ways. If you want easy ways you just sit in a chair and you meditate
what is your problem my dear child? My eyes are running and bla, bla, bla. I don't need anything else.
Take Euphrasia, Clematis, Graphites and Sulphur. And you become a guru.
I mean when I was in Pakistan, I met the doctor of the President of Democracy. He was his personal and I said,
can I sit with you to see your practice? Of course sit there. He was chewing some kind of red stuff, you know.
The patient would come, I could not understand of course but I could hear 2-5 words and then I could see him writing
a kind of prescription with 5-6 remedies. Take these remedies, you go there, he has his own pharmacy.
I said, 'very impressive. Do you have success'? 'Absolutely. He says, what are you doing?'
I said, 'maybe I've taken much more time. But you see so many people, how can you spend so much time?'
And I explained to him a little bit,
very carefully, so not to insult him.
Because he was my host and when
he is your host you are a little bit polite.
In the end he said to me, how much money you're earning with this practice? I told him something.
He says, I earn 20 times more than you.
I said, good luck. I don't know what's happening to him today but he was much younger than me.
But the idea is that you can do that with Homeopathy. Is this the correct way?
And why you are here? You are here only for that reason to see another aspect, another idea and I must show you this idea,
I must show you this aspect. My idea is not to give you easy solutions.
My idea is to give you the difficult and the difficulties and then the reward will come.
Because people will understand
eventually who is good and who is bad.
-The heritage, the inheritance, these nets are becoming more and more tight for our children, right?
Is it possible through correct treatment and through lifting one miasmatic layer after the other to make it possible
for our children and future children
to become more and more healthy?
And would it be possible in the end even to eradicate all these nets and miasmatic difficulties and if it is possible,
is it possible within one generation or how
many generations do you think it will need?
- A lot of difficult questions but I can give you my impression. It's not the truth but my impression is that yes there is a possibility
of taking away the miasms; to what extend I'm not sure. Yes there is a possibility of regenerating the race.
That means instead of your children being born in that state, if you take good Homeopathy for 3 years before,
your children will definitely be born better. But how many generations may take, it may take 3,4,5 I cannot say.
What I want to tell is this: let us say that somebody is using heroin which is the strongest of the recreational drugs.
And this person at a certain moment decides
to give up and become what they call, clean.
And he goes to a detoxifying community or whatever. He doesn't do Homeopathy and then he marries
and that person has a child. Is his child going to be affected by the heroine miasm, yes or no? Who says yes?
Who says no. Nobody.
I'll tell you my experience that each organism
has a kind of resistance to any chemicals.
Whatever chemical you give to my organism, it has a kind of resistance. So I resist, therefore when I say I resist,
I eliminate and no effect until such time when my resistance breaks at a certain point and my symptomatology
starts changing. Once this has
happened, there is a possibility
of a miasm which is going to be
transferred to the next generation.
That means the effect of the drug has been written upon my DNA. There is a DNA effect, further than that
with this particular drug. This particular drug
will create a miasm for my offsprings.
"progeny" that was the word I was trying to find. So therefore a person who has taken heroin
or has taken penicillin or whatever drug it doesn't necessarily mean that he has created a state of miasm.
The state of miasm is created once this
broken down situation has happened.
You know the people who have taken marihuana, they may develop a state of a miasm with a little bit of marihuana, when?
When you will see this person is going to a state of anxiety after that, they lose totally their inner quietness,
they go into a state of anxiety and fears,
esp. fear that they're going crazy.
Once they're in that state of anxiety
and fears and they have children, forget it.
Their children will be born with anxiety and fears.
But if you treat them homeopathically you can spare the children from these anxieties.
-George if I can come back to the story of the miasm, we study miasm to understand the different level,
to understand the process of cure but what is essential is always to come back to the symptomatology
and to prescribe according to how clear is the picture and how many keynotes and
how much confirmation we have
on prescribing the remedy.
-Is it correct?
-That's correct. Of course there are a lot of things to be discussed
and we can spend hours and hours to discuss in detail and there is also a possibility for reasearch in these matters
which can clarify for us much more issues but at this moment from a practical point of view what we need to know
is that we're dealing with that situation, that's the first one. We're dealing with a case of complex miasmatic conditions.
The second is to know that the elimination of such nets is done due to the correct uppermost remedy.
It's not possible to say, this person needs Calc, let's give him from the beginning Calc. No.
-Can you explain again the difference
between the miasm and the layers?
-Ok, this is a miasm.
What is a layer on the miasm?
This is a layer on a miasm and
this layer we call it Arsenicum
and once the Arsenicum is gone there
is this layer which is called Sulphur.
And perhaps even a third remedy.
And this miasm is lifted.
Let's go back to the case of A. with Pituitary gland extract that we gave. Which is the miasm?
You believe that by taking different
remedies you have the same effect, no.
You have to find the uppermost layer, nevermind what you call it. What is the miasm that was created under the vaccination,
let us say chicken pox or the triple vaccination etc. One organism is producing a state of Cuprum,
the other organism is producing a state of Stamonium, the other first Stam. then Pitu-gl. then Bar-c...
-What is your opinion about using the pills so frequent now and cortisone. I pay attention that the children
who received cortisone because of asthma came to school with restlessness, with hyperactivity.
And then they received Ritalin and this is
very complicated case for me to treat it.
-Exactly. This is the idea. I mean you take some chemicals in the body...they found out
ah, you want to have safe sex, you take the pill.
-Not only chemical. It is hormone. It is something very active for the organism.
-That is what I say. Hormones are deep chemicals which affect the organism tremendously.
It's not lightly that you advice a young girl,
just take the pill so you just have safe sex.
Because there are other ways to have safe sex after all. There are the condoms and there is no harm for anybody.
Why should the woman go into that state?
And then have children which are
born with cancer? Sterility?
This is the state which the whole of planet is going at the moment because we need easy solutions
and I'm not going to give you easy solutions.