[...]
-For how long?
-3 months. Since last November very mildly and then it became worse.
I took some treatment when it was still mild and over the treatment it went worse and
worse; so I stopped that treatment and over the last 3 months I've tried other things.
-Chiropracticing.
-Yes the last 3 weeks I went to other people to do more gentle things and then
Homeopathy the last 3 months has been every week.
I've got to try something now. I tried a treatment for 3 weeks and after 3 weeks
I realized it's not working, not changing, so I'm very desperate. Sorry.
-I'll give you my first thoughts very quickly.
The history, as she relates, it suggests that might be a slip disc, in which case you might
have a serious condition.
That means the sciatic nerve is pressed and it is a mechanical pressure.
This is what I'm thinking at the moment and the second thing I'm thinking, looking at her
in her body, I see there is a kind of flabbiness and I see also that the abdominal muscles
especially are not strong enough.
That means she is a girl who has not been doing exercises and she has a predisposition
for lumbago and with sciatica.
The other thing which I perceive is that she is suffering very much, that the pain is
constant and what I'm interested is to see whether there is any position in which
she is better and she can answer now.
-Usually when the pain is bad  sit on my hunches of my hands and knees.
It used to help but then owed to be sitting on the floor on my knees with my hands on
the back, that would help.
But now sitting like this the pain is a little bit better.
-You have sciatica on right side? Do you have a lumbago at the same time?
-I don't know.
-The first thing we want to understand is the pathology because pathology is
quite severe and we have to understand exactly what pathology and the modalities.
Therefore my questions will be concerning the pathology and the modalities.
The sciatica is starting from where? Can you put your hand?
-There and travels all the way down...
-This is right sciatica on the right side and which goes right to the foot, suggest as
primary, Lachesis. The right sciatica extending to the foot suggests Lachesis primarily
because of the pathology. I have this in mind and my next question will be what is the
position that ameliorates?
Is it by pressing, by warm, by cold, by lying in a position, by standing, by walking
by lying in a particular side?
-Lying on my left side is better and warm is better.
-Lying on the left side means when she lies on the painful side, she is much worse.
I picked up the way she said much worse. The much worse is a symptom which I want
to take into consideration because she stressed that symptom.
During this time I want to know what remedies have been tried in this condition?
Could you enumerate the remedies that have been tried?
-First Colocynthis, then Sepia, Cantharis, then we tried 10M Thuja because it was a
constitutional remedy I had, 10M Lac Caninum because there was another remedy
I had before, then the homeopath finished, he said see somebody else.
This homeopath gave me first Staphysagria, then Ignatia, then Pulsatilla, then last
week Carcinosin all in 30, not high.
They all helped me a little bit but nothing touched the pain.
-Other remedies?
-With my constitutional treatment Lac Caninum and Thuja.
-Are you afraid of snakes?
-This was 3 years ago. Hypericum and Arnica were taken; two nights ago I took
Hypericum 200, 5 doses and it helped. And Ruta 30 this morning, 2 doses.
-All these underline 3 times. Underline is very important, how long you underline a case.
We don't have the symptom better lying in knee-elbow position, as she describes.
In the case we don't have a symptom, I have said many times, we can take a similar
symptom; that means worse or better in general lying on knee-elbow position.
So lying on knee-elbow position better, which is peculiar position in a case of sciatica
we have remedies like Medorrhinum and Kali carbonicum.
When she arrives at that point of information my main thinking is, is this a Kali carbonicum case,
a Medorrhinum or Lachesis case?
But we don't have enough information at this moment to prescribe any of these remedies.
Crying while telling her symptoms now is not really a symptom because the pain is so
severe that she can cry. We can not really take it as crying during consultation because
it's almost inevitable symptom.
I want to differentiate between these remedies and we have also a symptom which is
worse lying on painful side.
There is a kind of restlessness, as you can see. She can not stand in one position.
Restlessness, she has to move all the time because of pain.
I am thinking what can be the best question that I can ask her.
I want to differentiate the Lachesis possibility. My question would have been in case
you have not heard all my thinking, the question would be how do you feel with tight
clothes around your neck, your waist, your breast?
-I don't like them around my waist. I don't wear them around my neck at all.
-Why?
-I don't like tight clothes.
-This now gives me a confirmation for Lachesis but in my mind knowing that she knows
Homeopathy, that's the first. The second is that she may be interested to have Lachesis.
I do not take this into consideration very much.
Therefore I'm going to ask other questions which are pertinent to Lachesis.
Then I go back to the original state, why this situation has arised on the first place?
So thinking the idea of Lachesis and thinking that maybe before this incident there was
a kind of incident between herself and her husband, boyfriend.
Whether there is a causative factor that will confirm Lachesis, for instance a jealousy
situation that has arised by last September of October, just before the incident took place.
My question that you will hear asking is why she thinks this whole thing has started.
Most probably the answer will be I don't know.
-I know.
-Tell us.
-Because I left my partner last November, in the same month that the pain started.
It was not jealousy. I had to leave him.
-Whom you liked?
-By the time I left, I hated him.
-Because he had done something?
-A lots of things.
-Between these things that he had done, what it was? Can you describe a little bit?
-He hits me and we argue and he was very dominant and he never listens to me and
I felt trapped; it took a long time for me to decide...
-But you have thought of leaving him a long time ago?
-Yes.
-And you were battling with this idea for several months?
-Yes a long time, a year.
-But what prevented you from leaving him much earlier, most probably was what?
-Just a feeling that it might be the wrong decision and my daughter and my father
I was worried for my family thinking I had failed. I was afraid as well of being on my own.
-This was your husband or your partner?
-Partner.
-So legally you are not bound to him but emotionally very much.
This is a case of Lachesis. I expect some extra passion was involved in this affair
and therefore I will ask her the question, what kind of a relationship was there?
Was a relationship of rather cool or it was real passionate things involved?
-Tempest. Very passionate and I felt deep in love when I met him. We have a child.
I thought we were going to be together for ever but he changed.
-And he changed in such a way as to disappoint you mostly?
-Yes and it was unacceptable.
-His behavior towards you?
-Yes but I stayed and stayed thinking he will change.
-What was the first incident which you remember which made you decide this is not
good for me? Do you remember?
-Very well.
-Why I do these questions? I'm asking her in order to decipher whether under all this, but
I will tell you later on, I will let her talk first.
-The last decision I said, that's it. I'm leaving now, whatever happens I don't care.
The last time he hit me because there was no argument.
-I wanted the first time that made you think I have to leave or something like that
that was really bad, his behavior was really bad. Can you remember?
You will notice something else also in her, as she will bring out all the memories.
Now she has difficulty in bringing out the memory; that means there is something
there which she has hidden in her subconscious mind.
As she will bring this out, more and more, she will feel a little bit more comfortable in her sciatica.
As the sub-conscious anger, fear will bring out, she will be feeling better in her sciatica
and that is the reason why many times after the homeopathic consultation, we have the
patient saying, I'm feeling better.
It's never cured but it might be feeling better because he has brought out some
sub-conscious anger, fears, depressions etc, which were hidden very deep inside.
In this case I expect that the kind of sciatica has a deep root, that's why it keeps so
strongly and this root is mostly with the emotional level which is really hurt and really traumatized.
I insist that you will see how difficult it is for her and I observe that it is difficult, that
means it is deep. She has hidden the first incident that made her decide in her mind
almost sub-consciously that this is not a good relationship for me.
-There are so many. I can't remember the first time. I can't remember and...
I should have left a year ago but I can't remember the first time.
-By doing a repertorisation in this case and repertorising the symptoms, sciatica right side
combine the two. Leave out the general sciatica and put sciatica on the right side
because it is absolutely sciatica on the right side.
She does not complain about her left side at all.
Therefore we have sciatica lying on painful side, sensitive to clothing, abdomen,
sacral region extending to feet, lower limbs extending to foot and then ailments from grief.
Give the analysis.
The analysis says too many symptoms with intensity 3, you can ask questions about
Lycopodium, Apis and Lachesis. Very good.
The repertorization points to the idea of Lycopodium as well and points to the idea of
Apis, except of the idea of Lachesis which we have been investigating.
Back to the question.
She says she can not remember. Because she insists that she can not remember
I want to put now a straight forward question that is connected with Lachesis.
This question will not be, are you jealous because most probably she will say, no.
My question to her will be whether this man looked or had flirt or something with
another woman at another time, not lately. I'm talking about 2 years ago, 3 years ago
and what actually took place during that time?
-It was when we had seen each other, not long seen each other and he met a friend
of mine. It was a big flirt and she gave him a big kiss on the lips in the pub.
-In front of you?
-Yes and he was responded. I was furious and I could not talk and I wanted to leave.
I just stood in the corner of the pub and he came over and said, sorry and he gave me
a big kiss and she came over and she said, I'm so sorry. You know how I am like.
You know me. I didn't like it, not at all. He never did that again.
-Now with her answer we may have the idea of jealousy again but I'm not satisfied
with the idea of jealousy and I'm going to pursue it further. I will then ask whether such
incidents later on took place and more serious than this incident.
-No.
-You did not feel that he was flirting with other women, neglecting you.
I used to think that he was neglecting me but I think I had a fear that he was.
-According to you he was faithful?
-Yes.
-You believe that?
-Yes, I believe he was faithful. I think he looked.
-He liked the idea of flirting but not actually doing.
-No.
-I'm a bad investigator.
-He might wanted to.
-Now as I have lectured on Lachesis and I have said several times that Lachesis is not
always aware of her jealousy. Why? Because once she feels jealousy, then she is
closing inside, she will say I will never feel jealous again and then she presents another
picture where she becomes demanding.
You did not come on time, you left me there and this demanding on the part of the
woman who says, I'm not jealous, she will not accept she is jealous but the demands
are too much.
On the other hand, on the part of the man are received as excessive demands and
almost sometimes demands which are illogical.
Since we do not have this information from the man side we can only have information from her.
She seems to be quite prepared to talk openly and to talk the truth because she is
suffering a lot and she needs desperately to be well soon.
Of course all this time if I was examining this case without talking my thoughts, you would
have heard some questions but some of them would look like irrelevant questions.
The idea is that I'm investigating still the idea of Lachesis.
I have not gone to the idea of Lycopodium, Medorrhinum.
-My pain is better.
-Yes, you will be able now to talk a little bit more about these things and give us
information. You will have to analyze for us your character so I can understand.
The repertorisation of the computer gave me the idea of Lycopodium.
What I observe also is that she has the water here and drinks sips of water frequently.
Drinking frequently sips of water, one of the main remedies is Lycopodium, is not only
Arsenicum, you all know.
The repertorisation shows for me Lycopodium possibility, at the same time there is
a little symptom, which I observe, but maybe is because of anxiety that she is in front
of the class; therefore I will ask whether the water she is drinking now, in the way she is
drinking is a habit of the last months or it is only today?
-No, it's drinking water all the time because my mouth gets very dry.
-Actually you don't want a lot of water, just sips?
-Yes, I have to have a pint of water next to my bed every night.
-Here we got a good symptom which is a general symptom of the organism which points
out to the idea of Bryonia or Lycopodium.
Since we have Lycopodium, this we enter into our repertorisation and see what happens.
Do you put thirst frequently for small quantities and then we see.
You saw the idea of Lachesis was coming up and you were elated but the moment I see
the repertorisation, it points out to another possibility. I examine immediately the possibility
given the fact that I have seen a symptom of that remedy as well.
In my mind now there is Lachesis and Lycopodium and differentiation between
Lachesis and Lycopodium. How shall we differentiate?
I ask, can you describe your character in the idea she does not know what I'm asking.
She maybe describing a character which may be Lycopodium or a character which can
be Lachesis or she maybe describing another character all together.
Show the repertorisation. Again the same.
How would you describe your character? What are the main points in your character in
which you feel of course that there is some kind of pathology at this point?
I don't want to say, I'm a nice girl, I look after my children, I have a nice father who looks
after me, I like my family. All these are natural things which do not pertain to the idea
of pathology. We are asking to find what do you think that in your character are traits of pathology.
For instance, I'm very sloppy, I'm very egotistical, I'm very jealous, I'm crying, I'm demanding,
I'm manipulating others, I'm dictatorial. If I want something, I want this.
All these questions I'm putting now you would have heard without knowing what is in my
mind. But I've told you in my mind at this moment is the differentiation between
Lycopodium and Lachesis because Lycopodium also has the right side sciatica
and the other points which we have discussed.
-The best thing I can say is my sister, whom I live with now, she says that I am very
dismissive and I don't listen to her when she tries to tell me an idea or suggestion.
She said... her feelings because I didn't listen and I just swept over it and she said that
I was very one-track-minded, that I'm only interested in what is good for me
and that I couldn't take onboard anything that she suggested.
That was surprised me but I feel like I like to be on my own when I'm feeling strong but
then when I'm in pain, I need people around me.
But when I'm OK...
-You are quite independent?
-No, I think I'm quite needy with my partner that's why it was so hard for me to leave.
-Before I ask this question I have to explain to you why I put this question:
She said something important concerning the observation of her sister.
I want to know if that observation could be confirmed by the husband.
So I will ask what was the opinion of your husband?
-My husband said that I was always in control and that I was always got my own way.
-And I said, no you got your own way. But that's what he said.
We always said of each other the same.
He said I was in control and I said no he was in control.
But he said it all the time that I was the one who got it my way but it didn't feel like I did.
-I see. I'm not prepared to jump into conclusions and for instance conclude that she is
quite authoritative or dictatorial and jump into the idea of Lycopodium or to the idea of
being egotistical.
She actually describes an egotistical state where I dismiss others, I want my own way.
This is the idea of egotism, maybe we have to analyze this in the class, later on.
I want the egotistical element to be in the Repertorisation.
Now at this point, she is quited down because the sub-conscious does not resist the pain.
At this point if I perceive her well, she is very concentrated in what I'm going to ask her
next and how she will deal with the next questions. But I will forget about this and I'll go
to the father and ask the father what is his evaluation about the daughter.
Whether he can give us some information, an insight which can help us in the differentiation.
Can you show the Repertorisation?
We see here Lycopodium and Lachesis the two first remedies with the Lycopodium
being quite ahead of the list.
Lycopodium, show me how many of her symptoms covers? 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8 all of them.
So Lycopodium actually covers all the symptoms on which we have repertorised.
And Lachesis covers ...
So the father will try to describe. I will give you my observation concerning the father.
What I see from the father is that all along by the time that the daughter is relating her
case, he is in tears, he almost is very sympathetic, very much suffering at the same time.
Though being English and very phlegmatic and suppose not to show any emotions
he is crying and now he will stop to cry so to give me some information.
But the information he is going to give us, is not going to be very reliable.
This is my opinion at the moment, maybe I will be totally out but due to the very
sympathetic element towards the daughter, he can not be very objective.
Therefore, I'm asking but I'm not going to rely completely on what he is going to say.
After hearing all that he will try to be more objective.
Tell us.
-With pleasure. Little of the family background.
She and her twin brother was very, very pretty and she got very much attention.
Then when our daughter was born, when her sister was born, being a Taurus he was
very cuddly and I think without realizing I shifted a lot of my attention
onto the younger one not intending to neglect Sara.
I think that is something worth saying because what Sara has told me, when we talked about this,
when she had Lac caninum which helped tremendously, is that I was in my career becoming
famous and Anna was in the marketing job earning vast amount of money when was 18 and 19
very successful and she thought I was nothing which we all said it's rubbish.
I think she is very, very strong and very, very good and I think she is going to be a good
homeopath but she doesn't believe it. So she gets very dependent and I always say
we should always try to get the best and be the best and Sara was always thinking that
she is not worth the best and settling with less than good.
She has always been a bit dependent and needing support emotionally and she is
very rewarding because she is a lovely person but she just tends not to appreciate
herself and that's my view.
-As I thought, the father tries to give a good idea about the daughter making in
any case a hint concerning jealousy from young age that jealousy may have arised
in young age, already by the birth of the second daughter. So we'll ask Sara whether
she remembers having jealousy feelings when you were a child.
-I don't know but me and my sister never got on.
-That means you fought together?
-Yes.
-You must have noticed, it does not escape my attention, the moment I mention this
matter she will almost start feeling the pain again.
She will feel a little bit discomfort. So the observation sometimes will be of a tremendous
importance in your analysis of the case but never jump into conclusions because still
the case is not solved.
If we jump into conclusion giving Lachesis or Lycopodium, we may be totally wrong.
We may be discovering something very important on the process.
What is definite there is the fact that her sciatica at the moment is connected with
some emotional stress which she has kept inside, she has suppressed it, gone to the
sub-conscious and then this inner torment expresses itself in the physical body with
this sciatica.
-I think also she is very giving and sometimes she is too generous and gives of herself
too much. So she is depleted, wanting to please, wanting to help others.
-I want to see if Lachesis has desire of drinking sips of water.
-What about the issue of money? We should be talk about that.
What Sara told me about her relationship was that he was draining in her resources
financially and she wanted to be much stronger and not have this strain because he
would contribute sufficient.
-Was he working?
-He did work but very erratic and the last summer he didn't have any work at all and
I was working hard.
-You had actually support him and the child.
-Yes and study.
-And at the same time he was biting you?
-Yes, so I left.
-It was too much.
-Yes, it was the last drop.
-But I noticed something else. As she relates that, I see her color becomes a little
bit red which shows actually to me that she is still connected emotionally with him.
That means she has not really decided in the very deep part of herself to leave him
finally and totally. There is still some connection and some battling and some conflict
in her, whether this was the right decision or the wrong decision. Correct?
-Yes. My idea was that we would live apart and then perhaps that would make it easier
and we would change and I would change, we could perhaps look together again in a year.
I never wanted to say that it was totally over but since we have lived apart, I decided
that it has to be but it makes me sad.
-OK. Having reached that point I'm vacillating between Lachesis and Lycopodium.
I will put a question which is irrelevant to the mental-emotional state and which refers to
the general.
Lycopodium we know is much more sensitive to cold, whether Lachesis is more sensitive
to heat. We'll ask whether she is a warm person, where she can not tolerate heat or a
person who can not tolerate warm. What would you say?
Locally she has given already information that she is better heat, which is against
Lachesis and in favor Lycopodium but I ask in general.
-In general I have been feeling more chilly over the last months.
This winter in England has been very cold for me, more than normal.
-In bed your feet they both have the same temperature?
-I can't remember.
-This was a direct question of course for Lycopodium.
Lycopodium in bed feels the one foot can be warm, the other cold.
-With the sciatica this is always cold. This foot is cold and this foot is normal.
-You mean now with the sciatica, not before?
-Not before the sciatica.
-That means during the sciatica you noticed that there is a difference in temperature
between left and right.
-Yes definitely. One of the things I noticed is that this foot is cold.
-So the idea of Lycopodium again because of better heat and the difference in the cold
and heat of the feet, the idea of Lycopodium becomes even stronger.
Therefore my question in order to confirm Lycopodium, for the time being at least, will be
whether she is a person fond of sweets.
-Yes. I have all the time. I just love chocolate and ice-cream and cakes.
-Now?
-Yes, with the sciatica. I say to my sister when you go to the shop, get me chocolate
cake please. Get me anything sweet. And more sugar in my tea gradually.
-This is a symptom for which I have said in the class before, by chance, that when we
come to the point do you like sweets and you get an answer like this, which actually
can confirm and can save your life and the life of the patient.
Because you can imagine what can happen if we give the wrong remedy.
But I'm a very cautious person and I would like to know the truth and only the truth and
if it's possible the whole truth.
Therefore I want to understand what actually took place in this nice girl that we have
in front of us.
My idea now is that, is it possible perhaps that this is a case of Lachesis before
and then after has been beaten and decide to go away from this relationship, she has
gone into the state of Lycopodium?
If I understand it in this way, her problem, then I have a better chance of curing her
in depth; that means curing her sciatica and curing her predisposition to relapse and to
come back again and again.
I know also from our experience and from our books that Lachesis and Lycopodium are
complementary remedies.
So is it possible that the intolerance of clothing that points to Lachesis is a symptom that
we have to treat with the second remedy?
And is it possible that by giving Lycopodium some amelioration will take place and then
the Lachesis symptoms will become more prominent? How this will be?
It will be by reducing the desire for sweets and reducing the sensitivity to the cold.
There is another question here, is it possible that after Lycopodium it might be an
exacerbation or the sciatica with a change in the warmth and then immediately after
2-3 days of Lycopodium we may have to give Lachesis, in case there are some changes?
These are thoughts which I have in my mind while I'm taking her case.
Of course for one old looker what will hear is desire sweets...
If you take the questions, only the questions, you will not see a sequence, a real logic
behind it.
I will ask now another characteristic symptom of Lycopodium which is how do you feel
waking in the morning? You feel refreshed from sleep, unrefreshed?
-Do you mean now? With the sciatica?
-Yes.
-It's worse in the morning when I wake because it's worse in staying still for a while.
Whenever I have a short sleep for a few hours, when I wake up I know it's gonna be
really painful. So I'm not sleeping very much. 3 hours.
-So you wake up in the morning and you feel very sleepy still and you want to go back to sleep?
-Yes but I can't.
-Why you can't?
-Because of the pain in my leg.
-Now what she relates is the idea of suffering during sleep. So I go back to Lachesis and
I want to investigate the idea of suffering during sleep.
Therefore I will ask her whether she really suffers after going to bed the whole night
until the morning, more than the day time?
-Yes I do.
-This is so. You are suffering more in the night than in the day time.
-Yes.
-You suffer from the moment you go to bed or you go to sleep and then you wake up and
you start suffering?
-No, the only way that I could get any sleep is with pain killers.
Then when I wake up after 3 hours I'm in so much pain, I don't know how to stay awake.
-And then you take another pain killer?
-Well you can't. You have to wait the pain killers to wear off, 3 hours is not enough time.
So I have to wait 3 hours to take more pain killers and then perhaps I will go back to
sleep for 3 hours and then it's 8 o'clock in the morning.
-My question confirming Lycopodium actually confirmed rather Lachesis than
Lycopodium. There are some symptoms of Lycopodium there as well.
Therefore I will ask another symptom, whether she feels bloated in the abdomen
whether she has a lot of gas, a lot of eructations?
-No.
-She has no gas, no eructation.
-I think I used to, maybe last year but no.
-Another symptom that could confirm Lycopodium is whether she has an aggravation
from onions. You can eat onions?
-Yes, Greek salad.
-Onions, everything and you enjoy, no problem?
-Yes.
-Pain worse lying in bed, did you put?
Actually by lying you are not feeling better in pain.
-No, not really. It's a funny kind of pain.
-So back to the idea of Lachesis I would like to investigate how strong is the symptom
of intolerance of clothing around the neck.
-I just never wear anything round my neck.
-You can forget it?
-I have a jumper which has a raw neck but it's very lose.
-But you keep on doing this?
-No because I know it's not touching my neck. I just don't have any clothes that do that.
-So you know what to buy.
-I don't like tight things.
My daughter often comes behind me and puts her hands arround my neck and I hate it.
I have smacked her once. I really hate when she does that.
-Tell me something else. You answer if you like, if you don't like you don't answer.
Were you faithful to him?
-Yes.
-Were you very passionate sexually with him?
-At first.
-Very?
-Yes.
-You enjoyed sexual intercourse?
-And it was perfect?
-Yes.
-Later on what happened? You lost interest?
-I didn't exactly lose interest of having sex but lost interest of having sex with him
because I didn't like it. He wanted but I didn't.
-You were quite easily excitable person sexually, right? -Yes.
-By the moment you do not have sex with him, you miss sex or not too much.
-Not too much. I can remember complaining to my friends that I have wanted sex too
but not with John.
-And you did not attempt to have sex with somebody outside?
-No. I wanted to but I didn't. Fantasy.
-You can say, I don't like this question. You know what I' m going to ask you?
-No.
-Did you have to masturbate sometimes?
-Yes sometimes.
-Here we are stuck with a very difficult decision between Lycopodium and Lachesis
as you can see.
Lycopodium is a person which goes for sex and sex which is easy, easy partners.
If she was a Lycopodium case, she would most probably have had some sexual
relationships, like one time, just to release.
-She denies that.
-I haven't.
-And as you can all see, she is quite honest about it.
Therefore the idea of Lachesis again is challenged and the idea of Lachesis again has
come up due to intolerance of clothes which is underlined 3 times definitely.
-George the idea of Lycopodium is challenged or Lachesis?
-The idea of Lycopodium is challenged.
Lachesis will stay with passionate, she will go with masturbation, that is capital in
masturbation but will not easily go with another partner because she is emotionally
involved in a kind of binding, emotionally involved with some kind of real passion.
-Lycopodium is the opposite. They are attached to responsibility and if they find the
freedom for no responsibility, they should go for it.
-She is taking responsibility for the family actually and she has tolerated quite a lot
and what I see is that she is quite calm, the pain is reduced to a considerable degree.
So this is the time where you ponder, you think about the case.
It's not very easy to prescribe on the case and you may have given because of the right
sciatica, as I said, in the very beginning.
I said immediately, these are Lachesis symptoms. I could have given Lachesis and it
could have acted.
But if you really want a responsible work to know what you're doing and then the person
will eventually become better and better in her health, then you will have to investigate
in this kind of investigation.
Understanding exactly what is the situation and knowing exactly why you are prescribing
one remedy or another.
What about the desire for sweets which has arisen lately and which points to the idea of
Lycopodium?
Shall we go straight to Lachesis or shall we go through Lycopodium?
This is the question.
Therefore we can ask some more details to see what she was before and whether
anything has changed.
Concerning her menses, what can you say about that?
-Before my period my breast is swelling up which is new.
-So swelling of breast before menses. What else?
-The period about 3 months ago, my period kept coming early but now it seems to have
settled again.
-Before, did you have any problem before menses?
You became irritable or weepy or pains in the abdomen?
-Mainly if I get any PMT it would be irritable and then a burst of tears and then OK.
Usually the day before period comes and then usually my period is fine.
-So the disturbance in the menses most probably comes because of the different
remedies she has received already.
What it appears is that in her hormonal system, it works quite good, the sexual sphere
is quite correct, we do not find much problems in that sphere.
That's why we don't see very clearly the premenstrual syndrome of Lachesis where
we have all this premenstrual syndrome, relieved immediately with the flow of menses.
She has said the same thing, the first day only etc. which points to the idea that even
that little disturbance which she has is ameliorated whilst the flow is established.
Correct?
-Yes, even the breast goes down when the flow comes.
-Can you put this into Repertorisation?
What about fears? Do you have any fear?
-I feel like my biggest fear at the moment is being on my own.
Being a mother of my own since I left.
-And having all the responsibility by yourself and carrying everything on your back?
Then what are your feelings inside this? That you lost your time, you wasted time?
-Yes and I feel ...
-You hate him for that?
-Yes, I hate him for failing.
-You or himself?
-Everything. I am 28, I feel that I've already lived a whole life. I'm very tired.
-So by this answer and if you could look at her eyes, you see really the deep suffering
that has gone through this girl and this deep suffering and how much she tolerated so far.
You tolerated a lot, that's why you feel tired. You did not have enough enjoyment.
-That's right. And after I left it was even harder because I had to look after on my own.
I thought that leaving would be the end but the last 7 months I've been very hard as well.
-And as she describes the inner state, harder and harder, the more we see this impact
upon the nerves, the peripheral nerves, that means none of these remedies have gone
deep enough to relieve her from this hatred and anger which is there and all these  feelings.
-And suffering.
-Why did I have to suffer?
-Yes, it's not fair. I feel angry because I feel like I did a good thing to leave but now I have this...
-And you suffer much more. This actually is the manifestation of suffering on the
physical body and that is why you see her in spite of all this suffering, in spite of all this
anger inside, she is in a quite good and balanced condition mentally and emotionally.
Your condition mental and emotional could have been much worse in case the whole
thing had not manifest in the sciatica.
-Yes I agree.
-This is what [..]  said who saw her that years ago she had been emotionally dependent
[..] so her health has progressed very well over the years.
-She is able throughout this manifestation to keep her balance in spite of all these
adverse things which are happening in your life.
-Yes, now I'm happy with what has happened in my life now. I have to get through this
last of this pain, that's what I feel.
-There are a lot of other questions of course we can be asking in this case like
previous diseases etc. also vaccinations and also whether previous to this affair
to this man, you were suffering with another affair?
-No. Not the same way, not bad. No one is ever hit me before. That was the first one.
-What about with your tongue? You could hurt him also with your tongue?
-Yes.
-You will not forgive him very easily.
-I think so, but not to his face because ...
-You will talk badly about him with others, with friends.
-Yes.
-I hate him very much but you were afraid that he may hit you very hard if you do
something in front of his face.
-Yes.
-That is again another Lycopodium symptom that you will feel not able to face him and
tell him and face the hurt and the heat.
So with this idea I think we can stop and since you are ready, feeling better, you may
be able to walk and see what happens. I will bring you the remedy and then we'll have
a follow up in 2-3 days before the examination.
It's very interesting the Expert System says, I can not make a decision between
Lachesis and Lycopodium!
It says the most probable remedy is Lycopodium and the most probable remedy is Lachesis.
-But in the first when we used to have arguments, I did use to fight and shout and just
be like him but he was stronger than me.
-He would hit you finally so you had to subdue.
-Yes but then I went inside.
-Thank you.
-Thank you George.