-What is the problem?
-I try to tell the story in sequence. The symptoms, because of which I come, last back
15 years. It's started suddenly after the delivery of my first child.
I had to deliver in the evening and the next morning I woke in an unknown room, I felt
the emptiness in my head. I stood up, there was a door, I went in and I took a shower.
I was amazed what I'm doing here, I was not amazed what I'm doing here, there was a
breakfast beside my bed and then I sat down and I was just staring to the emptiness.
For about one hour and then the door opened and the nurse came in and she said
don't you want to see your child? I said, yes I have given birth to a child and from then
on I had again and again such sequences of blackouts. I forgot to go and get my children
from school, I have 4 children and every birth it was a sudden fall down and I slightly
recovered and after the next delivery, the same happened again.
At the same time I had difficulties in wording, in speaking, I used the wrong words, I couldn't
control my tongue anymore. That improved too but at the same time I'm an interpreter too
and even though I had these difficulties I could work as an interpreter for 8 hours the day
without any mistakes. And when I went out of the cabin, it started all over immediately.
-Is she suffering with anemia? -No.
-And the third symptom I couldn't estimate how the ground on which I was, was.
Sometimes it turned roundish, sometimes I couldn't estimate the distance.
I had the impression that it was coming up to my nose, like the ground was broken and
I couldn't walk or I couldn't really see the color. It was very dramatic after the deliveries and
this state comes too in a more mild form, when I'm emotionally upset.
-Sudden loss of memory after pregnany. Did she ever had any concussion?
- I had a neurological check-up.
The first neurologist said it was an emboli in my brain and I said that can't be because it comes
on again when I'm emotionally excited; so I went to a second neurologist and he said
narcolepsy because on the E.E.C. you have in my waken state, you have the reason of sleep.
Waves like in sleep. It's very exhausting for me to fixate at certain point, I just stay into the
emptiness. It just happened to me again, some days ago, when I left the airport of Dusseldorf
I went through the first control, it was a chair, I sat down and everything was just gone.
I just don't think. I have no thoughts.
-There is an complete emptiness, nothing.
-Nothing. The second said narcolepsy, I wasn't content with that either so I went to see
a third neurologist and he said, he can't really explain that but he thinks it's a latent
depression which always comes up after the delivery.
-But it was a definite change in the encephalogram? They were able to do an encephalogram
during the crisis or even outside of the crisis?
-It's difficult to say. They put these electrons on my head and then I had to sit down and
as soon as I don't have to do anything, as soon as I don't push myself to do anything
I fall into that state.
-She can fall back so easily?
-Into here during the lecture when there is break of some minutes, I just fall back into it.
I just sit there and I stare in front of me and I don't hear anything, I don't see anything.
-She never has any picture?
-I see but I don't produce any thoughts. Recently it happened to me when I was on the
telephone. I was on the telephone and I said, yes I will look it up immediately.
After I had said, I immediately forgot it, so I stayed on the telephone and the other guy
is waiting but I forgot it and so he waited and I stayed on the telephone and me too I had
forgotten that I was on the telephone too.
-So she put down the telephone?
-No, I stayed like this and then suddenly I heard that voice and I got frightened.
-Then she remembered?
-Yes, I can recall, I can remember. The neurologist didn't talk about weak memory but
deficiency in concentration.
-Is she a medical doctor?
-Healing practitioner.
-What she was doing before?
-I was a simultaneous interpreter.
-Did she push herself too much? She lost herself in the effort?
-The first time it happened I was in a state of exhaustion.
-When it was the first time?
-After delivery.
-What age?
-33.
-She can recall things of the past. I had no problems after the delivery, no problems at that
time; the first time I went back to interpretation, it was two months after the delivery and I had
to learn about 200 vocabularies, over night in two different languages.
I had no problems with this.
-Has this ever happened during driving?
-No because then I'm intense. When I' stressed, never.
-She has to relax to happen.
-Yes.
-This delusions that the floor is curved or broken come frequently?
-No they don't come very frequently, they come in certain emotional situations.
Like when I pick up my sister from the airport or when I say goodbye to a good friend of mine.
-She was married the man who loved or she loved somebody and then she broke away with
him and then she married somebody else?
-I have been married for 25 years.
-I didn't ask how many years she was married. I asked something else.
She has a good relationship now with her husband?
-Yes.
-She has dreams?
-Hardly.
-She can not remember her dreams?
-No.
-She has any dream which she remembers, a vivid dream?
-No, but it's always the same pattern. When I have a special day, on the next morning
I always dream that I lose something and that I can't find something that I definitely need
for the next morning. And then I wake up and I'm sweating.
-She wakes up in a fright?
-Wet with sweat.
-So what she feels is losing is very important.
-For example my shoes.
-Anything else?
-I'm always tired, as far as I can remember I've always being tired and I have a sudden
attacks of tiredness throughout the day which I break down in energy that I hardly can make
it home. I'm driving home with my car and then I get panic when I see the traffic light
turns red because that is gonna cost me 1 1/2 minute to go home and then I'm home and
never mind that the kids are around I say, make yourself something to eat, I have to sleep.
And I go immediately for sleep. And that is usually 1-2 o'clock at noon.
-Always has she been like this?
-Always.
-She examined the thyroid ever?
-It was always on the edge.
-Is she warm or cold?
-I'm always freezing.
-When she gets into that sudden weakness, is she more cold?
-Yes.
-She has chills?
-Yes chills.
-Is she very fastidious?
-I'm terribly untidy. Only not in my work.
-Otherwise she is... because she does not have much energy or it's her character like that?
-Both.
-Menses are regular? Before menses irritability?
-Nothing. I forget when it comes.
-It comes always in the day, always in the night or it can be anything?
-I don't know. The only thing I know is that it stops for one day and then it starts all over
again. Always.
-Menses interrupted. Any constipation?
-No. I have to pay attention very much to what I eat. I can't tolerate some things like carbohydrates if I
eat a plate of spaghetti I can't even walk for 10 m., I have to lie down for a sleep.
-She is worse with carbohydrates. What else?
-Spaghetti, bread, when I eat meat I get very excited. I reduced my food to fresh fruits
vegetables.
-She likes them also?
-Yes and raw fish.
-You eat in Germany raw fish or herself only?
-They eat in Japan and we have a lot of Japanese in Dusseldorf and you can eat that in
Dusseldorf. I get along very well with this.
-How much thirst?
-Not much.
-Perspiration?
-None unfortunately. I realize that sometimes I make like a special treatment, I put hot water
bottles in my bed and I try to get to sweat and it is the only possibility for me to wake the next
morning and be recovered, be refreshed.
-She does what?
-When she puts a lot of hot water bottles into her bed and covers up and sweats.
Sweating makes her next morning to feel refreshed.
-So sweating makes her feel good?
-Yes but otherwise I don't sweat ever.
-But she has to heat up, like sauna. How she feels emotionally?
-Up and down.
-Changing moods.
-Do you have dryness?
-A little bit.
-Not very much. Ever the tongue sticks up on the palate?
-Not that way but it is dry.
-For 9 years I have been in homeopathic treatment. I always take 2 years with every
homeopath because never a remedy worked. The only thing that once worked was
Phosphoric Acid.
-What did it do Phosphoric Acid?
-I suddenly had wings on my back, I couldn't walk anymore, I was just running and then
I don't know if there is any connection but I took one sip of coca-cola and within two
days it was like I was going out and I was falling back.
And I took it again but nothing. Since then I have had several remedies which didn't work.
-Sepia she had?
-Nothing. Natrum Muriaticum for years. Helleborus.
-She has self-confidence herself?
-It depends. Not here.
-I see she has too much actually. She is afraid of anything? Thunderstorms fear, fear of
dark, fear of death?
-Fear of economic crush.
-How much salt she takes?
-Normal.
-She likes lemon?
-No.
-She is restless?
-Very.
-What do you do? You just walk up and down? You take the telephone and you walk?
-I'm jogging or I'm cleaning.
-In a hurry inside?
-Always.
-And others must hurry also?
-No.
-Any salivation during night?
-How much water she drinks?
-One liter.
-One liter the day, 5 glasses?
-More.
-Any bleeding from nose?
-No.
-Tired, tired, tired but one time...total exhausted?
-Yes.
-Does she remember having skin eruption as a child?
-Yes on my left hand between the fingers.
-How it went away?
-With French homeopathy. Many, many remedies in the day.
-What age started with this syndrome?
-When I was 33.
-Did she have any time loss, she couldn't remember, any slight incident before?
-No.
-What other things she was suffering in her life?
-I have chronic bronchitis, always, the whole winter.
-And then she has dyspnea, she coughs a lot?
-Cough a lot, a lot of mucus and never fever.
-Cough that brings mucus and dyspnea?
-No dyspnea.
-And the whole winter goes like this?
-Yes.
-It starts when?
-In October and it goes up to March.
-All winter she coughs?
-The cold comes and then I'm tired for one week, I don't know why, then I have this cold
for about 3 weeks and then there is a break for 2-3 weeks and then it comes over again.
For some years I have problems with my lymph nodes. I have checked and there is nothing
to be found. I always have throbbing pains when I'm stressed, after alcohol, after spaghetti
or other things and now there is a permanent pain which I realize when I have certain
position, during sleep.
-Where is the pain?
-In the axilla.
-When she is depressed, do you think of suicide?
-Never.
-Do you enjoy sometimes and sometimes you go down? You are very excitable?
-Yes terribly like I've drunk too much coffee, so excited.
Several times during the day this state comes on.
-Of excitement?
-Of thoughts. What I want to do, what I intend to do.
-And these thoughts come during the day, during the night in bed?
-Mainly during day time. But I can push myself like having drunk very strong coffee.
I can do that myself, just powering me on, push me on.
-How is her sleep?
-Good.
-You can sleep right through the night or you can wake up?
-Normally I sleep well, recently I didn't sleep well when I was at the sea but that calmed down
again.
-How she is at the sea?
-Not so good?
-Sexually how you feel?
-Weak.
-She is too tired. If she is not feeling well, what she wants to do?
To go by herself, sitting on another room?
-Just sleep. Always sleep.
-What is your character?
-Very unbalanced. I can get very aggressive in certain situations.
-Which situations?
-When I'm in front of an authority.
-She took Causticum?
-No.
-First I have to kick.
-Kick by words?
-Yes.
-If she has a fight or an argument how she will react?
-There are certain topics where I can't restrain myself
and then I go through for any price
never mind how badly I get hitten.
-What about these topics, politics?
-When somebody has been treated unfairly.
-She takes sweets?
-No.
-In some situations I'm very close to tears, for example in the last term,
the last afternoon was so heavy for me, so this time I booked my flight earlier, so I can leave on Friday noon.
-She doesn't want to be in the afternoon.
Why? Because of separation from friends?
-Yes.
-She doesn't stand the separation, good bye.
-Separation, that is the problem.
If you see somebody suffering, you are very sympathetic? You suffer a lot?
-It's getting worse and worse.
This summer it was really bad. I hardly could watch a child
taking off a splinter out of his foot.
I though I'm going to faint.
-If she sees blood coming out, she will faint?
-Normally not.
-If her children are suffering, she becomes ...?
-It's very hard to take this.
-When she is coughing in winter does she has lose urine?
-No but when I laugh.
-Then it's a big problem.
-It's a flooding.
-What shall we do?
With her case one thing that we have to understand is what is happening.
I say we have to know the diagnosis because of the prognosis of the case.
A simple weakness of the legs it may be nothing at all, it may be the beginning of multiple
sclerosis or the beginning of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.
The prognosis is totally different and therefore your strategy for repeating the remedy, for
expecting results, is totally different.
That is why in every case, it is important to understand what is the underlying pathology.
You can never be absolute about these things but since the organism is such a complicated
machine with millions and trillions of functions!
So what is the pathology in her case? We have certain facts.
First of all, a blockage, everything goes away, that's one thing.
The second fact is that the electroencephalogram is affected, presenting rhythms of sleep.
Do you understand that?
The encephalogram says that she goes into sleep but she, herself does not go to sleep.
She is awake but blank. What is the pathology? The pathology is narcolepsy.
Narcolepsy is when from one moment to the next, the organism switches off to sleep
and then back and then back. Not in her case. So what is the pathology?
Who can give me some idea of what might be the pathology?
You collect all the information because you want to know also the remedy and the pathology.
The question that I would put in such a case, is whether the pathology is due to some
emotional shock, an automatic switch off of the organism to stop remembering?
I don't want to remember on a sub-conscious level, because if you ask her on a conscious
level, she will say I don't want to forget anything, correct?
On a subconscious level the organism tries to forget something and then this phenomenon
happens or is it a syndrome or a symptom which has underlying pathology?
What can be the pathology?
In case we may have some pathology here, what can it be?
A functioning of the brain and the heart which is similar to the one that happens when we
fall asleep. This is what it is said by the encephalogram.
That is one possibility of a pathology. A functioning that happens, similar to the one that
happens during sleep.
The third possibility is when due to dysfunctioning of certain organs, the liver or
the thyroid we have problems with memory which may end up into serious pathology eventually.
What happens in this case? I want to understand. When I give her the remedy I want to
expect certain things.
Is anybody here who would like to ... let's hear more. We like to hear the opinion of the
psychiatrist or the neurologist who had given us an opinion yesterday which I think it's
very good.
I searched for this syndrome in English, I don't know how it's called but definitely this is
the diagnosis, the syndrome affective loss of tonus.
I like her diagnosis. So I like to hear her opinion in this case as well.
-For this case I have no diagnosis and I don't even know what is going on with this case.
I personally find it very difficult this case and I find very difficult to find the remedy.
I would need to see the EEC, EEG and I think it would necessary to take EEG at different
times, not just one EEG, in different situations.
I don't believe it's a narcolepsy and I don't believe either it's an brain disease.
I'd rather think it's your second possibility that these processes go on, on a sub-conscious
level but this is my personal opinion.
-We know that the state started with the first delivery but we never asked how the first
delivery was for her, how she experienced it? That would be for me very important question.
-I tried to answer the questions. First of all to my own birth, it must have been a nightmare
for several days and several nights. I know every detail.
After she tried several times without success to get me aborted by using knitting needles
and that was to the first story that she left to tell. When my sister nearly brought friends home
my sister too was an unsuccessful abortion. I never wanted to have kids. I always thought it
would be nonsense to put children in this world. If at all I would adopt children and the
second point was that I was so afraid to lose a child that I thought I wouldn't survive this.
The first birth of my own children has to be introduced because I was over the date and they
were no contractions and the cervical region was very tight and it didn't move on and I got
an infusion and finally I said I want anesthesia in my back.
The second delivery was shorter and the third delivery went over in half an hour but the
symptoms remained exactly the same. Afterwards I withdraw to the toilet.
And after the fourth delivery I went to the toilet and I didn't tell anybody and nobody knew
and I forgot that I was there. The only thing I remember was that it was heating on the floor
and it was comfortable and I was sitting there. It was like a time played that was turned over.
-It's interesting. Still my original question for me, in order to be able to make a prognosis
if I give a remedy and I want to know what to expect, this is the question I want to answer
at this moment. I want to answer what is happening in physiology and pathology, what
might be happening? Because you can not know, she has been examined by several neurologists
who could not really say. That means we have to have an idea only, not certainty.
-Nevertheless you have to do thorough blood examinations because she is talking about
constant pain in her lymph nodes, which specially comes up after alcohol.
I think in every case you have to exclude a hematological blood disease.
-The blackouts are for 15 years and the problem on the lymph nodes is only the last 4-5
years. So it can not be connected, it might be a consequence of whatever it might happening.
What I was interested is that she said in cases of alcoholism, you have lymph nodes, pain.
Is this correct? How do you know that?
-It may be indication for Hodgkin's and then, in this disease after alcohol the lymph nodes, which
are diseased, may be painful. It's a so called B symptom.
-But in case of Hodgkin's not in every case of alcoholism.
-To ask the patient what was the mental state during the first pregnancy? How was the
emotional and mental state?
-To get a child was a decision of my head. I was already pretty old and I thought I would
miss out on something. The pregnancy was just going along like this. I had no problems
at all, I put on a little bit of weight but nobody saw it and I was just curious.
But there was another question, the first remark concerning paralysis.
Paralyzed is a word that I use very often. For example last summer, when this incontinence
started, when I was laughing, it always happened to be with my sister and I always said
stop it, stop it, I'm paralyzed. My face was paralyzed by laughing and everything was just
flowing, tears, urine, everything.
And very often when I have a stressful argument with somebody, whom I'm don't  trust, I have like
a paralysis on my face, like a cramp on my face.
I'm just able to move my lips slightly, open and close, can't smile anymore.
-Very good. So we have analyzed the case inside out.
For me the way that I see the case is that there are several facts.
One is that the brain is like going to sleep. The second fact is sudden exhaustion.
The third fact is, exhaustion in general. The fourth fact is that this happens only if she is
relaxing, when she tries to concentrate, never happens and therefore my conclusion of what
is happening physiologicalwise is that, what happens when you are very exhausted
you go to sleep. What happens when, in spite of exhaustion, you push yourself to be awake
most probably blood is sending out, through the vascular system to the brain.
In her case, there is a point where the arteries they just give up and they are paralyzed and
the blood just flows, keeping her awake. But it isn't nourishing all the cells and all the synapses
so she can remember where she is, who she is etc.
It's a state between awakening and sleeping due to- we agreed- a paralysis to a local
paralysis of the arteries.
I say that in connection of course with the remedy which I came to the conclusion finally that
she needs.
Especially when she related that severe loss of urine while laughing.
Also when she described her antithesis, her repulsion to authority and the need to kick
the authority.
Therefore I come to the conclusion that the problem is functional but on a quite deep level.
But there is no anatomy, there is no gross pathology at all. Therefore with the remedy we're
going to prescribe we have to expect cure of this case to a considerable degree.
That means from the severe loss of time and place, we come to minute things which may be
happen, then the arteries they just give up and they go into paralysis, as she describes.
happening; we give a tonus to the arteries and the bladder.
I come to this conclusion that it's only functional because the way she describes different
facts. For instance, I can learn very fast, I can remember two languages etc.
When she is under pressure, that means when the blood is flowing, there is no problem.
When the organism either very tired or very relaxed, because she says if I relax, this may
Through the symptomatology that was put in her case, the remedy Causticum is appearing
quite strongly.
So you may be lucky to get rid of these nonsense.
Have you ever heard that before? No. It's the first time I hear this syndrome.
I've never met it again but still we are able to put it together.
Neither in the Materia Medica it is described, in the way she does.
In the Materia Medica, we describe paralysis of local organs, larynx, vocal chords, bladder.
So paralysis of arteries on the brain, we say.
Put the analysis. Do you see this?
Loss of memory, difficult speech, sensation of emptiness, weakness of memory for what
it was about to do, sudden weakness, sudden chilliness, intermitted, worse farinaceous food.
All the symptoms she has said, 21 symptoms, cough in winter, can not support injustice,
aversion to sweets. Aversion to sweets in her case becomes important because
Causticum usually, 90% of the cases do not like.
Involuntary urination...It says only Causticum, don't think of any other remedy.
We put all your symptoms so easy, how is that possible that for 9 years...
-9 years, 5 homeopaths.
-9 years, 5 homeopaths could not have thought of that simple remedy, which the whole
class...How many prescribed Causticum?
-How many points to this case?
-Not many. If I had not asked the last question, I would give you more marks but the last
question, I asked in front of the class, the marks came down.
Wait until you find a difficult case, then you get the 100 marks.
You don't need more confirmation. Once you come to the idea that it is a functional
paralysis and then you come to the idea that she is really meant, what she said and if
you remember last time, I made a remark with Uta.
She jumped... that means she was serious on what she said, because I have seen it
previous time how strongly, I got him, I kill him, that saved her actually.
Because when she said that, I said here it is the remedy. And after that, it was easy.
Because I immediately connected her reaction previously with what she was saying.
I've told you Causticum will jump on the street and try to hit you because you hit the donkey.
He will kill you. If you do something which they feel it's injustice, they jump.
They can not retain, they can not hold it where other people will say, that's an injustice.
That's the world. I don't like injustice. Who likes injustice? Is anybody who likes injustice
to himself or to others? I don't believe there is anybody but Causticum has to lash out.
That's it.
-It's like a motor.
-Yes, you can't stop it. I have cases of video, they say on the street I will lash even if
there is a bigger man and I know maybe he will hit me, I can't stop it.
I will just lash and try to hit him because the feeling of injustice is there.
Remember this for Causticum. We ask many times, do you like injustice? It's not that.
It's this. A very good example.
-I understand that the paralysis in Causticum is supposed to be gradual.
-Not gradual, local. That means it can paralyze only a portion of the organism.
Some nerve on the face, on the trigeminal, it can paralyze the vocal chords.
What potency do you like? What potency you will give in this case?
Who said CM highest. Who says 50M? Who says 10M? Who says 1M? Who says 200?
Who says 30? 12?
200.
-Why?
-Because the organism is exhausted. She is running on exhaustion all the time.
Therefore high stimulation may not be felt at all. So I think 30 would be too low, 200 is
a good prescription for her, to see what happens and then eventually we will repeat it in
case, she may go a few months free of the symptom and then maybe she will start coming