-Tell me how are you at this moment where it is more than 24 hours. You took the
remedy yesterday at 1 o'clock, now 28 hours later. Give me first how you are at this
moment and then you tell me what actually happened.
-This moment I have a bit of pain which is bearable pain in here.
-It doesn't extend down?
-No.
-It stayed on the original part where it is originated. You still have some pain there.
-Like a tight.
-How much you would say you are better in percentage?
-60-70%, 50-60%. I'm just scared that it's gonna come back again.
-How did you sleep?
-Good. 8 hours. 5 hours and then I woke up and then I had a little pain and then I slept
again for 3 hours.
-So you made up from the sleep you have lost.
-Yes.
-Since you took the remedy you did not take more pain killers? -No.
-When did you feel that the pain has left from the extension? In the night in bed was
still there, the extension?
-Yes and this morning like a knife going down.
-When it has left the extension?
-About 1 o'clock. 1 o'clock I had a big explosion of pain, agony like yesterday.
-For how long?
-For an hour.
-And then the pain started going down substantially?
-Yes. And no pain at all afterwards. Just a feeling but no pain.
-And then what happened?
-Then about 4 o'clock it started to come back a little, here.
-Can you tell me if you felt any other change?
-A lot. I just feel really good, very good.
When yesterday afternoon fell asleep and in 5 minutes my whole body jerked awake
like a big spasm, my whole body just woke me up, so I did go back to sleep.
I stayed awake till late evening. It was as if it was saying, don't sleep.
-When did you fall asleep?
-11.30 and I had feelings about the relationship and sadness.
-You rethought about the whole issue.
-I was trying to remember what you asked me, like when was the first time that I wanted
to leave and I remember a few different incidents that made me feel really sad, cried.
-You cried?
-Yes.
-Quite a lot?
-Not excessively but it was a deep cry. But this afternoon when I had this explosion
I got really angry and I just decided I was gonna fight it and it wasn't gonna beat me
and I just briefed into the pain. I'm going to beat this.
-Or to bit the whole situation?
-Everything. I'm not going to be weak again and I'm going to be strong.
Nothing ever again. So I feel very different. I feel as if I understand myself better.
-OK Sara maybe you will give us some more feedback before the course and then
I will tell you how to continue. Thank you.
-Thank you.
-This is Sara again. Tell me your experience. Did you have another dose?
-No because I felt like it was changing and last night I had a sort of aggravation of the
sciatic nerve, not like the other pain I was getting. It was very short and intense.
It was like a spasm here but the sciatic nerve went right up my leg and my foot.
It's never done that before. It always went over my foot. And it finished.
-How long it lasted?
-3 minutes, very quick.
-It was like an explosion?
-Yes and then my foot and my leg were burning hot after that.
-For how long?
-An hour and I was very hot as well.
-Like if you had a flash.
-But my foot was like on fire.
-After that there was a release of the pain?
-Yes after that I fell asleep, I was released.
-What was the time that this happened?
-11.30 last night.
-So it was the beginning. You went to bed let's say 10.30 and this happened in the
beginning of your sleep and then you slept?
-Yes I slept.
-Right through?
-No.
- You woke up?
-Yes.
-What time?
-I think about 3 o'clock in the morning. I had about 3 hours sleep.
-How was the pain by that time?
-It was OK. I have a lot of activity in my leg, like tinkling and sometimes a little pain
on my ankle and more tinkling, it seems like my leg is changing all the time.
-So there is activity going on?
-Yes, so I didn't take the other dose.
-In general how would you say you are?
-In general much, much better. I took the remedy on Monday. On Tuesday I had two
aggravations in the middle of the day of the muscle and it was very emotional and intense;
I was moaning and crying and shouting. I felt as if everything was coming out
and then I had this other aggravation last night which felt different.
-Which was local actually this time, it was really the nerve reaction as it wanted to go back to place.
-Yes that's right and today I didn't have an aggravation in the middle of the day.
-Today you did not have.
-No, I've been stable and just I did have a local pain here and as I said a lot of activity in my leg.
-How much you put the improvement?
-80% at least. I feel like it was, when I first received treatment, 2-3 months ago.
This is what I had.
-That's how it started.
-I feel very stiff.
-Still? It's not totally loose sure. But this I believe, the way you are saying that you are
improving, I believe that within 10 days about you will be totally free. I thought maybe the
improvement was not so much and I thought maybe you need another.
Don't' take dose because then it's dangerous because you gave the impression that it
was stuck, it was stalemate  and then I said OK it it's a stalemate that means...
though I gave you a remedy which I know it is well potentized.
It was from Siffra 10M, so I say very strange maybe she needs another remedy.
-I think I was frightened that I was a little bit stuck myself.
-You were afraid because of the experience.
-Yes afraid of pain but today I feel much happier that it goes backwards.
I remember lots of things about me.
-Like jealousy.
-Now you remember!
-Yes! And going back to my teenager, when I was a teenager with friends and I feel
like I have pushed down my sexual energy and not I felt that it was wrong and I was
scared of it. I feel like I'm going to change a lot and be much more natural.
-Also can you tell me if you remember when you suppressed your jealousy, was any
moment that you remember you decide that feeling is no good?
-I can't remember when I suppressed it, I just remember being very devastated by
friends when I was a teenager. I have to think more.
-How do you evaluate your relationship with your husband?
-I just think that I was a fool for being so ...
-Vulnerable.
-Yes and I look back and I think, thank god I left. I feel that the intensity of this acute
situation is how much I suffered and how much I pushed it down over 2 years, perhaps
maybe 3 years, since my daughter was born and so I understand why it happens.
I am very glad that all this has happened.
-If in 10 days it's not completed gone, you give me a call and I will tell you but I
believe that you will be totally different from now on.
-Me too.
-To handle better situations.
-OK thank you.
-Now I saw you for the first time 2 years ago and you were in great pain by that time.
Eventually according to the follow ups that you wrote me also, you were doing quite
well and you got remarried with another man.
The last report I had from you was that you were quite happy and quite satisfied with
your life. How is the situation here now? What can you say now?
-Everything you say is still true. I'm very different person and I feel much stronger.
I'm very happy and my leg, my sciatica never bothers me. I changed in many ways.
-Is some acute symptoms that bother you at the moment?
-Not so much acute but the right nostril it blocked, it discharges sometimes especially
after another Lachesis but very slowly and so I have catarrh.
-This catarrh came after a cold and stayed after?
-Yes. I can't remember the exact situation but yes, it's just catarrh that never left.
-Do you have anything else? Your menses, period are normal?
-My periods are lovely. They are really good. Sometimes I have gastric wind a bloating.
-Your sleep is good?
-Yes.
-Appetite good?
-Yes appetite has changed. I took a Pulsatilla after Lachesis and my appetite changed
my desires changed.
-Do you have special desire now?
-I still love humus and black pepper, I love strong tastes but the way that it changed
is that I prefer fruits now and not so much the heavy foods that I was eating before.
I don't like milk anymore. I gave up milk and now if I drink any milk it sits in my stomach.
It's horrible. So I don't like milk and I gave up tea.
-It is an aversion to tea or you just don't desire it anymore?
-Yes I drink herbal.
-So there is some catarrh from the nose which is bothering you and some gas in the stomach;
this gas is more in the morning, in the afternoon, in the evening?
-It's after eating and more in the afternoon and the evening.
-What about sweets?
-Yes I like sweets.
-Do you take cheese?
-Not as much as I used to. Cheese is not the same.
-You sleep in a particular position?
-Always in one side right and left but usually start on the right.
-Do you have tiredness in the morning when you wake up?
-Yes in the morning it takes me an hour to feel good, I like to be slow in the morning take my time.
-Do you take salads? All kinds of salads?
-Yes.
-What about raw onions?
-I don't like raw.
-You don't like or they sit heavy in your stomach?
-No, they don't aggravate me but I don't like raw, it's too strong.
-But you said you like strong tastes and pepper but not onions.
-Not onions.
-How is your temperature with the weather? You have become more cold, more hot?
-More hot. I'm very warm.
-Your feet are warm?
-Yes.
-Do you stick them out of covers?
-Yes sometimes. I like to sleep with the covers half and change in the night.
-Thank you.
-I like to know what is your criteria for a good solid symptom.
-Very simple question and very simple answer.
When the person tells you I have a pain in the right side of the right colic flexure
that is a solid symptom. When he says my feet are burning, it's a solid symptom.
When he says, I'm very tired, it's a solid symptom. When he says, I'm this or I'm that
and the you don't make it out of your mind, you don't project it.
She says I have a pain in the right colic flexure and you make a projection.
You say, she has most probably a fear of dogs or a delusion that a dog may bite her
on the right side of her abdomen and therefore I take delusion that the dog is barking.
That is stupid, that is not a solid symptom. It is only the projection of your mind and if you do that,
you go wrong most of the time. The delusion.
I have a delusion that he can not raise the left arm and he has a delusion that he can
not raise his arm because his nephew is too heavy and does not want to carry him
in his lap. If you do like this, then you don't have a solid symptom and your prescription
will be entirely out.
-One small remark. In the Repertory there is an addition for Silica in italics, desires fat.
I don't want to say whose addition it is.
-It's my addition. A lot of these additions are not mine but they have put my name into that,
which we are correcting all that.
A lot of additions which they bear my name are not really correct.
There is some additions on Scorpio. I have added symptoms of Scorpio?
I said where the hell did I add symptoms of Scorpio? I don't even know the remedy.
I never prescribed it; now there are some additions in the Repertory bearing my name.
What people try to do is just send information to confuse the issue and the information
that has gone in the Repertories is a confused information, I believe on purpose.
Because I speak very badly about certain things which are happening in Homeopathy
so they thought, let's have George be involved also.
George gave symptoms of this and of that and so there is a total confusion, nobody can
clear up the matter except from me, because I know.
-The serious question is whether the prescription for the acute situation, let's say if a
pneumonia really comes back, will it have a direct relation to the remedies that are
prescribed now? Will be a follow, a complementary?
-It might have, it might not.
-Can I ask a couple of questions about the model, the groups?
Can I read them?
You spoke of the significance of the time in which acutes appeared in each group.
Can you do the same thing for the initial aggravation, the primary aggravation when you
give a prescription?
-There are two different things that we are talking about. One is the initial aggravation.
This is a totally different subject.
Here we are talking about treating acute conditions during chronic treatment
First of all what it means to have an acute and secondly whether you should treat or not.
Thirdly whether this acute you should expect to be a mild or a severe acute.
Knowing all these things, you need to know the model.
Concerning the initial aggravation is another subject altogether.
We can not be talking everything, in a seminar, like that.
-Can I put another question. On page 2.2.7 of your "Science [of Homeopathy]",
it says a truly curative response will be preceded by some degree of aggravation of symptoms.
Is this modified according to all groups?
-Absolutely. This is modified through experience which I have written there in 1976.
The book which I wrote has been written in 1976 and published in 1978 for the first time.
Since that time, 20 years later, there is a lot more of experience and observations.
This model comes the last 5-7 years where I really had to classify.
When I wrote the "new model for health and disease", I wrote it in 1985.
In 1985 I started understand these things, that's why I wrote a new model for health
and disease. Do you know this book?
In this model I have inserted in a code form, the ideas. These ideas I'm talking about now
more in detail. And what I talk here is not all the details.
In the normal school, I talk very much in details about this model.
For instance Ortega from Mexico, he is a very good homeopath, when I was saying that
there is definitely aggravation of symptoms, he was saying in 1976, I have never seen
an aggravation of symptoms.
Actually a journalist went and met him in Mexico, took an interview from him and asked
him specifically this question which was published in the
American Journal of Homeopathy.
Ortega said, I've never seen an aggravation after the homeopathic remedy, which was
amazing for me. How can he say that? Either he has never seen a real cure or he has
seen most probably cases on the uppermost or the lowest group.
When I wrote this, I was writing main things, still not going into details.
Here I'm going 10 times more into details than what is written in the "science".
People read the "Science" and think that's all. No, that's not all.
That' s why I made the School in order to give all the teaching.
And the teaching is much more than what I give you now.
In these last cases also we say there is no aggravation, there is immediate
amelioration but that also is stated in the "Science" already by saying that, in incurable
cases you may see an immediate amelioration.
I stated there as well but I have not yet completed my understanding of Homeopathy during that time.
This was also Volume Nr 1. I was supposed to be writing Volume Nr 2 on the "Science"
because you will see it says Volume Nr 1 but I never wrote Volume Nr 2.
This is the Volume Nr 2, a lot of more information, more details which clarify a lot of
issues that we have in Homeopathy.
-Will you let us know how (?) given us in the chart.
-I put the miasms yesterday. First one miasm, then two miasm, then three miasm.
It goes like this 1 miasm, 2,3,4,7,8 miasms. It's just an idea, as it goes down.
-Where is the syphilitic miasm?
-Here the 1 miasm can be syphilis, here syphilis. Syphilis can be anywhere in these
levels. The only thing is that syphilis here is not complicated with other miasms.
It's only syphilis. Here, it's complicated syphilis with psora and with cancer.
Here is more complicated, tuberculous miasm, sycotic miasm, cortisone miasm
antibiotic miasm and it goes like this.
As the case gets more and more complicated, you have to separate more and more miasms.
In the previous case that we spoke, we said maybe she needs Radium bromatum to
counteract the radiotherapy. Radiotherapy can have created a miasm actually.
In which case we come back, we see no effect from Sulphur, no effect from
Cal. carbonica, then we may go back and give Radium bromatum.
-Is it possible to give say 30 at the time and just after the treatment as an immediate
reaction to deal with it as an acute? Sometimes that can be quite effective.
-Yes you can but always I feel the best way is to sit down and take the case and see
whether you can make a logical prescription for the case.
Also it's very interesting that the cases from the School, where I treat the cases, that
means they come twice a year, they try not to take any other medicine, they wait until I see them.
They are doing all of them, very well.
And they are complicated cases, difficult cases.
Why they are doing all of them well, because nobody else interferes with another remedy.
Then you can see really what I say doing well is not the person saying, I'm well.
This is not good enough to say, I'm feeling better, no. It may feel better and may do
really well or he says, I feel better and not doing well. You have to realize these issues.
Otherwise the person stays on the same level.
Unless this person comes to the level where she gets again the pneumonia
you have not cured, in spite of the fact she may say, I feel better.
She may say, I feel better with 20 remedies. Give whatever you like, she may feel better.
Actually with any remedy you can try because the remedies have some effect.
Better, better, better but she stays on the same level. The cancer is there.
She is going to develop the evolution of cancer unless you are able to bring back the
acne and the pneumonias.
Then nobody can say to us, you are placebo effect. I say yes we have placebo effect
like everybody else but we have rules and if these rules are not followed, we do not claim
that this a cure.
We claim this is a cure when these rules are followed and we can prove to you by
showing the cases.
You have the shouter?
-Talking about miasms, Hahnemann describes 3 and some people describe more
like tuberculosis and cancerinism and so on but wouldn't you believe that all the
miasms AIDS and whatever could join the 3 of Hahnemann, being part of 1 of the 3?
-No. The tuberculosis is a specific miasm which is treated by Tuberculinum and then
it goes away, the tubercular miasm goes away, not the syphilis.
You give Tuberculinum and you treat the syphilitic miasm, no.
You treat the tuberculus miasm through Bacillinum or Tuberculinum or the other
remedies or Stannum and then may come the Mercury state where you suspect
that most probably this person has a second miasm which is syphilis.
Then it comes the sycotic miasm. And then you treat.
But I don't accept miasmatic prescriptions.
You can not know from the beginning, before you analyze a case that this is sycotic miasm.
In order to be sycotic miasm uppermost, you have to have Medorrhinum or Thuja
and then you say yes, the uppermost miasm in this case is sycotic or you analyze the case,
you see Cancerinum.
OK I have to give the uppermost miasm is cancerus miasm, I give Cancerinum and then
I proceed from there. This is clean work like surgery.
It is not just throwing remedies here and there, just because you have some ideas.
And then you see the homeopathic results.
Now we go back to this case that we saw. You saw the video.
Who thought of Lachesis from the first case? You have to be true to yourself.
When you see a case on the video, I let you study the case on the video.
Actually I should give you more time to study; but then you have to write down
the remedy. I would prescribe this remedy and then only you can compare your
thinking with my thinking.
Where did I go wrong? Or I took into consideration this, this and that symptom
which is not the correct one. That is how you may correct yourself.
That is the value of coming here, to compare your thinking with my thinking.
And then you correct yourself, you adjust yourself. Who thought of Lachesis from the first case?
-I thought because I took the same remedy for the same subject.
-Very good. You are honest, as usual.
You saw all the follow ups or one?
-One.
-OK it does not matter. She did quite well on that level which was the emotional level
on that case, the emotional case was involved very much plus severe lumbago which
might have been also a slip disc situation.
Now she comes here to us today two years later and she has a sinusitis.
It's not exactly sinusitis, it is a constant discharge from the nose and the question is
shall we give a remedy or if we give a remedy, what should be the remedy?
I would like to hear from you who says we should still wait?
-When was the last one?
-One year ago.
Who says we should give another remedy?
The rest what do they say? Nothing.
-She took Pulsatilla.
-Yes, she took Pulsatilla, the main remedy which has acted was Lachesis which did
most of the job and now we take into consideration this fact - Lachesis is the remedy
that really has acted- and she comes there with symptoms.
Shall we give a remedy yes or no?
-I think we shouldn't because in all her health, she is quite well.
She says she is happy, she is content in her life and she tells about this discharge and
if I remember well, she doesn't complain really. She only wanted to show you the
symptom but in the overall she is quite well, as she's never been.
-Not she wanted to show me, this is necessary. Also something else that happened
in these seminars which are open and you are not forced to come and give follow up
is that, once is better, is finished, he doesn't come anymore to Alonissos.
I would like to hear what has happened really. So I need the follow up myself to know
what has happened.
So it is good she has come and she has volunteer to come and give a follow up.
I'm not sure she really needs desperately a remedy, I don't believe that but it is come
she has come here to give a follow up and see what happened after all.
Here is a tricky case, why? Because over all she is quite well but there is a temptation.
A remedy appears to be indicated now which actually is complementary to Lachesis.
And the remedy is Lycopodium.
For certain reasons, first of all because the right side is the discharge, the second
reason is that she wakes up in the morning and she is unrefreshed.
The third reason is that she has some gas and the fourth reason is that she has
problems with onions. Actually onions make a Lycopodium case feel very much worse.
They have bloatness, even general malaise feeling, it's very bad, it's like poison.
Thuja also does not like and Pulsatilla and Nux Vomica. All these remedies they can
not tolerate fresh onions.
So she has 4 symptoms of Lycopodium, shall we give it yes or no?
-No.
-No because she is still happy with Lachesis...
-So what shall we say to such a patient?
-What did he say?
-He said that the person in general she is quite happy, in good health, so we don't
give another remedy. But what can we say?
We can say that most probably the remedy which will be indicated later will be Lycopodium.
Don't give it, have it in mind that Lycopodium may be needed.
So in case she goes into severe acute, to big sinusitis, whatever it might be, then you are
ready with this study, you are ready with the next remedy to prescribe.
-What level?
-She was A level.
-Why did she take Pulsatilla?
-Because most probably she had some symptoms.
-If she would say to you I feel fantastic, everything is good but this is really annoying me.
I need to get rid of this, what would you do then?
-I may still have waited if that was the symptom, just the discharge.
Because the discharge is not a bad thing.
Whatever happens with the discharges, you let them go for long time.
-But if she gets to a state and says, I've had enough.
-No, no. I will say, I also have enough. There are some rules which you have to follow.
If you don't follow the rules, you make mistakes. That is a law.
You make mistakes and then you will have the problem and the patient.
Not only the patient, you also have the problem.
It doesn't matter. What it matters is that we have a severe state of emotional stress
which stresses the nervous system on periphery and that is why I say, we have A level.
One or two remedies suppose to clear the case. In A level we have acutes which are infrequent.
If she eventually gets something acute, it has to be treated but in A level you can ignore
the acutes. You can say, the organism is OK or you give placebo, as much as you like.
As much as the patient likes actually.
-Now this proves that Lachesis was the first remedy or if you had chosen Lycopodium
then later the Lachesis symptom had been more?
-I think, I don't remember now but I think we considered Lycopodium in the analysis.
Most probably, I don't remember if I have said it, maybe this is going to be the second remedy.
But if you give Lycopodium nothing happens. In the beginning, instead of Lachesis
you prescribe Lycopodium, forget it, nothing, no effect.
-How do you know that?
-I know from experience.
-But the lately symptom, if we think about Lycopodium, and then you take the first
layer and then the other layer maybe is Lachesis but...
-No. If the first layer is Lachesis you can not replace it by Lycopodium which is the  second layer.
If you give Lycopodium, which is second layer, you will confuse the case because
symptoms of Lycopodium will try to push up while the Lachesis is on top and
therefore you can forget about curing.
She will be aggravated only, especially in this case. No effect at all, if you prescribe
first Lycopodium. If you understand that Lycopodium is underneath and then you think
maybe she will go later into Lycopodium yes but to give first Lycopodium in the place of
Lachesis, forget it only aggravation.
In this case only aggravation. In another case just changing of some symptoms.