In All-c. you have to remember a few things.
Of course the one that everybody knows is that the nose is running watery acrid discharge, that makes red the nostrils.
The nostrils become red. There is lacrimation also. The lacrimation is not acrid; it's the opposite as the Euphrasia.
This everybody knows.
How do you recognize a chronic case of All-c.?
You will recognize by two things. One is a desire for onions. Excessive desire for onions.
And another thing which is not recorded in our books it is sleepiness, excessive sleepiness. Lethargy, lethargic.
And you will see in common colds towards the evening where the All-c. becomes worse, they become lethargic
they want to lie down and you just want to sleep. The head is full, the headache is there, the nose is running
the coughing starts and you are lethargic, especially in the evening time.
This sleepiness and this lethargy can lead up to the point where we have a mental case.
And a mental case that will look like Opium, sleeping all the time.
I remember a case, the mother said I gave him some money to go and buy something.
And from the house to the shop, he lied down and slept. I went there in the shop, he had the money
he couldn't remember what was to buy. He came back and he couldn't remember anything and when they brought the boy
the boy was sitting there with his mother and as the mother was talking, the boy was sleeping.
And a total indifference about the surrounding. Whether you are there or not it doesn't matter.
He takes out his penis and urinates, oblivious of the surrounding.
The mother said, we were on the train and he wanted to urinate, he urinated in the train in front of everybody.
I'm talking about a boy of 14 years old; it's not a small boy of 2 years old.
But this shows the tendency of the remedy on the indifference, on the non perception of the surroundings.
He is oblivious of the surroundings.
No signs of catarrh. Nothing. In these chronic cases you will not have.
One thing you have to remember that All-c. goes fast from the upper respiratory track down and starts
with pharyngitis, laryngitis and then bronchitis. And it can go very fast and in case that you are giving wrongly,
in a case of coryza you prescribe wrongly All-c., you will speed up the laryngitis or the pharyngitis and the coughing will start.
Also it is a remedy that you have to be careful in people who have sensitivity with their bronchial system.
That you don't give it easily because you will cause dyspnea. It will cause dyspnea very soon.
The cold goes down and people are sensitive and they start having dyspnea. That means the remedy was wrong.
Is pressed downwards, this is very important. Also All-c. is worse with heat, worse in the evening.
So you will confuse it with what remedy?
It's going to be confused with Pulsatilla because the moment the heat is there, the fever rises.
If you have a room which is very warm, the fever and the dysphoria arises; so they need to open quickly the window
to get fresh air and in the meantime they get fresh air, they are chilled. But heat makes them very much worse.
So therefore it looks like Pulsatilla. What is the difference?
The coryza with Pulsatilla is blunt. That means you will see no redness around this area.
With All-c. in 95% cases you will see redness around this area.
Which is another remedy which has this redness around this area in coryza?
Arsenicum. What is the difference? Ars. will need heat, All-c. will be worse from heat.
If you have a coryza that will start on the left side and go to the right side, the nose running on the left side
1 day, 2 days, then right side. Then this can be All-c.  What other remedy can be?
A remedy which is worse in heat and goes from left to right?
Lachesis.
Onions which is very strong, better in open air, hoarseness.
It's painful hoarseness. You do like this and you feel as if the throat is split.
All these remedies that we have talked, we have talked on the essential features.
We did not talk about the essence of the remedy, a little bit on All-c., a little bit we talked about it.
- I had a case of lumbago and I gave Bry. and this person had a sensitivity in the lungs. She had chronic asthma but not often.
And she got a severe asthmatic condition after Bry. for lumbago. Did you ever observe this for Bryonia?
- Most probably during the time of the lumbago he must have had some respiratory infection and the infection
went down, most probably.
-She did not have.
-Well it's very strange.
Most probably she had but she had no apparent symptoms because since she was sensitive in her lungs
I believe that Bry. was suppressing in this caseand brought the respiration down. How long it lasted?
-It was very severe, it lasted for several hours and was not functioning. She had to get cortisone.
-This is the same with All-c., in case there is an inflammation here and you give All-c. you may have this problem.
I cannot explain this if you take it as a proving...
-What's the pathology this sleepiness about All-c. is something very new that the texts don't say it.
I have a case of a 42 years old man who has chronic sinusitis for 20 years.
He has a sleepiness to the extent that I have to go out to the waiting room, call him that your appointment is here
and come into the chamber. He even sleeps if you have a little pause while you are talking to him. I gave him Opium
because his airways are so full of enlarged mucus back here and in the nose also.  Where is the pathology in All-c.
I understand about Op. but how does All-c. gets to this state of sleepiness? Is it the sleep apnea as we explained in Op.?
-I don't know. What I know is that if you eat a lot of onions in the night and you have sleeplessness, you are going to sleep.
Garlic and onions, especially onions will make you sleep.
Actually it relaxes most probably the vascular system because both onions and garlic bring down the blood pressure.
And because of that relaxation, the stimulation which is there on the brain, becomes less most probably.
I don't know the physiology, it's very difficult.
In this case you can try because it is exactly the case that we are talking, the sinuses are affected
and this tremendous sleeplessness. Try high potency 1M, 10M and write back to me.