-I have a question concerning the rubric you used this morning.
The rubric 'cries when telling their a story'.
I notice in my practice, I don't know the reason but many patients cry
during telling their story, I was wondering because there is a few remedies in there, Sep., Puls. and Ign.
Is it really worth using this rubric?
-No.
I almost never use this rubric. I almost never into account that rubric but since we are working with certain tools
at this moment, we cannot take it out and bring something else.
We have to work with these tools so far as till when we have a better tool. But it is true, most probably
first of all Ign. is not crying while telling her symptoms, usually. It should not be there at the first place.
Maybe in one of my lectures I have said, if you see Ign. crying at a certain consultation, that does not mean
you have to exclude Ign. Ign. may cry sometimes. People take this and said, Vithoulkas said Ign. crying during consultation.
The idea is that you don't exclude Ign. if it's crying.
Well Psor. is a difficult remedy to recognize when it's needed.
You know that in the books they say, it is the chilly of Sulphur, the chilly remedy of Sulphur. Sulphur is warm.
That means that Psor. is looking dirty, is untidy, is lazy. There is no connection really.
The only connection you may say is that both remedies many times are used for skin eruptions which are severally itching.
And the one remedy is warm and is aggravated by warm and the other remedy is cold remedy and
aggravated by cold, very much aggravated by cold.
The drafts, the cold especially in the head. They are people who will go out and wear hat in winter.
In winter, in summer very seldom. Maybe in summer also.
Sometimes when in summer it's a bit cool, especially in Germany, they may put the hat. Here it's very difficult that
people will say in the summer I wear a hat because I feel cold in my head. It's very difficult to hear that.
What we're interested in is to find the essence of Psor. It is a remedy which is quite anxious, quite easily going into despair.
And the anxiety and the despair concerns very much material things.
They're anxious mostly they don't have enough money. They have a fear of going into poverty.
Poverty is something they cannot tolerate like other remedies also. Like Bry., Calc-f.
So it's a cold remedy with a severe aggravation from coldness, despair remedy, easily going into despair
and anxiety about the future. What is going to happen in my business? My business is not doing well.
The business are doing quite well, they bring money etc. but still Psor. will have the idea that the business
is not doing well. Worried about the business.
There is an interesting keynote: whenever they're going to have an attack of something, whatever, an influenza
a cold, an epileptic fit, headaches. Before the headaches they feel extremely well and then
the body works perfectly and then the headache comes.
-Does that mean that anytime when they have an aggravation before, they have some amelioration of the symptom?
They feel quite well, enthusiastic and then something happens?
-No, no amelioration of the symptom. They may not have amelioration, they may have some pains but the feeling
of the well-being. I fell well and then stop.
-So they have some emotional amelioration?
-Emotional and energy wise.
The energy is feeling good and emotionally are feeling good, the mind feels clear, I have some pains here, you don't pay attention.
If you feel well you have no problem with little things. 'In general I feel well, it's ok, I don't need a remedy'.
Many people will say 'I don't need a remedy, I don't have anything', but if you search out you find 20 symptoms
but they are not bothered by these symptoms. So actually there is no amelioration of symptom.
No, it's the sense of well-being, of feeling well and then it comes. The storm comes.
The most important thing for Psor. which you will find in 95% of the cases is what?
-Total desperation by itching.
-No. This is belonging to some other remedies but they have a characteristic that belongs to them.
-What's typical for Psor. is the offensive discharge.
-The offensive perspiration especially, offensive discharges but especially perspiration. In a typical Psor. case
you cannot sit next to him. If you work in the office, the whole office smells. That kind of offensiveness
that comes out through perspiration. It is not possible to stay next to him, if you work side by side, forget it.
You have to go out and breathe. And these people they say, 'I will use antiperspirants, this, that, there is no effect'.
Still the smell is coming. It seems that they eliminate all the toxins through their perspiration.
This is a great characteristic for the Psor. cases.
Another characteristic?
-Great appetite at night.
-The appetite comes in peculiar times.
Eating has to do with their well-being and feeling. They get up at night and they need to eat.
They go and open the refrigerator and they start eating.
They are going to have a headache and the appetite increases. And unless they eat, the headache will not subside.
Where are the eruptions? The seat of the eruptions mostly are the folds here and behind the knees and in the elbow folds.
These are the seats mostly of the eczema, with terrible dry skin, itching, worse with wool. Any wool will make the itching
much worse and also in the night in spite of the fact they get warm in the night, the itching becomes worse.
Dreams of robbers, this is not important; and danger is there but it's not important. Fear of being alone.
This is something which we have to explain a little bit.
They are not secure. Insecurity on the material level and insecurity also when they don't have people around them.
Psor. people will have a family, are prone to have people with them. They like it.
Nux-v. is the opposite. Platina also. They don't want the family. They are tendencies in these remedies
which are not to be taken literally. Because you may go into mistakes.
Somebody says, I want to marry you give Psor., forget it. He has to be chilly, he has to have offensive discharges.
He has to have the anxiety the despair, the insecurity about his business and all that.
Then you have the picture of Psor.
Fear of marriage. Did we speak about Nux-v.? We've spoken. Fear of marriage in Nux-v., why?
Who says fear of marriage is important? Because in Nux-v. he has to have a lot of experiences.
This happens with men mostly, not with women. Women don't have fear of marriage. They always want to marry.
Nobody laughs.
Why? Because you half believe it.
But is true to a certain extent that women are more insecure and they want more the security and
marriage gives the idea of security.
Ok, I'll change it. I will phrase it differently.
I will say Greek women...
You don't give Psor. to all the Greek women because they want to marry.
The same way Nux-v. has fear of getting married because has experiences with this woman, with that woman.
They have in their own perception that women are basically unfaithful individuals.
If you marry... unfaithful.
The idea how Nux-v. perceives because he projects his own experiences into the outside world.
So they have some experiences, an affair with a married woman and then another affair with a married woman and a third affair.
He comes to the conclusion that all married women have extramarital affairs. I don't want to marry.
And they are jealous and they are ambitious and they don't want this to happen to them.
And this is what makes them fear of getting married.
But Lyc. will have fear of getting married from another point of view; because they don't want the responsibility.
They don't want the responsibility of the children. Platina will have fear of getting married for different reasons.
Because they don't want children. Bar-c. also will have fear not of marriage, they will marry but they don't want children.
I'm the baby, you keep me.
So take the essentials of the case and put them together. Don't take one portion of what we have said because
if you take only one, the whole is lost.
-I don't understand the combination of two symptoms in Psor. We like all kinds of skin eruptions.
Psor. not only has skin eruptions but offensive skin eruptions which is even better.
If they have offensive, they have even more detoxifying quality in them.
Why is Psor. then a remedy for lack of reaction, lack of reactivity? Where can I find that?
-They have an eczema that resists all kind of treatment.
You give one remedy and then another remedy  and another remedy, especially in children, and you see no reaction.
With other people you will see some reaction, you give some Sulphur and something happens. With Psor.
it will not happen anything. And then you give Psor. and it's better but it will take a long time before
you can see it is better. That means it gives the idea of a weak reaction.
This is stated in all books, from Kent and the old masters.
Lack of vital reaction, chilly. I will tell you it is the idea of being cold of being chilly, not to get warm.
I mean an organism who cannot get warm like Sil., like Hep., like Ars. and this is even worse, it's very very chilly.
So if somebody is very chilly and cannot get warm, then you see lack of vital reaction. It's an expression.
The idea is behind.
But it's a good question because I had the same question.
When we read the Materia Medica many times we read an impression of the patient by the doctor
who has attended several cases. He gives an impression and the impression is not always for 100% of the cases.
Profuse sweating.
And of course better in lying down. This is also interesting in asthma where they lie down
and they spread their hands and it seems that this position makes them feel better.
It's very strange, the position of knee-elbow makes them feel better. The Med., the Kali-c etc.
The position in sleep also makes them better, right side or left side.
Why is that? We have some explanations but they are not the real explanation.
Can you say, oh he wants pressure on the side where he has the inflammation.
Then another remedy has inflammation, it want to turn on the other side.
So it's not really the physiology, it's something else. It's the individuality.
Puls. is a terrible remedy.
You tell her this she will start crying; they cry in such a way that they complain. It's like saying: why did you do this to me?
Please say a nice word. I am a tender woman. I am in a tender state. Please hold me, touch me. Give me consolation.
Here we have 'consolation ameliorates'. Actually is the woman who one way or another you must console.
If you don't console the good way, the nice way , she will manipulate you to console her on another way.
How she will manipulate you? In different ways. She has ways. She understands, especially the husband, the children.
Children they cry in order that the parents will grasp them. They get like this. Each remedy cries in a different way.
Ok sweetie, come here. You are nice boy, nice girl.
It's different than Calc-p. You have seen Calc-p. or Cham. or Cina or Nat-m crying.
Will fall down Nat-m. on the floor and will kick.
It's totally different, hysteric.
You say, you are hysterical. Then he will look at you, the Nat-m., 'what is he saying now?'  Because they mentalize.
But Puls.s are acting out of emotions. The emotions are important and you say, 'you cry so easily'.
Yes I cry. In what circumstance? In front of others? Yes in front of others it's even better she will say.
When they have audience to cry then they will feel comfortable, they can do it.
They like the people paying attention to them
and that others are sympathetic towards them.
They like consolation.
Puls. also can be very aggressive.
They can throw a tantrum. You've done this to me. They take this and they can throw it.
But never in the head. There is no real aggression. It is an aggressivity which seeks attention, manipulation.
So she will throw things with such a tantrum, so the husband knows that he has to shut up.
Be nice to her and then he can go out. Otherwise she will continue the manipulation until she gets the attention;
it's her organism you see. She says: I go to my husband and I say, please embrace me, out of the blue, say a nice word.
I love you. Thank you. Nice. Then they can go.
Not the Germans of course. I'm talking about the Greek women.
You see I don't know how the Germans are behaving in this matter, I don't have the experience.
Maybe they are doing the same but in different ways.
But actually the manipulation is there so they can get the attention which they need.
Puls. are women or men who are so emotional and the concentration is on the emotional side.
Are they sexual? It's very strange. They need tenderness, they need affection, they don't need sex.
It's not a sexual remedy. It's rather from medium to low and sometimes from the old times, you see now homosexuality
is much more spread in the societies. In the old times when this was written in the Repertory 'in love with one
of her own sex'. Homosexuality. What they were writing actually is the need for tenderness and affection.
You see the Puls. woman does not like aggressiveness. She's not the woman who will challenge a man.
She wants to be next to the man, to be protected, to be consoled, not to challenge.
So if she has to challenge, she has an aggressive man, she is afraid and finally she becomes cool. Frigid.
I'm not interested in sexual matters. Then she needs affection. She has a girl friend with whom they speak
they tell each other stories. And then they form a kind of a bond between themselves and Puls. suddenly feels
'I'm in love with that person. What's this?' They
fell in love and they can go in great problems because
in much older times this was considered as very bad and when Puls. finds out that this is the case
they have fallen
suddenly in love a man with a man or a woman with a woman, terrible. What shall I do now?
And the idea is they don't want sex they want tenderness and tenderness can be given,
woman to woman, they give much more tenderness and they understand the need for tenderness.
Where men they just go home, 'ok bring me food, now we go to bed, we finish, now we go'. This for Puls. is...
she does not know where she is. And then she starts either she will react crying for the least reason
or manipulating by throwing a tantrum by taking this and throw it but in the wall. The man is there, she throws it there
to make sure that it will not come to him. So there is no aggressiveness, still in her tantrum she is sweet.
And of course we have the big keynote in Puls. The aggravation from heat. She suffers this, she has to go near
she has to have air, to open the window. The fresh air and the cool air rejuvenates her.
The Puls. will be the first in a party to open the window. She goes there, never mind the house is not hers.
She goes to the window and opens it;
it is too stuffy. And flushes of heat, heat.
And that's why she indicated very much during the climacteric period where flushes are tormenting women.
Another keynote is changeable.
We see this changeable element in different actions, functions, ailments.
When I was first reading Puls. and it would say, 'the color of the menses changes. One time will be green, blue...'
I said, what is this? Is this possible?
It is possible but with a big difference.
The color may change according to her, it doesn't change according to you who listen, especially if you are a man.
It doesn't go to blue, to green, to red.
It changes a little bit.
A little bit towards the dark side but the woman observes that almost never the menses are the same color.
More clots, more dark, more brown, less brown, more red etc. The mood also changes from one hour to another.
They are moody and depressed and despaired. And then somebody comes, they have nice company
somebody consoles them. The world is nice, they start again. It is easy to change their mood. They are not steady.
Also changes the place of pain. You get a pain on the shoulder joint, a pain on the hip joint, on the elbow joint.
It's a changeable.
It is the idea of the woman. Which is this opera? In Rigoletto I think.
It says: a woman is like a feather in the wind. Changes all the time.
The Greek translation which I have in my mind says... wind flower.
We go to the idea of signatures, it says Puls. with the wind goes like this and then it goes like that.
The wind blows this way, it goes like this, the wind blows that way, it goes like that.
You can say all these nonsense but the fact remains that all flowers with the wind will go this way
and with the other wind will go the other way. And still of course Puls. will do that but it is not the main thrust.
If you put your mind into that many times we do say things like that. Kent used to say, I said it a lot but
if you fix your mind and you say Lac-c dog's milk, likes dogs. People who like dogs. Who likes dogs here?
87%. 87,45%. It is natural to love dogs.
I had a secretary once and I had a little puppy in a box inside my apartment.
I called her to come to my apartment to bring me something.
Then I am in the room and I hear the door opens and she screams. I go out and say, 'what is it?'
'A dog!'.
I said, 'A dog? This dog? 1,5 month old little puppy like this? Is this a dog is going to bite you?'
'Take it away!'.
I said 'I have been giving you the wrong medicine'.
Fear of dogs. This woman actually she had to take Tuberculinum.
When you are sick, you are afraid of dogs, don't like dogs, you don't like cats. You don't touch cats.
Cat comes here and Tuberculinum is terrified 'I'm going to become sick now.
I think I swallowed a hair from the cat. This house has cats, I don't go'.
This is a symptom. But to say I like dogs, I like cats, it's a natural thing.
About Puls. you have to know a few more keynotes. Which are these keynotes?
Which is the biggest fear of Puls.?
-Being alone?
-Being alone. Being forsaken, being abandoned yes. It is a strong fear but this fear is not as tormenting
as another fear which is very strong and very tormenting.
Fear which really can destroy the life of the patient.
Fear of insanity.
They feel 'I'm going crazy'. It's a fear which overwhelms the patient.
Now you may say, tomorrow all women are going to take a dose of Puls. because you may have thought that sometimes
under stress, you may go insane. No. This is not the case. The case is when without any reason, everything is alright
the fear of insanity overwhelms the person.
The fear of insanity becomes the main problem.
And of course as we described Puls. needs the support of the family, of the people whom she loves.
And tenderness etc., it is natural, she will feel fear of being abandoned because there is no this power for fighting for life.
Once, as I said, I had a patient from India whose position was a minister in the government of India, a woman.
And she has been to all Homeopaths in India and in Europe.
The best. Nobody has given her the correct remedy and she kept on having these problems with the liver.
She had a liver that was misfunctioning and the whole body  was retaining water
and then she would go like this and then go like that.
She came to me and she said, what remedy you will give me?
I was in India, I' m talking about 1964.
I said, Pulsatilla.
Because she has taken so many remedies, she has read Materia Medica herself. She goes to the Homeopath in Delhi
because he is alive I don't want to mention his name. And she says, you know there is a young man here
- but I was treating Krishnamurti and that's
why I was a little bit known in these circles -
he gave me Puls. He said, you Puls.? You, like a boss, you know Minister in the government, do this, do that.
And the example is to show you that you don't need to have the mental-emotional picture of Puls., you may have
only the physical symptoms. Where the mental and emotional is normal.
Because you will come one time I will prescribe Puls. and you will say but she is not crying, she is not manipulative
she is not hungry for consolation, why you give? You don't have to have. Once you have the changeability of symptoms.
And of course a few other things which lead me to the idea of Puls. like the heat. In which part of the body the heat is most?
Feet. Feet become hot, burning and it has to cool them out of the covers.
But sometimes you may have a chilly Puls. and especially during a cold,  Puls. may get a feeling of
coldness in the back as if there is a wet towel stuck on her back.
So there are some chills, wetness and chill on the back where she cannot get rid of this wet towel on the back.
Then of course you have an aversion to warm food, desire for cold food. Aversion to fat, not only aversion but worse from fat.
They will have diarrhea from fat. But you may get some Puls who like bread and butter. And they like also creamy things.
They have an aversion to pork and worse from pork, if they eat it.
Of course they can have different other fears. Fear of the dark, fear of ghosts. These fears are not so strong as the fear of insanity.
Also Puls. are like me. They like to walk. Amelioration by walking.
Desires cold food but ice-cream. Cold fresh air, cold application, gentle motion, gentle walking.
It is one of the remedies that they don't like sun and they don't like the time of sunset. They become
sad during this time. Sunset brings a sadness. It's as if life is going away.
Styes. Don't forget the styes in the eyes. They get frequent, repeated styes.
These are the things that you have to remember about Puls. If you remember these things you will not miss
a Puls. case, nevermind what it is.
-I've got a question. We've always been talking Puls. as a woman. How often does it occur that men need Puls.?
-Men need Puls. I remember a man, a builder, you know very rough man who carries the wheelbarrows, strong man.
He had come for his stomach and different things. Eventually he told me why he had come.
He says, 'I think I am a homosexual'. 'Why?'. 'Because I see a man and I feel that maybe I will be in love with this man'.
This is a disturbance that can be cured very quickly with Puls. In the same way the woman who is
in love with some of her own kind.
This is fear of being in love. They suffer because of that. You give the remedy, they stop suffering.
Puls. men in conjunction with Puls. women,
I would say between 30 and 70%.
70% of your cases will be women and 30% will be men.
That more or less is the experience but maybe in different countries have different percentages.
The men are tender, exactly the same, they need consolation and confirmation. Puls. men easily become impotent
especially if the woman is aggressive.
They cannot handle it.
Also the main thing is, you have to memorize this. These are little information, 1,2,3,4,5 you have to memorize.
For Puls. we said too many things. But all these are really strong points that will lead you to Puls.
-Please, can you differentiate the sadness of Phos. in twilight, when the sunset is and the sadness of Puls.?
-They are the same. They are similar.
-Puls. is yielding. Is it possible to suppress Puls. like Staph.?
-To suppress Puls.? No, the Puls. does not suffer easily from suppression. Why? Because if you try to suppress
if you are aggressive, she breaks out crying.
By breaking out crying, she balances where Staph. will not cry.
She will take it inside and it is very very dangerous when you have a pain in your soul, in your emotions and
you cannot express that pain. You cannot talk to a friend, you cannot cry, you cannot shout, you cannot bring it out.
It's going to stay there and eat you up.
Also jealousy, if it is expressed, if you have a friend and you express your jealousy you talk about it all the time,
it's not going to damage you as much as will damage you if you don't talk to anybody.
You are suspicious your husband or my wife is going out with another man. You are suspicious, you keep it
it's absolutely sure you damage your heart and your blood pressure will start rising etc.
If you can talk especially with the person concerned, then you will save a lot of suffering. This is a general rule.
Sometimes I' m surprised some people they just perceive this and they write a whole book. A whole book of how
to express your emotions, it's a whole literature about it.
And it's simple things that they have to be understood as common senses things.
And they blow it into a big book, best selling.
You cry out your pain.
-Is Puls. reactive as a disappointment of love? Will she also be grieving over years or she will think
well there are other people in this world as well?
-She will be crying a lot and she will cry more than another woman who is more healthy. A healthy woman
will cry, she has an affair, nice affair. But if the man leaves her, she immediately reasons out  that this is not
the right person, ok. It would be nice because I like him but still one week, two weeks, she is finished.
Puls. will cry for 6 months and will not have the side effects of the grief as the Ign. or the Nat-m  may have.
Because it will save her, will balance. Crying out is a big outlet for a lot of problems and if we were crying is like oozing
eczema is like oozing out. Actually we have so much pain inside us, kept inside
that we should be crying most of us, we should be crying, crying.
I'm too proud to cry, the other one says, I'm going to be ridiculous if I cry, the other one says, I'm going to be considered
as a crazy person, so you keep it inside and this is how it develops your clientele, to be treated by you.