The strongest indication for Tub. is a hereditary tendency. That means parents who had tuberculosis.
The hereditary tendency that means it existed in the family tuberculosis, before the birth of the child
that is the strongest indication for Tub.
You take it as a symptom and
that symptom has very high value.
Sometimes it overrides other symptoms which are quite strong but indicate another remedy.
The basic type of Tub. is somebody who
has the tendency not to stick with anything.
The tendency to go away to find another
job, another lover, another interest.
They are people who have a very active mind.
There is like fire inside them, burning the physical body like a candle which is burning in two ends.
And it's melting away the physical
body, giving a lot of energy.
Then the brain of these people feels that they can do a lot, they can accomplish a lot, they have the possibility
to live a lot of possibilities.
I can do this, I can be a musician, I can also be an engineer an architect and a doctor also.
This feeling inside them that they
can do almost everything.
They don't want to stuck with one
person, with one job, with one situation.
That is a basic element of these people who usually are lean, they have a white transparent color in the face.
It's like candle.
Very reactive, quick to perceive.
The tendency is to leave the
place in which they live.
That is why it says desires to travel.
The desire to travel is why?
Because the place in which they live
becomes soon a place of boredom.
In the same way they are very excited.
The first time they go to Alonissos.
It's a beautiful place, fantastic, they are exalted, very happy and then they decide to come, they go and stay in Alonissos.
And after 2-3 months the whole enthusiasm goes down, the boredom starts. 'What shall I do here?'
'I am a person for the world.
I should go and do big things'.
'Here is a small place and
I'm suffocating here in that place'.
It's very interesting that Anton Chekhov who was the Russian writer -who died from tuberculosis-
-in all his plays there is this element
of boredom and wanted to go away.
You read the 3 Sisters who live in a village and they are longing to go away, one day we go to Moscow.
Moscow is the place of fantasy
where they will change their boredom.
It's very characteristic in his
plays the tuberculinic miasm.
And the idea of the combustions, of this burning inside and the longing and the desire to do so many things.
It's depicted in the physical
body by great appetite.
They eat a lot and still they are losing weight. Their physical body is wasting away.
While they can be eating a
lot they don't put on weight.
They burn all this food in order to produce energy for all these projects and things they want to do.
It's interesting also that Tub. people will very seldom stay with a relationship.
They're not steady, they cannot be steady.
They get enthusiastic, they fall in love, they are very romantic, they are not rude people, they are not crude.
They are sensitive, with ideas, with strong feelings, they fall in love and after a while they find no interest.
They cannot be with that woman. It's not possible. I have to leave. Suffocate, all this kind of excuses.
You know if you want to get out of
a situation, you say I'm Tub.
I cannot help it. It's not me,
it's the tendency which I have inside.
The chemistry.
The last case of Tub., the case
of a young man, a musician.
He had an affair, the last
affair he had, with a woman.
He said, after a while it was so difficult to stay with this woman, he went to another country
he fell in love with a woman from another country he went to meet her and she was very much in love
because they are very lovable people, very alive, they describe things, they have ideas, feelings, so you like them.
She fell in love with him very much.
He said, it was so difficult for me to stay though she treated me so nicely, she gave me everything.
She was rich and treated him like a king.
He says, 'it was so difficult that I had diarrhea'.
He pressed himself to the point
where he started having diarrhea.
He said, 'finished, I have to leave'.
I said, 'do you grind your teeth?'
He says, 'my god I can't believe it'. 'Why?'
'Because while I was with this woman, she
told me you grind your teeth and I said, no'.
'She says, yes you grind your teeth and how is that you know that I grind my teeth? Only this woman knows'.
He says, 'If somebody says to me, oh he
is a musician. By this time I get chills because I feel
that they put me on a box and I'm only a musician. I don't want to be a musician'.
'What do you want to be?', 'I don't know,
I have to be free, so I can be anything'.
He is a musician and he lives as a musician but the moment that he hears they put the label on him
he feels that he is now enclosed in that profession. And maybe he cannot leave.
The idea 'I cannot leave! I have to stay in Alonissos' and then it gets bigger and bigger and then they have to leave.
The desire to travel, of course.
There are other remedies that have that need and the amelioration comes from different reasons.
Ignatia for instance.
I have seen an ulcerative colitis case, of Ignatia and she would say, 'when I go for holiday and I travel
the moment I leave the
place the diarrhea stops.
And starts as soon as
I come back to the place'.
While the Ignatia is travelling and
changes pictures, she is perfectly well.
The Tub. is not like that, it's the idea of
leaving in one place which is boredom
which is dragging him down, which encloses him. Making the possibilities are very limited.
Element of dissatisfaction in a child who does
not understand what is happening inside me
it will appear many times as children
who are nasty and naughty.
In order to break their boredom,
-they don't understand what is going on-
they have to do acts that enrage
others, enrage the parents.
I remember another case where the mother would say about the child, 10-11 years old, she said
'he would go to the wardrobe and he knew I like this dress and he took razor and cut this dress'.
It destroyed the best dress of the mother.
Then you look and he doesn't know
why. They can do very nasty things.
They can attack, they can be aggressive
with their sisters and brothers.
A great fear, which is very characteristic,
has always to make you think of Tub.
This is fear of cats. It's not only fear. They may say, I have a kind of aversion to cats. I don't like cats near me.
They can be far away, it's OK I'm not afraid.
But when they come near...
They are also allergic to the cats.
They can say, I enter a room where a cat has been before and I can start coughing, so allergic to the cat.
It's not only that they will breathe
one of the hair of the cat.
Because cats are losing their hair and you breathe in and you maybe coughing also.
They don't have to come in touch at all.
And usually are people with allergy
in their respiratory system.
The respiratory system is the
most vulnerable to them.
You get tuberculosis in different
systems and in different organs.
But the most common is the
tuberculosis of the lungs.
When I was lecturing many years ago,
in the class were some old Greek doctors
who have lived the era of tuberculosis. They were in hospitals where tuberculosis was very prominent.
They were special hospitals where they would go, they separated themselves in order not to infect others.
When I was lecturing I was saying these things and one of the doctors who had himself been tuberculosis patient
and who, later on, he was doctor
on a hospital with tuberculosis...
and I talked to him about this intense feeling,
this intense desire for contact, for sex
these romantic affairs, he says, 'you are absolutely right. I remember in the hospital'
where I was working, in the night we would find out that all the men were missing from their ward
and they were all in women's wards.
And they had affairs and in the morning everybody was sleeping nicely.
And most probably they changed
partners quite a lot.
It is interesting also to realize how
disease is undermining the organism
and deviates the organism in
its different functions.
When the Italian group was here, one woman said, 'George we want you to tell us what is normal in sex?'
The Italian woman says,
'finally tell us what is normal!'
I said, 'it will take one week. Are you
prepared to stay one week?', 'Yes!'.
The normal according to my understanding of course is that a man and a woman are made only for one relationship.
Which can be satisfying and can be rejuvenating and can be interesting for all times.
This is what would be the most
normal for human beings.
That was sub-conscious absolutely.
I am innocent.
There are some birds like pigeons, they form a couple and if one dies, the other stays celibate.
-This is a legend.
-It's a legend also that pigeons are the symbol of peace but it's the most evolved from the birds
and the most evolved from the humans should compare with the most evolved from the birds.
I really feel that this is correct
but why it does not happen?
It's because of diseases that undermine.
The disease has undermined the human organism in such a way as to bring about different deviations.
So a child at the age of 11 starts having strong sexual desire. We see children at the age of 7,8,9
they start masturbating because
it's a hormonal disturbance.
These children how can they keep celibate until they find the right man or the right woman to live together?
They cannot wait, so the first
chance they have, they have sex.
Then the more they have sex and the more the deviation goes and in the end what happens is,
even if you meet your real partner in life,
you cannot recognize it anymore.
You think it is one of the usual...
What is the usual? To have an affair for 6 months, 9 months, 1 year, 1 week, whatever.
Depending on the hormonal imbalance because there are people who need sex 3 times the day; it's a hormonal imbalance.
Let's not go to that subject.
I believe in an ideal society where people are healthy, they will not have sex before 18 or 19 years old, no one.
And then at this age may still start searching for the right person to be connected and to have a relationship.
I lived in India and I saw this. The Indian culture is such that does not allow, does not give the possibility
of multiple contacts.
As a result we have marriages that
stay much more than the European.
When they die they burn the wife? No.
-I heard that some of them are very miserable...
-No, I don't agree. She said, some of
them are very miserable. Some, OK.
But concerning the misery that the western people are going through by practicing these kind of relationships is nothing.
It is much more happy as a race than we are because of that reason. Because they stay celibate.
I was in the College and I was quite older, 27 years old when I was in the College there and
the others were 18,19,20,21.
And I talked with a lot of my schoolmates. None of them had any physical contact with a girl.
All of them were in a platonic state of love.
This girl I love etc. but they wait and when the marriage comes, the marriage holds.
Later on I went to America and I had a class and I said, how many of you are divorced? The whole class raised their hands.
They were young doctors from 25-39.
All of them were divorced.
But Tub. is one of the remedies that will
not stay with a... Why they don't stay?
Because of the miasm.
And then take syphilis and take the sycosis, take gonorrhea and see why we have so much
deviations in sexual matters.
We also find some cases where they have these ritualistic behavior; where they have to do their bath in a particular way.
First you take the soap and you put it there. Then you take the sponge and you put it on the other side.
Then you open the water for a certain period of time. Then you take this and that and they cannot
get out of this ritualistic behavior
which is quite limiting.
Another keynote which is very strong is the desire to have fat in their food. And which is the most fatty meat?
They love pork. When they say, 'I love pork'
you have to think of this remedy immediately.
There is also another strong desire from the
side of the fruits which is desire for bananas.
Excessive desire for bananas.
Pork and bananas if they say these two,
what do you like? Pork and bananas.
This is the only remedy
that you will have to think.
It is a remedy which is usually affected by
cold very much.
They are worse in the night.
The night time is difficult and especially the anxiety rises during the night and becomes unbearable.
Coldness and dampness is aggravating them and that is why we say that the Tub. people are worse in the sea.
It is not the salt of the sea, it is not
the elements of the sea.
It is where you get cold and wet and
they are getting worse if they go bathing.
But from the pathology point of view of course, you will need in frequent colds, frequent bronchitis
frequent infections of the respiratory
track indicate the possibility of Tub.
Grinding of the teeth is a concomitant
which is very characteristic.
Strong and repeated infections on the respiratory tract with grinding of the teeth, makes a case of Tub.
Where frequent infections we have in Calc., we have in Sulph., we have in Psor., we have in Sil.
we have in different remedies. But when it's coupled with grinding of the teeth, then we think of Tub.
Better in warm weather of course and dry weather.
Another thing that you have to remember for Tub. is that it has rheumatic and arthritic conditions which
resemble Rhus-t. Worse in the beginning of
the movements and eventually amelioration.
Worse cold and wet and you give Rhus-t.
And Rhus-t. does nothing.
And then you ask about fruits
and he says, 'I like bananas'.
You see how you differentiate with little
things, little information like that.
'I like pork'. It goes from Rhus-t.... 'I desire
cold milk', there you have to differentiate.
If the cold milk is very strong, I can drink 3
liters of cold milk a day, that is Rhus-t.
1.5 liter cold milk it is Tub.
Rhus-t. also would like milk whether cold
or warm but Tub. would like only cold.
It is a burning feeling inside which
they have to calm it with cold things.
Drinking cold milk, drinking cold drinks,
taking ice cubes, taking ice cream.
Rhus-t. does not like cold things, except from milk. It can drink cold milk but in general does not like cold things.
Tub. likes to drink or to eat cold things.
-There are different sorts of Tub.
Is there a difference?
-For me I have used Tub. Bovinum. I have not used the others. I don't know. I cannot say.
- It's not only that Tub. people don't like cats.
Also the cats don't like them.
I have a child with many colds, she was so typical Tub. that I didn't ask her about cats
but the mother related that when she came home for the first time in her life, she was 5 years old
the cat came near to her. I gave her the Tub. and half an hour later the situation already was different.
The cat came to the child and the child for the first time contacted the cat. And the cat never liked the child.
-The cats are very independent things.
They can answer, they cannot answer, they
do whatever they like, like a woman.
-I would like to know if there is an influence on us because most of us got Tub. vaccination. What is the influence from this?
-If you are Tub. really, you have a big reaction. That means you have a predisposition.
If somebody had a big reaction on tubercular vaccination, you have to consider Tub. for that person.
-My daughter when she was born she was quite low and in Israel they usually give the first day the Tub....
-The first day?
-The first day, as they are born.
They used to, 27 years ago. Now
they don't give it at all.
For the whole year or two years it was coming out and stopping, coming out and stopping and she didn't eat
she was really low. Then she had a pneumonia about 2 years old and they checked with the test
and it was very huge and they started giving her pills every day against tuberculosis and she started eating.
She quite resembled this picture
actually. Could it be?
-Sure absolutely, you must consider it.
-There was a case that I thought she was Tub. She is a nurse in the hospital and she has made this test
they wanted to look if she got in contact with tuberculosis in her work and there was a patient in this hospital
who had active tuberculosis. I was not
sure if I now give Tub. to the nurse.
Could I make her more
sensitive to this disease?
-By Tub., if it is indicated, you
will protect her definitely.
-I would like to ask, if anybody else has this experience also I want to relate it back. One of my Tub. children
it was not very malicious but many pneumonias and much better after Tub. but many and high doses.
And then I was in Alonissos and somebody in the kinder garden made the test and I found it out by chance afterwards.
The child got very sick, it got 40.000 leucocytes, they had to send it to the hospital and they found a pneumonia
without any microbes. They didn't know what it was, they gave lots of antibiotics and it didn't really help
but after 5-6 days it receded.
And it had to have Tub. afterwards again.
And I though is it possible that the child was so sensitive to Tub. that these children if they are under treatment
they shouldn't get the test.  I try this
now with all my Tub. children.
-Yes, that means the child was still on Tub. level and the fact that they gave  actually the test, which is the same thing.
The child was very, very sensitive to such tuberculosis and the whole organism came down.
Because the organism tries to fight out the vaccination or the test with the antibodies produced
and bringing down the defense.  Then of
course pneumonia or whatever can appear.
It's not always that this happens. The child
was very sensitive to the vaccination.
-Tub. people are much better on the mountains and pine woods. Those hospitals have always been on the mountain.
-That is true. They need a specific height like
600 m. which they feel best in that height.
If you take them to very high place,
like 3000 m. they will not feel good.
Most probably it is the best concentration of oxygen and due to the fact they do not have perfect lungs
they feel better there.
-If you have a patient who's about 60 years old and you know that she has part of the lung removed
when she was about 18 because of tuberculosis, would it be dangerous to give her?
-No, not at all.
- The father had twice in his life tuberculosis. Twice he was in a sanatorium up in the mountains
and later on he worked in the gastronomic field. He was smoking a lot and he died at 78.
Up to then he was quite healthy.
What happened, without Homeopathy?
-He was cured by his organism.
He had a strong organism.
You get tuberculosis when you are
putting yourself under a stress.
And if that stress concerns mostly the
emotions and there is a predisposition
then the possibility of tuberculosis
arises very much.
In the older times where things
were much more strict in families
and a woman would fall in love with
a man whom she could not marry
it was known that because of that longing, because of that desire which was not fulfilled
the woman could waste away
and could go into tuberculosis.
Even they were stories written about such cases. The constant stress upon the feelings of the person
if there is a predisposition,
it may lead to active tuberculosis.
But if such a person finds a solution to that, at the same time it does something which promotes his health
right food etc. then he may
recover from tuberculosis.
Strong organisms which belong to the
first group, they can go to tuberculosis.
They will recover perhaps even by
themselves like her father.
-If I remember correctly my mother told me that people who had tuberculosis used to get a lot of pork, ham to eat to recover.
-Could you then look at Tub.
as a remedy for grief?
-For grief yes, if the grief is connected with
a love, not love disappointment.
You cannot fall in love for long time with somebody whom you think is not interested in you.
So Tub., how it can develop? It can develop when you know this man is interested on me, I'm interested in him
so there is this longing, this hope that this is going to be a very good affair. And somebody is preventing you.
So that kind of grief yes. But the grief when somebody leaves you and it's a rejection, no.
The grief has to have a particular type.
The grief from different remedies they
have a different connotation.
Aurum grief is different than Ignatia grief.
Aurum grief is very deep and it concerns
the ego, it has destroyed the ego.
The Ignatia is a grief which has cut off the possibility for contact and possibility of emotional rapport.
-You said that Tub. is a remedy for
arthritis and rheumatoid affairs.
Is it too a remedy for arthrosis,
degenerative joint diseases?
The discs are destroyed, they
are degenerative diseases.
-Is she talking about ankylosed spondilitis
or spondiloarthritis, deformative arthritis?
Anyhow. All these diseases, all this group
of diseases they can be helped by Tub.
For instance osteoarthritis
cannot be helped by Rhus-t.
Osteoarthritis needs remedies like Nat-s.,
like Kali's, like Calcareas, Sulph.
Tub. goes deeper and can affect
or can make better the situation.
Tub. is a remedy that you may
need as an intermediate remedy.
Maybe not as the first remedy but as the case progresses there are some symptoms of Tub. appearing,
which show that there is the tubercular miasm somewhere in the case  but not as a first and main remedy.
Tub. is similar in this respect to Carc.
-You can read very often that if the child is hairy along the spine on his back, that this is a sign of Tub.
What do you says concerning
your experience?
-I have seen other remedies
having that as well and this is true.
But I have not confirmed this frequently
enough to give it as a keynote.
Because if you give it as a keynote,
you see this, you give Tub., then you fail.
But some of the cases they may
have this hormonal disturbance.
My problem is that I connect all things together.
For instance, when a woman develops hair
in the body, that means actually that we have
male hormones excess in the body.
My problem is this, that Tub. I have seen it is not a case of a woman where there is this type of person sexually.
You see it is different the behavior of a woman with hair, with high testosterone and it's different in sexual contact
with a woman whose hormones
are mostly female hormones.
And Tub. has mostly female hormones.
So it's difficult for me to say this may be.
Maybe sometimes it goes to the other way.
Like pork, like grinding of the teeth, like fear of cats, aversion to cats, these are strong elements for Tub.
Especially when you have that type of person. The hairy part is with a lot of other remedies.
Even Phos. can have hairy part.
-Only in new born.
-I don't know.
-I've seen in children this violent behavior, the kicking, the biting, the striking and so forth.
In adults, as they mature, does this violent behavior persist or they just develop this tremendous
restlessness moving from
one situation to another?
-The violence here is subtle, it's not
a violent person that will fight, quarrel.
What you are describing, I would think of Tarent., I would think of Stram., of more aggressive remedies.
This has a violence which is more subtle. And that subtle violence of course will develop as deviations
in a grown up where he can control this.
- Concerning the question you
just had before, I can add something.
My father had tuberculosis and we have a
lot of cases of tuberculosis in my family.
I was born as a baby with hair on my back,
black hair on my head and on my back.
When I was a little child I had tuberculosis in the lymph nodes of the lungs, in the middle part of the lungs.
-You should have said that in your ... We keep it in mind.
-In my homeopathic treatment I already got Tub. and before that concerning my character I was always on the go
always jumping from one topic to the next.
I never felt at ease in my relationship. I always thought I have to look for a different man, this is not the right man.
After Tub. this settled, this calmed down. Changed completely.
-I had a child of 5 years and I gave him Tub. because of his mental state and this little boy had phimosis.
This phimosis went away within 14 days. Do you know more cases of Tub. healing phimosis?
-The first time I hear that but what happened with the child in general? What was his character?
-It was very destructive, very provocative towards the mother, he said no to everything and anything
and after Tub. the child a 100%
better on his character side.
-Provocative maybe is a very good word for describing. They just want to create emotions.
-I had a child and I was treating her with Tub. and she had a very bad cough and I gave her Tub. and then
she developed whopping cough.
This whooping cough was very bad for one week and then it was gone and with this too all the
respiratory tract affairs were going too.
My question, you hear again and again that if children diseases come up, they might
extinguish a miasmatic layer, is that true?
-If the child disease comes up, that the
disease itself extinguishes a miasmatic layer?
Well there is some kind of truth about it.
It is better to let the epidemic diseases, in my understanding, go through instead of trying to suppress it
by different vaccinations, as they do today.
But this idea may take many, many years before finally is established because it's going to be understood
that the other way, trying to suppress all these children diseases is not the best course of action for the human race.
-Do you know any cases of Tub.
who likes or even loves cats?
-As far as I can remember yes. I can recall certain cases which they had no problems with cat.
I'm interested very much to hear your experiences on the remedies that we're talking about.
Just to get a feedback.
-I read in a book of Bernett that he gave for children, with a lot of infections, Bacillinum in between.
For example Calc. and in between Bacillinum. What that be the same procedure as you described?
-Yes, it's the same idea. It's protection through the right remedy. Of course if you do it mechanically
you just give mechanically to everybody,
some will be protected, some will be not.
-A young woman who might be treated for mild psoriasis with Carc. and Ign., she would not respond to that
and then she went to China for one month with a girlfriend and psoriasis disappeared completely
only to return when she returned home. Would that be the desire for travel and into the direction of Tub.?
-This is rather a symptom of Ign. You gave
Ign., maybe you had to go higher in Ign.
because you had some
reasons for giving Ignatia.
Maybe the Ign. you gave was not active, maybe you have to use other pharmacies or two pharmacies
and give Ign. higher.
-But the psoriasis started before she had
reason for Ignatia. Many years before.
-Still the layer of Ign. is there. So first you eliminate this and then you find out what is left.
- As to the hairy state, as I've been working with many Turkish and Arab people, in the middle of Berlin
I see very many babies who to my impression have Tub. miasm.
They have very long eye lashes, blue sclera, very many of them and those who might be treated with Tub.
most of them had a hairy state.
Of course all people around the Mediterranean have more hair than German people but it was really very regular.
-It's a matter of race rather than...
-The other thing is, I also have had very aggressive Tub. children.
Of course they are different from other aggressive children. They look if you look
and they only do something bad that they see they can make somebody angry, it's subtle.
-Exactly, this is absolutely correct.
-A child, one of my patients, got Brucellosis by chick and the parents went to hospital with the child
and it got antibiotics and when the child
came home, it got rheumatoid complains.
The grand father of this child had tuberculosis and I gave Tub. to the child and these
rheumatoid complains went away completely.
-Were the modalities of the case, if she remembers, were Rhus-t. modalities?
-Yes.
-I have two very interesting observations concerning my patients. One is a young man
he came to me because of palpitations after playing squash. His heartbeat was very fast.
I found out that when he saw
a cat he got the desire to kick her.
During this I asked him if there was
any case of tuberculosis in his family?
And he said yes, his grand father.
And he got Tub. and afterwards he never had again the symptom of having the need to hate a cat.
And he was able to go on playing squash.
And another little boy was masturbating right in front of me during the history taking.
And after giving Tub. his masturbation desire was getting better and too his frequent colds.
-Very interesting.
This kind of behavior, you see the whole idea? They like to provoke reactions, angriness.
-Six weeks ago I gave Tub. to a schizophrenic patient, 23 years of age and he was very much in a phlegm
but now he is very much better.
I don't know if this stays.
He does a lot of sports and he is reading books again. Before he was only in front of the TV.
From morning to evening he was seeing TV and doing nothing else.
And he is visiting friends and things.
-Why you gave him Tub.?
-For several reasons. I made a repertorisation and he was very much ... discontent to everything
and he wanted to go away and to
commit suicide with his mother.
They were sitting by the sea side and he wanted to tell the mother to make suicide with him and things...
But do you think Tub. could cure
or could help with schizophrenia?
-No, if this is real schizophrenia, that means
he will need other remedies as well.
But as a start it's a very good start.
The moment that he has a relapse that is the difficult period where you have to find the next remedy.
-I give him every second day a C30.
-Good luck.