I have to say a few things concerning the idea.
I have seen some homeopaths accusing others with their remedy.
If they know that this is the remedy they have taken, they accuse the person and say, ah yes Hyos. or Plat.!
Man giving information, she is Plat.
Like Hyos. is a difficult situation psychologically.
They are really obsessive, jealous.
They don't trust anybody.
They feel that everybody, most probably is plotting against them or maybe they try to poison them.
This is the turn which takes the Hyos. mentality.
It has to do a lot with the sexual instinct and you can say that is one of these remedies which are perverted sexually.
The perversion will take a turn where the person  has to talk about things which are disgusting.
For instance they'll talk about stool, urine, they will talk about it and also people who are...
...not in an asylum. They are quite all right.
They would like to deal with the stool. They have a stool and then they touch it and they play with the stool.
I have this experience which I have seen in a patient. It is terrible, very disgusting habit.
They can have very disgusting habits in many cases.
Another case I have seen is just taking
stuff from wounds and eat them.
But they also like to talk about these things, about sex, about sexual things and stools and urine.
A woman, for instance, if she goes to the bathroom to have stool, she closes the door, this is natural.
For a Hyos. it's different. She will leave the door open on purpose that the man will look at her.
All this idea. Playing with the stool etc.
This is what I call obsession.
There is something inside them which makes them do things obsessively, counting or doing like this.
They are upset and then you see....
and then they have an epileptic fit.
-Which other remedies are counting?
I didn't find it anywhere.
-One of them is this. Or they count objects.
1,2,3 curtains.
Can you understand the obsession when
they touch the stool and they mix the stool.
It's a state of madness almost but they
are not crazy. They are living in the society.
I remember a case when I was in India.
Also they are exhibitionists.
They will open, the men especially,
and expose the genitals publically.
I remember a case when I was in India, one of our teachers in the school, he was a very old man
with a lot of experience and he was telling about Hyos. He had a mental case he was treating, without success.
He said, one day in Calcutta the man got up into a high wall he climbed there and waited for the doctor
to pass underneath.
And while the doctor was passing, he urinated.
He saw him and he said, 'oh I know your remedy'.
He said, I gave him Hyos. and finally I got him better. He was trying to cure him with different other remedies
it was not possible. The little ones are
going out... It's too much.
That's why I don't allow little ones here in the class.
Why do they take it out? In a case where you will see real insanity, they will expose constantly this.
They feel as if they cannot have something on the skin.
You take the case of a Hyos. woman. She is sitting there, you sit here and you know some women they sit
relaxed, let us say.
In which case they can expose a little bit more than necessary.
Now the Hyos. woman she will sit there and it's very warm and she will pick up.. and ...
As if nothing happens. What's the difference? It's very hot.
I'm talking from experience.
There's a word in Greek? It's not naivety.
It's as if nothing happens and then continues to talk to you about her headache, about this, about that.
No emotions. No shame.
Also there is a tendency, even the
children, they hold their genitalia.
They sleep and they hold their genitalia. They put their hands inside all the time and hold their genitalia.
Plays with his genitalia, lies in bed with the
hands between thighs, touching its genitalia.
'The symptoms you describe', she says, 'makes me think of children 2,3 years old where they do like this
or they expose their genitalia'.
No, this is not Hyos.  Hyos. is when the urge is there to expose the person, without shame.
It's very interesting that when Hyos. gets into a state of grief, they are withdrawn inside them and there are no emotions.
Emotions are like wood. Not steel which become in Aur. Like wood, I have a wood inside.
It's not as heavy as Aur. depression. But it is almost no emotions. They can communicate, they can talk
they can say things but they feel nothing.
It is a blockage. Jealousy comes and overtakes them from here.
They feel tremendous jealousy and they feel here and then this catches the emotions.
I don't know how this happens in anatomy or physiology. I cannot know the physiology of that thing.
Why these feelings here of jealousy will cut out the emotions? But this is what happens with Hyos.
They lose the feelings. They lose the idea of life. It's not life anymore.
Whatever happens it doesn't matter.
And then in order to stimulate themselves sexually, they have to play with the genitals, to expose
the person and to do all this kind of things.
I remember a case in the hospital. I had a severe case. Very severe case where he was in a coma.
In the hospital, after an operation for an aortic transplant.
I gave him certain remedies, Op., Sulph. and then came out of the coma but not completely.
He started having delirium because he was having still fever and he was in a delirium state.
He was talking all the time, all the night. The nurse told me that he is constantly talking and he had a high blood pressure.
Constantly talking and his face was red. I said, that's a case of Lach. So I prescribed Lach. 200, I think.
I went next day and he was almost dead. His blood pressure shoot up much more, he was in a much
worse state and he was mumbling.
The words could be heard the day before.
When I went the next day....
... they had become mumbling but the nurse who was attending all night, she told me that after Lach...
He was a nice man, very conservative man, living in a religious family. His wife very religious but the nurse
told me 'after you gave him that remedy, he started swearing', not swearing but talking about prostitutes ...
You understand. He started saying words of that type, with prostitutes and what he did or he did not do and all that.
Then when I saw him the next day, he was ....
I take the blood pressure, it was very high.
I thought he had a brain stroke because the vascular system was very much sclerosed.
Strong arteriosclerosis.
I said, oh my god I made a mistake.
These mistakes are fatal.
The blood pressure was high, it's finished.
He will have a bleeding and it's finished.
But then I noticed he was lying in bed and his hands were in his genitalia. And the information that she gave me
about swearing and saying words like this,
I said my god, Hyos.
I gave Hyos. and brought him out of
the coma and that saved him.
This man lived another 10 years in very good condition.
The idea is that they use swearing words. Which is another remedy which likes to use swear words?
Something from A.... Anacardium!
Hyos. swear words which are connected
with sex, with stool, urine, things like that.
Fear of water also is there. That means they get in a state of rabies.
Mad dog.
Also in cases of acute with high fever, there is a restlessness in the fingers, playing with the fingers
playing with the bed clothes, making a lot of movements with their fingers while they're in a state of high fever.
Because they are desperate, they come to you to be treated and they feel very bad. Apart from the fact that these people
may be epileptics, asthmatics, with colitis and all that.
And then they need to be treated. If you hit exactly to the point and tell them exactly how they feel
and what they do, they will accept.
-Are they able to develop any emotional
contact with other people?
When they come? Do they have family?
-Yes but they are people who are quite apart, quite isolated.
A typical Hyos. case can't be married but still  there is a distance between men and women very much.
She keeps a distance. Also what I have to say further for Hyos. is that even in a child this desire to kill
we said it has the desire to kill, I have been described.
When the patient sees that you really know
what you are doing, they confess.
I'll tell you what one woman has confessed to me.
She said, 'while we were children and I had my sister, she was younger but I was very jealous of her.'
She was sitting in front of the swimming pool, the little one, and she went by and just pushed her.
Then the little one ... and then she looked and said , 'I looked but had no feelings. I just pushed her to die'.
Then the mother heard the voices and came
and took the child out of the swimming pool.
This is desire to kill and many times people they have confessed to me, oh yes I have desire to kill!
Did you ever try? No. They do not try very frequently, otherwise we have a problem but the desire is there.
There are a lot of remedies which have that. Plat. and Hep. has that but for Hyos. is quite strong.
-The sexual behavior could it be related to some sexual abuse that they had in the past or some history in the family life?
-I do not know.