-The draft will affect you?
-I would prefer not to be in a draft.
He says I do not tolerate the cold-wet but I can not sit in the sun as well but
a hot bath I enjoy.
So when it is warm-wet maybe he likes it,
when the heat of the sun dries him up maybe he does not like it.
So after taking into consideration all the explanation he is giving about the weather
we do not see a contra-indication really for Causticum.
-We were down eating dinner and it was a kind of chilly in the afternoon and
I found that my fingers were aching from the cold and it's not very cold.
In the winter I don't go out very much.
Why this pause? What am I thinking?
You would have stopped perhaps the consultation. Causticum is all right long time ago.
But I still continue to search and my mind pictures that may fit this whole picture.
Maybe still I have to ask something else, there is another remedy that may fit that
picture except of Causticum,
if we are completely wrong on Causticum and what is the other remedy?
There is a remedy that you don't know very well but it fits somewhat of the case.
It fits the case because I know the remedy somewhat.
You don't know the remedy in the mental-emotional picture but
you may know the remedy in its physical manifestations.
That remedy I'm thinking has a lot of suicidal tendencies,
strong suicidal which I don't see in him. Let's see, continue.
-If I get irritated, agitated, if I have to carry something heavy and it's very hot,
my hands get ret and they itch, they swell up and it also seems they have too much sugar.
If there is too much sugar, it seems I start to get the swelling.
My feet swell and get red. I used to get a lot of hives in my leg,
I don't get them anymore.
Another point for Causticum.
Causticum does not like sugar because it has a lot of energy without sugar,
so if he takes sugar, the energy is too much and it burns itself.
It's too high. The same with coffee. The energy is too high.
Therefore there is an aversion to sugar.
The organism says don't give me a ready made sugar because I'll burn it quickly and
then you have problems.
It says no sugar.
If we were in a school, for instance, I would say put down all the symptoms.
We have a lot of new symptoms like smoked fish. He likes smoked fish.
Smoked meat is for Causticum, what about smoked fish?
And we will see it again and again, we will verify it.
Put it down as aggravation from sugar, another symptom which Causticum may have.
That's why I say if there was a bank where we could put the information,
then we give the remedy, then we take the feedback.
What happened to that symptom?
Then we complete our Materia Medicas, we make them much more complete and
that's why there is a need for organized education because
if there is a really organized education...
I would never sit down myself and note it down and take into consideration and
then search it, I cant' do it anymore.
I used to do in the old days.
I don't know if I will be ever in old age but anyhow.
-Whenever I take a bath, I'll be covered with hives all over my legs after bath.
-After any bath whether it is warm or cold?
-Usually a bath will make it worse.
-Perspiration?
-I don't perspire very much.
-Do you lose your voice from time to time? Do you have hoarseness?
-No, I only had hoarseness once.
-Any warts?
-No.
-What kind of vaccinations you had?
-Small pox vaccination and I don't know if this was the result of
what my brother was doing to me but it would never heal up,
he used to walk up and punch it my vaccination
and I had vaccination for a very long time, a big swelling.
-A big scar that was irritated by your brother punching it.
-Yes and I'm sure I had all the other vaccinations like measles.
What he says what reminds you about his vaccination?
Another thing concerning the remedy?
-Staphysagria.
-It reminds you of Staphysagria. Can you imagine the child with a wound and
the brother punching again and again.
He says it wouldn't heal because my brother kept on punching the wound.
-Younger brother?
-Younger or older! You perceive the suppression, you perceive the type of person,
he was not able to defend himself.
He would just sit there and being punched.
-You are from Canada?
-Yes.
-Your nails they have any problem?
-I did have when I was really sick,
they were just breaking all the time and they were thin but now they are quite strong.
-How do you sleep? In what position, left, right?
-I used to sleep on my left but that makes my bowels worse.
On my left immediately I had bowel movements but I have four bowel movements when
I go to bed and then I sleep for an hour, I wake up, go to the toilet,
go to sleep for maybe half an hour, wake up.
It's really bad, I wake up every 15 min.
It's also worse from pressure, if I press my abdomen, if I take something heavy and
ghave it on my abdomen, the chances are a couple of minutes later I have to go to the toilet.
And eating, worse after eating.
If I had some food right now I could probably induce a stool by just eating.
As soon as I start eating I have to run to the toilet.
So everybody at home they are used to when I eat or
I go out with friends I always sit near the toilet because
I will have to go three times.
-You said the desire for fish; actually the desire is for fresh fish or for smoked fish.
-During really the bad time it will be for smoked fish.
-And you said smoked oysters.
-Those are the only ones we have in Canada. I've never had fresh oysters,
so I don't know.
-Would you say that you have periods of depression?
-Not depression but melancholy.
-The melancholy is not very painful.
-No, it's kind of enjoyable.
-Do you fall in love easily with a woman? Ah, you are married.
-I'm married but I was very romantic before I got married.
-When you had a relationship you wanted a very romantic relationship?
-Oh yes, every girl I had I would give a ring always,
I could never just go out with a girl and go to bed.
It was always romantic, I'm very romantic. She used to love it because
I get very romantic and sing and dance with her, she is great.
You see how I learn about remedies? This way. And if I speak much more,
I ask more questions, I learn all the aspects,
the inside and the outside.
Because I'm very attentive, very perceptive, I understand more than what he says.
He says one thing and I perceive where exactly he exaggerates, how much,
a little bit exaggeration here, he withholds information there,
all these are taken into consideration, not only what he says, whoever is in front of me.
I'm taking into consideration everything that takes place on all levels,
on a sub-conscious level, on a level which is not spoken out.
I take it into consideration and
yes it's different from one remedy to the other and no it's different,
just one word, he pronounces it differently.
Why I ask the last questions? The possibility of Aurum maybe.
But you see the person is not depressed and he says melancholic and all that
but it is romantic.
He enjoys almost the romanticism.
How can I describe this when I give a lecture and says give us the Materia Medica.
I try my best but never I can describe it in the way you see it actually happening.
It is beautiful.
I read you a remedy now and you tell me which is the remedy.
It says the use of this drug in Homeopathy has been confined to the action of the
alimentary tract.
It produces a diarrhea very similar to Croton, Croton tiglium has been given to him.
-Gambogia.
-Very good. Gambogia. From the pathogenesis it is very evident that it has very intense
and definite action especially on the gastro-enteric tract.
Great irritability of the stomach, burning, smarting and dryness of the tongue and throat,
pain in the stomach after food, tenderness in the epigastrium, pain and distention of
abdomen, flatulence after stool, rumbling and rolling with pain in sacral region,
diarrhea with sudden and forcible ejection of bilious stools,
tenesmus after with burning at anus.
This is the remedy yes. This might be the remedy but it is not the remedy that
we should prescribe.
Logically we must prescribe Causticum. Why?
Let's go back to the beginning, we have somebody who can not retain his stool.
He says I'm holding my anus to run because the anus cannot hold,
it is paralyzed on the sphincter, he has to hold the anus to go and have a stool.
It is Causticum. Then he comes up with a story which shows Causticum.
Can you go and give Gambogia? No.
You have to give Causticum with a possibility of after Causticum developing a picture of
Staphysagria and then maybe you have a beautiful cure.
-Gambogia has suicidal tendency?
-Yes very strong, depression tremendous. It is not written in the books.
The mental picture of Gambogia is one of promiscuity, a lot of aggressive energy inside,
like him. Promiscuous and at the same time suicidal, they don't want to live,
it's a crazy remedy, very strong. I will describe it to you once in the Materia Medica,
you will see it.
Not today, I just give you a few information.
What do you think now of Causticum? Do you understand the analysis?
Is anybody who does not understand? Nobody, very good.
-After all these remedies he had.... how can you recognize...
-Can you be sure? That's why you have to be sure. If you are sure about the remedy,
the remedy is going to do the right thing. There is no question about that.
The main thing is are we sure? To my understanding the remedy fortunately it appears
still to be there though with special accent on Phosphorus but my question is after having
a lot of Phosphorus high potencies, which is close to Causticum, is it possible that
the Phosphorus symptoms have been accentuated a bit more? Maybe.
Apart from the fact that he has a pathology which requires a lot of water, for instance.
I believe that if you analyze a case like that...
I have not seen ever in my practice a thing like that.
How is it that I have not seen it and I've treated so many cases?
Because I knew the Theory quite well. I think I avoided most of the mistakes,
which others do because I know the Theory very well.
-What about Ferrum phosphoricum?
-For this case?
What about Ferrum Phosphoricum? I said why?
Because he has many Phosphorus symptoms and many symptoms of Ferrum phosphoricum.
Which are the symptoms of Ferrum Phosphoricum in him?
-In the beginning weakness and bloody stool, change of mind, alternate moods.
-Not enough.
-George would you give Stramonium for dancing and cursing?
-Stramonium is not going to be alternating.
Stramonium is wild, when he had the fights he would have mentioned that
he hurt many people.
I almost sent somebody to the hospital.
I almost killed somebody by punching him.
You will get much more violence. Tremendous fear of the dark.
Causticum has fear of the dark but not as strong as Stramonium.
Do you have fear of the dark?
-No.
-Calcarea phosphorica?
-No. If you noticed he has a lot of energy inside and he is intense and
the energy is coming up easily, fast. Calcarea phosphorica is tired, tired, tired.
He is not all the time tired. He says if I sleep four hours, good sleep, energy.
-Phosphorus?
-Phosphorus yes it can be like that.
-Do you know why? Do you have any idea why they saw the need to make such a remedy?
-I don't know.
-There is one possibility. Mixing Sulphur and Calcarea carbonica...
-According to his understanding, which is quite logical, he saw mixings of Calcarea and
Sulphur with Hepar sulphur and in this same way, in this same frame of mind he saw
Causticum by mixing Cal. carb and Sulphate of potassium.
In this way we might say that he tried some combination of remedies.
He was a mixer, mixopathy!
The difference is that he proved this and he gave it according to the proving.
We can mix five remedies together and give it according to their proving.
There is nothing wrong with that, as long as we do it correctly and scientifically.
-Ammonium carbonicum for the respiratory problems and the bleeding of the anus?
-But many remedies have the respiratory troubles and bleeding from the anus and
Ammonium carbonicum is a remedy which is indicated mostly when the heart is involved,
when the thyroid is involved. We have another symptomatology all together,
we don't see the symptomatology of Ammonium carbonicum here.
-Which potency?
-What do you say? Let me hear some of you.
-200.
-I have to obey to the majority.
-It appears to be sensitive, he may have severe bleeding.
-We should be careful but I don't think 200 is too high potency.
We could have started with one dose of 30 but I will not go and give 12 here.
A dose of 30 is the most sensitive,
a dose of 200 is the highest that you can go.
We must not go higher until we see the reaction from this remedy.
So tell your homeopath to give you a dose of Causticum 200 and observe correctly.
Did you like the case?
-Yes.
-Do you think that you learned from that case?
-Staphysagria?
-I would say that this person most probably will need Staphysagria maybe after 9 months
or a year or two years even but at some point also he will need Tuberculinum again.
But when I will give Tuberculinum, I will have the symptoms to give it. This is different.
I would expect that underneath there is a tubercular miasm, most probably that's why
he was so sensitive to Tuberculinum and reacted into such a deep manner.
We most probably are going to see the tubercular miasm and
we may have seen it in the father,
not so much psychosis as tuberculosis that may have brought about the mental derangement.
This is only a conjecture. What I can say for sure is how we start. This is a supposition.
I suppose that he will need Staphysagria. I suppose, it is not absolutely certain.
According to what we see, the logic of that, the analysis will point out that
he will need Staphysagria. That's all.
I'm not saying give it anyhow.
Because many times Causticum,
then with the least thing Staphysagria and then it is a mistake.
-Do you give up Medorrhinum all together?
-No points of Medorrhinum.
-Is any inimical state with Phosphorus?
-An inimical will be if Causticum is acting and during the action of Causticum do not give
Phosphorus but it may go to Staphysagria and then to Phosphorus, this can happen.
But during the action of Causticum be careful not to give Phosphorus because
it may upset matters.
The inimical action has been devised by this fact,
by this kind of cases where people would show opposites effects from what they thought.
Phosphorus perforated the guts and brought about the peritonitis.
-With 10M what would happen?
-Perhaps a very strong reaction.
-Any prognosis?
-About the prognosis? I don't like to make prognosis, I don't like prophesies.
I will tell you what it says my experience in this case, hoping that the remedy is correct,
he will be 50% better within three months. He will still have some loose stool but
they will be less, the stool will start forming and
he will have an initial aggravation not more than 2-3 days, if he has.
So he will get better and better, when he will be completely well in Chron's disease in
that severity, two years from now, if we treat correctly,
we give one remedy after the other correctly.
Maybe I'm totally out, maybe tomorrow well.
I don't know.