-In looking over the cases that we got in the course I got this idea in my mind...
I want to ask you if this is right. (?)
It seems to me (?) then you look for some keynotes.
-I cannot say that I have a fixed way of looking in a case.
I have seen thousands of cases and I can say that everytime I see a case it's a new case.
I might decide of a remedy by just looking at the person, I never did.
That's an extreme and then in another case I may go on for two hours with keynotes, essences.
I cannot put it down to a process inside which is stabilized.
I try to give you on what I base my prescription, in that analysis I did.
You will see with every case and you will see with that case also what is in practice,
what happens really when you take a case.
This is a man of 65 years old, 63 years old, sorry.
He is 86 kilos and his height is 1,67m.
Since four years he complains about severe arthritic condition,
which affects mostly the joints,
together with an allergic kind of swelling of the hands.
The palms become very red, swelled up, they produce little pimples, they itch tremendously.
The other thing he complains is bloatedness of the stomach, which is underlined 3 times
and gas, which is not offensive.
Worse with beens and peas and with tea, underlined both 3 times.
The arm, the hands and the allergic condition,
which is mostly on the hands but go to all the extremities, it goes on the legs as well,
is much better by warm bath, underlined twice.
By warm bath also the the pain is ameliorated.
Mostly the joints which are affected are the wrist, the knees, the shoulder joints
and the ankles.
He complains for sleeplessness, he wakes up at 2.30 and he cannot sleep anymore.
Restlessness during sleep, underlined twice.
And jerking of legs during sleep, underlined twice.
The last year there are flashes of heat.
He is worse in warm weather, underlined 3 times.
Better open air, underlined 3 times.
Better in the sea, underlined 3 times but not the allergy.
The allergy is not affected in the sea.
He is very allergic to the pine trees and he has bought a place near the sea with pine trees
inside, it was a very beautiful place, where he was not able to enjoy.
For the last 4 years I heard that I cannot go, I cannot approach the place.
As soon as I'm there the itching starts, it's real hell, I just don't go anymore.
He is generally worse onions, underlined 3 times and garlic, underlined once.
And he has an irritability on wind.
Desires. There is one very strong desire for sweets, 3 times.
This is the case. We have to find the remedy.
Just look a little bit in your Repertory and tell me if you get any idea.
Out of the 5 people, whoever said Lycopodium?
There is bloatedness of the stomach and gas, which is not offensive, which is Lycopodium.
Worse beans and peas and things like that are very much Lycopodium.
Bloatedness from tea, very strong, But we don't have it in the Repertory.
We don't have that information.
He has bloatedness from the tea, we could have used that information, in case we had it
and in case we are desperate, we go to generalities and we make a general idea on there.
In generalities we got this idea.
I shall give you now some more information about the person.
He said that at the age of 23, he had a collic of the kidney,
he cannot remember which one of the two, he had colic of the kidney
and staphylococciassis at the age of 26.
Staphyylococcus infection, very severe, he was hospitalized.
At the age of 17 he had gonorrhea.
If you have the better in the sea, which is very strong, underlined 3 times
but his allergy is not ameliorated in the sea.
What I wanted to say is that you would prescribe Medorrhinum, if the information stops here.
Most of you, you would have prescribed Medorrhinum.
He had been operated for hernia and he had an eczema on the penis.
He had a slight swelling of the heart, he is a very solid man, solidly built, intelligent,
realistic and all that...
The position, which he sleeps now. Where, in which position he sleeps?
If he was Lycopodium, he would sleep on his right side.
It is characteristic of the Lycopodium, he wants to lie on the right side
because on the left side he is aggravated.
He does not like to lie on the left side, he is aggravated lying on the left side.
Lycopodium likes to lie on the right side.
The Medorrhinum likes to lie on his abdomen. He is ameliorated by lying on the abdomen
and he likes lying on the abdomen.
Now, which position this man sleeps? He sleeps on abdomen, underlined twice.
Now you make your decision.
I was thinking the same line as you are thinking about Medorrhinum.
I said, my god, I have a case of Medorrhinum.
This gonorrhea, better in the sea, sleeps on the abdomen, desire for sweets
and a man who is sexually quite good.
Something is missing, not enough information to really bring it down to Medorrhinum.
Therefore I continued the investigation in this case to find out a few more things about him.
He is warm from the waist downwards, he said I'm quite warm and I stick my feet out of covers.
Sticking feet out of covers, if you look on the Repertory, heat in the extremities,
feet uncovers them, see which are the remedies there?
Uncovers them and then there is another one which says soles, burning on the soles.
When it's only down on the soles, it has another rubric further down,
which is Lycopodium and Sulphur and then it says uncovers the soles.
Not this one, uncovering the feet.
In this case you have two keynotes symptoms of Medorrhinum and uncovering the feet...
There is another keynote of Medorrhinum. You have 3 keynotes of Medorrhinum now.
But the third keynote is a keynote also for Pulsatilla, for Sulphur
and for several other remedies.
I told you that he is thirsty, did you write that?
The person is thirsty, underlined 3 times.
The irritability from wind... Did you find it?
You go to the 1422. We see no Medorrhinum.
Be careful now. With the information I'll give you further you will see,
everybody will say this is the remedy.
I was thinking of Medorrhinum all the time and Lycopodium.
And then he is very thirsty and then there is a strong desire for alcohol, beer and wine.
Then I asked what about fears? He does not have any fear.
He says I'm a man of... He works for the intelligent service and it's a fact.
No fears really but he says I have one fear only and that's fear of high places.
It's impossible that I look down from a high place and vertigo also.
Look vertigo high places, look in your Repertory, those who do not know.
A warm person which sticks his feet out, he is afraid of the high places
and at 11 o'clock he has an empty feeling...
This is a fact, this is how a case develops.
You try more and more to get the totality, I could not get the essence.
The person had more fears, he was very matter of fact man,
he didn't seem to have aberrations concerning his psyche or his mental abilities,
he is very acute, his psychological condition was quite good.
And then I said to myself, Ok there is a fear in this case, a keynote
which is against Sulphur. Which is it?
-He is warm.
-Very warm, itching but better warm and something that puts out of your mind Suphur
because Sulphur usually gets worse when it gets warm and the itching gets
tremendously aggravated, especially with water.
We had here a keynote, which is against Sulphur,
which is the opposite of what Sulphur has.
And yet we had strong argument eventually and we have the totality of the symptoms here
to base a prescription on the totality of the symptoms, which is Sulphur.
One or two of his symptoms are not covered by the totality.
Worse onions and aggravated by onions is Lycopodium, Nux vomica, Pulsatilla and Thuja.
It's not Sulphur, so the aggravation from onions could have taken away from us
and the thinking could have been this man perhaps is Medorrhinum or Thuja case.
Because the worse onions could go to another layer,
where Thuja would appear after Medorrhinum and that was a line of thinking I was doing.
But when you put together everything, all the information finally,
you come to a totality of a symptom where you say this totality is Suphur.
You don't have essesnce but you have the totality with some keynotes to back it.
-If it was a Medorrhinum case would you see the emotional symptoms of Medorrhinum?
-You cannot say that. If you have Medorrhinum symptoms yes.
Aversion to vinegar and garlic, did I give you that?
-No.
-There is also strong aversion to vinegar and garlic.
Aversion to vinegar, there is no rubric. You will find aversion to acids.
Sulphur is there too.
Medorrhinum likes acids or has an aversion to acids?
-Likes.
-Likes acids and why? How do we know that he likes acids?
-Sour fruits.
Medorrhinum has a desire on unripe foods, the green foods desires them very much.
Unless you have a knowledge of Materia Medica, you cannot very much appreciate
what I'm talking about but I hope you understand and we communicate.
This is a case finally where you have to prescribe Sulphur,
you cannot prescribe another remedy,
yet the whole totality of that person is not covered by Sulphur.
So we have a partial totality of the prescription here.
I expected that some time or another he would get Medorrhinum.
In his process of development, it's going to be a stage where he would need Medorrhinum.
There was also another information, better open air I did not give it to you?
-Yes.
-Did I give it to you? Underlined 3 times?
-Is Sulphur worse with the wind?
-Not characteristic of Sulphur, it's characteristic of other remedies like Lycopodium,
Podophyllum, Camomilla, Nux vomica, much more than Sulphur.
You go to wind aggrevates in the generalities
and you will see there Sulphur is perhaps ordinary.
I prescribed Sulphur 200 for him one dose.
When I say he had a severe arthritis, it was really severe, he was limping from pain
or he would stay in bed.
The arthrosis were swelled up and red and very painful
and also the allergic condition quite strong.
He says that the first 3, 4 first days he had very severe pain on the left side
and then on the right.
The itching went down to the legs and then came up to the head again.
He had the itching in different parts of the body, it went down and then it came up severe.
And great weakness, weariness the first 10 days
but the sleep became better immediately and the stool became better.
He was having most probably a constipation, which he did not mention on the first time.
Now the constipation went away and the sleep became normal.
You remember he had a great problem.
2- 2.30 he would wake up and could not sleep anymore and he would get up and read
and walk and do anything until the morning where he would leave the house.
Now his sleep became better.
He said he had such a bloatedness the 12th day that reminded him a situation around 1959
that it was found in his intestines lamblias, it's a parasite.
There was a period in his life where he did not mention
when I was taking his past history but now that the bloatedness became so severe,
he said it reminded me of the state of 1959...
This case was taken around 1979, 59 was 20 years before that he had the same situation.
Desire for sweet, less.
He has a hunger during night and if he wakes up he eats something,
which is a characteristic of Sulphur.
In the beginning also he said I had more irritability than usual.
He went to his country house and there was no problem.
Perspiration is less, desire for alcohol and stimulant is less.
Lately he had developed a desire to eat eggs.
Now he sleeps at 8.30 in the morning. He sleeps even afternoon.
In Greece we take naps in the afternoon and he was never able to sleep in the afternoon.
Now he takes a nap.
During the last days he says, he wakes up frequently.
He sleeps and wakes up frequently, he sleeps again
which is a characteristic of Sulphur as well.
Anyhow he remains well for at least a year.
The third time he comes is after a year where a dentist has given him injections
and put some oil of cloves inside and he starts having a relapse.
He starts having a relapse with one difference now. There is a desire for oranges.
You know the desire for oranges is Medorrhinum characteristic.
Now what you will do?
-All the other (?)
-Not to this severity but there was a relapse definitely.
So you have a relapse of the case with the same symptomatology plus a symptom
which indicates Medorrhinum. What you will do?
I repeated Sulphur. I prefer to be on the sure side.
You see Sulphur definitely worked beautifully for him and I was waiting for Medorrhinum
and here was my chance but we don't go according to our desire
but according to what the person's organism tells us.
Taking the fact that it was a full relapse and Sulphur had helped him,
inspite of the new symptom, I would not go and give Medorrhinum but I should wait
when symptoms have changed more and they go towards Medorrhinum.
That will be the time where I shall give Medorrhinum.
Still that was the last time on 30 of April 1980 that I saw him, still he is well
and I have not given him any other remedy.
Sulphur 200 again.
The second visit was one month after the first.
Not a full relapse as far as his intensity is concerned
that means he did not have so much severe pain and he did not have that severe itching.
He had been for one a half or two months to the dentist and he had all this.
He waited because I said to him, you've been to the dentist,
we don't know if it's going to be a relapse.
He didn't come to the office immediately. He telephoned and I told him wait.
And then he was going worse and worse and then eventually he came to the office.
If we say 100 for the beginning, that was 65 or 70%
but the main thing is that the main constitutional symptoms
on which we prescribed Sulphur are back and then we were justified to give it.
If the relapse is total full and it's because of chemical interference,
I follow the law which is I repeat the same remedy, the same potency.
So this was a case where he had chemicals but if the relapse was full I could have given
and you could have gone a step higher in potency.
In case we have a relapse because of an interference with a chemical in the body
whatever it is, antibiotics, hormones, coffee etc. and you have a relapse,
you repeat the same remedy at the same potency.
If you have a relapse without interference, you step one higher
but if the remedy has worked beautifully and the person has a full relapse
absolutely as he was in the beginning, you may go in spite of the interference,
you may go one higher in case you have not given a high potency, like in this case.
200 is not a very high potency; so you could have given 1M.
Usually the law is to repeat the remedy, to repeat the same potency.
After dental treatment many times within one week or two weeks or three weeks
there is a relapse and there is again a restoration of the health
without any interference at all. So you have to wait 3 weeks at least.
The more you can wait, the better. Six weeks is very good, if you can wait.
To persuade the person to wait, to see what happens
because the organism it may come back to the balanced condition.
It depends what kind of cheiropractic interference.
Strong cheiropractic interference perhaps it may have some effect.
The body has intelligence and if you have stimulated the body correctly,
supposing you gave the right remedy and the body wants to maintain an inflammation
at a certain point, on a joint for three months
it's wrong to interfere with that pain.
If you know what you are doing with Homeopathy and the remedy has acted
you can say confidently that this pain is going to go away, just be patient or you give some placebo
but don't interfere with it.
But now you are having a person like that under homeopathic treatment,
he is doing well and then he climbs up a stair to fix something and falls down
or makes the wrong movement and then his back is hurt. That's another state.
This condition can be interfered by cheiropract without interfering
the deeper action of the remedy.
Actually many times we would like to have that because in this case
this has happened exactly.
His daughter is a doctor who attended the classes and she telephoned
and said my father was climbing a stair to fix a curtain and he fall down
and he is now having severe pain on the back and she described an acute condition of Rhus tox.
So he was in bed and he was very painful and I had to prescribe
and I did prescribe a dose of Rhus tox 200, which relieved him immediately.
If I had a cheiropractor, I would say you try to fix him.
I would rather have a cheiropractor fix that case than give a remedy if it was not correct.
In this case the symptomatology was absolutely clear and I had no doubt
that the remedy was correct.
In such a case you can give a remedy without fearing that the remedy
maybe interfering wrongly with the organism.
Why not give him Calcarea? But he had symptoms of Rhus tox, not Calcarea.
It was not that.
-But you don't want to treat an acute case with a remedy very similar to constitutional remedy.
-Very similar.
If he gives me symptoms of Rhus tox clearly, I would give this.
We are going to talk about this problem tomorrow.
What we do when a person is under constitutional treatment and an acute arises.
What are we going to do? When to prescribe, when not to prescribe, when to wait etc?
We don't work very much with so low potencies.
I used to work with 30, 200, 1M, 10M, 50M. Very seldom I would use 12.
In such case I was certain that it was going to work and I gave 200 Rhus tox.
No more questions. Thank you.