-Very sensitive to cold air, aversion to water, cannot bear to touch it.
So if one had prescribed that remedy that syndrome here it looks like this one.
A cold remedy, that has vomiting and diarrhea before menses, Ammonium carbonicum, this is.
Nobody has mentioned it and neither I gave it.
-Why did you give (?)
-I did not.
Which is the remedy which is so cold?
-Veratrum album.
-Veratrum album. It is a case on which we prescribe on pathology, not on symptomatology
but which is so strong that indicates the heart of the remedy which is Veratrum album.
It is not that we went through repertorization but knowing the remedy, not the essence
but only local symptoms and general symptoms of the remedy.
So where are we now here? We just have the general symptoms of the remedy
and local symptoms general, we put these together
and see no other remedy except  Ammonium carbo that comes closer.
So in my prescription Veratrum album with possibility of Ammonium carbonicum.
Dysmenorrhea for how many years?
-19.
-Within one month, no other remedy.
(?) we do not prescribe.
Sometimes you will see me prescribing on one keynote but before I do that,
l have exhausted the whole Materia Medica and see that no other remedy fits. Then I do it.
That is the idea, a completely different way of thinking here.
We don't have the essence, we don't have enough general symptoms.
We don't have local symptoms to indicate.
We do a combination of local and general symptoms and Veratrum album.
You look disappointed. These are difficult cases.
We have some cases later which are very difficult to find
but these cases are not difficult cases.
And if you struggle with such cases then when you go back home,
you will see that your cases become much more easy. Do not get disappointed.
There is also one point...
I can forgive for not finding the remedy because you do not have real responsibility
at the moment, you are very safe.
So it's a different feeling from when you really have the responsibility, it's a different thing.
It's much more the mind, much more to the point.
That's why most of the people have difficulties of these cases but you are learning quite a lot.
You can read so many cases that are not of that level.
So we have learned aspects of Argentum nitricum and Veratrum album and you will not forget this.
It says about the heart here, a heart remedy, (?) sensation of heart beating,
palpitation from the least exertion. Especially when you (?)
Has anybody found that remedy?
You suggested Ignatia? Who suggested Ignatia?
Who was in favor of Natrum muriaticum? Who suggested other remedies?
-Bryonia.
-Bryonia was good but something was lacking, here it says palpitation tremendous
and a heart which affected by cigarette (?)
-(?)
-The remedy is (?)
What (?) did in that case is that it took away the effect of tobacco
which had rearranged the whole system in such a way that it didn't go back.
What we observe is a nosological influence.
We have on top of a Natrum muriaticum (?) and understand what is going on.
So this person was a Nat mur case (?) with palpitations and all these symptomatology.
There is a stimulation and grief and tobacco and there is a further disorganization
of the system and with Nat muriaticum...
The woman that had the problem had to decide.
She is a Nat mur, that's the person and then he still (?) and then here comes (?)
It's a different (?) competition is too strong, it aggravates.
It's a new state on top of Nat mur.
In my experience I found that it is not going to act
You have to find the new layer.
A new layer has come about, a new remedy and you have to face that remedy (?)
and then go back in Nat mur condition; then you may repeat Nat mur.
So what (?) did, it took away (?) it's a good function, after 3-4 days I repeated Nat mur
because what was happening is that she had already antidoted the remedy.
So the Nat mur state was already back and on top of that it was created another state.
If the Nat mur was not back, if she had not antidote the Nat mur
and it was a bit different in modalities, then most probably the Nat mur would be indicated.
I will tell you more to understand.
Here we have a case of Nat mur on top.
Underneath it was another layer which is Sepia
and perhaps we have another layer Sulphur which will not show so much disturbances.
So when you give Nat mur, this layer goes away and we have the possibility
to see the Sepia layer manifesting.
But if you wait too long or we don't have contact with the patient, the patient feels
that he is quite all right and doesn't come back, what happens is he antidotes the treatment.
In Nat mur state, that layer which went away first, will come back.
That means this layer is the result of the underline predisposition layer.
All these underline layers they may be so that Nat mur is the uppermost.
You give the remedy, you take it away.
If you don't give the Sepia the next remedy, then every time it will have a relapse,
most probably you'll have a Nat mur layer.
But if you have given Nat mur and Sepia, the Nat mur layer will go away,
the Sepia layer will be there and the (?) layer will be here.
You give (?) and Sepia. Here it was state Nat mur antidoted, a new situation.
You took away the (?) and Nat mur is there, take Nat mur and you see normal.
-What potency you use for (?) ?
-200.
-Why you chose (?) ?
-Because this is the Similimum in this case.
If you read (?) you will see that the whole picture of the remedy comes very much,
a hard remedy and there is a great palpitation and very much aggravated by exertion.
What is more important here, what is a keynote, it says a tobacco heart,
what this person has said to me, it says I have been smoking a lot yesterday...
-Did you get it from the analysis of the remedy or did you use the Repertory at all?
-No I didn't use the Repertory.
-Not even there? In palpitations on tobacco? You have to know the remedies.
-Yes you have to know the small remedies.
You see the Repertory is better but many times we need to have the information
which is beyond the Repertory and apply it,
otherwise if we try to apply the Repertory every time...
Did you give Bryonia in that case? I'm sure.
A little bit of change but still a whole syndrome will be there.
You may have a little bit of change but the person still (?)
The keynote was for me from tobacco poison but it has stimulated through tobacco.
(?) has exactly that sensitivity.
These persons that are (?) they are affected by tobacco, by smoking cigarettes,
their heart is affected.
When you have somebody who claims that if I smoke my heart will be affected,
then it's (?).
If he tells you that if I smoke just a little then my head is affected, then what is there?
-Spigelia.
-If a person will tell you that if I'm exposed to gases to downtown where there is pollution,
then I feel weak with a headache, with hemicrania, with anxiety, all these symptoms come
when they go down town, where there is a lot of exhaust gazes which is the remedy?
-Phosphorus?
-No.
-You have to remember that because you may find it.
You have people being exposed to pollution, again and again
and they develop that symptom where there is tremendous hurry feeling inside...