-What is the problem?
-I start with the physical.
Two months ago I started backache, I didn’t have it before,
in the low part of the back and
it was always in the morning.
When I wake up and walk 2-3 steps, it goes away. Suddenly it comes with pain,
it came 14 days after and when I get up in the morning and walk, it goes away.
I feel it’s something wrong in my life now. I lose my energy when I’m not working.
I sit there and something is away, I have to lie down and sleep.
I try some healing now and that makes me total caput.
I know there is something wrong with my spleen because my tongue is too brown now.
From too much drinking.
-Do you eat a lot of drinks? Any type?
-Yes any type?
-You drink tea and coffee?
-Not coffee, not coca-cola. I drink beer and water mostly and wine.
-So tomorrow you have here last chance.
-The wine here is not doing me well.
I have a reaction by that. My colon stuck with constipation and at the same time
depressed. It comes together.
It comes and goes. I got diarrhea like yesterday and then energy comes up again and
always when I’m coming to a new place like this,
I have constipation always the first 3-4 days and that is always the same
with my mother.
-Characteristic of your mother also?
-Yes. When I was about 6 years old I got asthma that lasted for 3-4 years,
then it was got away without treatment.
I know in my life there was when I was one year old my mother tried always to take me
from the breast and every time I got a cold.
When I come to the breast it was OK. There is a part in me that I want to go back in that
breast again. There is something regretting inside me. I want something with love, safe
-Affection and security.
-Yes, I was in India and I met a man whom was clairvoyant and I was talking to him and
suddenly lied down on the floor and cries to me mother, mother!
He has seen that part of me.
-Who lied down?
-Him, I asked him something... Let me lie down and say mother, mother in a way that it
really came to me. I feel there is something with my mother.
I’m divorced. Now I live together with a girl. I have a child who is two years old and in one
year she got asthma, a real heavy asthma.
We cured the asthma with Nat sulphuricum but not the mucus, so when gets a cold, it
takes about 2-3 days when the asthma comes. Then the Nat sulphuricum,
the asthma goes away but still she is with mucus.
-This girl you have it with your second wife?
-Yes. My two first children are very healthy
I’m very afraid to start with a new remedy after new remedy and then end up after 50
remedies…because I’ve tried only 5 in my life.
-What did you try?
-I tried Medorrhinum, I had gonorrhea two times and
that was when I was brought in Thailand and I got a sycotic strong
I was sitting in the room in China, I had to run and talk with people,
the first time in my life and there was something itching in my penis.
Both of these gonorrhea was treated
-With penicillin?
-Yes.
-You got it after the gonorrhea was treated?
-It was years after. Gonorrhea I got in 1979 and this was in 1981.
I got Medorrhinum for that. It took about 7 days when I got that reaction.
-Did you have a discharge from the urethra?
-No, only a little mucus and then I had tried Medorrhinum afterwards and no reaction but
then I got Sulphur and I got a little bit change, then it goes a little up but then it’s not coming.
I feel I’m going towards disease now. I feel it really.
-Can you show your tongue?
There is yellowness in base and white.
There are marks from the teeth.
You got Medorrhinum first. Did you have a good reaction?
-It was this reaction, nothing else.
-You didn’t feel any better in your health? More energy?
-Nothing. Then I took Sulphur and then I got diarrhea.
-You got diarrhea from the first time?
-Yes.
-With the diarrhea you felt better?
-Yes, a little better and I’ve tried so far 10M and 50M without reaction.
It was one year ago and I wake up one night about 3-4 with pain and I can’t find a
situation to lie. Then I took Nux vomica and it went away.
-In the thoracic area?
-Yes.
-The thoracic area is the area of Sulphur, pain on the thoracic region is characteristic of
Sulphur very much.
So you took Nux vomica what potency?
-1M.
I tried Tuberculinum because my grandfather died when my father was 3 years from
tuberculosis and I had no reaction in vaccination. That was strange. And no reaction from Tuberculinum.
-Now you have diarrhea?
-Yesterday. The pain was from here down the back a little upwards but today when I got
constipation it was down.
-Sacral region?
-Sacral region and I feel something in my achilles tendon.
-The symptom as it is said in the beginning pain in the lower back, worse in the morning,
better on walking, pain in the achilles again worse in the morning, better in walking
What is the remedy?
-Rhus tox.
-Rhus tox and it’s not only Rhus tox. The first remedy that he needs is Rhus tox.
We have sudden weakness.
-Sudden weakness complete and no energy.
-Especially when you are not busy?
-No, when I work in the clinic I can start 8 o’clock and continue till 6 o’clock in the
afternoon but I have 3 days free in the week and then
-You are exhausted.
-Yes but it’s better towards the evening, about 2-3 o’clock...
-At 8-9 o’clock better?
-Better then but it’s a general feeling of something stuck in there, something not moving
and sadness is coming, the constipation is coming, I don’t have energy to train again, not
doing meditation or yoga, my relationship with the girl is not stimulated.
I know that I should change my diet. I always
I took something from [name] that is a clairvoyant person in Denmark and
I took something in Norway and I know it’s coming but I don’t have the energy.
-You don’t have the energy to take the decision.
-Yes... It’s quite hard. I need too much energy for that but I’m grown in that areas,
so I feel I can take it, I need it but it takes a lot of energy.
I never get a cold. I haven’t been sick for 10-15 years not a single cold, very good health.
And suddenly this situation comes.
I smoke for 3 years now.
-How old are you?
-39.
-Do you drink a lot of beer now?
-Yes.
-Are you aware that there is yellowness the conjunctiva?
-I have some pressure and I was sitting with a patient,
I was involved emotionally and something like
-Like a spasm?
-Yes.
-Have you examined for that?
-No X-rays, nothing.
-When you go to the diarrhea, you have normal stool and when the diarrhea started?
-I was on Saturday, Sunday constipated, Monday constipated and yesterday diarrhea came
-Before that?
-I was constipated.
-In Norway?
-The tendency is constipated and then I take some laxative, some natural and I feel better
but it is unstable. I’m going back to a little depressed, the colon stuck again.
My mother had that problem always, she is 60. My father never.
It is something happened, I think I was 2 years old, and there was a horrible thing from my
father. I make stool on the street and then he took me here and put my nose in it and
suddenly I was finished with it, no more stool.
I always have a lot of trouble with stool, I remember sitting on the toilet pressing and
pressing, with pain quite young.
-How was your other life? It was without big problems?
-It has been an easy life in one way. I studied Medicine in Germany, easy life but I’m
divorced, that was hard time. Then I got angry.
When I get angry I don’t get a distance.
Then I sit down with my ex- affair and takes… and writes that I was an idiot and things like that.
When I’m angry, I sit down and I write and I put it in a red box an envelope and send it to
her and then it’s coming back in
When I was to Boston I divorced, I found my ex-wife with another man and I got letters.
I live very much in my phantasy.
When I was young I dreamed about struggling, it was always somebody following me and
there was a lot of nightmares. But since I was 10 I can’t remember a dream.
Now I can have a dream that I’m saving the world, it’s good dreams, half awake, half
asleep and I’m doing good to humanity and things like that. But I dream very little now.
-Daydreaming?
-Daydreaming yes, I jump into my phantasy, a lot of phantasy, not in the night, in the day.
-The phantasy is around what?
-Around to be with the right girl or to be in a safe place and to get a lot of love because I
cure patients. In one way I’m weeping for love in this world and things like that in my
phantasy. It’s not to be the best in Medicine, not that.
-When did you divorce first time?
-It was in 1979. For a period before we separated, we stayed together.
When we came to the divorce it wasn’t planned. In our relation, it was more struggling or
fighting but that consequence… I wasn’t prepare for that.
-Did you overcome this?
-I went into Nux vomica state, I buy new things and I change my job and I train and run
All the spiritual side of my life to help.
-When did you meet the other girl that you are now with?
-I met her when I was so lonely after I got divorced. I worked as a psychiatrist and I
started a relation to get my loneliness away.
-And you got involved?
-I tried.
-Do you feel trapped in that situation now?
-I feel trapped, I’m not getting that money and things away as long as these things I had to
stay in the house because I can’t tell my old address and I had to stay there.
I can’t make my own house now for living. Of course I love my third child.
The first two I see them some times the year and that is a tragedy.
2-3 days in the week, I play, that is the only thing.
-When did you start drinking?
-The last 2-3 years I feel I must relax in a way. After 8 hours to the clinic I go to some
place and take one beer and it’s OK. But I’m never drunk. It’s coming to my life to relax.
They told me that you must drink cold drinks and I continued and I easy get flatulence
now and if I drink much alcohol I get a horrible smell, it’s the same with my father.
-Do you feel distended?
-I feel distended. I feel like 90 kilos when I’m 78 or something like that.
-This distention is always there or sometimes it is more?
-If I put myself together and say I have to eat vegetarian but
if I eat some beef then it grows but especially with alcohol,
I get a lot of flatulence and it smells horrible.
-Your sleep is good?
-My sleep is quite good. I got some energy and I wake up 4 o’clock in the morning but
it was for only 2-3 days.
I got Hyoscyamus then I took Medorrhinum again, that was with an interval of one week and
then everything was gone.
-When you sleep you have salivation?
-No, it’s more dry. I smoke 15 cigarettes the day.
-Do you have great thirst? You are a thirsty person?
-No, I don’t have thirst at all.
I don’t eat breakfast and I’m not drinking, then I can work until 6 in the afternoon without
drinking, without eating. Then I feel some thirst and that’s natural but
it’s not the thirst, it’s a general thing.
-How you sleep, in what position?
-On the back, on the sides, on both sides, never on the stomach.
-What is your reaction to weather?
-I’m grown up in front of the sea and I love the sea and now I’m better by the sea but
when the weather is changing, I don’t feel anything.
-When it is very warm like here?
-Let’s say here 4 years ago it was marvelous to come here but now I feel more sensitive
to the heat. I will sit more in the shadow than to go in the sun.
I must say that in 1980 I took Lycopodium CM because I did some research, they were
some students that say you look so old comparing your age and I had some flatulence at
that time and I took Lycopodium CM. I didn’t know Homeopathy at that time how is working
-How is your sexual drive now?
-It is out, it’s nothing.
I never had very strong sexual drive. I have not the feeling. I can make sex every day and
no problem with potency but there is no feeling, it is flat. There is no fun, no enjoyment.
I’ve always been a little reserved about that, especially when I was about 19 years old.
I was reserved, I was playing football
But if I get alcohol I can be extrovert but at the same time not extrovert.
-During sex do you have easy ejaculation?
-No.
-During sleep… do you have night emissions?
-No, never.
-During sleep do you have night flowing?
-Never.
It’s a same my sexual life, it’s a distance. I can have some closeness but I must have
some distance. And the girl I stay with, she is quite distant, that’s good for me.
She doesn’t bother me.
…we talked about contact or intimacy and then I faint, that was too hot for me.
She did something like that and I fainted.
-What age?
-At the end of 20, about 1975. It was too strong.
-Can you urinate in front of others?
-Yes no problem.
-How much salt do you take?
-I don’t like salt.
-Because of logical reasons or because the taste is not good?
-No, I’ve never been for salt.
-What do you like?
-I can eat a lot of tomato, green fruit, green apples
-Unripe, sour.
-Yes.
-Fish?
-No.
-You are a fisherman.
-Yes but I don’t like it. It makes me heavy. I don’t like the bones in the fish. All my life I
don’t like.
-The fish that we caught the other time? Do you like?
-That was small. But it’s not a desire for me.
-What about sweets?
-I can get periods, that means one day that I can buy chocolate but that makes me sick.
Then I can for half a year without.
-This half the year you have aversion?
-Not aversion but it’s not a desire. I can eat chocolate but I feel it’s something with my
energy
Then I can eat one day a lot of chocolate but it makes me at the same time sick.
Then I tend to be constipated and depressed.
-Did you take Nat mur?
-I never took.
I feel that my psychotherapy… I have to provoke it.
To be in action, to sit there listening and analyzing that’s no good.
If I work, I can go home 10 hours then it’s OK, then I’m stimulated.
-This crisis of weakness is coming the last 3-4 years or it was all your life?
-No, the last 3-4 years but especially the last half year but I don’t get anxiety about my
health, it’s more like I feel I have to put some will power.
-To do something for your health?
-Yes, I don’t have the energy, I need something else to push me.
I can’t take it in front of me and use it.
-What about your feet, are cold, warm?
-Very warm.
-You stick them out of covers?
-Yes and I put all my cover away. All my life I have soles with thick skin and
I got some heel cracks and I think it was 9 years ago that I took Antim-crudum and
these cracks went away.
-I’ve not decided yet. Different thoughts.
Do you feel that there is a big disappointment inside you?
-It’s a disappointment.
-In which area? Or it is in all areas?
-No, when I work not. I’m not disappointed.
-Can you say the disappointment is from the emotional life?
-From the emotional life I’m disappointed, with my father-mother I’m disappointed, there
are people like bingo players, there is nothing in their life there is nothing there.
In a way I feel alone. If I come to a course, Acupuncture for example, and I feel that
something is suppressing me, not giving the right knowledge or something like that makes
me angry and sad.
There has been something in my life that I want to put my hand and be involved because
you don’t feel usually that feeling. It has been there but there is no force, it’s not very
strong. It has been but it’s in my phantasy.
When I dance and flirt and things like that, then I’m higher. But that’s an ego trip at the
same time. That makes me very good. I like music.
-What kind of music?
-Elvis Presley or Beatles more romantic, I like that, not the heavy ones from Elvis but the
slow ones. Popular music I cannot stand that.I would say romantic.
-You can weep in music?
-Very difficult. I can’t remember.
-To the school you have been good student or medium?
-I would say medium. I came to gymnasium because I jumped a class because of my
athletic part in it.
I learn very easily languages.
Then I went to Germany and studied Medicine and afterwards...
Very little force behind to come to the place I am now.
But the other things and I know my horoscope says that if I don’t take [?] it will come a
disease, very much resistance.
-You said something about spiritual practices. When did you come in contact with some
spiritual person or guru?
-In 1982 É went in Himalaya and then I met with Matthias Thomsen who has written a book
of life, he is very clearly speaking, I have been with Rudolf Steiner.
-Since when?
-Everything came after 1980. In 1979 I was in shock and then I went into that spiritual
-When you wake up in the morning you are refreshed?
-Not now.
-Did you have a lot of love affairs? Do you change easily or you prefer one?
-No, my first sexual experience was when I was 20. I had only 2 girls in my life.
-The first one you were in love, you married her? Because you were in love with her or
you just got used to her?
-We met at the hospital, then we made sex and it was a guilty kind of sex, it was too easy.
It was more a moral question for me. Then I make a car accident and the wife from the
other car came in front of me and I broke my sternum and then I got this feeling
again of being alone and I wrote to her. She was older than me and no future plans
We came together again, she was a little hysteric, funny and then she got pregnant.
That was the second time.
I thought about that when I was asthmatic period must have been some
I’m fastidious, I must take control of the right things in the right time but at the same time
it doesn’t matter. There is polarity there.
I feel a lot of Sulphur but at the same time I’m not sure. Medorrhinum is not working.
-Is there any peculiarity that you have in your system? Fear? High places?
-Not fear.
-Are you afraid about death?
-I can have some but it’s not a strong fear. I would say from high places when I look down
it’s not such a good feeling but it’s not very strong.
-Did you feel any time when looking down that you want to jump?
-No.
-This relationship with your mother has suppressed you?
-The first remedy it was Sepia but she is always negative thinking, very suspicious and it’s
only the family and the people around are dangerous. My father is quite opposite.
He is extrovert and he wants to make speeches and I can think he is a Sulphur but
he does not stand contact.
When he does something with his children or grandchildren he must do it with movements,
to get some activity around, he never sits and tells stories.
When there is this activity, then he can take it but never in a quiet position.
-You also want physical activity?
-Yes I like it.
-You feel better with that?
-I feel better with that. When I get some energy I start training.
-You give us problems.
-I have tried only 5 remedies.
-OK. Let’s hear more.
-Very difficult to take affection. He comes to a point where he can’t take it. He is scared.
-He cannot take affection.
-It’s not easy for me to give things away.
I first give some gifts when someone is marrying and it’s terrible. I always avoid that.
-Why?
-I’m not clear, I don’t know. When I was 9 years old, I was sitting in my room and saying
this is mine, this is mine…It’s coming from that period.
-Do you have any problem in wearing a tie?
-I can’t wear a tie, I can’t wear it!
-Is anybody who wants to ask a question?
-Is he eating in the morning? Is he feeling better after eating.
-I’m not eating in the morning. I go to work at 6 o’clock and I’m not eating before I go to work
-I’m satisfied with my life, my profession. The divorce
It is something to get close contact, to feel emotion, the affection and I chose two girls in
my life and they are that way. So there is something missing there.
-If you treat patients how do you feel then?
-It was difficult before but today I have trained myself not to take it. I feel good by that, I
can be a little tensed but I can take it and then I have to produce some negative thoughts,
some negative feelings, I can take it.
-If somebody gives you a gift?
-I feel that he wants to have more in one way, he wants the next step.
What is the next step? When the next step is coming, it makes me a little frozen,
unsecure.
-If they give you something, they wonna ask more?
-I’m not trustful enough. I’m a little suspicious, what is the next step, to lose my freedom?
-In your free days, if you start doing something then do you feel better?
-Then it’s OK, when I sit down and nothing goes, it’s too little activity, then it’s terrible.
-Is it hard to get start?
-Yes the first step, I don’t have the energy or the will power to take the first step. I know
what to do, to stand up and make some meditation, some walk
But the first step? It’s better to sit down with a beer and think that the world is going
against me, it’s easier.
-What about your feelings? Do you have strong feelings inside?
-No, it’s not strong. When I get in love, then it’s really strong.
But it must be a situation like that, mostly it’s flat, I don’t have strong feelings.
It’s something closed up here. I’m very tense in this part.
-Emotional tension.
-About the bowel, do you ever have like any other day or is it constipated?
-I can’t remember that.
The tendency is to get constipation, then I can fix it up and I get to diarrhea but then it’s
back again.
-Do you like to talk or do you like to stay silent?
-I like to talk, to be alone that’s OK but if I’m in a situation like it’s OK to talk a lot.
-...or it’s more a way to avoid?
-To avoid. If I’m in affection or have stimulated then it’s OK.
If I’m sitting alone, a day off, then it’s there and it’s complete nothing to go.
I had to work and bum like that with the same feeling.
-Sudden weakness?
-Sudden weakness, I can’t stand it.
-Do you quarrel at all with your wife?
-Not as general tendency.
-Does she say words that can hurt you?
-She can say that.
-You pay her back?
-If I’m all right, I can pay back. She says I’m lazy or things like that. I’m a little lazy but
that’s not so
Something which affects me and be angry, I can shout.
It’s heavy for me to take an affection or to take closeness or to take a gift but to be angry
that’s OK.
-You can smash her?
-Yes I can be really angry.
-The homeopathic remedy gives a non clear picture concerning the remedy.
Neither his pathology is clear cut.
We suspect something is going on, I won’t have in that stage any laborative test to show
some changes but definitely what he feels is right, something is going on with his health
which will end up into something.
Why this has happened? This is interesting in his case because it starts with a shock.
And now he is in a crisis where he reevaluates values of life, consciously and
unconsciously he reevaluates and he finds out certain things about himself and about the
world that he does not like and that realization has immobilized his defenses, his reaction
and will power.
He is going through I would call it a spiritual crisis at the moment, trying to find out what is
true and valuable, trying to sort out the truth… As a result there is immobilization.
Otherwise you would have enough power to take action.
He enjoys life in a way, he is successful but he is disappointed. That means he was
thinking other things and other things happened.
This is the result of a grief or spiritual crisis and the question that we have would be
whether we shall be treating this which comes about through the crisis or shall we go
deeper and find out what is the constitutional-let us say- remedy?
Practically we are thinking of remedies that will come, which is Nat mur, Ignatia,
Staphysagria that will treat the grief or remedies like Graphites, Mercury, Sulphur,
which they seem to be deeper.