As we said this is a picture of Stramonium.
The boy is disturbed quite deeply.
What is interesting for us to see is the contradiction between what he appears to be and
what he becomes when he is mad.
Ánd that is a characteristic of Stramonium, as we said before.
What I will mention in this case is that the boy seems to be a kind of a genius.
This boy you may see becoming very famous one day by bringing out an invention or
bringing out something new.
If that prediction comes true, then we may understand how close is a genius with a
hyper activity of the brain. Perhaps the hyper activity goes too far. With the Veratrum this
is the same thing, hyper activity of the mind that makes the person perceiving things that
others will not perceive.
Showing the potentialities of the brain also and the potentialities we have to involve further
as a human race.
And how much important it is to keep the mind intact.
This boy seen by psychiatrists, neurologists, later on when he will break things, he will be
put under sedatives and this boy that perhaps is going to become a genius, it is going to
be lost for ever.
Unless we realize, unless we see things like that, unless we perceive the whole situation
with Homeopathy, we will never appreciate what Homeopathy can do.
And this is very important.
In these cases when you see a boy with a pathology which is mental so much, you don’t
have a problem going high. You can go 50M, you can go CM if you want.
It is best, when you start the highest, to start with 10M. Why?
Because you do not know yet how many times you will need to repeat and whether you
have to go higher and higher.
Perhaps starting with CM, if we suppose that we have remedies that are really done
100.000 times, then it would be very difficult to find higher potencies that have a gap.
To find 200.000 times, 1.000.000 times. So it is better you start with 10M and highest
50M.
This is the follow up now John? OK, let us see.
-He took the medicine on February?
-Yes.
-Do you remember the date exactly?
-13th of February.
-Could you tell me what you have observed?
-Initially, in our first week just before he had it, he was very angry. I went back from
London, he wanted all the attention, he could not cope with not getting it and during the
first week after he had the pill, he was oscillating between being much more relaxed and
suddenly exploding.
By Wednesday evening I spoke to his teacher on the phone and he said, he is doing
marvelous and he was astounded, he was waiting to see how long it would last and he
said he really has improved enormously. He is doing excellent work and he said that
he realized he was one of the brightest children of the class. About a month after we saw you,
he said he realized this.
This is a very objective report from the teacher and what the teacher that he realized now
he is one of the brightest children in class.
He saw the potentials of the boy with one dose, Stramonium.
It is unbelievable how the balance comes and then a human being becomes a whole.
What Homeopathy does is it brings the pieces together.
Many times it has been described as if I become a whole, the action of the remedy.
The idea of unity, of one, it is the same idea and the idea of pieces breaking up together.
If we were united all of us on a cause and we said OK we spread Homeopathy all over
the world, within one year Homeopathy would be.
Not only we are not united, not only each one is individualistic but we fight between us.
There is a lot of fight, disunity and breaking up into pieces.
We cannot come into consensus and understand that our strength is only because we
are very weak at the point by being united; it  doesn’t matter what.
And then we become a healthy whole and we have to manifest that as a homeopathic
community at least from a level before Homeopathy. This is prediction, I’m telling you.
Unless there is a consensus, there is a unity, Homeopathy is going to go into very slow
pace. As soon as we feel all together, Homeopathy will go
It is the same thing as a cure. Pieces come together.
My mind was scattered, my heart was scattered, my body was scattered and they seem to
have come together, now they work to another level of existence all together.
-About a month after we saw you, he said he realized this. Because this particular teacher
has been teaching him since last September.
In the look of the child do you see something else now?
-Not so dreamy.
-Yes but what is more now?
-He is listening more.
-He is listening more but what is his inner state?
-He didn’t fall asleep.
-What is his look?
Serious but what I can see is anger. You could not see anger before in his eyes.
There is a little bit of anger now, it is coming in his eyes.
In these cases I have to tell you how it is going.
The progress is not always going like that, in a straight line.
You will see progress, regression, progress, regression and if you are observant and you
wait, you will see the regressions and you will not immediately jump and give another
remedy but you will wait and it will come up again.
It will go like that until you have a real relapse.
He may have a relapse at a certain point but it’s going to be after a year or two years or
after three years the relapse; it’s not going to be the next month.
The next month he tells you he was doing so well but one day he was very angry, it
doesn’t matter; two days he was angry, it doesn’t matter.
You will see the upwards and you wait.
-He was angry but not so much.
-What are your observations?
-He seems to be less frightened. About six weeks ago it’s probably the last time he’s got
so angry I didn’t know quite what to do. It was a kind of anger that was bitter.
And I was getting that quite a bit before. About six weeks
-That’s good.
-There were changes in my circumstances too which I know affected him because
I broke up with my last boyfriend not long ago before I saw you and I’ve got very close to
someone I’ve known for some years who used to baby sit the children.
And we intend to get married but it will take two years because I respect he’s got three
sons living with him. And that I think it’s done two things.
It’s given a security in the fact that the man who was coming to his life quite a lot,
he is more open and he’s very unworried by Thomas anger.
He can take it and he can a sort of brick wall against which he gets angry and
it’s getting strength.
So I can cope and I think he knows and he can unwind.
What do you think? The amelioration of the child has anything to do with the new love
affair that his mother has?
-No.
-Who says yes? Who says no?
Both hesitating.
If it has, then we are not going to see a relapse.
When you see the relapse, then what do you say?
Continue the relationship with your lover and he will be all right?
It doesn’t matter who is the lover.
When the child is in the state, he will kick, never mind the lover.
It’s in a state in which he cannot resist doing certain things.
She explains away all that because it suits her, not the boy.
From what I perceive the boy is listening with great concern what it’s said about him,
which he does not agree according to my understanding.
I don’t think he is agreeing about all that,
I do not see a sign of consent of what his mother
said. I perceive no sign that he agrees at all.
A new lover for his mother but she likes of course the man and she wants to present it
in this way and suits her that the child is more calm and she is better in her conscience,
so we don’t argue with that. It’s all right.
Though we should argue, though we should say OK, next time he is in relapse, just bring
your lover and calm him down or next time you are in relapse drink the water that you said
to me you are drinking a particular water, that’s why you are better.
And better because my mother is bringing more chocolate.
OK when you relapse eat more chocolate and see what happens.
Things for me are very clear and I have seen it again and again and again.
I’ve heard these stories again and again. When I see the relapse I say now what?
The environment is perfect; why he is kicking again?
-I can remember it happened on a Friday night. I knew something in him had changed and
I was actually able to present the fact that he wanted to stay at school because he was
not making noises about him leaving. Then he was to choose and he couldn’t cope, that
was fine and he could show them that he could stay.
I couldn’t have done that a couple of weeks before, he just couldn’t handle it and he
breaks into tears so I can’t do it but I said it’s all right, it doesn’t matter,
if you can’t handle
it, that’s fine.
You see the reaction? Why he didn’t react when she says I found a new father who is so
nice? Why he doesn’t do that when his mother said?
This is the story of the mother, not of the child and there is no child that can be attached
to a new father after a week. After a week he becomes calm. Well
Within a day when he saw him he is in love affair with him, with the lover of his mother.
We don’t buy those stories.
Unless we understand what is going on...
-So how is it now? The teacher said that you are one of the brightest in the class.
Do you like it?
-Yes.
-Are you encouraged by that or it makes no difference to you?
-It doesn’t make a lot of difference.
You see another intellectualization.
Before, the practicionner said, the child needs encouragement and he does not get
enough encouragement and therefore he is like bad and he is behaving like that.
Here it is with the best encouragement he can get and the child says, it doesn’t matter,
it is not so important. You see the intellectualization of things?
It’s a phlegmatic kind of reaction. I understand that but the boy that really needs
encouragement he will show some reaction. He cannot hold it back.
If it is a Pulsatilla boy that needs encouragement, he will not hold it back.
You will see the reactions in the child to tell you, yes he really needs encouragement.
Here we have a peculiar case, according to me it’s a unique child with specific qualities.
The qualities he has is a kind of wisdom which is much beyond his age.
I cannot admit that the remarks of the practitioner in the beginning, the boy needs
encouragement, he does not get encouragement and therefore that is why he is behaving
like that
This is what I’m stating now, I state this was an intellectualization, not the reality.
Tell me something else that you notice.
You see how much more frequently he is making that?
When I spoke about Stramonium, didn’t I tell you?
It comes on the periphery and you will see it as a tick.
What you see there it can become a strong tick and then come up to that extend.
-Are there others?
-Yes there are, it is Zinc, Cuprum, Agaricus, different but sort of that kind.
It is very little still. There is a small tick. What is this tick?
It is a signal which comes from the brain because of some thought.
The thought passes and there is a reaction and the reaction does not stay inside.
It goes to the peripheral nervous system and makes the tick, that is how more or less we
can explain.
-He does underplay the praises he gets.
The week we’ve seen he did a piece of work. We had a strange week because he did a
piece of work and he really exploded, he didn’t want to do his homework.
You see how he listens? With what attention he is listening to what his mother is saying
now? She is going to say something which I don’t like.
He does not have this cut off look, dreamy state; he is more in reality now, here.
-He had no supper, he refused to eat, spreading out everything.
He sat on the table and started doing his work  without asking of any help at all and
it was so good
If you watch his facial expression
The facial expression says, what my mother is going to say now?
When he realizes that what she is going to say is not something bad, he relaxes.
He changes. Do you see that? Who sees it? Who does not see it?
-The work was very good and when I asked him what the teacher thought of it, he said
What the teacher said to me was didn’t I tell you how marvelous this work was?
-How do you feel in yourself? Can you tell us?
Why you don’t get angry now? Do you feel that you try to restrain yourself or anger does
not come as easily as it used to?
-It does not come as easily as it used to.
-You don’t want to explode now.
-Not always.
-Do you restrain yourself at all if anger comes?
-Sometimes yes.
-The last time you exploded, you couldn’t restrain, six weeks ago?
-He was exploding regularly; he can’t handle the change, so coming to London.
It used to leave two hours later and sometimes more because he would do everything to
stop this going. This time we were about three quarters late and this was partly because
my back was been diseased and I was kind of slow.
You did get angry, you said you didn’t want to go and you kicked the door and you
threw a few things but it isn’t as bad as it was.
It’s still much more anger than his brother, I think it’s more anger than a normal child.
-The migraines that he used to have did not return? He did not complain of any
headaches.
-No.
-And neither he will wake up in terror or something
I think it’s enough. What is important is from the state where the teachers called the
mother and father and say the child has to leave the school, cannot stay in the school, to
another statement which says this is one of the brightest students.
That is a difference within a space of two months.
A year later he had a relapse.
He got again Stramonium and we’ll see now how he is going.
The mother knows very well the situation and when she will see the situation coming
back, then she will tell.
-between the mother and the child… sensation of isolation?
-I can’t see that very clearly. Maybe what you are saying is correct but what I see is the
child is also cut off from everyone, not only from his mother.
There is a cut off feeling in the child that he lives in his own world.
Therefore what you say is correct but it applies also to others, therefore I cannot really say
at this stage, whether there is a cut off feeling with the mother and taking it into
consideration very seriously.
In such cases we will see the real results in 3-4 years after the remedy.
When this child will have become a child that will go into another rhythm of working, all
together. It’s a matter of adjusting to new situations which come from the inside and
undertaking responsibilities, undertaking ambitions to be realized, undertaking emotional
contracts we have with each other. The mother wants me to do this and I have to do that.
When you are in a state of Stramonium, you don’t care about these things, you don’t think
about responsibility.
What you think is, your energy has increased, your mind is going completely bizarre and
you just hit.
From that state to go into all other conditions where we have a human being which is very
creative within the society, it takes long time.
This interview is I think on February and the original was on October?
Do we have the dates?
-Five months.
-Do we have another follow up?
-This is eight months after the original case. There is another one.
-Let’s see it.
-We just happened to meet at the station.
-Can you tell me what happened since that time?
-It’s a big change. A lot of different things happened to his life, he changed school.
-He has?
-He has. And he likes it. At the beginning of the autumn I knew that I was getting ready to
change and he suddenly was ready to do it, moving from a school of 200 to a school of
500 children and he is much more confident.
In fact he is taking the change easier than his little brother.
This school now is a regular school where there is no special at all methods.
-No problems apart from homework because he still finds difficult to face stuff which he
hasn’t met before. He doesn’t feel confident about. He was initially getting angry about it
-The work is different from the work he was doing?
-It is different yes and some of it he is so frightened about that he put up the rest.
He stated it quite clearly last week that
he was not feeling very well but not on the school
He wouldn’t miss the slightest opportunity.
Usually in the autumn he gets very tired
What is important here, I’m not going to miss school. A child like saying I’m not going to
miss school in spite of the fact I’m not prepared, it’s great.
Once he will go to Stramonium state, forget it, he will just say, I’m not going.
-and by this time he is like I can’t cope and
this is the first autumn for many years that he is not going down.
- Is he actually doing his homework?
- Yes. He has been kept a couple of times because he hasn’t done things.
I think he chooses to forget, occasionally.
He’s still not feeling to get hit on but much less so.
-How does he react if he has to stay at home?
-Not bothered, which is surprising.
-And what about leaving his own school, how does he feel about that?
-Very relieved because by the end the relationship with his teacher
was getting very difficult.
His teacher began more and more and it’s a man who had a huge ego and
it’s very exciting to be with but you had to love him and we didn’t love him.
When he went to a school camp, he still couldn’t handle be expected to be part of the
group all the time and
He became very tired and he went to bed which offended his teacher enormously
because his teacher did a story telling every night and he was going to miss it.
By the time the teacher said about this at the end of the report, I was so angry because it
was trying to make him improve his behavior by making him guilty and
I knew thought it very hard to get him away from that school because it was very important to
get him away from that teacher.
-So it was the right time. How is he settled with his new class?
-He seems to be fine. Initially he didn’t get new friends but in fact today when I pick him
up from school, he was friend with another child from the class and he’s been hit and
the boy get to me and apologized; he said I want to make it clear. It was wonderful to see and
the boys get contact and they are good friends now.
-How is his behavior at school? Have you spoken to anybody?
Let’s talk about something which is not in the case.
Why do you think the boy had a clash with his teacher?
The teacher seemed to have some kind of dislike for the boy and the boy had some kind
of dislike for the teacher. Can you imagine why is that?
-He is more intelligent.
-You can say he is more intelligent but the fact remains. The teacher if he really is an
egotistical person full of himself, he perceives that that child is a challenge.
Especially when the child will sit back and very quietly make a remark, which is very
acute, very sharp. He does not like it.
How the human element enters into a relationship and a misunderstanding comes and
there comes the fighting; it is just misunderstanding.
The teacher is not threatened, the teacher is responsible for bringing out more of his
genius, whatever it is. Yes, continue. You have a genius, he cannot say that and the child
leaves.
- And his behavior at the school?
-I spoke to a special needs school and they said they keep an eye on him and having
read what the school report and things about the fact and they considered to give him an
extra lesson, painting and major stuff like that.
They talked him and said no I didn’t want to get behind and he is doing fine and
although all the teachers are aware...
-He seems to be more tight. It’s got more order to it but it’s still very tight writing.
-What about at home? How is his behavior at home?
- It also occurs to me. Also I should give you an idea that
the hand writing it may depict to different remedies.
Perhaps for those who understand graphology, we may have an idea of the remedies by
different ways. One of the way it might be a sampling of finding the common features
between Calcarea carbonicas or Nux vomicas or Stramonium but especially among those
people who are mentally disturbed.
So she describes a kind of writing for him, which is interesting to have in mind and try to
see whether other Stramonium children have the same type of writing.
-He is growing up, he definitely is and I’m engaged to someone who I first got involved
shortly after we came here, that was in February. And he somehow helped me with the children
it was Christmas in fact and he has been looking for a father figure and
he has found one. They do have rows but this was fine because within minutes it’s all forgiven
-And so the relationship between you and him?
-It is much more relaxed. He’s being more responsible. He still can’t be generous except
when he is feeling very confident.
He still only point out that, you know I have back problem, if my back is bad,
suggest him to do but he will eventually do it, while before he wouldn’t.
He would create such a scene if I went down. Now I can go down and he is OK.
- Has he been violent towards you? Because a lot times he has been hurting you
-Hardly at all. He does little things and I explain that’s really hurts and would you like
me to do it to you and that’s it. He finishes it.
-What about the kicks? How does he behave afterwards? Is he sorry?
-He hasn’t come to that yet.
It was a day that he was very angry and I told him something to do, he forgotten, he
didn’t want to do it, he went upstairs and he kicks the door very hard.
And  when he came down, I said put the books back and he did it,
which again it wouldn’t have done it six months ago.
-Good. What about his sleep? How is that?
-That is better and it seems that he is not waking up every morning. He is tired but it’s not
that very heavy I can’t face it. In fact sometimes he is up already before I go to wake him.
-Really and he stays in bed?
-Yes he just lies there.
-And you have to go and touch him to get him up
-He got the point when I said
-And that worked. Generally he sleeps without disturbing at night?
-He is not anymore.
There is one symptom, the way that the mother describes that the boy wakes up in the
morning, which says unrefreshed, you will find it...
It is not recorded with the Stramonium, unrefreshed sleep.
But Stramonium has it. So you will see many times it does not have that symptom.
It is not recorded, it does not mean that the remedy does not have that symptom.
It has not been recorded.
The child used to be very unrefreshed. I can’t… This kind of description.
-And he goes to bed early?
-In fact when he goes to bed at night I read and while I read his…is on the
floor but he is so brilliant, he is doing something.
Eventually when I finish the story I want him to be in bed but it’s not very big resistance,
its’ like more like the average child.
-What about the relationship with the other children?
-There are times where he has been difficult and Matthew felt that he couldn’t
take anymore. Certainly last year I was having to have Matthew in one side, I was
saying you must give him space, I try to keep them separately
-Perhaps, I do not know if that eventually will go away or will change.
We may say this is a strict of Stramonium.
-Do you think this child will grow up and be a Stramonium all of his life?
-That’s a good question. Whether this is what we call constitutional Stramonium or
whether Stramonium was printed upon him, as a second remedy.
I believe that Stramonium in this case is quite deep.
I believe that maybe for years he will be under the influence of Stramonium and perhaps
he will develop another remedy but quite later. It is not just one time Stramonium.
-The other remedy was present in both and we just remove it away once again?
-Right but I’m not sure whether he was born Stramonium really, the first remedy was
Stramonium or with the first fright he became Stramonium.
What is very interesting in this case, the most interesting part for me was the fact that for
a certain period of years, he was a Stramonium with different symptomatology than after
these years.
In the beginning you remember fear of the dark, waking in fright, shouting, dreaming,
having all these night things happening to him, these they subsided and the violence
started and the child started kicking and doing violent things.
So we see how the remedy develops in stages.
We do not always find the violence in Stramonium, as I have said, but you may see it in a
night terror.
If the child was brought to me at the age of 1,5 I would have prescribed Stramonium.
And the child definitely would have been spared everything of what is going on, the child
would be a normal child.
It is much more easy to cure a small child than curing somebody who is 14 years in that
state.
Don’t forget; you remember I asked him a question and I said, how do you feel in the first
interview?
He said I’m feeling calm. I said to him is this a good feeling or a bad feeling?
And he says in between.
What the child is living, he is living a hell.
When you will have lifted him, it’s like taking him from hell, out.
Don’t get the idea that he is calm but what is calm?
It is like a lake which you have fire underneath, great fire and at a certain point it’s going
to boil and it’s going to be like a volcano.
It’s like this surface calmness, which feeds underneath the volcano.
The volcano is there all the time, the possibility of explosion is there all the time.
That is a feeling and that’s why he says good feeling being calm? No.
I remember a case of Ignatia, a severe chorea case since childhood.
She came and we prescribed Ignatia and after 1-2 months she rushed unexpectedly into
the office, she says I must talk to you.
All the rooms were filled, so I take her to the kitchen.
The kitchen was for special consultation. Roger knows.
Special consultations where ministers were coming and I would say do you mind if I take
your case in the kitchen? No, we don’t mind.
That was the spare room, where I used to do my consultations.
Otherwise I was inside the other rooms but no room for me.
She comes into the kitchen and she tells me there is something I’m frightened about and
I said what it is?
She says I feel calm.
I couldn’t understand in the beginning.
I said is this a good feeling or a bad feeling?
She says it’s a good feeling.
So why you are afraid? Because I never felt like that again before.
She has never in her life felt what is to be calm.
That experience I’m calm again the next day I’m calm...
What is this? It must be something which is unhealthy.
This boy has lived from the age of one into that state. It’ s not going to come out from one
day to the other, out.
It should have been one more follow up one and a half year later where his mother will
describe a kind of relapse.
This is the last follow up which I have so far. The last follow up from Stramonium.
-What happened since then?
-About March-April I think the pressure of what was expected from the school started to
come into surface; he couldn’t keep up the pressure of work, he didn’t want to take
responsibility for homework.
We were having battles at home and there was particular weekends and it’s got very
difficult. He was getting more angry at home and when I went to a parents meeting
You see what is happening? First he doesn’t want to take responsibility.
You see where he breaks down, he does not want to take responsibility anymore.
Then the second thing he becomes more angry in the house.
But in the house he was so nice. Now why?
-I realized that he wasn’t asking for help at school, he was hiding
a back roll, trying to avoid the problem to a certain extend and
the teacher said it wasn’t that he was lacking intelligence,
it was that somewhere on the line he wasn’t connecting it
-So he found it very difficult?
-Yes.
-You were not doing the work because it was difficult?
-And you had changed schools, haven’t you?
-Yes.
-How long by this time? Are you enjoying the school?
-I decided I will do call a social work and I described what was happening and it took 3-4
weeks because people had gone away, it was Easter.
Finally they put me in touch with the child-psychiatrist,
he is specialized in adolescence and he said he wanted to see him.
That was in April. Has been seeing him once a month since.
-What was happening at home then with the anger?
-I found [?] He was resisting any obligations that he didn’t want to face.
He was resisting any obligations. You see how the relapse starts?
They have a report from previous school and they say this is a problematic child and in
the school they know this is a problematic child.
So they advise the parents to find a social worker.
Is the social worker going to work with the Stramonium? Good luck.
-He was doing anything, door slamming... Everything required a lot of work just to make
him face getting on with a task that he had to get on with.
-You were aware of this behavior?
-Yes.
-What spark was for that behavior? Why you are doing it?
-Things are that I can’t do them. I want to do something else.
-So you are not being allowed to do what you wanted to. It’s only that?
-I don’t know.
-What are the things that you are not allowed to do?
-Use computer and my electromagnetics.
-When you were prevented from doing something that you feel you should be able to do,
how do you feel? How does it make you feel like?
-I feel like hitting.
-Does this make you feel better?
-Yes.
-And afterwards how do you feel if you have done this?
-I can’t remember.
-You don’t remember how you feel or you don’t remember what you have done?
-I don’t remember how I feel.
-There has been changed since I phoned you and I wondered about whether to come because
I see the progression but the psychiatrist thought it would be a good idea if we came.
- What sort of ground has he been covering
- Certainly when we were talking together he was talking about complete
dependence on me and his total inability to take it on himself.
You see once the relapse starts, you see the chaos, the intellectualization, the
explanations that are going to be given?
Everything was fine from September until April he goes to school, he takes responsibility,
he even says even I’m not prepared I go and suddenly now he does not take
responsibility, he becomes more angry, his teachers are annoyed and the psychiatrist
says there is a big dependence of the child to the mother.
What shall we do about that and blah, blah, blah.
All right the blah, blah, blah but I would like to see the effect.
Eventually give him Aloperidin… to sedate him finally.
This is the usual story with such children.
Why now he is in relapse? Why the lover of the mother cannot balance the child?
He is still there, he still loves the child very much.
It doesn’t matter. These stages are not so superficial; there are other stages that are
superficial stages but not these conditions.
-This is going to be a slow process to get him to take responsibility.
This is going to be a slow process to make him again take responsibility.
It was not slow when he was given the homeopathic remedy, he took it immediately.
He is going into a kind of relapse. Am I going to give him a remedy or not?
That is the main question.
Definitely the child is going to a kind of relapse.
The best policy will be to wait, as much as possible, to see whether this relapse by itself
is going to correct itself and may come up.
How long you will wait? What you do?
You ask how much is the same as the original state? Definitely if it’s the same as the
original state a month, you give it, no question.
If the mother hesitates at different points, it’s better to wait until you have
a full relapse.
The best thing to wait, is he going definitely towards Stramonium?
Most probably there is no question, the anger but maybe the anger is so much and there
are other changes in the boy that may indicate another remedy, not in this case.
But in another case you may still see the anger but there are other changes that will be
indicated but now the case is going into Hyoscyamus or to Belladonna or to Pulsatilla, it
doesn’t matter.
But this boy is going towards Stramonium, you will not perceive changes.
My suggestion at that point to the practicionner who takes the case is wait a little bit
further and then repeat the initial remedy.
He is going to be in that kind of relapse I believe before he goes out of Stramonium, he is
going to be 2 or 3 times more and this can be within a period of 4 to 5 years and then
eventually he is steady on that remedy and then perhaps the next remedy may appear,
which will be great.
-How many weeks would you wait in this state?
-I would still wait another month.
-There is a danger here.
-Yes you are correct. The psychiatrists will say whatever. If people do not understand
what we are trying to do, they are deserving their fate but to change your principles
and your understanding because you will lose the patient, this is the wrong way of thinking
and you should never do it for this reason.
You may do it also because you are concerned about the child, it’s is going to be lost.
Then you explain.
You say this is my understanding that if the child takes sedatives, it will go into much
worse state. This child after six months of sedatives, he will go to tremendous
aggravation. It will go crazy.
-The initial potency?
-The initial potency 10M you repeat it and then you go higher.
-What would happen if you give the remedy too early?
-Most probably it would aggravate the situation, the child would keep on in Stramonium
and perhaps one day the mother will come and say he has broken all the glasses in the
house. He will be facing all the situation quite violent.
-For a long period?
-Not for a long period perhaps but it will aggravate for one month, two, three months even
it will aggravate the situation.
Then you will have to pass judgment to know whether you should again give another
potency, which is higher than the previous.
We gave two times 10M, we go to 50M now, during the aggravation, when the picture is
really very strong.
You gave by mistake and you relapsed your case completely. Now that is the time you
can go on a higher potency and give it again and this will antidote the whole situation.
So far what we used to do is wrong remedy, go to another remedy.
You gave Stramonium, it was worse with Stramonium.
And you never think of giving Stramonium again at this situation.
It’s not the case of Tuberculinum that. Do you see the difference?
Here you know that this is the remedy that has acted and this is the remedy which
aggravated and brought about a relapse.
Then you go higher and you give it. Do you understand?
Is anybody who does not understand? Please tell me I did not understand.
Otherwise you just wasted your time, effort, money.
-I think
-I’m talking about if Phosphorus was your right remedy; it was not your right remedy.
Therefore it’s not going to act, it’s not going to do anything.
If the remedy is the correct, Stramonium and you repeat it untimely, too early, you
aggravate the case because still it is Stramonium.
When the case is aggravated then you give it in higher potency, then you have results.
If the remedy was the wrong remedy and you repeat it, you have an aggravation, you
augment the aggravation.
-You might do the repetition during the aggravation?
-Even during the aggravation. You wait to see first if it’s going to act the remedy, maybe
it’s an aggravation and after a week the child is going to be better.
You wait for a week, two, three weeks, no effect, four, five weeks it’s doing worse, worse,
then you give it.
These cases I hope if we had a hospital, we could show this kind of severe cases where
there is life threatening and we could demonstrate what we have to do.
-When you give Stramonium too early and you have an aggravation, then you give
Stramonium once more?
-During the aggravation of the second repetition.
-The third time?
-On higher potency, as long as you wait enough on the second remedy to see whether
it’s going to be curative.
You know, you have the experience already. We gave a remedy, he was a little bit
disturbed for one week; after the week he started settling down. So you have this
experience.
The second time you do not expect that he will have an aggravation on one month.
If you see the aggravation is continuing, that means you brought about full relapse.
Then give a higher potency.
-Do you think it will be any…  for repeating in a low potency?
-In a low potency we try sometimes.
There is another possibility, if the relapse is not really great and still you feel it is quite
strong the relapse, you may repeat instead of high potency,
you may repeat a few doses of low potency.
Let us say Stramonium 12C. You give it for 10-15 days and see what happens, whether
this low stimulation, brings about a balance.
More or less, we cannot judge exactly what is happening because we do not have the
measures.
You may. Most of the times the aggravation is less than the first time.
When you repeat it timely, the aggravation is less than the first time because definitely the
first remedy has lifted some of the heaviness of the case.
I would like to make a remark now concerning Stramonium.
I would say that I find Stramonium in late years much more indicated than my first years of
practice.
I don’t know whether I learned to recognize it more easily or whether there is really a
development of aggressiveness in our societies and we have the appearance of more and
more of such remedies as Stramonium, Hyoscyamus, Nux vomicas.
You see the Nux vomicas were always very prominent.
The aggression that creates problems in the human body were taken away mostly by
Nux vomica.
Today we have much more aggressive remedies being indicated and also we have
remedies which cover pictures of drug abuse.
Also what I want to show you again is the time that you have to wait.
Remember, Bill Gray left his cases for two years, he returned and found all of them cured.
Maybe it’s a little bit of exaggeration in that but just stick that into your mind.
You gave a good remedy, there was a good reaction, leave it alone.
Don’t repeat it, don’t give other remedies. This is the idea.