This seems to be a quite deep, there is a hard mass very painful?
-Yes.
-Quite big, about 3 cm big.
-It became worse by the evening.
-When did she develop this?
-She had it for about 8 years.
-What you see there it is for 8 years, this tremendous boil inside.
Did you see the color?
The color now it's not blackish but it is towards that.
What happens is that he squeezed it and aggravated it and created a lot of pain.
That's why he brings the case, he is an American practitioner and this is his wife
and he brought the case because of tremendous pain.
The woman can not sleep because of tremendous pain. Burning pain.
And we are called now to treat this boil.
In such a case if you do not find the remedy, what might happen is a little bit you
ameliorate the pain.
You can give Sulphur in this case or you can give Lachesis, what she will say is that
the pain for 1-2 days was less and then it came back and then you give Sulphur.
But nothing substantial.
The thing is not something that came 8 months ago, it's 8 years.
Did you find the follow up?
What happened is that I stayed in the United States for 5 weeks.
This case I have seen it the second week, so there are several follow ups, 2 days later on,
7 days later on by her husband.
He gives the follow up and eventually she comes herself about 3 weeks, after 18 or 20 days.
It's a pity, it's a pity, I hope he will find the 3 week follow up
and you will see where this boil is.
Let us hear a little bit the story because through this story,
you are learning a new remedy, Anthracinum.
-I squeezed out quite a bit offensive smelling, white sebaceous matter.
-What smell?
-It smelled like very strong cheese, offensive.
You see it smelled like strong cheese, listen now why I did not give Hepar sulphur.
This is the smell of Hepar sulphur, why not giving Hepar sulphur?
It is very important.
And also the fact that it smells very badly, it shows perhaps a process which is quite severe.
- It smelled like very strong cheese, offensive.
But from what I've seen in other sebaceous cases it's exactly the same smell.
Then the next day again it was still... always it would be something oozing,
so I squeezed it and it became about 30% of the size that ordinarily is.
This is roughly the size than ordinarily is.
-Like that all the time for the last 8 years?
-Yes.
-And this redness was always there?
-No, never discoloration, never pain.
-Now there is an information.
-So it was painful the second day, so we decided to leave it alone but it was small.
I could feel all the context of the cyst.
Then we didn't touch it and slowly over the next 3 days, she was not feeling well.
-It was still oozing then.
-Then what happened was by Wednesday morning, she was having a headache,
she couldn't make any decisions, she was dying for open air and had a feeling that
she wanted to go outside in the cold.
-At 7 in the morning when it was really cold and I felt the cold great, wanting to cry.
-Emotional, so I gave a dose of Pulsatilla 1M.
What this case will be teaching us eventually will be that Anthracinum
in its mental picture it is quite like Pulsatilla. That's one lesson. What is Pulsatilla?
It wants to cry, it wants window open but she will feel more the cold.
In the reaction she was having eventually, you will see other symptoms coming up
which are very interesting and which look like symptoms of Natrum muriaticum.
But you see the dullness of the mind, the difficulty to make decisions?
-I gave one dose of Pulsatilla has done good work for her in the past
and within a half hour she was...
-I didn't have a headache or stomach ache, I was in charge, I wasn't emotionally dispersed.
Another lesson we have to learn.
What he says is, Pulsatilla has been working for her all these years.
He is giving Pulsatilla and something was happening. She was feeling better all the time.
It brings about some kind of amelioration with a remedy which is similar
but not the Similimum, which is the exact remedy that we need to give.
And why this case was treated for 10 years with Homeopathy and no deep changes
but still she kept on with her life?
Because we don't know enough of the picture of Anthracinum.
The heart mass, the picture of Pulsatilla, the desire for open air,
the headaches that are associated with this and also the indecision
come to form a picture of another remedy.
And you will see other symptoms as well.
-It started getting red, painful, hot.
It reminds me of an animal, here I am.
Did you hear the intensity? She said it feels like being in a fire, like an animal.
The animals they stand, to make a mark on the animals and she feels that feeling.
Both they described the pain.
The intensity of the pain will become also characteristic of this case in order
to decide one remedy or another.
If she was Hepar sulphur, would she say desire open air? No.
Hepar sulphur likes to be warm.
The burning pain is it characteristic of Hepar sulphur? Not so much.
It is Arsenicum, it's Anthracinum but not so much Hepar sulphur.
It was a difficult case, don't think that this case is easy.
George saw the case and gave her Anthracinum?
No, it took a long process of thinking before I concluded on this remedy
but because the remedy was correct, you will see the effect.
-She is not sleeping well, anybody who touches it...
-Do you feel cold?
-No.
-It still feels warm?
-It feels warm, no other way.
-Emotionally I feel much better than when this was draining.
By evening it hurts all the way and down and there and then when I lay down
for the night it feels the best, when I lay down for hours it feels the best.
-Although the sleep is not really good.
-Any other symptom?
-Just it's always hot and burning.
It comes in waves, sometimes it feels really hot and then others it just aches.
She says it comes in waves, that points out to another remedy which is...
Pain comes in waves and with this color which is bluish black and bluish red
the remedy is Lachesis.
-Just it's always hot and burning.
It comes in waves, sometimes it feels really hot and then others it just aches.
-Do you have any anemia?
-Yes, she is pregnant now.
-She is always anemic?
-No.
-But actually this is her third pregnancy and it's the best pregnancy by far.
With good homeopathic treatment.
-I did go to India recently, came down with hepatitis, not yellow eyes
but itching all over, terrible itching.
And that was 80%.
-She has a new remedy between Dolichos and the Pulsatilla, that was 2 months ago.
She was more anemic in the last pregnancies her hematocrit is 34,
she would be around 29 or 30 in prior pregnancies, so for her it's probably reasoned.
Do you have the analysis?
There was a discussion in the class and I would like to show you the discussion that took
place and I decided on Anthracinum.
Do you have the fist follow up?
It is her husband talking about the case 2 days later after Anthracinum.
With Pulsatilla she says it's stopped discharging but the pain was much greater.
When she came the pain was excruciating. The husband told me she is very patient,
she can stand a lot of pain and because she is not shouting,
do not think that she is not in very great pain. She is in very great pain.
That is now the follow up 2 days later.
-She took the remedy on 14.00. Anthracinum 200 and she felt dizzy very soon
after she took the remedy and she was about to get a headache.
The infected area became very, very hot after the remedy.
And she felt...  contractions when she was walking around.
That persisted pretty much till today.
One hour after she took it, she went to sit in the park and she said she had
more peaceful concentration than in days and she realized that something was right.
She said she didn't realize that she had lost that until the peace returned.
By two and a half hours after the remedy, she was exhausted but she had
more pain free movement of the neck.
Suddenly by 7 in the evening, 5 hours after the remedy the muscles that were very painful
involved with the ulcer were much better.
And she had an aggravating feeling of peace and sleepiness.
She said I'm a walking zombie where the previous night in the same time
she was worse with pain and restlessness.
She said I feel like I'll sleep forever.
The first night she looked forward to the nighttime because she had very bad nights.
And she was confident that she would have a restless sleep and she had very improved sleep.
Then the next day there was definite improvement in the sense of the pain being lessened
but you couldn't really see any difference.
Now yesterday it's spread out, it involved more area especially extending to the neck.
It was more painful again though not like before the remedy, it was worse than the
preceding day and she experienced throbbing pain but not that burning that she had.
Today it was down in size, yesterday it was purple and she didn't want to touch it at all
and then today it was down in size, softer and more flat and after an hour
it began exuding small amounts of the same infected discharge.
It's harder and more painful while she is up and moving and definitely better
while she is sitting.
She had some headaches today but it is much less painful than yesterday still.
This actually is the fourth day that he talks about the case and about every day progress.
He says actually some interesting things.
What is interesting to hear in this case is that she became sleepy.
Sleepiness after a remedy, desire to sleep and sleep for days perhaps is a good sign and
you have to understand that this shows that the remedy is acting deeply.
Another point that was good is the sense of peace that she felt.
She had a sense of peace inside her and also you see that the actual mass becomes bigger.
Don't worry about that, as long as the other signs are present.
The actual size became bigger, that is no problem as long as there is a sense of peace,
there is sleepiness, there is a sense of well-being or mental-emotional amelioration,
a regression of the tumor.
As long the general state of the patient is getting better,
both of these actions are acceptable.
In this case it followed the first course.
-3 days after the remedy was given...
-For how long it was there the cyst?
-For 8 years.
She is much better, every day better, there is ups and down but today she is doing
extremely well, yesterday it opened up.
Friday she felt... actually there was an evolution...
After the remedy the pain were dramatically and there were immediate effects that were felt.
But to be brief the actual thing became large, it became really large, it was 5-6 inc.
across and people would look at and they didn't believe.
But she was comfortable in comparison.
-It's very strange that the size is bigger but the actual pain is reduced.
-Now what happened was that by Friday, 2 days ago, there were a lot of sensations,
not hot burning that was there but prickle sensations and a lot of pressure and you could see
at certain points where it was beginning to get right, in different areas
where little white areas were forming and you could see underneath.
Yesterday after she got out of the bath it was starting to discharge.
Maybe she lost a teaspoon of pus and today maybe a table spoon.
It's way down compared to what it was, there is no pain whatsoever or very mild
and the skin coloration started to come in around the edges.
She is a prover, she always has that with the remedies, she has proving symptoms
all of which are very strongly representing Anthracinum.
She had some dizziness all the week, headaches and in the afternoon very irresponsive
to work which is strong to Anthracinum actually and if anything she is a workaholic type.
Then she gets restless at night and at 3 in the morning she sleeps better.
Her appetite has been decreased, she lost a couple of pounds
but overall she is feeling very well.
-Great.
That must be the 7th day, already it has started discharging.
It discharged for another 10 days. It discharged quite a lot of matter.
In the beginning the matter was offensive, eventually there was no smell from discharge,
it was discharged without smell but the most important thing is that this lady
had a tremendous amelioration.
If you can find the follow up, there are some more follow ups I think in paper.
I hope you will find it because it is very impressive.
This is completely gone but this is not important.
What is important is that this woman had gone through grief 18 years ago.
15 or 18 years ago, long years ago she had gone through grief and because of that grief
and after that grief she was never able to have her feelings back.
Her feelings were cut off in a big manner.
She was not able to really enjoy life and not only that but she had
not exactly an aversion to sex but she had really not enjoyed sex ever since that incident
where she had that big grief.
Nat. mur. was given, Pulsatilla was given and several other remedies were given without
ever touching the case.
After Anthracinum she felt everything was coming back and for several days
she was crying and crying and she would have pictures of the past coming back.
Pictures of the past would come up and her husband would call me and say,
she is crying all the time, she wants the window open and what shall I do?
I said console her.
He said that's very strange because yesterday, I was in the class and he was coming and
she was crying so much that he telephoned her and tried to talk to her.
After talking to her he said I was a little bit upset.
In the night I would go back to the house to see how she was because I felt
she was really bad crying all the time.
He had spoken in the middle of the noon, in the middle of the course
and then the course was finished and he went back home.
He said I was amazed to hear that she said that after talking to me, consoling,
I was much better.
Now you will think that this is a case of Pulsatilla and you go and prescribe Pulsatilla.
No, this is wrong.
When you see all this upheaval happening inside the patient, wait and you will see miracles.
If you give Pulsatilla in order to stop her crying, you may spoil the case.
In this case I doubt if one dose of Pulsatilla would have really spoil the case
but you may spoil the case.
She went on crying for 7-8 days.
She cried and cried and cried exactly the way that Pulsatilla does and Pulsatilla
was helping the case according to her husband but never touching the case in a deeper level.
What was interesting is that what I have been teaching all these years that sometimes
it does this work.
In my teachings several times I have said that you have a case with different layers.
That's very interesting phenomena which I have seen many times.
Here we have Anthracinum, maybe Pulsatilla, Silica, Calcarea carbonica.
This is actually the real state of the patient, that means the patient will need
first Anthracinum, then Pulsatilla, then Silica, then Calcarea carbonica
in a course of 2-3 years before this person is really cured.
Now you never discover Anthracinum because it is a small remedy, a difficult remedy and
you prescribed different other remedies.
That is every time she has something severe or a cold or something in disposition or
a general symptomatology or acute symptomatology, a picture is here formed.
The one time is Pulsatilla, the other time is Lachesis, the third time is Gelsemium
and every time you give the remedy this goes away.
This layer upon the layers goes away with a particular remedy and you have the impression...
What she says it's absolutely here.
He feels that this woman had good homeopathic treatment because every time she was treated,
she was treated successfully.
I had this and I was treated, I had that and I was treated.
But the actual peeling off layers had actually never started.
It is now with Anthracinum that he has the first deep remedy that takes away that first layer.
Everything else that happens upon that layer, it was taken care.
This woman could have upon that chronic state, could have lumbago.
Rush tox and lumbago away. She could have headache, Pulsatilla.
Pulsatilla takes headache away.
She has a common cold, Gelsemium. Gelsemium takes the cold away.
Everything happens from Anthracinum upwards.
But never from Anthracinum downwards.
Once you see this kind of deep reaction, don't be in a hurry to give a remedy.
You would be surprised the way he describes the case how close she was to Pulsatilla.
Everybody would say she is crying so much, she is suffering so much, why don't you give
a Pulsatilla to relieve her? Wrong.
You should never give Pulsatilla in this case.
Console her, yes. You can give all these measures but don't give a remedy.
As it progresses the energy is strong, the mental clarity became very acute,
she never had that clarity before.
The emotions became alive, the sexual sphere was open.
She says I'm enjoying life as I've never enjoying before.
That is the action that you expect from the right, what we call, constitutional remedy.
Whatever you call it. Here it is a confusion of terms.
Let us say that this person really needs Anthracinum, Silica, Pulsatilla and Calcarea.
What can be said would be the constitutional remedy out of the four?
But we call it a constitutional remedy once it affects the whole organism
and takes away a layer.
The next time that we shall have a Pulsatilla situation and Pulsatilla will go deeper,
then we can also say that we are treating this person constitutionally.
It happens sometimes that the person from the beginning of his life till the end of his life
will need one remedy, it will be a Calcarea carbonica case.
Every time he has a relapse, it goes to Calc. carbonica.
But these cases are very few.
Usually the cases are of that type.
Our generation is too ill, too sick to be treated with one remedy.
One remedy on a whole life of a person means that the person is really very healthy and
they are the cases where you treat and you are happy, you are satisfied,
your patient is satisfied, yourself is satisfied, you say you are god,
you make a miracle and things like that.
It doesn't happen every time, it doesn't happen every day.
-I had the impression from what you were saying that had Anthracinum being given
before the sebaceous system became inflamed at the time when she became emotional and
she was given a Pulsatilla but you were referred that Anthracinum would have acted at that state.
-No I said that about 15 years ago when this woman had an emotional trauma,
after this trauma she went into an Anthracinum state.
So she was in an Anthracinum state for the last 15 years in her life.
And if Anthracinum was given by that time, the cyst would not have developed
and she would have been spare of all the suffering.
She said I was not living before, she could not even remember how life was.
When she came back into life it was another experience all together.