This is a good teaching case, very good teaching case.
It is teaching us a lot of things.
How would you evaluate what is taking place in this man?
If this man was given the correct remedy from the very beginning,
would he have arrived at that stage?
-No.
-So he could have avoided it with the right remedy, he could have avoided all this.
But now humanity understands that, understands Homeopathy it can prevent all this?
It doesn't seem; otherwise we would have schools, we would have Universities,
10 years of studying and then after 10 years, you come out and you treat.
Now you come to a seminar, 2-4 weeks, you go to another seminar, let me know everything,
just tell us more. What to tell more, there is no more to say.
There are a few things that we have to understand and to have them in mind
when you are treating and then study your Materia Medica and then under supervision
you see what is happening and what is happening with the right treatment
and eventually you become a homeopathic physician.
And that's why I have all these problems which I have.
What is happening in this man now?
Most probably he has not received the right remedy on the right sequence of remedies.
Maybe one remedy would not be enough, maybe a sequence of remedies, maybe 2-3 remedies
he needs but in the right sequence.
Have we started correctly?
No, we started incorrectly and unfortunately...
Why Tuberculinum? There are some people who they teach first you give Syphilinum,
Medorrhinum and Tuberculinum to clear up the miasms.
To everybody first and then you start proceeding with the case.
But before you take the case, give these 3 remedies to clear up.
You see how he is clearing? For 5-7 years he is clearing up and still he is not clear.
He has 40 bowel movements, it is not clear, 7 years and it's not clear.
That's why I get mad, not at people never. I've never spoken against anybody.
I'm speaking about principles, don't misunderstand me.
I could have made a mistake like that easily but I would have reasons and I would explain
why I gave Tuberculinum.
And I would like to know the reasons why he gave Tuberculinum.
The only remedy that was given with some reason was Phosphorus, as we shall see.
But is this a Phosphorus case? That is the question that we have to face eventually.
What is the remedy?
It's a great puzzle.
The first question that comes to my mind is why this whole thing started.
He says it started at the age of 31, I understand it is 7 years.
I want to know what happened at the age of 30, 29 just before.
What took place and he prevents my question further and he says, wait a moment
the actual pains had started when I was 14, I had the tenderness.
Do you understand also another thing? What happened with the peritonitis?
He went into peritonitis. What happened?
After given Phosphorus repeated doses 1M, 10M, again 10M then he went into peritonitis.
He had this flare up, this severe pain on the right side of the abdomen with fever
and he went to the hospital with peritonitis.
What happened?
-Perforation.
-Why perforation, it has anything to do with Phosphorus?
-Ulceration.
-Ulceration has anything to do with Phosphorus?
We don't know but we may say it has to do with Phosphorus, repeating Phosphorus
without being needed.
I want to know what happened before that.
Why this man is so severely affected in his physical body? Why?
Let us hear the story.
-I had a terrible aggravation.
My wife thought I was gonna die, I was so weak but I kept working all the time
and studying Homeopathy, 30 hours the week just study, study, study and work at the same time.
-When did you get involved with the spiritual group, that means when you were 20,
can you say what group it was?
-It was transcendental meditation.
-In the beginning you felt good with the meditation?
-I felt very good, I became a teacher, I devoted my life fully trying to help the world from suffering.
-Can you say you were disappointed from that? Disillusioned?
Here we have an important information. What is the important information?
-Disillusioned.
-No, it is not.
He wants to help the world, the humanity. He got disillusioned yes but he wants to help the humanity.
So you start forming an aspect of the personality of the person.
He is 20, you can not say he went there because he thought logically it is better...
No, I don't want logical explanation. He is 20, he wants to help the humanity
and this is the tendency of many young people of today that have been disillusioned
with the situation in which we live in this world and they become either anarchists or guru prone etc.
And they want to change the situation, we are in a terrible situation, we are going into pieces,
this is my evaluation of the world at the moment. We are going with great speed into pieces.
Now this everybody knows.
What he is telling is, he is a young man I can't live in this world, I have to find something
and then some guru comes and says here I am, I'm going to give you enlightenment,
breathe in and out. This is not...
I know everyone here has gone through experiences and I have gone through the experiences,
whatever is the experience, one way or another. Why we went?
Because the world is in that state. Why the world is in that state?
A crazy world, why? I wrote a book about it, you can read it.
It is a very bad state of health. Humanity at the moment, especially the Western civilization
is at the worse state of health in general. That's why we see what we see
and not healthy things are happening.
So this man wants to help the humanity, it is an aspect of this man.
Most probably he was teared into pieces by looking at something that helped him very much,
affected him very much. What are these things, we want to know.
We want to understand more of the personality now,
what is this person who is having that disease?
Can we find the remedy that fits that personality? Is it an Aurum, is Argentum nitricum or what?
-In 1978.
-That is 10 years ago.
-Disappointed and feeling of great loss because this was my whole life.
-The tenderness started really to bother you how long after this disillusionment?
-About 2 years after.
But what happened was that my wife and I, didn't have any children until 1981
and I was in the labor with my wife and that was devastating for me.
I got fright, the suffering upset me so much that I didn't even think,
I had no thoughts about sex for a year and a half. Never.
I just could even think of inflicting that pain again and being involved in that pain.
You see how the information is coming? The information is not coming through question,
it is forth coming by his own volition. He gives information which is very important.
What he suggests, the first time he says I want to help the humanity,
so we see the element of want to help, the sympathetic element, which we call it.
And as a second information comes again that sympathetic element, he is in labor with his wife
and he is devastated, the experience lasted for one and a half year,
he can't even think of having sex, inflicting pain.
That is an over sensitivity towards certain things, towards pain, pain from others,
they can not tolerate. We have another point of the aspect of the personality now.
-Crying?
-Crying also yes. The experience is so intense.
He says for one and a half year I didn't have a thought of sex.
He is a man who is indifferent to sex. So for one and a half year he has not thoughts of sex.
So we would like to know how much indifferent to sex he is eventually, to evaluate that information.
If this is a man who has desire for sex, the sex desire is very strong and
because of that incident that desire is taken away, that means the effect is pathological.
It is not normal that a man will see a labor and behave in this way and have this effect,
unless he is over sensitive towards that aspect, the suffering of the human being.
It's not normal, otherwise all the gynecologists would not been able to have sex
for the rest of their life.
And gynecologists are not famous for that.
I don't know if there is any gynecologist here but the information is that
they are not famous for that.
Therefore this becomes pathology, it is a pathological sensitivity, we write it down,
we keep it as information.
The sympathetic element, affected by seeing people suffering.
I hope you excuse me for being over sincere.
-I've been involved in that pain and all women I would look at them and think, my god,
this pain, too much pain and then my daughter wasn't a very well baby.
So I slept 2 hours the night and I would be up all night with the baby
because my wife would feed her and I would walk on the floor all night long, trying to help.
I was completely broken because I didn't know how to help her and that upset me.
-Why you went into the labor with your wife? You wanted to help, just of curiosity?
-I wanted to be there to give her support.
You see how I try still to confirm, why you went there, what you wanted to do?
It was curiosity perhaps? I just put a question that may minimize the impact
of the symptom that he is relating.
I do not jump into conclusions and say this is this remedy.
No, I want to test it, is it or it is not?
And I'm ready to see the symptomatology and to reevaluate the whole case from
another point of view all together.
Because by that time, as you understand, I know the remedy, I understand the remedy
but you will see the questions. You will see what happens.
-That she would feel pain and you wanted to support her, hold her hand and things like that.
-Yes she almost bite my thumb. She needs support, particularly during pain,
she doesn't like pain.
-She doesn't like pain and you were there hearing her screaming and you could see
the labor actually.
-Yes and crying.
-You were crying and sobbing?
-I wasn't sobbing.
-Did you feel at this moment that the doctors were doing something wrong
or they did not handled properly the case or you felt helpless?
-I felt helpless, completely helpless.
-That nobody could do anything at this situation, she was just in the hands of the god.
-That's right and I decided that I will learn something so this will never happen again.
Another point. I will learn something, so this will never happen again.
What is important in this? Why do I ask about the doctors?
Is he blaming the doctor, does he know better than the doctors or not?
-It's not that.
-If there is a kind of indignation.
-Watch people or watch the situation.
-You are close.
You see different remedies will react in a different way during the same set up.
If he is Nux vomica, he will not cry at this moment most probably.
He will give help perhaps to the doctors, can you give something to stop the pain?
He will comment something.
If he is Phosphorus, what he will do?
-He goes away.
-He may faint Phosphorus under these circumstances, he may try to help the doctors
to help his wife, he has to do something to help the doctors. What can we do?
Can we do something? Wait a moment, something has to be done.
He stays paralyzed there and he says god I do not want this to happen again.
I learn something now, so this will not happen again.
That is a reaction which is unique. For every individual, that is his uniqueness.
We have to take it and evaluate that symptom.
Yes but we do not intellectualize, we do not explain. We say what happened?
I stayed there helpless and I said to myself I don't want this to happen again.
We have an information that he went into a transcendental meditation
because he wanted to help humanity, he can not stand the pain of others
and he wants to help humanity.
Most probably this is the explanation, we'll hear more.
-Then we had the baby, the baby wasn't well, I said I have to find something,
I have to learn something so I can help.
-To do something so that this will not happen again. Did she have caesarian?
-No. She had very long labor, very painful.
-She was teared in the perineum?
-Yes and the baby came out pressed down into the coccyx for hours,
so it was very painful for her.
-This daughter was your daughter?
-Yes.
-You said you lost your daughter.
-That was my first daughter and then we had another baby in 1984 and the day
before she was going to be born, they told us she can't live.
And then I learned Homeopathy to try to help the children and I couldn't help her
because she couldn't live.
-She couldn't live why?
-She had no brain.
-She was missing a piece of brain.
-I can't think of the name.
-This incident did not disturb you as much as the labor? The labor was a terrible experience?
-The labor was devastating. The loss of the baby, I cried a lot and still today upsets me.
If you are observant, he says I cried a lot and still today upsets me. How much?
Very much, medium or very little?
-Upsets him a lot.
-Upsets him a lot. Who says medium? Who says a lot? Who says little?
We have some objective things here. First of all he cried.
The fact that he cried it means that he brought out his grief by crying and that is a good symptom.
It is not a very deep grief which is affecting the organism, it is affecting the eyes
and the lacrimal duct and it is getting out.
This is a good reaction, natural reaction for a person to cry.
The baby is not born, therefore he is not connected with the child, he is not connected really.
Therefore from that objective fact, the grief is usually minimized,
unless one does not have any child and he is 44 years old and he can not have another child.
That can be a big grief but that's not the situation.
This is a situation where he has a child already and they told him it is born dead.
The third observation is that in spite of saying it is upsetting me,
the actual physical condition is not changing; it remains the same.
Therefore we do not have a real grief to treat.
Our mind should not go to grief because of that reason, maybe there is grief for another
reason but not for that reason.
-Before you said you went to transcendental meditation, what led you there?
Can you give me a little bit of the history of your life?
-As a child I was very sensitive child, I had a lot of religious feelings,
I used to go to church a lot, I felt very close to god, I was going to be a priest
and that's all I wanted to do, to be devoted to god and just do that.
-Since childhood. You were serious or you were playing with other children?
-I had these periods of intense devotional feelings and then I would have periods
of great wildness where I would shoplift, steal things, I would break into places
and I would do that and then with the religious feelings which overtook me,
I would never do that again.
Even today I have very wild tendency, when I have more energy, I'm very wild.
-What are you doing?
-Doing things that are very exciting that other people might not want to do.
I'll dance in public, in a shopping center.
So far we have been thinking of a remedy. Which is the remedy?
Causticum, very good. I told him the whole class will see the remedy, I promised him.
What he is saying now at a certain moment I was praying, I was serious, not exactly.
Why I'm thinking that? The possibility of Aurum. Was it an Aurum child?
He said he was praying though the feelings of praying were not the feelings of Aurum
because Aurum does not go so easily into ecstasy.
It is first the deep depression and then the relief through praying.
He says he is a character who is mixed, he goes to extremes.
I would say an extreme character, he goes and steals and then he prays and then he goes
and begs into places and then he prays. He goes to extremes, an extremist.
But what he says is when I have a lot of energy, I do things. What do you do?
I get up and dance. A lot of energy, you get up and dance...
Which is the remedy that your mind goes to?
-Tarentula.
-Why Tarentula? Because he has done the other naughty things, mischievous things.
Is this a case of Tarentula?
-No.
-Don't say no. I could not say no.
I want to know, I want to find out, is this a case of Tarentula, yes or no?
Maybe I was mislead so far. I did not explain well the situation.
-Tarentula dances when it hears music.
-Platina.
-Sepia likes to dance yes. We will see whether he is Sepia.
-Lilium Tigrinum?
-Sepia is not so extreme.
-I do not know whether I have given you wrong impression about Sepia or other teachers
or the books but you have the impression that Sepia is a very dull individual,
without love, without affection.
We know that, it is like that and sometimes the mind is very foggy, very slow.
This idea is completely wrong especially young Sepias, children of Sepia, 10, 20
that they have not been affected on this hormonal level and the mental-emotional level,
they are very excitable children.
They can do things, they can feel very happy, they can be the center of attention of friends
and they can reach a place where they will get up and dance and will be very vivid
and when the emotional level is not affected, you see a lot of love.
-I'll dance in public in shopping center, if I feel like it, that's what I will do.
Now if have 4 hours of sleep, now I wake 5 times a night,
but if for some reason I don't wake up for 4 hours and I get 4 hours unbroken sleep,
I wake up I feel more energy, I dance around. Wild energy.  I dance around.
My wife says this is god's way of stopping me from hanging off the chandeliers, Crohn's disease.
When I'm well, I'm like a bulldoze.
-What do you like to do? Mostly dancing or breaking in shops?
-I go into places and steal ice cream or I steal cigarettes and go and have a smoke.
-Do you smoke normally?
-Not now, this was when I was a child, I smoked until age 19, then I stopped.
-Now can you steal now, can you enter a shop?
-No, no.
-What actions can you do? You become violent at all?
-No.
-When you have the energy therefore, you have a lot of sexual energy?
-I asked my wife, tell me objectively because I have to tell George.
She said, right now you are not well. When you were well before,
you were Rambo, a lot of sexual energy.
Girlfriends that I used to have would tell me, you have just so much sexual energy.
-Now you do not because you are tired.
-Yes.
-When you have a lot of energy in general how do you spend this energy,
what mostly you will do to spend your energy?
These questions are for what? My mind has gone to the possibility of Tarentula.
From Causticum it has gone to the possibility of Tarentula and I'm trying to confirm Tarentula.
If this man is Tarentula, a lot of sexual energy, we know how much energy it has Tarentula,
how much sexual energy and excitement and loud music and vibrant music,
where they vibrate the doors and then they feel excited, happy and they can dance.
Also Tarentula is mischievous.
Tell me something, is he telling the truth?
Is he honest?
-Yes.
-Very honest, how do we know it?
Because he has mentioned things that somebody else would not dare to mention.
These countries like America and Canada they don't keep secrets.
They will give out the whole story.
It is a healthy attitude to be able to balance with the craziness
which is going on in this part of the world.
Canada not so much as much as Berkley, Los Angeles, San Francisco...
Let us see if he is Tarentula.
-What mostly you will do to spend your energy?
-I will organize things for Homeopathy because that is one of big loves of my life,
I'm involved with another meditation group, I work very hard on that, I have a project
where I raise money for deaf children, I work on that, things like that.
-What about dancing that you said before? This happens very seldom?
-Let's put it this way. The organization that I become involved does chanting
and I get a great feeling of ecstasy, joy, joy.
I have to get up and dance. Nobody in this group does this except me.
I dance, I just can't sit there, it's too much joy, excitement.
-Are you enjoying that?
-Yes.
-You don't feel any timidity because you do that?
-Initially I felt a little bit because nobody else did it, everybody was just sitting and chanting,
I was the only one who was dancing, I felt a little bit strange but now I don't care.
-Music brings you into a state of...
-The music I listen to is melancholic religious music and it gives me feelings of joyfulness
and devotional feelings.
If I'm not feeling so happy inside I put on George Harisson and he sings melancholic music,
how much he loves the Lord etc. and I just become overwhelmed with the feeling.
-The sound is too strong, too high or you want it normal?
-Normal, I don't like strong music, I find it agitating.
-Were you ever violent with somebody?
We were talking about Tarentula because of the getting up and the hearing of music and
the dancing on music but the kind of music is not the kind which Tarentula would like to.
It is the opposite; so we can not confirm Tarentula but still I want another question.
I want further to find out and that's why I ask this.
-I don't have a tendency to violence, to attack people.
When I was young 18-19 I would get into fights but then where I come from,
everybody gets drunk and gets into fights.
-Tell me some more about yourself.
When you were a child you had this different kind of reactions?
-Yes I was alternating between the two.
-Too devotional and too...
-I would have devotional and I would have the other. There was periods when I was 9,10,11
where I had sexual thoughts before going to sleep and that's the only way I would go to sleep.
I didn't know what sex was but I would just think about the sexual parts.
-What age?
-Starting about age 9, 10. That continued to about age 25, I suppose.
In which remedy do we see these sexual thoughts before going to bed in order
to be able to calm down and sleep, we see it, they have it a few remedies.
Mostly we see it in Staphysagria.
Is this then a Staphysagria case?
-No.
-Wait a moment, you didn't hear the whole story. Is this a Staphysagria case?
This is an idea, don't say no beforehand. Let us find out what is happening really.
We are trying to understand, the human being is so complex. Never mind how well we
may describe the picture, still we can have loose points which we don't know yet and we
have to be aware and not to lose important points and lose the thread.
Because the thread in this case is three remedies, in order to cure him.
If you lose the thread, you start with the wrong remedy, the wrong time.
You lose time, you lose energy, you have a lot of suffering and that's why we are asking
whether this is a Staphysagria case. Let's see.
-25 I suppose. It doesn't enter my mind anymore.
-Sexual thoughts do not come?
-Not very much really since age 25.
-What else about your character?
-I'm sympathetic, if I see somebody who is hurt and I can't do anything about it,
I  immediately go and help them, especially a child or if I see suffering.
Just before I came here I was watching a program of what happens in Burundi in Africa,
I saw people in the hospital with their hands chopped, it haunted me for days and days,
the thought would come back.
When I was watching that case of the little boy, inside oh no, no, it's going to be cured
and 5 billion other people, there is so much suffering and it bothers me so much.
You see again and again he turns to the point of sympathetic.
And it comes out and he does not present this point because he wants Causticum
because he would have taken it himself.
Neither he has presented the case in such a way he thinks it's Causticum,
presents the case in a Causticum manner because he would have done it before
with the other homeopaths.
What comes out therefore, it is genuine information, because he knows Homeopathy,
all these doctors with a lot of questions but from time to time,
his own initiative brings out information which is very important.
-It hurts your feelings and you cry?
-I cry.
-When you see injustice?
-Injustice really bothers me. That's one of the things that bothered me in the Organization
I was involved in. In 1975 I was working in the printing press
and there was some injustice went on and I got furiously angry,
I've never been so angry in my life. A week later I had asthma.
And it was only later that I realized it was from the anger.
-Did you express the anger? Did you voice it?
-Oh yes. Strongly, I curse a lot, I do now too.
-The people that you curse you were dependent upon?
You see again it comes strongly the case of Causticum, injustice but I put a question
straight forwardly to him, though the answer comes so strongly.
I have never been so angry in my life.
He says when I saw this injustice going on, I told them and all that.
I still want to see the degree of the intensity.
How much he risked when he did that?
Did he risk his position in the Organization?
He saw an injustice, he couldn't hold himself, he knew if he would tell what he thought,
he had to leave. Did he go so far as that? That is a strong point.
So I'm going to ask about that now.
-The people that you cursed you were dependent upon financially?
-Yes, I depended upon them financially, that bothered me.
I don't like to be in a position of dependence.
-But in spite of being dependent, you still curse them, you couldn't retain.
You felt that if I speak badly to them, then I will lose my work?
-I was too angry. In this Organization I was considered quite radical
because I would always speak my mind.
That isn't right, you shouldn't be doing that, that is wrong, that person is too weak,
you are taking advantage of them.
Never mind how much I can describe Causticum.
Whether we give Causticum or not it doesn't matter,
this is what I'm trying to describe in the lecture. The government, down the government,
I'm an extremist, throw a bomb, finish with them.
-Would you physically almost want to attack the person?
-Almost, I don't physically attack people but I'm very irritable.
-I see that you had an incident where you most probably you became...
-This time if I saw somebody hitting a woman, a man hitting a woman,
I will physically intervene or a child, very upsetting.
Here what you see is the sympathetic element because he is Phosphorus
but there is another element which is much harder here.
Do you see the hardness? If you hit somebody who is weak, now I'm going to kill you.
This is the attitude of Causticum. Phosphorus will try to love both.
It's different, most soft attitude, most soft approach though he is suffering.
-Did you read religious books when you were young or was just the religious feelings?
-I would go to church a lot, sitting in front of the statues and I would go to communion every day.
-You felt relieved by that? What you felt? Why you did it so frequently?
-I felt that that was what I had to do. I didn't feel that this makes me feel good.
-Tell me about your family? How you lived?
-My father was very mentally unstable, a lot of depression,
he was in a mental hospital several times, very physically abusive of all of the children,
never my mother. She said she would kill him in his sleep.
He never was abusive to her but he was very abusive of us physically.
-He hit you?
-Yes.
Kicked us , punched us and I was so afraid of him. I didn't speak until I was 3 years old
and they thought I was dumb.
-He didn't speak till he was 3 and they thought he was dumb.
Why? Because he got great fright from his father. What is this?
Does a Causticum stop talking or he talks?
-Talks.
-He talks rather than keep his mouth shut, difficult to suppress the Causticum.
The Causticum also can be suppressed and then he goes into stuttering.
Which is the remedy which is suppressed?
-Staphysagria.
-We see signs of Staphysagria from the very early age.
Let's see a little bit more.
-I was so afraid of him. I didn't speak till I was 3 years old. They took me to a doctor,
he did all the tests and he said, there is nothing wrong with this boy.
The doctor said do you have a husband who is very angry man? He said he is afraid of him.
He won't talk because he is afraid of getting trouble. Then I was very dreadful at his presence.
-Do you remember this consultation yourself?
-No, my mother told me and I wet the bed until I was 13.
During one period for months and months I can remember, he would come in,
feel the bed if it was wet, he would pull me out of bed, bit me, throw me back in the bed, curse me,
bit me and always when I was wetting the bed, I had a dream of falling.
And every time I was falling, I was wetting the bed, it happened every night.
That was till about age 13, then at age 14 I started getting this tenderness in the abdomen.
-Do you have other brothers, sisters?
-An older brother and two sisters and a younger brother.
-The others are suffering with any serious disease?
-My sister next to me had ulcerative colitis, when she was 20, my other sister has psoriasis
and my older brother has very sensitive abdomen.
-Your mother had any problems with intestines, digestive track, duodenal ulcer?
-I don't think so but her brother was operated recently. She thinks it is Chron's disease.
-Her brother who is how old? 60?
-About 60.
-Your father you said he was in a mental hospital?
-2-3 times.
-What was the diagnosis?
-I never learned what the diagnosis was but to me it seemed like a paranoiac
schizophrenia. He sees people, watching him all the time. Do you see that person?
He is watching me. Ever since I was young, he is watching me
and I had a lot of conflict with my father.
About age 15 I never talked to him anymore.
I'd been in the same room and never talk to him, as if he didn't exist.
Till about age 19. I would talk to my mother.
-You had very strong feelings against him.
-Very strong.
Can anybody give me the indication, what took place in him? In his organism?
At the age of 13 he started having the tenderness and he did not speak to his father
from the age of 13 and for 5 years.
He is living in the house but he rebels now. He has been hit, beaten by his father,
he was really badly molested and only when he is 13 he stops speaks to him and the pain appears.
What it means?
-Suppressed anger, it went into the liver.
-Yes but from another point of view, from the remedy point of view,
how could we explain the transition? We see a picture of Staphysagria in the beginning
and then he rebels.
The picture Staphysagria subsides and the Causticum picture starts to come up.
Why in our books we say Causticum and Staphysagria are complementaries?
That means you give the one and the action of the other is complementing the cure.
They are complementary remedies, they complement the cure.
We call it complement each other, that is the wrong expression.
What we mean is that they complete the cure. This is the idea.
You give one remedy, brings the organism up to a certain extend and then another remedy
which completes the cure. That is the idea.
With this boy we see a Staphysagria picture, underlined the trembling from 3 years old,
he can not even open his mouth and talk because he is terrified.
Inside this boy's mind is how can I get out of that situation? How can I get out?
And then eventually there is a battle on his organism and the organism finds a way
on the mental level to find a solution.
Once this mental level is not confused anymore and it is clear, I'm going not to speak
again to my father and it's clear, it takes the decision, then the disease
is going to another level and it is somatised, going to another remedy.
Which remedy? The rebel remedy now.
How is it possible that we have complementary action between Staphysagria and Causticum.
That is how it is possible. Many times I have explained in lectures this story,
now we see that story.
Staphysagria picture turning into Causticum picture.
Now we are almost sure. Let us see a little bit more.
-Anger, a lot of anger.
-Yes.
-Today I'm quite irritable, I find I'm quite irritable. My wife and daughter don't take any notice.
I just say why the hell you put a knife in my bag, you gonna cut your hands if you reach
that knife. My wife goes...
I tell my daughter, clean your room up. She blows at me, they don't take me seriously.
I know that they don't. And I say to my daughter I'm so irritable, no, no you are not irritable.
Fear of criticism, I have it quite strongly.
If I'm criticized it feels like if I have an ulcer inside my emotional body
and somebody stuck his finger.
What is he describing?
Causticum, we have a grand symptom, keynote which says pain feels like raw, the skin is out
and then you are touching a wound and that is how the pains of Causticum are felt.
Now what is he saying? On the emotional body I have an ulcer which somebody is touching,
it's raw, he doesn't mention the word raw but it is as if raw.
This is exactly the description on an emotional level. It is painful and somebody is touching,
it is an open wound.
It feels like an open wound, I can't touch it, it says the Causticum.
I told him the whole class is going to find the remedy. You will hear that now.
-An ulcer inside my emotional body and somebody is stuck his finger on it. It hurts.
If I do something emotionally stupid, it hurts. I don't like to do that.
-And the pain, this tenderness what kind of pain?
-It is a clumping pain, twisting my stomach and when it is really bad,
it feels like my intestines are all stuck together and if I move, even if I don't move,
it feels like being ripped apart.
-Now you have described the physical state, you have frequent stools that you can not retain.
-That's right, I get these collics before the stools and I rush to the toilet,
this colic goes away but I always have discomfort in my abdomen.
-Before the stool you have a pain and as soon as you have the stool, the pain goes away.
-It goes away. The cramping pain but I've always, there is always pain down here.
-How many stools the day you may have?
-At least 20. I took account before I left Canada but that's good.
-That's the best.
-Yes, sometimes it can be up to 40 and I don't know what causes it. It is just water.
-Does it come out with a lot of gas?
-No, I just sit down and psss... a little bit and then 5 min. later back I go again
and a little bit and 5 min. later back I have to go again.
-If you retain it, you may lose it.
-I can't retain it, it is not physically possible. I have to keep paper in my underwear
and I have to hold my hand on my anus. I can't control my anus.
-What kind of diet do you follow? Do you follow a diet?
-I don't eat high fibers food because it makes stools.
So I try to eat massy foods, my food desires very strong, salt, 4 underlines,
I salt everything before I eat it. Potatoes, my wife said when I'm in Greece
they want one potato because I eat potatoes every day.
Season foods, I cant' stand blald foods, just can't stand them. It has to be season.
Milk, I love milk but I can't drink because if I drink it my anus is even worse.
Cold water, icy water, I don't like room temperature, it's terrible, I won't drink it
and I drink about 3-4 lit the day of water or juice.
Why do I ask? I ask about desires and aversions because the Causticum picture is very strong
and therefore I expect to find in the Causticum picture desire for salt,
aversion to sweets, to confirm.
Causticum does not like sweets, usually in 98% of the cases do not like sweets
and of course Causticum likes smoked things but here we have very strong thirst for cold.
Have we been mistaking a Phosphorus for Causticum?
If the symptom thirst for cold water was a symptom without a reason,
we would have to think twice.
We have loss of fluids very much, 20 stools have to be replaced and it is water,
water which comes out, a lot of water has to be replaced.
Still it's important but not so important as to overturn all our prescription.
That is how one is mislead to Phosphorus.
Thirsty, desire salt, thirsty for cold water, Phosphorus.
Steals ice cream yes? Why not? That is Phosphorus.
But we say in our teaching that Phosphorus and Causticum are inimical remedies, why?
Because they look alike. Is that what everybody knows?
You see how close the sympathetic element, the thirst, the salt?
-Highly seasoned.
-That's why it is important to know the essences, what we call the essence.
They say Vithoulkas is speaking about the essences, he talks about his own phantasies.
These are the phantasies, if you don't have the phantasies, you have the results.
You chose either the phantasies or the results.
And when this man will be better, we'll say oh yes he reached an age now
where he had to be better. I know this also.
And Colocynthis may come into the picture eventually because again it falls
into the picture of Causticum, Staphysagria, Colocynthins.
It is a kind of circle that these three remedies they follow each other.
We thought of Medorrhinum, he said oranges? He didn't say that.
We have the possibility of Medorrhinum also because he shows some elements of Medorrhinum
and later on he will say that at a specific period in his life,
he used to eat 15 oranges the day. You will hear it now.
-What about Veratrum?
-Veratrum, that's why probably he was given Veratrum with the same thinking without an effect.
-Aversions, I'm aversed to coffee, never drink coffee, I just can't stand the taste of coffee,
I'm aversed to alcohol, beer, whisky, liqueur, wine.
I cant' stand the taste, it's too bitter for me. I can't drink it. I like fat, not a lot.
I was vegetarian for a long time and then I just got fed up with everything and I decided
that I will eat meat and I eat it. I'm going back more or less being a vegetarian
because I found I don't like meat very much.
And after I have this severe flare up, I always get craving for fish, oysters.
I get two tins of oysters and just eat them. Smoked oysters, just there.
-It's very interesting, you hear desire for fish is Phosphorus.
Oysters, Phosphorus has an aversion to oysters but then he continues smoked...
-Smoked oysters and salted herrings. I will eat tin after tin, salted herrings, fish,
I will crave fish very much, smoked fish. My wife is saying it's fish time,
now you are getting better.
-As soon as you feel better, you go to fish?
-When the pain is very intense I couldn't eat anything because it would make it much
worse and I would have 4 days of intense pain where I would be just riving around.
I can't do anything, I can't sleep, just very irritable, exceedingly  irritable
and then it goes down by 40% in intensity.
Then irritability becomes a kind of weepy. This is always happening to me.
My wife says you sound like a Pulsatilla.
And I get weepy and then I go to a depressive state and then I start craving fish,
that's the fish time.
-What about sweets?
-Not so much.
-What about cheese?
You see I don't want to hear desire sweets, so I let him talk, talk
and say what happened with the sweets, he didn't even mention desire of aversion.
I'm curious, I want to know that's why I put a straight question
because it's another confirmatory symptom for Causticum again.
Strong aversion for sweets the Causticum.
So he gives not an aversion really but still he doesn't like very much.
-Strong cheese, I like strong cheese and ice-cream a lot, strawberry ice-cream.
But I can't eat very much.
-Do you eat ice cubes?
-I would suck ice cubes, it makes my mouth cool.
We have the possibility of Medorrhinum.
-When I was up to about age 24-25, I would eat 15 oranges at one time.
-What age?
-From being a child up to age 25.
-I want to ask a question. Did you ever have gonorrhea?
-Not that I know.
-You would know if you had it.
-The sexual thoughts stopped?
-The sexual thoughts stopped at 25 why? Can anybody tell me?
-It's the oranges.
-No it's not the oranges, it's very simple.
I have not discussed with him and he can say yes or no.
-He got married.
-No, the sexual thoughts in Staphysagria and other remedies they come
when there is not satisfaction, actual satisfaction.
If the real physical satisfaction is not there, then we have sexual phantasies
and this also leads to masturbation.
Once sexual function starts being satisfying, the thoughts vanish.
So it is the time when sexually he is satisfied, he does not need a substitute.
What do you think about?
-Right.
-He said it's right. Did we speak about this before? It's obvious.
Why I forgot to ask about whether he had gonorrhea?
Because I saw through questioning that there is no Medorrhinum.
So it went out of my mind even to ask.
His state of health together with his brother, sisters is not a very good state of health.
His father is very sick, mentally quite disturbed but his mother saves the situation.
The mixture of the two and they do not go towards mental derangement the children.
If the mother was also with a severe chronic disease, the children would have gone
on the mental problems.
So the mother saves the situation here.
We didn't discuss about that also about his mother but I would consider his mother quite sane,
quite down to earth.
In order to have this kind of results, colitis, where the disease is able to somatise
his mother must have been down to earth woman, strong woman with strong mental-emotional body.
-She is very strong, she lives with me.
-Let us see.
-Up to about age 25 I will just eat oranges all the time.
This is a hint for Medorrhinum, we have to explore the possibility.
-For amusement when I was young I was very bright, at school I got very high marks,
I  used to read an encyclopedia and I would come home and take the encyclopedia
and sit for hours reading, just all that knowledge interested me so much.
-Do you have a time where you always feel better or worse?
When you wake up in the morning or the afternoon?
-Not a time. If I do physical activity, if I move all the chairs in this room,
I would be suck for two weeks, I would not be able to get to the lectures.
-Worse from physical activity?
-Much worse in energy level.
You see the question was for Medorrhinum. If he was Medorrhinum,
he would give straight amelioration in the evening.
After sunset I feel better and all that. Then we have to restructure all of our thinking
and go further to see what is aggravation, amelioration from the sea etc.
Let's see.
-How you react to climate?
-I hate the cold, I'm very chilly, I catch colds very easily.
If I go to sleep in a draft for sure I wake up with a sore throat, then I get a cold,
then it's on my chest. I don't like the damp.
When I was in England I hated the damp weather.
-This is not a good keynote for Causticum. It is the opposite.
Causticum likes damp weather. Let's see.
-But I also don't like being in a sun, I never sit in the sun but I like hot baths.
I never go to sea. We were in Greece for six weeks, I went swimming once.
I can't stand going swimming.
-You can't stand going swimming.
-No, no.
-In the sea in general you don't feel better?
-No.
-Worse from the sea?