This is a case of a child, it is a male child four years old
which came on October 1977, he comes for the first time.
His mother said that he is suffering with a skin eruption for the last two years.
Dryness of skin is underlined twice, there are white areas of skin which are wrinkled
and the skin is worse on the inner surfaces of the joint, here and back.
Worse in general in lower extremities and in the lower hands.
Certain points are more swelled up and more red, the skin is dry and rough.
The itching is quite strong, underlined twice.
The dryness of the skin is also underlined twice in the whole body but mostly in the places
where I told you. The itching is worse before he goes to sleep.
Many times it's bleeding because of scratching.
He has used different ointments, cortisone as well, without any effect.
The mother says that he is a quiet boy, he has no problem, he is fastidious
and especially in his dressing, he likes to dress well.
The fear of dogs underlined once, fear of dark, it is a sensitive child
and he is easily hurt, if somebody hurts him. He is shy.
There are no aversions and there is only one desire which is underlined, it is ice-cream,
underlined once. Fish, milk, omelet, no underlines in these.
His thirst is normal, nothing special with temperatures.
Five months old he had a generalized staphylococcus.
-Skin infection?
-Yes. He sleeps well and wakes up well.
Do you like this case?
What it appears to be wrong with that case?
-It's very difficult to get the sense of the child.
-That's one.
-We don't know the causation.
-You see a case like that which has no real, vivid symptomatology, a generalized skin eruption
which is also not strong appears that something is lacking in vitality in that boy.
Which shows that the condition is quite serious and the fact that is not suppressed
it's perhaps because it is too generalized, too much in the whole body.
Whether it is the boy's defenses or the doctor who is taking the case, we don't know.
Actually this taking of the case shows a poor rapport between the doctor
and the mother most probably because it is not the child, it is the mother
who gives the information.
And a mother who is not very much observant and you have this case to work with
and you will see how many mistakes we have made in that case.
I would like to see whether you will make the same mistakes.
You want to analyze such a case.
You look in your Repertory if you want some information, the most logical...
but you don't like the logical now, you say George is prescribing.
But the remedy which covers the totality, if you take it, it's Phosphorus.
-Because of the fear of the dark?
-Yes but this is what it's written there.
Anyhow all these prescriptions that you made are wrong and mine was wrong also.
But mine always when I prescribe unfortunately is quite close.
I shall give you the report after Phosphorus 1M I prescribed.
Most probably that was a poor rapport of the mother and the doctor
because the next visit they make, they decided to change the doctor
and to go to another doctor of the Center.
They have the possibility to change over, the patients.
-What's the date?
-The date is the 24/11/77.
The report says up to the 20th day the child was quite well. I don't like to hear that.
See the continuation. From the 20th day onwards the skin cleared up completely.
Until the 20th he was quite better but after the 20th he was completely well.
You don't like to hear this reaction in a child who is suffering for two years
with such severe eruption. You don't like it.
You want first the eruption to come out and then you are happy and satisfied.
Otherwise you have to wait.
There is only left some itching only on the hands but it's scratching quite a lot in the hands,
especially in the night and he may wake up in the night and scratch.
General psychological state quite good. That's very strange.
Appetite is better and pick up some weight and generally he is in good condition.
Desires and aversions the same. Sleeps well.
In the place where the skin was worse, it starts the color of the skin to be the natural type
and it has a dry eczema on the back of the hand. This is the report.
Now what did I do?
I said to you because I know what has happened later on that this is not a good reaction
but when you really fist see it, you may be proud of your prescription.
You think it may be not so severe as I thought and it maybe has just gone away
and different things like that but I don't like this.
Being aware of that, is it possible that you prescribe any other remedy?
Do you have any information to prescribe anything else?
-No.
-Do you have any information to change the remedy or to repeat the remedy?
Never in such a case.
You have to wait, you have to give placebo and see what happens.
So that was done, placebo.
The interesting thing is that in the first report you see the eruption, what you expect
it might be a suppression and you don't see any irritation inside, that is peculiar.
He comes on 4th of January 1978, two months and a half later and he says
that the condition of the skin has remained steady.
That means that the back of the head and the itching and the skin is better.
10 days ago he had a staphylococcus infection.
-Of the skin?
-Of the mouth.
The doctor asks of an X-ray of the lower jaw to see if there was any effect of that
but the report says about the child that he is more demanding now and more capricious.
Actually very capricious.
He says I want my milk now, the mother brings the milk and he says now you brought it
I don't want it. That kind of things.
I feel cold, the mother brings something to warm him, he says now I feel hot, take it out.
He cries much more and complains much more than before.
He has become more aggressive.
Itching is quite strong and especially when he does not direct his attention somewhere else.
In his sleep he scratches.
He scratches his hand and the back of the knees quite strongly to the extent
that he bleeds them, no changes in desires and aversions but it says
that now he desires pastry and fried liver.
Thirst is normal and he is not anymore so much timid and not as affectionate as he used to be.
So you see the changes.
-The infection is around the mouth?
-Inside the mouth.
-Did he take something?
-No, it went by itself.
Now he starts having a picture, a symptomatology
and he has some mental-emotional symptomatology now.
Especially this capriciousness is very strong.
Tell me if you can find the remedy now.
Evaluation so far of the case, what has happened?
Most probably here we have a case of suppression.
Next evaluation we have to make is whether we should give a remedy or not at that stage.
We have a suppression but during the suppression we have noticed many times that the
remedy becomes more clear and there are some symptoms to help you, to guide you.
The tendency is that now the remedy is more clear according to my understanding.
For you is it more clear the remedy now?
-Yes.
-What is the remedy?
-Sulphur.
-Another one?
-Chamomilla.
-Very good. No, I prescribed Cina 200 one dose because of the makeup of the child
that he became from quite child, he became so much capricious and all that.
-How do you distinguish?
-Chamomilla would be more shouting and screaming, this child is more give me that,
no I don't want, give me that, no I don't want, the description is more Cina.
We don't know, we don't trust. Now we are taking chances.
It says that 10 days before taking Cina the skin eruptions started breaking out already.
That means after having been suppressed then it starts the organism by itself
to throw out again the eruption and in spite of that it has a time between going to the office
and taking the remedy.
The remedy is prescribed a few days later because I had to see the case and go back
and take the prescription.
That is the time lapse of 10 days where it says now that an aggravation of the skin
has started before taking the last medicine already.
He had a great aggravation of the skin condition before taking the remedy
and that continued also 10 days after taking Cina.
-This is the follow up after Cina?
-Yes, I'm reading to you the follow up after Cina.
-What date?
-That is 78.
The itching was very strong and now it's gone.
The whole situation now on the skin is settled down.
The capriciousness became much worse during the skin aggravation.
Now it's less.
Yes, before the remedy the aggravation of the skin became much worse and then it came down.
This month the child was crying quite a lot and he became quite violent in his behavior.
It sleeps well and sleeps on the abdomen, desires ice-cream and cold water,
desires rice underlined twice, pasta and sweets,
he is not very timid anymore, cries very easily, he is very demanding and he is cursing.
He starts cursing.
You look up in your Repertory.
You see the illusion that keeps him coming, it is that he is doing better.
You gave him a remedy in the beginning for two months, then you give another remedy,
there is an aggravation, it's better now, the child keeps coming but have made the mistake.
They may feel that something has been done but actually nothing has been done
so far for that child.
What is your evaluation?
Anybody wants to evaluate what is happening and tell me what to do?
-I think it's suppression because in personality it's going worse and worse, more violent,
more cursing...
-Yes, there is a further suppression.
The eruption is better but not entirely.
Still there is some skin eruption outside, it's not the whole thing suppressed now.
So what is the evaluation? What we have done?
I gave Cina the second time, there is an aggravation of the skin
and it appears to be the right action.
Then after 10 days of big aggravation, there is sedation, he does not anymore
become so much capricious but he has this violence.
That means the eruption is inside. Great part of the eruption is inside.
Here I've made a mistake. Let's hear what you will do.
-Anacardium.
-I would give him Stramonium.
-What do you expect if you wait? Now we have made quite a lot of mistakes already.
But anyhow it's a good answer.
-You wait...
-This is a solution. What you will do?
-I go back to the original case and see if something is coming up.
-Difficult.
-Chamomilla.
-Hyoscyamus.
-Medorrhinum.
-I'll tell you what I have given. I prescribed Anacardium 30.
I go down the potencies and as I told you I'm a bad prescriber when I prescribe wrongly.
Taking Anacardium he says great amelioration on the skin.
-How long?
-For many days and eventually for two weeks the skin became like velvet he said.
-What is the date?
-17th of March 78, like velvet!
After these two weeks of velvet skin a terrible aggravation, the whole thing came out
and now it's in a terrible state the skin.
The itching is three times, the child is scratching all the time, the whole 24 hours
it's scratching, worse in heat, redness on his face and redness on his legs.
The sleep is good, he still says bad words, he doesn't cry so much.
What we will do now?
-The rest of the emotional state?
-The rest of the emotional state he says, he is not so timid anymore
and he does not cry easily. There is no information.
Now the skin is bad.
Less aggravated, the emotional state is better of course because the eruption is out
and the emotional state has been relieved quite a lot, he is not violent,
he just uses bad words but not stressed so much.
Skin is on a worse condition that it has started.
-Has Anacardium antidoted the process?
-No, what happened here is that with the homeopathic remedy you
pushed the eruption inside and the organism is angry with that.
This is exactly what happened.
There is enough vitality and it brings it out.
That's why we say there is no problem if you wait. You give the wrong remedy, you wait.
Sometimes it is 1,2,3 months at the most and the thing will come back.
-He may actually be proving Anacardium.
-No, because he has the cursing and all that before Anacardium.
Now he does not have so much the violence. He had violence.
We did it in the wrong order.
First ameliorated the skin, that's why I do not consider that Anacardium had really acted.
What it has been done here is that the doctor who was taking the case
was not very conversant with the Theory.
So by himself thinking that Anacardium has helped the velvet skin, he prescribed
by himself a 200 because 30 is lasting only one month and he prescribed 200
and here is what happened one month later, 21 of April 78.
You see how much useful is that Theory?
You see when they say better, better, forget it. I want to see first the reaction.
-What you have seen?
-First the aggravation of the skin, immediately the skin, amelioration of this
aggressiveness and then better, better, better.
What I saw here is better first and then the aggravation. Wrong remedy.
That observation is standard.
It ameliorated the skin, made it clear, it is a definite action of the remedy
and it is definitely wrong action.
Now he takes Anacardium 200 for 23 days. He says the 23rd day the redness
and the roughness of the skin started going down but the itching did not withdraw
and finally they had to use Phenergan, this is an antihistamine drug.
He wakes up many times in the night and scratches,
scratching worse in the night before going to bed, scratches and bleeds,
psychologically he is better, he continues to use bad words,
he has no capriciousness and if they make a remark, he won't talk or if he talks
he will complain about it.
He sleeps well, fear of the dark is there, he does not want egg as he used to want,
he has some boils on his fingers, he has no reaction from weather cold or hot.
You see how we spoiled the case eventually?
Now you have a case where - and this happens many times - you don't have any
symptomatology to go by, the condition remains rotten and the best course of action is placebo.
So placebo was given and he comes on 10th of June 78...
We left about two months of observation and he says that this month was very bad,
the whole situation was quite bad, especially the last 15-20 days.
He had an inflammation under his nail and the nail came out.
Also a boil in the chest with itching and pain, general dermatitis with severe itching,
scratches until it bleeds, worse during night in sleep, he doesn't want to wear long punches,
he wears short punches, skin is quite dry, also great itching on the genitalia.
They bleed with scratching. He behaves like a grown up person,
he wants to put everything in order, he is quite fastidious.
For instance he wears his pyjamas to drink his milk, he dresses with his night dress
to drink his milk, if he sees a button missing it is a big deal.
He wants to be dressed properly, his shoes...
He wants his bed very nicely and tidily made,
has great patience, he takes a lot into consideration the restrictions
that the doctor tells about his treatment not to drink coffee, not to take camphor,
he is very serious about this.
He doesn't use any more bad words, he has an aversion to eggs now and to fish,
desires rice twice, desires ice cream twice and wants cold water, underlined twice.
He perspires on occiput during sleep and here I've made again another mistake.
I went back to the original case, I looked again, I looked here
and I said this is again Phosphorus.
So the first Phosphorus has not acted, maybe something has happened,
let me give it again but now in 200.
So I gave Phosphorus 200.
The remedy has become clear now but something put me off the remedy.
Already I should have spotted the remedy at this moment and the remedy is not Arsenicum.
He comes in 8th of August 78 and he says that as long as he was in the sea, he had no problem,
the skin had cleared.
The moment he comes back from the sea, the whole situation starts all over again.
-At the sea?
-At the sea and in the sea. He goes and swim in the sea.
Since he stopped taking sea baths he has again the same condition, his skin became dry again,
redness in certain places, itching worse when he becomes warm, psychologically the same,
desires the same and the doctor writes here in my question he says, he does not answer me
but he goes to the mother, he says the answer and that's how he communicates.
The doctor writes that his sister had a lot of warts, perspires a little bit on the occiput.
What did I prescribe?
-Medorrhinum.
-I made a mistake again. I prescribed Medorrhinum.
The previous interview I read it to you and you will see the remedy.
-What potency?
-Medorrhinum 200.
He comes 28 of May 79, he disappeared after Medorrhinum.
He decided to come back, he said no amelioration at all during that whole period.
He has constant itching, dryness and becomes red.
One day he was scratching with that hard thing, he is scratching around his head now.
The scratching is voluptuous, the child now is six years,
he has grown up with this eruption and with good Homeopathy...
He scratches all the time.
Worse lying in bed until he goes to sleep he scratches, he is stood first in the class,
he is obstinate, he wants to do what everybody says, he is feeling the heat more now.
Desire for sweets is underlined twice and desire for ice-cream underlined twice,
desire cold drinks underlined once,
sleeps on the abdomen, there is a slight constipation if he does not eat much green stuff,
perspires a lot in the cervical region and on the forehead, the sweat is offensive,
at school he is perfect, he is very fastidious doing his job.
His nose, he cannot breathe because of growing of adenoids and his tonsils are swollen.
Finally I gave him the right remedy.
Going back especially the previous report where I gave Phosphorus 200.
That report I should have started with Sulphur.
I just decided not to think of Sulphur the other time but that time?
Because there is an aversion to eggs and aversion to fish, both are in Phosphorus.
And the child looked to me more as a Phosphorus child but I know the fastidiousness of Sulphur
and I told you many times Sulphur is very fastidious and it did not click.
Finally on the 28th of May 79 it was Sulphur 200.
The child did not come back until September 81, one and a half year later where he says
he has been well all this time but he had an acute situation for which he took antibiotics
and the whole thing relapsed.
He has now again flare up of the dermatitis, with intense itching, scratches a lot,
worse in warm, he went in the sea, it was summer, he was not better in the sea.
He was not ameliorated by the sea this time.
So I give him again Sulphur 200.
Then he comes on 15th of July of 82, one year later and he says the skin eruption
was very well until one month ago where he was on an island where he got a bronchitis
and he took again antibiotics and again flare up.
There is a relapse and I've given a dose of Sulphur 1M and that is the last report of that child.
Somebody has spotted the remedy from the beginning.
He has developed a boil which is painful and itching, this is Sulphur,
great itching, scratches until it bleeds, worse in the night, underlined three times also,
that is Sulphur.
Kent may have not have noticed but it is one of the very common characteristics
of Sulphur because Sulphur has great itching and by the effort to scratch it will bleed.
Then he is so fastidious, the child is very fastidious.
I know that Sulphur is fastidious and I should have thought of Sulphur already in that case
because there is the itching, the boils, even the inflammation on the fingers,
great inflammation with fever which sometimes is threatening, many times it's covered by Sulphur.
Then he has developed an aversion to eggs, see aversion to eggs and aversion to fish.
Aversion to eggs is Phosphorus, Kali sulphuricum, Ferrum, Sulphur and Nitric acid.
Aversion to fish you will see again Sulphur.
Perspires on the occiput. At this point I should have given Sulphur already.
When I made the mistake of Phosphorus then most probably I went to look back,
so I could see the trace of Sulphur going through the case which I did not notice.
Then finally I prescribed Sulphur.
The sea, that was a characteristic that most probably went away with Medorrhinum
because it was not there when I prescribed Sulphur.
It's very difficult here to say whether any of these remedies have done something to produce,
because there is an aversion to eggs, an aversion to fish,
the amelioration in the sea which is gone...
There are changes which are pointing towards Sulphur more clearly.
So it must have been some of these remedies, one of them or two that have produced
the picture of Sulphur more clearly than definitely was in the beginning.
-If you look at the first case and you leave out the ice-cream, you have dry skin,
itching worse at night and fastidious.
-You can say but you have the information there, it's written.
Every case that you will repertories, it will come Sulphur and that's another fact.
And you are aware of that and you don't see any characteristic of Sulphur
in the beginning except of the fastidiousness, without having anything to support that.
-Where did you go in the first remedy?
-They seem typical of what remedy?
-You said the child liked ice-cream and then fear of the dark.
-Because I had nothing else to do, I had no information.
You use that information, it's written there after all, you say you are justified
to give that remedy. All the other it is conjecture.
You cannot go completely away from the information that you have
when you prescribed the remedy.