Today I'm going to show you a case which nobody has seen before
because I took it yesterday night.
The hero is a member of the class and I would like you to think together,
we are searching for his remedy.
So everybody is going to participate in finding his remedy.
Then you will see the results of your decision next year.
It is a very interesting case, that's why I'm eager to present it and to analyze it
as it's fresh in my mind.
-You have been treated...
-When I first have been treated I didn't know what it was.
I was having tenderness and some pain. So I started from there and then I went to homeopath.
It was on May 1981 when I started having a lot of tenderness and pain in the epigrasic area
and underneath in the liver area.
And I was admitted to the hospital in July of 1981 in emergency.
After having me for a week they couldn't find what was wrong with me,
so they told me that probably there is anything wrong with me.
They told me just go away, they gave me pain killers.
They didn't know what was wrong, it must be something very rare.
So I just had the pain until January of 1982, then I heard about Homeopathy.
I decided before any treatment I would find more about it.
So I started taking homeopathic course by somebody in England and decided that
I would go for treatment.
This was about 2 months after starting the course. He gave me Carcinosin 30
which had no effect on this pain at all. In February 1982 he gave me Thuja 30, still no effect.
On March of 1982 he gave me Tuberculinum 10M and the next day I started having severe cramping.
I would turn white, sweat would pour down my body and I start having constant diarrhea.
-For the first time?
-For the first time, I never had diarrhea in my life.
I can eat all kinds of food and I never get diarrhea. All of a sudden I started having diarrhea.
I was told that this was homeopathic aggravation and just go through it. That's all right.
Then for about 2 months I was having this diarrhea and pain and then gradually it cleared up,
it went back to normal and I went back again. He said that was great aggravation,
tremendous results.
Now what we need to do is to tap it up and just clear the rest of the miasm.
Then I was given Tuberculinum CM. Next day the diarrhea came back, pain.
Two months later.
This man had a symptomatology and he was given different remedies and finally
he did not have any action and finally he was given a remedy that had tremendous aggravation,
tremendous reaction.
He complained for pain in the epigastrium and pain in the liver region, he was given a remedy
and then diarrhea started, severe diarrhea for the first time of his life.
For 2 months he had diarrhea, the diarrhea cleared up and the practitioner said
we must boost this reaction by another dose of Tuberculinum.
Let's understand that because if you don't understand the Theory you will see the story
which is coming.
When do you have a homeopathic aggravation?
-When the symptoms for which a person is complaining are aggravated.
Then you have an aggravation and the symptoms must take the right direction.
-In this case do we have an old diarrhea coming back?
-No.
-He said I never had diarrhea in my life.
There is a deep effect upon the organism but you have to understand one thing,
in order to have a homeopathic aggravation you have to have eventually an amelioration.
This is a rule.
If the aggravation is homeopathic, then you have a cure after the aggravation.
If you have an aggravation, especially if the aggravation continues for a long period of time,
without a final amelioration, then you don't have a homeopathic aggravation.
It is an aggravation which comes if you give a remedy, which is close to the case but not exact.
This remedy was close, a kind of layer for him.
But which layer? Not the first layer, not the first remedy that should have been given
because otherwise he would have felt very well after the aggravation,
the aggravation would not have lasted for so long and the aggravation also is taking
where the intestines were inflamed, now they ulcerate. From inflammation goes to ulceration.
This is not a homeopathic aggravation.
Therefore not knowing the Theory, what is the logic?
He says that was the right remedy, take another dose now, take another dose.
If he knew the Theory, he would never have done it.
He would say I made a mistake, don't touch again Tuberculinum in this case.
Instead of saying don't use Tuberculinum under no circumstance in this case,
he says let us take another dose, not only that but we are going to take it from 10M to 100.000.
What is going to happen? What do you expect to happen if you have a sensitive person
to Tuberculinum and you give Tuberculinum constantly, you give CM every day?
He didn't give every day but one dose was enough to produce what you will hear.
-Diarrhea came back, intense pains in the abdomen and he said this is an aggravation.
I thought it lasts very long, that's fine, that's OK.
Then the idea was that probably it is a proving of Tuberculinum.
So I thought this is interesting, I will find what Tuberculinum is, so I started taking notes
of Tuberculinum proving, I thought after this I'll try Syphilinum proving.
But what happened was that it just stayed until I started wondering this is wrong,
I'm getting weaker and weaker, I started having hemorrhaging from the bowels.
-At what time?
-Probably in 1983, I started having hemorrhaging.
I went back to him not knowing what to do. At one point he told me Natrum Sulphuricum,
It looks like the remedy, Natrum Sulphuricum came no effect.
Then in July I saw another homeopath, much more experienced and in July I was given Rhus tox 1M.
I had an aggravation but inside aggravation, I was very irritable and depressed
and that lasted for a week, then it cleared up. The stools became normal.
-For how long?
-For about 2 weeks and then it all started up again.
After a remedy you may have an aggravation, mental-emotional aggravation.
Can you have and still the remedy can be correct?
-Sometimes.
-No.
-Sometimes they say yes, sometimes no.
It could be, in which case you may have a mental aggravation?
-In psychological.
-In case we have mental problems. These mental problems can be aggravated for a time.
You are treating a person for a mental condition and he is aggravated, he is mad or he is...
This is OK the aggravation.
His own symptoms are aggravated, his fears are aggravated for a few days, his mental
-emotional symptoms are aggravated and you treating him for mental-emotional symptoms.
But if you are treating him for a colitis and the colitis gets better
while the mental symptoms are aggravated.
By the time he is aggravated, then colitis is better. Wrong prescription again.
I have to note that the first homeopath and the second homeopath, the first I do not know
but the second I know very well, they are good homeopaths.
The first one I do not know because he should know that he should not touch Tuberculinum
but still he does not give a lot of remedies.
He waited until the aggravation was cleared up, until the proving was cleared up
but left an effect. The second is knowing what he is doing.
Still you will see after we finish the case, how careful we must be in analyzing a case,
understanding the case and taking the right course of action because of that condition.
-It all started up again but I wasn't in a position where I could contact, I was travelling in Europe.
So I saw him again and it went back at about 20-30 bowel movements the day.
-Some of them were with blood, mucus?
-No mucus, just blood, not all the time but quite often blood.
Then in November I saw him again the second homeopath
and he prescribed me Natrum muriaticum 10M.
I had lost a baby in February, my daughter died and I was quite upset about that.
But I was exhibiting signs of Nat-m. and...
I want to point out another point here.
When you have a condition going on and while the condition is going on there is a grief.
Unless there are drastic changes on that condition, grief is not considered.
He lost a child, it doesn't matter. It did nothing to him.
It doesn't mean that anybody who loses a child needs Ignatia or Natrum muriaticum.
Some people they just go over it without an effect.
In order to give here Natrum muriaticum, you have to have a drastic change in the picture
after the loss of the child and you have a new picture and you see a picture before
and a new picture now.
Yes you are justified to give Nat mur.
But if you give Nat mur while the picture is continuing and of course it is not covering
the whole picture, the remedy is not going to act.
These points you have to have in mind.
You ask me Materia Medica and I will give you Materia Medica but the Theory
is much more important and nobody understands the Theory I can tell you.
Because when I see even my best students doing such mistakes, that means
they have not understood the Theory. And I said so many times these things.
-I had an aggravation inside once again, depression, crying, sadness and I didn't know
what was wrong with me and my bowels.
I was back in Canada at that time and I started drinking, brandy and I would go into
melancholic states, crying...
-That happened after Nat mur?
Do you see this is not immaterial with the remedy because Nat mur makes the people closed,
they close up and how do they open? By drinking.
Nat mur will open up if you drink a few glasses of wine and then you become loquacious.
You can't stop talking then.
What he says during the proving in Nat mur? He becomes melancholic and he needs to drink.
It is a proving of Nat mur. If he goes out of the phase of Nat mur he will stop drinking.
Be very careful with high potencies and with low potencies and learn to take seriously
what the person is saying.
Take the case seriously and before you give a remedy, understand that this remedy...
I'm quite happy now.
First of course learn the Materia Medica to match because to be quite happy
if you know 10 remedies, it's dangerous.
-Take brandy, gin, I hated the taste of alcohol but I just felt like being drunk all the time.
So I did that about March of 1985 and then I got tremendous hemorrhagic,
40-50 bowel movements the day.
I was trembling all the time and I saw a friend who is a medical doctor
and he said something very wrong is with you.
I knew that I was sick this time, I haven't told anybody except my wife of course
but not family, my friends, nobody knew that I was sick.
-Did you work?
-Yes.
I was seeing patients at the same time, making excuses to run out of the room all the time.
Then he admitted me to the hospital, they took blood, my hemoglobin was 60
and he said you have to have some blood transfusions and then sent me to a specialist
who diagnosed Chron's disease.
He suggested I would take cortisone, I told him I will not take cortisone.
I phoned my homeopath once again who prescribed Mercurius, the hemorrhage stop.
I was having mass of hemorrhage like a bottle of blood just dropped out of my hands.
Mercury stopped the hemorrhage at that point.
Then in July I got a very severe cystitis.
-The effect of Mercury lasted?
-Diarrheas kept on, cramping kept on but the hemorrhage stopped.
-Did you have a general effect?
-No, no effect inside.
Then I got Nux vomica 10M because I had the cystitis and very strong symptoms.
Giving Nux vomica 10M cystitis got better but not changing in the bowel.
It stayed the same.
Inside I felt increase of energy, joyfulness came up but I was so weak that if I did anything,
just climb many stairs I was exhausted.
So what happened very soon the effect of Nux vomica was gone, the cystitis didn't come back,
I didn't feel good feelings inside, anymore.
Then I had Phosphorus prescribed, good feelings inside but again something happened,
I must had lifter a chair, exhausted, good feelings went away.
I was given Calcium carbonicum 200 no effect, Sulphur 200 no effect, Arsenicum 1M.
At this time what happened was that the weakness improved.
I would walk around and everything would be dark and I couldn't hardly see where I was going.
But no effect in the bowels, the weakness got better.
Prescribed Veratrum album no effect, Carbo vegetabilis the bowels firmed up slightly.
Slightly felt but there wasn't much good feeling, nothing much but then after about a week
the bowels once again.
They were about 20 bowel movements the day I was prescribed Crotun tiglium no effect from that.
Then in July of 1986 Natrum arsenicum was prescribed.
There was some increase in energy, no change in the bowels.
Then I was prescribed Phosphorus and then what happened was the next day the bowel
movements, I would have 2 bowel movements where I had to rush to the toilet all costs.
I was just losing my stool in my pants. That happened to me before.
-You lost stool unnoticeable or you could not retain?
-Not retain, I have no retain in my bowels at all.
-No power of retention.
-None.
-As soon as it comes you have to run.
-I have to be in the toilet or I have to hold my anus.
I have to close it physically with my hand or it comes out.
So what happened was the bowel movements, then I had about 8 the day,
I could just slowly go to the toilet, 2 would be rush to the toilet.
Normally I would wake up from getting the Tuberculinum up to this time,
I would wake up 6-7 times the night to go to the toilet.
Sometimes I would be up for 4 hours in the night, so forget about 3 hours of sleep.
So I started having 1 bowel movement in the night, 2 rush bowel movements in the day,
6 bowel movements where I could calmly go.
Inside what happened I experienced overwhelming feelings of devotion, pray fullness.
This lasted for 2 months. All day I would walk around feeling ecstasy of a feeling inside myself.
-Pray fullness?
-A kind of feeling of adoration for the universe. It's not mental, it's from my heart.
-Were you involved with some kind of spiritual movement at the time?
-I had been up to 1978, I was still meditating but very disillusioned.
-You went to different gurus?
-No, I went to a guru in 1970, I became a teacher to his meditations and then at 1970
I became quite disillusioned.
I just started again having these strong feelings, I had them as a child always inside.
-You had feelings of adoration?
-Feelings of joyfulness, feelings of praying it would be like god I love you so much.
This feeling inside. No words but feeling.
-How long it lasted this period?
-Two months and what happened was I drove down to southern interior to see my sister,
the feelings went away and I knew that I'm in trouble.
About 2 days later the bowel movement started again.
-What was the remedy before?
-Before Phosphorus? This feeling was after Phosphorus 1M.
Another effect that it had was that at 1975 I had asthma.
There was worse in the winter or I would get a cold or if I would get upset stomach,
I would have wheezing and was able to walk around in the winter.
I still have it but the asthma got better.
So Phosphorus 1M was prescribed again no effect.
March 1987 Phosphorus 10M no effect.
-This repetition of Phosphorus did not aggravate the whole situation?
-What happened was that I started developing a large mass in my lower right quadrant
and I woke up one morning in such pain, I thought I must have appendicitis.
It was so intense, I thought this is it, I'm dying, I couldn't think so my friends
rushed me to the hospital. I got there, they thought you have probably a peritonitis.
So they said if you don't accept that treatment, there is nothing we can do.
So I said fine I can't take that pain right now. So they put me into antibiotics treatment
and cortisone 16mg and kept me in the hospital for 2 weeks, no food and they had
a surgeon check me every day but that cleared up.
Then I phoned my homeopath again because I was still hemorrhaging, cortisone didn't do anything
for my bowels, no effect.
They put me on Asacol hd which is related to aspirin
and that was supposed to replace the cortisone.
So I'm taking that and it doubled the bowel movements, I got tremendous aggravation from it
and back to the hospital, big swelling in the lower abdomen.
Then they said you should go on chemotherapy.
I said you keep that, keep the cortisone, keep everything and I took myself off.
-You walked out of the hospital?
-I couldn't walk because of the pain.
-During the week they gave you cortisone and all this?
-I was in cortisone anyway because I wasn't able to come out, I was on 60 mg
and they took me down to about 30 mg...
-Then it subsided quite a lot, the pain, the swelling?
-Yes but I've had it since, I didn't go to the hospital.
I just decided I won't go back there. So I just have it for about a week now.
-So you got periodical crisis now?
-Very bad, swells up, this under here becomes very painful, painful to touch,
I can't sleep because of the pain, I curse, I pray, nothing works.
It's very painful, I have to stop eating, I become very weak during these flare ups.
After I got at the hospital the second time we prescribed Mercurius corrosivus
because I was hemorrhaging again but I was still in cortisone. Hemorrhage stopped.
Then I lost contact with the homeopath because I had to phone him and I couldn't move,
I couldn't find his phone number anymore.
So I went to another homeopath in Canada whom I considered better than the one I had
and he prescribed Nux vomica 12C to try to come off the cortisone.
Coming off the cortisone was horrendous. Now I just laid in the bed,
I couldn't move my arms, I couldn't move my legs, I was freezing cold, shaking
and I went through that for about 2 weeks.
He prescribed the 12C, no change in my bowels, still 20 movements the day,
then Silica 200 was prescribed with a slight increase of energy.
-What was the remedy?
-Silica 200 with not much results.
Then I was prescribed Magnesium muriaticum with no results, Phosphorus 1M which he didn't prescribed
but I got a very bad bronchitis.
I have a tendency to get cold to my chest, so I went back in the Repertory,
it looked like Phosphorus. I took Phosphorus, a day and a half later it was better.
It lasted 2 weeks and then I phoned and he said wait, maybe the Phosphorus will affect
your bowels as well.
No effect on my bowels at all.
Then prescribed Rumex crispus no effect, Colocynthis no effect.
I had Sulphur about 3 months ago and what happened was 3 days after taking the Sulphur
I had passed 2 bowel movements formed, because I don't have formed bowel movements
and I got an eruption on my left forearm, which also had come out
with the Natrum muriaticum some time ago.
-Other than these 2 stools, one normal and then back again?
-It had 20 bowel movements and during the day with these 20, one of them was formed.
-How old are you now?
-38.
-And the whole thing started 7 years ago at the age of 31?
-31-32.