I wanted to show you a case, I'll make the introduction.
I will not show the whole case because we don't have time.
I will make only the introduction, you are not going to show anything,
only the pictures maybe.
I will tell you only the introduction of the case I'm going to
present to you tomorrow morning.
Two years ago when I went to give a seminar in Germany,
as soon as I arrived in Germany,
one of the doctors of the Center that organized the seminars,
said George I have a big problem with my mother.
I said what it is?
She said she is in the hospital and
they are preparing to cut both her legs from high up the thighs.
I said why? Because there is gangrene, there is no flow of blood.
When are they going to cut the legs? She said on Tuesday.
It was, if I remember well, Thursday or Friday.
So from Thursday or Friday till Tuesday we had to show some effect on legs that
they were black and gangrenous.
Because she was in the Center, I knew her, I said OK we'll go to the hospital.
We went to the hospital and we got some pictures,
not a video but some pictures of her legs.
Of course she could not walk anymore, there was no flow of blood,
the legs were dead...
Can you show some pictures?
You don't have the pictures. OK, show the report.
I gave the report to the class and I gave the symptomatology in the class and
you will hear that and then you will see the legs.
This is a good example of usually what they say about Homeopathy.
"Homeopathy is good for common colds".
Yes little things, if you have a pimple here it's good.
I want to inform you of what I saw yesterday.
We enter the room and we see this lady lying in bed, covered from the waist downwards
with quite heavy blankets.
From the waist upwards she only wears something for her breast. She is uncovered.
Immediately as I enter the room, I see she is doing like that with her fingers.
There is a great restlessness in the fingers.
In the meantime her daughter has told me that she has flashes of heat.
I said where? In the upper part.
Then I uncover the blanket to see the situation in the legs and it is within one week that
this condition is developed. Can you show the pictures?
You see the black spots?
The right side is more affected, the right leg is more affected than the left.
Can you give the next picture?
The tissues are there totally destroyed, totally black, as you see.
No signs of real alive inflammation, just dead tissues that become black.
There is no pain, she does not complain. She says she feels nothing in the legs.
She has no feeling in the legs.
The idea is that they have to amputate her from higher up in the thighs, very soon.
-When she walked last time?
-That condition has come about the last week as I have been told, very fast.
-No pain?
-At this moment no pain at all.
-How old is she?
-She is 70 years old.
-She has diabetes?
-No diabetes. It is a case of severe arteritis.
-She is smoker?
-Never said her daughter.
She loved her family, loved her house and her husband,
this is information I get from the daughter.
She was rather a chilly person, constipated all her life almost.
-Constipated all the time, cold feet all the time.
This case I have brought to show you in order to show you that
there are certain emergency cases, certain emergency states in which you may be...
There are certain emergency cases, very urgent for which you may be justified sometimes
to give more than one remedy.
I want to show you such cases as well.
In such cases you cannot really make out the exact remedy, if you can it's OK.
So if the woman yesterday was an emergency case and it's a matter of life and
death like this, it's a matter of losing both her legs from higher up...
It's a very, very urgent case.
And you are not certain about the remedy,
you may be justified to give a second one at the same time.
But always of course not just give 2-3 remedies just like that,
always after great study and consideration of the case.
In this case I give to the class in Germany and you also listen to what I had observed
in order to prescribe.
I hope you studied this case yesterday and today you will be able to prescribe.
Can you give a little bit more information?
-Four years ago it started with an inflammation of the right ankle and
it was treated by antibiotics. The situation got worse and worse back then.
She had to go to the hospital and they detected an occlusion of the arterior
in the popliteal.
And when they did a chest X-ray by accident they found a carcinoma and
cancer of the left lower lung.
There was an operation three months later which she overcame quite well.
The situation of the right leg was quite well, she had to take aspirin daily,
she could walk but she had some pains in the right leg.
About four weeks ago she had mycosis of the right toe nail and
the practitioner doctor extracted the nail.
Then she developed an inflammation beginning from the
right ankle up to the right lower leg to the knee. Half of the lower leg.
She was again treated by antibiotics and reacted with an allergic reaction of the
antibiotics. After that there was a total occlusion of the arterior tibialis.
So they first tried the lysis therapy with drugs and also tried surgically to get the artery
reopened but this didn't succeed and then they implanted a bypass from
the femoral to the tibialis arterior.
She also received infusions of certain drugs, Prostavasin, which opens the arteries but
that lasted only for four days.
After that her leg turned white, pale and sweaty.
At the same time the situation on the left leg got worse,
the tips of the toes turned blue and black.
I saw her in that situation about one week ago.
She was very sensitive to pain and to touch, she sometimes took off the cover and
then put it on again, put it off again...
I gave her the remedy Secale in a potency D4 three times daily.
After that she got reduced the pain medications, the pain killers, the blood flow got better,
the toes became warmer on the left side. The only thing that stayed was the discoloration
of the left second toe.
A couple of days later again I came to her and I gave her Secale in 200 and 1M,
a potency mixed in water. There was a good development for about one and a half days.
At the same time she tried to find a bed in the hospital here in Celle because
before the mother was far away and I could not see her daily.
She succeeded, just yesterday she was transferred from the other hospital to here,
so I can see her daily and watch the development.
-When I see her, I see the leg but that leg is totally dry, there is no perspiration at all
and it is cold.
I ask the doctor to open the Repertory and to see the first symptoms.
I asked her to see discoloration black.
The next symptom I asked her to see what was?
It was impressive for me that her cheeks were very red, exceptionally red.
I asked her whether she has always that type of redness in the cheeks and
she said yes, it was not an accidental thing at that moment.
So I asked her to see this symptom as well and then she said that she was having
flashes of heat. She showed from here upwards.
So I asked her to look flashes of heat in chest.
Then I asked whether she is thirsty and if you look at your Repertory you will know why
I ask whether she is thirsty and she said she is thirst less.
Then of course I put it constitutional, I used the constipation, as she was constipated all
along and I take it into consideration and cold feet as well.
I asked her whether she is eating the fat and she said no, she is not eating the fat,
she has an aversion to fat.
As you could hear, everything possible was done from the allopathic point of view.
They tried everything, to open the arteries through surgery and Medicine and through
different other things and also some homeopathic medicines were given.
The end result of all that is that on Tuesday, it is Thursday,
she is going to be amputated on Tuesday.
I have to act in three days.
In three days we must show to the hospital, to everybody, to her also,
she is also a medical doctor the daughter but especially to the hospital people to hold back.
So until Monday evening we have the possibility.
Fri-Sat-Sun and Mon are 4 days that we have to show some effect in this lady.
In the meantime of course the arteries are completely...
It's a specific case where we see a great development.
This state has developed in the last 10 days.
The arteries tend to close and they do everything not to close.
They inject, they try to open the arteries. The arteries close.
This is the tendency of the organism.
So I consider her suffering from a genetic kind of
predisposition towards this kind of element.
I know it is a very serious case.
I have treated similar cases, even older women, with great success, not as severe,
because she had gangrene spots higher from the knee.
It is a quite severe case, so what shall we do?
Somebody came to me and said I put together three symptoms that you gave yesterday
and this is the remedy I found. I said yes this is correct.
This is the idea with Homeopathy.
Take essential things, rely on essential things.
Do not distract the information, do not interfere with the information.
Essential things are very important where you know you can rely upon.
You can go on and ask question and questions and finally give the wrong remedy and
of course she will be amputated.
So what were the three essentials things that you heard in the beginning yesterday?
Restlessness of fingers, it was impressive. What it shows?
Is it natural that we'll do like that?
-No.
-Watch this. She was sitting immovable but doing like this, she was talking to me, giving
answers but she would go on like that.
-Numbness.
-If it was numbness what she would do? She would do like this. This is numbness.
This is restlessness coming from most probably inner anxiety.
This is an interpretation but I do not even need that.
You can go and look restlessness of the fingers, look in the Repertory.
Restlessness of fingers, of hands. Kali bromatum and Tarentula and then Hyoscyamus,
Alumina, Arsenicum italics.
Show me now gangrene. Arsenicum, Tarentula and Vipera.
You don't have gangrene in extremities?
-We have lower limbs gangrene, capital Arsenicum, Lachesis and Secale.
Secale had been given, Veratrum, Vipera, Plumbum.
Now you have looked these two things in your Repertory and what you have seen is a
lady who is hot in the upper and cold in the lower, what is the remedy?
There are remedies that have different temperature in different parts of the body
like the Belladonna.
Belladonna is burning heat here and very cold in the extremities.
Is this a Belladonna case?
-No.
-OK, another remedy?
-Arsenicum.
-Arsenicum has a hot head and wants to be fanned.
In the classic books also Arsenicum is appearing as a remedy which is while it is
covered in the body, the upper part and especially the head wants to be fanned.
This is typical of Arsenicum.
Another remedy that wants to be fanned in all kinds of elements is Carbo vegetabilis,
it wants to be fanned. But Carbo vegetabilis will not be covered with five blankets.
And then the restlessness in the hands...
Why the restlessness in this case?
-Fear.
-Because of anxiety, of fear, she is going to be amputated.
She is in the hospital waiting for the operation and she is immovable.
You cannot say restlessness, moving all the time but you have to be observant,
very observant before you can prescribe correctly.
In one of the seminars I had in Alonissos, one of the doctors, an elder one,
they call me at 12 o'clock in the night,
he is on the island and they say he has a heart emphract.
He has severe pain, he had recurrent angina pain but this time...