-And you told me to continue in this way, every time I needed
I should repeat Phosphorus.
When I returned to Berlin the first days I took Phosphorus regularly
on a daily basis, so that I had the feeling I'm not really in my full strength
and Phosphorus helped me to gain my strength.
For the first 3-4 weeks I woke up very early between 4-5 a.m. and it was really fresh
and relaxed but then I walked through my apartment and kept talking to myself.
I talked with myself wandering around in the apartment.
And many odd things came up, the main issue was that I had difficulties in saying
what I need or what I want and that I can't say no, I can't refuse anything.
The more I did this the more I had the feeling that from now on people you gonna have
to count on me, I'm going to show myself.
Then I changed my behavior and dared to say no a couple of times and it was really amazing
how much rejoice came up on me, how much strength I got out of it
and see how different I could react.
I took Phosphorus all the way up to LM15, every time I realized that the lower potency
is not acting anymore, I went up one potency higher and also during this time I noticed
that I hardly every had to drink black tea.
I have a low blood pressure and during this time with Phosphorus, I was hardly ever needed
to drink black tea. Then everything reduced again.
I noticed I need more black tea, I noticed Phosphorus isn't acting very well anymore
and things came back.
According to my feeling that would be the time to take a high potency but I decided to wait
because it was only 8 weeks until I would come back here for the course and I knew I was going
to have a follow up, so I thought OK I can hold these 8 weeks and wait to see what happens.
Another thing on the emotional level, I don't have enough self-confidence.
People when looking at me from the outside will never realize that but it's true
and also when I'm doing my practice I, myself, always have the feeling I don't know enough,
although according to the feedback I get, I do know enough but I always have the feeling
I'm not good enough.
Also we had this issue this morning with Hanna already, in my entire life I never let
my anger come out, I never yelled at anybody or showed my anger, it never came out.
Now I'd like to give you some physical symptoms I have.
What I still have is that if I jump or if I run, my bladder still is incontinent
but I still like to jump very much. For example if I see some place where I can climb up
and jump from there, I really enjoy doing it and do it often.
What came back is the Chlamydia I had, I was in the gynecologist and he did an examination
and there they came back but they are not in the blood.
When she diagnosed that, I also felt that again I have pains in my finger joints
and in my toe joints and these pains lasted until 3 weeks ago.
Since then they are gone but I didn't have any time to go to the gynecologist
and have another check.
-When she says the Chlamydia came back, she means a kind of leucorrhea?
-No, I have no leucorrhea whatsoever. I once told you that I use to have Chlamydia
they were diagnosed and it was treated with antibiotics, after which they disappeared and
now they returned.
-I don't remember this. What exactly was the original situation?
-That was at the time when I took Phosphorus 10M, I went to see my gynecologist,
just to have a regular check up, as I do and during this check up he diagnosed Chlamydia
and you had said, when I reported that to you that it's possible that maybe I had them some time
in the past and that the symptom was reappearing.
At that time, when I took Phosphorus 10M, I did not had a partner, so there was actually
no intercourse, no place where I could had contracted it.
-But that was with the original Phosphorus?
-Yes.
-And then disappeared and then they came back again?
-At that time they did not go away, I waited for 1 year and then I took antibiotics after which
they disappeared and I have reported this in May, when I was here.
-Yes, when she had the relapse and she was not feeling so well and then she started again
with Phosphorus.
-Exactly and now the Chlamydia came back.
My stool is formed partially but more of it is soft.
After Phosphorus for a couple of weeks I always had the sensation, as if somebody very tenderly
touching my liver and my gallbladder, not strong, it was just a very tender touch and the stool
always looked as if a lot of bile was coming out with it and I always felt well after it,
I always had the feeling of getting rid of something through it.
-She feels good now after stool? What do you mean?
-No, it was just at that time that I had the feeling that my gallbladder is emptying and that
my body is getting rid of it with the stool and it was a good feeling, as if the body was
getting rid of something old.
-During that time.
-My first menstruation after Phosphorus was very strong and I also felt very well with that.
I had a good flow.
-Now she continues to have a lot of blood in the menstruation.
-No, it's not very much blood at all, only in the first day and the next days is not a lot at all
but I have a premenstrual syndrome; the day of my ovulation I start having pains in my joints
similar with some kind of rheumatism and it lasts until the second day of menstruation
and then it ends.
The only thing which ameliorates me during this time is hot bath.
This bothers me a lot because it inhibits me in my emotions, in my activity.
I'm a person who likes to move a lot but when I have this I cant' move very well, it's like
I have stiff joints and I can't move the way I like to.
I'm still sensitive to cold and very easily chilly.
-As much as before or less? She used to have ice cold feet.
-It's a bit less and people ask me but you don't wear so much clothing, it's hard to believe
but I just don't like to wear many things.
When I'm cold my fingers turn white and numb. What has got a lot better is my strength.
I can swim in deep water now, I can swim long distances and I do it every day and I really enjoy it,
it's a lot of fun.
Right now I need a lot of sleep still, I really need to take a nap in the afternoon and
usually is in such a way that I lie down, mostly on my abdomen, for 1-2 hours I just remain
exactly the way I lied down and have a very deep sleep without moving.
Also at night I have long and deep sleep and don't wake up.
Every once in a while I feel the pressure on my thyroid, if you remember I had an operation
on my thyroid, years ago because I had a cold nod but the thyroid values are OK.
What I noticed, I very rarely eat meat but what I like a lot is cartilage, especially from the bones
of chicken, the pieces that other people would throw away, I really enjoy eating that
and I want to say that my nails have corrugated.
I still have my psoriasis but it did not get any worse, I still have in my belly button,
behind my ear and for a while I had it below both eyes but it's got a lot better here
due to the sun.
One week before we came here I twisted my ankle and after a couple of hours the pain got so intense
that I could not walk on it anymore and then I took Arnica in a C200
and Hypericum in a C30 alternating, for 5 hours all together.
Then on the next day everything was fine.
Here on the island I have several mosquito bites which were quite swollen
and I put some Apis cream on them.
During the time I was taking Phosphorus on different LM potencies, I had pains in my sinuses
and I always had a constant dripping of mucus down the back of my throat and my throat was
a bit red but there was no real inflammation. It was just a subacute state of it.
I don't like to stay in the sun for a longer period of time, I enjoy it but I can't stay any long
because I develop a strong inner restlessness and my whole temperature in my body turns
upside down and then I really have to get out of the sun.
-I want to ask some questions. The first symptoms that she has given was a pressing pain in the heart
and a very superficial respiration. How is that?
-It's gone, at that time it was an acute situation. It still comes back every now and then
if I'm very excited.
-Also she had nausea.
-When I'm excited I quickly react with nausea.
-She also reported of being very sympathetic, is still there this element as much as before
and the anxiety for others?
-Yes, this has still remained the same. The only difference is that now from my mind I try
to hold back a little bit more.
For example when I came to the island one of the very first days, I walked
and passed a house and inside woman was crying and sobbing really strong.
For me it was very difficult to just walk by the house and to get my mind out of it.
For hours I was still thinking about this incident.
-Also in the first interview she was quite depressed and she had thoughts of suicide...
-I've been in therapy since then, in several different ones and took a long while for me to get out
of that depression but therapy has helped me.
-What kind of therapy? Psychotherapy?
-Yes and the last kind of therapy I did was something where I went into trans
and looked at all my beliefs, my structures and I looked in there and told anything I found.
My therapist was noting everything down and afterwards we looked at it together.
It was very interesting for me to find out what was inside me.
-When it was that in time?
-The last phase was shortly before I came here, in the island.
-What about the aversion to eggs she had?
-I haven't eaten any since. Every now and then I think you might eat one now and if I would eat,
it would be soft boiled but I still can not imagine eating them.
-And salt?
-I take more salt definitely.
I remember that I hardly put any spice on my food but that already changed after the first dose
of Phosphorus that I started putting more spices on and now I like salt very much.
-How is her thirst now?
-Very strong still.
-Cold?
-Here I drink cold drinks but home in Berlin I like warm, I make a big pot of tea and I drink this tea
during the entire day, it just cools off during the day.
-Does she have any fear of thunderstorms, of the dark?
-No.
-Also she was complaining that she felt she is not appreciated very much.
-I don't know if it's solved but I feel a lot better with this issue. I have a lot more self confidence
and if I'm in my strength, its' not really a big problem for me.
Only if I feel weak, then it starts to be a big problem.
-How much is her blood pressure now?
-It's mostly 95 over 55.
-Still is low?
-Still low even if I drink a lot of black tea.
-But before it was lower?
-No, it wasn't any lower.
-But I thought she said, she doesn't need to drink the tea and she has more high blood pressure,
in the beginning. Is that what she said?
-Yes, during the time with Phosphorus it was so, the blood pressure was higher around 110 to 60
and then I didn't drink the black tea but afterwards when the Phosphorus stopped acting and I felt
I would need a high potency, the blood pressure went down again and I needed more the black tea.
In this case again we have the question whether she is still in the Phosphorus state or
we must change the remedy.
Phosphorus definitely has helped her, mostly because, who can say?
How do we know? There are certain things that you have to be aware, immediately as you hear them
you know what is going on with the patient.
The reason why I say it is acted it is because both times when a high potency was given
and also low potency, both times brought back the Chlamydia, brought back a suppressed situation
which is affecting very much cases like this.
Especially the Phosphorus cases are tipped over quite easily.
It is a sensitive micro element which seems to be disturbed very easily.
Therefore, if you give a remedy and brings back a discharge, that remedy is correct.
It doesn't matter what the patient will say.
You stick with this remedy. Both times she says it happened the same thing.
But yet you can see she is better in general but now she is in a kind of a relapse.
She knows more or less the relapse. Is she still in the state of Phosphorus, yes or no?
Do we have any change in her symptomatology? This is the first thing you ask.
If the general symptomatology, yes we have one, what is this change?
The change is that from aversion salt, she now has desire salt.
Then you are asking, is this change pointing to another direction?
Why? Because Phosphorus is one of the main remedies that they really need the salt.
So therefore in spite of the fact there is one change, that change falls within the range
of Phosphorus and you don't change the remedy. It's as simple as that.
Here we investigate the cases quite thoroughly, so we make as little mistakes as possible.
Homeopathy can not be practiced on a mass production level.
You have to take care every time because you are battling not with the symptoms, you are battling
with forces which suppress life, which are coming from different departments.
It's the pollution, it is the stress of life, it is the every day clashes, interpersonal clashes.
It's a lot of things which can over turn an organism, a lot. And you are watching all this
play between life, which is the organism going on, and death which is this pollution and the stresses.
There is a battle so always to keep the organism in a state where it can face all these pollutions,
internal and external. That is why it's so difficult, it's not a matter you have a pain,
take a pain killer, you have an inflammation, you just give an anti-inflammatory drug.
You see how much difficulty we have in keeping up the balance of a person and how easily
is that balance over turned?
What is the potency? Now since she has gone in the low potency LM and seems to be affecting
the case, then we have to keep on going higher and higher and every time she can go higher,
in case she feels a relapse.
These are cases that go like this and then at a certain moment you lose these cases and
then you see them after 10-15 years, they are quite well, they stay well.
Oh you remember me? No, I don't remember you, who are you?
You gave me this, you have treated this person for 1-2 years and then he remains well.
It's the beauty of Homeopathy.
Question? You have 5 minutes to ask a question.
-I didn't understand the potency.
-8LM she takes now.
-No, she went up to LM15 at home, as far as I understood. She raised up her potency
from LM8 to LM 15 by herself.
-Now 16.
-Although she thinks the LM potencies don't work any longer, she needs a high potency?
-No she thinks that the last potency which she took, it exhausted its action.
Now she will go higher. What is higher? Between 15 and higher is 16.
-She said that she has got the feeling that LM potencies don't work all together anymore.
-Where is she? Who understood what I understood?
I understood that the last remedy she took LM15 has exhausted its action,
this is what I understood, is this correct?
-Yes.
-OK. Now another question, did you say that LM potencies do not work anymore?
You said that?
-In the beginning they had an effect and then I had to give higher and higher and then
they didn't work anymore.
-The last remedy which you took did not work, the LM15 or it worked for 1-2 weeks?
-I had this impression that something worked but after now this was gone.
-Then you will go higher like 16,17,18 and if necessary you can take one every day.
You take every day, 15. If it acts for one day, then next day you take it again
until it doesn't act. You go one higher than the last one that you took.
-I had the impression that with LM8 and 9 they really worked the whole day
and this was not the same with LM15.
-LM8 was better than 15.
-She, herself went back to 8 but she felt it didn't work.
She took it in her mouth and she felt wasn't the same reaction as before when she took the 8.
-The main thing is that the remedy has been potentized properly
because Phosphorus is spoiled in the potencies, is spoiled easily.
So you have to make sure that the remedy is really acting.
Therefore what you can do is try a C30 from the pharmacy and then use this instead of LM.
-How long would you expect the Chlamydia infection to last? I think it's a bit dangerous
if it lasts so much time it can lead to dramatic pains and so on.
-It's more dangerous when you suppress it. I don't know.
First of all we have to wait and to give the remedy which is indicated, that's the number 1.
As long as Phosphorus is indicated, she will repeat.
If the Chlamydia now become more and more, then most probably the remedy may change,
in which case we will see but I can not say how long may last this situation.
She spoiled the action of the remedy. Once it was given the 1M or 10M whatever we gave
in the beginning, she spoiled the action by taking all these antibiotics of course in order
to suppress the Chlamydia which came back and now we try to go more slowly to see what happens.
If it doesn't work, then we go higher and higher until we reach 10M or 50M whatever.
-Last time did you receive a remedy?
-I was recommended to continue to take Phosphorus Q8.
-What happened?
-First of all before I start with my story I want to tell that I feel great, I feel excellent,
I have a lot more of self-confidence. Many people approached me here during the course and
said that I had changed so much concerning the atmosphere that is around me, that me myself I
already recognized it about 7 months ago.
-So the interview is over. I don't need anything else. Does she still continue to take the
Phosphorus or did she stop?
-I had Chlamydia already for 1,5 years and the last time that I was here for the follow up
and I too had these pains in my hands and in my joints, my bones and I had the impression
Phosphorus doesn't help me anymore because as I always realized immediately that Phosphorus
was doing something for me, I realized that it has no effect for me anymore;
so I took Sepia in a Q8 for 14 days and then I spoke again with another homeopath
because I still had these burning pain with urination and I had this grief.
I was feeling sad but I couldn't cry and during the talking with this homeopath, he said
you still talk about this old grief which you can't dissolve and then I got Nat. mur. 10M
and then I had a very severe aggravation of my psoriasis.
That was going on for 12 weeks and that was very bad, I mostly had it in my anal region
and in my groins.
I couldn't walk anymore, I was just handling the whole thing with ice cubes day and night,
it was really horrible and at night too I would scratch, it was open,
they were fissures everywhere.
-When this was happening?
-After Nat. mur 14 days later.
-I understand that but when it was?
-November, December and January.
-From Sepia was any reaction?
-A lot of dreams which I would say I can't connect them to my being female.
-Nothing else.
-No.
-The psoriasis was there before Nat. mur. and to what extend?
-I have it since I'm 17 and before taking Nat. mur. I had it in navel and
small spots over my head.
-I see. She can continue. Then she had these fissures...
-I couldn't tolerate them anymore, I couldn't endure it anymore after these weeks.
I couldn't work either. So I took Sulphur Q5 and I took it for 6,7 weeks and gradually went away.
On the emotional side, things were not quite settled. I was still having problems with my parents
and problems with my divorced husband, divorced for 5 years, I couldn't really handle this.
I felt really guilty still and then the psoriasis was so bad and I had to lie in bed for weeks,
I was really dealing with this subject. I was really going into it again and I feel very free now,
very deliberate.
-For how long she took the Sulphur?
-For 6 weeks.
-But now she feels quite well.
-Yes.
Another thing is I took another remedy.
I moved to NY and I was putting things in order in the house and suddenly I found a nest of mice,
little mouse and they built a nest.
Nothing was in it but I had the anticipation that definitely has to be something.
It must be the mouse and I was under tension and suddenly this mouse was right across the room
and I don't know how I jumped onto the bed, which was really physical exercise,
I don't know how I managed this because I needed a lot of energy and I was screaming right
from my abdomen, it wouldn't come from up here, it was really coming from down and
everybody being in the house was frightened and I was all white, I felt nauseated, I was trembling
all over and then immediately I run into the bathroom because I didn't know do I have to
vomit first or go to diarrhea first. Nothing would come out but I was just sitting
on the toilet and I was just trembling over.
All day long I was in a shock, I was wearing boots up to here and then a symptom came up that
I know but I had completely forgotten about it and that is the feeling of being attacked.
And it flashes through my head about 10 times the day but it's just in my head.
I'm sitting on the toilet and suddenly I have the impression I've been stamped from behind.
It's just an idea and has no connection to reality. Maybe I'm sitting there and suddenly I see
a shadow and I would startle and after being in that shock at the evening I got Opium 10M
and immediately afterwards I could breathe again and got calmer.
I have the impression I would have never guess needs to be Opium in my case
but it really helped me a lot.
-Very good. Now how is the psoriasis.
-It never really went away totally. I still have it, mostly in the anal region but I can manage.
-Do you remember the remedies that you took before the treatment?
-No. I was seeing another homeopath and he gave me Calc. carb. and that didn't do anything,
Tuberculinum, Silica and Carcinosin. Carc. was the only remedy that I had the impression that
some action was following.
-Nat. mur. she had not taken before?
-I once took it in a C200 but then I wasn't very much affected.
-What about Sepia before?
-No.
-So Calc., Silica, Nat. mur. had no effect. Carc. had an effect before, correct?
-Yes.
-My evaluation is that Sepia did nothing. Nat. mur. acted very well because of this aggravation,
it was good and I don't know Sulphur maybe also has acted good.
About Opium maybe but at this moment as she said from the beginning she does not need to take
any remedy because she can continue like this. How are her fears?
-Which fear? This fear of being attacked?
-Yes.
-They got less but still I'm a sort of an anxious type, I get frightened easily.
I think all together I'm just a cautious person.
-The feeling of fainting?
-No, I don't have this.
-Nausea in the stomach?
-I would have this as a child for years.
-I forgot to ask her, she had taken before, Ignatia?
-Yes, I think so.
I think I took it in a C200, I'm not sure.
-Yes because the first thing she was telling it was the respiration very superficial.
Do you remember and difficult breathing?
-Yes.
-She had an anxiety during the night.
-True as a child, every night I would wake up screaming.
-Still she has it.
-No, I used to have it as a grown up too. Every 3 months I would wake up at night with a nightmare
and I would lie in my bed not daring to move like nailed down.
-I know but now she has that at all?
-No, it hasn't been there for a long time.
-The clairvoyance aspect?
_There are moments that I have it, I can't make it, it happens to me.
-But before she had it all the time?
-More yes.
-And the icy coldness of feet?
-Yes at night and hands. I always had cold hands.
-She did not think of suicide again because she was thinking a lot of this?
-God thanks, no more.
-And she mentioned this fear of being killed, of being murdered, that fear now she says
is still there but it's less.
-Yes.
-Very good.
-I would like to say something in the end.
I would really thank you very much for the treatment and I think thank you is just not enough.
When I started here I was really in a deep depression and I thought nothing
could have helped me and I'm so thankful that I got help, that Homeopathy helped me
and this four years here contributed incredibly much to my personal development.
Thank you very much.