-I hear you had some acute problems. What happened exactly?
-I strained my left leg.
-Then what happened? What did you feel?
-It hurts when I walk.
-It hurts when you walk. Where? The whole muscle there or in the joint?
-Yes.
-There is any swelling of the glands there?
-No, it's a strain.
I know how I did it. I did it doing some exercises to improve my knees
which were strengthened and it started then but it just got worse and worse.
-And now you have to walk with a cane?
-Well this is just today because my dear lady who runs the hotel she just borrowed that
from her father in law. It just can't take any weight or any force now.
I can stand but if I want to put the muscles on effort, they complain
and they become very painful and then all the walking muscles just cease up
and I' m just exhausted.
-I heard you were taking pain killers? What kind?
-Anti-inflammatory drugs because it's something that helped.
-That means you have done it before?
-As far as I can see or experience this is an acute problem of a chronic problem
that I have and this is a rather vicious attack.
Something that is been going on for quite some years and one way or another,
a lot of the time I feel quite lame.
-A lot of the time?
-Yes, increasingly the last 10 years.
-In the same place?
-No, this is new.
I've had exactly the same thing here, about 8 years ago, not as aggressive or acute
but lasted about 2 years , the same thing on the back of my thigh and the same thing here.
This has compromised my walking muscles severely.
It's a like a myalgia.
-Have you taken remedies for that?
-Yes.
-What remedies?
-If I think back starting the very first one, I worked at the London Homeopathic Hospital
and I saw Peter Fisher and I think the first remedy I ever had from Homeopathy
was Rhus Tox because we thought this is a fibromyalgia.
Then the next one was Natrum muriaticum.
-You are a medical doctor?
-Yes.
-And you have a specialty?
-I come from a long time in general practice and in the last few years
I've taken a different direction, one of which is Homeopathy.
-Very good.
-Starting with Rhus tox that was the first time I ever took a homeopathic remedy and
I was very excited; nothing really happened. This is several years back.
Then Natrum muriaticum, because they were thinking there was a background to this
which we may not go to hear and after that it was the time of my menopause,
so some Lachesis and then I think I gave up from Homeopathy.
This was a lot of aggressive pain which prevented me cycling, prevented me walking
and restricted my mobility a great deal.
It comes and goes. I have an acute episode and I think it's getting better.
I had acupuncture from time to time and manipulation and a range of things
and short of various resolving this, which is a strange thing
because apart from this I'm a very active, healthy...
I think other remedies I've had...
The next homeopathic remedies when I got involved with Homeopathy on a course
in London and we were all looking for remedies for each other and I had some Ignatia.
Then I went to see doctor [name] who is Director of the hospital
who is very elderly and then I had a sequence of things.
When it was very, very bad, aggressive in the buttocks, in my gluteal,
on my walking muscles, I had a sequence of Sulphur and then Dulcamara
and then Cimicifuga without any lasting effect.
-None of these remedies had any effect on you?
-The only remedy that I thought helped me and that's by looking back was the Lachesis.
That was before I went away on a year's sabbatical.
It's very difficult and more recently I've been using much more locals.
Myself I always thought that this was more a ligament problem.
-Did you even have rupture of a ligament?
-No. I used Ruta quite a lot in Arnica as local.
-Ruta and Arnica you use a lot?
-Regularly. Sometimes I thought Ruta helped a bit, I'm never quite sure.
I have to say, when I'm like this I have found the most helpful has been the balsam fir
but that only lasts for a short time and then it ceases to act.
-It ceases suddenly.
-Ceases to act, then I have a break and then I can take it for a few days.
-So pains start usually suddenly or gradually?
-It always seems to be the result of a strain. I had a lot of trouble with the attachments
on the country here, which I think it was brought by cycling but I always cycle
and I think some time I over did it.
-Did you ever take Calcarea Carbonica?
-No. This is a very acute and a very aggressive one.
-It looks as if you have broken some muscular fibers.
-Probably yes and strain the tendon. To me it feels like where the tendon attaches
to the bone, that's an inflammatory process.
I feel as if I have been moving around with chronic tendonitis on my pelvis.
That's what it feels like to me but there isn't a diagnosis for that.
-Most probably you have a sensitivity on your muscular system which is a little bit loose
and maybe strain.
-I have tender spots, so tender I can't bear to be touched.
-In your muscles?
-Generally here and I had extremely excruciating tendons so much that I can't lie or
let anything to touch me.
You know you have the seats in cars and I can't bear it, I have to hold it
and I haven't been able to lie on my side at night for a long time, it hurts.
-So there are sensitive spots on your thighs and buttocks actually.
-Yes.
-You are a more complicated case than we thought. Did you ever get Bryonia?
-No.
-Your general state is good you say or you have some general symptoms?
-This is my thing, this is my ailment. It actually limits my life. It has limited my life.
Apart from that I would say the rest of me is pretty well OK.
One thing that has changed about acute illnesses which we were talking about
and as well this is related because it comes much later, is that all the time I was
a general practitioner and I had my own family, I never got cold.
I was sick perhaps once every two years.
And then I had a little epidemic of grand children and since the last three years
I have had upper respiratory tract infection, one after another
and occasionally they are really so severe.
I had to take some time off work and one homeopathy medicine that really helped,
I had a very nasty tracheitis to one of these infections and Hepar Sulphur helped a great deal.
But this has been very unusual for me although to have infection after infection...
-What was the year that you had the infections?
-The last 3 years since I had grand children. I catch them immediately from them.
-But the pains?
-Much longer. But that's a change in my health. Something different.
-From A group you went to B group. You were A group, you were in good health and
most probably you took some antibiotics...
-Never I took antibiotics. Antibiotics is not been my style.
Pain killers sometimes when I have bad headaches but not antibiotics.
-When you had the first acute that was serious you didn't take?
-No, I wouldn't dream of taking antibiotics.
-Not even once?
-No.
-How you treated the first serious infection,  tracheitis or bronchitis?
How did you treat it?
-Probable a few lemon sips and hot lemon.
It doesn't make me ill, it is uncomfortable but it doesn't make me ill; this makes me ill.
Except one hormonic case that it did but I just had a few days in bed,
took a few codeine I think.
-Do you perspire in sleep?
-Not much.
-If you do perspire, where it will be?
-Yes I do actually. Head.
And there is one thing I have noticed recently, which we look for changes.
It is that I perspire very, very much if I do any physical activity
and I've always perspired here, not much on my body but now if I was to do the housework,
I pour here.
-Your feet are usually cold?
-Very cold.
-In bed do you have to wear socks sometimes?
-I don't wear shocks because I think make me more like granny but I have to use electric blanket.
I get very cold feet.
-Sometimes can be cold and sweaty?
-No, never sweat feet. Sweating very much on head, here.
-Do you take a healthy diet? You are healthy conscious?
-I think so. I believe in home cook, lots of fruits.
-What about sweets?
-Here it might be a keynote. I adore sweets, not chocolate, children sweets.
-Sugar sweets.
-Do you ever crave of anything? I would crave, I would go out at night and get myself
some sweets and I always put this down to not having any sweets during the war
but I do. I can crave for something more than chocolate and more than cakes.
-These Greek sweets like 'baklava' with a lot of syrup, you can take these?
-Yes I like them but I wouldn't crave them. It's actually sweets that children have in paper.
-What about eggs?
-I like eggs.
-In what form you prefer them? Soft, hard?
-I love hard boiled eggs, I like soft boiled eggs, hard eggs, I like omelets, scrambled eggs.
-All forms.
-Yes, I like them.
-Tell me there is any aversion for food?
-I often think about that and I don't think there is.
-How much salt you use in your food?
-Just a bit but I do like salt.
-Not excessively.
-I would very unhappy to eat some chips without a bit of salt on but not a lot.
-Your nails are strong or they are a bit weak?
-I think they are strong but they are ridged.
My father had very ridged nails but they grow very quickly and they are strong.
-Do you have any of your toe nails going in growing, inside?
-The big toe a bit but not much.
-Do you have any fear?
-I fear of someone jump in the dark like most people do.
The fears I have would be deeper fears of being unloved, alone, those sorts of fears.
-Fear of poverty?
-Not poverty. I'm quite happy. It's not being loved.
-What about fear of dark? Are you afraid to sleep in dark room?
-No.
-Are you afraid of a high place to look down?
-Are you afraid when others are close to a cliff? Do you say, come in?
-No, just normally.
-Neither you are fearful of thunderstorms?
-No. I love it.
-You are not fearful of cancer? Developing this or that?
-I have a great fear about the family illness which is arthritis.
-But do you have a hereditary history like this?
-Yes.
-Your father?
-My father and my grand mother very much.
-Your weight is a little bit over. You try to keep it down?
-Well it's difficult. When you start exercising, every time you exercise something,
you strain something. The last few years my weight is more than it has ever been
and I can swim but I can't walk as much, I can't cycle now.
I'm very limited in the amount of physical exercise I can do, I'm very frustrated by that.
If I was normally, I would normally have walk up here and enjoy it.
I used to mount and rock climbing and here I am having to be brought up with the car and a stick.
-Have you find that your muscle becoming flabby?
-It seems to work all right. I can swim, my arms are strong.
One of the things that happened I think, is that when I had a pregnancy,
my rectus muscles sometimes they really split, which I think compromised my abdominal muscles
which compromised my back muscles.
At the time when you ligaments are slackering and eventually I had about 12 years ago,
a horrible operation to stitch up my back again. Really horrible.
-How many years ago, the operation?
-About 15 years ago.
-And how long is that this condition with the fibromyalgia?
-About 11.
-That means 4 years after the operation.
-I don't think I recovered totally well from that operation.
-And after the operation you had some antibiotics?
-No.
-You refused to take?
-I didn't need them. You only take antibiotics to bacteria.
-Yes but here they give it after the operation, it is just routine.
They give in case you develop.
-Not all doctors do.
-There are some wise doctors left over. Very good.
Do you have any constipation, diarrhea?
-No.
One thing that happened that is when you begin to make connection is...
When I had all tummy fell apart with pregnancies and then I did have trouble with the bowels.
When they put the two rectus muscles back together again, my bowel started to
work about 4 o 'clock in the morning.
I think that's possibly why I wake up at 4 o'clock in the morning.
I'm not sure that is because my metabolism changes all the time now.
So I have a lot of that.
-Did you pick up weight after a certain period or your weight was always like this?
-No, I was very slim. In the last 10 years.
-Would you say that you suffer more in a climate which is cold and wet or hot and wet?
What is the worse climate for you?
-Cold and wet. I like cold, I can tolerate cold, I can tolerate heat, as much as I can
tolerate cold but if I get cold and wet here, I cease up and I have a sense of going rusty.
That's how I feel. That's what it does to me and I feel very stiff.
-How much water do you drink?
-Normal.
-Did you have any problems with your glands?
-No.
-As a child you were healthy child?
-Perhaps with all these things, the scarlet fever, I had.
-That's why you are healthy because you had them. Now they don't allow them.
-I had all the exanthemata.
-Did you ever have any skin eruption?
-I had eczema as a child.
-Where?
-Here.
-Back of your knee?
-Mostly all the way up here.
-What age?
-From four and I know I had this when I was in secondary school.
Perhaps until 15 or 16 and then it just disappeared.
-Do you remember how it went away?
-We used to live in Lynch and then we moved back to the seaside and swimming in the sea
this would clear up.  Steroid didn't help much but going in the sea I could come out
and see that my arm looked nearly healed.
-Always the sea was good for you?
-Always.
-Your father is still alive?
-No.
-What age he died?
-82.
-From?
-I think that this was his natural life spam and for a year before his death, he just ...
-Went down.
-It was his kidneys but it was one thing after the other.
I felt that it was his natural life spam.
-What position do you sleep in bed?
-I sleep on my back now because it's the only way I'm comfortable.
-Your menses did not give you any problems?
-Only very painful.
-In the lower abdomen?
-Yes it's like when I had labor pains it was identical to the period pains.
-Every month you had a labor.
-Yes, it was quite bad.
-After the menopause did you have any flashes?
-Not much.
-Your temperature of the body has changed after the menopause?
-Not particularly. A little flash is quite pleasant, it wasn't a bad one.
I didn't have anything that was particularly unpleasant.
-Do you have your luggages now?
-Yes.
I could say what I feel about where I am with this pain. I have a chain of results.
It was more what I did before I left the train 8 or 10 o'clock from Heathrow
that perhaps is important.
-What?
-I packed up my home and put it into a container because my next home is not ready
and I think all of this started when I packed up the family home 12 years ago.
That's when it started.
-When you say you packed, that means you worked yourself quite a lot physically,
to understand that?
-Yes.
-And also what you mean is emotionally you were traumatized in a way or in a big way?
-Pretty big.
-So it was a traumatic experience plus a physical exertion.
That means you had to do a lot of physical work, at the same time feeling sad
because you were leaving your home but you were going to another home
that was not as nice as before? Or that is what you thought?
-The first time is packing up, what I call my family. The whole thing.
-You separated with your husband?
-Yes. So the big family home...
-Different.
-And I did it all on my own. And this is like a re-run, doing the same thing all over again.
-Now you separated again?
-No, this is very good. It's not the same. But it has special qualities.
Now I live on the water. I don't live in a house and it has a special quality to it.
-You live in the water, you mean on a boat?
-Yes on a boat. And I'm going from that size boat to that size boat.
-The water is salt water?
-No, it's the Thames.
-It's a lot of wetness there?
-I didn't think is any more wet than anywhere else. Not unless you fall in.
-The weather in England is sort of falling into the water.
-I often wonder if it has to do with being at the river but I get a lot of relief from the sauna;
it makes me feel like I have been oiled. It's hot, dry heat.
-And you separated from your husband because you wanted or
because you caught your husband with another woman and this kind of things?
-It had become an unhappy relationship and the children had grown up and two had left home.
I remember the next thing that happened quite soon was that my parents died.
In one year it was a puff... like this. One minute was all and then next minute...
-Nothing was left.
-It was a big, big thing.
-Still affects you?
-Yes.
And the noise of these crickets reminds me of family holiday in France.
The flowers, the whole thing reminds me of all this.
-Which were happy times for you?
-Yes.
-Your first husband ...
-I only had one. That's enough.
-With the husband you separated, you do not live together now.
-No.
-Is he alive?
-Yes.
-He remarried?
-He has other children?
-No.
-Your first husband was a playboy?
-Not at all. An unusual man.
-But not going out with women easily.
-No.
When I began to study Homeopathy I thought he was like a Lycopodium person,
he was very much a distance person with people and with the children.
In a way, since the separation and the divorce I think I've been mother
and father for the children, although they have grown up.
-He doesn't pay attention?
-Not much.
-So not responsibility for him?
-I don't see it. Very important is his work.
-And you were the type of the person you will not confront him in case he would
speak badly to you or you will confront him?
-Probably not confront him because if I did, he would just move away.
We wouldn't have an argument.
-Silence.
-Yes. And a lot of drink.
-To release the anger or whatever.
-When he was drunk he would hit you, he would do cruel things?
-No, he just wasn't there.
-Did you ever take Staphysagria?
-No.
I thought about it but after reading Catherine Coulter lovely description of indignation  that's it.
That's the trouble with studying Homeopathy.
-You read a remedy, you find yourself in the remedy.
-Yes but you can't do that, ah it's that one. I thought of Staphysagria.
I think I go into Staphysagria mood and then I come out of this.
-The eczema went away in the sea, not swimming in sweet water?
-Definitely by the sea. I was brought up by the sea side and we swam on holidays.
It was the Irish sea, it was very cold.
-Not in a river?
-No.
-Do you take fruits a lot?
-Yes a lot of fruits.
-What fruits do you love most?
-Difficult.
Apples, bananas, all of them. Apples is the one but they have to be crisp and sour, not too sweet.
-Unripe?
-Not unripe, just nice.
-Oranges you like?
-I like oranges.
-Sour oranges?
-No, sweet oranges.
-But oranges is not your favorite fruit?
-I would squeeze them and drink the juice.
-OK, thank you.
-... with the prescriptions, homeopathic prescriptions. You can be treating a person,
3,4,5 years, nothing happens unless of course you find the correct remedy.
In this case she said Hepar Sulphur has helped her in a trancheitis condition.
And that was the only remedy perhaps that really showed an effect except of Lachesis
which showed a little bit of an effect.
The main symptoms that she has are symptoms of?
Calc. carbonica.
So how is that most of you see Calc. carbonica and the homeopaths who were treating for years
they could not see the Calcarea element? How is it possible?
Definitely we have a Calc. carbonica which is after a period.
Which is the period on which Calc. carbonica starts being appearing?
-Going out of home.
-You may have a grief, show me the grief remedies, ailments from grief.
Usually when somebody has grief, we don't think of Calc. carbonica.
The last remedy we think is Calc. carbonica.
I say what was the symptom that pointed that now a Calc. carbonica is established?
Ailments from grief. You see the Calcarea is there but in small letters.
We have Aurum, Ignatia, Natrum muriaticum, Phosphoric acid, Staphysagria, Lachesis,
Ambrea grisea, Causticum and then we have the other remedies which are italics
and lastly we have the ordinary letters, Calc. carbonica is there.
But you see the idea is, she was given Natrum muriaticum so much grief, no effect.
She was given Ignatia, so much grief, no effect.
She could have said, after a few days, if you have given Ignatia to her and you ask her
after a few days she comes back for a consultation and you say, how are you?
She will say, I think I'm better.
But in the long run after a few months she is the same. Actually there is no change.
The same with Natrum muriaticum. I think I'm better.
Better in this, psychologically, this, that, why?
Because in her case in spite of being in grief not one of the main remedies is indicated.
So therefore if you don't see the symptoms of Natrum muriaticum, putting salt,
the symptoms of Ignatia, sighing, you know how you do when you lose your boyfriend.
He has lost his girlfriend, he knows. Nobody else knows here, you see.
Therefore you search for general symptoms.
My question to you is when, at what time in history, she started being Calcarea carbonica?
-After the operation?
-Yes but not because of the operation.
If you have an operation, you don't need Calcarea carbonica.
-The strain from the physical exertion.
-Physical exertion is a symptom of Calcarea carbonica definitely but I don't mean that.
-When she became the head of the home in the family, a parent in the family.
-No, this is not Calc. carbonica.
-When she left her first home from her husband.
-I understand she had that grief but because of the grief, she would have other remedies,
not Cal. carbonica.
What she said that it tells us that this now starts to be a Calcarea carbonica case?
-I think she had a hormonal disturbance on the pregnancy.
-Like? What hormonal?
-She became more flabby.
-Since the recurrent infection.
-No.
-When her feet became cold.
-When she started to perspire? Because she was not perspiring before and at the time
she started to perspire a lot with exercise.
-When did you start perspiring?
-Well in my head always but not much. Only more recently.
-How recently?
-The last two years.
-You perspire the whole body?
-No, I'm just worse on my head.
I've always only really perspired on my head with exertion, like playing tennis
and so on but more recently it's got much, much worse and at night time.
-At night time you perspire there?
-Yes.
-Since when?
-Many years.
-How many?
-Let me think, 10 to 12.
-You see there are two things which make the case Calc. carbonica. When she starts
putting on weight. She said I was a thin girl. I said, when did you start putting on weight?
About 12 years ago she started.
By that time most probably the perspiration has started slowly.
So you see putting more weight, more perspiration, worse cold, cold feet,
the case is Calcarea carbonica. Now before Calcarea carbonica what was the case?
You take a chance.
-Medorrhinum?
-Yes.
Most probably the second remedy she will need is Medorrhinum.
After Calc. carbonica she most probably, we are not sure, she will need a Medorrhinum
because of this amelioration by the sea.
But now she does not have other symptoms of Medorrhinum to say, first remedy Medorrhinum,
then we go to Calc. carbonica.
Another thing also you have to remember here, in these groups we have all the remedies.
All the remedies can be indicated in each group. There is no group here you say that
the remedy is not indicated. It is indicated only to that group.
The same way all kinds of nosological entities can belong to one of these levels,
you have cancer, cancer, cancer.
The more you go down, the more difficult it is, the more easy to spread the cancer.
Here, when you have cancer in these cases, the cancer just explodes, you can not hold it.
So to which group she belongs?
She belongs to A group, perhaps she has come down because of the acutes,
to the third level where frequent acute starts with B level.
That means the defenses are going down and then they start frequent acutes.
Most probably she's still on A level.
On A level, on third here. Most probably she needs Calc. carbonica
and then perhaps Medorrhinum but her health in general is quite good.
Mentally, emotionally also quite good, in spite of having been through such tremendous grief.
As she says, she packed her house, she lived with a man whom she loved and she has to leave
and pack and take the children, this is very traumatic experience.
In spite of that, not much has been left, still there is of course,
you can not give the remedy of total forgetfulness.
It would be nice if we had that remedy.
Each one would take, forget the past, we live in the now and the future.
So she has a good constitution, she needs Calc. carbonica and we are going to give
the Calc. carbonica and by the day after tomorrow...
Unless it's a rupture, if this is a rupture on the fibers, it's not going to go away
but what is going to go away is the general sensitivity.
But if it is really a rupture of fibers, it will take a few months before it goes totally.
If it's only a strain, it will fix itself quite fast.
I did not give you this case for study because everybody would come back and say this is
Calcarea carbonica. It's not a good case for study.
-In the repertorisation Arsenicum came close. Is that a possibility?
-No.
-I have a question.
If we had met this lady a couple of years ago, because of the tremendous grief,
would it still be Calc. carbonica or might had start with a grief remedy?
-I would have given still Calcarea carbonica. The reason is that I don't have enough symptoms
for a grief remedy and I have strong symptoms for a deeper constitutional remedy,
which was coming all along.
That means in the last grief, which she had, is not changing the symptomatology
drastically in order to go to another remedy all together.
The basic symptomatology continues. It's this sensitivity, this weakness in the muscular system,
the muscular system is quite weak and this we know that Calcarea carbonica is doing
and it is a specific remedy. To give a remedy for grief in this case will not do anything.
-We can start. Tell me what happened because you had some big reaction.
-I think so. One never knows with this Homeopathy. You never know quite where you are.
Stick with the medicine.
-Stick with the facts.
-I took the medicine and that was very good.
I have taken nothing else at all and no coffee and it really was 100%.
-Very good girl.
-However I have suffered considerably yesterday. Not particularly immediately after the medicine
but the next day I knew I didn't feel right. I felt awful, no energy, ill inside.
But I came up to the Center and I thought I was going to faint so I rang for the lady
in the hotel who has been so kind and she came and rescued me and I went home.
And I laid on bed and just collapsed.
With the most extreme exhaustion I think I've ever experienced in my life.
The medicine gave me permission to do this perhaps.
-What else? Some other things are happening?
-I had terrible headache. One of my very serious headaches but I just laid
and stopped a bit and slept. All I wanted is a little fruit and to drink .
-You said excruciating pain?
-Yes I get headaches, very bad quite frequently, not infrequently
and this was one of my headaches. It doesn't really bother me.
-But somebody was telling me that you are crying.
-I had this desire to cry; what I felt pretty choked, the whole week I felt choked.
-But did you cry?
-Only a bit.
I really wanted to have what I would call a good cry but my head was so painful,
I couldn't bear the thought of it. It's a pity.
-So crying would make your headache much worse?
-Yes and speaking.
-You held yourself back not to cry. You don't allow yourself...
-Yes, I've got enough suffering. I felt like having a good cry when yesterday
and when I left here the day before, I wanted just to cry and cry and cry.
-Why you did not cry? Because of the headache?
-Yes.
And because of people, because it upsets people and the lady at the hotel is sweet
but she is a bit mystified of what's the matter with me. I don't want to explain.
-How are you today?
-I feel better today.
I feel, not full of energy, but a bit better but far from well.
This pain is the same and I'm sure it's a tear It feels like I had an operation yesterday
and every step is like this.
That's very tiring, it takes my energy and very worrying and if I'm honest I'm anxious
that it isn't an acute onset of the family disease, which is arthritic hips.
I don't think it is but I fear and I should have to go and have it addressed when I get back
because I think it's silly, not to.
-You should be checking the degree of osteoporosis in your bones.
-I might be.
-You will have to be checking when you are back.
-I'm not osteoporotic person. I think it's the joints.
-Calcarea carbonica maybe but psychologically you feel good today?
-No. The week has been very difficult for me.
-I'm talking about today.
-Today I feel better than yesterday. I feel better sitting here talking to you.
Over all I feel a sense of failure being here and walking around with the stick.
I feel somewhere humiliated and not at all myself.
-But this is not your fault, if you did some exercises and there are some tears,
anybody could have an accident, it's not to be feeling like that.
How was your sleep last night?
-Not bad.
Two hours at the time and then wake up, two hours at the time and a lot of heat.
-Did you perspire last night?
-Finally there is something I remembered. I perspire tremendously up about midnight and
then not after that. Yesterday while I was resting, I was pouring with perspiration on my face.
-The whole night?
-No, just the beginning of the night. And a lot today but then again it' s hot.
-Do you feel more the heat today than other days?
-No.
-This kind of heat is bothering you or it is tolerable?
-No, it's all right providing you don't have to do anything. If you had to work,
if I had to get dressed properly, put my proper clothes on, I would find it very uncomfortable.
-What about this sensitivity on the buttocks? How is today?
-Not so bad. Up until the last two days I've taken an anti-inflammatory and I stopped.
I haven't taken any for two days and this is not bad at all.
In fact I've been lying on my side.
In fact I've got a preference tonight on my side and as the mattress is considerably hard,
comparing with the one I have at home, it's not bad.
-Very good, thank you very much.
-What I wanted to ask you George, is it all right to take any anti-inflammatory or not at all?
-Nothing. Don't touch coffee, no pain killers, nothing.
-Do I repeat the medicine at any time?
-Only in case you feel a relapse is coming.
That means you will check it by the sensitivity on your buttocks and by...
You see the perspiration will stop eventually.
After you go back to England you will have no perspiration and then the sensitivity
also will subside.
As long as the sensitivity is within limits, that means 20%-30% has remained, don't take.
If the sensitivity goes over 85-90%, then you can repeat.
-It doesn't come if I do everything correct. If I was to walk up here would be in agony...
-You try for a while not to exert yourself, let us say for two weeks.
After that you can exert as much as you like.
-So minimal exertion for two weeks and no medicine. Right, you are on.
-Very good.