-You have no information, no paper, nothing?
-I'll tell you everything. Let me just with the pathology first, I'll give you the whole list.
-Tell us what is the problem now.
-It's high blood pressure which I had previously in my pregnancies, I used to have
when I gave birth it was 220-190 in the labor and I was each pregnancy 3 months in the hospital
as a high risk. Then after the first pregnancy I took pills and the high blood pressure stayed,
I'm talking about birth control pills. In the second pregnancy I had the same story again
and then I decided that maybe it's from the pills and when I'm pregnant
and when I'm taking pills is the same story and I had an IUD
and the blood pressure dropped to 220-80 which was OK all the time.
When I didn't take pills it was 120-80 which is normal and last few years I started having
problems with my period and the doctor advised me to take pills again and I forgot, it was
20 years ago, I forgot and I took it about 6 months, then I didn't feel good, I went to
a doctor to do a normal check-up and I found out that I had very high blood pressure
like 160,170-120 and he wanted to give me medications and I said, no way, I'm doing that
and I took a remedy but the remedy story started before because I started having the problem
of the period and gain water, I really felt bad, everything bad, stomach, diarrhea.
-With the pills?
-Before the pill. When I was about 42 I started having a lot of problems, everything came back
like all my pathology from young age came back and the worse feeling was that
I felt sick and I can't stand feeling sick.
-You felt that you were ill, not sick like vomiting?
-Like vomiting, I never vomit but I felt nausea all the times and headaches, diarrheas and
everything was off. Then I started trying with vitamins, because I study naturopathy,
so I have a lot of practitioners around. Everybody gives you something to help you and
I was very down on my mental. Everything was completely down.
Then about 3,5 years ago I got Lachesis 1M, I didn't know what remedy it was and it was
like water, like I didn't do nothing, nothing changed not to bad, not to right.
Then about 9 months later I received Argentum nitricum 7C every day, I felt good mentally
but within 2 weeks I start getting paranoid, I could feel what people think from another country
and so sensitive that it made crazy and crying, I felt that I'm going off the edge
and I took lots of chocolates and coffee to antidote it.
-How long it lasted this feeling of being sensitive.
-About 3 weeks till I stopped it, I just told the homeopath I can't stand it and he saw it.
It was in a seminar we went to Ireland.
-First you felt good with Argentum nitricum?
-Yes, not bad, I didn't feel bad, I was happy to take it every day, I enjoy it.
It wasn't really that it changed the symptoms, at the beginning when I started I had more diarrhea
and problems and a headache and then I took it every day, every day 7C and
then I felt OK it dropped a little bit diarrhea and everything. It's still been 5 times the day
but then when I start feeling quite good, then I became crazy, people didn't recognize me,
my eyes when I looked at myself in the mirror, I didn't recognize me, you know the way you look,
you look crazy, it was really a mental case. I really felt that I'm going off the edge
and I was crying for everything, I felt like people talking, really paranoia.
People talking about me, doing things against me, a paranoia case, I have a paranoia case at home,
so I know it, my brother has schizophrenic paranoia, I have the picture.
So I stopped it.
-It was the fear maybe.
-Of course there is a fear when you behave like this, I behaved obsessive, talking all the time
and the worse thing was the feeling inside. In the end I found out that it was true
but I exaggerated, it was exaggerating the things that happened, the things were true,
no imagination but you can make from a little mouse a big elephant
and normally I don't care about these things, I just pass through it and I don't care.
-When it was this incident?
-2 years ago exactly in June. Then immediately I stopped it, I stopped taking it,
I took coffee, chocolate, I just packed chocolates and coffee, which I hate coffee, I don't drink
I have aggravation from coffee, I never drink coffee and it's stopped.
Then I still felt bad, not as before, that was in June and in December I went to a homeopath
to see what happened to me in June and he gave me Mercury and I didn't feel ease
about the Mercury because all the symptoms are opposite to me and I told him
I don't think it's me but whatever, I didn't read the Mercury, only what I knew from Mercury
from before. And as I took it within half an hour I had hot flashes and
I felt like somebody is watching me, like penetrating me from the back, I had to put a scarf
on my shoulders and then I felt good. It was very funny and I asked him, is it possible when
you take a remedy you open like this, like you don't have covers, like everybody can penetrate you
and he said, yes it could be. Next morning I had very inner sore here and here in
the tender places, like burning and it was half a day I remember lying in bed reading a book
and suddenly I start choking, I felt like I had a lump behind my throat, burning as if something
you have to take out and within less than a hour I had a flu, high fever.
It came so sudden and I felt so bad like very strong bronchitis and nightmares the whole night,
nightmares and choking and sweating, I was wet and normally I don't get fever at all,
for me 37 years I never get fever at all and I felt so sick for about a month and a half.
I've never been so sick in my life and if I tell you my pathology you will understand what I passed before
I was diarrheas and the worse was the lung area, every night I was choking
and coughing, it's like shocking yourself and the nightmares.
Normally for me the night is the best time, I sleep good, I dream, I just put my head on the pillow,
I'm not there. I can wake up for a second, my husband talks to me and
I answer him and I'm gone and it was very bad for me because it ruined my life, I couldn't
function during the day. I don't like to lie sick, normally when I'm sick even if I have flu
I always go to work, I don't stay in bed, so with this thing happened I stayed maybe 2-3 days in bed
and I just continued my life.
I had decongestion in my head and deaf, I was completely deaf and that stays till today.
I feel like in the airplane, the ears are blocked. Now I got used to it, it's already a year and a half
but all the time you feel the things going around you and you blurt, that's crazy.
That's left and after a month and a half, two months I started sleeping again normal
with normal dreams, not crazy dreams and actually that's what happened.
The pathology from a kid, since I was a child I had quite severe illness, as a child
I was a very nice kid, eating good, no bottle with the glass and what I asked from my mother what
did I do, she said, you played with newspapers, you ate them and the only problem I had
was with the ears, I had infections to my ears.
Two and a half years old I had mastoiditis they took out on the right ear the bone,
when I was 7 everybody in the house had Asiatic flu and I had asthma attack.
They gave me (?) and I had a shock with urticaria on the body and I was in a hospital for 3 weeks,
I came out with scarlatina and since then I had very severe asthma attack,
I couldn't do nothing, I couldn't even walk to the toilet.
-Since then you mean till today?
-No, after giving birth it finished, I don't have it anymore, I used to call myself doing like this,
getting inside myself, calming myself, otherwise I would have completely chocked
but always came and started with some kind of allergy, if somebody shaked a blanket the
house dust and I started (?) immediately or if I laughed too much I started (?) and
from this (?) nose running and then asthma and then pneumonia and then sequence.
And when I was 11 this pneumonia turned to atelectasis
when the lungs stuck to each other collapsed lungs
-Atelectasis.
-And I was quite a long time in the hospital with very strong antibiotics and physiotherapy
they wanted to cut a piece of the lung but my mother didn't let them, so it went like this.
When I was 15 I started bleeding from the colon, I still have very severe colds, asthma and
pneumonias and then I had bleeding in the stool and diarrheas. It started with diarrheas
then bleeding by the time I was 17,5 I had very strong attacks of ulcerative colitis,
I'm talking about 16 times the day buckets of blood, getting blood and taking out blood,
5 hemoglobin and I dropped to 42 kilos, which today I'm 90, less than half from now.
They tried for a year, I was in a hospital for a year, at the beginning they gave me cortisone,
injections intravenously then because I got urticaria from the injections, then pills,
then I moved to another hospital because it was getting down and down and they gave me Imuran.
Afterwards I heard that I was the first in the world who tried it.
So I took 1 year only cortisone and then I left home.
-What year was that?
-1968,67. I was 17,5 and when I left the hospital I went to study in Jerusalem,
I went out of the house and study in Jerusalem for 1 year and slowly...
-What did you study?
-Art, painting. I studied since I was 14,15, I studied in the high school 4 years and
I did Academy and slowly, slowly it finished the colitis. I still have diarrheas a little bit
3-5 times the day but it didn't disturb me and then I studied in Jerusalem and next year I
then went to London to study and I still had very severe asthma attacks in London.
-What you were taking during this time for medication?
-Nothing, I just finished with the cortisone and Imuran everything stabilized.
-When the asthma started?
-Nothing, I never took nothing.
-You were rocked like this.
-And get calm, just not to be hysterical because in the minute that you get frightened,
I don't know I used to take care of myself instinctively;
I didn't like this gas and inhalers and all this.
-You mean that never during the asthma period you took any drugs?
-Nothing. They used to give me some kind of aminophylline but I hated it, antibiotics yes,
a lot of antibiotics because it used to go through the lungs.
I think what changed the ulcerative colitis was my understanding because I used to sit with doctors
the they used to explain me what's wrong because I wanted to know why I have it,
explain me how does it work and they said that usually it's a psychomatic problem,
you take everything inside, I was very quiet, I used to take care of animals, I liked animals and books,
I was busy raising little birds catching from everywhere and cats, dogs, that's all and nature.
I was living like intuitively, naturally, I didn't mind what's going on around
I had my books later on where I can read and was inside very romantic books.
-Until what age did you live this way?
-Till I went to high school.
-That means 12?
-Yes, afterwards I also collected every dog in the street, till now I do, my kids do,
it's the whole family problem now, to pick up every poor thing, people also.
-And you say you were closed to yourself until the age of 12?
-Till I had the ulcerative colitis, then I found out that I take everything in, I was a kid that
when somebody looked at me a little bit funny and I thought they are thinking a bad thought about me,
I start crying. Even if they didn't say, the feeling, I cry till now for every beautiful thing
that I see, every story that is moving, music, mainly my husband always laughed at me,
he said you cry also in Buffy and Jody, this story, everything that moves me.
-Easily cry.
-The tears come out, it's nothing I can do, it's something that moves with me.
-That's crying started when?
-Always, as a child yes, I would get offended very easily and
especially if something wrong was done to me.
-Tell me from homeopathic remedies, what remedies you took and what effect they had?
-I took this Mercury which gave me a horrible thing, afterwards I wrote everything down
a month and a half, then I went to Boericke to look, it was like a golden proving, it was so funny.
Then I didn't take anything, that was 3 years ago, then a year ago I started having cramps,
I started having cramp in my throat like chocking, suddenly.
I think left side, it looks like it goes through the neck into the head, I had one incident a year before
that my kids or my husband made me crazy with an argument, normally I don't argue at all,
I like harmony around, I give them what they want and my husband is more,
they are afraid of him, not from, from me they can get everything.
I don't know what happened, I was before my period, I was very angry and I had like a knife
going through all my right side of the body to the brain and then I didn't feel half of the face,
I went to the hospital and they told me that it's nothing, I was afraid that it's a stroke,
they said it's because I was angry, they gave me some tranquilizer and it passed.
A year later this cramp started but nothing to do with anything, out of the blue, if I was dressing
or in the class if I write something, it started actually when I was studying and
then cramps in my legs, then cramps in my calves, it started like a cramp but I can sit, I can walk,
I can go downstairs, it starts and then the whole leg I can't stand on it, it's very painful
and paralyzed. Then I started taking Magnesium and Zinc and Vitamin B6 and it stopped,
I never had that again till I stopped taking this every day, then I started having it again.
Then I used to have in my bag few of those, I used to take them half an hour later.
-Made from homeopathic or allopathic?
-No, vitamins.
-Where they contain Magnesium?
-Magnesium, Zinc and B6. Somebody told me try it, so I tried it and it worked, I took it every day
for a few months and I never had cramps again. Then I fed up, I said how long
I'm going to take these vitamins and then occasionally when I had, it used to come here
and then another leg and then here and here. All kind of funny places.
Then I took Calcarea phosphorica and I was so scared of having again proving or anything,
I took C30, it didn't do nothing but I thought it's OK for me and then 4 months later
I had courage and I took 200, sorry Calcarea sulphurica, I always mix them.
When I have to say Sulphur, I say Phosphorus.
Then a few months later still I didn't feel good, I took 200, again it didn't do much good
then a very good friend of mine had very high blood pressure and she went into coma
she had brain damage and died. Then I was really scared, it was really shock for me.
Till then I didn't care about the high blood pressure, I will go over it, I'll go along with it
but when she died, we were sitting with her in the hospital and I couldn't do nothing
because I found out only a week after, because at the beginning we could give her some
homeopathic remedy to save her, I felt really bad, really depressed and my blood pressure went up.
I checked it, after this incident I start checking, then I had the guts
and I ordered myself Calcarea sulph 1M and I took it and since then I start feeling better.
-You order Calc sulph and finally it worked on what?
-It worked on some things, on some pathologies I had.
-Have you taken Calc carbonica?
-No, only Calc sulp I forgot to tell you that after the second birth I had the caesarian cut
which they didn't give me antibiotics, they didn't cover me with antibiotics,
they put me on special group and I had really big infection and they had to cut the stomach again
and I had to stay a month in the hospital and they found all kind of germs inside, they gave me
antibiotics and after a month I went home with open stomach, pouring in all kind of stuff
and since then I had a problem in my right lower, a special spot.
-Your appendicitis is out?
-No, it was not the appendicitis, it was more up, like a cramp, like a hot knife and
whenever I just move, I can't do exercise for instance, it's like a nerve stuck inside a muscle,
that kind of feeling. Whenever you do a movement that you are not used to suddenly it's like a knife.
The worse was when I was in my period, the days after it starts it starts hurting
and continue for 10 days and it was unbearable, some months I couldn't move from lying to sitting.
The problem was when I used the muscles of the stomach from lying to sitting,
from sitting to standing. That, the last 3 months has gone. If I do like this,
I feel something because I always felt something till it came, it used to be like having something there
but bearable but then in the period...
-You never had been examined by some doctor?
-They did ultrasound, once they saw something white many years ago, so they said it's
probably a myoma hanging out, then they didn't see nothing, then when it was really...
it was unbearable, I couldn't stand it any longer about 6 months ago, they wanted to do
laparoscopy, then I said no thank you and I ran out, I'm not going to touch anything.
Like for instance for the colon I had to do checks ups all the years because it's already 27 years
and all the time they are sending me letters to go and check. I said no way, as long as it's OK
I'm not putting anything in me, forget about it. So they said you can get cancer,
leave me in my cancer alone and I'll do whatever I feel like and I never checked it again.
Only in the pregnancy, the first pregnancy I had a little bit bleeding, my stomach is very sensitive,
if I'm in stress but my work is very stressful.
-What is your work?
-I'm self-employed, I have my own office, we send volunteers to Israel to work to kibbutz with people
and their problems but always you have the stress.
-Like a social work.
-Yes.
-And you do well with people?
-I'm the best in Israel.
-No problem?
-No problem at all.
-Since childhood or after 12...
-No, when my had the ulcerative colitis.
-After the age of 19 about? When this change took place? From being introverted to be extroverted?
-Yes, I decided.
-You decided yourself that you have to bring out your emotions, otherwise you will be very sick
and then you did it.
-Yes, I did it and I don't care and even now when people look at me sometimes because I tell
everything, I don't like hurting people, I wouldn't do anything to hurt somebody's feelings,
sometimes it puts me in a very awkward position because people hurt me
and I wouldn't give it back, I wouldn't insult. That's what my father told me, don't do bad things
to people that you don't want them to do it to you. So I don't hurt people intentionally
even if somebody did something bad to me, I always go to this side.
-But here is a kind of controversy because you said that in your family you like peace
you will not go into a conflict and you pointed out that your husband is more aggressive.
-No, he is not aggressive at all, he is the softest person you ever met, if somebody will
rape his daughter wouldn't do anything to him. He is even more peacemakers than I am.
-But you said that the children are afraid of him.
-Yes because he gives them everything and he knows where the limit is and they know it.
-So he will be angry?
-Sometimes he did things that they made me crazy like if they go against him,
he said if you don't like it, you can leave the house and they take their things and they go.
I start crying and running after them and he knows that he made a mistake because
these things you don't say to kids, sometimes you have the impulse to say things but...
-What I want to understand is you don't suppress your anger anymore or your feelings?
-No, I don't suppress, I'm not impulsive as I used to be, I'm still very emotional
but the logic thing is together. Even if I let myself I wouldn't be here at all because
as I grew up as a child, it pushed up more than the ground could go to my dreams, to my paintings,
I used to do things with animals but that was my love, being in nature, animals, reading books
living in a different world and if I would have let it... I think my husband is the one
who put me on the ground because he is very logical, he laughed to things like this.
Even Homeopathy he is now OK.
-What is your husband profession?
-He works in the Israeli TV, he does all the things for electronic.
-He is not a doctor?
-No, he is not, he wanted to be a film director but he also compromised.
-Can you drink milk?
-I like milk, I don't do it because it's no good for my...All these I put on the last 4 years
since I start studying I put 20 kilos and it annoys me a lot, I feel so ugly.
-You put easily weight?
-I put it slowly, very slowly during these years but I can't get rid of it, I retain water.
Now I start the diet which I think it's good for me and I lost 5 kilos, it's the first time I lost
something, it's the addict to hydrocarbons and it works fabulously for me, slowly, slowly
but it works and I felt very bad about it. Before I took the Calc sulp, I was a nice girl
I felt good, I like beautiful things, the harmony and beauty played a lot and I felt so ugly,
so horrible. Till now I feel it disturbs me, otherwise I wouldn't talk about diets and things,
it bothers me.
-Do you feel more the cold, the heat?
-I'm very hot. If I look back, I was sensitive to cold and sensitive to heat but to cold more.
The last few years maybe it's because of the menopause and things like this, I'm dying
not from the heat, from the humidity plus heat. Normally I'm very dry and I never sweat
and I never drink, I hate drinking.
-Drinking water?
-I hate it, I can't drink water like this, I always have to put some lemon or something but I hate it.
If you don't remind me I can drink maybe 1 glass the day because I know that you need to drink.
On the other hand, the last few months I'm very dried from 9 o'clock at night in bed very dry,
not thirsty but dry, so I have to drink something to wet my mouth.
The only thing I hate, it makes me completely crazy is when I sweat in a sticky way.
In Israel, in Tel Aviv is very humid and the minute it starts getting hot, you sweat and I feel so...
my sweat is funny. It goes from the head, like this, like a shower of freezing cold sweat,
it could be the hottest day and the stickiest day but the sweat will be very cold
the same when I have bronchitis, what comes out the mucus is freezing cold.
It's very funny because normally you would think what comes from inside is hot, it's cold.
Now another thing that bothers me now, the last 9 months, I didn't pay attention to it
till I flew the last flight and then I flew here, a few hours like 3-4 hours after I start
having pain in the right lung, like a knife, very severe pain because I'm used to pain,
I'm not sensitive to pain at a certain point.
-Which point, can you show me your lumbar region?
-Here, exactly here.
-On the lower scapula?
-No, it's under the scapula, here. For many years I have sometimes a feeling like a hand
to the same place, I thought that maybe is the blood vessels, like in sleeping, when a part
is sleeping you feel a numbness. It comes and goes and in the same place now I have
this pain but it's inside the lung, it's completely inside. When you deep breathe is like a
knife but every step which I do with the right leg is a knife. It started in October, we went
to a seminar in Germany and I had very severe flu before that. So I thought it's from that.
The thing is not the suspiciousness, I'm naive and I believe everybody, they signed my life away
a few years ago, I signed to somebody and they nearly took my house and I didn't know
I'm signing a collateral, they told me something else, just to help somebody, I couldn't say no,
I'm very naive. At work for instance, people come and they don't have money,
I always give the money, I never see the money back but I keep giving, so I'm not that suspicious.
I'm cautious sometimes but not enough but always when something happens, I can tell you
what is going to happen and that's what my husband says, I'm suspicious. If he does
something and I see the coincidence, what is going to be after, I say don't do that
because you lose your money, don't do that because something like this will happen.
And he says, you see the black thing about it but in the end it happens as I said
and he laughs but I don't think as suspicious because I can see also the good thing out of it.
It's just that I'm thinking ahead, I'm a very good organizer, I found out after start working
that I can organize everything, everything I do, I do it and I close it with all the little details
and it's very important for me that it will be closed with all the little details, nothing will fall.
So I think it has to do with that, not suspicious, just be prepared.
-What other remedies you have taken?
-That's all, the Calc sulp for that, now the cramps coming but after a few minutes going by
themselves, the last month but the high blood pressure still on and this pain here
bothers me a lot, it stays for about 3 days, I can't move.
I'm sensitive to lots of things.
-Two times you went crazy, it's a matter of expression or it's a matter of facts?
-When I have before my period and in my period a very... Normally I talk quite a lot
but before menses and in my senses I just can't stop, I find myself talking too much and
I feel that people, it's also my imagination, my husband tells me and I can see it.
-So you are very talkative before?
-Very talkative, very excited, about 1 day before and during.
This happened during this period, when I was like this, it was the normal situation
which went 100 times more and very sensitive like you've seen yesterday but that's only before
menses, 1-2 days.
I have another thing which bothers me, since I remember myself I can't sleep in the afternoon.
If I go to sleep from 1-2 o'clock fine but if I go to sleep and wake up around evening
I'm so nauseated and a headache.
-You are sick from a nap in the afternoon.
-So sick from a nap in the afternoon, since I was a kid. Very, very strong. I just hold myself
not to go to sleep, I just hold myself. Anyway I don't do it, only Friday or Saturday
when everybody does it, I like cooking, I like entertaining people, I like to give them food,
I find a lot of things to do and I like to be busy all the time.
I can go on till 1-2 o'clock at night.
-Which is the best time for you?
-Morning is bad, I can't t wake up in the morning.
-The worst? When you feel tired, depressed?
-I don't feel depressed normally, I don't, I just don't think about bad things, I take a book
and go over it but I found out that in the morning it's hard for me to wake up.
I wake up and then I give myself another hour, I am lazy, I have two workers in my office,
so I give myself morning time, I like to be relaxed in the morning, I like to sleep longer but
at night I can stay up 2-3 o'clock, sometimes when I reach 4 o'clock I can't fall asleep.
Since I took this Calc sulph I can't sleep at night. I found out that I'm reading a book and
a kind of wake myself, when I sit like this, I wake myself not to sleep, I don't know why
and then I force myself to sleep at 4 o'clock because I know that I can't go to work in the morning.
If I don't sleep proper for 7 hours, I'm just like this in the day time.
-Can you tell me about the diseases of your parents?
-My father died from... when he was 57 he had diabetes which ended with insulin in the end
and he had angina, then he had high blood pressure, then prostate, then 2 heart attacks
which they brought him to life twice, then he had a stroke and another stroke.
He died from heart attack because the day before he had a lot of retaining water in his lungs,
so he died from heart attack. He was 71 and he was a very strong person,
he'd never been sick till he had this diabetes, he was a very strong person and all the doctors
that with the pathology he had now, he should have died long ago.
One of the heart attacks he had was 12 minutes dead and then suddenly he came back to life
and the next day he ate sandwich and the doctor said to check his heart because
it was funny that it was functioning normal, it should be a brain damage or something.
My mother was a very strong woman, now she is 73, she had colitis, not ulcerative colitis
she is very strong person, now she starts having funny blood pressure, sometimes it's up.
And she has arthritis now. My grandmother from my mother side had also heart problems.
My grand father from my mother side also heart problems and my grand father from my father side
died when he was 42, I think also from heart problems or stroke.
-Do you have any fears?
-That something will happen to my kids. If just a thought coming into my mind that they are sick
or heights or I used to have dreams about waves coming, covering us and the kids,
my heart would just stop. Just a stupid thought for a minute. That's the worse fear I have.
Other fears? I wouldn't like to stay without any money, I like to be secure.
I always go back to my house, I have a house where I have a little bit savings but
I can also spend without thinking, I'm a big spender, if I know that I have the money to spend
I spend and I don't care, I don't count anything, I give, I spend on others, I don't care but
I always need the security. For instance I wouldn't stop my office before I have another
practice to have money coming, even if I'm fed up with something, I always run it.
Because it's a source of security. Fears from heights you mean?
-Yes, heights, dark.
-Dark no, animals no, I love them all except snakes, I don't like to be bitten by one but
I won't run away, I will go around. They disgust me but when I was a kid I had snakes and frogs,
they are even more disgusting.
-Mice?
-Mice not, I'm not afraid of them, if they are whites no problem. The big mice I think they
can bite you, so I wouldn't touch them. Heights? Sometimes I look from high down and it
makes me a little bit dizzy and I wouldn't cross a rocking bridge, if there is a bridge too
high, I wouldn't cross it. Not when I was a kid, not because it's more logical.
-With the time that the sun sets?
-It's beautiful.
-You like this time?
-Yes, I like it especially when you are on the beach, I love open air, I'm craving for open air,
in a room that is stuffy I'm going nuts. I like to feel the breeze, even the draft when I'm sweat
I go to the air condition and do like this and everybody say, you will be sick,
you will be sick, no way I love it.
-Your nails are strong?
-They are breaking a little bit. I never broke any bone.
-Do you have special kind of food that you like, dislike?
-Yes, I like meat with fat but only if it's on the fire, I'm not that crazy about meat otherwise
I'm crazy about sea food, if it's lobster, shrimps, everything just name it. Meat I like only if
there is fat in the steak.
-Do you eat pork?
-Yes with fat. The pork itself I don't like, I like its fat better than the pork. But when I took
the Argen nitric I felt disgusted from the fat. I couldn't touch it, that's good for my diet,
not meat, not butter, it really kept me off. I like butter, I put quite a nice portion of butter
on the bread, I like fruits only if it's unripe, sour, I don't like sweet food. I go usually more
to the sour side of food, if I eat meat I like it sweet and sour, this way.
-But unripe fruits like green?
-If I can pick an apple which is green or tomatoes if they are still green a little bit.
-You like it?
-Yes, I like the sour taste, that's nice.
-Do you bath in the sea here in Alonissos.
-No, usually the last two years I don't go into the sea. I just lie in the beach to get
sun but also with an umbrella on top, I don't like to stay to direct sun. I suffer from that.
-And you don't go inside? Why?
-You have stones and it's very cold, if not I would have gone in. I like it, I love it, I feel so
good inside, fantastic and when I'm singing I also feel happy inside. A lot of happiness.
What do I hate? Raw onions make me belch and apples, I found out that apples give me
heartburn normally I like every food. I'm very good eater but I wouldn't
eat in the sake of eating everything, I like good food, cooked good.
Sweets I eat only before my menses. I can eat the whole pack of chocolate, just before
menses, normally I'm not a sweet eater.
-What position do you sleep in bed?
-Only on the right side. When I turn to the left I feel awkward, if I'm on my stomach I choke.
-In abdomen, do you ever sleep on abdomen?
-I feel choked.
-But if you didn't feel choked, do you prefer?
-Only when I had stomach aches, I used to put a pillow and lie on it but normally like this
like a baby on the right side with the hand underneath the pillow.
-Have you ever been hurt emotionally?
-Many times.
-In your relations?
-When I was very sick, I had a boyfriend and his parents took him away?
-You were born in Israel?
-Yes.
-How do you speak so well English?
-I studied in England, arts. So these 3 years gave me the base and after 11 years I start
working with people from all over the world, so it came back. I remember a situation from
my childhood when I was very hurt, I still remember it, when I was in the first class.
-Because you were not first in the class?
-No, I tell you the story. I have my grand mother in the USA and she sent me water colors
and there was another girl who had this one in the class and one day I came to the class
and she said that her purple color is missing and I had mine and the teacher told me to
give her the little pen and I said no, it's mine, maybe she forgot hers at home, I didn't
steal. And she said, no you took it away from her, so she took it away from me and I went
home crying and my mother came the next day and the next day she brought the pencil
it was at home and then they said, OK sorry but it doesn't work this way, I was 5,5 or 6
years old. I never came into this class, I moved class. That I remember, the whole story
even the table, the color. I don't remember many things from my childhood. I remember
another incident when I was 2,5 years old because I remember the house, that's the age
that we left the house, my father found a porcupine and he brought it to the terrace and
he gave him milk, I even remember which glass it was. That I remember and another
incidence, a happy one, when my uncle came from Switzerland and they brought some
chocolate, I remember it was waffle with liqueur inside the same age as this and
it was singing to me ... I remember even the song that she was singing and another incidence,
I remember screaming like hell. When they had to take the stitches out, they decided that it's not
nice, so they cut it alive again, they just cut the whole place and stitch it again when I
was without any anesthesia. That I checked with my mother because I said, listen I
remember a scene like this, me screaming. And she explained me that it could be this
incidence, then I remember me running after dogs and cats and collecting birds...
-What I mean do you remember having being hurt by a relationship?
-Of course.
-Like boyfriend who left you?
-That was already when I had ulcerative colitis, when I was very sick at the hospital.
His parents bought him a car and sent him abroad because they decided that I have
cancer and I'm going to die, then he came back and he brought me all kind of art books
and presents, it was beautiful to see him back but I found out that in the book he cut the
first page, so I looked and I saw in love and everything. They made him cut even what he
wrote on the book for me and then the next day came and said, listen while I was abroad
you went with somebody else, you were unfaithful to me. I was only 5 days of the
hospital. I knew it's not true, in the beginning he was so convinced he said, maybe I didn't
know what I'm doing, that's crazy and then I told him that it's because of his parents.
I just broke up, he wanted me to meet him in the street, I'm not a married woman to go
and hide, unless you want me, go away. It hurts me and it relapses for 2 months my
colitis but in the end I was strong, I said that's it, enough. Then I decided to change, not
to get hurt so much. Of course every girl has a boyfriend that they break but the
relationship was not that deep then, not involved with sex, just emotions.
-Any other incident? You met your husband and you married? You have 2 children?
-I had before a boyfriend that I loved very much.
-And what happened? He died?
-No, he continued studying, I met my husband and I decided, my mother decided that it's
better to marry somebody who loves you more than you love him.
-How is your sexual desire? High, low, medium?
-I think medium. It depends, sometimes more, I found out that after 40 I was more
feeling sexy than I was after having the children. After having the children, I didn't like it.
Well I never said no.
-You became aware of sex at the age of?
-21? I had a boyfriend since I was 15 but 21. They told me in England that they are going
to make a show, the only virgin 13 upwards, in London, in hippy times.
-But you became aware of sexual matters at what age?
-15. When I had a boyfriend and things like this. I never wanted to sleep with anybody.
It was important for me, the romantic way. That what always matters more, even today
I wouldn't have a love affair, just to sleep with somebody, I have to have the emotions
involved very deeply before I do that.
-Would you say till now that in the evening you are more or less energetic?
-More, from about 10-11 o'clock I'm OK, I can work full, I don't feel that time passes when
I'm working, if I don't do nothing I would be like this the whole day long. I need to do
things, I have to have something that interests me, I feel asleep if something bores me.
I just drop.
-But when you feel more energy?
-I think in the evening, night.
-Evening onwards you feel better.
-Yes much better. Thank you.