-Tell us what are your problems?
-I had a cough for many years, very hard cough.
-Many years?
-Yes, 25 years but not all the time but very often.
-Are you now on crisis?
-Maybe in a way but I have all of a sudden colds, I take colds very easily since my childhood.
-And the cold starts from the nose, eyes?
-Yes from the nose to the chest.
-And travels fast to the chest, one day, two days?
-Fast. This time actually two days. Other times it could start a week before
and then calms down. But when I was a child it was not a cough, it was a cold.
The cough started when I was in my first pregnancy.
I coughed 2-3 first months, I was quite afraid to lose the baby but I didn't.
I coughed and coughed.
-You were in danger of losing the baby because of the cough and the pressure but you did not.
This was the first time when the cough started?
-I think so.
-But before you used to get colds very easily.
-Yes very easily and a lot of coryza.
-Did you have tuberculosis in young age?
-My mother had before I was born. And I was positive.
-What remedies have you taken?
-The first one was 15 years ago, Pulsatilla and it helps my stomach for 1 year.
I think the next was Tuberculinum.
-What potency?
-I think from 200 to 10M.
-Do you have any effect from that?
-I'm looking [doctor's name] for homeopath, I could [doctor's name] he give it to me
but I read it 2 years ago.
I think it was some effect but he changed the remedy, I think I got Sulphur,
I don't know why.
-This is the remedy after Tuberculinum, Sulphur. What other remedies he gave you?
-Then he gave me Thuja 1M and Medorrhinum 1M and he waited for 2 months
and then I got Pulsatilla again.
-The second time did you have any effect from Pulsatilla?
-No.
-What was the potency the first time?
-200.
-Second time?
-1M.
-No other remedies? During the colds what do you take?
-In autumn here I tried Hepar Sulphur. I had it with me, it was D30.
-What happened?
-Nothing.
-By that time you have another cold?
-Yes, immediately when I came here it started.
-But let me understand, give me an idea. You have a cold and a cough.
You have cold and then cough. The cough is all the time, you get a cold, the cough becomes worse.
Is that the situation?
-Yes, that is the situation.
-Coughing, coughing, coughing, you get cold then it becomes very much worse and then
you can not breathe? You have dyspnea? I see you difficult in breathing.
-Yes and I have pain here but maybe it's the muscles because of all the attacks,
they are quite hard and before it was always dry. Now it's loose.
I took Lycopodium in January and maybe something changed, the cough.
My stomach is a little bit better because I have constipation since I was 2 years old.
-When you say stomach, you mean constipation?
-Yes bloatedness very much but much more before.
4 years ago I stopped taking milk products and it helps.
-Because the distention was worse, flatulence with milk. If you take milk do you have
more easy stool or still you are constipated?
-No, still I am. Not that bad.
Many years ago it was a week, 10 days.
-10 days no stool. Afterwards you will have normal stool without taking laxatives or you will take
laxatives and then you will have stool?
-I just take some herbs.
-Every day you take herbs?
-No, I wait, always wait to see.
-How is your energy in general?
-In general I think it's quite good but I have this for so long time, the stomach problem,
the colds, I got pain in joints but it has disappeared.
It disappeared after I eat very healthy.
I was 5-6 years old that I get urticaria here and here and when I was 8 I got high fever
and when I was in the first pregnancy I was 19, the cough started
and I was one time in the hospital to check and they called allergic asthma.
They wanted to treat me but I didn't want with the usual medicine.
-And you didn't want?
-No, never.
-You knew about Homeopathy already?
-No.
-But still you didn't want to treat you?
-Yes I knew this homeopath 15 years ago, I'm now 45, so I was 30.
Yes it was after that I go to the hospital and I checked. But I don't use Homeopathy at that time.
-But still on the school medicine you said no, I don't want.
-Yes, I don't want.
-The cough was certain hour, when you wake up, when you lie down, before eating, after eating?
-Yes, in the evening is worse, night, when I lie down in bed.
-Then cough starts.
-Better to sit up.
-Then you have to take out some mucus before you can stop? How it stops?
-I think actually only this time I had mucus. I never had it before.
-Only here in Alonissos?
-Yes, it was always dry but I had always something in the sternum and if I start blow
I could go on for 5 minutes.
-When did you take Lycopodium?
-In January and I had to repeat it quite often because I was in a depressed situation
and I want to cry, I most work, so I didn't cry and I took Lycopodium because my stomach
was bad and it helped.
-It helped your psychology?
-Yes, very much.
-And Lycopodium did not help your cough?
-No. But it is loose.
-So Lycopodium actually is helping you. We cannot change the remedy because if you say
psychologically better and your cough has become loose, you have to wait with Lycopodium
and see what Lycopodium can do. You have taken Nat mur also?
-Yes one time.
-Ignatia?
-No.
-You take fruits?
-I'm quite thirsty so here it's warm, I like fruits but I want food.
-Solid food.
-I'm very often hungry, I have to eat very often.
-Otherwise you feel emptiness?
-Yes, I feel hungry and I can't think. But I have some suppression in a way because
when I was after the pregnancy I got very much perspiration under my arms.
It was very strong odor, it stained the linen I had to wash 3 times.
The doctor said it's nothing wrong with you and it went on for 5-6 years and I didn't want
to have it anymore, so I asked for an operation and took it.
-When it was that?
-I think I was 29.
-At the age of 29 and at the age of 30 you started having dyspnea?
-It was worse yes.
-Did you use these anti-perspirants?
-Yes but I was so sensitive to them, I get eruption, soreness and redness.
-The perspiration was offensive?
-Yes it was very strong odor.
-You feel cold in general?
-No.
-Very hot?
-Not very hot but hot.
-Feet?
-No.
Before it was cold but I think some remedies did something with that.
-You take sweets?
-No.
-Salt?
-Spicy food but I like the olives and smoked salmon and soft boiled eggs.
But I was not thirsty before.
-Now you are thirsty here in Alonissos?
-Yes.
-Because it's very warm?
-Yes and the last years.
-It's very warm for you here? You feel very warm?
-Yes, here I drink 6-8 liters. I drink all the time but the last 2 days I have to have it
not so cold because it's irritating so much.
I try to drink a little less. Warm drinks help. I got tea yesterday and a little whisky.
-You like whisky?
-It disturbs so much, I had to do something.
-The whisky helps your thirst to be less?
-No, the cough.
-That's why you go out to cough?
-Yes.
-And so I was 12 years, I have a very bad warts under the soles and they use X-ray treatment, 24.
-You mean radiation.
-Yes.
-To kill them.
-It's a long time ago.
-They are painful.
-I have to use liquid.
-Cratches?
-Yes.
-You have any fear?
-Narrow places.
-Like going into a lift?
-Yes I can take a lift but if it's stairs and it's just 3-4 floors I take the stairs. If it's 10...
-Other fear? Dark?
-No. When I was a child yes very. Ghosts.
-You were afraid of ghosts.
-Not now.
-The water you drink you prefer it cold?
-Yes, I prefer it cold.
-But you don't drink it because it makes it worse. You had fear of thunderstorms?
-Not really.
-Did you ever take Calc carbo?
-I think maybe.
One person said take it because of the soft boiled eggs but maybe I did not take it, I waited.
But Medorrhinum did something. My legs get very heavy and stiffness when I go upstairs.
-After Medorrhinum?
-Yes.
-You said that you are a warm person?
-Yes, I need fresh air but fresh air goes here.
-Fresh air is not good for your chest.
-No.
-But you are rather warm.
-Yes but with the cold sometimes...
-You have problems with your stomach like indigestion?
-Yes.
-Pains in the stomach?
-More the distention.
-Not indigestion.
-Yes, heavy and fat food.
-You have any dizziness, vertigo?
-Not so much, sometimes I feel little weak with all the cough.
-The perspiration was mostly in arms or in your head also?
-Only arms.
I noticed for the last 2-3 years that after some cough I get palpitation.
-How many times you cough? You cough 1-2 times or you cough constantly?
-Sometimes just one, a hard one or 2,3,4 after.
But the high fever is gone. It's just cigarette smoke and some odors but the last one was the cat.
-You have sensitivity.
-Yes, the grass everything.
-Do you grind your teeth at night?
-I don't think so.
-And you never had again the eczema?
-No, I don't think so.
-And the perspiration gone totally?
-Yes, before the menstrual period is so little but if I exercise I have much perspiration,
I'm all wet.
-All the body?
-Yes and I noticed after this operation more perspiration when I exercise.
It's more easy to go to toilet when menstrual period comes.
-Do you have diarrhea during menstrual period?
-Yes, it could be the first day. Before I had lots of swelling in the breast but it's less.
-Psychologically you have?
-Lots of stuff?
-You become irritable, crying, depressed?
-It's less, more before, little sadness last evening, going down before menses.
But my mother after the tuberculosis she had chronic bronchitis.
She coughed and coughed every night for years and in the morning...
-She is now?
-She died when I was 15.
-From what?
-Exhausted.
-She was just very weak. She had tuberculosis at the age of?
-I think she was 21,22.
-Did you take Sepia?
-Yes, he had in the paper.
I saw Sepia one time and there was no effect.
-Are you married now or divorced?
-I've been married twice and I've lived with a man for 6 years and we ended this January.
We tried to end it 2 years before but we got together again.
-And then on January you divorced. You did it?
-Yes, actually is both but I asked for it.
-Did you suffer because of that?
-Yes.
-Very much?
-More 2 years ago, I cried for half a year every day.
It's difficult if you are going to work because the lacrimation is swelling like this.
So this time I think I can not do that anymore so I have to do something.
But the Lycopodium helped but I had to repeat it quite often.
-How often?
-After a week, 2 weeks.
-Lycopodium 200?
-200 2-3 times, 1M 2-3 times and when I took it the second time I shaked it and then
I took 10M 2 times I think. The last one I think it's 3 weeks ago.
-I can not see another possibility to advice you. You continue with Lycopodium
and see how it develops. You may, after Lycopodium, you may need again Pulsatilla.
-Another thing, my father had a heart attack when he was 50 and he has been a seaman.
-That's why you took the Medorrhinum.
-Yes.
-This cough because it's very long it's not easy to get out and you have to be patient.
Lycopodium seems to be working for you and we can not change it.
-OK.
-I don't know if it will stop working then see also Pulsatilla may come back
or some other remedy but I can not really tell you at this moment.
I don't have to say more about the case.
Anybody wants to ask something about this case?
The remedy seems to be acting because she says she feels better psychologically
and the distention is better, the cough is loose, that means you have to wait
and see how it's going to develop.
This kind of cough does not just go away like that. It will take time.
Maybe she will need another remedy before the cough really is better but now the remedy is correct,
she has to continue. As long as it's acting, she has to continue taking the remedy.
-I wish to ask you about this case, I think she is taking very often.
I think she doesn't wait maybe enough, maybe she is afraid and don't wait to see what happens
after some days or 1 week and so on.
Maybe it will be better the next time, I ask you, or now to begin with C12?
Because they are so many high potencies and maybe she will go in a proving.
-As long as she follows the rules, that means when symptoms come back, she takes the remedy,
there is no problem even high potency. If she takes without reason,
of course  she may go into a proving.
If the high potency stops acting, she may drop into low potency and try the low potency
repeating 3 times the day 12 or even lower, you can go to 6 and start with 6,
3 times the day and take for 10-15 days.
If it is better yes you can continue but it seems that the remedy is acting.
And many times it's acting, maybe the first dose is acting, we take, we repeat,
we think the repetition is doing something where actually the first dose is doing something.
But if there is a relapse, then you are allowed to take another potency.
-No matter?
-No matter how long. Some organisms are more weak undermined and they need more
frequent repetition, as long as you have the symptoms back. This is clear.