-I have to read you the remedies that he has taken so far and it is Arg. nitricum 200
no effect, Aurum 1M, 10M and 50 M with positive effect, Amyl nitrate no effect,
Bryonia 200, 1M some effect, Ignatia 1M no effect, Natrum muriaticum 1M,
Phosphorus 200, 1M some positive effect, Staphysagria, Thuja, Tuberculinum, Palladium
all in 200 no effect, Acid phosphorus 200 and 1M little effect, Anacardium no effect,
Arnica no effect, Mercury no effect, Baryta carbonica 200, 1M little effect, Bryonia 200
1M little effect, Kali phosphor. 200, 1M some effect, Lycopodium 200 no effect,
Natrum phosph. 200 no effect, Picric acid C30 no effect, Sepia 200,
1M little positive effect, Sulphur 200 small effect, Psorinum 1M, 10M small effect.
Three homeopaths have seen the case. At least you've kept the remedies that you took.
-Yes.
-From the remedies you have taken shall I tell you what is your problem?
-If you want to.
-I can understand but it's a difficult case. No much physical pathology.
-Not at all.
-What is your biggest problem?
-Since I was a child is being extreme shyness. Terrible. As a child was terrible.
Going to school was very painful.
-Do you remember why you were shy?
-No, I remember this is the way I always was.
-But no why?
-Not really.
We had a difficult situation at home, in the family was lot of quarrelling,
my mother was very unhappy, she cried for days in a row, then she was completely exhausted.
-You come from Norway?
-Yes.
-And you have brothers, sisters?
-I have a younger brother.
-During these problems in the house you felt you had some responsibility?
-Yes, I was the preferred child. I was wanted and she came to speak to me about her problems.
-And you knew all the problems from the age of 8,9?
-I can't remember. Probably about that time she started confining in me, I'm not sure.
It was a very heavy load.
I love my mother above anything and to see her in that state
I just didn't know what to do, I didn't say anything.
-But you felt very sad?
-It was great pain to see her like that.
-And you did not cry because of that?
-I don't think so. I didn't.
-You listened to that silently without any...?
-Yes.
-So as a child you became already sad because of the situation.
-A kind of alone, it was a very lonely child, that's how I feel it was.
-You did not have contact with your brother?
-I looked at him as some problem. He was just on my way.
My father said I was jealous of him. Maybe of him.
-Your father did not like you very much, you think?
-He didn't show any kind of affection, he was cool, he was mild person really.
But he was aloof, in his world. School was very painful.
-How the shyness came to the school?
-I don't know.
-You felt inferior?
-Yes very.
-Why? Because you were poor or because you were not having good luggage like the others?
-We were not rich. We were under lower but ...
-Not for that reason?
-There was nobody really rich where I lived. It wasn't a thing there.
-In the meantime you had feelings of sadness and grief?
-Yes. They came more as I grew, my mother got more desperate. She felt worse.
So I felt worse. I couldn't go to school and forget the situation at home.
She tried to leave us. She couldn't stand. Me and my brother was fighting and she said,
if you keep on I'm gonna move away and I was afraid when I came home she was gone.
I couldn't see a life after that. That was the end of the world.
I just couldn't imagine anything beyond that.
-Your mother is still alive?
-She is dead. She's died in 1987. My father died in 1974.
-Your mother what was her age when she died?
-She was 67.
-Your mother as you look back now she was suffering with some depression?
-Yes I would say so but she came out of this state after some days.
It took her a while to recuperate and then she was back to normal.
She was quite happy, she did the same things, she had no changes.
She was back to what it used to be just waiting for the next spell of this.
-As you describe now the situation I feel that emotions are coming
and you are ready to cry, is that correct?
-To a certain degree but not so much because I cried a lot over these things.
In connection with a separation from a girlfriend, it just came up very strongly.
Quite heavily for a few days actually, many years ago.
-Not the last months.
-15 years ago.
-You say that the main problem is shyness. You will not be able to stand up
and talk in front of public?
-I do sometimes and when I actually do it, it's OK.
When I first speak it's all right but preparing for it, before it's gonna happen I'm very ...
-You never received Silica?
-No.
-Next problem what would you say?
-Lack of concentration and memory. That's actually more of a problem in my every day life.
And having to be with people around.
If I stay alone for half a day I start feeling irritable and I feel uneasy,
especially if I don't have anything to look forward to. It's like it takes me down slowly.
-So you are better with company.
-Yes very much.
-What is the problems of memory, can you specify?
-If I have been out working and I've seen quite a few people, so I go to give a report.
What did you see? What happened? It's like I'm blank. What did I see today?
I just have to look at the names and then slowly comes back.
-Do you remember names?
-I have a hard time remembering names. Really hard.
And I might go from one room to another room and when I come why did I come here for?
And slowly OK, maybe I have to go back to the other room to get back the idea.
And if I work with papers is so hard to keep order in papers, it's such a mess.
-Especially keeping order with papers or keeping order in general?
-In general but especially with papers.
-Why is this? Because you feel it's too much work for you?
-Partly and then it's like papers are single things.
They are single pieces of paper and I don't see everything as a whole.
I just see pieces, so I just put them in wrong orders and try to fix my attention
to just one thing and then the next thing and then confusion.
-But your desk is organized or it is disorganized.
-Quite disorganized but I try hard to keep it organized.
-So you don't know where you put papers.
-No, I put piles...
-Piles of papers in one place and then you try to bring order.
-Yes.
-What else?
-Concentration like if somebody speaking I always drift off.
If he just says 2-3 sentences, I go off somewhere and can not fix my attention on something.
It's very hard, try to recall what happened.
-Do you fall asleep easily?
-Yes.
-During talk?
-Yes, not here but it can happen.
Like in meetings if I've said something when I'm through, I can easily half fall asleep.
It's like I'm so excited and then I'm done and am tired and fall asleep.
-You feel mentally tired you will say?
-Yes but it's very much up and down. Suddenly I'm very alert and then it's the opposite.
-Can you memorize if you want to study something?
-Very difficult.
If I read something, I might just look at it and I don't remember what I read.
Or I keep reading and my mind is going and I want to go back and reread it
because my mind is drifting.
-You have some notes there?
-Yes.
-Why you laugh? You remembered something. What did you remember?
-No, because sometimes I feel it's ridiculous. I feel my problems are ridiculous.
-You have any fears?
-Fear of the future and some very high places.
-Fear of the future?
-Yes like anxious about how I will be.
-About your health?
-Not about my health.
-Security, financial?
-Yes maybe financial, general security.
I get very cold in the night, towards the morning hours.
-While you are in bed?
-Yes, sleeping.
-Your feet mostly or the whole body?
-The whole body.
-When did you have that symptom, lately?
-I had it for many years, quite a few years. That time in the morning 2-3 o'clock
if I wake up, I always felt terribly bad at that time.
-I don't follow.
When you are in bed and you are asleep, you suddenly wake up and you feel terribly bad?
-Yes, if I have to go to the bathroom. I usually wake up once or twice. I get so worried.
I concentrate maybe on a small thing and I feel like it's the end of the world,
I just feel so bad.
Even if my dreams are fairly OK but very often my dreams are also at that time, very bad.
-You say you wake up from sleep in a state of anxiety or fear?
-Anxiety, depression, like the future is black.
-Not that you wake up in a fright.
-No.
-Are you homesick?
-In general you would say you feel more the cold or more the heat?
You are more comfortable with the heat?
-With the heat.
-So it's a person who need a lot of covering.
-At night definitely.
-More than anybody else?
-Yes.
Even in summer I have thin [blanket] It's almost like it's worse when I'm at home.
When I'm out travelling, living with somebody else it's not so severe.
Neither the depression, nor the coldness.
-Do you have any notes concerning your desires, aversions for food?
-Yes. I like sweets, I like cakes, chocolate.
-Strong?
-Yes it's strong.
-Another?
-Fruits I like very much.
-What kind of fruits?
-Sweets fruits.
-Another? Salt?
-Yes I take quite a lot of salt.
-Have you checked your blood pressure to see whether it's normal?
-Yes I have. I think it's fairly normal.
-The diastolic, the minima is towards the high side?
-I don't know actually. I had checked it a few years ago, they said it was normal.
-You are now...?
- 45.
-Like now I'm trembling with cold.
-But you are not dressed either, it's cool.
-Yes but when I'm in a pressed situation I easily tremble of cold, even if it's not very cold.
-Salt desire would you underline it?
-I'm not very fond of milk and I have aversion. I never liked milk very much.
-What about the sun? Can you stand lying under the sun or also the sun affects you?
-No, I like the sun.
-You don't have much in your country either.
Do you have anything else in your notes?
-Yes.
Those dreams are also like I'm not good enough. When I have these dreams at night
are also like I'm not good enough.
-In the dreams?
-Yes.
I feel inferior and unable to do whatever I suppose to be doing.
In the morning when I wake I feel quite OK, when I sleep enough I feel quite OK
but I don't want to talk to anybody. I just want to stay and wake slowly.
-In the morning you don't like company.
-No I don't. I want to slowly wake up and not talk to anybody, listen to the radio.
Then if I don' t go out working, if there is nothing to do, I get either very anxious
about that time 10-11, I need to do something or the other way around I get very sleepy
like if I start reading. That 's the worse thing I can do.
If I start reading, I get sleepy.
It's not that I might so much the company in the morning, it's that I don't want to talk,
I don't want to say something.
Sometimes I smile about serious things, I feel I'm expected I will be smiling over serious matters.
-Tell me something else.
-When I'm in a very bad state like when we are out eating in a restaurant
me and somebody else, I don't want the people of the other tables to hear what
I'm saying. Even though it's not important things, I just don't want them.
I think I don't want them to hear how weak I am, my weakness.
I was very late maturing.
-Why you say that?
-I suck my thumb, I was 12 years.
-Sexually when you became aware? At what age?
-Quite early I suppose.
-10?
-Probably yes.
-Have you been married in the meantime?
-Not married.
-You just live together, from time to time with different people or just one?
-No, I've been with 4.
-Do you ever talk about your sexual matters with friends?
-Not really.
-You never got Pulsatilla?
-No.
-How much water do you drink?
-Quite thirsty. I drink mostly when eating. Half a liter during meal.
-And you drink a lot during that time?
-Yes.
-You say like one liter?
-It could be yes, half a liter or more.
-The water has to be cold?
-Yes but not ice cold.
At night when I wake up I have to have just a sip of water because it's all dry inside.
I can feel the cold water coming down into my stomach it feels very good.
-Otherwise you feel dryness in general?
-In general the day time, no. At night only.
-Do you drink also, except of meal, do you drink tea or cold drinks during the day?
Do you need?
-Sometimes.
-How is your digestion?
-Very good, I never had problems.
-No constipation?
-Never.
I would say rather on the contrary.
-And the stool is not formed?
-Normally formed.
Also when I wake up at night, my eyes are agglutinated. I have to pull them apart.
-Every morning?
-Not in the morning but in the middle of the night.
-Are you restless or you are rather calm?
-It depends on the situation. At home I would say I'm quite restless, when I'm alone.
When I have company, I don't feel that so strongly.
Also when I've been alone for a while and go back to see people, it's like my voice gets very thin.
-As if it's constricted.
-And the smiling is maybe involuntary.
-Involuntary or you are thinking something when you are by yourself and then you maybe smile?
-Maybe but it's more nervous when I'm with company
or when it's something expected from me.
When I go into a room with people and they all look at me then I might smile.
It's almost like I can not stop it. It's strong.
-Something else have you noticed?
-My tongue is usually white coated.
-Can I see it? Yellowish -white especially in the back. Do you have any salivation?
-Actually I did have before. I think it was clear but it felt sticky.
That was before different remedies.
-According to your report the remedy that has helped you most is Aurum.
-Yes, undoubtly I would say so.
-And it has worked to a certain level. What it took away? The deep depression?
Suicidal depression?
-I thought a lot of suicide as a relief but I knew I would never do it.
But I kept thinking, I wish it's over, I wish it's over.
-Would you say you are religious?
-Not particularly.
-Praying, did you have that?
-No.
-Always when I get a cold I get swelling of tonsils. A lot of cavities I have.
My teeth are really bad, a lot of toothaches I've had since childhood with pain
sometimes extending up to temples.
-Always your pains extend to temples?
-Not always but sometimes it takes a long time, until I go to a dentist, so it starts shooting.
-Always your tongue is like that ?
-Yes.
-But your digestion has no problem?
-Some flatulence, like with company if I feel stressed...but that's not a big problem.
-You never took Sulphur?
- I took Sulphur.
That's the remedy that had negative effect.
I got some headaches afterwards that lasted for quite a while,
it was very uncomfortable with Sulphur.
-What about acutes? Do you get acutes?
-Sometimes.
-How frequently?
-Once a year.
-What type?
-Flu quite strong. It doesn't usually last very long.
-As a child did you take antibiotics?
-Not much I think.
I had some bad back pains when I was 10-12, at night. I couldn't sleep.
So I got heavy duty pain killers but then it disappeared. I don't know for how long I got it...
-And it was lower back or the whole back?
-Middle back in bed.
-While sleeping or even if you lie in bed the day time?
-No, I remember it to be only during the night but I'm not sure.
-Otherwise do you remember other remedies, vaccinations?
-Vaccinations I've had. I'm naturally positive to tuberculosis.
My father had tuberculosis when I was very small.
-You were born already.
Are you afraid of high places looking down?
-Yes very high places. If it's very high, I feel very uneasy.
-And some vertigo also?
-I feel it to my guts, not really vertigo.
-Do you eat eggs?
-I like eggs.
-What type of eggs?
-Soft boiled.
-Why you laugh?
-Now I don't know.
-Because it's really something which is strong?
-No I like eggs, not very strong.
-You thought of Calc. carbonica?
-Yes I thought of Calc. carbonica right now.
-Did you think like this?
-I don't think it's my remedy.
-I see. How strong you would put this? You can eat every day?
-I don't do it, I could. I eat several times the week.
-Two eggs every time?
-Yes. Mostly fried or soft boiled.
-Any perspiration during night in your back?
-In the summer I do and it's like cold perspiration.
-In your feet do you have any cold perspiration?
-Yes always my feet are cold and perspire a lot.
-Is offensive perspiration?
-Not particularly.
-The perspiration eats up the socks?
-No it doesn't.
In the summer I have big covers and I perspire and I perspire cold.
I can put my hand and I feel cold and clammy.
-In the summer?
-Yes.
In the back, everywhere. Maybe not every night.
-What about onions, if you eat raw onions, do you have any problem?
-No problem.
-Tomatoes?
-No, it's OK.
I'm not very fan of tomatoes though these tomatoes here are good.
-Lemon you like?
-Not particularly.
-Between salt and sweet which one you put more?
-That's difficult.
-Almost the same? You would underline both two times?
-I always put extra salt on the food. Sweets I like very much, especially chocolate.
But then I have times that I don't eat it like now, I don't eat much. But I like sweets.
-How is your sexual desire?
-It's very strong.
-If you have sexual intercourse, afterwards you feel good or you feel bad, tired?
-No, I think it's OK.
I had some pain in my right testes. Not serious pain about 22 years ago.
Then in a period of some months I had it.
-And it reappears now?
-Yes.
-Did you ever have any gonorrhea?
-No.
-Infections?
-Maybe yeast infection with my girlfriend at the time.
All my childhood it was very bad;
when I got 16 I just felt I had to get away from the family and I went away.
-You went to work?
-I went to the sea.
-Fishing?
-No merchant, was very good for me, I liked it even though I still had some problems.
It was still a step forward for me.
-After that you changed professions?
-Yes, I've done different things.
I was always very attached to my mother, even if I was far away I felt very strong bonds with her.
-When she died did you cry?
-Yes I cried.
-For half an hour?
-For some days.
I had some spells quite deeply. I was away then and then I came home
and very soon it became OK.
It was all right but I still for years dreamt of her that she was alive, we were together.
These dreams I had up to recently.
But I also think I never forgave her for threatening to leave.
That's part of the reason why I left, like I wanted to punish her for doing that to me.
-She made you feel very insecure all these years that you may be abandoned.
Do you have fear of being abandoned?
-I had very strong fears of being abandoned.
I pick my first girlfriend looking at that thing very much, I knew that she wouldn't leave me.
That was one thing but there were other things too.
I went in the same pattern, I wanted to help her like I helped my mother.
It was her life that was important, so I was there for her. I did everything
and then it got just too much.
-She drew some energy, too much.
-Yes and then at a certain point I said, this is it, I can't give anymore. I got to get out.
That's when I cried terribly, deeply and gratefully. I felt good for months afterwards.
We separated, we got back together again but it was on different ground.
-More on give and take.
-Yes more but still it wasn't very good and finally we broke up.
But she is actually one of my best friends now, this is a long time ago.
Also I couldn't get another girl until she had got another man.
As long as I was number 1 I couldn't let go her and I knew she had to get another one
so I had to feel that pain before I could be free.
It took a while but it happened, it was very painful, when she got another man.
I realized this is serious, she cares more for him than she does for me.
-That became painful.
-Yes and almost for a week I was awake night and day and then suddenly I could start crying;
so I cried it out.
-And then you felt OK?
-It was OK, I cried for some time within a few days and then it was OK.
-You like consolation?
-I'm not sure.
If there is a problem, if there is something where I'm really hurt I want to fix it myself,
I want to take care with myself.
-You don't want interference?
-Yes, I want to show that I master it.
-OK.
-Thank you.
-He had some peculiar symptoms. You can read from here.
Is anybody that wants to insert in this repertorization another symptom?
-I feel that I miss one rubric and this is my feeling that in his childhood, he was...
-Given a lot of responsibility?
-Yes and I couldn't find.
-I agree. We don't have that symptom.
-So when there is an ailment from that what do we do about it?
-We don't have.
-I think Carcinosin has.
-No.
The rubric we don't have it in the Repertory. Ailments from too much responsibility.
As a child, he was given a lot of responsibility, we don't have that.
Taking responsibility too seriously.
-Self-confidence, want of.
-Put want of self-confidence.
How many times you want to underline it?
-3 times.
-Here in Murphy mind responsibility, burden with too young of age, Calcarea and Carcinosin.
Could that fit?
-There are a couple of rubrics I would like to add; one is untidy, accepting what is performing.
He mentioned that he is very untidy throughout.
-Do we have such a symptom? Where?
-It says untidy except in what he is performing.
-This rubric is there? What are the remedies?
-There is just one remedy, Carcinosin.
-Very good, put that.
-There is also another rubric which is ailments from prolonged and unresolved grief
and it seems the thread of this case when even though he left for the sea,
maybe it's also an indication of what he left for, but when his mother died,
he continued to have dreams for years after her and the dreams were that she was still with him
and still having relationship with her.
-If you want pathology wise to characterize this case, what you would say?
It is a case of depression? Grief?
-Grief, a lot of grief. Give him Natrum muriaticum, finish.
-During the case taking he once said that he hates his mother and that by leaving home
he wanted to punish her for her threat that she had given to him in advance.
That's something I think we might have to add in the rubrics.
-He hated his mother. It is an expression, wait a moment.
We have to go to the real meaning.
He was very sad because his mother threatened him to abandon them and he was not hating,
he loved his mother. He was attached to his mother but every time mother is leaving...
mother is leaving. This is not hating.
And finally he said, OK let me leave, see how you feel. This is not hatred.
It's something different. I didn't perceive it as hatred of the mother.
-The way I remember that the patient said, he didn't say I hated my mother
but he said I couldn't forgive my mother for doing this.
-I think that if he hated his mother, he would not have suffer so much after her death.
It's very obvious that he loved, he was attached to his mother very much.
That's why he suffered a lot. These are the facts.
Now the fact that he was suffering all these years by the threat of his mother,
threatening him that she will leave, it is a fact.
He was suffering because of that but I didn't perceive that he was hating his mother.
The case, as it was developing, let's see the different remedies that came to the mind.
He has received a lot of remedies already.
The remedy that I was thinking in the beginning was Silica
because of this tremendous shyness and Pulsatilla also. These were two of the remedies
that they were coming up.
Eventually there was another remedy that appeared because of lack of concentration
and the difficulty and the memory and especially because he had a keynote symptom.
In the morning when he wakes up, he doesn't want to talk and that is a symptom of Alumina.
Alumina is having a similar type of mind as is the one that he said.
I can not concentrate, I can not remember, I read and I don't understand what I read,
I forget etc.
Eventually the idea of Baryta carbonica also was there
and finally the idea of Calcarea carbonica.
As far as I remember these were the remedies that were going through.
The possibility of Lycopodium, smiling etc. you may have been thinking of Lycopodium.
And also in the repertorization Calcarea carbonica is very strong and then Sepia of course.
Sepia was another remedy but Baryta carbonica and Sepia, if I remember well were given already.
The possibility of Sulphur also, I was investigating as well.
Especially with agglutinated eyes, ice and things like that.
-He had Sulphur.
-He had Sulphur with bad effect. Lycopodium had without any effect,
Sepia I don't remember he had Sepia?
-A little bit of an effect.
-And the most of the effect was from Aurum, where he felt better.
That means that that was a case of depression. Now is the next layer.
Say, he would have come originally to us, most probably we would have given Aurum
because the type of depression that he would present during that time,
would be much stronger than the depression he is showing now.
Now he is not showing that he is in a deep depression.
That there is some grief the brain is tired, he can not follow, he can not study,
he can not remember etc. but you can not say that this is a deep depression.
Actually what we're trying now to find out is the underline remedy after Aurum.
It's very interesting and we have said it many times that a similar remedy,
a remedy which is close may have some effect and therefore people will say,
I felt a bit better in this and a bit better in that.
But actually going right to the center and prescribing for the layer,
the real layers Aurum was prescribing upon the layer.
Aurum was put on his back by the behavior of his mother.
You see, the same behavior in another constitution, it would have made the child Veratrum album.
And another, it would have made the child Lycopodium, Ignatia, Nat. muriaticum.
You see how each organism gives its own peculiarities.
So there seems to be some confusion in the case because of having received so many remedies
and some of them having an effect but still I maintain that the remedy is quite clear
and therefore you have to study the case tonight and tell me what is the remedy.
I would like to see who prescribed Lycopodium? Who prescribed Baryta carbonica?
One. Who prescribed Calcarea carbonica? Who prescribed Alumina?
Who prescribed Pulsatilla? Who prescribed Silica?
So Calcarea carbonica and then Silica is the choice of the class.
What about me?
He does not look like Calcarea carbonica, he looks like Silica more.
He is quite cold, he is perspiring a lot. Both Calcarea carbonica and Silica they feel cold,
they perspire a lot.
What is the difference between the Calcarea perspiration and the Silica perspiration?
-Silica is more offensive.
-And Calcarea is more clammy.
The Silica has definitely more offensiveness, the perspiration is quite acid
and it eats up the socks.
When there is a lot of perspiration with Silica.
So here the perspiration it goes in favor with Calcarea carbonica.
He is very shy. What is the difference between the shyness of Silica
and the shyness of Calc. carbonica?
Silica, as you remember, is shy mostly in front of the public, when she has to perform
when she has to give a speech.
I can not be Silica. Forget it. Silica will be much more organized.
I walk, I do my hands, not very much shyness. I have but not very much.
In the Repertory also, if you open the Repertories, it shows very strongly
and there is also a kind of, how can I say? The shyness which contains some intelligencia.
Intellectuals with shyness.
Self-conscious, lack of self-confidence and what shall I say?
Calcarea carbonica is not known as a remedy for shyness.
You will not of Calcarea carbonica when you have shyness.
You have other remedies to think when the main problem is shyness.
He says my main problem is shyness.
So it's less intense and in the end perhaps he brought out an information
that was more specific.
I'm not sure, I want to confirm now, whether he was saying that I feel the others
and what they are thinking and to that I am quite shy.
Can you specify more?
-If I'm in a bad state I don't want them to see how I feel,
I don't want them to see the weakness of my eyes, I don't want to show my vulnerability.
-Yes but is this what you call shyness or what you call shyness is something else?
-This is the shyness I would say.
-So this kind of shyness fits again not with the Silica shyness
but with the Calcarea carbonica shyness.
We had a symptom for Alumina, he said my mind does not function.
Now maybe you have not seen a case of Alumina but does Alumina speaks in this way?
-No.
As I have performed Alumina or you have seen a case, Alumina speaks much more slow
and the constipation is coming out of words.
It's not stammering, it is an effort to think that is it so, I don't know, maybe.
This type is the Alumina mentality.
He is not. He gave straight answers. Then I asked are you constipated?
Let's forget that his mentality is typical, let's see if his digestion is typical.
He says no, my stool is lose and normal. Out of the window Alumina.
In this way you differentiate quickly and then you say Alumina is worse heat.
Another question. Are you worse heat or cold?
No, I'm worse cold but I'm perspiring. And what is the perspiration?
-Clammy.
-What is further? Cold.
I take this and my feet are cold and clammy, the case is finished.
Then you ask about eggs. I would have like to show you again this reaction.
Eggs everybody likes but when there is an excess in the liking, there is this spark
that comes with the feeling. There is the feeling, well I like eggs. Soft.
On top of all that it was coming the soft eggs and on top of all that came what else?
What else is characteristic of Calcarea carbonica?
I do it by memory, you have studied the case, I have to do all the work.
-Fear of his condition being observed?
-We said that but one more symptom which confirms again Calcarea carbonica
which he spoke about?
-Sweet and salty and fear in the high places.
-This is typical for Calcarea carbonica. Fear or vertigo high places is typical.
It is typical for a few remedies, not only Calcarea carbonica but let us say
how many Calcareas have fear of high places? I can say between 70-80%.
It's very high 80%, if a symptom is always there, is very strong
and when a person gives you that symptom, which confirms all the others,
that makes definitely a case of Calc. carbonica.
What is not typical of Calc. carbonica for his perspiration?
-That it's not at the back of his head, in the neck.
-That is not here. You like to see the perspiration on the cervical region mostly.
So when you say where do you perspire, he puts his hands there.
He makes this movement.
He made this movement. This is not typical but still is this.
You see how subtle you have to be and at the same time put things together
from different angles? Don't leave it only to perspiration.
Clammy perspiration, Calc. carb.
Not like that. You have to have all the other symptoms.
And then you have the slowness of the mind.
There is definitely a slowness of the mind which he says, Calc. carb. is OK.
The shyness is OK.
That is why in the Repertorisation, which I showed you, it came very prominent.
So Calc. carb. in this case, what potency? Who says 200?
Who says 1M? Who says 10M?
You are learning. Who says 50M?
You can do 50M. In this case you can easily do 50M, no problem.
This is how you learn. Why? Because you know the why also, why you say 10M?
You don't just say 10M. You know why?
Because his pathology is mostly on the mental-emotional, there is no physical pathology,
as far as we can understand and therefore 10M or 50M is a potency
that can be given easily in his case.
So you have to take one dose of 10M and one 50M. So all the class is satisfied.
And see when you come next time, you better give a positive follow up.
Otherwise the students will require this to be played back.
-A question please. I found typical, instead of Silica, he had fear for the future,
for Calcarea, a lot of phobias and instead of Silica...
-Very good. That's another point for Calc. carbon., fear of the future and fear of poverty.
Calcarea is one of the main remedies, with Psorinum, with Sulphur, with Calcarea-flourica etc.
The Calc. carb. is also there and he expressed his fears in future and in financial matters.
We have a typical case of Calc. carb. in which he has been given for 3-5 years
all the other remedies except of Calc. carb. Why is that?
That I am very concerned and very disappointed?
What happens? They are not my students?