-You got Phosphorus.
-30C on 24th of June at 02:00 o'clock in the morning after I came home.
-1996, 15 months ago.
-I had quite a lot of aggravations during the next weeks.
-For how long all together was the aggravation period, 3 weeks?
-Till beginning of August.
-Actually 5 weeks different aggravations. Can you mentioned some of them?
-The first thing was I was very confused. I couldn't even find my keys that I put it in a
certain place, it took me 2 days to find them and I looked there.
And I had urine in my blood the next day.
-You had blood in urine.
-Yes, I was very tired, I had stomach ache, gas, constipation, which is funny. I couldn't
hold myself awake till 6 o'clock in the evening, I actually fall asleep. For 2 days I slept
most of the day. I had to go to work but immediately as I came I went to sleep which
normally I'm awake until 2 o'clock in the morning, I was so tired.
Very confused, I felt very bad like nauseated like in a pregnancy, headaches,
constipation, gas like big stomach, it was like blocked. Mainly tired, no appetite, dizzy.
I didn't get my period for 2 months. When I was here in June I had it on the 14th of June
and it didn't come, while it was the seminar and then I didn't have until the first of July.
I had a pain in the neck, a pain that comes from the hip, I woke up in the morning, it was
a pain from the hip up to the neck into the head. It was exactly the same pain as I had
4 years ago when I had Whiplash and I suffered for a month and a half till I had bioenergy
treatment and I got rid of it for 4 years. That was the first time it came again but it took
1 day and it went. It's gone when I took a pain killer. It was so severe.
-What pain killer you took, aspirin?
-Maybe aspirin or... or Ibrufen,  one of them. It was for 3 days and then I took a pain killer.
After I got the period I lost 2 kilos, I was so bloated and on the middle of July was the
first time that I managed to sleep in the afternoon without having a nausea. For me it was
beautiful because since I was a child I couldn't sleep in the afternoon without having it.
Then something else started, in the middle of July was one of the biggest aggravations
I had, it was pain in the jaws, up right side, top and bottom one but it's not a certain tooth
that hurts, it's both of them, half the face. It was more the jaws, underneath the tooth
like rheumatic, like toothache, very strong which took quite a long time. It came and go,
came and go for about 2 weeks.
Together with this it was at 8.30 in the evening when I was in the middle of a dinner
it was my in-laws my daughter supposed to get married and then an hour after the tooth
pain started the pain in the chest. It was in the left side, like I used to have in the right
side. It was in the left side and very strong and the tooth together and then at 10 o'clock
I went home, it was so severe that I took a painkiller, then it reduced. In the morning it
continued and at noon the next day, it moved to the right. Stops in the left, starts in the
right and stays there for 3 days, again like it used to be before.
Funny enough I spoke with somebody in the bus, she asked me about the atelectasis
that I used to have when I was 11 and she asked where it was and
then I remembered it's the same place, the same pain, the same cut, it was like a knife.
And now when I think about it, it's the same thing.
Anyway the pain was by movement, when I sleep I couldn't move a cm, even not thinking
about moving. It was so severe and it unabled me to stand up, to move, to function.
Normally it took 3 days. Till then I used to have it only after flights, maybe after exhaustion.
After that it started a few more times during the period, till now. I had it in August,
I had on the 10th of September after my daughter's wedding. At night it was the wedding,
in the morning I woke up with the pain and on the flight here in September 9 days after.
Since then I didn't have it in the right anymore. That's the aggravation. After that I felt good,
the ears and the stress on my head gone all together, the well-being was beautiful,
my memory came back, I was more clear on studying, it was more easy for me to study
and to remember what I studied because normally I used to read the Materia Medica,
understand it beautifully, after 2 hours I completely mixed it with others.
It was very disturbing this. It was fine and then about October we studied at home with friends
and suddenly one of them told me that I look bad, that I'm very red and she was very worried,
I felt good, I didn't feel bad, I run from the kitchen to the study room and I
checked my blood pressure and it was very high. She was very concerned, she took
some symptoms and a few days later she gave me a remedy. I asked her what it is, she
didn't want to tell me. I took it and then within a week or something I started feeling bad
really bad, lack of the well-being, I saw really a big difference.
-Still today you don't know what it was the remedy?
-I thought that it was Sulphur because of the things it gave me and another homeopath
when I explained, he told me it was Sulphur and she was talking about all the time that
she thinks that I'm Sulphur and not Phosphorus and I'm sure it was Sulphur. After I asked
her I felt bad and I asked her, please tell, I need to know, she said I gave you a placebo
because I wanted to see how autosuggestive you are, to prove it. I don't think it's right
because she was quite concerned about my health and I don't think if somebody is that
concerned will give you a placebo, just to check you. It's stupid but that's what she says
and she keeps saying till now.
Anyway I had burns after I took it, all my body was burning and then I had underneath
the breast really itching and burning and red and then in the end of December I went to
the Dead Sea and I went to the swimming pool in the hotel, have the water of the Dead
Sea, for a few minutes. I came out and it was like a burn, which held on for 4 months
really suffering like a real open burn, very liquid, very scratchy and nothing helped.
It didn't go away, that's why I think maybe it was Sulphur. I don't know but it gave me the
idea. And there is a lot of Sulphur in the water of the Dead Sea. That's why I thought, it
smelled like Sulphur. In April I went to Ireland to a seminar and I met Vega again.
He gave me the Argentum nitricum last time and he said, maybe you need another
remedy, you should take another remedy because I owe you one, come on, let's do your
case. I really had high blood pressure and I really was worried, I tried to call here and I
was stuck because everything started going down again. So he took my case and he told
me, listen I think you are the princess on the pea. I looked at him and said, what do you mean
princess on the pea. He said because you are princess on the pea I'll give you a very noble herb,
I'll give Colchicum, it's a safran and it's suitable for you. I asked him to explain why,
what he sees and he said that I'm very sensitive to everything, all external and especially to rudeness,
that's what he said and a few other symptoms. He took the asthma and the colitis
and a few other things and he gave me the Cochicum. I took the Colchicum just when I came
and he said don't take a lap because you are very sensitive,
take one globule. So I took one globule and then 10 days after I came to the seminar
here in May, I was so irritable, I've never been so irritable in my life. Everything bothered
me, everything, every smell, every movement, everything that everybody did. It was such
a strong irritability, worse than ever and I was before my period again which combined
the both and it was a real mess.
Normally I need my sleep. I need to sleep at least 5 hours and I had a problem with the
room mate that used to wake up very early like 4 o'clock in the morning and I couldn't
sleep and it made me more edgy, more edgy every day it went more and more and then
after 4 days suddenly I had like the acid of my stomach came up, real acid up and burned
the whole trachea, everything. I felt like acid was poured in and I was sure that it's
burning holes. I started taking water and water, it didn't help, then I took one globule of
Nux vomica 30, diluted in water and took one spoon out of it, everything gone away plus
the irritability, everything cut off, then I was much more calmer. But later on irritability
came again and again, my head wasn't clear anymore and in some ways I felt good but
in some ways I didn't feel good, I was too irritable for the people around me, for me it
wasn't so bad but everybody complained. I called Vega and I said listen it's impossible
I'm losing my friends, he said forget it, it's good for you, what do you care about them, in
the end it will help you, probably you didn't take the right potency, we'll try higher.
-What potency it was?
-He gave me 12C one globule, so I said forget it and in the middle of July I took
Phosphorus again 200, no beginning of August, I said that's it I'm going back to Phos
forget everything else, I felt good, I'm going back to it and I took Phos 200. I had a
horrible aggravation, I thought I'm having a heart attack, it's exactly what the girl with
Phosphorus said about. I had real strong pressure and pain in my left chest and very
strong pain in the hand that I couldn't even move, it was paralyzed and I told myself relax,
relax, it's OK it's the Phos, don't go to the hospital, it's OK you are not going to die and I
begged him and said, don't do it to me. It was my daughter's birthday and we had to fly to
Switzerland 5 days later and I said please god don't do it to me, don't let my daughter
remember every time in her birthday this way. And it passed in the evening and the next
morning another thing started, again it was pressure in the hand but it went like a needle
inside my throat like pulsating, like a needle is pulsating, it's not the blood that you feel.
It was like a sharp instrument pulsating here, it was very funny feeling and I cope with this
till the afternoon, then I was fed up, I was really worried then and I asked a friend of mine
and she told me go to the hospital now, don't leave it. I said OK, I went to bed, I fall
asleep, I woke up an hour later, fabulous I felt really good, no nausea, no vomiting, no
bad feeling and... and I studied till 12 o'clock at night in another city and then we went
out till 3 o'clock in the morning. And I came home happy and since then I have any
problem at all, I just feel better and better every day. The most important for me my head
is clear and the ears are clear, I can study better, the main thing that changed since a
year ago is my inner feeling. It's my well being and the way I look at things, I'm not that
obsessed anymore, I had the irritability after the Colchicum but it's not the same kind that
I had before. Before everything that happened around touched me, everything. If I saw
somebody in the street needing help, he didn't have to open his mouth, I was on him.
Sometimes it's too much.
-I remember you were describing this before.
-Some people don't like that, don't like to owe you anything, they don't need your help.
-Yes, it's better if somebody wants your help to ask always.
-And that's what I learned, I had a good lesson and another thing I learned the last two weeks
which changed me a lot, I got somebody very clever told me that my soul is driven
by two energies. One is red which is the feeling and one is blue which is the logic but
they all stand in one line waiting for the referee to ring with a whistle and then the both
running at the same time, none of them letting the other one to go first and it makes me
stand on the same spot all the time, I don't go forward. So he said, let the wise one
retreat back and then you will do whatever you need. I think the wise one is the feelings.
-I don't know.
-They are more wiser than the logic, so the feeling will go back and the logic will go front.
-These are theories.
-All kind of theories.
I just wanted to tell you I have new symptoms. By the way after the Colchicum the urine
was bright yellow like the color of the Colchicum, it's very funny. I still don't drink enough.
I hardly drink 2-3 glasses the day, I still am thirsty at night, dry and the urine has a smell
lately of turpentine like oil colors, remind me when I used to paint, the same kind of smell and a funny
feeling on my feet for a few months now. I wake up in the morning, the feet is cold but it's burning.
-It's cold outside?
-Yes if you touch it it's cold but it's a few things. Sometimes I feel it like burning from the
inside but it's usually that the toe and the little fingers, this part but in the legs but
sometimes it's feel like from chilblain, like from ice, if you step on ice. Sometimes it's like
needles and sometimes is tickling, tickling also here, not only up but all the time when it's
happened, the feet feel like an edema, like half-numbed. If I touch it it's like I'm touching a
part which is covering it. It's funny and it's every day, usually when I'm resting, not when I'm walking.
-How long you have this symptom?
-Since the beginning of the year or something like this.
I had it already before she gave me the remedy and that's why I think of Sulphur. I don't know.
My last 2 periods were a disaster.
-A lot of blood?
-In bed at night, even here in Alonissos, very embarrassing. Maybe it's from Phosphorus.
-Maybe it's approaching the end.
-I wish to get rid of it. And I have like a little here only when I'm ovulating but not every
month, twice the year or something. Now it came here. It left a mark, it never comes out
it stays in, it hurts it gets red, it hurts and then 2 days it goes down and it leaves a blue mark
like this. until the next time if it decides to come in the same place or on my buttocks or somewhere.
-No other eruption?
-I had a little bit in the beginning of the year, I had a little bit eczema in the hands and
scratching here and there but that's all. I used to have an eczema here when I was
younger and after giving birth but I don't wash dishes anymore. My kids and my husband
are doing it, so I don't have eczema anymore.
The last time I had this pain in the right chest was after the Colchicum.
In the left I had after the Colchicum, a very strong pain in the left, like I had after the last
Phosphorus and now it comes in the left, not in the right anymore.
-Anything else?
-I'm trying to think what I had before and I don't have now. I think that's the only things that I have.
-OK, it's easy prescription, they will get only 5 points for your case.
She is sensitive, she is very sensitive and she is a good prover. She could be in a proving
group and she could give most probably a lot of information about wrong medicines.
The problem of course is that, as you see, the remedy which is touching the case,
of course she would be touched most probably by most of the remedies because of her sensitivity
but let us say it is a stronger organism. You give the wrong remedy,
then an aggravation is produced without real amelioration and as a result...
You know after Colchicum she was having this big reaction, then she had to take Nux vomica,
she took Nux vomica. What happened? If we want to analyze her case, she is Phosphorus
and she takes Phos and then most probably she will need another remedy.
Who prescribed Phos for her case?
You knew it that's why because it was not a clear Phos and we debated very much for 1 hour
and then I said Phos, nobody was happy. Everybody wanted to give another remedy
but anyhow it doesn't matter. Now she takes Phos and Phos layer goes away and then
there is another layer, whatever it might be, a milder one and somebody gives her a remedy
and aggravates this layer and then another remedy and it's further aggravation
and then eventually you see the layer which is formed is not the Phos, it is the Nux vomica layer.
Let us say she took Phos in that stage where she took Nux vomica, Phos won't work.
Phos will not work. She needed Nux vomica to reduce. It's like an acute.
Let us say you are needing Lycopodium and you get an acute, a bronchitis, in which you need
Nux vomica or Sulphur. You can not take Lycopodium and by the time you are needing
Nux vomica. It's not going to work and if she had made a mistake,
she says OK let me go back to Phos, by the time she was producing a picture of Nux vomica,
Phos will not act.
Now she takes Nux vomica and this goes away and then the layer is back because the pressure,
the nausea, all the symptomatology that was Phosphorus symptomatology eventually
came back. What would have happened in case she had not.
Let us she had continued without taking any further medication. We can not know of course
but my idea would be that she would, eventually because it was a low potency 30,
though for her being so sensitive 30, you remember we had an argument in the class
that because she is sensitive we didn't want to give a high potency, we only gave 30.
So 30 would keep her for say 9 months and then eventually out of a stress, she may had a relapse
and then she would need again Phosphorus. So actually she took Phosphorus 1 year again later,
almost exactly 1 year you repeated Phosphorus 200.
So that means now Phosphorus is going to act longer and you have to be careful not to take
easily medication because your system will be upset very soon. Let it strengthen, be strong.
This element which she described that went away it is very important for Phosphorus element
because she jumped into a situation to help.
But this is beyond the natural thing and she realizes it now, she says maybe I was interfering
too much out of my anxiety, which is a sign showing that a balance is coming from a deeper level,
which is the most important.
What is the blood pressure now? After 5 minutes take it again, it will be different. Don't worry.
-How important is thirst?
-You see how important it is, she has no thirst.
-It doesn't matter?
-Of course it doesn't matter. If all the other symptoms are Phosphorus where is the thirst?
-How many percent of the patients do they have thirst?
-I don't know, I can not say but definitely there are cases where there is no thirst.
The high blood pressure now it shows the suggestibility that there is with the Phosphorus.
Something very interesting also she said about this numbness on the toes.
Phosphorus has, I want to show a rubric. I want to show you the tendency of Phosphorus to produce
numbness on the tips of the fingers or of the toes. I want to show you in the Repertory so
you can remember. This is a keynote for Phosphorus. For those who have the Repertories,
if you open, numbness on tips of fingers. Open your Repertories on numbness on tips of fingers.
There is only one capital. Go now to numbness on toes. Phosphorus is with italics.
Can you make a comment on this? She pointed out on the toes that are the tips of the toes.
She showed you. You go there, you see the toes. You go on the other,
you see the tips of the fingers are numbed, so that means Phos has a tendency to produce
numbness on the tips. So therefore that symptom is a symptom that belongs to Phosphorus.
-We started with the findings here. You came here and you just found them?
-No, I started feeling bad lately, I didn't even want to come.
-How lately? 1 month, 20 days?
-It comes and goes. Actually all this started at the beginning of May after I took Phos again
on the 26th of April, I took 30C again and then the feeling this stooped
ears started so I presume it was again the high blood pressure going up.
-Did you check it by that time?
-I checked it and it was 149 over 110, 135 over 100 or 111. It didn't go up to 120 the
lowest and now it starts getting worse and worse. Yesterday especially I started feeling
bad, so at night I felt, when we left here I felt really bad and I asked Costas to bring the
blood pressure from the pharmacy to check and Sylvia checked it and it was 220 over 140.
-Yesterday evening?
-Yesterday at 9.30.
-I see. Before that did you check the previous day?
-No, I didn't check.
-Only last night. Because somebody was telling me that you have a very high blood
pressure but not today, it was telling me this before.
-Yes I had, I knew that I had but not that high.
-I see.
-Only when I gave birth I was very high.
-I see also that you put on some weight. You've put about 6 kilos, you know that?
-I don't get my period that's the main problem.
-No, the main problem is the eating. You try to find an excuse.
-Yes I stopped my diet, I couldn't do it the last 2 months, I stopped. I didn't watch.
Before I was watching.
-What is happening inside your psychology?
-A lot of problems.
-I can see.
-It started last November, December and I started having questions. I always put them
aside, I was too busy doing things and I never went inside and ask things and I started
getting really worried about Homeopathy, about taking cases, I got cold feet and it really
troubled me because normally when I do something I like to know that I know what I'm
doing and I found myself in a way that I'm afraid that I wouldn't know what I'm doing.
Like OK I can take a case and good I'll get the remedy, that's not a big deal, I hope I will
not make any damage. Even in taking the remedy I was worried if I give another potency
but this wasn't the biggest problem. The biggest problem will be in handling the case
which I got the answer now. I feel a little bit more comfortable but it bothers me a lot that
I can take a case and then what happens. If something like this happens, what I do?
I don't like that. I like to be prepared especially if I'm dealing with somebody's health
because in my experience I had a lot of problems with people's remedies before and I
don't like to hurt anybody. That was my biggest problem actually. Then there was a group
arranging to go to India. In December they told us that in January they are taking 20
people to go to India, whoever first, will go. So sure I went, I did decide to go, I thought
maybe it will give me some more answers and then I'll decide what I'm going to do.
Because I was in the middle of opening a clinic, I have my own office which I'm
running, I have enough things to do, many things to do and if I'm going into Homeopathy
if I want to do, I want to do it full time but then I have to give up the other. So I was in a lot
of stress, here, there. So I went to India and I felt quite OK, I felt very fine there, relieved.
It's funny energy, it's very special energy, I didn't care, it wasn't me. My friend said, look
how Phos works on you, you have so changed.
-It's not Phosphorus, it's the fact that you went away from responsibilities. Your high
blood pressure is the responsibility blood pressure.
-It could be.
-You went away and you felt now I don't have anymore responsibility, I can relax and you
relaxed, not Phosphorus.
-It could be, anyway everybody had this case taking there and we discussed and
everything and somebody told me, now you are not Phos, you are something else.
You have mixed with some things and I said OK, let's see you take it differently because
you take it in a different way, dreams and like this. And this thing really worried me.
-Yes but can you give me the symptoms, you give me all the stories. Just give me your symptoms.
-Then or now?
-Now.
-Now I just wanted to tell you that I took Magnesia phosphorica.
-Why? How you came to that? By dreams?
-By dreams, everything that came out from childhood and things like this that I always
manage by myself because nobody was there for me. Anyway I took it and it didn't
accept that I cried the whole case taking and I came out with a headache and I took
immediately the remedy and the headache continued until the morning. I didn't have any
aggravation symptom or any special symptom that I can say but 2 weeks later we had
Jurgen Becker came back in Israel in a seminar and during the seminar he gave people to do
proving. He said if a lot of people doing the proving, the others who sit next to them
maybe they can get affected because too many people taking the remedy.
-If you sit next to the man who takes the remedy?
-Yes, you get affected.
-It must be a man or a woman?
-Ask Ortega.
-Because by a woman you can be affected, I don't think by a man who takes the remedy.
-I laughed at it and I didn't believe in it and the next day I came to the seminar after 100
people took it, it was something made of tar, the tar remedy.
-It doesn't matter. You felt you were affected?
-It doesn't matter; the first day nothing, the second day I don't know I thought about it 2
weeks later and I don't know maybe it's from that, maybe it's from the Mag phos but I was
very depressed. I fell into a very deep depression that I never had in my life.
-Yes?
-Never, in my life I was so depressed, I felt like I don't know what I'm doing here, what
I'm living, what I'm going to do, I don't care about nothing, I don't want to go to work,
I don't want to do nothing, I just want to die. That was the feeling.
-How long it lasted?
-10 days.
-10 days in depression and you were sitting next to the same man all the time?
-No. It happened after the seminar, I'm trying to find answers, so it could be either this or
not. I don't know really. I never had depression like this in my past, I don't know.
Then I started having this burning sensation that I have in the acute, like acid comes up
and burning, even at night suddenly I wake up like a vomit.
-But that was in India with the food?
-No, that was in Israel after I came back.
-With the same food that you usually eat.
-Yes, it's nothing to do with the food. That was together with this depression and I said
that's it, enough. I took Nux vomica, like I do when I have this. I took Nux vomica diluted
in water, I tried 5C it didn't help, I took 30C, I took a few sips in the morning I was a new
person, no burning, no depression, no nothing. It went away.
-So I see you can cure yourself better than the Professors.
-I don't know. Nux vomica helps when I have this kind of feeling, I take it and I did it
already 3 times and it works. Maybe it cleans up also the bad force and everything else.
-I see you are sighing, why you don't realize this? You feel a heaviness on the chest or what?
-Yes I feel heavy and 2 weeks after I took the Nux vomica I start having hot flashes. It's
not hot flashes, it's like burning from here up to here suddenly like an oven opens,
burning so strong, real fire that you look for air.
-How long you have this burning?
-I have this burning since April.
-And you don't get your menses for how long?
-I didn't get it since then. I had last time in March.
-So it's climacteric with much...
-Yes but the funny thing that I get the symptoms which I get before menses, the
symptoms that I get in ovulating, which is also certain ones which I'd like to tell you.
I used to get the last 2 years in ovulating an abscess, not each month but quite
frequently. Like a round red ball between the legs, once here or here, sometimes on my
buttocks and one I had here.
-This abscess opens?
-No, it could get very hard, very red, it could come to this size and really painful and then
it leaves a purple mark, when it calms down. The last one I had was on the 26th of the
same day as I took the Phosphorus, I got one here and at night it was so painful.
-But you never mentioned that. That is such a strong symptom, as you describe it.
-Because it went away, 2 years ago. I didn't have it anymore. I think it went away after
Calcarea Sulphurica and then I had it once or twice but very little. Now I got it again.
I have new symptom before menses which I never had the last 6 months, I feel like I
have a flu, pain here, in all my bones.
-As if you have a flu but no real flu.
-And then the next day no flu, menses come. The body aches and the back aches and I
feel hot like I have a fever.
-That's a symptom of Magnesia. It came after Magnesia?
-No, I had it before, already 6 periods and I had only 1 period after the Magnesia.
-When did you get that?
-End of January, I got the Magnesia around the 7th of February. Maybe that's why she
gave it to me because I told her all this and this is at least 6 periods that I had. Otherwise
I wouldn't have paid attention to it that it comes. Only after a few times I found out that it's
just before the menses.
-Then?
-Another symptom after I took the Phosphorus the numbness in the feet came back
which I didn't have anymore the last few months and the nails are breaking. The last year
are breaking to pieces and still ascending is very hard for me and very strong ailments
from bad news I have, very strong.
-How you came to that conclusion?
-I found out that every time I hear something about somebody's health...
-Anxiety about others, this is not ailments from bad news.
-No, if I hear something bad that happened.
-Bad news is when you see in television.
-Also, I really feel sick afterwards. Things like this but especially if somebody is sick or
dead, I feel very sorry when I hear that somebody got very sick.
I still have this feeling, it came back, when/if I go to sleep in the afternoon, when I wake
up I feel very heavy and nauseated like heavy headache. I have again this thing in the
back, like somebody is putting his hand here in the scapula. The pain didn't come back
in the last 8 months but the hand is back.
-As if somebody is touching?
-Yes, as if somebody is put a hand.
-Touching or pushing?
-No, touching. I feel the warmth of a hand, so funny. For years I have it.
-You can create any symptom under the earth by your mind.
-No.
-This is what I think.
-No, I didn't have much symptoms left. I just had it now, so I remembered and I wrote it.
-The feeling of a touch of a hand, you will not find it.
-And a very dry in the evening. I don't drink in the day at all, nearly nothing. Only if people
remind me to drink. But in the evening and at night my mouth is really dry, so I drink more.
-With these flashes that you get, you get a feeling of anxiety at the same time?
-No, just horrible. I can't stand it, it's burning but since I took the Phosphorus at the end
of April, I don't have it anymore at night. I used to have it the whole month at night I couldn't sleep.
I went for vacation for 1 week to Hungary. I though I'll rest there. I didn't sleep 1 night.
-From flashes?
-It was like a central heating, suddenly burning you and then I had clammy...
-It was from the waist?
-It's here, it's not coming up, it just comes like this and it burns you. Right now and it
comes off very easily, very light and not that often but then I used to have it 15 times the
day and non stop at night. I used to wake up wet, clammy and in the morning I had a smell like...
-Now you don't have that flashing?
-Not in the night, only in the day, 2-3 times the day after I took the Phos, really less.
I still have it for 1-2 min, before it was really strong, impossible and it was very cold in Hungary.
-Next tell me.
-I don't think I have anything. I still sleep on the right side.
Memory.
-It's down?
-Down. What I found out is I desire company, I can't stay alone. It really aggravates my situations.
-Next?
-I desire sweets before menses, I still desire the menses didn't arrive but still desire and  a smell acute.
-Your smell has become acute?
-Yes, the last 2 months crazy, it bothers me. Now a little bit less the last weeks but it's
difficult, over sensitive to smell, I can smell every little thing and ...
That's the most important things and the feeling that I have.
-Feeling?
-Yes, I lost the joy of life.
-You feel?
-Not happy.
-And you cry much more.
-Yes, when I think about it  I cry.
-In general your temperature of the body has become warmer or stays the same or even more cold?
-When I feel bad it's cold. I feel cold, when I don't feel good I suddenly have a chill but
normally in comparison to others I'm still hot but not that hot, as I used to be.
-You eat a lot of sweets? Why you put on weight?
-I stopped the diet. I did a diet and I lost weight and I went to Hungary and I decided
that's it, enough. I can't stand it any longer, watching all the time, not eating what I like.
I lost my joy of life, be on diet all the time. You become a not happy person, what do you
need to live for? You don't do this, you don't do this. I prefer to live shorter life and a  happy one.
-Not with the blood pressure 220.
-I never went up to this high. Maybe I was upset yesterday.
-Anybody will tell you a remedy, you will just take it. That is a problem with Homeopathy.
-No. I didn't want to take it but I didn't want to offend the person, so I took it. That's
another problem I have. I don't like to offend, to hurt people and anyway it was such a
long time and blood pressure was still high and I thought may be because you touched
little things that happened when I was a child. Really what she explained to me sounds really...
-But this suppose to be a release, when the sub-conscious comes to conscious, this is
a treatment actually in psychotherapy, it releases the organism. It doesn't load the  organism.
-I felt good, with the remedy or without the remedy. I cried and cried and cried.
-If you cried... but then the organism if the remedy is correct, has to be a release.
If the psychotherapy brings out something which is there underlined on the sub- conscious,
brings it up, then it's good for the organism, not putting pressure.
-Pressure is now after 3 months already. It was 3 months ago. Something happened
maybe he was right with this horrible drug that he gave everybody, I don't know.
-You see the organism does not keep order. If you take remedies which you don't  need...
-When I took Phos now I start getting all my old symptoms, one by one again the 30.
Little cramps, little this, little that. Now I got high blood pressure, last time I nearly had
heart attack when I took it. I felt like I'm going to have a heart attack.
Not coryza, the nose is not running, it's just like a fever and pain here and in the back
it's like a flu with no coryza. I never have coryza unless I cry.
-You don't get acutes?
-The last one was 2 years ago, a very strong one.
-What was? Bronchitis?
-Yes.
-And you took antibiotics?
-Yes, after a while I had to because it became pneumonia and problems. A homeopath
gave me antibiotics.
-What he can do?
-After we waited nearly a month, it was very strong, very problematic.
-Flashes on chest did you find?
-On sternum?
-No, this is different. This is internal.
-I have that also.
-Heat flashes on chest, can you find this?
-Rising to chest?
-No.
-You have strong aversion sex?
-Not aversion but I don't feel like. I don't desire it at all.
-No desire. When did you lose this desire? 10 years ago?
-Not 10 years ago but at least the last year.
-Your feet in bed are warm?
-Yes.
-You stick them out always?
-Today not, the last 2 days but when it's hot yes for sure. Even in winter I like to put my
feet out. Tickling, the feet are tickling...
-Cracking of your feet?
-No, it's tickling.
-Itching?
-Like needles it tickles sometimes.
-When we took your case you had this vertigo from high places?
-I still have. I don't like high places. I imagine myself falling down.
-Do you remember having any skin eruption in young age?
-Yes a lot. I used to have a lot of eczema.
-And you took cortisone or things like that?
-Yes. I had this what the other lady mentioned, that she had here, I used to have it a lot.
I had asthma, I had eczema...
-Do you say you are better with company, you feel better?
-Much better, even a male. Even if I don't feel good and I have company, I feel different a different person.
-It's not only that you desire, you feel better.
-I feel better. It's more feel better than desire.
-Worse alone.
-I have to tell you that I took Mercury and I had 1 year symptoms, I wouldn't like to pass this again.
-You see the idea is to find a series of remedies, once you mix up now, you will have a problem.
-It's the same symptoms that I always had except this heat.
-No.
-The heat I had when I was 42.
-Do you eat fruits?
-No.
-You don't like fruits?
-Not so much.
-Do you like motion?
-I like to be busy, I don't like exertion.
-You sigh a lot?
-I take a deep breath, it's not sighing.
-Need for deep breath.
-Sulphur.
-Next remedy which comes after Sulphur?
-Nothing.
-Nothing? Only Sulphur. What symptoms did you put, it's interesting.
-What caught my attention was that I have the impression that she has a thyroid and I 'd
like to know if she takes a medicament for this or if she has been examined before.
-It was examined and everything is normal.
-Sometimes when the thyroid is misfunctioning it has a repercussion on blood pressure.
So that's correct, what you thought is correct from your studies in medicine.
Remedies which I was thinking also is Phosphorus, Ignatia and Sulphur and most
probably many of you have been thinking of these remedies as well. Whether we are
going to repeat now Phosphorus on high potency, whether we are going to give Ignatia
first or whether to go to Sulphur is the main issue that occupied my mind.
To my understanding, we left it here, I said when we finished, you didn't tell the whole
story. She said yes. You see this loading inside which is quite strong, you see the blood
pressure going so high, it's not for nothing, that means things are inside the organism
which are pressurizing though she has a tendency to high blood pressure, the blood
pressure is now too high.
And therefore my reasoning is, is it because of some malignant stenosis or kidney
problem or is it purely because of psychological reasons?
I see she is loaded, she cries quite easily, there is a possibility also for Amyl nitrate
because of that particular way she has these heat flashes. Amyl nitrate has this in the
upper part of the body; and high blood pressure and flashes can bring from that point of
view Amyl nitrate. The same, we can have the idea of Pulsatilla because she seems to
be changing symptoms or the crying which is quite prominent but her character is very
sympathetic. She maintains that and she insists when others have problems, she takes
her and that is again very strong symptom of Phosphorus of course.
She says also that she does not take much...
-If I eat fruit, I eat pineapple when I'm in India or hardly I eat any fruit.
-Why? Because you don't like or you don't have the opportunity?
-No, it is there. If I eat an apple, it gives me heart burn and if I eat fruit, I eat hard and
sour, not ripe but I hardly eat any fruit. So in the beginning of the season I eat a little bit
and then when they are ripe, I don't touch it.
-Feet out of covers as she says, it is a characteristic of both Pulsatilla and Sulphur.
The desire for sweets is quite strong, she puts on weight. What other symptoms of
Sulphur you have there except of desire for sweets and feet out of covers?
-Acute smell.
-Chest, breast heat flashes.
-Which she says it's quite prominent.
-Skin eruptions, mind sadness, mind sighing, mind desire company when alone.
Stomach thirst less, extremities peeling off of nails, mind ailments from bad news.
-Itching of course of the sole of the feet you have there, sexual desire diminished,
desire for company, abscesses, sighing, sadness, hypertension. There is also one
strong element, let's put there sympathetic or anxiety for others and also sympathetic
and see what happens.
Underline the sympathetic 3 times and anxiety about others put 2, there you'll find
Phosphorus quite strong.
-80% less.
-80% less after Phosphorus. So we don't nee that symptom, we can take it out. What
about the symptom sympathetic, you still maintain 3?
-Yes.
-OK. After Phos what did you take?
-Nothing. I just took Phos in April 30C.
-After Phos you took any other remedy?
-After Phos I took Mag phos in the beginning of February and I took back the Phos in the
end of April.
-So the last remedy was Phos.
-And I think maybe it brings up things like last time when I took Phos, I though I'm going
to have a heart attack. Every time I take Phos I have problem with my heart.
-Do you drink a lot of water?
-No, I never drink a lot of water.
-So you see how easily it can upset because she has a sensitive organism and she is suggestible.
This case we call suggestible, she suggests that somebody is sitting next to me,
he is taking a remedy, I may be affected. Definitely she can develop symptoms
because of that, it's not objective but the belief system is so strong that she can develop.
-One of the things that Phos and Sulphur came up strong in my repertorization, one of
the things that I feel is causing her stress, is her irresolution regarding to become more
involved with Homeopathy, in professional level and she mentioned that and so
I used the rubric delusions fear giving medicine that would harm others.
-Where is such a rubric? Where did you find it?
-Who put that?
-I'll find the source.
-It doesn't matter.
-I think the rubric was originally by Kent, I have to look that up to find the source.
-What are the remedies?
-The only remedy is Sulphur.
-But this is not true, Baryta carbonica has that, Anacardium has that, Silica has that,
Pulsatilla has that. Especially Anacardium, I have seen doctors who even try to take
blood and they feel they may harm the patient. They give a little remedy, aspirin maybe
and it was an Anacardium case but this goes to the section of lack of self-confidence.
This is the section which contains this rubric. If you have rubrics like that, you don't rely.
Therefore her case is not clear, as you see, first of all. Secondly we see Phos has taken
as the last remedy, the blood pressure is not controlled, second point.
Third point is that she has developed lately some symptoms more of the Sulphur type
and the possibility of Ignatia is always there but as she is sensitive I would not give
Ignatia for her at that moment, though she says I' m not interested to live. It's not a matter
of depression yet, it is the beginning, this is more the Sulphur type when we say, with
Sulphur indolent, she doesn't want to do anything.
Delusion, gives people something wrong from which they may die.
Therefore we have one more point for Sulphur and she takes a dose of Sulphur quickly
now, tonight then see, tomorrow the blood pressure... Who checks the blood pressure?
Now you take it, you have lower blood pressure because Sulphur causes high blood
pressure, then it brings it down as well. When you took it, it was wrong, so you had a
proving. Now you need Sulphur you'll see how you will feel.
Now finish with this case.