-What is the problem?
-I'm here now because I'm completely exhausted. Exhaustion is not because I'm pregnant,
I'm in 5th month now but it also was before already and it has got worse.
-During pregnancy?
-Yes.
-Exhaustion is mental, emotional, physical, all three?
-In the first 3,5 months I was so tired all three levels and since many, many years I have
strong tension here in the back of my neck and in my shoulders and I wake with
headaches almost every morning.
-This is a feeling of stiffness or real pain?
-It's as if the muscles contract, go into a spasm and it is so strong that it dislocates
the vertebrae.
-Why does she think this happens?
-The tension? Because I've been under a lot of tension for many years quite intense.
Just alone to ensure my existence, so to speak financially every month is an adventure
because I'm alone.
-She means the husband is not with her?
-No, I don't have a husband and my monthly payments which I due every month
are quite high, so just alone this factor already is a lot of stress.
I work every day, including Saturday and Sunday.
On the weekends I go to flea markets to make sure some income is coming to pay
for all the necessary expenses.
Besides that I have my practice and also other jobs.
-She works too much all these years.
-Yes but I have to. In my heart I have a feeling as if it is torn apart or if a knife
was in there. This happens every time my emotions come up, most of the time
I try to keep them down, to suppress them but if I can't manage and they come up,
this is the feeling, I have a strong pain in my heart.
-Strong pain emotional or real physical pain?
-I feel it physically but it's an emotional pain and it's coming from my soul.
There is a lot of sadness.
-Shit I intended so much not to cry.
The fact is since years I've been looking for a way out of this emotional load.
I have progressed during these years but still I didn't reach the point where
I can say now I have my full energy, now I can work, things are moving.
-What remedies she has taken so far?
-I started homeopathic treatment 3 years ago, I received Ignatia in 1M and this brought me
many suicidal thoughts and depression but no amelioration.
Then I received Carcinosin with hardly any effect, Baryta carb., Sepia and Nat. mur.
-No effect?
-Not much.
The next homeopath again gave me Sepia and a colleague here in Alonissos gave me
Nat. Carbonicum 1,5 years ago.
I don't remember exactly the potency but it was quite high and the reaction to it
was that my ankles were swollen greatly.
-No amelioration?
-I got memory back to the time when I was 4 years old. It was a very clear memory.
I was at the beach close to the sea, a small child playing in the sun and there was a man
next to me who with his fingers was playing around me.
-She got back this memory?
-Yes, with Nat. carb. and so I asked this man what are you doing there with me?
And he said, you've got sand there and it has to be taken away, otherwise you get ill.
Today I think that's one of the most stupid answers you can give because if a child is dirty
all it has to do is go into the water and it's finished, there is no need to play
around with your fingers. So today I assume something must have been there.
I can't remember who it was. The good thing about it was that this memory came back without
injuring me, without hurting me.
It came up, it was like it was always have been there but it was no pain.
-Then after Nat. carb. you got another remedy?
-I then started a treatment and I received Nat. mur.
-Was an effect?
-I took the remedy briefly before I came to Alonissos, it was last year and you know
when I'm here I always feel better.
It has nothing to do with the sea because I can be in the sea side other times too.
It's really Alonissos, so maybe we will have to make an addition at the Repertory
Alonissos ameliorates.
When I came back to Germany this inner amelioration slowly faded it, then I had
a strong argument with my father and he made me so angry that I took the kitchen chair
and smashed it onto the ground, breaking it into pieces.
And after that I received Staphysagria. And after that I didn't break things anymore but
also I didn't feel any amelioration concerning this inner pressure I have.
In January I was cleaning up my desk in my practice and I found a paper bag that
I had contained the Nat. mur. 1M and without even thinking, as if I was unwrapping a chocolate,
I just opened the paper back and licked it and gave myself another dose of Nat. mur.
without really wanting it or knowing it and the effect was, after being single for 5 years
and not even having one night stand in between, I fell in love.
I was so sure and so happy and love makes you blind and we were together, we had a good time
and I got pregnant. During this pregnancy my feelings started to fade also because I always was
so tired and exhausted and nauseous and things got less.
We separated 3 weeks ago, he went to Israel to work in a kibbutz and I don't know how
it's going to be when he comes back. He is going to be gone for half a year.
-This was happening in Israel?
-No, he is a German but he wanted to make the experience to be abroad and especially to be in Israel.
-So she was disappointed from that departure?
-Yes I was disappointed but I buried it all within myself.
And my situation in the pregnancy now is that I have to work because I have to earn money,
I'm getting no support from the father of the child, neither financially or physically in any way
because he is not here.
-From the social security?
-I just have to.
It's all too much for me, it's beyond my capability.
I don't want to go on socially, I don't want to be dependent and I have enormous difficulty to go
anywhere and say, please help me, it's terrible.
When I was pregnant in the 4th month, my father had another discussion with me and tried
to convince me to have an abortion because he sees my situation and he is afraid
he will have to help me.
Sorry.
-It's OK don't stop. No problem.
-And my mother told me it would be better if I would have a miscarriage because
I wouldn't be able to manage alone anyway. That's the situation how it is up to today.
When I prepared for this talk, I also thought that I might say some things about my childhood,
how the family situation was then but I don't know if it's important
and I don't want too much time of you.
Usually at home I can't cry, I can only cry when I'm very excited.
-Before I start asking questions, she can tell me what ever she likes to say.
-When I was a small child already, I always had problems with my mother.
I always felt unloved by her. I did strange things when I was small.
When I was 2 years old, I stopped eating, I didn't eat anymore and I did this for such a long time
that my parents brought me to a hospital, so that I would learn how to eat again.
In the meantime I have learned to eat again, unfortunately.
And there was also times when I was a small child that I purposefully vomited into my bed,
just that my mother would come once more and take me into her arms.
I can't explain what really happened between her and me, this is just how it was.
She always told me I was a desired child, they wanted to have me but I never was able to feel it.
-She is the only one?
-No, I have one brother.
He is younger two years. I had a grandfather who was very good to me, very kind
and I loved him a lot and we had very good understanding.
My grand father died when I was 4. My parents didn't tell me that he was dead, they didn't tell me
for weeks and months and even though I was such a small kid, I kept asking every day what's wrong
with grandpa, where is grandpa?
When they told that he had died, I developed such a high fever that I almost died.
It was way above 40 degrees Celsius.
-Does it ever happen again this, that after bad news she developed such fever?
-Besides this I'd like to mention that my father was very dictatorial father.
He did not tolerate any contradiction, any opposition within the family and in spite
I dared repeatedly to contradict him because I just had different opinion.
And I was beaten repeatedly, very often during my childhood, especially every time I contradicted him.
They always only beat me, my brother was never beaten.
-Why does she think was this? Because she was very obstinate?
What was the difference between her and her brother? What does she think?
Because she was obstinate or because they loved her less?
-I'm not sure. I think maybe because my brother would not endure as much as I was able to endure
in my childhood.
And within our family we had constant conflicts about tiny little things, nothing important really;
there was a constant conflict between my parents, between my parents and my grand parents,
in the entire family and today I'm very, very sensitive to any kind of conflict, arguments,
I can not bear it.
When I had different opinion from my father, there were two possibilities for him to react;
either he beat me or he told me you are twisted in your thinking, you have strange thinking.
And I heard that almost every day.
My father terrorized us as children psychologically.
For example he would repeatedly tell during the day to eat fruit.
-Do you like fruit?
-My brother and I, we don't eat any fruit.
-She hates fruit.
-I think fruit is very beautiful and very healthy but I just can't eat it very often.
-And like every day he told me, you are not supposed to put butter on your bread
otherwise you will become as much fat as your mother.
-Does she like butter?
-Very much.
I enjoy it really but I don't have to have it every day.
-Is she feeling hot or cold in general?
-In general I'm sensitive to any kind of temperature. I'm sensitive to cold, I'm also sensitive to heat
but I can endure cold better than I can endure heat.
-Is she having any salivation during sleep?
-I don't know but I think not because probably I would realize if the pillow was wet.
-She is grinding her teeth?
-Yes very much, during sleep very strongly.
So strong that I've already broken some outer parts of my teeth.
-Is she afraid of the dark?
-No.
-She has any fears?
-Very large fear of spiders.
-Only.
-Besides that of course fear of the war but who doesn't have this?
-Another fear, of thunderstorms, dogs?
-No, I love animals.
Animals are my big love. And always when I'm here there is some animal that comes to me
and wants to stay with me and I keep while I'm here.
-Perspiring a lot?
-No.
-Does she have any headaches?
-Yes, I frequently have headaches, strong headaches and when I was a child
I had headaches that were so strong that I was weeping from pain, as a child.
-Where they were?
-I can only describe how it's now.
Within the last 8 weeks the headaches were mostly there when I awoke in the morning
and it was a dull pain.
-The whole head?
-Yes.
-This headache can become worse from the sun or from any movement?
-Yes, heat aggravates. And it's ameliorated if I press with my fingers in the hollow of my eye.
-Does she have any feelings or ideas about committing suicide?
-Not anymore, not since Nat. mur. I think. Before I had many and often but not anymore.
-Did she take Aurum?
-No.
-Is she sighing a lot?
-Yes, very much.
Not now because I'm excited but during lessons very often and also in my free time,
only not now because I'm excited.
-Is she jealous? A lot?
-Oh yes, I think so.
-She can wear clothes tight around her neck?
-It's uncomfortable. What I wanted to tell you, I have problems with my thyroid.
-It's hypo?
-Function wise it's border line to hypothyroidism but I mainly have nodes and cysts in there.
-How is her thinking? Is it clear or is it clouded?
-I can think clear but I have problems of concentrating over a long period of time.
-The desire for butter is strong?
-It's not that strong, I can go without for weeks, it's not that strong.
-What about fat in the meat?
-If it's soft and slimy I can't eat it. But a little bit it's OK.
-Salt?
-I like taking salt, I always add salt to my meals.
-And this adding of the salt came after Nat. mur. or it was there before?
It was before already.
I realized here I have enormous problems climbing stairs, ascending.
It's so exhausting, it just takes my breath.
-Feet cold or hot in bed?
-At the moment warm.
-What about her thirst?
-2,5-3 lit per day.
-Not for cold?
-It doesn't have to be ice cold, it actually doesn't matter.
I really have to tell you one thing. A colleague advised me to take Palladium.
I took Palladium two weeks ago because with all the other grief remedy,
more or less I've been through and I just don't want to experience this pain anymore.
-The pain in the heart?
-Yes.
-Phosphoric acid she has taken?
-I'm not sure, it's possible.
I wanted to say that I have very strong desire for tobacco meaning to smoke and I'm really angry
at myself because I cant' stop it.
I don't want to harm my child but I tried to stop smoking twice and it's just really impossible.
When I stop smoking, I can't think anymore, I'm so nervous.
It's unbearable.
-She drinks coffee also?
-I don't drink any coffee anymore but I used to enjoy it very much, I like the taste of coffee
and also this feeling that gives you of being a bit more awake.
-The exhaustion is very great?
-Yes.
-Eggs she takes?
-No, I dislike eggs, very seldom I take but I don't like them. I also don't like to drinkmilk,
milk for me is slimy.
-Her character is to be quite or to be aggressive?
-It's hard to say, in general I'm quite calm but if I'm under stress, I become highly irritable,
very easily and I have to invest a lot of strength not to explode and minor
explosions can happen repeatedly.
-Does she have any fear from high places?
-No.
I have very swollen ankles, especially the right one is very swollen.
-During pregnancy?
-I've always had the tendency to swollen ankles, even before the pregnancy but it really got worse.
-Bathing in the sea has she found out if it gives any amelioration?
-Yes, it does give some amelioration.
-Certain.
-Did she ever have gonorrhea?
-No.
-Any discharge from vagina?
-As a child I had some kind of infection of the lower abdomen with leucorrhea but not in the past years.
-When she sleeps which side she keeps?
-I can not sleep on my abdomen, not just because of the pregnancy but in general.
I mostly sleep on my side, even before pregnancy.
I never was able to sleep on the abdomen, even before the pregnancy.
-She likes ice-cream?
-No, except salt I don't have any pronounced desire or aversion.
-She is very sympathetic to pain for others?
-Yes, I'm often noticed this especially with patients who are sitting up in front of me
and describe their pains, I could feel their pains.
Or I brought a friend who have had a knee operation, I brought him to the doctor and for
the rest of the day I couldn't walk anymore because I then had such strong pains at the same spot.
-Nails are strong?
-Yes.
-She has an anxiety about her health?
-No.
-She wakes up refreshed or unrefreshed?
-Completely unrefreshed. It's even worse than when I go to bed at night.
-She said the water drinks it cold?
-I prefer to be a little bit cold than too warm.
-And she takes 3 lit?
-Yes, two bottles of this is very possible.
-She was always very thirsty?
-No.
During the last 4-5 years I've developed this thirst. And what I wanted to say my symptoms in general
haven't changed in this entire time period.
Basically they stayed the same.
-She said about eggs but exactly is aversion to eggs?
-No, it's no aversion, I can eat them but I don't need them.
-She can or she can not eat fruits?
-I can eat some pieces of fruit but not more than one piece per week.
-She has taken Pulsatilla ever?
-Yes, I took it once in my life.
That was the end of practitioner school, I had been the class speaker and I was very close
to the people, I liked them very much, so when one after the other left, this hurt me so much
and then I took Pulsatilla and it helped me.
And I have a desire for fresh air. In class I have to go outside in between because I can't stand it
and if I may add, when the two of us entered the room here, the first thing she  said was,
this is bad air in here and we opened the window to get fresh air.
-She eats pork?
-I can eat it but I'm not crazy about it. In general I don't eat much meat at all.
A little piece of meat once every two weeks, that's sufficient, maybe even less.
-Fish?
-I like to eat fish.
-Her menstruation was anything particular?
-When I'm under stress the irritability before menses was clear often
but otherwise no problem whatsoever.
-The blood is how many days?
-3 days.
-Clear blood or clotted?
-I think it's difficult to tell if you use tampons. I don't know if it's normal because blood coagulates
a little bit, if you use tampons, sorry to say. Otherwise I didn't see any clots.
-Does she have any important symptom she did not tell?
-When I'm under stress and when I'm nervous, I bite my fingers.
And I would like to add that I'm very unhappy with my figure, with my weight.
I don't eat very much but it's incredible difficult for me to lose any weight and in general I like to fast,
when I'm fasting I feel better overall and this helps me to control my weight.
In the beginning of the pregnancy, within 3 weeks I gained 8 kilos, just like that.
And I hate it.
-The thirst is the same big or it is only during heat?
-Of course the heat increases the thirst but in general I'm always quite thirsty.
I like to drink and I feel it does me good.
-She likes to be with the company of the people or she likes to be alone?
-With dear people yes I like to be but I wouldn't want to be with anybody.
There are certain people I don't feel I'd like to be with and in general
the desire for company has decreased.
I just realized also that I'm so sensitive right now like a raw egg and I have a great fear to be hurt.
-In general looking back in her character, would she say she is obstinate and
if she wants something she would do it?
-Not at all.
As a child also and as a young woman I had hardly any self-confidence.
I mean over the years, I've gained some, thinking of the fact that I started from scratch
I did accomplish some things but in general I'm not very strong and I have rather problems
with the power of my will and I'm not very well organized.
-If somebody is hurting her, does she forget or she remembers it always?
-I remember.
-And she wants to retaliate?
-No.
-Was any tuberculosis in the family?
-Not that I know of.
-She eats bananas?
-Once in a while.
I don't know if this is of any help and maybe it's the same for everybody but the mosquitoes
are feeding from me here.
On my lower left arm alone I have 7 mosquitoes bites and they go on me everywhere,
on the face and in every free spot.
-The only thing she is afraid is spiders?
-It's not real claustrophobia but for example here in class I have a very narrow sitting place,
right between the window, the wall and somebody else and every day it's a real challenge
for me again to go in there and sit there and endure this.
But I can't just start screaming and say, hey somebody else come on and trade places.
So I try to endure but it's very uncomfortable, I don't like it.
-She is taking Belladonna?
-Yes.
-How much she would underline the desire for salt?
-Twice.
-Lemon she likes?
-Not so much.
I don't know if this is of any help, years ago I tried to kill myself with an overdose of tablets
after a broken relationship.
It is just that I think I have to do something for myself now and not only for myself
but also for this child.
-The grinding of the teeth is very old symptom? As a child she remembers it?
-I don't know if I had it as a child but definitely when I was a young woman, I already had it.
I definitely had it when I was 23 and whether I had it all along I can't tell you
because if I sleep alone, how shall I know?
But I realized it 3 weeks ago because I woke due to the fact that I have broken a part of my tooth.
The pain in the neck is quite strong right now.
-This pain is affected at all by draft?
-No.
-She likes the draft of air?
-No, I don't like draft so much and I try to avoid draft by covering my neck and my shoulders
but I like fresh air.
-She has no other pains or other problems?
-Last year in May I had a severe pyelonephritis and this was caused by a kidney stone
which has gotten loose and it went to the urethra and I had very high fever
and I had a septic condition.
-And she took antibiotics?
-Yes I had to.
I was in hospital, it was a life threatening situation and I had to take.
-How many times she took Pulsatilla?
-Only once in a C200.
-And what was the effect exactly? When it was?
-It was in December 1995 at the final celebration of our school and before I was just
watching the people of my class living one after the other, I had the feeling that is breaking
my heart and I felt the pain and I felt that I can't endure it any longer and I took Pulsatilla
and afterwards I felt better.
-Just for that pain only, not in general.
-I didn't feel any other changes but I have to say I drunk coffee immediately the next day again
because I wasn't real homeopath yet.
This was the most difficult case so far.
I could not make a decision for this case.
I don't understand the reason, maybe she is too timid to say things deeper or maybe because
of the remedies she has taken already.
They have confused the case but this definitely is a confused case and I can not make a decision.
I have to work now again in my house and see if I can come down to some kind of logical conclusion.
Either some information is missing or the case is really confused.
It doesn't look like any remedy, you don't put together the main things, the strong grinding of the teeth,
the desire for salt and sighing and this here.
This is another contradiction that on one hand she seems dependent, on the other hand she says
I don't want to be dependent from anything, even from the social security from my father or from anybody.
She goes ahead and she keeps the pregnancy while the problem is there whatever it is.
So there are contradictions in my, not being able to put things together for one remedy or at least for
the first remedy, which has to be a remedy which is exhausted. I didn't feel she was so exhausted
when she talked, that's another contradiction.
She said I'm exhausted mentally, emotionally, physically and she cried very much but she has
strong emotions, I felt.
Then she said, no emotions, I don't have emotions, my emotions are quite low.
-I was thinking on Causticum and maybe we should ask some questions because she said
she was always contradicted on father in childhood and she has a very big love for animals.
-Causticum don't love animals. It is afraid of animals, all animals, typical Causticum.
Love of animals is Aethusa, because she loves animals and because she has aversion to milk.
-My feeling the whole time was for Pulsatilla. If you remember how she opened her case
and how she closed it with the last example, when she took Pulsatilla.
She gave the example of the feeling that it's breaking her heart and that is what she also said
in the beginning.
Something is tearing her heart apart, a knife in her heart, a strong pain and it was relieved
with Pulsatilla. Pulsatilla can be very controlled, very strong outward, if she has to cope alone.
They can not at all look like the classic Pulsatilla we know but I felt it before and I talked
to her again just now.
The deepest inner longing actually would be to be able to let go and to receive some help
but since there is no help around, the only possibility to clench your teeth, not to become soft,
not to be overwhelmed but to continue alone. And that can be Pulsatilla in this stage if the situation
is like this. When we came here, I forgot the cause of the incident, I think it was when she was selling
the T-shirts downstairs.
The break was over and I said, come on let me carry your suitcase upstairs,
you are pregnant and everything, you can use some help.
And she said, no, no I always have to do everything alone, I can do this on my own.
I said sure you can, everybody knows you can, you have to prove it again and again
but now there is a situation, accept some help you don't get it every day and she said, no,
no please if you tell me this, it makes me cry almost immediately, don't, don't.
It was almost overflowing and she just managed to hold herself together.
No matter if general symptoms or if anything fits or not, from how I understand Pulsatilla
can be very well be the other side of the matter.
-I don't think that she wants pity. I don't agree. She is too proud to accept some help for
which she thinks, she has not done anything.
If she has worked and has produced this and she wants to sell, you want to buy, OK.
But you can not give it back, she doesn't want it.
She has been vaccinated for rabies?
-Yes, twice.
-Twice with the injection in the abdomen?
-Yes.
Because I was in the practice of a veterinarian doctor and when the second
injection set of injections was done, I had very strong reaction swelling of lymph nodes.
-We have several possibilities. Tell me a possibility.
Ignatia, Pulsatilla, Nat. mur., Staphysagria, Carcinosin, Lyssinum, Phosp. acid Medorrhinum.
We vote. Pulsatilla, who votes for Pulsatilla? Ignatia, Nat. mur.Staphysagria, Carcinosin,
Lyssinum, Phos. acid, Medorrhinum?
Can we use the rubric sympathy aggravates? Show me this rubric.
This rubric says Ignatia capital, Belladonna, Calcarea, Platina and Silica, Arsenicum,
Helleborus, Kali sulph., Nat. mur, Sepia, Sulphur and Syphilinum.
I have chosen for her a very dynamic remedy, in spite of what she said,
in spite of what she showed, I've chosen a very dynamic remedy with great presence.
A remedy which grinds her teeth very badly. Grinding Apis, Belladonna.
During sleep? Tuberculinum has to be very strong here, it's not this the right rubric.
Now it is. Tuberculinum, Cina.
She is a difficult character. Not only she challenged her father several times, as she said
but she also took the chair and broke it.
-I did that because he lied right into my face. He told me I never beat you.
-You did very well, nobody said you didn't. You did very well and according to your remedy,
expressing anger. It's a volcano.
You remember what he said? I like his observation, my observation is also the same.
She is a volcano, suddenly exploding but Belladonna has so much weakness?
Let's see.
Underline once.
Belladonna has quite strong weakness and restlessness, at the same time.
Belladonna is very restless and very weak.
Stramonium also can be an idea because she has received the injections but don't forget that
Belladonna and Stramonium look alike but the difference is that Stramonium almost invariably
has fear of dark, which she does not have.
So I chose Belladonna because she does not have fear of dark.
Stramonium also has strong fear of dogs, Belladonna also, they are similar remedies,
similar in their explosions.
Belladonna is more explosive and Stramonium is more violent. In their explosion they hit, they strike.
-I forgot something to mention. Pyelonephritis. That's a strong indication for Apis.
-Apis is not a bad idea and I have thought about it and the repertorization shows ...
Good bye. Show me Belladonna.
Thirst for large quantity is also a symptom which made me take out...
mind, aggravation from sympathy, thirst large quantities, desire for open air, unrefreshing sleep.
Also there are some symptoms of Phosphorus with her.
Milk aversion, cold drinks desire, grinding teeth in sleep.
-I'm stick to the idea of Staphysagria because of this tremendous anger and this ...
-Suppressed anger.
-And because she is throwing things.
-I can tell you she is not suppressing her anger now when the students are talking.
She immediately reacts, she says, no, no... nonsense, I'm not like this, there is no suppression.
Suppression to Staphysagria acts totally different. Staphysagria is subdued, she is not reacting.
She is reacting. Good luck, Belladonna 10M with a possibility that she will go to Calcarea carbonica,
as a deeper remedy later, because she had exhausted herself and these are
signs of exhaustion but I can not give her Calcarea carbonica.
She is not, she is too strong while she complains she is not feeling her energy but
maybe what she says for her, feeling tired is not like others who really feel tired and exhausted.