-I was having very deep depression and was thinking whether I want to continue living or not.
-Do you want to live now?
-Yes.
I want to start with a normal follow up before I tell you my acute symptoms.
I received Phosphorus and after taking Phosphorus at home for about 3 weeks
I repeatedly had the feeling that I was going to faint any minute but it was only very brief.
And also after taking the remedy for some days I had swelling of my eye lids, my upper
and lower, it looked a bit like a quick edema but not so strong, it disappeared again.
After taking the remedy I had the feeling as if my entire life was running in slow motion.
Everything was going on a lot slower than normally, I can not express it any other way
than that everything was in slow motion.
-Before, she was in a state of hurriedness?
-Yes always.
-And suddenly this calmed down, slowed down.
-Before I always felt a kind of pressure.
For a couple of months I developed an old symptom again, I had my premenstrual syndrome
again with pains in the breasts from the ovulation but that also eased off again.
What I probably didn't mention last time was that when I jump, I lose urine and
that also has ameliorated and I love to jump.
My blood pressure also ameliorated, normally I always had a low blood pressure 90-50
and for a while I was like 110-60 but now is down again.
My psoriasis also aggravated for a while, I had it in places like my scalp, in my ears,
around my belly, in the genital area, meaning concealed areas and it had aggravated
and in my bellybutton there was a kind of exudation which looked like crystallized honey
and when I removed it I could see beneath the exudation in the skin, it had cracks,
also in the other areas of the skin was very dry and cracked.
In general I became warmer, I always used to be very chilly and that has become better.
I developed a wart in my middle finger which stayed for 3 months and then it disappeared again.
My energy has ameliorated, when I wake up in the mornings are not that depressive anymore
but I also really worked through a lot of things with myself, this time.
I also had one dream which I also want to tell you.
One dream I had pretty soon after taking the remedy and I had written to you about it;
that was a dream where a voice very clearly told me that I should not be so yielding, submissive.
The other dream was a situation where I was lying in a room on a chair similar to the one
I had in the college.
I was lying there naked and across for me was a door and on the side was a door.
While I was lying there the door opened and in came a girl.
I used to go to school with her and in the class she was the most tender, the most shy,
the most fragile people and she came and she was just just talking with people and
then turn around and left the room again. While awakening I had the feeling, she made it,
she was able to make it.
-Actually she, because both is the same, her friend and herself.
Most probably there is an inner feeling of confidence that she went out of depression.
-But it was not her.
-Yes but the dream represents the same person, this is a projection of her own image.
If you look at the girl with so sensitive and yielding, this girl represented her,
it was very similar with her.
That which is similar, she said, oh she made it. Is it clear what I say?
-After this dream I had to cry for some weeks very often because only after this dream
I realized how many things I had suppressed in myself, how many things I have never dared
to speak out, how many things never came up and I had to realize that I had to start doing this,
to start speaking out to do this.
Many days after the dream, I was walking in my apartment talking to myself in different voices,
one part of me said this and this and the other part said no look at it in this way and for many days
I just kept on going.
-She had an inner discussion.
-Loud.
-Very good.
-And after that I started to write poetry again, I start doing collages, painting and I nearly needed
to do this to express what was going on inside.
-Feelings came back.
-Yes and also I gained more self-confidence. It's not so much as I would like it to be
but definitely noticed.
People used to say why do you look so self-confident, you are self-confident and I know I made
this impression but I never had the feeling going along with it.
Now I can feel that something happened.
And I'm very happy about that. I put more spices in my food again now and I go out to theater,
to concerts and so on, I really took up life again but I still have not regained my complete energy,
I still feel that I'm easily exhausted.
And I sleep very much still, even during the day, all I have to do is lie down and boum...
-Now she feels good after sleep?
-Yes, sleep is refreshing.
Now I will have the acute symptoms.
-Yes.
-Since last Thursday I developed headaches and also some throat pains.
Saturday evening I had quite strong pains and Sunday I barely managed to have breakfast with
a lot of pain in swallowing already.
Since Sunday was our free day I thought never mind I just go back to bed, it will do me good
but then within only a few hours, the development on my throat got so intense got so swollen that
I felt I was going to suffocate.
It was like a strong pharyngitis, my tongue was burning and I felt that I'm going to suffocate,
I felt real fear and as nobody else was around.
-Had she ever had a similar condition in the past, so strong?
-I can remember having pharyngitis in my life but I can't remember having it ever so acute developing
but already in the evening it was ameliorating again.
-What I want to know is when it was the last previous pharyngitis of that type?
-Long time ago, about 15 years ago. During the day I also noticed rambling development
on the abdomen and in the evening I had diarrhea and so I hardly ate anything since then.
The only thing I ate this morning was a half banana and I usually drink very much but
I can not drink anything, the moment I drink I feel nauseous, so I haven't' taken anything since then.
-Yesterday she did not or today?
-Hardly anything on both days, yesterday because I couldn't swallow and today because
it makes me feel nauseous.
-Not only nauseous but she has diarrhea.
-Diarrhea was only last night, it has gone now.
The secretions of the diarrhea were burning and I've been sleeping very much.
Yesterday I slept the whole day, I slept the whole night, I came here this morning after one hour
I felt so tired and I went back and continued sleeping and I feel very weak.
And I cried a couple of times yesterday just out of desperation because of this weakness
coming so suddenly and so intensely; usually I'm the type that props myself up again and continue
and now I just couldn't, very weak.
-The thirst is not there or she is afraid to drink?
-Thirst is less than usual, I would like to drink because my mouth is dry but the minute
I take one sip and it reaches my stomach, I get nauseous.
-And she doesn't have much flesh to lose.
-I definitely lost about 2 kilos in this 1,5 days and also my urine has a certain smell.
It smells like I have ketone I'm pretty sure I have that in my urine right now, that's the smell.
-I asked her about her menses because they were scanty, as I have seen here and that was a point
of argument with Phosphorus most probably, with the class.
I was saying it doesn't matter, the class was saying it matters, so therefore I asked her how are
the menses now and then she remembered something changed and that's why we came back.
-My menstruation remained exactly as it was, always very little.
Once I had a bleeding in between my menses in February and so immediately I went
to see the gynecologist and she then discovered that I have Chlamydia, which I don't know
where they are coming from  because I haven't infected myself within the last months.
-She took antibiotics?
-No, the doctor recommended antibiotics but I didn't want to take them and up to now
I haven't done nothing at all.
-There are any symptoms concerning that? More itching, discharge, leucorrhea?
-About one month after she diagnosed the Chlamydia, I had a little bit of leucorrhea not much.
Sometimes I go jogging in the morning and afterwards there is some but otherwise no.
Sometimes but that's only due to the fact that I'm really paying attention that sometimes I feel
some pain in my joints.
-Did she have Chlamydia in the past where she had been treated
and she has ever been treated for leucorrhea?
-I only had leucorrhea once after my pregnancy but that was not treated, it disappeared.
-Thank you.
It's very simple now, we don't have to say many things about this case.
Again it is interesting to see whether this was a case with really deep depression and why?
In which level you would place this situation?
-Top 3 going to 2?
-Somebody else. Middle 3, he said.
-Originally the case was very deep because there was loss of will to live, that was border suicide
or tendencies so I would classify it 3 going to 4, prior to a deeper physical pathology probably.
Now since the Phosphorus, it's middle 3 and she is having acutes moving to the 2,
where she can have acutes.
-That's correct. What he says is when the person does not want to live, we have a deep depression.
Yet a very deep depression with no will to live could be actually 3 level and almost 4,
yet if we see that the remedy is quite clear, we suspect, as I was suspecting when I was
analyzing the case, that this case was actually uppermost 3 level going to 2.
In spite of the fact that she said also I don't have the will to live.
She didn't exactly say I want to commit suicide, I want to die, there was not that deep depression
that we see the darkness of the depression.
So though the words are the same, I don't want to live the intensity of the depression is different,
the depth of the depression is different and that's why also everybody says, you don't look...
This is very important for you, for observation. The deep depressed people,
they look also depressed.
They can not hide it. You see little subtle signs that we have to evaluate a depression and to say,
well you will see with the right remedy.
Subtle things like this where anybody else would not take care but what I was interested very much
with her, it was her dreams.
The dreams which came show actually a psychotherapeutic process going on without
the interference of any psychotherapist of course, a total psychotherapeutic process
which she did herself and the dream was showing that she was projecting this girl who was having all
the qualities of her, she saw her coming and she said, she made it.
That was herself actually and the deeper feeling finally after all this self-psychotherapy,
you did a self-psychotherapy actually, it is the seal that she is out of the depression.
She made it and now the interesting thing is that we start with the acutes.
How deep is the acute? I told you the acutes when they come at this level,
in number 2 level the acutes
will be very strong and most probably you will have to treat because they are quite life threatening.
She is not in life threatening situation but she is suffering.
And the problem we have at this moment is what shall we do in this case?
Where is she going? What is happening in this organism under the acute?
You remember we have certain rules and certain principles which guide us.
As we said, the main rule is, if the case if life threatening you treat no matter what.
That's rule number 1. Rule number 2, if it is on first level, you treat or you don't treat it
depends on the intensity etc.
When you come to group 3, after you get out of the group 3, the acutes are going to be strong.
And she is going through a strong acute.
So the decisions that we have to pass is, shall we give a remedy for her acute
or shall we repeat the Phosphorus?
If we have clear picture of an acute remedy, Mercury clear, Arsenicum clear, then we give the acute
and we say another rule, if you don't have a clear picture and there is a serious situation,
we repeat the chronic remedy.
In which case is she? Is she developing a clear picture of another remedy?
Margaret was putting also the repertorisation.
-I believe there isn't enough information to get a really clear picture but I have a question.
If the constitution of the chronic remedy, Phosphorus was repeated, would then she get
another acute with stronger symptoms so that a more clear picture would come out
of another remedy?
-I didn't understand your question.
If now we give Phosphorus, she is treated and she is better...
-She is treated and she is better and then she develops another...
-You are asking me and whoever...
-For myself I don't see enough to give an acute, Arsenicum or Mercury, not enough
and so for myself I would repeat the Phosphorus.
-But there is a need for repeating or we say carry on, because we saw in previous cases
they went through.
He went 3 times in bronchitis and he pushed it without any medication.
In this case, if we push what is going to happen?
If we tell her, no medicine at all because we have 3 possibilities, 1 acute, 2 the chronic
and 3 no medication, can we suspect what is going to happen to her with no medication?
Can we suspect what is going to happen after repeating the chronic or here in this case
I will tell you, this is one of the worse cases to make a mistake.
To make a mistake especially giving another remedy, you suspect this is an Arsenicum case
or Sulphur, Mercury, whatever and you start giving and she will go worse and
then you give Stannum and she goes worse and you give Muriatic acid and she goes worse
and by the end of your treatment she is back into depression.
You see for those who have some experience, they can appreciate what I'm saying.
Those who do not, they have to keep in mind and remember it.
-We definitely continue to give Phosphorus in this case but if I wouldn't be sure,
I would give Phosphorus in a low potency to be on the safe side.
-Phosphorus on a low potency, that is a good idea.
-George I think Phosphorus has most of her acute symptoms, if you look at the Phosphorus,
only the... is not there.
-I would like to hear who would give another remedy? Nobody.
Who would give the same potency Phosphorus 1M?
Who would give the same remedy in low potency?
Who would say, let's wait one more day?
I play jokes with you, don't forget.
I say one day so some people will raise their hands, one day she is not going to die,
so we can wait but what I'm gong to say is opposite.
The question that you had to ask to yourself is, is she by the force of the acute, is she going to
a state of relapse?
Do you suspect that this case is going into a state of relapse that means the organism is
pushing down more and more, is losing energy, in which case you prevent it by giving the remedy
or do you feel that she can make it, we let her.
She will not relapse. In this case, as she is now , it is very doubtful if we leave her she will recover,
she may recover in 4,5,6 days but she will go slowly in her energy.
After reaching bottom she will come little, little after 5, 6 days. If she picks up OK but
there is a probability that it will stay long.
It will stay low energy, perhaps not with the deep depression, where she wants to die but
a kind of a depression.
When you don't have energy, you have either depression or irritability.
What shall we do?
And posing these questions that you have to ask in every case you have to evaluate at this moment
where is she. Her organism is strong or is falling?
-Besides that she said she is very weak, I think we have to take into consideration that soon we all
fly home and this is a very strong factor from the outside which I think we should keep in mind.
-She is always practical in her application.
-Yes.
I have said that each remedy acts on different levels of pathology, different levels of pathology
and here we have depression. Here also we have depression here also we have depression,
here also we have depression, here also we have depression.
We call it depression, all this is depression and the remedy which covers all these depressions
is for instance Nat. mur.
Another case, we have cancer, here we have cancer, here, here...
When we deal with depression of that level, we don't expect such reactions,
we expect some amelioration, here and there and other things and developing and little bit this
and that and fears are coming and then irritability is coming, there is a process before we bring
this depression up to that level, where we finally give either the same remedy...
Maybe in repeating the remedy will raise the state of the depression.
She may be depressed after this, you let her and she has a relapse.
Here is the Phosphorus and the depression of what she had, it was here.
And it will go there. As a relapse it will go, it will not be as deep but quality wise it will be similar,
then she needs a repetition here and then again, another push and again.
The same way as if you understood with the Ignatia cases, that we said, we wait
whenever they need some Ignatia they repeat more.
Everything has to be very precise, very clear in order to take a person from here to health.
Usually the allopaths take them to eternity.
So you have to have in mind, there are cancers that are curable.
Calcarea carbonica can cure the uppermost cancer layer.
There are types of cancer that we know they are cured.
And we say, I gave a dose of Sulphur, Phosphorus can cure.
These are few cases which are standing very high but you go to the most aggressive cancer, forget it.
The only thing you can do is a palliation.
Calcar. carb. here, Calc. carb. here, it's the same remedy.
The remedy does not change but the pathology is underneath so strong that it will go up
and back again.
Here, in these depressions, you battle, it comes up and down, up and down...
it past a level. You don't see this kind.
We can have grades of energy and here we have the group. She was here, uppermost level,
she goes here, she has much more energy, she reaches very high here, she gets an acute,
she goes down in energy.
How far it can go to energy not passing through this level, unless we allow it to happen.
Finally she may have a kind of deep depletion of energy, which the organism can not bring it out,
it reaches up to there, then here we have the depression again, not perhaps as much
but still quite strong.
I believe that she will not reach that state because I hope we'll treat the acute correctly.
-As far as I remember she also had myoma and I would like to know what happened to them.
-I can't remember.
-I have a very small myoma which is 1,7 cm in diameter and this is still existing.
-Let us say it is a question and you want to know what to expect. What to expect in group
3 is different than what to expect in group 1. In group 1 the myoma has to be reduced.
In group 3 it has to be increased. You understand?
It somatises the disease.
She gets an infection and she says I do not have any chance of being infected.
What happened? The only thing it changed was the organism.
Actually in this particular case what changed is the Ph of the uterus.
The acid-alkaline environment of the uterus, that is what changed and allowed the development of the
microbes etc. which are already existing in these areas. So she says, I had never the
chance to be infected, what is this? This is what it is.
-What in her particular case concerns the level of health in this acute?
What is concerning you that she may relapse?
-The energy that goes so low, I am afraid she may go into a kind of a relapse.
If it was the pain, I wouldn't care. If it is the diarrhea, I don't care. The energy goes so low ...
Of course under an acute everybody gets low energy, there is no question but why she gets
the low energy in the end? Do you see the difference?
You have an acute, if I have an acute I go into coma almost but in the beginning.
But if I see after I go into the acute, then I go down, then I better take the remedy.
In this case we are allowed and justified to repeat the remedy.
-What about the aggravation of the psoriasis?
-Very good sign. The aggravation of psoriasis, the myoma if there is, later on it will be
and the aggravation of the Chlamydia all are in accord with the principles.
-I agree with the repetition but if you would go to give low potency, could it be dangerous
could it mess up the case, could it disturb?
-The low potency no. The action in the low potency is more mild, but it will take longer time to recover,
she may take 6 days to recover but with 1M she must be OK to travel.
I want the class to get involved. These are the points who make a homeopath.
The other, finding the remedy is OK.
If you want to become a homeopath, you have to understand fully this theory.