-Tell us what happened.
-When I left last time I didn't take the remedy yet and I really felt bad, I went to Skiathos
for 1 day and people in the shop...
-What was the remedy?
-Pulsatilla 12C every day and go up. I didn't get the remedy in time,
only when I took the boat Costas got it from Athens, so I didn't want to start taking
it and I stayed in Skiathos 1 day and I thought I'm collapsing.
I was crying all day, I was sweating, people in the shops told me to sit down
because they thought I would die.
Just water was coming out of my head. When I arrived it was a kind of weakness
and when I came home I took it.
It was in the 6th of October and within a day or two it stopped, all the sweating but
I started having within a few days very strong weakness which I couldn't even eat.
I was eating and all my energy was coming out of my mouth. I don't know how to explain it
but I couldn't eat, I couldn't talk. I used to start talking and... vanish.
So I moved to 13 and it became worse. Then I thought maybe it's from the Pulsatilla
and I stopped it altogether and I felt OK. I came to myself,
I had more energy, I didn't have sweating, it was fine till about end of November.
I can't say that I was fabulous but comparing to what I was before, it was good.
Then in November I tasted something and within an hour or so I developed food poisoning
and I was in such a pain that I didn't know what to do anymore.
I went to diarrhea and pain in the upper stomach like knives. I took the case
and I took Arsenicum 30 and immediately the pain stopped, it was cramps.
-Was food from the restaurant?
-No, my husband brought some chopped liver and he left it out and it's enough if it was
half an hour out in the minute I eat something which is not fresh, I can even smell in a restaurant
if it's not fresh and immediately I get it. It doesn't even take time, it goes into my mouth and
always like this. I don't if it has enough time to go down as I start feel it.
I had to take it about 3 times on Friday and on Saturday afternoon my husband
had to go to work from Saturday noon and usually he goes to the football, basketball,
he works on the Israeli television.
In the beginning a friend was in my and left and I really felt so alone
and I start calling and looking. It was a kind of suspicious mind with loneliness, it was terrible
and I made a scene because I told my children and friends and everybody was mixed in it
and it was a scene, it was something unbelievable.
-About this possibility of your husband going somewhere suspicious?
-No, he normally goes at 12 but they go to eat to a restaurant and the game starts
only at 9 o'clock in the evening. So I was cross because I didn't feel good and he knew
that I didn't feel good and he didn't even call to see how I am. That was what annoyed me.
Probably I did proving on Arsenicum or whatever. Then when he came home at 12 o'clock I told him
it's good that you come and he says, what do you think I'm doing? I'm working,
I'm not cheating on you, he put the word cheating, well it comes from your mouth not mine.
-He prevented the worse.
-That was the story for a few days and since then he doesn't forget the scene that I gave him.
I didn't make any scene, I was quite but he...
-But still it was out of your habit or you have done such things?
-No, I never care, I don't. He goes to work all the time like this but because I didn't feel good,
I'm a jealous person if there is a reason, it can be also imaginary but something has to be there,
I'm not completely blind but I think it was the Arsenicum working because I felt alone
and I felt neglected and sick and why he didn't call? I was sick and he didn't mind,
he didn't care, he didn't have work anyway until 9.
-Did you have some friends coming to you?
-I had Mary, she came to me and stayed until 2 o'clock that it happened. Then she went away.
-In the morning?
-After he has gone, she came for about 2 hours and then she left and then I started
developing loneliness and pity and how come that he didn't call when I don't feel good.
Because normally he goes every time and I don't care. I thought maybe it's the
Arsenicum proving because I took 3 doses which are a lot for me, one after the other.
But it helped the stomach, it was beautiful. Then in January I developed flu.
It started with throat pain and I lost my voice and then it went down to bronchitis
and then I felt that it went into my lungs and I felt it was a kind of Pulsatilla symptoms.
I was better outside in the fresh air but actually Pulsatilla when she has a flu
she is not better outside. It doesn't matter, I took it and it did pass within 2 hours
like I never had anything.
Then at the beginning of February, middle of January already, I felt very down mentally,
depressed and no energy, I didn't want to go to work. Every little thing irritated me,
I shouted at work I was on the edge, every little thing, I was crying, it was terrible.
Then they had a Reiki course at the beginning of February, so I decided that I'll go and do it,
maybe I can help myself, put myself back to energy.
There was a woman there coming to help and she had a very strong flu and coughing on everybody
and I remember telling myself be aware because you are going to catch the flu
and I never catch any flu. I never catch from people and I had a feeling that I'm going to get it
and within a few days I had it.
It started a very strong flu and I was in a seminar then and it was giving oscillo
and I had pain in my whole body and he said take that it's good, it's the same and I took one.
I think that was my mistake because then for a month and a half I was so sick.
I've been so sick in my whole life. Because afterwards Pulsatilla didn't work anymore.
I tried it and it didn't help, it was too late. I remember what you said, it's good to have acutes.
At the beginning I was very happy but it developed so bad that after 1 month
I had to stay in bed, I was so weak I couldn't go to work and for me it's the end of the world.
I never stay in bed, I prefer to go to work.
-Did you have fever?
-I never have fever, if I had I had 37, very low fever. It was as the same as when I had Mercury.
When I received Mercury a few years ago I developed this kind of flu, this kind of sensations,
burn throat, you can't swallow and I don't have tonsils. And I thought if it's the picture that
I develop proving on Mercury maybe I should take Mercury but I remembered what it did to me
and I said, I'm not touching nothing, I had enough.
After about a month the lungs started, I was coughing, I felt it's a pneumonia and
everybody in Israel was in the hospital and dying from pneumonia this time and I went to the doctor
and she wanted me out quickly before she would catch it. She said you should take antibiotics,
you have pneumonia and she gave me Zinnat. I took the pills, it take me another day
to take it from the pharmacy and another 2 days to hold at home to see maybe I don't have to take it
and then on Saturday afternoon I took 1 because it was really impossible and I lied down.
Normally I don't sleep in the afternoon, I can't sleep I feel bad when I wake up
and I lied on my left ear and within 10 minutes I woke up with a terrible pain
in the left ear and stooped the face, half of the face was paralyzed.
-After you took this antibiotic?
-About 1 hour after.
-What was the antibiotic?
-Zinat. It's called Zinnat, you take 1 in the morning, 1 the evening, a strong one.
I heard that afterwards it gives all kind of side effects and I put some ear drops.
-Did you take a second dose?
-Then they told me now you have a problem in your ear, you should take more.
Otherwise you will be with this and with that and you shouldn't stop.
So I took a few more doses, I didn't take the whole of it and it was getting worse and worse.
The whole situation was worse and worse, so I stopped the antibiotics.
First of all before the antibiotics I lost my smell, then after the antibiotics I couldn't see
and I couldn't hear and it was like in a bubble. I couldn't see the people from 1 m,
I couldn't see television, I couldn't see in a movie. Normally I sit on the 17th row,
I sat in the 5th row and I took my daughter's glasses and to read I could, which before I needed
glasses before of the age. It was funny, everything changed and people told me it's the flu,
that's the symptoms of the flu, many people have it but I don't know. Then my mouth started getting
so dry at night and in the day time I used to pour myself 20 cups of tea.
I used to put them in a line. I usually don't drink more than 1 or 2 cups the day and
that if you remind me or I force myself and then I was putting the big cups in a row and
pouring like this and drinking them like this. At night my mouth was so dry that I couldn't move it
and I had to wet my mouth, I didn't want to drink and I used to go every 15 min to the toilet.
It was unbelievable and then I thought something is wrong and I was so weak
and I couldn't see nothing. I don't how I lived. When I looked backwards I don't know how I coped,
I was in seminars, I was working and I was shouting at everybody.
My daughter told me not to come to work anymore because I'm offending the people.
You better stay at home because you make us nervous and I had enough, so I put my computer
and I said that's it, I'm going to find the solution for that. I put all the symptoms
I'll tell you which ones, I put dryness mouth at night, frequent urination, stopped ears, lying
ameliorates. When I lied down it was funny. At night if I lied down on the right side in the
morning I woke up and the left ear was fine and then when I just sit like this or make this
movement it used to get stopped again.
-What remedy did you take?
-At the beginning I took Sepia because of the pain in the throat and I took Sepia
and the next morning I woke up with no pain in the throat at all, clean and it was really a very
strong pain. Very happy I went out, I didn't go to work, I left 60 people there,
beautiful time but other things didn't stop so next day I took Phosphorus again
because there are more, depending over, throat, pain left, post nasal drip, it was the most
horrible thing and then it was even worse the Phosphorus.
It became terrible and then it started like normal.
Acid coming out and burning my throat.
-You still had this intense thirst?
-Yes. I still had, that's why I took it. I thought it might help and then I started vomiting acid,
acid came out and I said that's it, I'm going back to Nux vomica. It helps always.
So I took 2 or 3 globules of 30 Nux vomica in water and I had a spoon and then within 1 hour
the burning went away. Then I took another time, in the evening-night and within 1 hour
I felt a different person and the next morning it was fabulous.
I just could forget but the ear was still another 2 days like this. My well-being was different.
I felt good, I was not nervous and the urination dropped every 1 hour and then 3 times the night
and the mouth was less dry and after 1 week I had the guts to go and check my blood.
At the beginning I knew it's high, I thought it was 170, 200 maybe that means high for me
and then I went to my neighbor because she has the thing that checks and I said do me a favor
can you check my blood?
She said come tomorrow 6.45 in the morning before I go to work and I'll do it.
So it was about 1 week after I took Nux vomica and I really felt good already and she took it
and I looked at it and she looked at it and I was in a shock. It was 462.
-What? Sugar?
-Glucose in my blood, that was when I felt good and I didn't run so much and I didn't drink so much.
So I looked at her, I thought the end of the world is coming.
I said it's not enough the blood pressure, I have diabetes also. It was a real shock.
In the same day my friend died from cancer and the whole time that I was sick she was
also suffering and because I was sick I was not in touch so much and whenever I called
they said she is sleeping, I didn't think that she is in morphine because before we talked
and everything was fine. And only the last few days I found out that she is really dying.
I didn't believe in it but at the day that I went to the clinic, I went also to the funeral.
Since then I decided that I'm not going to take any insulin or any pills at all and if diet will help,
I had in my mind that as it comes it will go. I'll be on a diet.
-Before you had high sugar?
-I had 2 years ago 116 the most, a year ago after the Sulphur it went up to 140 but then the doctor
told me that I have to do a diet, the triglyceride went up and the sugar and the heart is OK.
-Did you check your heart when you went back?
-Yes she said everything is fine and I checked the eyes and everything is fine.
There was nothing in the back of the eye, no organ is getting real damage, it's like the function
is damaged, that's my feeling. When I had the ulcerative colitis I was in one of the worse states
that people ever being, I used to fill about 60 times a day buckets of blood.
And I came out of it and I don't look like one with ulcerative colitis.
So I don't know maybe my organism is going back.
-Wait a moment. When you saw this woman, this woman she has this instrument
and she measures it.
-We checked it again and again.
-You didn't go to a laboratory?
-Of course I did, 2 days later because I had to wait in a line.
-So what was the measurement.
-318 after 2 days of strong diet.
-And then you checked it again?
-Then I checked it again, I can give you the whole measurements. 15th of March it was 462,
that was 6.45 in the morning. At 4 o'clock in the afternoon it was 275 already
because I didn't dare eating anything. 16th at 9 o'clock it was 303, 17th it was 318,
19th it was 275, 21st in the evening at 7 o'clock was 384 and then I started Nux vomica
because I ordered LM, I was afraid to take anything but LM. I took LM2 once every
second day in the evening and the sugar started going down and it starts 256, 267.
It really went down, on 24th of March it was 283, 30 it was 256 and then after eating an hour
and a half was 272, which was good, and on the 31st of March was already 185.
But that was very strong diet, hardly any protein.
-Now how it is?
-Yesterday it was 159, now I checked it was 187 but I had lunch.
-You checked it after lunch?
-No. We took the blood pressure and we also took the blood, so I can tell you
but in the morning it was 187. It's exactly like now after lunch and yesterday it was 168.
-Your blood pressure?
-150 over 95 yesterday night and this morning but when I had a very high blood sugar
the blood pressure was 110 over 70. It's ridiculous.
When the sugar was high, the blood pressure was down, now they are getting even.
After few days, after about 2 weeks taking every second day, I developed a very strong eruption
and all kind of pimples and then eczema on my face. That was terrible. It was
dry and itching, I couldn't put nothing, so I stopped the LM too and within 2 days it went on,
off and then I had an abscess here which started like a little pimple and grew up to this size.
Then there was nothing I could do, I had to cut it off or find a solution.
So I called a pharmacy and asked to make me some mixture of cream to take it out.
-Who put it out, yourself? You cut it?
-No, I didn't. I just put cream on it and it came out, a mixture of Myristica and Hepar sulphur.
I didn't know what to do or take a remedy or just put a cream because it went like this,
the ear was standing like this, my face was red. It was a year ago exactly that
I had it and a surgeon cut it. He didn't do a good job probably and it came back after the Nux.
She mixed in 3X Echinacea, Belladonna, Silica, Hepar sulph and Myristica in a cream
and it works fabulous. In the morning it was out.
-Opened and discharged?
-Opened, discharged, it came out a lot.
-How are you feeling now?
-I feel now still very irritable, I cry very easily, everything bothers me, every little thing.
It was before and it still does. Physically I feel much better but mentally I get very angry
and it comes like this into my ears.
-The anger?
-Yes the anger comes from the diaphragm into my ears and my head.
-You become red?
-I don't know, I don't go to the mirror.
-Somebody must have told you, if he had seen you are very red. And then you explode?
-I explode yes.
-You don't retain, you don't hold it.
-I explode. I had last week a Shankaran seminar and I exploded there on him.
Quickly I stopped the LM because I started the LM again, not on him, I told everybody
what I think of them. That's my nature, I usually tell.
-But this aggression that you feel, this anger is something that you know about or it is new?
-No, it's not new, the last year.
-It's the last year which the anger has come?
-I always say what I have to say, I explode sometimes people look at me.
-To say something is different than to say it with anger. What I'm asking is the anger...
-I always did. Now it's with anger. Before it used to be with anger and
sometimes I think it's also anger because I say what I have to say. If something I don't like,
I say it, I don't care.
-So this is not something new.
-It's not new but now it's more intense.
-But why you complain? I asked you what is your complain and you say...
-Because it bothers me, it's intense.
-It's too much.
-Of course it's too much.
-Before there was a time where you had this anger?
-Of course.
-No, this intensity of the anger.
-Usually before menses it was very intense and I knew I'm going to have my period.
That's my nature.
-But now you have it whether you have menses or not.
-No, I stopped my menses a few months ago but I still have the signs
and after the Nux vomica I got my menses again.
-What I say is that you don't have anger before menses. You have anger every day.
How is your sleep?
-Good. I go to sleep very late.
-Why? You have a lot of energy and you want to stay up?
-I have energy and even, it's many years already, I read a book for instance and
then I feel that I'm falling asleep and then I wake myself up and I continue reading.
I go and have - well not now- but I used to go and have chocolate.
I used to go and have some kind of stimulant to wake myself. I don't why, it's stupid,
I don't know why, I should sleep because I love sleeping, I love being in my bed.
-How many pills of antibiotics you took? Twice the day for how many days, 5-6 days?
-Something like that. I stopped before the end.
-And was no trouble with your intestines?
-I always have trouble with my intestines but after the Nux suddenly I stopped having diarrhea.
Normally I wake up, I go to the toilet, sometimes up to 5 times in the morning
but when I took the Nux I hardly went once. I felt quite good.
When I started taking the Nux vomica it was much better and I feel good with it, I'm less tense.
-You let the anger out.
-I always let the anger out.
-No.
-Not enough because you have kept a lot of anger inside and in spite of the fact you let
some anger, not all, now you are letting it out, that's why you feel better.
-Sometimes I say things that people look at me like this, I say well I'm Bovista.
I say everything, I don't care I just say everything that comes out of my mouth,
so we always laugh with friends.
-Do you feel the heat still or you feel more cool?
-Here in Alonissos I started to sweat again, maybe because I was carrying the whole day suitcases
and another thing which is strong is the pain and heaviness of my legs.
I always had problems ascending, always. Even when I was a runner.
-Did you bring any cardiogram with you?
-I brought it last time, you have it, I didn't do since then.
-No, this time.
-They didn't want to do it. They said you are OK. That's what she said the doctor.
I did all the checks, you are OK, go away from here.
-She did not want to make a cardiogram?
-Because she checked me in August.
-Wait a moment. This is a private doctor or this is the insurance.
-It's the insurance, the government.
-So you don't do whatever you like.
-No, I have to wait a few days, I have to know 10 days before that I'm going to be sick
in order to make an appointment.
-You have a very good government. You better change it.
-Today we are changing it.
-Have Mr (?)
-Let's hope we are changing but still the anticipation is very strong.
I always have to be in time.
-Which is the highest that you have taken from Nux vomica?
-LM 3 twice the day now.
-The highest?
-30 in acute. It always worked.
-Not higher?
-Never higher. You did like this when I told you last time that I took Nux vomica, no good.
-It depends what you told me. If it was good, I would say it's good.
-It was the same thing, the burning and I found out that Nux vomica works. It's funny.
So far it did work but maybe the potency is not the right one. I just want to ask you
something else. I have something which is very prominent with my eyes like
if I'm in a movie or watching television. But if I'm going to a show like theater
and it doesn't matter which one, it can be a happy one, a music.
If I sit in the audience and there is a show and all the lights going to the stage my eyes
immediately become heavy and I fall asleep and I start snoring which is very embarrassing
to my husband. It's like this since I remember myself, in flamenco, in cats, in starlight express,
it doesn't matter my eyes become heavy and I'm somewhere else.
In a minute and I'm gone. I hear it, I know, I'm here, I'm not sleeping.
It seems that the strong lights... even here. I felt it today also
and from the light outside of the windows, it's not that I'm tired.
And this problem with my feet in ascending, it's really painful also.
-The thighs.
-Yes. I can't even walk.
-You feel weak?
-Pain and heavy.
-On going upstairs.
-Also if I'm going on the hill, if it's a little bit. Normally I can walk a lot.
-OK before we do anything, I would like to have a cardiogram made, we'll ask again our friend
to make a cardiogram for you. So we have this record on record and to be sure.
Then we shall decide.
-Another thing, the liver enzymes were very high and after the Nux went to normal
because I did check.
-Can you give me the numbers?
-It was in the 15th of March GGT was 35, the...
-That's normal.
-No, that's not normal in our scale.
-What is the normal in that scale?
-I have the whole list and I'll give it to you to see what is normal and not normal.
It went down from 25 to 23 and from 31 to 20 which is the normal.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
-You have a different scale in Israel?
-I don't know. She said there is hemoglobin, it's also the check-up that they do 3 months
backwards, after sugar, it was also 10,9 when the scale is 4,5 up to 6.
That means that I had much more than 500 the last 3 months, so I don't know if I have to do it again.
They checked albumin, my albumin was OK.
-Did they find albumin and urine?
-No, that was OK.
-What else was found?
-Everything is fine except the glucose now. It was not fine 1 month and a half ago, a lot of things
-Did you have your glucose check back? Let us say 5 years back?
-Yes, it always was 100, 110. I had a little bit of diabetes when I was pregnant, 120,130
not much but it considered as diabetes in pregnancy and my daughter was born 3750 in
8 months which shows it a lot.
-You have a very strange organism, reacting very aggressive with any stimulation but
as we have said the fact that you had some acutes is a good thing.
-As long it doesn't kill you.
-Of course and it seems that Nux vomica was correct, when you took Nux vomica.
For Sepia the way you said it, I would have thought of Bryonia.
-Yes, Bryonia came out also.
-Sepia and Nux vomica work complementary. Sepia and Nux vomica most probably did the work.
Now the fact that you are still very aggressive we'll discuss it in the class but
after I see your cardiogram.
-Things bother me like what is going in Israel. I'm so happy that
I'm here because I was sure if I would be there, I would get a heart attack. I'm so angry.
-With the government?
-The cheating that is going on, about the non-fair, I don't understand how people do things like this.
That bothers me, if somebody does something wrong, it makes me crazy.
I can fight to death if something like this happens and it annoys me, if things are not correct
but I shouldn't, I should leave it, it's not my problem. I should learn.
-The politicians.
-It's not only the politicians, it's also with your friends, if people that you know don't behave
correct and if people are rude especially. If somebody is rude, or I shout or I just blow up
and tell them in the face and sometimes it's not so nice but I do it.
This is a typical case of what happens in the practice. We give remedies, sometimes they are
right, wrong, right, wrong, maybe they come up right. So she came up right most probably.
The problem of course is here, what I have said many times so far.
When you have an acute and the acute is strong, that is the critical time whether you
better find the correct remedy. It will be much better picture if she had been treated
during the time of pneumonia but what can you do? She never contacted me of course
but she could have found by chance even the right remedy and then you could have seen
a much better situation and you would not have these imbalances which her organism presents.
Her organism seems to be very sensitive to any kind of stimulation.
It's very unusual to see such reactions as she describes, maybe she exaggerates of course,
when this is there, she makes it there, it's a little bit of exaggeration but still OK.
You get an idea, you say is that true now, it came up to here?
But the reactions that she gets this organism is really peculiar and very strong
and with her imagination she blows them up as well, so she doubles them in size and in severity
and you get tremblings. But when she says sugar 4... this is not her imagination.
Most probably that's why I asked what about having a laboratory examination and if the
laboratory says the next day, after 2 days it's 380 that means the sugar shoot up very suddenly
and not in a constant state. Something happened and your sugar levels shoot up.
I don't know what it was. What is important for her is of course to have a better diet.
You remember last time we strongly advised her to have a better diet.
-I lost 12 kilos.
-That's good but unless you were frightened by the sugar level you most have probably
lost only 2 instead of 12.
-No, I promised Hannah.
-This is my experience.
But what is interesting, as you see also, is the anger which is coming out.
By taking the case, by getting all the information, you know quite a lot about the person how she reacts.
She has kept anger inside, there is no question about it.
This anger does not come out of the blue. If she has kept sadness, sadness would come up.
If she had kept anger, anger came up and anger has to be expressed.
This is a problem for her husband and children most probably and her friends.
But still as a homeopath you have to say, when you feel this, don't hold it back.
She says, I have expressed anger all my life but not enough.
You see, each one of us has kept a certain portion and if what is kept inside
then we see this physical symptomatology arising.
Then of course treatment by chemical drugs can put you on a vicious circle and then
going down, down, down.
At this moment what is the remedy for her?
Graphites? You put some symptoms. I was thinking of Chamomilla and I said, show me
and Chamomilla was coming up by certain things you put.
It's very interesting the way that she describes it can be a kind of Chamomilla
where she cannot really retain the anger at all. You put too much anger.
But if she says that I feel good with Nux vomica at this stage and not only that but she says
I had an eruption with Nux vomica...
-I started the Nux vomica again because I had the tooth fixed and the sugar went up,
so I started the LM again and then after 2 weeks I had this anger
and an attack of ulcerative colitis with blood which I didn't have for years.
-But when I asked you with the antibiotics did you have anything?
-No, just a week ago.
-Later, it doesn't matter.
-Then I changed to LM.
-That means 1 month later but...
-I think it was from the Nux vomica.
-Forget it.
-No.
-What, from the antibiotics?
-Yes sure.
-But it was for half an hour and it was gone.
-It doesn't matter. The disturbance was not so much but why did I ask you did you have
a repercussion on your stomach? You are a person who has been suffering with ulcerative colitis
and you took antibiotics, so it starts spoiling the flora.
-No, I took acidophilus. I take all the time acidophilus, I'm pouring in acidophilus.
-What I know is that antibiotics will irritate the guts and most probably you will have symptoms
of colitis and Nux vomica took it away. Therefore Nux vomica is good for you
and I would suggest that you continue with LM every second day and if there is an
eruption coming, you have to continue. The eruption has to come out.
You can not say oh my god.
-I continue the LM even if there an eruption.
-You continue and then the eruption may become even worse, as much as the organism needs
in order to get out of the situation.
-Because it says that with LM if there is something like this, you stop it, so I stopped it.
-Since LM has reacted so well as to bring out the eruption, keep the LM, don't change to 200, no.
-Couldn't it be that this colitis is an old symptom coming up again under Nux vomica?
-No, I don't think.
-From last time we saw some changes in the ECG and the posterior wall of the heart and on the side.
These changes represent the ECG in the following leads that is in II and III.
Then we saw an inversion of the T-wave, so that this wave is negative instead of positive
a slight impression of the T-segment. Now we don't see this at all, we see a normal examination,
the posterior wall will have the following lines. This is a bit disturbed by her trembling
but nevertheless we can't find any negative changes.
What is very impressive I registered it with higher speed and you can see one part of
the ECG especially clear.
We can find absolutely normal examination. That's all.
-So the Israeli cardiologist was correct not to give you a ECG. Now you consider yourself normal.
-After I took the Pulsatilla a year ago, it started a rheumatic pain in my joints,
especially in the left hand, coming and going.
Sometimes it was really hard to work with it and also in the bones that lead to the fingers
and also in the left foot. After the Pulsatilla the cramps in the calves stopped
even though I was stretching.
I used to have it in stretching and it came back with the Nux vomica these cramps again and
after the Pulsatilla all this feeling with the numbness on the feet came back which went away
with the Phosphorus in the morning.
When I wrote this was when I was here during the seminar. I had little pimples in my mouth
and I was still feeling bad if I slept in the afternoon, I checked that.
This is a symptom since I remember myself, I feel like a headache and vomiting, nausea.
If I go, which I never do but if something happens and I do go to sleep, I wake up very nauseated and
with a headache. The last time I had that was last week, even if I sleep 5 minutes I wake up like this.
I don't sleep anymore only on the right side, I used to sleep only on the right, I don't.
-The last time you took Nux vomica LM for how long?
-I'm coming into it because usually I don't pay attention to what is going on with me.
I just wrote a few things and I'll come to it later. The only thing which I saw after the Pulsatilla
with the Nux vomica was that I didn't sleep anymore the same way. I sleep like this with the
hands up and the legs are like this, one is up but that's how I slept always.
I found myself too busy, too much involved with everything that is going on and very upset
of what is going on in Israel, people cheating on the back of other people.
More like a Causticum, everything bothers me and I used to go very mad.
It annoys me in a minute and it's like it goes straight in my head and blowing it, it was terrible.
The only thing that I had amelioration was shaken a little bit, which then I remembered that
I used to do it as a kid when I had asthma, the only thing that ameliorated was sitting like this
and doing like this all the time, slight movement.
I start everything from May. Memory, since May and before and now one of the worse things
is the memory.
-What happened?
-I lose words, I want to tell you something and the word doesn't come. I have to look through a draw,
you know, to think, think, think till the word comes and I don't remember the names of people
that I know very well. I want to do something and then if I don't do it or immediately
don't write it down within 1 minute I forget what I had to do.
Another funny thing is when I see a cut, like my husband cut his finger, I get like a...
it goes through here to my buttocks.
-It's almost fainting.
-It's not fainting, it's like ticklish that moves from my feet up to my buttocks which it's funny.
I could see people in the hospital dying and nothing moved me this way.
-Is this something which is lately?
-No, it's not lately, it's the last 10-20 years but it's quite strong now.
From the 14th of May while we were here, my left eye was all the time I had tears all the time
and it was red like an eruption. On the 20th of May all these little blisters on my tongue came,
especially at the end of the tongue, big one burning and then I had a kind of herpes inside my nose,
but it's an old symptom. It's something that came back.
Then I had like flu. Now I know what it is. The last 6 months when I get my period, if I do get it at all,
I have feeling like a flu, my back aches, my head aches, really like a flu and then 2 days later
I get my period. It happened already in the last 4 periods. I was not thirsty at all.
The levels of the sugar were quite high. If I look at it on the 22 of May it was 199 and
after eating 248, that was high.
-How did you examine? When you examine the blood?
-14 hours with no eating.
-How much it was then?
-Then it was 199, that's why you told me to take one dose of 30 and then one dose of 200 and
I tried to do that and it didn't help. So I went back to the LM and I continued with LM.
-You had only once sugar level check?
-All the time. I used to check it every day.
-Yourself.
-Yes, I have the machine.
-And what are the readings?
-The readings then in May were very high, 171 up to 248 two hours after eating.
What I'm telling you, I'm telling you the low one, the low one is without eating,
it's from the evening, about 14 hours without eating.
-Yes but how many times?
-It was the average. The lowest one was 171. It was quite high, then I went back to the LM
and it went down a little bit but still it was 154, it didn't go much down anymore
and I went up to LM 7.
Then I had very strong gas and the stomach was very bloated and in the afternoon I got my period.
It was when I was here. Then at 9 o'clock I took Nux vomica 30 and 10 o'clock at night
I had diarrhea and really strong pains in my stomach.
It was like old symptom and the diarrhea smelled like a vomit and I slept very good at
night and in the morning the gas were gone. The sugar in the morning was 167.
All the time I had a desire for lemon, something sour, something refreshing.
I usually drink water of soda with lemon and I found out that I don't take my feet anymore
out of the covers and I sleep good and I didn't come in a messy bed in the morning.
I wrote everything in mistakes like writing 4 instead of 5, April instead of May
and at about 3.30 to 4.30 I was breaking into really tired.
-Just for 1 hour or continuous?
-Yes like a break into this hour.
-You are talking still about the last seminar.
-I'm talking about after I tried Nux vomica the higher one and the low one because
we didn't check it afterwards.
In June I went back to LM and the sugar stayed from 111 which was the lowest one up to 298
which was the highest one.
-Without eating?
-No, the 111 is without eating, the 298 is with eating, 2 hours after eating but it was annoying
because I did make a diet and if you eat only cheese and really little and to get up
to such a sugar level it's really annoying. It's terrible. Anyway the pain was very
strong in the joints and the numbness in the feet was strong and I felt when I wake up in
the morning, my circulation didn't work.
When I rubbed the fingers was better and the stomach was still very bloated and gas and
then I had a new symptom. When I used to eat something, it doesn't matter what,
I just fell asleep in the middle of eating.
-You used to have that?
-I never had that before.
-While eating?
-It started while eating and after eating I wanted to sleep. I couldn't hold my eyes open.
-During eating?
-While I'm eating after a few bites, they become heavy.
-Not that you have been sleeping really.
-They become heavy and they close, they just fade away. It's very funny.
I used to have this when I see a theater for instance, when I'm in a theater and it could be
even a flamenco dance which is noisy or something very funny that everybody laughs
my eyes go down and I fall asleep and I start snoring. My husband does like this to me.
I think it's the light because usually the stage is lighted and I'm in the dark
and that bothers my eyes and they become heavy and I just go. My kids and husband hate that.
They make sure that I stay awake but not in a cinema, just in a real stage.
For instance in Cats I slept the whole show, even in Star light express where they go on top of you
with all the sketch and the noise.
-What is cats?
-Cats is a famous musical.
-It's a musical.
-Yes and I slept very good.
-If you want to sleep, you go to a musical and have a deep sleep.
-Did you sleep in a flamenco show? I slept in a flamenco show too.
-It's a good symptom, why should we take it away?
-It depends what the play is all about. Anyways I have the same thing while I'm eating.
I had suddenly a wandering pain like the right ankle and then the left knee and then a cramp
in my left calp and dry mouth at night, about 11-12 midnight and numbness in the tips of the fingers.
Then in August I started having again the sweating thing. I was getting extra sweat,
when I walk outside and it's hot I don't get sweat and then when I go into a room with air condition,
then I start sweating. I found it a bit funny because I should sweat when I do exertion in the heat,
not when it's already cold and nice, it's dripping like a shower.
-But if you have not exerted yourself, you are just in a cold room?
-Then I don't sweat. I need a fanning. If I can put some rubric in 4 that's fanning.
I need air moving. Even if I have an air condition. And it's also ameliorating everything.
The normal stool that I have is usually half an hour after I wake up and when I start moving already.
I wake up, do whatever I need and within half an hour I have to go to the toilet or at about 9 o'clock
in the morning. The stool used to be very smelly. I always try to find the smell, to say how it smells,
I don't. It stings, I don't know how to say it. I remember my husband once said,
a few years ago, it smells like a dead body sometimes.
Now it doesn't smell anymore that much, I took another remedy in the mean time
but it was like force able with urination together, it's like a diarrhea, yellow like a baby
and sometimes it's a bit fat and floating, that's the normal one.
-Do you have an excessive thirst with this high blood sugar.
-I don't have thirst at all, I have to force myself to drink twice the day.
I could pass the whole day without drinking one glass.
-Do you have any dryness in your mouth?
-Yes in the evening.
-In the evening your mouth becomes very dry?
-Yes, very dry. Some days yes, some days not but if I do, usually it is in the evening.
Yesterday I had it but maybe because I was flying over and everything.
Usually is around 9, 10 o'clock at night.
I was already on LM 7 and I had cramps on my feet and cramps on my back and on the side
and in the morning I had an eruption on the tip of my nose which is a symptom that
came many times the few months that I took the Nux vomica.
I used to have it, every time I took it.
-Real eruption or you just had a little...
-No, a little red one on the tip. I started to have crying comes out when I think about something,
anything that makes me feel, grows the feeling up. For instance we have in Israel a show
that everybody listens to the radio. She is a woman ,she is a psychiatrist
and people call her and tell their problems. All the time there are problems of children
and people that you can hear the remedy and she tells them, take this pill, take that pill
and makes me so annoyed because I think if they would have taken this kid to a homeopath
within few days it's over. And she sends a kid of 7 or 8 to take psychiatric medications
which is crazy and I used to really cry over it, it makes me nervous.
-Just throw a stone on the television.
-It's not on the television, it's on the radio, every day for 3 hours.
On the 5th of August I took the 200 Nux and I tried to move it a little bit and in the evening I took 1M
and in the morning I went out shopping, I was very happy and I had an urge to clean
and throw everything out of the house, which usually I don't do.
I'm usually a collector, I collect things and I decided to throw things and then on the 8th of August
I had so many days which were really intolerable, nightmares.
-What do you mean? You had nightmares?
-I had anxiety and stress about coming here to Alonissos, I decided to change the hotel
to go to live here in Melia Bay so I can walk but then I was very upset because I thought that
I have to tell Costas that I want to move and I didn't want to offend.
-Just a little thing like that?
-Just a little thing bothers me so much.
-You don't have to think twice, if you want to change you just tell them, I don't come.
-It bothers me. Anyway I woke up with very bad mood and I felt that something bothers me
in the background and another new symptom is that normally I don't have hair.
I have little bit on the left side and none on the right side and the last few months with the Nux
I start growing hair. It grew like a normal person.
-Finally.
-And I felt sweat again, now it changed but I felt like I have smelling and sweat more.
Around the 12th of August I just give this report that I gave you.
On the 12th of August I decided to take Causticum.
-What potency?
-LM. I didn't have the courage to take something else. With LM I can stop it if it's too bad
and it was very bad. I took LM 2 and the sugar still went up because I already had 200 sugar
by that time and the sugar continued going up. The next day I took LM 3 and within 2 hours
the sugar went down to 130 and since then I took twice the day LM 3 and the sugar
was maximum 147 after eating, which normally went up to 300.
At night I had a very bad dream. It had something to do with jealousy with my husband
and I was very furious and the whole day I walked with this feeling,
very cross with him and it continued.
I had such an uneasiness and stress in a stress the whole day. In the 15th of August at 2.30
in the afternoon I felt very bad, pains in my stomach and diarrhea like I ate something rotten.
It's an old symptom, I had this a few times before and since then I didn't have any diarrhea at all
except one wedding in the 2d of September.
The stool stopped being a diarrhea, since the Causticum, which I had diarrhea all my life
and it changed that, I have soft stool but formed, not a diarrhea anymore, still the same hours.
Just after I took the Causticum the left eye all the time wet, all the time with tears
and a kind of swelling on the top and underneath a red eruption and then on the 15th started
like a crust on my nose which I took out and it continued all the time for about a month.
The sugar went down from 200 to 150 in the morning. On the 20th of August I went up in LM 4
and still the eye is dripping and the joints are still painful and the crust in the nose
on the 22 is still there and then I decided not to take anymore Causticum because
I didn't feel good and I thought about calling you and see maybe I go back to Nux vomica
and I decided to leave it, to let the body do whatever it feels like and stop with everything.
-That's the best.
-Then within few days the sugar started going down, down and stabilized
and from the 22 of August it was 142, 117,126,160 and I had already 2 days without a remedy and
the sugar was 140 in the morning and I had a very strong desire for soft boiled eggs
with butter and bread.
Then I had a lot of problems in my stomach. I had a feeling that there is something
that grows in my stomach and pushes my bladder and I had an urge all the time to go on
the toilet but nothing came out, very little.
It was not like cystitis. It was something different because I had a few times cystitis.
It was not like that.
It was like something big growing and pushing like you are in the beginning of pregnancy.
Then I had also a heart burn like pushing up and pushing down and I thought that maybe
it was a stool that didn't come out because I didn't have my diarrhea, I didn't clean up enough
like I'm used to and I had a lot of gas that came out with very nice voice.
Then the whole system of the sugar went differently than it used to be before.
Before if I would not eat for 14 hours, it used to got the lowest and then after 2-4 hours after eating
it goes higher. In this time it used to go down during the day and go a little bit after eating
but then at night it used to go up and in the morning it used to be very high.
It was with no rules, even if I didn't eat for 14 hours it was going differently, not like it used to be
with the Nux or normal. On the 29th of August I had a very strong pain in my back like a flu and
I got my period. I'm in menopause and every time I take a remedy, I get back my period.
I gave you all. There was one time at the end of August that I got very very angry at work
and I thought I'm going to have a heart attack and then later on I got angry and I thought
I'm going to have a stroke. It went up to my head for a few days and the blood pressure
was quite OK and on the 1st of September the sugar started going down, the levels.
I didn't have any Causticum anymore and it went 136, 123, 124.Then after food 196.
Then on the 6th of September was 136, 129, 110, 109, 106 really nice and in the holiday
I had a very good meal and I said, no I'm going to check it. I eat something sweet and
I wanted to see if it went up and it did not go up much. It went up to 164 which previously
used to go up to 300 but I felt it's on the good way. I was quite happy with this Causticum thing
and mentally I felt better, I just didn't like to go to work anymore.
I wanted time for myself, I wanted to take care of myself more and I didn't want to care for anybody.
I had a wedding coming, my daughter got married last Tuesday.
-Very good.
-And I had a new grand son 2 months ago, so it was... First the grandson and then the wedding
and I was quite happy.
-This is usual today?
-No, the grand son is from the other daughter. She is married 3 years already.
And the sweating comes back after the Causticum and a very nice things happened to me
while I took the Nux vomica. First time in my life I like to walk, I start walking a lot.
I had so much energy and I wanted to walk all the time.
-Fast or slow?
-Fast, only fast and I love it. I think it's going down now after the Causticum but with the Nux
it was beautiful because I never liked it. I enjoyed walking but not that much.
I really enjoyed it. I think that's all. The memory is terrible.
And a new symptom. I had here in this part of my head scratching.
I asked my husband to look if there is eruption, he said there is no eruption, nothing.
I was scratching like I have lice. Even after washing the hair. On the 12th of September I had here
all red and burning in the left eye and the period was not moving much in the beginning
and I was very nervous. My daughter was nervous because of the wedding and I was nervous.
The only thing that calmed me was holding this baby. It's like it moved me to another world.
Holding and nothing happened around. It isolated me from all the problems around.
-It was the first time you became grand mother?
-Yes.
Now the only thing I can tell about right now, mentally I don't like to work in my office.
I have all these volunteers, there is a lot of problems going with the government towards
volunteering, a lot of problems for me. I just avoid them, I go away because I feel like I'm going
to have a stroke physically. I feel that it makes me so crazy because it's not right, they do things,
they throw people out of the country, they don't let them in the country,
they do so many things.
It's one woman there, a clark, who decides for what has to do with people like she wants,
like it's her private business and it's so much annoying.
-Was anybody known to you who wanted to enter the country and they did not allow him?
-Of course, all the people that I work with. It's young people who come to see the country
they stay in kibbutz. She just decided that, it's kind of a plot actually.
You know that they know that they do all kinds of plots when it's the interest of this one
or that one and it's money involved. They like to bring foreign workers.
There is a lot of people who gain money out of foreign workers and the volunteers who come
for little money, just to enjoy time and it helps a lot and they don't want them because
if the farmers didn't have them, they take foreign workers and they gain money.
So what they did, they influenced this woman, just before the election and she took out all kind
of rules and things and she told them in the airport whenever any check of (?) come in,
just report them. Immediately put them on the plane back home.
It's young students who hardly have any money and you don't do these things.
I could not stand that. So I had to be at home, I had to be at work, when this happened
because it was too difficult. They used to call me at 4 o'clock and say listen there is a group of yours,
she said not to take them in but I'm letting them in.
So she used to work with me till they caught her and they gave her a lot of problems.
I found out that I go crazy at work, it's only problems all the time which I go really mad.
My health is ruined, so I decided to avoid as much as possible and friends of mine started dying.
This man doesn't wake up, the other one got suddenly cancer and
too many things happened in the last few months and I decided that in order maybe
to be healthy or in case I wouldn't finish this millennium, just to go out.
So I'm coming here and then about a month ago I booked for my husband and me
I had to go but where shall I go, every world is crazy. So I decided in New Zealand.
That's far enough and it's still nice, the nature and the people are beautiful.
So we go in New Zealand and Australia, I took all my savings.
-You are happy now?
-After that I felt a little bit better and I just had this wedding to finish with.
I enjoyed it a lot and it was beautiful, my daughter enjoyed it.
She had it exactly like she wanted it.
-OK.
Can you switch off the lights?
I want to know who prescribed wait? 73. Who prescribed a new remedy?
Who prescribed the same remedy? Who prescribed the same potency? Very good.
I'm very happy with the progress of the class, this is the idea. I don't know if for the same reasons
as are my reasons but still the decision is the same. So it doesn't matter, the results matter.
She is a sensitive individual with reactions to different potencies, so give time.
She is impatient, she has done it before, she takes other remedies, she interferes
with the reactions of the remedies, so you don't know really what is the result of the
previous remedy or the now remedy. I have some result, I stop the remedy, I feel better, I start again,
then you have to suspend all remedies and wait to see this organism how he settles down
and what kind of a picture eventually produces.
The reason is why? Because we have some easy disturbances.
The pancreas one time is working, one time is not working.
This kind of changing of the organism so easily, it needs some time to settle down.
The advice should be don't take any remedy, take placebo, why not? It makes good.