Here in case 14 with a 45 years old man with loss of voice,
partial paralysis of vocal chords.
This man had a very interesting but hard life.
At this time he was Director of a School for the hearing impaired and the teacher.
He had come to Athens from his village when he was 12 years old
and stayed with an uncle of his who treated him poorly.
At 13 his own parents were killed in a car crash and the poor boy was going around
from relative to relative.
He was a closed boy, did not show his emotions freely
and he was given to bouts of non stop weeping.
This continued until he was 18 years old when he finally got into the University.
At that time his life took a turn for the better.
He joined certain political functions where anarchist tendency was a leader amongst them.
He always stood up for the underdog and was the first to see whether a situation
was justly held or not.
He could not abide seeing suffering in others and was always there for the other person.
He was very empathic to other's suffering and he would go out of his way to alleviate the suffering.
Desires for fish, ice cream, smoked meat and especially bacon.
Here the decision should be between three remedies.
The one is Staphysagria, the other is Phosphorus and the other is Causticum.
If you wrote any of these you will get some marks.
Who wrote Staphysagria? No one.
Who wrote Phosphorus? Who wrote Causticum? Who wrote another remedy?
Next case a woman passing 30 years old complaining for pain in the right scapula.
This began approximately three months ago and it bothers her
whenever she has to lift something heavy.
She also suffers from distention of the abdomen with much gas and
flatulence and she also has pain from varicose veins on her right leg.
All these symptoms are worse from 4-8.
About 5 months ago she also had problems with her gallbladder.
She has stones in her gallbladder and she must be careful in her diet to avoid fat rich food.
As to her character this woman wants other people to listen to her
and she is angry when they do not.
She exerts quite a sphere of influence on her family and wants to run their lives.
She has a fear of snakes and sometimes dreams about them.
Desires sweets, hot drinks and aversion to cheese.
Between Lycopodium and Chelidonium, that is the choice.
You have strong symptoms of Lycopodium, worse 4-8, desires sweets, bloatedness
but you also have strong symptoms of Chelidonium.
That is what we discuss and aversion to cheese comes in favor for Chelidonium,
the pain in the right scapula comes in favor of Chelidonium and both they have
gallbladder problems, both desire warm drinks.
What will make you decide this way or that way?
She has no other fears except fear of snakes.
-I thing the character is very important.
-The character is very important.
In this case where you have the balance of physical symptoms,
you have the balance of two remedies almost equal but you have a description
of a type of a person who fits more this way or that way.
Then the balance is shifted towards that which gives weight to the remedy
due to the character situation.
Therefore in favor of Lycopodium or Chelidonium?
If we listen to what we know is in favor of Chelidonium and here we are prescribing
according to the Materia Medica and not according so much to the Repertorization.
Who prescribed in favor of Lycopodium? Who prescribed in favor of Chelidonium?
Who prescribed another remedy, Lac caninum?
Because the fear of Lac Caninum is this enough here to balance the symptoms of Lachesis?
We don't have other symptoms of Lac caninum.
Therefore the decision should be Chelidonium first, if it does not act,
then you go to Lycopodium.
Here the idea of 4-8 is it possible for another remedy to have 4-8?
Let me explain a little bit more the case.
Is it possible that other remedies have worse from 4-8?
It is possible. Is it possible that Chelidonium might have that aggravation.
It's also possible, it's not recorded but it is possible but there is another thing here
in this case, which is very apparent for me.
The case says that you will have to give first Chelidonium and then the pain in the right
scapula and psychologically she will feel better, still she may continue to have bloatedness
and still may continue to have worse 4-8.
In this case Lycopodium has to be given as a complementary to complete the cure of this case.
What you have to think is, I give first Chelidonium, if it does not work I'll go to Lycopodium.
If it does work and it leaves out Lycopodium symptoms, then OK Lycopodium and
Chelidonium are complementary, then I go to Chel. then I complete the picture.
I remember a case in Germany. Severe headaches in a woman, tremendous headaches
for 15-20 years, her life was ruined.
I prescribed Chelidonium and she had a tremendous reaction.
She came after a few months for the follow up and the idea of Lycopodium was developing
and then most probably I felt she would go to Lycopodium and then to Pulsatilla.
The patient went out, I explained into the class and the practitioner who was treating
this patient a few years back, he was in the class.
I said that to the class and it was written of course in the video what I said because the
Expert System also had given Lycopodium and then Pulsatilla as the two best
prescriptions after six months of Chelidonium.
She was still having pains, she was not cured, I explained to the class that that is developing,
Lycopodium is developing and most probably will be followed by Pulsatilla.
She is on video, all that I tell you is on video. She comes after again I'm back in Germany,
she comes for the follow up. She says I have to tell you that your remedy did not cure me.
So I went back to my practitioner who gave me first Lycopodium and then Pulsatilla and
now I'm well. I didn't say anything, I said OK, very good practitioner because I meant it,
he listened at least to the indications which I had given.
The only difference is that he did not tell her that that was explained in the class.
It was his decision but it's OK little things like that are totally forgivable,
as long as the patient is doing so well.
Then I went back to the video and I said to the class, do you remember?
Lycopodium and then Pulsatilla, so we do know that these remedies follow each other
and complete the action of each other.
-In this case the development of hers is friendly from Chelidonium to Lycopodium.
Can you give us some good marks to differentiate when we shall change the remedy?
Because differential diagnosis is very difficult. How to decide?
-So I come back to his questions when he says what are the indications,
when is the time to prescribe Lycopodium?
I say in this particular time once you see the changes, that means
the person feels better psychologically, the pain on the right scapula is not there
and perhaps the bloatedness is even worse or the general worse 4-8 is really established.
Even after a month you can give Lycopodium but there are other cases where you have to
wait until the development of Lycopodium.
There is another possibility. You give Chelidonium and then it feels better all around,
better the bloatedness, I'm not so much down during 4-8,
you think the whole thing is developing, don't touch it by the time it's developing.
But now after six months comes back and says, now I feel 4-8...
my bloatedness starts again being great, that's the time when you prescribe Lycopodium.
-One can possible say that Lycopodium is working deeper, has a deeper action
and that one first should take the remedy that does not act deep,
does not hit the personality on such a deep level?
-Yes you can say. Actually the remedy which finally brings about the total person
to another level, that remedy is the deepest.
It might be the third or fourth remedy that will do that.
Of course third or fourth not because you gave three wrong ones.
Because you gave three correct ones and the fourth correct one brings up the change.
-I decided for Lycopodium because you told us that the mental symptoms of Chelidonium
are not so sure and Lycopodium too can be a dictator.
The second thing is that at the time 4-8 is very important,
then there is the warm drinks that Lycopodium has and in case there is only a value of desire
for hot drinks second degree, the Lycopodium in the Repertory says that there is a pain
from the right hypochondrium to the scapula.
And it's a right sided remedy, so that was my decision for Lycopodium.
-Yes. You are right in a way because the case is structured in such a way as to confuse.
What I say is that you have to read through the lines in the case.
If we said here she is a dictator in the family where outside she is a cowardice,
you are absolutely right and there will be no question about Lycopodium.
But in this way that it is structured the case, it's expressing the idea of Chelidonium more
than Lycopodium. Lycopodium also has some fears, what will be the fears of Lycopodium?
You are asking. If this person develops fears, the fears of Lycopodium
will take the turn of Lycopodium, not they will take the turn of Lachesis.
So she has some fears but the fears do not belong to Lycopodium, also she runs the family,
she has some opinions but it shows a powerful person, not a weak person which
shows Lycopodium. Otherwise we would have some indications in the case.
-What would have been if we would not have the information about the character?
-Then Lycopodium.
-If we had to choose between aversion to cheese and the time, what would be the main?
-If you did not have any information about the character,
then the prescription should be Lycopodium.
You have more symptoms on the physical level, the balance is in favor of Lycopodium.
On the mental symptoms the balance is in favor of Chelidonium.
That's why the balance is shifted, without the mental symptoms at all but with desires,
you have to prescribe Lycopodium.
-May I say something?
-I want to make observation between this case and the case we should do tonight
at Argentum nitricum.
Here we have a very special physical pathology and this is the varicose veins in the right leg.
They are potentially life threatening.
I don't see in the Repertory, Chelidonium under varicose in the legs.
So my question is if we have to choose what is to be cured in this case,
actually I would say that potentially from those varicose we might have troubles.
Like for example pulmonary emboli or something like this.
Maybe we should either add as an official addition Chelidonium in the Repertory
for the varicose veins of the right leg or give Lycopodium to this case.
-No, it's not like this.
When you have some pathology which does not belong to the remedy,
it does not mean that this pathology will not be cured by the remedy.
It means that most probably is going to be cured by the remedy.
If it is not cured by the remedy, Chelidonium has acted, then Lycopodium has acted and
the varicose veins are staying, that means that the next remedy in order to touch that level
it's Pulsatilla which comes as a complementary to Lycopodium and then
you have symptoms of Pulsatilla.
Varicose veins do not endanger death, I have not seen that.
-I have seen that.
-Excuse me for interrupting but I wanted to clarify something.
Before I translated the question of a lady who spoke German.
The question was does Lycopodium acts on a deeper level than Chelidonium which you said yes.
But I understood her question in such a way that her question was,
would you suggest to use as a first remedy the one that does not act
as deeply on the psychological level?
Is that the reason why you start with Chelidonium? That I wanted to correct.
-It's good that you make this explanation.
I don't suggest that in cases you give a superficial remedy first and then you give a deeper
remedy, no. Not at al.
I say that you have to choose the uppermost layer, what information you have.
This is the uppermost, you use it.
If this uppermost is a polychrest, use it.
If the uppermost is a remedy which indicated or a small remedy or superficial, give it.
It's the correct remedy and it will act. Don't worry.
It will act. It may not act curatively totally but it will take it to the next remedy
and then you can say the next remedy took away everything, it is deeper.
Yes it is deeper, in a way you can say it is deeper but give always the remedy
which comes out of information from the patient at the moment.
-I meant my question another way. I wanted to say if there was the same information
for both remedies to choose, is it more important to use the chemistry,
so to use the aversion or is it more important to use the time, as a deciding factor?
-No. It's equal important. Your choice then could be only on intensity.
If it is very clear, underlined 3 times worse 4-8, forget it.
If on the other hand this is not so clear but the aversion for cheese is very strong,
absolutely and then you have the scapula, then the balance will shift towards Chelidonium.
So the intensity and the clearness of a symptom will determine your choice.
-If we give Chelidonium to this case and then it begins to move towards Lycopodium,
should we observe that the person from a powerful one is becoming a coward?
And this is a cure or not?
-No.
-I still don't understand.
-You don't have to have mental pathology after that.
What I say, some of the pathology which is there, physical pathology is left over,
which is covered by Lycopodium then you can give it.
The question is in all cases do you have to have mental pathology? The answer is no.
You don't have to have mental pathology in all cases, not at all.
Emotionally and mentally people can be quite balanced
and suffering a lot in their physical body. You don't have to have mental pathology.
A Lycopodium may not have at all the character that we described.
In mental-emotional it might be totally balanced and we have only physical symptoms.
Then you treat the physical symptoms.
You don't have to have mental-emotional in every case.
That has to be very clear because then that is another misunderstanding coming from my teaching.
When I teach like this and my students say, George said prescribe only on essence.
What is essence? Mental-emotional picture.
When I heard eventually that after 2-3 years I said, no for god's sake don't say that,
I did not say that.
I gave some mental-emotional structure of some remedies, it does not mean
that you have to prescribe only on that.
Because you will get a Lachesis that has no jealousy, no envy, it will be a very nice person
and you will miss it. You will say he is so nice, how can I give Lachesis?
Of course because he is balanced in this level.
Like somebody who is balanced in his physical body
and you say how can I give Lycopodium to a person who does not have bloatedness
and his liver is functioning.
No, you can give because the mental-emotional picture is Lycopodium. This is clear.