<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tt xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1" xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#styling">
<head>
<horsedata><item name="editor_clearFormatBtn">true</item><item name="editor_alignButtons">false</item><item name="editor_underlinedBtn">true</item><item name="editor_valignButtons">false</item><item name="behaviour_transcriptMode">true</item><item name="appearance_showMultiLinesTitles">false</item><item name="appearance_showBlackBG">false</item><item name="behaviour_autocorrect">true</item><item name="behaviour_titlesGap">0.1</item><item name="behaviour_useEnterKey">linebreak</item><item name="editor_fontFamilyCombo">false</item><item name="editor_fontSizeCombo">false</item><item name="editor_italicBtn">true</item><item name="editor_boldBtn">true</item></horsedata></head>
<body>
<div>
<p begin="00:00:54.340" end="00:01:18.870" horseID="0">So the grand rule on Homeopathy is <br/>Similia Similibus Curentur.</p>
<p begin="00:01:20.240" end="00:01:36.070" horseID="1">This is the grand rule which means<br/> that a remedy can cure if fits, </p>
<p begin="00:01:36.170" end="00:01:40.950" horseID="2">if it is similar with the pathology of the case.</p>
<p begin="00:01:42.980" end="00:01:52.210" horseID="3">So, that means we have remedies <br/>that we know their pathology. </p>
<p begin="00:02:00.560" end="00:02:06.760" horseID="4">I want you to understand why such <br/>a thing is happening.</p>
<p begin="00:02:07.640" end="00:02:18.880" horseID="5">When you have a disease, <br/>you have a symptomatology.</p>
<p begin="00:02:20.160" end="00:02:29.130" horseID="6">This symptomatology is the result of a <br/>defence mechanism who is trying </p>
<p begin="00:02:29.230" end="00:02:33.390" horseID="7">to re-establish itself into order.</p>
<p begin="00:02:33.490" end="00:02:41.280" horseID="8">To bring back order into the organism<br/>through that symptomatology.</p>
<p begin="00:02:41.960" end="00:02:48.050" horseID="9">So the symptomatology is a useful thing<br/> for the organism and the symptoms </p>
<p begin="00:02:48.150" end="00:02:59.500" horseID="10">are absolutely necessary for that particular<br/>organism in order to stay in balance, not to die.</p>
<p begin="00:02:59.650" end="00:03:10.920" horseID="11">So we respect the symptoms of a patient whether in acute or in a chronic state.</p>
<p begin="00:03:11.240" end="00:03:23.160" horseID="12">We respect very much this symptomatology<br/> and we try to write down </p>
<p begin="00:03:23.260" end="00:03:29.310" horseID="13">all the symptoms of the case <br/>and then try to find which is the remedy,</p>
<p begin="00:03:29.410" end="00:03:38.650" horseID="14"> which has in its pathogenesis when <br/>it was proven in the healthy organism,</p>
<p begin="00:03:39.650" end="00:03:48.910" horseID="15">we try to find which is the similium, which <br/>is exactly that remedy that fits the totality.</p>
<p begin="00:03:51.190" end="00:04:03.160" horseID="16">And then if you are given this, the patient<br/> is cured. Why this happens? </p>
<p begin="00:04:05.040" end="00:04:08.380" horseID="17">Here we have a graph, right?</p>
<p begin="00:04:15.640" end="00:04:23.130" horseID="18">These are symptoms, strong <br/>symptoms of the patient, </p>
<p begin="00:04:23.830" end="00:04:33.730" horseID="19">here we have a very high fever <br/>with its modalities.</p>
<p begin="00:04:33.830" end="00:04:39.470" horseID="20">Fever which comes in the afternoon <br/> 4-5 pm, fever which comes </p>
<p begin="00:04:39.570" end="00:04:44.080" horseID="21">only in the morning, fever in the <br/>evening, constant fever, whatever.</p>
<p begin="00:04:45.570" end="00:04:57.320" horseID="22">But fever is not the only symptom. He can <br/>have also headache, strong headache,</p>
<p begin="00:05:01.290" end="00:05:09.930" horseID="23">headache with its modalities, we write them down exactly, the modalities of the fever.</p>
<p begin="00:05:10.100" end="00:05:25.940" horseID="24">And then we have exhaustion, tremendous exhaustion and then we have </p>
<p begin="00:05:26.040" end="00:05:33.440" horseID="25">together with these fever, exhaustion etc. <br/>we have coughing.</p>
<p begin="00:05:36.110" end="00:05:48.840" horseID="26">And then here we have excessive thirst <br/>and then here we have nightmares.</p>
<p begin="00:05:52.880" end="00:06:01.800" horseID="27">So you are searching to find a remedy<br/> with fever with a specific modality, </p>
<p begin="00:06:01.900" end="00:06:02.900" horseID="28">do you understand modality?</p>
<p begin="00:06:03.000" end="00:06:09.460" horseID="29">Anybody does not understand <br/>some words, I'm using words </p>
<p begin="00:06:09.560" end="00:06:17.780" horseID="30">which are used in Homeopathy and <br/>I suppose that everyone understands them.</p>
<p begin="00:06:17.880" end="00:06:22.540" horseID="31">If somebody does not understand, <br/>he has to ask so you can follow </p>
<p begin="00:06:22.640" end="00:06:29.770" horseID="32">step by step everything. Otherwise <br/>it's not good, you just follow, follow, </p>
<p begin="00:06:29.870" end="00:06:35.630" horseID="33">follow and then a confusion is created, ok?</p>
<p begin="00:06:37.120" end="00:06:42.610" horseID="34">We try to find a remedy that has fever, that <br/>has a particular headache we are looking for, </p>
<p begin="00:06:42.710" end="00:06:48.110" horseID="35">which has a particular exhaustion, <br/>which has the coughing, nightmares etc.</p>
<p begin="00:06:48.210" end="00:06:55.980" horseID="36"> So that means it will be a remedy similar.</p>
<p begin="00:07:01.760" end="00:07:09.780" horseID="37"> The remedy will have more <br/>or less a graph like this.</p>
<p begin="00:07:13.960" end="00:07:25.260" horseID="38">If the exhaustion is very great, then<br/> it will have a graph like this. </p>
<p begin="00:07:25.360" end="00:07:31.980" horseID="39">So the most characteristic of this patient <br/>is the exhaustion he is totally exhausted, </p>
<p begin="00:07:32.080" end="00:07:38.130" horseID="40">then the remedy has to have exhaustion<br/> in very great degree also. </p>
<p begin="00:07:40.050" end="00:07:49.590" horseID="41">So for each symptom we have <br/>intensity and modalities.</p>
<p begin="00:07:49.720" end="00:08:00.000" horseID="42">How intensive is and what <br/>modifies this symptom.</p>
<p begin="00:08:08.790" end="00:08:22.710" horseID="43">If we give a similar remedy, the patient will<br/> be cured. There is a logic behind this. </p>
<p begin="00:08:22.810" end="00:08:28.400" horseID="44">There is a very, very clear logic.</p>
<p begin="00:08:33.150" end="00:08:42.520" horseID="45">Can anybody know why? Can you tell me<br/> why if you give a similar remedy </p>
<p begin="00:08:42.620" end="00:08:49.040" horseID="46">- that means the symptoms - I’m going <br/>to be worse, not better.</p>
<p begin="00:08:50.240" end="00:08:58.940" horseID="47">The symptoms are going to be worse <br/>because this organism produces this graph </p>
<p begin="00:08:59.040" end="00:09:03.700" horseID="48">that means this symptomatology <br/>as a reaction to what?</p>
<p begin="00:09:03.800" end="00:09:13.670" horseID="49">To a bacteria, a virus or whatever. <br/>So a bacteria has invaded my body </p>
<p begin="00:09:13.770" end="00:09:18.490" horseID="50">or has developed within my body<br/>and then the organism in order to </p>
<p begin="00:09:18.590" end="00:09:29.500" horseID="51">counteract this invasion produces symptoms. And then I come and I give a remedy </p>
<p begin="00:09:29.600" end="00:09:35.220" horseID="52">which has similar symptoms. At this point <br/>we have to be very clear because </p>
<p begin="00:09:35.320" end="00:09:37.780" horseID="53">when we explain Homeopathy we <br/>have to explain it in this way </p>
<p begin="00:09:37.880" end="00:09:46.420" horseID="54">that makes sense to the patient, to ourselves <br/>to understand what we are doing and this</p>
<p begin="00:09:46.520" end="00:09:55.400" horseID="55">understanding is useful for later on when you evaluate that case, what has happened.</p>
<p begin="00:09:55.950" end="00:10:00.730" horseID="56">Shall I give another remedy, shall<br/> I wait, what is this, what is that. </p>
<p begin="00:10:02.440" end="00:10:05.950" horseID="57">Do I give a remedy for one symptom?</p>
<p begin="00:10:06.270" end="00:10:12.000" horseID="58">I mean these questions are going to be <br/>solved if you understand very clearly </p>
<p begin="00:10:12.100" end="00:10:16.520" horseID="59">the mechanism of cure.</p>
<p begin="00:10:20.860" end="00:10:31.820" horseID="60">So my question to you is why this <br/>remedy is going to cure this patient </p>
<p begin="00:10:31.920" end="00:10:36.600" horseID="61">and not make him worse?</p>
<p begin="00:10:44.250" end="00:10:47.720" horseID="62">There is a clear logic behind.</p>
<p begin="00:10:47.850" end="00:10:57.100" horseID="63"> The explanation is this. If the organism<br/> tries to bring about a cure through</p>
<p begin="00:10:57.200" end="00:11:04.110" horseID="64">developing this symptomatology <br/>and he cannot succeed </p>
<p begin="00:11:04.210" end="00:11:10.980" horseID="65">because he comes to us to cure him,<br/>that means he is suffering chronically</p>
<p begin="00:11:11.080" end="00:11:19.300" horseID="66"> or acutely. That means that the organism is having the symptoms constantly</p>
<p begin="00:11:20.000" end="00:11:29.860" horseID="67">and through these symptoms the organism<br/> is trying, 'let's make it a little bit more</p>
<p begin="00:11:29.960" end="00:11:36.520" horseID="68"> this headache and then I will cure you'. <br/>The defence mechanism behind. </p>
<p begin="00:11:36.620" end="00:11:42.220" horseID="69">You see for those who suffer with <br/>chronic headaches, every week </p>
<p begin="00:11:42.320" end="00:11:46.500" horseID="70">there comes a headache, every <br/>week 3 hours come the headache,</p>
<p begin="00:11:46.600" end="00:11:57.210" horseID="71"> every 3 hours come the pains in the <br/>abdomen, every day or every 2nd day </p>
<p begin="00:11:57.310" end="00:12:04.140" horseID="72">comes the pain in the gall bladder etc.<br/> That means the organism </p>
<p begin="00:12:04.240" end="00:12:15.980" horseID="73">That means the organism is bringing<br/> an epileptic fit every 5 days, <br/>every 3 days, every day.</p>
<p begin="00:12:16.410" end="00:12:25.880" horseID="74">This epileptic fit we claim it is an effort<br/> of the organism to cure itself.</p>
<p begin="00:12:26.320" end="00:12:32.090" horseID="75">This cough is an effort of the<br/> organism to cure itself. </p>
<p begin="00:12:34.350" end="00:12:45.750" horseID="76">Therefore if we strengthen by <br/>a mechanism, if we strengthen this effort, </p>
<p begin="00:12:46.170" end="00:12:55.560" horseID="77">the organism will be cured. If we find <br/>a way to strengthen the defences</p>
<p begin="00:12:55.660" end="00:13:05.420" horseID="78">of the body, then the organism will be cured because the organism is saying that </p>
<p begin="00:13:05.520" end="00:13:14.650" horseID="79">'through these symptoms I try to cure myself <br/>but I cannot, I need some extra strength</p>
<p begin="00:13:14.750" end="00:13:23.880" horseID="80"> to make these symptoms a little bit <br/>more so that I can overcome the disease'.</p>
<p begin="00:13:23.990" end="00:13:28.310" horseID="81">And there we come with a remedy <br/>which is similar which </p>
<p begin="00:13:28.410" end="00:13:39.380" horseID="82">touches the organism on an energy <br/>level, as the student said,</p>
<p begin="00:13:39.480" end="00:13:51.810" horseID="83">and for a period of time we have an <br/>aggravation, smaller or bigger aggravation.</p>
<p begin="00:13:52.770" end="00:13:59.540" horseID="84"> In every case, in the homeopathic cure <br/>we have an aggravation of the symptoms, </p>
<p begin="00:13:59.640" end="00:14:04.470" horseID="85">what we call the aggravation of the <br/>symptoms. That means that the symptoms</p>
<p begin="00:14:04.570" end="00:14:13.150" horseID="86">will become a little bit stronger for a small <br/>period, for a fraction of a minute sometimes, </p>
<p begin="00:14:13.250" end="00:14:21.550" horseID="87">in an acute disease or for several days <br/>in a case of chronic disease.</p>
<p begin="00:14:25.320" end="00:14:32.160" horseID="88"> The patient may experience an<br/> aggravation of the symptoms.</p>
<p begin="00:14:32.580" end="00:14:39.810" horseID="89">The symptoms become a little bit more<br/> or sometimes quite a lot more. </p>
<p begin="00:14:40.850" end="00:14:46.340" horseID="90">If the symptoms become quite a <br/>lot more then most probably </p>
<p begin="00:14:48.080" end="00:14:59.560" horseID="91">we have given the right remedy. We shall talk about the different modifications of that.</p>
<p begin="00:15:00.310" end="00:15:11.180" horseID="92">But giving an extra push, brings about what <br/>the organism is not able to do by himself </p>
<p begin="00:15:11.280" end="00:15:24.000" horseID="93">and there is a release. Did you understand <br/>this? Do you comprehend this point? </p>
<p begin="00:15:24.100" end="00:15:29.880" horseID="94">This is a point where we have to discuss so everybody will understand very clearly.</p>
<p begin="00:15:29.980" end="00:15:34.300" horseID="95">You have it in your mind <br/>established very clearly.</p>
<p begin="00:15:34.400" end="00:15:40.660" horseID="96">- Dr. Vithoulkas, do you mean that if there is <br/>no aggravation at all there is no cure?</p>
<p begin="00:15:44.110" end="00:15:57.490" horseID="97">-Good question. I mean yes, when there <br/>is no aggravation it cannot be a cure </p>
<p begin="00:15:57.590" end="00:16:00.010" horseID="98">with a difference.</p>
<p begin="00:16:00.110" end="00:16:09.590" horseID="99">When this reaction has <br/>reached its highest point, </p>
<p begin="00:16:09.690" end="00:16:16.630" horseID="100">the reaction is almost<br/> imperceptible, is very little.</p>
<p begin="00:16:16.730" end="00:16:27.570" horseID="101">The organism needs a little bit more so the patient himself does not realise the reaction.</p>
<p begin="00:16:27.670" end="00:16:37.130" horseID="102">And usually this case is in severe,<br/> acute diseases, where the patient </p>
<p begin="00:16:37.230" end="00:16:42.950" horseID="103">hardly realises the reaction,<br/> a little bit more fever,  </p>
<p begin="00:16:43.050" end="00:16:50.140" horseID="104">it doesn’t' matter, a little bit more <br/>headache, it doesn' t matter,</p>
<p begin="00:16:50.240" end="00:16:59.140" horseID="105">because he is in a very bad state already. <br/>But when we have chronic cases </p>
<p begin="00:16:59.240" end="00:17:06.730" horseID="106">there we have to be careful because<br/>the reaction can be quite severe.</p>
<p begin="00:17:07.760" end="00:17:18.580" horseID="107"> If in chronic cases we have problems that <br/>are functional, functional problems only</p>
<p begin="00:17:18.680" end="00:17:29.030" horseID="108">that means it is only a spasm of a <br/>vessel which makes the problem </p>
<p begin="00:17:29.130" end="00:17:34.830" horseID="109">with the headache and that's all. <br/>We have different kinds of headaches, </p>
<p begin="00:17:34.930" end="00:17:39.760" horseID="110">there are severe headaches etc. <br/>and in Homeopathy we learn</p>
<p begin="00:17:39.930" end="00:17:47.300" horseID="111">that each organism has <br/>its own severity of state. </p>
<p begin="00:17:47.400" end="00:17:52.660" horseID="112">That means, headache one person,<br/> headache the other person.</p>
<p begin="00:17:52.760" end="00:17:56.340" horseID="113">In this headache which looks <br/>similar to his headache, </p>
<p begin="00:17:56.440" end="00:18:01.330" horseID="114">is much more easy to cure<br/> than his headache.</p>
<p begin="00:18:01.430" end="00:18:07.670" horseID="115">That means there is a depth on this headache and not a depth on that headache.</p>
<p begin="00:18:07.770" end="00:18:16.040" horseID="116">That means that this headache will be cured without almost any perceptible aggravation.</p>
<p begin="00:18:16.810" end="00:18:25.470" horseID="117">His headache which is of a deeper kind is<br/> going to have a tremendous aggravation.</p>
<p begin="00:18:26.360" end="00:18:34.700" horseID="118">So it will depend on something which is <br/>called the depth of the problem, </p>
<p begin="00:18:34.800" end="00:18:42.200" horseID="119">which depends on different characters <br/>which we will be talking about, later on.</p>
<p begin="00:18:44.240" end="00:18:50.120" horseID="120">I don't want to bring a lot of issues<br/>together at the same time. </p>
<p begin="00:18:50.220" end="00:18:55.820" horseID="121">I want to keep it clear, basic things <br/>and then we'll elaborate as we go along,</p>
<p begin="00:18:55.920" end="00:19:03.400" horseID="122"> we will elaborate more and more<br/> on these issues.</p>
<p begin="00:19:03.720" end="00:19:11.660" horseID="123">But this I consider as a major <br/>understanding of how the remedy acts.</p>
<p begin="00:19:12.120" end="00:19:22.370" horseID="124">That means that every symptom is an effort of the organism to be cured, to bring balance, </p>
<p begin="00:19:22.470" end="00:19:30.010" horseID="125">because this organism after this will <br/>come to a kind of a balance, like this. </p>
<p begin="00:19:30.920" end="00:19:38.030" horseID="126">That means little symptoms anymore, <br/>they don't bother etc. he's almost well. </p>
<p begin="00:19:38.130" end="00:19:41.450" horseID="127">Maybe at that state we can try <br/>and give a second remedy </p>
<p begin="00:19:41.550" end="00:19:47.760" horseID="128">or may not try even,<br/> to give a second remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:19:47.860" end="00:19:53.860" horseID="129">So my first question to you will be:</p>
<p begin="00:20:14.960" end="00:20:35.550" horseID="130">Find where, in the Organon, which <br/>paragraph, states the law of similars </p>
<p begin="00:20:35.650" end="00:20:46.810" horseID="131">and in which paragraph Hahnemann <br/>explains this law, how it works. </p>
<p begin="00:20:52.820" end="00:21:04.960" horseID="132">State whether this explanation is the same as Hahnemann's or Hahnemman is different</p>
<p begin="00:21:05.090" end="00:21:11.150" horseID="133">or my explanation is different. </p>
<p begin="00:21:52.340" end="00:22:04.740" horseID="134"> State in which paragraph, the law of <br/>similars is mentioned in the Organon</p>
<p begin="00:22:04.840" end="00:22:14.640" horseID="135">in which paragraph the explanation<br/> of how the remedy works, </p>
<p begin="00:22:14.740" end="00:22:24.360" horseID="136">and 3rd question, whether this explanation<br/>is the same as the one I gave you here.</p>
<p begin="00:22:38.120" end="00:22:51.020" horseID="137">The body is trying through this symptomatology,  to bring back the balance but you will say</p>
<p begin="00:22:51.120" end="00:23:00.870" horseID="138">if you have an epileptic fit is it possible that through the epileptic fit the body is trying to</p>
<p begin="00:23:00.970" end="00:23:10.040" horseID="139">cure itself? Have we ever seen a case of epilepsy where it has been cured </p>
<p begin="00:23:10.140" end="00:23:22.730" horseID="140">through the epileptic fit? Such questions <br/>I would expect from you. Do you understand?</p>
<p begin="00:23:23.710" end="00:23:28.880" horseID="141"> I want you to put forward your <br/>questions or whatever you feel,</p>
<p begin="00:23:29.400" end="00:23:38.120" horseID="142"> well I don't understand, and we discuss<br/> until everything is clear in you.</p>
<p begin="00:23:38.220" end="00:23:49.080" horseID="143">Symptoms are developing in order to <br/>prevent a more severe or fatal outcome </p>
<p begin="00:23:49.180" end="00:23:55.700" horseID="144">from the disease. So an epileptic fit <br/>actually in the body which</p>
<p begin="00:23:55.800" end="00:24:04.850" horseID="145">   points out to a heavy electric discharge, </p>
<p begin="00:24:04.950" end="00:24:14.580" horseID="146">it could have killed that organism if the <br/>organism did not have the defence </p>
<p begin="00:24:14.680" end="00:24:21.970" horseID="147">mechanism ready to produce that kind<br/> of unconsiousness and spasm etc.</p>
<p begin="00:24:23.400" end="00:24:32.070" horseID="148">So yes definitely, this is to balance the <br/>body so it can exist, it can survive, </p>
<p begin="00:24:32.170" end="00:24:34.880" horseID="149">otherwise it can die. </p>
<p begin="00:24:36.200" end="00:24:42.910" horseID="150">But the fact remains, if we are <br/>interested, that this points to us, </p>
<p begin="00:24:43.010" end="00:24:50.060" horseID="151">how we shall go about finding the <br/>remedy, by taking into consideration</p>
<p begin="00:24:50.160" end="00:24:54.890" horseID="152">all these symptoms of the patient.</p>
<p begin="00:24:56.040" end="00:25:01.170" horseID="153">- I just wanted to say that several copying strategies for people who have chronic pain</p>
<p begin="00:25:01.270" end="00:25:05.520" horseID="154">and one of them is to increase the pain,<br/>to go into the pain mentally and so </p>
<p begin="00:25:05.620" end="00:25:09.620" horseID="155"><br/>they can cope with the pain, they can <br/>reduce the pain by increasing it.</p>
<p begin="00:25:09.720" end="00:25:12.370" horseID="156">So this is similar to what<br/>we are talking about.</p>
<p begin="00:25:12.470" end="00:25:23.630" horseID="157">-Yes. There are strategies, as you say, <br/>that the people who are really suffering </p>
<p begin="00:25:23.730" end="00:25:29.030" horseID="158">are trying to go into the pain and <br/>increase the pain so it can relieve </p>
<p begin="00:25:29.130" end="00:25:39.290" horseID="159">but always in a kind of temporary <br/>decrease, not real cure.</p>
<p begin="00:25:41.060" end="00:25:43.940" horseID="160">There are strategies in psychotherapy<br/> which are the same, </p>
<p begin="00:25:44.040" end="00:25:50.260" horseID="161">for instance somebody is fearing <br/>microbes, he is fearing the microbes.</p>
<p begin="00:25:50.360" end="00:25:53.590" horseID="162">In everything he touches, <br/>he feels there are microbes. </p>
<p begin="00:25:53.690" end="00:25:58.600" horseID="163">So there is a strategy in psychotherapy<br/>where they take him in a bathroom</p>
<p begin="00:25:58.700" end="00:26:06.110" horseID="164">where the bathroom is full of dirt <br/>and say now wash your hands</p>
<p begin="00:26:06.210" end="00:26:14.150" horseID="165">into this basin and see how you feel. <br/>I mean, you understand that the increase </p>
<p begin="00:26:14.250" end="00:26:28.540" horseID="166">of the fear will be so great and then<br/>this symptom which is fear of microbes, </p>
<p begin="00:26:28.640" end="00:26:32.310" horseID="167">it goes very high.</p>
<p begin="00:26:32.410" end="00:26:45.850" horseID="168">And they have observed that through <br/>such thing we can have a cure of what ? </p>
<p begin="00:26:45.950" end="00:26:48.580" horseID="169">Of the symptom. And this is the difference between Homeopathy and Psychotherapy.</p>
<p begin="00:26:52.950" end="00:27:01.460" horseID="170"> Here they cure that symptom which was<br/>over ruling the body, fear of microbes,</p>
<p begin="00:27:01.970" end="00:27:05.460" horseID="171"> tremendous fear of <br/>microbes and all his life is..</p>
<p begin="00:27:05.560" end="00:27:09.450" horseID="172">and then they put him <br/>there and then it increases </p>
<p begin="00:27:09.550" end="00:27:14.420" horseID="173">and they find out that <br/>this symptom goes away.</p>
<p begin="00:27:14.520" end="00:27:26.080" horseID="174">But many times they find that the organism replaces this symptom with another one.</p>
<p begin="00:27:27.890" end="00:27:40.400" horseID="175">So therefore, the patient remains as a mental case but with a different symptomatology.</p>
<p begin="00:27:41.680" end="00:27:46.950" horseID="176">- Mr Vithoulkas, I would like to ask, in §2 Hahnemann uses the word gentle, </p>
<p begin="00:27:47.050" end="00:27:51.940" horseID="177">are you saying that the severe <br/>aggravation can we call that gentle?</p>
<p begin="00:27:52.040" end="00:28:02.720" horseID="178">-Very gentle. We call it gentle in <br/>comparison with suffering.</p>
<p begin="00:28:02.820" end="00:28:12.270" horseID="179">If the suffering is really severe and <br/>for years, the aggravation of the few days </p>
<p begin="00:28:12.370" end="00:28:20.190" horseID="180">is nothing for the patient, who is suffering<br/> for the last 10-15 years and after that</p>
<p begin="00:28:20.290" end="00:28:34.720" horseID="181">to be cured. A second question, and <br/>be careful these are questions that</p>
<p begin="00:28:34.820" end="00:28:46.110" horseID="182">contain a catch inside, be careful. <br/>Find in which paragraphs Hahnemann </p>
<p begin="00:28:46.210" end="00:28:52.760" horseID="183">talks about the aggravation. </p>
<p begin="00:29:04.750" end="00:29:11.990" horseID="184">And state whether this <br/>explanation in the Organon</p>
<p begin="00:29:12.090" end="00:29:19.160" horseID="185"> is the same as the explanation <br/>we are giving here.</p>
<p begin="00:29:27.400" end="00:29:39.060" horseID="186">So you will write, Hahnemann talks for aggravation on paragraph 78,103 and 104.</p>
<p begin="00:29:39.160" end="00:29:45.410" horseID="187">The explanation is different or <br/>it's the same. That's all I want.</p>
<p begin="00:29:51.510" end="00:29:56.910" horseID="188">- We know that with some patients we have symptoms that depend on the presence </p>
<p begin="00:29:57.010" end="00:30:04.810" horseID="189">or the absence of some elements in the<br/> body, like for example we might have goitre</p>
<p begin="00:30:04.910" end="00:30:14.640" horseID="190"> because we lack iodine in the water. How <br/>are we going to differentiate such symptoms</p>
<p begin="00:30:15.250" end="00:30:19.120" horseID="191">from the symptoms that really have<br/> a sense in Homeopathy? </p>
<p begin="00:30:19.220" end="00:30:26.950" horseID="192">Let's say for example, if someone <br/>has lack of sugar in the blood </p>
<p begin="00:30:27.050" end="00:30:33.300" horseID="193">a very simple method to correct<br/> this is if we give him sugar </p>
<p begin="00:30:33.400" end="00:30:36.820" horseID="194">and not if we give him a homeopathic remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:30:39.490" end="00:30:57.240" horseID="195">- Yes, that is correct. This is how most of us exist by doing certain supplement things in our life,</p>
<p begin="00:30:57.980" end="00:31:05.140" horseID="196">correcting the diet, doing a little more diet <br/>of this type than this type etc, etc. </p>
<p begin="00:31:05.240" end="00:31:19.580" horseID="197">and these are measures on a level <br/>which is quite superficial in order not</p>
<p begin="00:31:19.680" end="00:31:32.170" horseID="198">to suffer so much chronically. <br/>The correct homeopathic remedy finally</p>
<p begin="00:31:32.270" end="00:31:41.450" horseID="199">corrects the organism so it can receive the elements, the micro elements that needs, </p>
<p begin="00:31:41.550" end="00:31:49.760" horseID="200">the vitamins, the minerals etc.,<br/> it can receive them from the food easily.</p>
<p begin="00:31:49.880" end="00:31:55.120" horseID="201">Our organisms today, most of our organisms,<br/> are not in a position to do that. </p>
<p begin="00:31:55.220" end="00:32:04.470" horseID="202">They are degenerated to a greater or <br/>a lesser degree and they cannot do that.</p>
<p begin="00:32:04.570" end="00:32:15.710" horseID="203">So some supplements sometimes are <br/>necessary to feel better, what we call better. </p>
<p begin="00:32:15.810" end="00:32:22.210" horseID="204">So if I take a particular mineral<br/> I feel better, that is true.</p>
<p begin="00:32:23.100" end="00:32:31.540" horseID="205">The homeopathic remedy will correct <br/>this, imbalance and this is the idea. </p>
<p begin="00:32:31.640" end="00:32:38.880" horseID="206">So the organism will feel best with <br/>only natural food finally.</p>
<p begin="00:32:38.980" end="00:32:45.960" horseID="207">But many times we cannot attend <br/>this and therefore we resort </p>
<p begin="00:32:46.060" end="00:32:54.040" horseID="208">to different other measures to <br/>support the organism.</p>
<p begin="00:33:02.560" end="00:33:10.320" horseID="209">Let me complete this. What I want to say<br/> now is, do you understand this? </p>
<p begin="00:33:10.420" end="00:33:23.550" horseID="210">Everybody understands this? Ok, now <br/>we come to the question whether all reactions</p>
<p begin="00:33:23.650" end="00:33:32.100" horseID="211"> from homeopathic remedies, that means all aggravations, are curative reactions?</p>
<p begin="00:33:34.120" end="00:33:48.840" horseID="212">So we know that we have a reaction<br/> from just proving a remedy. </p>
<p begin="00:33:55.050" end="00:34:08.600" horseID="213">We have a reaction which is curative, <br/>we have a reaction that can come from-</p>
<p begin="00:34:14.530" end="00:34:39.160" horseID="214">we said this we call the - similimum the best remedy, the correct remedy is called the similimum.</p>
<p begin="00:34:41.120" end="00:34:50.300" horseID="215">But things are so close to each other, <br/>that many times we choose a remedy</p>
<p begin="00:34:50.400" end="00:35:00.800" horseID="216">which is similar, it's only similar.</p>
<p begin="00:35:07.990" end="00:35:22.160" horseID="217">What do we mean by similar? We go back to <br/>this and we see that the remedy we choose,</p>
<p begin="00:35:22.260" end="00:35:28.810" horseID="218">did not have the modality of this fever,<br/> it has another modality. </p>
<p begin="00:35:33.570" end="00:35:45.700" horseID="219">And it had the headache and it had the <br/>microbe but this, the thirst was not there.</p>
<p begin="00:35:45.800" end="00:35:55.010" horseID="220">Actually, it wants negative here. So this <br/>graph is similar because it contains</p>
<p begin="00:35:55.110" end="00:36:06.580" horseID="221"> that similar, that similar, that similar but <br/>we do not know anything better</p>
<p begin="00:36:06.680" end="00:36:16.010" horseID="222">and we give this remedy. Then we give <br/>what we call a similar remedy, </p>
<p begin="00:36:16.110" end="00:36:18.250" horseID="223">we have a different reaction.</p>
<p begin="00:36:18.350" end="00:36:24.370" horseID="224">We shall be examining now the reactions <br/>of the organism in each particular case </p>
<p begin="00:36:24.470" end="00:36:32.920" horseID="225">and make it very clear in our <br/>understanding what exactly we mean.</p>
<p begin="00:36:33.880" end="00:36:42.220" horseID="226">So this 4th point it can be what? <br/>You have an aggravation, </p>
<p begin="00:36:42.320" end="00:36:48.850" horseID="227">the patient comes and says <br/>'oh, I was much worse'.</p>
<p begin="00:36:49.600" end="00:37:06.480" horseID="228">Because the patient is a hysterical<br/> patient. He does autosuggestion; </p>
<p begin="00:37:06.580" end="00:37:11.980" horseID="229">he likes to have an aggravation because<br/> he has heard that it is good to have</p>
<p begin="00:37:12.080" end="00:37:22.520" horseID="230">an aggravation. In this category there is<br/> another case, hypochondriac.</p>
<p begin="00:37:25.930" end="00:37:32.620" horseID="231">The hypochondriac patients who <br/>are both these categories, </p>
<p begin="00:37:32.720" end="00:37:41.450" horseID="232">they will produce symptoms of their own,<br/>that have nothing to do with your remedy,</p>
<p begin="00:37:41.550" end="00:37:49.620" horseID="233"> they will tell you here, 'oh I have such a big reaction' and it is good that I had this reaction</p>
<p begin="00:37:49.720" end="00:37:55.780" horseID="234">and this hypochondriac person will tell you,<br/> 'I had this reaction and I had that reaction, </p>
<p begin="00:37:55.880" end="00:38:01.540" horseID="235">what's happening to me, am I going<br/> to die now? I have a little bit of </p>
<p begin="00:38:01.640" end="00:38:20.640" horseID="236">this buzzing inside my head and this <br/>buzzing or a little bit of dizziness'. </p>
<p begin="00:38:20.740" end="00:38:26.350" horseID="237">It becomes almost a matter <br/>of life and death for the patient.</p>
<p begin="00:38:27.710" end="00:38:34.500" horseID="238">And then you feel that your <br/>remedy is not reacting at all. </p>
<p begin="00:38:34.600" end="00:38:40.530" horseID="239">You have to be able to perceive<br/> these things. </p>
<p begin="00:38:41.000" end="00:38:52.660" horseID="240">And then of course, we have a reaction<br/> from an organism when and if </p>
<p begin="00:38:52.760" end="00:39:00.020" horseID="241">we start the treatment while the <br/>patient is on allopathic drugs</p>
<p begin="00:39:00.120" end="00:39:10.440" horseID="242">and we tell him stop these drugs and <br/>take this remedy. Withdrawal of drugs.</p>
<p begin="00:39:14.620" end="00:39:21.440" horseID="243">Withdrawal of drugs can produce a lot<br/> of symptoms that do not belong </p>
<p begin="00:39:21.540" end="00:39:27.000" horseID="244">to any curative reaction.</p>
<p begin="00:39:28.100" end="00:39:37.620" horseID="245">So these are the categories which <br/>you have to be thinking about.</p>
<p begin="00:39:37.920" end="00:39:41.080" horseID="246"> The patient <br/>comes and gives a reaction.</p>
<p begin="00:39:41.180" end="00:39:47.910" horseID="247">You have to evaluate: is it proving, is it similar,<br/> is it hysterical, is it hypochondriac?</p>
<p begin="00:39:48.010" end="00:39:52.630" horseID="248"> Immediately you have to know. <br/>If you are clear in this, </p>
<p begin="00:39:52.730" end="00:39:58.000" horseID="249">then you can continue. <br/>If you are not clear forget it.</p>
<p begin="00:39:58.080" end="00:40:02.270" horseID="250">The patient will tell you this <br/>time one group of symptoms, </p>
<p begin="00:40:02.370" end="00:40:08.310" horseID="251">another time that group of symptoms<br/>and you will continue throwing remedies</p>
<p begin="00:40:08.410" end="00:40:12.520" horseID="252"> without knowing exactly what <br/>is going on with the patient.</p>
<p begin="00:40:19.880" end="00:40:28.190" horseID="253">So we go to the first category<br/> and we say provings. </p>
<p begin="00:40:28.290" end="00:40:32.450" horseID="254">When do we have a proving <br/>and not a cure?</p>
<p begin="00:40:32.980" end="00:40:38.960" horseID="255">What will be the difference?<br/> In provings you will develop </p>
<p begin="00:40:39.060" end="00:40:48.950" horseID="256">symptoms that you did not have before.<br/>But I will tell you something. </p>
<p begin="00:40:49.050" end="00:40:55.000" horseID="257">In a curative action, you may develop new symptoms that you did not have before also.</p>
<p begin="00:40:58.400" end="00:41:02.220" horseID="258">How do you differentiate between <br/>one time which is not curative </p>
<p begin="00:41:02.320" end="00:41:07.070" horseID="259">and another time <br/>which is curative?</p>
<p begin="00:41:10.280" end="00:41:26.110" horseID="260">In the provings there is no amelioration. <br/>You have new symptoms </p>
<p begin="00:41:27.720" end="00:41:35.620" horseID="261">which have nothing to do with <br/>the symptoms of the patient and </p>
<p begin="00:41:35.720" end="00:41:41.510" horseID="262">at the same time the patient says <br/>'on my other symptoms I am the same'. </p>
<p begin="00:41:41.610" end="00:41:49.820" horseID="263">There is no general <br/>amelioration of the case. </p>
<p begin="00:41:55.080" end="00:41:59.450" horseID="264">So in the provings what he will<br/> tell you exactly?  </p>
<p begin="00:41:59.550" end="00:42:17.650" horseID="265">Υou gave a dose of Nat-m 10 M.<br/>You gave a dose of high potency, </p>
<p begin="00:42:17.750" end="00:42:22.720" horseID="266">what we call a high potency and the <br/>patient comes and tells you,</p>
<p begin="00:42:24.240" end="00:42:31.260" horseID="267">'It's strange that I did not suffer any <br/>headaches and now when I wake up</p>
<p begin="00:42:31.360" end="00:42:41.920" horseID="268">in the morning I have some headache'.<br/>What do you have to ask immediately after that?</p>
<p begin="00:42:43.900" end="00:42:48.020" horseID="269">He says 'I did not <br/>have the headaches before'. </p>
<p begin="00:42:48.120" end="00:42:53.790" horseID="270"> Your first question immediately to <br/>short out, there is a typical question </p>
<p begin="00:42:53.890" end="00:43:01.320" horseID="271"> that you have immediately to ask: <br/>how do you feel in general now?</p>
<p begin="00:43:01.420" end="00:43:10.490" horseID="272">He came for his phobias, for his fears, for <br/>his colitis, for his duodenal ulcer, whatever. </p>
<p begin="00:43:10.590" end="00:43:16.640" horseID="273">How is your duodenal ulcer and pains? <br/>'Oh, there are much better.' </p>
<p begin="00:43:16.740" end="00:43:23.230" horseID="274"> But what about the headaches? <br/>If the headaches are typical </p>
<p begin="00:43:23.330" end="00:43:28.100" horseID="275">headaches of Nat-m which has <br/>headaches on waking in the morning</p>
<p begin="00:43:28.200" end="00:43:35.140" horseID="276"> or at 10 o'clock especially, this is typical, <br/>he says every day at 10 o'clock starts </p>
<p begin="00:43:35.240" end="00:43:43.410" horseID="277"> a headache and he says my duodenal <br/>ulcer is better. These two information </p>
<p begin="00:43:43.510" end="00:43:51.150" horseID="278">make absolutely sure that your remedy<br/> is correct. But if he says that</p>
<p begin="00:43:51.250" end="00:43:58.300" horseID="279"> 'I have the headaches but my duodenal <br/>ulcer is the same or my other symptoms</p>
<p begin="00:43:58.400" end="00:44:03.290" horseID="280"> are the same, no change' <br/>this is a case of a proving. </p>
<p begin="00:44:03.390" end="00:44:13.160" horseID="281"> That means you gave a remedy <br/>which had an effect and he is a prover.</p>
<p begin="00:44:14.780" end="00:44:19.700" horseID="282">So in a prover you don't have an <br/>amelioration on the energy level, </p>
<p begin="00:44:19.800" end="00:44:25.140" horseID="283">you don't have an amelioration <br/>on local symptomatology</p>
<p begin="00:44:25.240" end="00:44:31.550" horseID="284">and you have the appearance of new <br/>symptoms that he did not have before.</p>
<p begin="00:44:35.730" end="00:44:43.980" horseID="285">These things you have to know very <br/>clearly and immediately. </p>
<p begin="00:44:44.080" end="00:44:50.970" horseID="286">Otherwise my experience is that cases <br/> have been spoiled mostly because of</p>
<p begin="00:44:51.070" end="00:45:03.580" horseID="287"> lack of this knowledge. 'Oh, it is a proving<br/> I must antidote' or different ideas</p>
<p begin="00:45:04.920" end="00:45:15.660" horseID="288">but if the person is better generally, better<br/> in his ulcer, leave alone the headache </p>
<p begin="00:45:15.760" end="00:45:21.520" horseID="289"> of the Nat-m because it's going <br/>to go away very soon,</p>
<p begin="00:45:23.030" end="00:45:31.780" horseID="290">by itself without any further remedy. <br/>If you enter with another remedy </p>
<p begin="00:45:31.880" end="00:45:37.880" horseID="291">you are going to spoil your good <br/>action of your remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:45:43.060" end="00:45:50.340" horseID="292">And of course when you're dealing <br/>with deep severe chronic cases, </p>
<p begin="00:45:50.440" end="00:45:56.100" horseID="293"> things are not very clear.<br/>But the general rules should be there,</p>
<p begin="00:45:56.200" end="00:46:04.250" horseID="294"> the general rules should <br/>be understood by you.</p>
<p begin="00:46:05.500" end="00:46:21.950" horseID="295">The first thing you'll see is a feeling of <br/>being better, I feel better, general. </p>
<p begin="00:46:28.010" end="00:46:36.680" horseID="296">I have more headaches, I have more <br/>pains etc. but I feel better generally</p>
<p begin="00:46:36.780" end="00:46:55.360" horseID="297">it is and indication that your remedy<br/> is correct. Then, psychologically better,</p>
<p begin="00:46:58.050" end="00:47:14.300" horseID="298">that means in mental - emotional better<br/>then most probably your remedy is correct.</p>
<p begin="00:47:26.320" end="00:47:54.060" horseID="299">Better in symptoms, better in the symptoms<br/> and either no change psychologically </p>
<p begin="00:47:54.160" end="00:48:00.970" horseID="300"> or no change in general that means <br/>general the same, psychologically</p>
<p begin="00:48:01.070" end="00:48:11.160" horseID="301"> the same.....you see you have<br/> to be very precise.</p>
<p begin="00:48:12.120" end="00:48:19.230" horseID="302">Here, somebody tells you 'my stomach <br/>pains, my headaches, </p>
<p begin="00:48:19.330" end="00:48:27.700" horseID="303">my physical symptoms are better but <br/> I have no change psychologically</p>
<p begin="00:48:27.800" end="00:48:36.370" horseID="304"> and I have no change in general', is it better, <br/>is it curative action or is it not?</p>
<p begin="00:48:42.820" end="00:48:49.200" horseID="305">You see, immediately you have doubts. <br/>Here we do not have doubts, </p>
<p begin="00:48:49.300" end="00:48:52.740" horseID="306">we have to be very clear, ok?</p>
<p begin="00:48:54.960" end="00:49:04.880" horseID="307">If these symptoms are better and<br/> it is curative that means, </p>
<p begin="00:49:04.980" end="00:49:12.030" horseID="308">that the general state and the <br/>psychological state are quite well,</p>
<p begin="00:49:12.130" end="00:49:17.640" horseID="309">quite balanced, did not need <br/>a rearrangement. All the force </p>
<p begin="00:49:17.740" end="00:49:25.720" horseID="310">of the disease was in physical level.<br/>That physical level gets better</p>
<p begin="00:49:25.820" end="00:49:31.650" horseID="311"> and then that's all that the <br/>remedy should do.</p>
<p begin="00:49:32.310" end="00:49:37.800" horseID="312">If you expect every time to say the<br/> patient is better psychologically</p>
<p begin="00:49:37.900" end="00:49:49.210" horseID="313"> and better generally, it is wrong, <br/>as long as these states,</p>
<p begin="00:49:49.310" end="00:49:55.840" horseID="314"> general states, psychological states <br/>are in a good condition.</p>
<p begin="00:49:55.842" end="00:50:11.930" horseID="315">If the symptoms are better but worse <br/>here or worse there, that is another story. </p>
<p begin="00:50:22.610" end="00:50:36.420" horseID="316">In curative action here, you <br/>may have a proving symptom. </p>
<p begin="00:50:37.870" end="00:50:47.770" horseID="317">That means, better generally, better in the symptoms but one or two proving </p>
<p begin="00:50:49.240" end="00:51:00.570" horseID="318"> symptoms are appearing that shows <br/>that the remedy is absolutely correct.</p>
<p begin="00:51:00.670" end="00:51:07.980" horseID="319">It is a confirmation that your remedy <br/>is correct if you have the proving</p>
<p begin="00:51:08.080" end="00:51:14.840" horseID="320"> of one or two symptoms of the remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:51:15.560" end="00:51:20.220" horseID="321">While the person is getting better <br/>psychologically or better generally </p>
<p begin="00:51:20.320" end="00:51:23.070" horseID="322">or better in the symptoms.</p>
<p begin="00:51:32.500" end="00:51:39.680" horseID="323">So therefore you say, you give a remedy<br/> 'ah I have a symptom, it's a proving'.</p>
<p begin="00:51:39.780" end="00:51:44.800" horseID="324">No, no, no wait a moment.<br/>'How do you feel psychologically?', 'Better'.</p>
<p begin="00:51:44.900" end="00:51:47.830" horseID="325"> Generally, better and <br/>you have a proving?</p>
<p begin="00:51:47.930" end="00:52:00.430" horseID="326">That is a confirmation that the remedy <br/>was correct, it's not a proving.</p>
<p begin="00:52:02.920" end="00:52:18.710" horseID="327">Now you come here in this group where <br/>we have most of the problems, why?</p>
<p begin="00:52:19.350" end="00:52:33.180" horseID="328">Because the remedy we many times give, especially when we prescribe fast, </p>
<p begin="00:52:33.280" end="00:52:41.470" horseID="329">when we give a similar <br/>remedy which what it does?</p>
<p begin="00:52:46.440" end="00:53:02.660" horseID="330">Here, in this group we have <br/>1) change of symptoms,</p>
<p begin="00:53:05.640" end="00:53:12.720" horseID="331"> 2) no general amelioration, </p>
<p begin="00:53:14.650" end="00:53:23.240" horseID="332">3) no mental amelioration. </p>
<p begin="00:53:38.690" end="00:53:46.350" horseID="333">When I say change of symptoms what <br/>do I mean? I mean that a headache </p>
<p begin="00:53:46.450" end="00:53:54.500" horseID="334">has been changing to vertigo. You gave <br/>a remedy because of chronic headaches </p>
<p begin="00:53:54.600" end="00:54:03.580" horseID="335"> and the headaches have been changed <br/>to vertigo. The person says I feel dizzy.</p>
<p begin="00:54:04.350" end="00:54:10.180" horseID="336">Yes you feel dizzy but are you better <br/>generally? He says no.  </p>
<p begin="00:54:10.280" end="00:54:18.060" horseID="337">Are you better psychologically? No.<br/>That means you gave a similar remedy</p>
<p begin="00:54:18.160" end="00:54:21.680" horseID="338"> and you are going to change <br/>symptom after symptom.</p>
<p begin="00:54:21.780" end="00:54:31.690" horseID="339">Now, how you handle that we'll talk. <br/>In hysterical and hypochondriac patients </p>
<p begin="00:54:31.790" end="00:54:37.660" horseID="340">you have a reaction almost with every <br/>remedy you give. You don't know if the </p>
<p begin="00:54:37.760" end="00:54:46.190" horseID="341">reaction is because of the remedy or <br/>because of the make up of the person.</p>
<p begin="00:54:46.680" end="00:54:54.510" horseID="342">In these cases, hysterical, you see that not always the symptoms belong to the remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:54:54.610" end="00:55:02.760" horseID="343">These hysterical people can bring out a lot of other symptoms that do not belong to the remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:55:09.210" end="00:55:16.700" horseID="344">And many times in group 6<br/> because you decided to give a remedy </p>
<p begin="00:55:16.800" end="00:55:22.570" horseID="345">under allopathic drugs you don't know<br/>what are the symptoms underneath. </p>
<p begin="00:55:22.670" end="00:55:28.700" horseID="346">So you withdraw the drugs and all <br/>other symptoms start appearing.</p>
<p begin="00:55:29.280" end="00:55:34.410" horseID="347">You don't know whether they belong to<br/> the remedy or not to the remedy etc.</p>
<p begin="00:55:34.510" end="00:55:40.760" horseID="348">  and that is why the best thing <br/>to handle these cases is to stop </p>
<p begin="00:55:40.860" end="00:55:50.020" horseID="349">the allopathic drugs at least for one month, <br/>see the picture and start from that picture.</p>
<p begin="00:55:50.120" end="00:55:57.300" horseID="350">If you start while the person is under <br/>allopathic drugs, then you will have  </p>
<p begin="00:55:57.400" end="00:56:04.920" horseID="351">a problem in evaluating what is <br/>happening under your remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:56:08.510" end="00:56:25.900" horseID="352">So handling of provings. How you <br/>handle a proving? What do you do?</p>
<p begin="00:56:28.820" end="00:56:33.500" horseID="353">A proving is when you have new <br/>symptoms, belonging to the remedy. </p>
<p begin="00:56:33.600" end="00:56:37.680" horseID="354">Characteristic symptoms of the remedy<br/>without any change of the condition</p>
<p begin="00:56:39.680" end="00:56:47.150" horseID="355"> of the person. That's a proving. <br/>What do you do?</p>
<p begin="00:56:50.750" end="00:57:00.470" horseID="356">Here you have to wait and the symptoms <br/>of the remedy will subside within </p>
<p begin="00:57:00.570" end="00:57:09.320" horseID="357">a period of time which is between <br/>a few days to a few weeks, 5, 6 weeks.</p>
<p begin="00:57:12.660" end="00:57:21.500" horseID="358">If you wait the symptoms will subside but <br/>that means that the remedy you have given</p>
<p begin="00:57:21.600" end="00:57:27.770" horseID="359">is wrong and you have to search<br/> for another remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:57:27.870" end="00:57:35.030" horseID="360">In such a case you can prescribe<br/> the next remedy even when</p>
<p begin="00:57:35.130" end="00:57:41.470" horseID="361">  the symptoms <br/>of the provings are still there.</p>
<p begin="00:57:41.570" end="00:57:45.290" horseID="362">The organism does not care.<br/> If you give the next remedy</p>
<p begin="00:57:45.390" end="00:57:50.040" horseID="363">which is the correct one, will react.</p>
<p begin="00:57:51.680" end="00:57:59.460" horseID="364">So here, for the provings the best is to wait <br/>until the symptoms of the provings go away.</p>
<p begin="00:57:59.560" end="00:58:05.980" horseID="365">If the person is suffering a lot you cannot <br/>wait. Then you can still go ahead </p>
<p begin="00:58:06.080" end="00:58:10.500" horseID="366">and give the next remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:58:10.600" end="00:58:20.940" horseID="367">Will you take in consideration the <br/>symptoms of the proving together </p>
<p begin="00:58:21.040" end="00:58:27.440" horseID="368">with his other symptoms? <br/>No, in this case, no.  </p>
<p begin="00:58:32.040" end="00:58:38.430" horseID="369">You go back to the original case and <br/>you study the original case only, </p>
<p begin="00:58:38.530" end="00:58:40.780" horseID="370">not the proving symptoms. </p>
<p begin="00:58:40.880" end="00:58:52.700" horseID="371">If you put together the proving <br/>symptoms then you make a confusion.</p>
<p begin="00:58:52.800" end="00:58:58.020" horseID="372">- Can I make a contradiction and go to the <br/>first remedy and then to the next, </p>
<p begin="00:58:58.120" end="00:59:02.220" horseID="373">right remedy, is it possible?</p>
<p begin="00:59:02.320" end="00:59:09.660" horseID="374">-To make a contradiction? Counteraction, antidote, you mean antidote?</p>
<p begin="00:59:11.800" end="00:59:17.530" horseID="375"><br/>No. It's not necessary <br/>to give an antidote.</p>
<p begin="00:59:20.770" end="00:59:30.520" horseID="376">The best is going back to the case, <br/>restudy and give the next, best remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:59:35.510" end="00:59:44.580" horseID="377">On the curative reaction, especially <br/>when he says better generally </p>
<p begin="00:59:44.680" end="00:59:54.940" horseID="378"> but the symptoms still are <br/>there, what you do?</p>
<p begin="00:59:55.039" end="00:59:57.750" horseID="379">-Wait.</p>
<p begin="00:59:57.850" end="01:00:09.140" horseID="380">-Wait, better psychologically the physical symptoms are still there, wait.  </p>
<p begin="01:00:09.240" end="01:00:18.240" horseID="381">Don't interfere with another remedy.<br/> Please don't spoil a good prescription. </p>
<p begin="01:00:19.760" end="01:00:26.940" horseID="382">You will see eventually that these <br/>symptoms also subside, </p>
<p begin="01:00:27.040" end="01:00:33.440" horseID="383">maybe they need time <br/>3 weeks, 3 or 5 months.</p>
<p begin="01:00:33.540" end="01:00:40.660" horseID="384">If you leave alone the organism, <br/>the symptoms will subside.</p>
<p begin="01:00:45.590" end="01:00:54.980" horseID="385">If you have a proving here, will you do<br/> anything? No, leave it alone. </p>
<p begin="01:00:55.080" end="01:01:04.140" horseID="386"> Once you make sure that the person is <br/>better generally, better psychologically and</p>
<p begin="01:01:04.240" end="01:01:11.920" horseID="387">   some provings are there, leave it alone, the proving symptoms will subside by themselves.</p>
<p begin="01:01:16.000" end="01:01:19.480" horseID="388">- How long can we wait?</p>
<p begin="01:01:25.990" end="01:01:36.540" horseID="389">- Three years. Bill Gray, you know <br/>Bill Gray? Everyone knows him. </p>
<p begin="01:01:36.640" end="01:01:41.080" horseID="390">He came here to study with me for <br/>2 years. He stayed in Greece.</p>
<p begin="01:01:41.180" end="01:01:46.380" horseID="391">One year he went back for one <br/>month to see his cases  </p>
<p begin="01:01:46.480" end="01:01:51.750" horseID="392">and then he came<br/> back again for the second year.</p>
<p begin="01:01:51.850" end="01:01:57.260" horseID="393">In the meantime he was treating some <br/>of the cases through correspondence </p>
<p begin="01:01:57.360" end="01:01:59.820" horseID="394">and all the cases that <br/> he treated a year ago, </p>
<p begin="01:01:59.920" end="01:02:06.660" horseID="395">when he came back to me he said,<br/> 'I cannot believe it, all my cases</p>
<p begin="01:02:06.760" end="01:02:15.750" horseID="396">are doing well. Why? Because I did not<br/> interfere, I was not there to interfere </p>
<p begin="01:02:15.850" end="01:02:23.000" horseID="397">with the remedy all the time. What I was<br/> doing stupidly all the time before. </p>
<p begin="01:02:23.770" end="01:02:33.580" horseID="398"> I left them alone, he says I want to see you, much better, diabetes, chronic diseases, everyone'.</p>
<p begin="01:02:33.680" end="01:02:41.270" horseID="399">He has given the right remedy many times <br/>and he was doing this kind of things, </p>
<p begin="01:02:41.370" end="01:02:46.349" horseID="400">oh now I have this pain, take this remedy.<br/>Now I have that, take this, take that</p>
<p begin="01:02:46.449" end="01:02:53.340" horseID="401"> and you spoil the case. You leave it <br/>alone and you see.</p>
<p begin="01:02:53.440" end="01:02:58.330" horseID="402">I mean there is placebo, you can <br/>give placebo if you want, </p>
<p begin="01:02:58.430" end="01:03:06.230" horseID="403">if the patient needs to take <br/>something, you give placebo.</p>
<p begin="01:03:06.330" end="01:03:14.060" horseID="404">But it is very important to know the rules<br/> here. If you don't know the rules, </p>
<p begin="01:03:14.160" end="01:03:18.150" horseID="405">the proving, <br/>the similar, the withdrawal,</p>
<p begin="01:03:18.250" end="01:03:27.450" horseID="406">if you are not clear in that how can<br/> you proceed? You have to be clear.</p>
<p begin="01:03:29.200" end="01:03:37.420" horseID="407">The remedy is correct you leave it alone. <br/>How long you leave it alone? </p>
<p begin="01:03:37.520" end="01:03:42.740" horseID="408">I would say if the person feels better <br/>generally, better psychologically</p>
<p begin="01:03:42.840" end="01:03:53.760" horseID="409">, 6 or 9 months, wait.<br/> As long as it is a real information,</p>
<p begin="01:03:53.860" end="01:04:03.890" horseID="410"> not the idea of, 'are you better <br/>psychologically'? The patient thinks, </p>
<p begin="01:04:03.990" end="01:04:10.200" horseID="411">'you are better, you are better, <br/>oh you are better'.</p>
<p begin="01:04:13.420" end="01:04:23.580" horseID="412">Not like this, this is dangerous. You are<br/> better,  I can see you are better. </p>
<p begin="01:04:23.680" end="01:04:27.870" horseID="413">Many times <br/>I can see if somebody is better.</p>
<p begin="01:04:27.970" end="01:04:34.180" horseID="414">They enter the room and there is another<br/> air, you feel immediately the remedy.</p>
<p begin="01:04:34.280" end="01:04:40.180" horseID="415">He says, how are you and you have <br/>a problem there with the patient </p>
<p begin="01:04:40.280" end="01:04:49.070" horseID="416">who wants everything to go in one month. <br/>Then you have to pass judgement quickly.</p>
<p begin="01:04:49.170" end="01:04:57.060" horseID="417"> I see he's better, how much he accepts, <br/>what type of the person he is etc.</p>
<p begin="01:04:57.160" end="01:05:04.680" horseID="418">This is what we have to learn through <br/>taking the case and evaluating. </p>
<p begin="01:05:05.520" end="01:05:15.500" horseID="419">Because human beings are not simple <br/>beings, they are complicated. </p>
<p begin="01:05:15.600" end="01:05:22.270" horseID="420">They have a lot of back thinking, think in <br/>one level and there is another level </p>
<p begin="01:05:22.370" end="01:05:24.510" horseID="421">where he thinks something else.</p>
<p begin="01:05:24.610" end="01:05:29.600" horseID="422">And perhaps some of them are thinking<br/> on 3 levels at the same time.</p>
<p begin="01:05:30.880" end="01:05:38.270" horseID="423">One level tells you one thing, the second level says let's see how he reacts if I tell this thing</p>
<p begin="01:05:38.370" end="01:05:45.270" horseID="424"> and the third level is criticising you <br/>and says this, this and that.</p>
<p begin="01:05:45.370" end="01:05:52.340" horseID="425">All these are happening together. <br/>It's not so easy, we say better </p>
<p begin="01:05:52.440" end="01:05:57.020" horseID="426">psychologically and generally better, yes.</p>
<p begin="01:05:57.120" end="01:06:08.370" horseID="427">These reactions you get from people<br/> living in the country, villagers, farmers, </p>
<p begin="01:06:08.470" end="01:06:16.280" horseID="428">people who work with their bodies <br/>a lot, have simple reactions.</p>
<p begin="01:06:16.380" end="01:06:26.700" horseID="429">The more educated is a person, the more complicated he is in his reactions and</p>
<p begin="01:06:26.800" end="01:06:37.310" horseID="430"> transactions and you have to be very <br/>aware of how he gives you an information, </p>
<p begin="01:06:38.080" end="01:06:45.340" horseID="431">what he says, who he is. A simple<br/> person, you say to him you are better,</p>
<p begin="01:06:45.440" end="01:06:49.560" horseID="432"> you are better, he will say <br/>yes I am better finally.</p>
<p begin="01:06:49.600" end="01:06:58.760" horseID="433">An intellectual he will not accept this<br/> treatment, he will judge you,</p>
<p begin="01:06:58.860" end="01:07:03.390" horseID="434"> he will leave you, he will say 'oh, you’re<br/> stupid you are this or you are that'</p>
<p begin="01:07:03.490" end="01:07:10.260" horseID="435"> and he will go to somebody else. <br/>But an intellectual can be better</p>
<p begin="01:07:10.360" end="01:07:16.660" horseID="436">and not tell you I am better because <br/>he's judging you all the time. </p>
<p begin="01:07:16.760" end="01:07:22.870" horseID="437">He gives you one thing and he's <br/>judging you on another level.</p>
<p begin="01:07:22.970" end="01:07:27.690" horseID="438">Does he understand, how much he <br/>understands etc. and you have to be </p>
<p begin="01:07:27.790" end="01:07:33.010" horseID="439">aware of what you have in front of you.</p>
<p begin="01:07:34.550" end="01:07:46.980" horseID="440">The evaluation of the reaction to homeopathic remedy is an art really of high order.</p>
<p begin="01:07:47.080" end="01:07:57.720" horseID="441">Because you are judged by the gods how <br/>much really you understand human nature, </p>
<p begin="01:07:57.820" end="01:08:00.970" horseID="442">do you understand human nature?<br/></p>
<p begin="01:08:01.070" end="01:08:08.220" horseID="443">You say yes, I understand but who <br/>understands human nature, nobody totally.</p>
<p begin="01:08:08.320" end="01:08:14.980" horseID="444"> But as the experience comes, you see more <br/>and more cases, you are able to perceive</p>
<p begin="01:08:15.080" end="01:08:20.740" horseID="445">more and more what is happening in the <br/>soul of a person, in the mind of a person</p>
<p begin="01:08:20.840" end="01:08:31.280" horseID="446">who comes to you to be treated. Because <br/>your desire is to cure him, you don't care </p>
<p begin="01:08:31.380" end="01:08:34.480" horseID="447">about judgement and things like that,<br/> he judges me or he doesn't judge me. </p>
<p begin="01:08:34.580" end="01:08:42.800" horseID="448"><br/>What you are concentrated<br/> upon is his health.</p>
<p begin="01:08:42.840" end="01:08:53.940" horseID="449">So you have to be an objective observer,<br/> not conditioned, not prejudiced.  </p>
<p begin="01:08:54.040" end="01:08:57.780" horseID="450">Because if you are prejudiced when <br/>he comes there  and he judges you</p>
<p begin="01:08:57.880" end="01:09:10.240" horseID="451"> and you understand, you judge him back <br/>and you say he's pissed, he's this, that.</p>
<p begin="01:09:11.360" end="01:09:20.260" horseID="452">Forget about the cure, your ego comes <br/>into the picture and then </p>
<p begin="01:09:20.360" end="01:09:26.540" horseID="453">some other person comes and you say<br/> how nice, only good reactions</p>
<p begin="01:09:26.640" end="01:09:32.530" horseID="454">and you will have only your friends and <br/>people who like you as patients. </p>
<p begin="01:09:32.630" end="01:09:36.040" horseID="455">All the others will leave you. </p>
<p begin="01:09:40.630" end="01:09:52.460" horseID="456">When you give a similar remedy you have<br/>the most unfortunate thing happening, </p>
<p begin="01:09:52.560" end="01:09:58.659" horseID="457"> changing the symptoms of the case <br/>without curing the patient.</p>
<p begin="01:09:59.600" end="01:10:03.500" horseID="458"> And this is the most unfortunate<br/> that can happen. </p>
<p begin="01:10:03.600" end="01:10:08.160" horseID="459">Unfortunately<br/> it happens frequently.</p>
<p begin="01:10:10.280" end="01:10:20.170" horseID="460">You give a remedy and then the patient <br/>comes and tells you 'my stomachache is better'</p>
<p begin="01:10:20.270" end="01:10:24.410" horseID="461"> but he comes after 3 months,<br/> because he follows you.</p>
<p begin="01:10:24.510" end="01:10:31.000" horseID="462">These cases will follow you <br/>for 3 years, 5, 10 years. </p>
<p begin="01:10:31.100" end="01:10:35.421" horseID="463">They are patients who will follow <br/>you the rest of your life.</p>
<p begin="01:10:35.460" end="01:10:47.940" horseID="464">Because they have found out that <br/>something you can do but not the best </p>
<p begin="01:10:48.040" end="01:10:55.130" horseID="465">and they follow you, they are good <br/>patients, they support us financially</p>
<p begin="01:10:55.230" end="01:11:00.420" horseID="466"> because if you cure everybody one time, <br/>the whole planet in 1 year is finished.</p>
<p begin="01:11:03.360" end="01:11:17.020" horseID="467">No patients, I'm just joking. These patients<br/> here you have to know yourself, </p>
<p begin="01:11:17.120" end="01:11:21.670" horseID="468"> you don't tell them.  Or you can<br/> tell them if you think they are</p>
<p begin="01:11:21.770" end="01:11:27.540" horseID="469"> intelligent enough to understand, you say <br/>I made a mistake and I just changed</p>
<p begin="01:11:27.640" end="01:11:36.850" horseID="470">your symptoms without curing you. <br/>And I have to search for another remedy.</p>
<p begin="01:11:36.960" end="01:11:43.220" horseID="471">Now here the situation is very difficult. <br/>We'll talk a lot about the second prescription</p>
<p begin="01:11:43.320" end="01:11:50.620" horseID="472"> in such cases, in detail, how to handle<br/> this because it's a very very serious</p>
<p begin="01:11:50.720" end="01:11:57.250" horseID="473">  condition and it<br/> goes into a lot of details.</p>
<p begin="01:11:58.910" end="01:12:04.230" horseID="474">In this case you'll find that certain of the symptoms of the initial symptoms </p>
<p begin="01:12:04.330" end="01:12:11.700" horseID="475"> are going away or are going away on a big degree like 80% gone but some other</p>
<p begin="01:12:11.800" end="01:12:19.250" horseID="476">symptoms are developing of the<br/> same order, of the same level.</p>
<p begin="01:12:19.350" end="01:12:30.640" horseID="477">Sometimes by giving these remedies a lot, you may change level and go in a deeper level.</p>
<p begin="01:12:35.140" end="01:12:41.620" horseID="478">Now, hysterical or hypochondriac patients <br/>are those who will tell you with every </p>
<p begin="01:12:41.720" end="01:12:48.860" horseID="479">remedy you give, that they have different symptoms that you cannot find in the provings. </p>
<p begin="01:12:48.960" end="01:12:56.920" horseID="480">They are symptoms of their own. <br/>Which do not present symptoms</p>
<p begin="01:12:57.020" end="01:13:06.570" horseID="481"> of a remedy. You gave Sepia and <br/>you have developing some phobias</p>
<p begin="01:13:06.670" end="01:13:14.090" horseID="482">fear of the dark, fear of this or that, <br/>symptoms that do not belong to Sepia.</p>
<p begin="01:13:14.330" end="01:13:22.700" horseID="483">You search for Sepia and you don't see <br/>clear symptoms of Sepia but the patient</p>
<p begin="01:13:22.800" end="01:13:25.700" horseID="484"> is presenting a lot. Then you give <br/>another remedy then they present</p>
<p begin="01:13:25.800" end="01:13:31.900" horseID="485">other symptoms etc, etc. All the time, <br/>every time you give a remedy </p>
<p begin="01:13:32.000" end="01:13:43.180" horseID="486"> there is a new set of symptoms. It's better<br/> to wait with this patient to settle down </p>
<p begin="01:13:43.280" end="01:13:51.220" horseID="487">and give very low potencies before you <br/>can make head or tail in this case, </p>
<p begin="01:13:51.320" end="01:13:54.300" horseID="488">before the case is clear.</p>
<p begin="01:14:02.800" end="01:14:13.620" horseID="489">- But the word hypochondriac means that <br/>it comes from a very deep place, </p>
<p begin="01:14:13.720" end="01:14:17.800" horseID="490">so it means that it's coming <br/>from a very genuine source.</p>
<p begin="01:14:17.900" end="01:14:23.570" horseID="491"> So you may have to do something about <br/>it even if it's called hypochondriac.</p>
<p begin="01:14:23.620" end="01:14:32.180" horseID="492">- Oh yes, absolutely. I don't say you leave <br/>them alone, you don't treat them. </p>
<p begin="01:14:32.280" end="01:14:38.040" horseID="493"> I say better be careful not to give,<br/> with every symptom that they give you,</p>
<p begin="01:14:38.140" end="01:14:46.900" horseID="494"> another remedy. You can wait for such <br/>people for months to collect all </p>
<p begin="01:14:47.000" end="01:14:53.580" horseID="495">the symptomatology they present <br/> and make an evaluation of the whole</p>
<p begin="01:14:53.680" end="01:14:57.430" horseID="496"> of the symptomatology and <br/>see the general picture.</p>
<p begin="01:14:57.640" end="01:15:12.030" horseID="497">Then you see the hypochondriasis <br/>and what is hypochondriasis? </p>
<p begin="01:15:12.130" end="01:15:21.010" horseID="498">Usually it's about the health of the <br/>person  and every symptom is exaggerated</p>
<p begin="01:15:21.110" end="01:15:30.740" horseID="499"> and every time, I mean whatever, <br/>some people look their (pulse) and say</p>
<p begin="01:15:30.840" end="01:15:39.720" horseID="500">'I cannot find this' or they pick <br/>up the telephone and tell you </p>
<p begin="01:15:39.730" end="01:15:56.150" horseID="501"> 'I think I have 78 pulse'. You say, 'don't worry<br/> it's ok, it's normal'. They say 'normal, 78?'. </p>
<p begin="01:15:56.250" end="01:16:11.460" horseID="502">'Yes it's normal', you have to be certain.<br/>'78 pulses are normal', they say 'oh 68', </p>
<p begin="01:16:11.560" end="01:16:22.020" horseID="503"> '68 it's also normal. The normal pulse<br/> is from 68 to 78', you have to be sure.</p>
<p begin="01:16:22.120" end="01:16:28.210" horseID="504">Then you wait, what you're doing behind <br/>your mind you are searching if this is </p>
<p begin="01:16:28.310" end="01:16:40.220" horseID="505">a case of Nit-ac. or Lyc. or Nat-m <br/>or Kali-ars. The remedies with such kind</p>
<p begin="01:16:40.320" end="01:16:52.480" horseID="506"> of an anxiety which all the time say<br/> 'oh, I have a little pain I think'.</p>
<p begin="01:16:59.800" end="01:17:09.170" horseID="507">'Do you feel pain?', 'I think, I think'. <br/>You do not go and say pain in the right </p>
<p begin="01:17:09.270" end="01:17:19.580" horseID="508">hypochondrium and give Chelidonium, no.<br/>You take the whole situation of the patient, </p>
<p begin="01:17:19.680" end="01:17:25.380" horseID="509"> it's different all together. The one who<br/> has pain in the right hypochondrium</p>
<p begin="01:17:38.820" end="01:17:45.420" horseID="510">he says, you read his mind at this <br/>moment, he says: 'shall I tell him or not.</p>
<p begin="01:17:45.520" end="01:17:50.900" horseID="511">If I tell him that I feel a pain maybe he <br/>will say it is cancer but if I don't tell him  </p>
<p begin="01:17:51.000" end="01:17:56.540" horseID="512">that I feel a pain that means that he will <br/>forget about me. So what shall I tell?'</p>
<p begin="01:17:56.640" end="01:18:03.500" horseID="513"> That kind of thinking is going on<br/>on a hypochondriasis state. </p>
<p begin="01:18:04.240" end="01:18:09.380" horseID="514"> Then you don't take this pain and that pain <br/>and that pain, you take the whole picture </p>
<p begin="01:18:09.480" end="01:18:12.701" horseID="515">which says wait a moment. <br/>With the blood pressure,</p>
<p begin="01:18:12.801" end="01:18:19.080" horseID="516"> hypochondriacs who have blood<br/> pressure, forget it.</p>
<p begin="01:18:19.560" end="01:18:23.920" horseID="517">Because the blood pressure normally goes <br/>up and down all the time, in the morning, </p>
<p begin="01:18:24.020" end="01:18:32.640" horseID="518">in the evening etc. and then when <br/>they learn to put this 'I have 148'</p>
<p begin="01:18:32.740" end="01:18:44.080" horseID="519">Yes but then you are 58 and 148 <br/>is normal. They say 'it's normal?'. </p>
<p begin="01:18:45.310" end="01:18:52.660" horseID="520">So when you come to these cases you <br/>have a lot of problems, stop giving remedies.</p>
<p begin="01:18:52.760" end="01:18:58.100" horseID="521"> You gave 1 remedy, you gave 2 remedies,<br/> every time it was a big reaction</p>
<p begin="01:18:58.200" end="01:19:08.190" horseID="522">you didn't know where you are. <br/>Wait a moment, wait and observe now. </p>
<p begin="01:19:08.290" end="01:19:10.880" horseID="523">Eventually the picture will develop. </p>
<p begin="01:19:10.980" end="01:19:19.130" horseID="524">Is this Agar., is Nat-m., is Lyc., because <br/>you think on another level in the case.</p>
<p begin="01:19:19.530" end="01:19:28.780" horseID="525">They guide you to look upon little symptoms<br/> here and there when the main symptoms</p>
<p begin="01:19:28.880" end="01:19:36.840" horseID="526">are on mental level and then <br/>you have a problem.</p>
<p begin="01:19:36.940" end="01:19:42.360" horseID="527"> Because you are describing these <br/>little symptoms all around and</p>
<p begin="01:19:42.460" end="01:19:46.860" horseID="528">you forget about the mental level. </p>
<p begin="01:19:49.100" end="01:19:58.830" horseID="529">What do I do when I give a remedy <br/>and the patient has severe aggravation, <br/>which he cannot tolerate?</p>
<p begin="01:19:58.930" end="01:20:12.420" horseID="530">We shall be talking about these cases and <br/>if this case is very close to be incurable, </p>
<p begin="01:20:12.520" end="01:20:16.780" horseID="531">most probably you will have to interfere<br/> with another remedy </p>
<p begin="01:20:16.880" end="01:20:19.646" horseID="532">in order to upgrade this patient.</p>
<p begin="01:20:21.560" end="01:20:26.410" horseID="533">Otherwise if you let him<br/> go like that, he will die.</p>
<p begin="01:20:27.400" end="01:20:31.620" horseID="534">So in an aggravation, real aggravation <br/>from the homeopathic remedy,</p>
<p begin="01:20:31.720" end="01:20:41.390" horseID="535"> in the so called incurable case, it needs <br/>an interference with the next remedy.</p>
<p begin="01:20:41.490" end="01:20:46.590" horseID="536"> And usually the next remedy <br/>appears, you can see.</p>
<p begin="01:20:58.840" end="01:21:03.750" horseID="537">- With the hysterical, hypochondriac <br/>cases isn't a symptom on itself </p>
<p begin="01:21:03.850" end="01:21:05.700" horseID="538">when you look out  at the rubric?</p>
<p begin="01:21:05.800" end="01:21:18.150" horseID="539">- Absolutely, you take in consideration <br/>the anxiety hypochondriac as a rubric </p>
<p begin="01:21:18.250" end="01:21:22.780" horseID="540">but this is not enough because <br/>there you have 50 remedies.</p>
<p begin="01:21:22.880" end="01:21:38.970" horseID="541">Which of the remedies.... a lot of remedies<br/> which you have to differentiate. </p>
<p begin="01:21:47.390" end="01:21:56.380" horseID="542">Is it good to give placebo to such cases? <br/> Absolutely you give placebo 3 times the day,</p>
<p begin="01:21:56.480" end="01:22:06.700" horseID="543"> you start with 1 time, you say double it, <br/>3ple it, 10 times whatever satisfies their need</p>
<p begin="01:22:06.800" end="01:22:22.210" horseID="544">and because these patients are usually <br/>led by their minds and hypochondriasis, </p>
<p begin="01:22:22.310" end="01:22:30.640" horseID="545">to keep them in a low level  it is very <br/>good for them and will make them</p>
<p begin="01:22:30.740" end="01:22:37.699" horseID="546"> survive enough time for you to observe <br/>what other symptoms are there</p>
<p begin="01:22:37.700" end="01:22:45.920" horseID="547">so you make your correct decision. But have<br/>in mind with these cases especially, </p>
<p begin="01:22:46.020" end="01:22:53.340" horseID="548">that it is an element which will always <br/>be there to a certain degree.  </p>
<p begin="01:22:54.510" end="01:23:06.910" horseID="549">It's like personality traits.<br/> So it will stay, but the exaggeration, </p>
<p begin="01:23:07.010" end="01:23:11.780" horseID="550">the fears, the anxieties, the panic attack <br/>which goes with such cases,</p>
<p begin="01:23:12.260" end="01:23:22.220" horseID="551"> all this will go away. And in the back of their mind it will remain,  what about this pain?</p>
<p begin="01:23:22.320" end="01:23:31.230" horseID="552">But then just a thought and then it goes <br/>away. Otherwise, the thought stays and </p>
<p begin="01:23:31.330" end="01:23:41.160" horseID="553">tantalize them and makes them really <br/>fearful, I'm going to die.</p>
<p begin="01:24:06.870" end="01:24:18.520" horseID="554">Find in the Organon where Hahnemann talks about hysterical and hypochondriac patients.</p>
<p begin="01:24:59.760" end="01:25:09.270" horseID="555">Where Hahnemann talks about this group,<br/> the similar, in the Organon?</p>
<p begin="01:25:21.360" end="01:25:27.360" horseID="556">And which are the paragraphs in <br/>which he talks about provings?</p>
</div>
</body>
</tt>
