<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<case>
  <ID>EL284cf7902002ff72c498e44ecf021305</ID>
  <patient>
    <case_date></case_date>
    <gender>female</gender>
    <patient_initials>R.S</patient_initials>
    <age>43</age>
    <circumstances>Please enter the personal circumstances&#13;
&#13;
A lady aged 41 years fixed an appointment with me on 15th of January, 2015. She entered inside the consulting room with a staggering gait. Her face was so dull and drowsy. She was obese but beautiful. Her hair is curly and neatly combed. She was perspiring profusely after stepping through the staircase to reach the consulting room.  Every step she made with caution. When I questioned, what brought her here, she replied that the vertigo accompanied by nausea and her tottering movement were the reasons for that. One year before all the problems started and before that she was perfectly alright. She also added that she was suffering from renal calculi and bladder stone. Her voice was so soft and talking in a low voice. She sat like a statue and moved her head along with her body like a robot. Eyes filled with fear and tear. She feared that turning her head quickly would aggravate her vertigo and make her to fall down. Whizzing noise was there in the ear along with the vertigo. She was keeping her hands by the side of the ear to hear clearly. Someone of her close relative was an allopathic doctor who advised her to undergo a surgery in the ear to correct the noise and vertigo. Fearing surgery and loss of hearing as an after effect of surgery she came for homeopathic treatment.</circumstances>
  </patient>
  <new_patient>
    <description>
      <main_complaint>
        <origin>Please enter the Origin of the complaint (since when it appeared)&#13;
&#13;
At the age of 40-41 the following complaints started. Vertigo - turning head quickly  - bending forward - bending head backward -  rising from stooping - looking steadily - accompanied by nausea - rising from bed or lying down or turning in bed aggravates vertigo.&#13;
Previously  at 39 whizzing noise in both the ears - hearing impaired because of the noise - to hear clearly keeps her hands by the side of the ear - sleep disturbed because of the noise - when she was thirty nine, Gentamicin was injected near her ear by her allopathic doctor to reduce the noise and improve her hearing but worsened the symptoms  </origin>
        <causative_factors>Please enter any possible causative factors&#13;
&#13;
                        First the suppressed  ill effects caused by Gentamicin injection is to be treated and then the continuous ill effects of the vaccination she had during her childhood days is to be cleared. Her depression, her food habits are to be corrected. The multiple stones in her kidneys and bladder,  the other disturbances like burning after urination, pain in kidney region and the pain in abdomen and urethra caused by those stones are all the troubles considered here for cure. Her hearing loss accompanied by the noise in her ear and the vertigo which confine to her in bed and her sadness produced by those symptoms are all to be corrected. </causative_factors>
        <modalities>Please enter Modalities (what makes the complaint aggravate or ameliorate)&#13;
&#13;
Vertigo - turning head quickly  - bending forward - bending head backward -  rising from stooping - looking steadily - accompanied by nausea - rising from bed or lying down or turning in bed aggravates vertigo. Insufficient intake of water caused burning sensation after urination and pain at times in the kidney region on exertion. &#13;
</modalities>
        <occurrence_time>Please enter the Time of occurrence, aggravation or amelioration&#13;
&#13;
Walking slowly without turning her head amel. Lying down and rising from bed agg. Fast movements, bending forward and backward agg.</occurrence_time>
        <body_side>Please enter side of the body&#13;
&#13;
Head and ear both sides were affected.</body_side>
        <appearence_frequency>Please enter frequency of appearance&#13;
&#13;
Every quick movement aggravated her condition.</appearence_frequency>
        <pain_desc>Please enter a description of the pain&#13;
&#13;
Burning pain after urination in the bladder. Aching in the kidney region extending to abdomen.</pain_desc>
        <complaint_ext>Please enter any extension of the complaint to other parts&#13;
&#13;
At times pain in the right kidney region would extend to the abdomen.</complaint_ext>
        <other_complaints>Loss of hearing, vertigo and the pain caused by her renal calculus caused depression and fear. </other_complaints>
      </main_complaint>
      <diagnosis>
        <conv_med_presc>Please enter the conventional Medical Prescriptions&#13;
&#13;
At 39 whizzing noise in both the ears - hearing impaired because of the noise - to hear clearly keeps her hands by the side of the ear - sleep disturbed because of the noise - when she was thirty nine, Gentamycin was injected near her ear by her allopathic doctor to reduce the noise and improve her hearing but worsened the symptoms.</conv_med_presc>
        <lab_tests>
          <desc>Audiometry test was done and found some deficiency in her hearing. She had not presented the report but explained what was the result of the test, narrated to her by the doctor who took the test. </desc>
          <file></file>
        </lab_tests>
        <pre_homeo_presc>This was the first time she wanted to consult with a homeopathist. </pre_homeo_presc>
      </diagnosis>
      <medical_history>
        <personal>
          <therapies_vaccination>Please enter Suppressive therapies and vaccinations&#13;
&#13;
Gentamycin injection was given when she was 39 to improve her hearing. One or two vaccines were given when she was a child. </therapies_vaccination>
          <traumas>Please enter Traumas (physical, emotional, mental)&#13;
&#13;
Specifically she had nothing to quote.</traumas>
          <infections>Please enter Acute infectious diseases&#13;
Hale and healthy up to 39 before the treatment for her ear and noises.</infections>
          <other>                                      </other>
        </personal>
        <family>
          <diseases>Please enter Diseases that occur in the family&#13;
&#13;
                                       Father and mother were teachers in an elementary school living in a village but now shifted to the nearby town due to their teaching job. Mother had noise problem in ear after an injury on her head. Grandparents both father side and mother side were hale and healthy and were doing their farm work in their native village and died in their ripe age. Her husband is working as driver in a government transport company and he was healthy without problems. Got married at the age of twenty three after finishing her degree in a private college and was healthy up to 39 before her vertigo and the sudden noise in her ear. Only one son was doing his engineering course in a college. She had one brother and a sister. Brother with normal health and her sister is also having the same vertigo and hearing loss accompanied by noise in her ear. She too was given Gentamicin injection near her ear to worsen her complaints. She had all the available vaccinations available in her time.</diseases>
        </family>
      </medical_history>
      <physical>
        <reactions>She did not give anything to record here, but explained that cold things affected her much.</reactions>
        <sleeping_habits>Feeling better after a short sleep.</sleeping_habits>
        <food_modalities>Desire for cold drinks.</food_modalities>
        <menstruation>Menstruation almost normal.</menstruation>
      </physical>
      <mental_emotional>Please enter mental and emotional symptoms                          &#13;
&#13;
  Over sensitiveness to all  external impressions, light noise -full of  fears and anxieties at dark, twilight, health about, diseases about - delusions that she cannot hear - having a disease incurable - doubtful of recovery. &#13;
&#13;
</mental_emotional>
    </description>
    <analysis>
      <prognosis>
        <anatomopathological></anatomopathological>
        <personal_medical_history>Please enter personal medical history&#13;
From birth to 38 years&#13;
At 39 the ear problem with whizzing noise started. Gentamicin was injected near her ear by the allopathic doctor. Situations worsened after that. Continuous noise in the ear and after some time accompanied with vertigo and both the problem continued. At 40 multiple stones were deducted in bladder and in both the kidneys with burning sensation during and after urination along with pain in kidney region extending to abdomen and urethra. Much depressed because she could not hear clearly because of the noise in the ear.&#13;
&#13;
</personal_medical_history>
        <family_medical_history>Please enter family medical history and hereditary predisposition&#13;
&#13;
Mother had noise problem in ear after an injury on her head. Grandparents both father side and mother side were hale and healthy and were doing their farm work in their native village and died in their ripe age. Her husband is working as driver in a government transport company and he was healthy without problems. Got married at the age of twenty three after finishing her degree in a private college and was healthy up to 39 before her vertigo and the sudden noise in her ear. Only one son was doing his engineering course in a college. She had one brother and a sister. Brother with normal health and her sister is also having the same vertigo and hearing loss accompanied by noise in her ear. She too was given Gentamicin injection near her ear to worsen her complaints. She had all the available vaccinations available in her time.  &#13;
&#13;
</family_medical_history>
        <level_of_health>3</level_of_health>
        <conclusion>Please enter Conclusion                         &#13;
&#13;
  A thorough analysis of the case will reveal the required information to treat the case. The vaccinations she was given in her childhood days are the first and foremost reason. The second reason for the present problems is the Gentamicin injection she was given near her ear by the allopathic doctor without considering the side effects of Gentamicin. Continuous noise in the ear, the deaf sensation and the vertigo accompanied by those troubles caused her the severe depression and making her to feel that her disease was not curable. Because of the food items she used to take, controlling and retaining of urine for a long time and the less quantity of water intake may be the reason for the stones in bladder and kidney.&#13;
&#13;
</conclusion>
      </prognosis>
      <symptoms_selection>
        <peculiar>Please enter Peculiar symptoms, Rank the intensity of each symptom in scale from 1 (lowest) to 4 (highest)&#13;
&#13;
1.	MIND - ANXIETY - future, about: 3&#13;
2.	VERTIGO - ACCOMPANIED BY - staggering: 2 &#13;
3.	VERTIGO - ACCOMPANIED BY - Ear - noises in: 1 &#13;
4.	VERTIGO - FALL, tendency to: 2&#13;
5.	VERTIGO - NAUSEA - with: 2&#13;
6.	VERTIGO - TURNING; when - head; or moving the - quickly: 2 &#13;
7.	HEARING - IMPAIRED - accompanied by – noises :3&#13;
8.   BLADDER - STONES in bladder: 2 &#13;
9.   GENERALS – OBESITY: 3&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
</peculiar>
        <intense>Please enter Intense symptoms, Rank the intensity of each symptom in scale from 1 (lowest) to 4 (highest)&#13;
&#13;
1.	MIND - ANXIETY - future, about: 3&#13;
2.	VERTIGO - ACCOMPANIED BY - staggering: 2 &#13;
3.	VERTIGO - ACCOMPANIED BY - Ear - noises in: 1 &#13;
4.	VERTIGO - FALL, tendency to: 2&#13;
5.	VERTIGO - NAUSEA - with: 2&#13;
6.	VERTIGO - TURNING; when - head; or moving the - quickly: 2 &#13;
7.	HEARING - IMPAIRED - accompanied by – noises :3&#13;
8.   BLADDER - STONES in bladder: 2 &#13;
9.   GENERALS – OBESITY: 3&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
</intense>
      </symptoms_selection>
      <repertorization>
        <desc></desc>
        <file_url></file_url>
      </repertorization>
      <remedies_differentiation>Please enter Differentiation of the remedies&#13;
&#13;
CALCAREA CARBONICA:&#13;
Delayed en slow development. Fat and flabby, or tendency to grow fat. Many fears and anxieties. Extreme chilliness; liability to take cold; coldness in spots. Profuse sore perspiration; perspiration on exertion during sleep. Craving for sweets, soft boiled eggs, salt. Aversion to and aggravation from milk. &lt; Heights.&#13;
&#13;
PHOSPHOROUS:&#13;
Too open and impressionable: sympathetic, affectionate- lots of fears and anxieties. Cold drinks [desire + ameliorates]. Burning heat and pains. &lt; Lying on left side. &gt; Sleep, even short sleep. Craving for highly seasoned food and ice cream.&#13;
&#13;
KALI CARBONICUM:&#13;
Strong mental control and sense of duty. Emotions felt in stomach [like a blow]; &lt; 2-4 A.M.' Stitching pains; Very chilly; susceptible to colds due to profuse perspiration; Swelling of upper eyelids. &#13;
&#13;
</remedies_differentiation>
      <prescription>
        <remedy>CALCAREA CARBONICA</remedy>
        <potency>200C</potency>
        <regimen>Please enter regimen&#13;
Nux-v-200c one dose in 25 ml water on the first four days before going to bed just to nullify the ill effects of the previous medicines she took early and then from the fifth dayCalc-200c one dose daily in the morning in empty stomach.   </regimen>
        <other_notes>Please enter other notes</other_notes>
      </prescription>
    </analysis>
  </new_patient>
  <followups>
    <followup>
      <number>1</number>
      <followup_date></followup_date>
      <conv_med_presc>Please enter conventional medical prescriptions&#13;
&#13;
 The second consultation took place on 06 th February 2015. She was not taking any medicine after the injection, Gentamicin because of the fear of losing her hearing .</conv_med_presc>
      <lab_tests>
        <desc></desc>
        <file></file>
      </lab_tests>
      <reaction>Please enter Reaction to the prescription of the former consultation&#13;
&#13;
For the first two, three days the vertigo was severe to some extent but she felt something good inside from the sixth day after started taking Calc-200c. The noise in her ear was also reduced to some extent. </reaction>
      <analysis>Please enter Analysis of the reaction&#13;
&#13;
According to the reaction of the remedy, the initial aggravation caused by the remedy confirmed the selection of the remedy was correct and it acted as expected. So the medicine could be continued till it ceased to act.</analysis>
      <conclusion>Please enter followup conclusion&#13;
&#13;
According to the words of the patient the remedy Calc-200 was acting good without much aggravation and the patient was feeling better mentally and physically and so it was decided to continue the same medicine till the medicine ceased o act or another aggravation or change of symptoms.</conclusion>
      <repertorization>
        <desc>Please enter repertorization</desc>
        <file_url></file_url>
      </repertorization>
      <prescription>
        <remedy>Calcarea carbonica</remedy>
        <potency>200c</potency>
        <regimen>Please enter regimen&#13;
&#13;
Calc-200c one dose in 25 ml water in empty stomach immediately after waking up after 10 minutes after brushing her teeth and nothing should be taken in the next 45 minutes. Daily one dose till the medicine ceased to work. As her kidney stones troubled her much at times Berberis  vulgaris-Q also was given to her as a supportive remedy i.e. 20 drops in half a cup of water to be taken daily at three times at 12-00 in the afternoon, at 4-00 in the evening and at 8-00 in the night in empty stomach. </regimen>
        <other_notes>Please enter other followup notes&#13;
&#13;
Her health considerably improved and the vertigo almost gone and her hearing also improved. If the medicine stopped working then her case must be studied again. After proper repertorization if the same medicine was to be given then the selected  potency must be increased and to be administered at long intervals.</other_notes>
      </prescription>
    </followup>
    <followup>
      <number>2</number>
      <followup_date></followup_date>
      <conv_med_presc>Please enter conventional medical prescriptions&#13;
&#13;
The third consultation took place on 8th March, 2015 and after that every month one consultation took place. </conv_med_presc>
      <lab_tests>
        <desc></desc>
        <file></file>
      </lab_tests>
      <reaction>Please enter Reaction to the prescription of the former consultation&#13;
&#13;
She was doing better and hence the medicine Calc-200c was continued and Berb-Q reduced her urinary troubles considerably. </reaction>
      <analysis>Please enter Analysis of the reaction&#13;
&#13;
The medicines selected and the way they were administered were acting favourably towards a cure and so it was decided to repeat  the same procedure.  </analysis>
      <conclusion>Please enter followup conclusion&#13;
&#13;
It was decided to continue the same procedure for some more time till we got the indication to stop the remedy by means of aggravation or appearance of new symptoms.</conclusion>
      <repertorization>
        <desc>Please enter repertorization</desc>
        <file_url></file_url>
      </repertorization>
      <prescription>
        <remedy>Calcarea carbonica</remedy>
        <potency>200c</potency>
        <regimen>Please enter regimen&#13;
&#13;
Calc-200c one dose in 25 ml water in empty stomach immediately after waking up after 10 minutes after brushing her teeth and nothing should be taken in the next 45 minutes. Daily one dose till the medicine ceased to work. As her kidney stones troubled her much at times Berberis  vulgaris-Q also was given to her as a supportive remedy i.e. 20 drops in half a cup of water to be taken daily at three times at 12-00 in the afternoon, at 4-00 in the evening and at 8-00 in the night in empty stomach. &#13;
</regimen>
        <other_notes>Please enter other followup notes&#13;
&#13;
From the fifth consultation  Berb-Q was stopped because there was no disturbance in her urinary problem and Calc -200c was was given occasionally.  </other_notes>
      </prescription>
    </followup>
  </followups>
</case>
