- Engaged?
- Yes. Girlfriend for 16 years, engaged for 3 years.
- But you know each other for 16 years?
- Yes.
- You have been together for 16 years and 3 years ago you are engaged finally
and in another 15 years you will marry…
- Maybe
- It’s a good arrangement. We must be taught by him. How he does it.
So this is a case of sleeplessness for 20 years and he got coff,
he had received quite a lot of remedies of course and he got coff
and this is the second follow up now?
- First follow up.
- You had I think the first follow up after a few days?
- Yes.
- You took Coff 10M 2 times.
- One time in the beginning.
- One time but you took again coff in middle of October
because the sleeplessness started coming back and you took 50M in the end of November…
- And all of these again because you told me so.
- Because from 10M you had no effect.
So after coff 50M slept better for 1 month but sleeplessness came back again.
Have had 3 colds since he began with coff with high fever?
- One time high fever.
- And what did you take?
- Nothing.
- Still pain and stiffness in the knee and pain in the wrist.
Then who told you to take phos?
- You.
- Because fears are still there, had some epistaxis,
sleeplessness is still there but not as before.
- That’s my own words.
- And then on the 14th of March you took lyc.
I gave you lyc?
- Yes.
- What did you write to me?
- I had some stress that influenced me.
I was falsely accused for something. Someone accused me for something that I didn’t do.
- Somebody accused you, made you mad but you did not attack him?
- No, I did not do what I was accused for.
This is big for me. I’m too kind I see the best thing in all people.
I lose because of this.
- No effect from phos, had some stress that influenced me,
you had some accusation from some friend or…?
- Yes.
- Friend?
- What was the accusation, can you say or you don’t want to say?
- No, I don’t want to say.
- Ok. But you were innocent, you haven’t done anything?
- Yes.
- I felt anger with myself and some anxiety.
- Yes anger with myself because I keep getting in trouble because I’m too kind.
I lost 100.000 euros when I was building my house
because I trusted the persons who built my house because I’m too kind.
- I see. So, present symptoms; sleeplessness still there but not…
- This is completely back. It was one month ago when I wrote this.
- That means you cannot sleep the whole night?
- It takes several hours before I sleep.
- “Still very sensitive to noise especially when I am about to fall asleep
and a sudden noise comes then it almost impossible to sleep.”
Have been constipated lately?
- No.
- “Also if someone, dog or girlfriend is breathing loudly next to me.”
You sleep with the dog or the girlfriend?
- Or both. I’m very sensitive to noise.
- You mean your dog is sleeping in your bed?
- Yes. I love animals.
- “Brain is still active but not as before. Sleep is deeper.”
So if you sleep for some hours that is deep sleep?
- Yes.
- You cannot still wake up if there is some noise?
- Yes, I still wake up but maybe not as easy as before.
- “Knee is more painful and stiff, worse when having knee erect, standing,
walking slowly and having the knee bent.” Lumbar pain you have worse standing,
walking slowly, lying on back for long. You sleep on your back or on the side?
- On the back. When I am asleep it is on the back,
when I’m going to sleep I turn all the time.
- Do you have nightmares?
- Sometimes.
- When you have a nightmare you always wake up lying on your back or you cannot sleep?
- Always lying on back I think.
- You became more hot or more cold?
- After lyc I think I also put the feet out of the covers for a while
but not anymore. I have the feet under the cover here in Alonissos, so it’s not outside.
- Pain in the left side of the neck under the scapula
but under the left side of the neck is here and the scapula is very down.
- No, left side of the back.
- Wrist is worse since a couple of weeks. Ganglion is bigger and more pain.
- But that is going up and down.
But it has been much better than before I received coff and the other remedies.
- The anxiety and anger with my self is almost gone.
- It almost went away directly after lyc. I also feel more confidence.
- The fears are still there. What are the fears?
- Fears… snakes.
- Fear of being alone?
- Yes, I don’t like that because of the things that happened to me before.
- So you want to have somebody?
- It can be the dog.
- Or anybody… but has to be in the house.
- Yes, only in the night.
- “Lately felt some pain in heart region, cold and draft aggravates,
desires are the same, chocolates and sweets and spices.”
- Chocolate is underlined four. At least. I love chocolate.
- How much you can take?
- Very much.
- One block of chocolate?
- No problem. I can take several times a day. One big block.
If I start to eat I can’t stop but I do not do it often because it’s not so good.
- How is your energy in general?
- It is good.
- How is your emotional in general? You feel happy, you feel depressed?
- I feel good.
- And you would like to sleep more. How many hours you sleep now?
- It depends but sometimes now… When we were going to Alonissos I slept 2 hours,
I went to bed maybe at 23.00 and felt asleep maybe at 1.30, so I slept 2 hours
but it’s ok, I can function anyway.
- You can function even with 2 hours of sleep?
- Yes but I don’t want to have this problem
because when I’m lying there and turning it’s disturbing.
- So you become restless in bed actually.
- Yes, kind of restless.
- Your reaction to weather, how is it now? Normal?
Are you bothered by heat here very much or cold?
- What bothers me from heat is perspiration. I don’t like to perspire.
But I can function with heat, no problem. I don’t like cold weather.
- Sun you like? Can you sit under the sun here?
- Yes.
- You take it easy.
I also have a new symptom that’s pain in this side. That has been more lately. After lyc.
- Pain on the left temple.
- What else?
- It can be worse sometimes when I’m turning my head to the left.
- It can be worse the pain?
- Yes, but not always, sometimes. And also I have sneezing from drafts. Not now.
- It’s a new symptom or you had it in the past?
- I’m sensitive to draft but I cannot tell if it’s a new symptom.
- Would you say you have anxiety about your health?
- No.
- You eat meat?
- No, only chicken and fish and no fat. I don’t like fat. Aversion to fat.
- But you like chicken and you like fish.
- Fish not so much. Chicken I like it.
- Salt? How much?
- I like salt. I would like to do it but I think before I eat.
- You control yourself not to put extra.
- I could put very much salt. When I eat French fries
and pop-corn I put a lot of salt.
A new symptom also is that I was sitting in the sun for 2 hours this week
and I was too red, I never became so red. So I burned myself.
I never do it like this easily, I’ve never been so red on my legs.
- Do you think that you are an open person, you can talk about yourself easily?
- Yes, I have no problem talking about myself but I sometimes I can be a little shy
because I cannot find the right words but if I can find the right words, I can talk very much.
- Are you able to cry easily or you cannot cry?
- I can cry but mostly when I’m alone. But it depends I think.
Much easier now than a couple of years ago maybe now I can cry in front of others
but I prefer to be alone.
- Would you like somebody to say “Come on” if you cry, come to console you,
you will like it or it will make you irritated?
- I think it will make me irritated but I’m not sure if I will like it.
Maybe I will like it.
- Here you go to the sea to take a bath. You can stay under the sun?
- Yes.
- You can tolerate the sun?
This is the first time that I go swimming,
before I was lying under the sun for some hours maybe but now I’m swimming,
I didn’t do that before a couple of years when I was here.
- Before you used to lie under the sun for hours and you would not go to the sea;
now you go to the sea…
- Yes, but now it was warmer this year.
- And now you go to the sea straight away and you stay more in the sea than outside.
- No.
- Still you stay outside under the sun?
- Yes.
- But you are not sunburned.
- Maybe not so easily.
- You sit under the shade?
- No.
- You had pain in the knee. It’s more painful and stiff.
- Yes the pain in the knee and the stiffness came after the coff.
I felt some stiffness and some small pain after coff maybe 2 weeks after
and then I was training with the boxing bag and then the day after there was pain.
- The pain started and is still there?
- Yes.
- In the left knee… Do you know if you had gonorrhea?
- No, never.
- Do you feel easily insulted if somebody says something…?
- No problem.
- You get angry very easily?
- No, I don’t think so, only with my girlfriend.
- And then you hit her?
- No. She knows the buttons to push.
- If you don’t feel well and somebody comes to console you, do you like it?
You don’t know or you know?
- I like attention.
But I don’t know if I like it.
- By the time you are really in a bad mood if somebody comes and says “come on…”
- If I’m in a bad mood I don’t think I like it but if I am sad maybe
then I would like it.
- How much salt you use?
- A lot.
- How much is “a lot”?
- Very much but I don’t use it because I think about my health.
- But your instinct is to take the salt and put it before you even tasting it?
- Only in pop-corn and in French fries, then I do it always.
- Still desire chocolate.
- Very much.
- You like consolation? If somebody comes and say “come on” when you are angry
or when you are...
- I’m not sure.
- You are not sure.
- If you were free to use salt would you use as much as you like?
- I think so.
- How much would you use? Can you give an idea? I mean…
- I would eat salt directly. I would salt my food.
- All your food?
- Maybe.
- Whatever it might be.
Not on the sandwiches but hot food. Spices I would also…
- Do you like if you are in a bad mood somebody to come and console you?
To say “come on, don’t worry”
- No, I don’t think I do when I’m angry, maybe when I’m sad.
- Not when you are angry.
- Maybe that would irritate me more.
- What you wrote desires are the same; chocolate and sweets.
You forgot to put the salt?
- I forgot. I love salt.
Also cookies I can eat a lot. I cannot stop to eat when I’m started,
I take several cookies in my mouth at the same time.
- You have a good appetite?
- Yes.
- Did you put on weight since last time?
- I also have some bloatedness. After eating and drinking.
- When you are sad, when you are angry if somebody comes to console you,
you will accept it or say “leave me alone”? You like rather to be alone.
- When I’m irritated I think I want to be alone.
- At this moment, you feel that you are more open than previous years?
- I think so.
- Or you rather go to yourself and brood in case something happens.
- No I’m more open. I don’t have a problem to talk to people about my problems.
The guilt feeling I had before is also completely gone.
- Also you had written you had pain in your heart, in the muscles rather you had reported.
How is that?
- It comes now and then.
It’s not a big pain. But before, many years ago I had this pain.
I think it was between ribs and I could only take small breath maybe for a whole weekend.
I was like that Friday-Saturday-Sunday.
- Do you remember what age you were?
- Maybe the last time I had it was a couple of years ago but not so severe,
it was more severe when I was younger.
When I was 7-8 I fell from the roof and I landed with my hand here
and I think it started after that.
But the pain in the chest that I have now it’s not the same,
it comes sometimes when I breathe. I don’t know if it’s a kind of stitching pain,
it’s a vague pain. But it’s not often.
- You are open with your girlfriend? You will tell everything to her?
- Yes.
- Your parents? You are talking with them?
- Yes, maybe not everything.
- If the food is oily or there is fat in the food you will like it you will take it?
- I don’t like fat in the meat but I can take fat food at sauces.
But not fat on the meat, I would never eat. Not slimy food.
Or if there is some cartilage on the chicken I would stick it out.
- Ok. Alright.
- Who knows the remedy? I want to see hands. Strange.
Some you know the remedy and you are afraid to make a mistake. The remedy is clear.
Dimitri, which is the remedy? Elia, which is…? Yes! Why are you afraid to talk?
It’s a nat-m case. After coff, which took away the extreme intensity in the nervous system,
then the nat-m is manifesting.
Desire for salt, aversion fat, he has all the symptoms of nat-m, what is the problem?
Consolation, I did not ask…
What else?
I asked about salt, I asked about fat, I said if I ask for consolation
and go to the class and next ok… everybody will know the remedy.
You see what made you vacillate or not be sure,
you know what it is? That he said he likes the sun.
That made you suspicious, maybe your idea is not correct
but if an organism has so many keynotes of a remedy and does not have the usual,
worse sun, worse from exposal to the sun, then no problem.
Because the… karma of this fly it was ended. She has sacrificed herself.
The other day it was a Japanese girl sitting there and when she saw me do it
she went like this. What was her remedy? Killing a fly.
What? Aethusa? No, I’m just joking. You cannot give a remedy
because somebody is reacting in this way.
It shows a kind of super sensitivity which is not natural.
So, sleeplessness from grief also is typical of nat-m,
people who have gone through lots of grief, they cannot sleep.
And what are the symptoms of nat-m? Difficulty falling asleep…
Med is the first on the symptoms. Why we prefer nat-m? Because instead of med,
nat-m has some of his keynotes symptoms.
Nat-m is the remedy which has to be given in high potency.
Let me see, desires salt, aversion fat, desires chocolate, cold aggravates,
you see cold aggravates? Nat-m is there.
Drafts of air aggravate, sleeplessness from activity of thoughts.
You see nat-m has one of the heaviest sleeplessness we have in the M.M.
They can go through the whole night without sleep, especially where there is grief
and because of grief there is sleeplessness.
This is a case of nat-m. So nat-m here, he had some more… Spices, aversion slimy also…
and you could see he does not like consolation.
So, nat-m what potency? He is strong you can give any potency you like, no problem.
His organism is very strong. Potency, Dimitri? 50M. I agree. Starts with 10M.
So, 10M , you just take one dose and maybe there is an aggravation.
Do not be bothered, wait and call within 2-3 months.
You have to wait before you give a report, ok?
Who thought of nat-m now? Everyone should think of nat-m in this case, it is very clear.
What confused you was the fact that he was lying in the sun.
No, it did not confuse some but some others were confused because…
Yes, sir? Say it again. Trusting? No it makes him healthy on this level.
He doesn’t have to have all the symptoms of nat-m from A-Z. Yes?
What level? The level you are until you have some… but you had already a high fever.
– One year before this last one.
– You are high level in health, don’t bother. If you don’t damage yourself with other things,
which are bad habits, you can live.
You have to reduce the chocolate a little bit but you see,
he is also careful about his diet. That is characteristic of nat-m. They will not eat.
They will need salt but they will resist. They need chocolate,
they want to resist as much as they can. And they try to eat more healthy food.
Nat-m can up to the point of being hypochondriac.
It can go as far as… He is not that far but he is careful with diet,
with what he is doing at this moment.