Ok, we can start.
I have seen one year ago and the main problems were peripheral neuropathy,
eczema on hands, abscesses on the teeth, pain in right hypochondria,
phobias and anxieties and the remedy that was prescribed was Bac 200CH.
Is this the last report?
–Yes.
– The overall reaction was an aggravation without amelioration.
“I had an aggravation with my headaches, impaired hearing from mental exertion,
developed other few new symptoms like faintness and vertigo from heat,
restless mind full of thoughts, I was not able to rest and to do something constantly,
waking early with busy mind, pain in stomach after eating.
There was no change in my main complaints
so I wrote a report describing my original set of symptoms
before I started being treated with homeopathy. I thought it might be good idea”.
So you wrote to me…
- Basically this.
What it is stated here. I wrote you the same list of symptoms.
– Original symptoms 10 years ago;
low grade fever most of the day, the worst time was always 4-8, offensive urine,
great weariness, flushes of heat in head especially after coffee or heavy food,
perspiration on scalp after the slightest exertion or in sleep, falling of hair,
indigestion and nausea after having fatty food.
Wounds healing slowly, muscles regenerates slowly after exertion.
Before Bac you have taken several remedies.
Ars, Psor, Phos, Cham, Lyc, Syph, Sulph and some others.
How many others?
– Quite a few I don’t remember.
At least 20 more. French homeopathy before…
- Then you wrote the report.
– You gave me Lyc.
– I gave Lyc what potency?
– 200CH.
–But you had Lyc in the past.
– Yes, I did.
– So  what happened with Lyc?
– There was again an aggravation and then back to the original state, no amelioration,
but some new symptoms appeared and some of mine previous symptoms got more intense.
– So you wrote another email.
– Basically I got Lyc at the end of October and then I wrote a report after Lyc.
I think it was 3 months later. I waited for 3 months after Lyc.
And then I wrote another report about the reaction to Lyc.
– You don’t have the email to read?
– I’m sorry but the information is pretty much the same. I wrote to you I think in February.
– February 18th so most probably…
- No February 18th it was later on.
– “There are some news that my state is progressing. I took another dose of arg-n”.
– This was after prescription of arg-n.
– The arg-n, I prescribed…?
– Yes, you prescribed.
After the Lyc. Because some symptoms of this remedy emerged.
– This is what I’m trying to find. Where are the symptoms.
– The symptoms are here.
–“ Eructations after eating, ticks, restlessness of extremities,
have to do something constantly, superstitiousness.
So I took another dose of arg-n 9CH in the morning”. So you took just one dose?
– You prescribed twice a day 9CH for one month.
I took only one dose and I got a reaction after one dose.
– “After one 9CH according to what I have seen in my throat it looks like tonsillitis.
My left tonsil is more painful on swallowing, whereas my right tonsil is more coated with pus.
The left one is also coated but less. The pain is worse on swallowing.
Also feel pain in the right hypochondria. The highest fever since yesterday it was 38,5C”.
Before you had low fever.
– Well for 10 years, I had almost no fevers.
– But before 10 years you had constantly, low fever, hectic fever.
–The original very syndrome was 37.1-37.2C.
– So that was the first time that you developed after many years?
– Not actually I developed such a fever after some remedies for example Psor
but only for a few days but not the tonsillitis. The tonsillitis I didn’t have for 10 years.
– You mentioned “My problems started 10 years ago with mononucleosis
which was misdiagnosed as tonsillitis and treated with antibiotics”.
So actually this was the manifestation of the old condition of mononucleosis.
– It seemed to me the same.
– “ Since then I have not had tonsillitis symptoms until now.
For all these 10 years I have still felt a pain in the left tonsil.”.
That’s all.
–Yes.
– And then I responded, what did I say?
– I think you said to take a dose of Lach.
It must have been 18th February because it started the night before.
I got the fever at 9 at night.
– I did not tell you to check your blood?
– Yes, you did but two days later.
– So I said take Lach 30CH one dose. And you took.
And what happened?
– Nothing.  It did not help.
And then I think it was on the left side and then it got worse from warm, didn’t help.
Then I wrote to you another email it just got worse and worse. The pain was worse.
I was more exhausted. I really didn’t know what to do
because for 2 days or something you were not responding so I took myself Merc.
And in between you contacted me and prescribed Nit-ac. And that helped very quickly.
– And what happened with nit-ac?
– It helped. Very well, very quickly. Good reaction.
– And the infection, how long it lasted?
– For 3 or 4 days it was very strong. I took the nit-ac…
- What potency?
– 30CH several doses.
– You repeated the dose once every day or as needed?
– You said to take it every few hours, every 2-3 hours.
Then I managed accordingly to this thing along with intervals.
I took less often  because I was feeling better and I stopped completely.
–And eventually became better and better.
– Yes very quickly.
It only took about a week…
- But it was quite dramatic as I remember.
– Yes, it was.
– You were quite in a bad state. There was tremendous pain.
You called me actually on the telephone. And you said you were totally exhausted.
Why don’t you say? I can’t remember all of this.
– So it seemed the same infection like this one 10-11 years ago when it all started.
– The mononucleosis you had 10 years ago. It seemed the whole syndrome was coming back.
And the main point was that the pain was really excruciating and constant.
- You mean why did you prescribe…
- The tonsils…
- Only on swallowing.
-By the moment you called me it was terrible I thought you will die in a few days…
- Yes it was terrible but only on swallowing.
The tonsils were swollen… like tonsillitis but quite progressed.
– I had a problem with you because it seemed that you were suffering a lot and…
- Yes but don’t forget that I am anxious. I might be exaggerating.
– Until I gave you the Nit-ac.
– Yes.
– Then I realized what it was happening but the last time you took nit-ac was 2 or 3 months ago?
– At that time, in February. It was only for the acute. Then I didn’t take anything.
I just repeated arg-n…
- You repeated. How many times?
– Once. You told me to repeat.
– I told you to repeat it when?
– One month ago.
– Because, why? What did you have?
– Because I wrote you that chronic state is the same…
- The pain in the tonsils…?
– No, the chronic syndrome, the neuropathy.
– The neuropathy, the tingling.
– Yes. It is more numbness.
Like wearing glass or something. But after the infection it was over.
At that time and even later on I started having aggravation in the chronic complaints,
after the infectious.
– After the infection the chronic complaints started coming back?
Or they were there all the time?
– No.
My main complaint is the numbness and the weakness, the neuromuscular complaints.
Then I took the infection, you treated the infection with nit-ac
but before the infection came up after arg-n.
– The infection came after arg-n.
– Yes.
After the infection was over then my chronic complaints started aggravating.
– But your general state was the same as before or now it was better.
– You mean after the infection?
– After the infection.
– First there was an aggravation and then slowly some improvement in some areas.
– So in the report you say ”complaints after mental exertion significantly better.
And I feel more mental power. I am able to work more, I do not get tired so easily.
Ticks are still there but are better. I have had them there since childhood.”
Which you call ticks?
– I try to hide, to control but I make things.
Some movements with the eyes, some compelling movements.
– This you remember started after the mononucleosis.
– No. I had it as a child. For quite long.
– If you remember in the childhood you had a severe acute that you were treated for?
– I don’t know. I had several times tonsillitis with high fevers.
Even at the age of 18, I had high fevers still.
– “My physical energy is slightly better about 10%.” Why you say 10% only?
Because as you said before you started working and you could take the work.
– Mental work. The improvement is in physical energy 10%.
But mental energy got much better more than 10%.
– How much?
– 30-40% like that. Maybe 50%. I am not sure.
– “Pain in stomach and hypochondria is less frequent. I have not put on weight so far“.
You stayed at the same weight?
– I’m underweight. I can’t put on weight.
– How many kilos are you know? 30?
– No, 50.
– You look 30! You’re 50 kilos.
“I have not put on weight.
My main complaints are better about 10%.” Are you sure 10%?
Today you feel any improvement which continues slowly or you feel it stopped?
Be very careful because I may make a mistake here and everything will come back.
–Are we talking about now, today or the months before?
When I wrote this report it was about a month ago or two months ago.
– That’s why I ask because there is a month interval between you wrote this report and now.
– So you’re asking now, how I feel now.
– Yes, now.
– It is better in some respect. When I touch something the sensation it is more or less the same.
But it is better in a sense that it does not aggravate so easily.
– If you do something, does not aggravate.
– So easily. It takes more time until it aggravates.
– So you can do more things without being aggravated.
When you say “I’m aggravated after exertion” what do you mean?
– These complaints are aggravated mainly by writing, typing on a computer, playing my guitar.
Mainly these 2 things.
– Now you can play the guitar for how long the most? 1 hour? 2 hours? 3 hours?
– Yes, maybe 2 hours.
– Before how long could you play the guitar? 20 minutes?
–No. One and a half hour.
– And now you can play it for 2 hours. So that means… how much percent is this?
Do you know?
– It is really hard to say.
–Like 10%, 20%, 25%, 35%?
– I would say 10-15%.
– Actually what you say is more than 20%. It’s 25%. But it doesn’t matter, really.
I just want to understand.
“The numbness gets worse after the exertion but now it takes more time before it aggravates.
However I have not had a full sense of touch in my fingers for about 10 years
and still do not have full touch. I feel like wearing rubber gloves all the time.
It is a fact that I have been working on a computer a lot recently
which aggravated the problem the most.” Why? Because of tiredness?
How long you work on the computer?
– Quite a lot recently?
– 4 hours, 5 hours, 6 hours?
– Something like that. With breaks.
– “My eczema got worse even when it is not winter now.”
– Now it’s gone at the moment but a about a month ago it was not bad at all,
but usually I have in winter only. But after the arg-n I have it also in spring.
But I have some information, if you like I can give you notes of the actual “now” state.
Because one month ago my mental state got worse again.
I was more tired, I couldn’t work again and I had this pain after mental exertion in my head.
– You had a pain on the vertex, on the top of your head.
– In the left side.
– In point?
– Yes.
– You had a point headache after exertion.
– Yes last year when you were taking my case.
– How is that now?
– It’s much better.
– Better or gone?
– I sometimes feel it when I  work very much but only…. It is gone.
– Can you tell me this pain with which remedy went away?
– It went away after arg-n.
– So when I asked you to do a blood test then you sent me of the 23rd February
and you said that the blood test sedimentation rate was 30 in the first hour or you don’t know?
They say 30 just  one number. They don’t say 30 first hour, 30 second hour…
The monocytes were 10.
They also made an Epstein- Barr virus antibodies test and a throat swab.
“Results of these should be available on Monday”. What were the results of the swab?
– There was no bacterial infection. The Epstein- Barr test showed… not the acute infection.
I had it already before. 5 years ago or something.
– But it was compared to 5 years ago? The numbers where the same or you don’t remember?
– I didn’t have a chance to see.
But the doctor said that definitely I must have encountered this infection at some point in my life.
It is very probable, she said. The monocytes ten. I was already feeling better.
They took my blood at the point I took when nit-ac had acted, I was already feeling better.
– When I asked you to take it immediately you said “I’m too sick I cannot…”
– No.
– This this what you told me over the telephone.
– The problem was that I came to the doctor the day where she was there only in the afternoon
and the laboratory did not perform in the afternoon, so I had to come next day morning.
So we had one day delay. In between I didn’t want to wait of course then I took nit-ac…
- But you did the test immediately after I told you to have a test? No, I don’t believe.
I remember you delayed quite a lot.
– At the first point I think I didn’t understand.
– You symptoms were as- a symptomatology syndrome -
were for me equal to mononucleosis at the time.
That’s why I asked, but you seemed no to be able to go.
I don’t remember for what reason you told me “I cannot go now”. You found some reason..
Maybe you were exhausted… And then finally you went. But it was already gone the syndrome.
– The monocytes were 8-9 or something like this for all these 10 years.
– The monocytes were high all these years.
– But in my country it is normal to have 8-9 monocytes.
– The interesting is you said that nobody performed any blood test
when you had the original tonsillitis. They did not suspect that…
- No, that’s way they gave me antibiotics.
– They gave you antibiotics and brought about all this.
– Most probably.
– And I did not know you had mononucleosis. You never told me.
– Last year you said it to me. I described and you said that most probably you had that.
– Then you had complaints, some pains in the thighs. Do you remember?
And then I asked you the pain in the thighs are not mentioned. What happened?
– Oh yes this was during the acute. I had pain in the thigh during…
- But disappeared?
– Yes it was just during the tonsillitis.
– The cervical glands… how long it took to get away?
– A few days, 3-5 days.
– “Swelling on tonsils slowly reducing… I have a lot more energy than 2 days ago.
But I am still a bit weak. There is still general malaise but I feel better resting.
I feel more the pain and pressure in the right hypochondria now.
Since yesterday I also feel a bit nauseous now and then.
Two symptoms were present during the original infection 10 years ago.
My general impression is that it is exactly the same infection as I had 10 years ago.
I looked in my medical documentation
and found out that monocytes were slightly higher 12% in blood test
performed 2 years after the infection.
During the original infection no blood test was performed."
So let me now understand your present situation.
What do you feel now has to be improved mostly? The tingling?
– Yes the numbness.
– This is the main.
– Numbness, weakness.
– Your appetite is good?
– It’s good, normal.
– You eat like a normal person? Like me?
– No, not at all.
– You eat less?
– Not less but I cannot tolerate some food.
– Which food?
–Fatty food, fried, some raw onions, spicy things.
– Have you ever examined your gallbladder?
– Yes.
– And it is ok?
– Ok. But I have pain here… but it is ok.
– I say it is not ok.
– But it is better after the arg-n.
– Better after arg-n. It’s functioning not well. And it is giving you this pain with spasms.
– But the pain is not very intense.
But if I eat very often fatty food, after several days I will get nausea and sense of discomfort
and pain on both sides.
– Do you eat eggs?
– Yes.
– You like eggs?
– Normal. I can eat them.
– Do you eat them really or forget it?
– No I eat them.
– Every day one egg?
– No every day, it’s a lot.
Twice a week or something like that.
–If you eat egg there is a problem in the gallbladder?
– No. I have this tension of flatulence after eggs.
–After egg? Have you noticed this?
– Yes.
– After onions you have also flatulence or discomfort in the stomach?
What is that bothers you?
– It is not that after one onion I will have the pain but onion is one of the things
which I know I should not eat because if eat it for several days then I get this pain.
– If you eat it repeatedly.
– Yes.
– The onion… you like?
– The garlic?
– I like.
– But the onion if you eat it repeatedly will give you a pain or will give you distention?
– The pain, no distention.
– What else will give you distention or pain?
– I’m not sure but I think pastry gives me flatulence, sweet cakes.
I didn’t notice anything else but in general before arg-n I had a lot of gas, this is now better.
I have also very frequent eructations. That’s why you prescribed. Now it’s better.
It’s almost gone after arg-n.
– The urination has a smell?
–No it was many years ago. When it all started.
– Your urine was offensive.
– Yes.
– What kind of offensiveness? Do you know the urine of the horse? Have you ever smelled.
–No.
– Anyhow it was a heavy smell.
– It was strong, I don’t know if it was heavy but it was strong.
It was like sometimes I had a feeling that what I eat the smell is similar to what I eat.
I think quite often it was like some grains and especially like buckwheat if you know how it smells.
Sometimes it appears also now but it is no that heavy.
– So the tingling is the most and then some food which still disturb you…
Do you drink water a lot? You’re thirsty?
– Yes.
Before arg-n for many years I have drunk about 4 liters a day. I take big glass…
- Cold?
– Not very cold, normal. But I drink a lot.
But after this arg-n I drink quite less. The thirst is less.
– The tingling you feel it in the whole or in the fingers?
– The most is in the tips of the fingers but it starts on the wrists both hands. Both whole hands.
– Both hands but mostly on the tips or the whole?
– I think it depends, it changes. Fingertips are most.
It is not tingling. It is numbness. Like a rubber.
Sometimes I feel burning and sometimes it is just different. But it is also sometimes here.
– Right or left more?
– I think it started on the left.
– But when it started on the left? You remember?
– When I had this mononucleosis 10 years ago then I started homeopathy treatment
and during the homeopathic treatment after some time it started.
– Did you receive phos during that time?
– I don’t know. The homeopath had not told me. I don’t know.
But I had phos quite recently.
– After you took it yourself or somebody gave it to you?
– I can’t remember. Yes, somebody prescribed.
– I see that you have taken phos.
When you urinate have you noticed the urine to be fogged?
– It is not.
– Did you ever have any warts?
–Yes. All fingers. Here.
– You have a lot?
– Not now.
– You had. And how they disappeared.
– After some remedies. Ars.
– When did you take ars?
– 3 years ago.
– You perspire now?
– No very much.
– Your perspiration has a smell?
– No.
I perspire on the scalp very much before I started any homeopathy treatment.
– Before?
– Before I took any remedies I was perspiring very much on the scalp.
– In scalp or on the top?
– The whole hair.
– Before nit-ac or before arg-n?
– No 10 years ago.
– You perspired a lot.
– Yes after slightest exertion.
– Not now?
– Not now anymore.
– Do you desire something to eat? Do you have special desire?
– I like cheese, tomato sauce.
– Not tomato?
– I can eat but the sauce…
- You mean ketchup?
– Not very much. The real sauce.
– Not tomatoes?
– No I like tomato but not as much as the sauce. But I don’t like sauce in general.
– In childhood you had fear of the dark. How is that fear now?
– Well sometimes if I am alone in the dark I don’t feel comfortable but it is not a fear.
–Fear of ghosts?
– As a child. Now not so much.
– UFOs you are afraid of?
– Not now. As a child.
– Fear of dogs?
– As child now not anymore.
– Your mother is alive?
– Yes.
– You are still clinging to your mother?
– No. But as a child I was very much connected to her.
– Felt very bad in the summer camp longing for parents.
– Yes.
– Very sensitive to my parents quarreling, it was very dramatic.
Listening in the next room and waiting until they stop.
How much salt do you need? Normal? You put extra salt in your food?
– I don’t put salt before I taste. I always taste first. I like a little bit more.
I don’t know what’s normal but compared to my girlfriend I take more.
– Sweets?
– Yes.
– More than salt?
– The same. I like sweets.
– You were never infected with venereal diseases?
- No.
- How is your psychological state now? How would you describe it?
– For some years I have been quite… not relaxed… tense.
I am quite anxious about myself, about my health.
–About your parents?
–No.
– You say also in your childhood you were compelled to harm yourself
putting wire into the plugs.
– Yes I had such impulses.
– “I did not do it. Got frightened, what a silly idea I had.
One day I felt into the glass table and injured myself and a piece of glass dug into my back,
ended up in the hospital. Important it was the reason why it happened. I was compelled to do it.
To fall into the glass.”
– Not fall. I was walking on it, as a child. But I knew that the glass was thin and it could break.
– It broke and you fell down?
– I knew it can break…
- “ I used to stand on this table several times before.
When I got back from the hospital I was very happy that I was at home with my parents.
That evening I got a fever without any other symptom. And next day it was gone”.
Fever from fear.
– I know I was happy…
- “ I had otitis a few times, tonsillitis… hay fever…
In 10 years I remember having strange fear of death before going to sleep.” You still have it now?
–  No it was a kind of panic attack.
– Do you eat fruits?
– Yes.
– You like fruits?
–Tell me again the things that bother you. Onions?
– It is not only onions. It’s many things. But I can tell you…
– It’s the fatty things. This is the first.
– Yes.
– The second is…? The onions? Or you cannot say?
– I can’t say exactly. I can just say that if I’m on diet
which is supposed to be for patients with liver, gallbladder…
- Good food.
–Yes. Then I’m ok.
But some other foods… I have problems.
– But cheese you can eat as much? How much? Half a kilo?
– I never eat it much because I am afraid of…
- When you desire such of that you may eat…
- No I can’t have it 3 times a day. 3 times a day is too much. It’s not so strong.
– You have a girlfriend. Are you in love with her?
– Yes.
– You have strong feelings?
– Ok, good.
This case is an example of what I am going through every day
with hundreds of people I have undertaken.
He forgot his very low key but he said that “I’m dying” and I was so anxious I had to telephone him
because I could not get in touch.
I said “How are you? Are you still alive?” he said yes. I have a double problem;
the one is that I don’t have the patient when there is a follow up,
I do not have the patient to talk.
So whatever the patient is writing to me I respond. And this is not good many times.
But I try to do my best.
But this case has been complicated because of wrong treating mononucleosis.
Mononucleosis treated with antibiotics, it can destroy the organism.
And needs very good homeopathic treatment afterwards to replace the damage.
What happened with him the treatment was given it was totally wrong
and aggravated the whole situation. So it became very complicated case.
But still this is an example case that if you do the correct way
that means giving one remedy observing the reaction and the going according to the symptoms
there is a time when the organism even if it appears that your remedy is wrong
the reaction the organism is giving if the remedy is close enough in a case
which is complicated you cannot see the remedy if the remedy is close enough
eventually it will push the organism towards the right direction
and eventually you can see more clearly the remedy.
He was in a terrible state the moment I realized this is a nit-ac situation.
I believe the next day he says “I was much better”.
Where he could not eat at all he was totally exhausted the pain it was terrifying,
“what shall I do? I am not going to be alive.” And I am going through the same problem with him.
I believe that the effect on the nervous system it was created most probably he was given phos.
In the beginning after the mononucleosis.
I wanted to tell you something also about the yesterday case
when you did not agree and you said most of you this is a phos case. You remember?
So I have to tell you to be careful because if you don’t have symptoms strong for phos
and there is a kind of let us say a small ulcer and you give phos which is wrong it will bleed.
So if you give phos to this case yesterday with the several ulcers in the stomach lining
the next thing you get is bleeding and maybe strong bleeding and has to go to the hospital.
In such a case I would be very careful to have absolutely strong confirmatory symptoms.
Thirst. The thirst for cold water if the stomach is involved is necessary for you to prescribe phos.
The organism wants to control the bleeding and how controls the bleeding?
By taking in cold water so the arterioles are contracting, are not loose so it can break out
and then bleed.
Once you see that the organism needs the cold
because I don’t know what they do now in bleeding in the stomach
but the old time they used to put cold even outside in the stomach.
Ice. And cold… whatever they drink. Not hot. So if the person says “I have a stomach ulcer.
And I like warm water” forget it. Don’t give phos.
I didn’t want to scare you yesterday but I thought I have to tell you. Just to be careful.
Because you will find the person is in the hospital.
We have several possibilities. One, no remedy. That’s the best. Second. Repeat nit-ac.
Third possibility. Give another remedy. So which one you prefer? The logical thing in such case,
the best thing of course is to wait because he received a dose of 30CH, 2 months ago the last…
For the acute it doesn’t matter. The beautiful thing in his case is that he got back all the syndrome
that he went through 10 years ago.
That is very important showing that his health has improved tremendously.
So that is very important and it is best not touch the case.
Unless -which is the law- you have a clear picture of the remedy.
Then you can be justified, go ahead and prescribe it.
You saw the struggle I went through in this case, trying to find out which was the next remedy.
The computer did not help, I had 2 computers, we compared,
we tried to find out what this computer what the other computer I did not like anything…
It was showing both of them phos.
There is a possibility that later on he may need some phos but not now.
Now what is the remedy… Since he is here he has the opportunity he cannot come very easy.
Can you fly easy to Greece? No. So I have to give him a possibility.
So let us see, first I will show you the case analysis. Show me the symptoms.
Anxiety about health underlined 2 times, ticks, stomach fat, nausea after fat,
pain right hypochondria, numbness in the hand on writing, numbness on fingertips,
weakness upper limbs, eruptions in winter, put 3 times, fat aggravated, onions aggravates,
desires onions and if you ask for analysis see now what happens.
The analysis shows Lyc first, chel second, phos third, podo, nit-ac, ars, thuja, lept, nux-v.
Now change, go back to symptoms and change numbness hand on writing and put it 3 times
and also fingertips 3 times. Eruptions in winter 3 times. And show me.
Phos, zinc. Zinc has come up why? Explain zinc.
Zinc has some strong symptoms on the numbness and ticks and weakness in upper limbs,
is missing quite a lot. Ok then? Lyc, forget it. Rhus-t. Go down. Chel. Only 4.
The chel is interesting because he has the right hypochondria problem
which is the gallbladder in his case and also desire for cheese that was the first he said “I want”.
Also the numbness in the fingertips and weakness in the upper limbs.
So actually Chel covers his pathology the most.
Because chel is a specific remedy of course for gallbladder with a specific desire for cheese.
Actually his pathology now is something
which is due to lack of absorption of some microelements
which nourish the nervous system and that is forbidden by the gallbladder function.
The gallbladder function does not give the proper enzymes to have a better digestion and absorption.
Matter of fact.
I ask him if this pain is really extending somewhere and he it extends to the left
but sometimes deep inside appears extents to the back, not only around,
he says right behind to the back which again is in support of chel and gallbladder function.
So therefore what we may decide is to wait for six months
and if the gallbladder problem becomes really bothering and strong
then he may try with one dose of chel 30CH.
Also do not get the idea that homeopathy cannot do damage.
Homeopathy can also suppress a situation.
Do not think it’s so innocent.
- […] And he mentioned I think when he was answering your question
“My primary problem is still unresolved” and one of the primary problems he says
that he had it since childhood and that was ticks.
He also says all the investigation does not point anything significantly wrong with gallbladder.
So I am not able to understand why we are not looking at the primary problem
which is coming from the childhood as the gallbladder problem
is probably sluggish liver coming on the point he has lived life for so long
and digested a lot of toxins and he is not still on a diseased liver or a diseased gallbladder.
– No, it’s not complete. What I should look for?
– I don’t know. That’s why I’m here. I should learn from you.
–I did not understand your question you see that’s why I said what I should look.
I will give you an answer.
I do never imagine or project things, I take the facts and I base always the prescription on facts.
Because you can project in any patient anything you like, actually.
He’s this, he’s that, he has been this, he has been that but his actual symptoms
are pointing to certain remedies. You have to go by this.
When the time will come when the traumataic experience from childhood will come up
that means his subconscious whatever has kept inside has been freed to react
you will see another picture altogether which that picture may be ign picture, staph picture,
nat-m whatever.
So this traumatic experience in childhood will be nullified
but it the right time with the right remedy and with the right symptoms. You cannot force it.
- Are the ticks still present at the moment?
I seem to remember from the interview that you said “you try to hide them successfully”
but there are still there? Still now? The ticks, all this central nervous disturbance?
– Are still yes.
– So my question will be why don’t we put this as well strong in the…
- It’s not the time for the ticks. The ticks belong to earlier
even beyond the problem of the gallbladder.
If we fix this then the reason of having the ticks may appear.
I am not sure we can actually eliminate that level so deep. I am not sure but we will try. But not now.
Ok, good night.
What I wanted to make clear is that with the example of the case we saw yesterday,
the follow-up; what we have seen; we prescribed first bac, aggravation, no amelioration.
Second remedy lyc, aggravation, no amelioration.
Third remedy… he’s aggravated and he sends me a report and in the report
I realize there are some changes which are interesting and then I said ok,
I see he is very sensitive and he is in a very precarious state,
I say very careful take arg-n 9CH once a day or three times a day I can’t remember
and with one dose he takes there is a big aggravation and brings out a syndrome
that was there 10 years ago suppressed by antibiotics.
We know that when an old state of health comes back that was suppressed
that is the best thing can happen to your patient.
That means the organism goes back 10 years ago
and finds itself in the same immunological state in which he was 10 years ago.
But due to antibiotics and to the suppression his whole health was really damaged.
After the suppression 10 years ago he starts taking homeopathic remedy.
After a while he starts with neuropathy.
What is due to the suppression by the antibiotics
and how much the wrong homeopathic treatment has helped?
Comes here to me after 10 years of 20-30 remedies maybe 100 remedies
usually they don’t say all the remedies and he comes and says “Help me. Solve the case."
Is it possible to find a remedy straightaway that will cure the whole case?
Wait I want to make you aware because it’s very important to understand this
and you can appreciate what to do.
So what you know after the reaction of the remedy that this remedy arg-n has done a lot good for him
but now he is in an even worse state than before. Because he has a high fever, he’s destroyed,
he feels that he cannot eat, he cannot sleep the whole night, he’s painful etc.
He sent me the case and now I remember I sent him a wrong remedy
which we did not mention yesterday Hep, no? Lach.
Becomes even worse and then I spoke with him and realize that the remedy is nit-ac.
He takes now the nit-ac which is the treatment for the acute that has developed.
So on the chronic condition it was arg-n which helped.
Developed an acute which has to be treated homeopathically now. I was arguing with him.
He said “I don’t know if it is…whether it is just tonsillitis…”
He gets the nit-ac and within 3-5 hours the pain starts reducing,
the fever goes down and the next he’s much better and a few days later much better.
Now what we have done, we have treated, we have brought back the organism to the age 23.
He has some numbness still.
And he has ticks which have started long time ago when he was a child since 6 years old
when he was receiving all these stresses because of the mother and father conflict.
Actually the problem that we have here is whether in order to help him further
to reach the level of health at 6 years old when he developed the ticks
because his organism could not tolerate the grief looking at his parents.
Before do we need to repeat arg-n for instance? Do we have enough symptoms at this moment,
2 months after nit-ac, do we have a clear picture?
Or do we have in order to progress with the case to repeat nit-ac or to give another remedy
that will complete the action of nit-ac
and then let the organism progress with the symptomatology of the ticks
and the nervous condition?
In order to have a new picture that we can treat which can go deeper.
So with homeopathy this is something which amazes me, always.
The laws and order that there is in the organism if you stimulate properly the organism.
There is an order that we know with information we have that this order should be like this
and if you know that then only you can tackle such cases.
If you don’t know the theory quite in depth forget evaluating what has happened to your patient.
You will give one remedy, then another… no real, deep changes in the organism.
On this occasion I will remind you of the case of the Turk. Now see the order in his organism.
He is a healthy person but with hereditary weakness he gets stress.
Then his stomach starts paining.
What kind of pain? Looks like gastritis, too much acidity and therefore some burning.
But why is not a simple gastritis and when they examined him they find 8 little ulcers?
I call it that is a Barrett syndrome according to my understanding.
Much more serious condition than just a simple gastritis.
He wants to get some relief and he gets some blockers
and you don’t allow the stomach to release and the organism needs another release.
And then he starts discharge from the nose and then you choose a remedy
that stops the discharge from the nose
and you think that the discharge from the nose has stopped, I have done a good job.
You’ve done a bad job.
You just gave a local remedy that stopped the detonation of the organism.
And then it keeps on giving anti-acids, treat it 3-5 years anti-acids, the organism is pressurized
and has to find another outlet. And most probably starts with the hernia and then the neurinoma.
You prescribe a remedy, what you should expect?
The normal thing that you should expect is that one of the first things
that will be released is the last that has appeared.
So he will start sleeping much better and his back… Not the stomach immediately.
The stomach it’s deep, it’s an ulcer. Is a problem which is much deeper but the hernia
which I believe is small still is touching the nerve but a little bit just…
The remedy will act will take back the hernia by 1mm or less and there is going to be a release.
Eventually the cure should go.
When he will say “I had an aggravation” the aggravation may not be here,
may be in the stomach from your remedy so by the time he has an aggravation in the stomach
this will be released because now the stomach is free to let out what the organism needs to let out.
I wanted to make clear of what is going on with these examples.
When you prescribe an homeopathic remedy.
The idea is when you give a remedy and you have an aggravation, you say stop the aggravation.
Just observe what is manifesting the organism now as a new picture and prescribe accordingly.
And if you do that and of course you know Materia Medica
and of course I am helped with the computer.
Nobody believes that I have everything in my mind. You believe it I can see it. It’s wrong.
It is not possible.
You have to look on the repertory, I have to look in the Materia Medica all the time to confirm
that I am not making a mistake. Of course I am wrote Crotalus cascavella
because I knew the picture and the picture was this woman, it was very characteristic,
I had seen it before and I had perceived it but then I wanted to see the repertorization
and I said “My god” cascavella was coming second remedy.
Now I feel more calm, more secure.
About arg-n.
- Although he was in a lower level of health you prescribed a high potency. Can you tell us why?
- I did not really. I gave 200CH really.
- I’d like to ask a question related to the case.
Let’s say we reach a point where we are back to age 6 and we get rid of the ticks
which developed when he was 6.
And in 2 years time for some reasons he takes antibiotics because the doctor prescribed
or he takes antibiotics…
- The ticks will be back.
If we had not reached that state
and if he takes now antibiotics the damage is not going to be very big
but definitely he is going to bring more depression, more anxiety, bring it down all his immune system.
Not only with antibiotics. With the wrong medicines.
I want to give you an example.
I was treating for 4 years a very rich American man who was told that he should go to dialysis
because of his creatinine, it was high, his kidneys were breaking down.
Anemia was very severe, the K was very high, it was a bad state.
I started treating and I treated him for 4 years.
I went to America, because of him I went 2 time, just to see him physically.
I treated him for 4 years.
Creatinine went down not completely gone, anemia was better, he was better…
Through telephoning me for 4 years almost once a day. Once a day he would give me a report.
I had enough. He felt secure. “I had a pimple here”. I said “Ok, forget it”.
But he would keep me for almost half an hour every time. It was unbelievable.
I said to my secretary “Write him a letter and tell him, for every call he would have to pay 500$”.
I never heard from him anymore. He did not telephone. I said thank God.
He thought because he knew exactly when he was telling me these symptoms
the remedy I prescribed was that.
He thought “now I know myself what I have to take”. I knew what was going to happen but I said ok.
After 6 months I received a call. “I’m in a terrible state. I have this, I have that.
My creatinine level has risen, my anemia is worse. Please save me. Money is not an issue.”
Now money was not an issue. I said “Now the issue is me.
In your place I’ve taken up another patient.
I cannot continue. So you go to another homepaths.
There are some homeopaths in New York.”
And in another 3 months he was in dialysis.
For 4 years you have been told to be immediately in the dialysis, for 4 years I was keeping him
and they thought by taking all kinds of remedies… the whole thing came back…
he did not take any antibiotics, just took a lot homeopathic remedies,
wrong remedies at the wrong time and the whole thing collapsed.
What I tell you is not a theory, it’s really an experience which I have for the last 52 years.
- Can I say something? Let’s say he ruins and then start treating him again.
Will he develop the tonsillitis that he had?
-No. Tonsillitis is cured now. It won’t come back…
Not that he may not get an acute but the kind of tonsillitis…
this was not a tonsillitis this was an abscess in the tonsils, so severe.
Maybe infectious mononucleosis is a quite serious condition.
People may also leave this world and go for the next world if it is not treated properly.
So it’s a serious condition. This condition, it will not come.
Because he has been treated now homeopathically and the organism got rid of that.
It will not suppress this time.
- Antibiotics will not suppress him?
-No antibiotics will not unless he has an acute, he has an influenza and he takes antibiotics
because of the influenza.
His organism will go down but will never come back again with mononucleosis.
-The main complaint belongs to the nervous system
but you said right now we treat a problem of the gallbladder
which prevents him from absorbing certain elements which support the nervous system.
- Yes it appears. But I told him to wait 6 moths. Because in 6 months, if you wait,
you may have a totally different picture
unless there is a crisis with the gallbladder he can use the chel.
Otherwise he has to wait for at least 6 months.
You will be surprised by the differences you will see in 6 months because of nit-ac.
-My question was if in this case you will agree to recommend him taking some supplements
for the nervous system or if this will interfere with the case…
- I don’t do it. I’ll tell you the reason.
Because if I had given a supplement and then he comes back and gives me some symptoms
I don’t know if these symptoms are real or because of the supplement.
That means the picture is disturbed due to the supplements.
So when I’m treating Idon’t want to give supplements.
Later on if the treatment is quite ok, he wants to take some supplements
there is no problem but a sensitive organism if you give supplements will change the picture.
-In this case he understands the process but with somebody who does not understand
and is very worried about this I will have the tendency to give something.
-Bad luck.
The American man just because he was stingy he had bad luck.
He was terrified with the idea of going to the dialysis.
When I first met him, he said “I am going to the dialysis”, he was paralyzed with fear
and he ended up because he thought “No, I don’t need George”.