-Tell me what is the main problem.
-The main problem is tobaccoism and obesity of course as secondary problem
because every time I try to quite up smoking.
I gained many many kilos in a few time.
Maybe in a month or two I can gain more than 10 kilos. Not for eating more quantity.
-Same food and you put on weight.
-Yes.
-Immediately. With tobacco. Cervical ailments.
-There was a problem and because of that I was not coming to Greece.
Because it was very painful. But thank God I find an osteopath and he put my…
-Straight.
-Yes and was perfect.
Because with a lot of paraesthesia and pain. I couldn’t work, I was rigid for many days.
-This was the first time that happened?
-No.
That big picture yes as I told you but from my childhood until now
it’s very frequent for me to have this kind of contractors and pain.
-You mean cervical region?
-Yes.
At the end it’s all paraesthesias in my feet, had paraesthesias in the hand,
paraesthesias in different parts…
-You mean contracture?
-No. It is the sensation of… formication…
-Numbness.
-Some times sensitive-less.
-How is your spine?
-It was contracted. Because…
- Did you have an x-ray?
- No, MRI.
First I had the atlas displaced, the whole of the head was like this with the atlas.
That was the problem when they put it ok in one day I was  fantastic like never…
And every day better and better… Until I get clear. I only have remaining here.
The sensation…
- But before this crisis of the cervical… you were feeling good?
- I think I had emotional concerns. This kind of crisis.
First it was contraction and it aggravated the mechanical problem.
- Because of emotional problems.
- Yes.
Every time I get disappointed or frustrated I become very contracted.
I am rigid to this kind of things and I react against that.
- Disappointed. You mean emotionally?
- Yes.
- Mostly or only emotionally?
- Everything is emotional for me.
- You have aversion to alcohol? Since many years.
- Yes, since I was born.
- You lack an enzyme, most probably. Mother died 58, breast cancer and father 70 years old.
But you had pancreatitis?
- When I was a child.
Because my sister had measles and at that time I made a pancreatitis.
- Chronic eczema. Where?
- I have it here. Lateral of the fingers.
- Between the fingers.
- And in the feet too.
- And you had warts?
- Yes I have some look. Like this…
- Mumps at 18 years old. Cyst in the ovary. When did you find this? What age?
- I found it when I began studying medicine. I think 20 years ago.
- Do you have children?
- No I don’t.
- You are married?
- No I’m not.
- Why?
- I don’t know. You tell me.
I didn’t find a person or he didn’t find me or I’m too difficult person.
- But you had some affairs?
- Yes. Not many.
I had one big relationship 10 years ago. And it lasted 10 years.
- What kind of relation?
- He was my boyfriend but we lived together.
- You didn’t marry.
- Yes we never got married.
- But you never had sex?
- Yes! I had.
- When did you start having sex?
- 22-23 years old maybe 24.
- Were you infected by any of these partners?
- No, I don’t think so.
- You have a strong personality.
- Yes.
- Most probably. And men do not like it.
- They don’t. And I cannot change it.
- Is this the reason?
- I think so.
- Syndrome Stein- Leventhal.
- This is because of the multiple cysts.
- This prevented you from becoming pregnant or you always…
- I think so because I didn’t use any anti-conceptive method within 10 years
with this only partner. And after me he had a child so… I thought he was sterile.
But it was me probably.
- Gastritis still continues?
- Sometimes because now I am smoking again and because of the cigarette I have...
- Burning.
- Yes.
But especially with emotional detonants. I get angry, frustrated and then…
- Do you get very angry sometimes?
- Yes. Every day, every time, every minute of my life but…
- The remedies you have taken are sil…
- Sil was in my childhood.
- And polypharmacy?
- Yes.
My homeopath became holist and he gave me Bach flower, everything mixed.
- Merc, nux-v, con, nat-c. Only these remedies you have taken?
- Maybe some more but I don’t know then because partners of me were my doctors
and I didn’t want to know neither they told me about it.
Con was because of some syndrome. For 6 months I had some pathology in my breast.
My left breast, like my mother had. The diagnosis to my mother I made it myself
because nobody could tell that was cancer. I knew it was.
And it is a very strange kind of cancer.
It’s like erysipelas, inflammation, in the skin only.
And many biopsies… and nothing happened, many tomographies… nothing.
But I knew it was a cancer and finally I had it. For 6 months 3 years ago
I had this kind of symptom.
- The same thing.
- Yes and then I asked an homeopath in that time and she gave me con.
I didn’t know what I was taking before I came I learned it was con.
But in 6 hours it took that symptom away. I remember it. Most outstanding.
- There is a mass in breast, you feel? Or there is some hardening…
- No, nodules.
- No nodules. The area which is inflamed.
- No I think it was all the breast.
The skin was like orange. Like a kind of cellulitis and the nipple was always erected.
Every time, every day for 6 months.
- You are talking about your mother?
- No. My mother became like that and me too.
- And you had the same. And you are now 42.
- Yes but that was when I was 39.
- And this… Breast started when you were 39.
- But it went away with con.
I took the con I didn’t know what I was taking and in the afternoon I went to sleep.
Every night it was very painful to sleep for me because it hurt really.
And in the morning I was without anything. I couldn’t believe. And never came.
- Con helped you in general as well?
- Yes but I stopped taking it because of 2 things.
First, I developed a bronchospasm that I never had before.
And second I had a bad situation for me that was this burn-out syndrome.
I burned my head. And I couldn’t work, was so depressed and I stopped taking this,
I repertorized myself and then began with nux-v and this took me away from this symptom.
- Nat-c helped you?
- I took only 1 or 2 doses because I was like this as I told you before coming.
I didn’t want to take anything because I was coming here. But I think it helped me.
- Have you taken Ign?
- Never. Not even when my mother died.
- Did you cry with your mother?
- A lot. I still cry.
- You can drink milk?
- Yes I can.
- You like.
- I don’t like the most but I can.
- What do you like the most?
- The most? Meat. Cow meat only.
Not any type of meat. And salt. I put salt on everything. I eat salt with food not food with salt.
- Is so much?
- So much.
- What about sour?
- I like them. Not especially.
- You are affected by the sun?
- Yes. For good. Sun relives me.
It’s the only thing that keeps me healthy in mind and in body.
I need sun. So I get depressed every winter. If I don’t take long summer vacation…
- You live in Buenos Aires?
- Half in Buenos Aires, half in Montevideo, Uruguay. I work both sides.
- But in both countries there is a lot of sun.
- Yes there is. And in winter I come to Europe so I can…
- You live with your father now?
- No since I was 17 I live alone. For 10 years I lived with my partner / couple.
- You have bleeding hemorrhoids?
- Yes.
- And you have hypothyroidism confirmed.
- Yes only in the lab test.
- But you feel cold in general.
- I am very cold person.
- You never took calc?
- I don’t think so. Maybe in this blind… but I don’t remember.
- The polypharmacy…
- Yes.
- You feel cold in general or in the extremities?
- I always have the extremities cold and I feel cold and I cannot get warm.
For instance last night I was with the air conditioner in 30 degrees all night and 3 coats
and my pajamas and I was cold all the night.
- You put the air condition on warm.
- Always.
- So much cold. And do you sometimes perspire around this area.
- Not much. Maybe if I am exercising and it’s very warm maybe some…
- In sleep.
- No I don’t think so. I never get wet.
- You sleep with socks?
- Not now. For a time I was sleeping with socks.
- You have some fears?
- Yes.
Maybe storms, I don’t like rain either I feel awful. Before the storm…
- Because of the wetness or…
- I don’t know because it’s mental, emotional and physical.
Before rain comes I know in my hair, I know in my bones.
And every says in the TV it is going to be a sunny day and I say it’s going to rain
because I feel this anguish inside. I feel it will rain for sure.
I put my sign on it. Because my body and mind feels it’s coming.
- So you can be employed in the meteo…
- For sure.
- Have you checked your hormones to check how your testosterone is?
- It’s high.
- Very high?
- How do you know?
- I’ve been doing this 50 years.
- Yes, I’m sorry.
- When did you have this syndrome with the breast?
- It was 2008. I remember because my sister was about to get married and I was the godmother.
Because my mother wasn’t and she picked me for that.
And I started thinking that has something to do with this and my mother’s…
like choose… I don’t know.
- 2008. You said you had a relationship running 6-7 years by that time.
- 10 years ago. I ended it in 2000. From 1990-2000.
- That was the longest but after this .
- Nothing important. I couldn’t get in love again.
- That means you suppressed yourself as far as sexual desire concern…
- For sure. Cause I didn’t have sex.
- So you had to suppress yourself actually.
- Not in a conscious way but I was like… hypersexuality.
I used to be, that’s my tendency. I am very passionate in everything.
This has been in studies if you have much sex you need more
and if you have less you need less.
- The one that gave you the con knew that you did not have sex for several years?
- I don’t know.
- Do you remember if you told her or she just gave you…
- No she gave me not for that. She gave me the con because of the breast symptom
and because I had a horrible syndrome because to be more concentrated
and for everything I had to play on the computer. Any kind of playing. I need that.
- You need to play in order to concentrate.
- Many teachers got offended by me because during the class I played solitaire.
Many people here laughed at me when they saw me but I need that.
When a patient is very difficult I put the solitaire.
- What is this solitaire?
- The card play they have it in Windows. But any kind of play.
I need to play…
- In order to concentrate.
Do you sometimes have clairvoyant…
- No I don’t think so. Only with my mother thing…
- Is there any other fear? Fear of the dark?
- Not of the dark. Fear of all kinds of insects, the flying ones and the spiders.I can die.
If you put me that kind of butterfly that eats clothes, that are bigger,
I don’t know if you have it here I can die.
Many times I walk outside of my home in the middle of the night
and  I stay until some neighbor comes and kills it because I can die. Spiders also.
I am very afraid of spiders. And I cannot watch horror movies. I don’t like.
I get very frightened.
- Sweets, you like?
- I like not mostly. I cannot eat without salt. That’s for sure.
- Have you checked your blood pressure?
- Yes. It’s always low. Very. 70 top.
90 if I have hypertension. 70 is the max.  I have 70-90/60 or 50.
- Have you ever had fainted?
- No. Never. I don’t remember.
- Have you taken calc?
- I don’t think so.
- Phos?
- Yes phos because I injured myself with a patient with blood,
of course not wanted to, it was an accident and I began to take the drugs in the hospital
they obliged me to.
It was awful and I called my homeopath and said “What can I do
because I will not take these.”
And he gave me a lot of homeopathic remedies one for Tuesday, one for Wednesday…
And one of them was Phos.
- Stram?
- I don’t think so.
- Verat?
- Carb-v?
- I don’t think so.
- You like smoked meat?
- No smokes. I like asado.
In Argentina they make it on fire but not the smokey taste. I don’t like it.
- You had always headaches but now you have only before menses?
- Yes.
- How is your menses?
- It was very Irregular.
They are very long lasting in time. Maybe 12, 14 days menses.
In this period I have very small quantity in the beginning and at the end
and I have 5 or 7 days with a lot of blood.
- Nat-m?
- I was thinking of it. I never took it.
Thinking of it before nat-c and because of that I took nat-c for this contraction.
- Your sleep is good?
- Lately I think I am not sleeping too much.
I am activating at night and of course I have to wake up early
but if I could run on I will… for sure I will sleep more.
- Your companion was from the same country as you are?
- Argentina yes.
- But you are not an Argentinian?
- I was born in Argentina but my origin is… My father Lebanese, my mother Italian.
- A very explosive mixture.
- I know. My friends suffer it.
- When was it the last time you had a high fever?
- High fever, more than 38 you mean,
Long, long time ago.
- Do you go to the sea? You like the sea?
- Very much. It’s my life. It gives me life. I need the sea.
- Have ever taken med?
- No.
- The position you sleep?
- I think it’s mostly left side.
- But you can sleep in other position?
- Yes I can sleep even in the abdomen.
- Do you eat fruits?
- I have to eat it. I never prefer.
- Pork you don’t eat because of the…
- I don’t like it.
- Because of religion?
- No because I don’t like it. But I eat ham, it’s from pork.
- You write here multiple keratosis actinic.
-This you cannot see because I have it well covered but I have a lot here.
- Are they like warts?
- First brown spots, then they become higher.
- Excrescences.
- Yes this kind of things.
Here you do not see all but I have it in all my body.
- Not warts really?
- They call it dermo… dermatologically speaking.
But mostly they beginning from actinic keratosis I think. It’s from the sun.
Because I like so much the sun and I never take care…
- Have you shown it to a dermatologist?
- Yes.
- Is any of the malignant?
- No but of course he’s that I have to take care and I don’t.
- Do you have brothers or sisters?
- Yes I have 2 sisters. One brother.
- They are married?
- All of them.
- My brother he has a boyfriend. He is going to get married next year.
- But they don’t worry that you don’t get married?
- I don’t think. I think are more afraid of me.
We don’t have nowadays a good relationship with my family.
Neither with my father nor with my brother and sister.
- You are easily excitable. Easily getting mad.
- I get mad easily because of strong causes.
For instance I felt betrayed by my family. I tell you one example. There are a lot.
One example is my mother died 10 years ago I signed to give to them everything
only I would have a small flat in Buenos Aires in which I live but there were more things.
I left to them in exchange for that because I wasn’t interested in having anything.
This was 10 years ago. Now they are asking me to give them the money of this small flat.
So injustice for me. Not only for me, for the others.
There’s so much indignation that comes to me that I can kill.
- From the fruits which one would you say “I like the best”?
- Strawberries, orange and tangerine. I eat pears. And stop counting.
I eat the others but I like these. Because I have to.
I don’t like grapes, I don’t like bananas, like tropical fruits not…
- Ok.
- Ok? I go?
- You’re free.
- Thank you.
Ok we have to speak about this case, this nice Argentinian- Lebanese case.
Many of you know the remedy. I want to see who knows the remedy. Only one?
No, I don’t believe it.
Who knows the remedy? You are shy, you are afraid if you say the remedy
and then it’s not correct then you will have a problem.
No, you will not have a problem. The idea is when someone thinks of a remedy
to know the reasons why he proposed that remedy.
He can say “I think the remedy is this because of this and that reason”.
If you say it like this you are always ok.
In homeopathy unfortunately we do not have the absolute tool through
which we can say “this is the remedy, basta!” We don’t have such a possibility.
Always there is a possibility of a mistake.
So what we are saying is the most probable remedy. Lyc. Yes? Med.
Who says lyc? Who agrees with him. Nobody agrees with him. Who agrees with med? Ok.
Who agrees with lach? Who agrees with phos? Who agrees with nat-m?
Very strange because she says she eats salt with food.
So, such a strong desire for salt should make you think of nat-m.
Yet I see very few of you support this idea. Most of you supported the idea of med.
Perche? Porquois? Why? Because she said that she enjoys very much the sun.
She is cold and when she goes to the sun, the sun is giving life.
This you will almost never hear from a person who really needs nat-m.
She needs a lot of salt. That means her organism does not absorb salt.
So whatever quantity is, she can take, it goes out. Otherwise with such salt…
No, you tell me, why I say this?
If the salt was absorbed, what would be different than what she said? The blood pressure.
You see her blood pressure is very low, unnaturally low.
And yet she takes a lot of salt and the blood pressure remains low.
That means almost nothing of salt is absorbed.
The organism needs salt, especially the nervous system to produce…
but she cannot absorb it.
That’s why when she goes to the sea with the salt which is all over the body,
she says “I feel rejuvenated”. So she is cold, she is better in the sun, better in the sea.
A passionate woman, has passions.
When I asked her “Just tell me the fruit” she told me “I don’t like fruit”.
But what she likes? She mentioned oranges. She does not like fruit but oranges are ok. Why?
Med is interested in oranges especially? Sour mostly.
But the chemistry of her body is not the typical chemistry.
There is a reason why we eat certain things, why I desire bread or salt or sweets etc.
It doesn’t matter we may not know the chemistry of the body to understand the real reason
and the complication of the biochemistry within the body.
But definitely in her case it’s obvious. She cannot absorb natrum chloratum.
She cannot absorb it.
And maybe she can absorb and be better if she is sunk in the sea through the pores.
So she needs something of that type.
But we know med is rejuvenated in the sea. We know med has desire for salt.
It’s one of the remedies which has desire for salt. I’ll show you the symptoms.
What remedy is coming?
Also, I forgot.
How do you explain the fact that con acted so well and did not touch the general condition?
Because of the suppression of her hormones.
But why con acted only locally? Con was correct or not correct? Correct.
But con acted without any aggravation. Immediate amelioration.
It acted as a remedy for an acute.
What she was having was a kind of a superficial thing happening upon her constitution.
We have said many times, we explained in the course how you have the basic constitution,
basic remedy, 1,2,3 layers but there is an acute and there is a layer on top which is formed.
In her case this was what happened due to the suppression
and not expression of her hormonal system the organism reacted.
How? In a place where she is most sensitive. So that is a sensitive area for her.
If in somebody the sensitive area is the guts, the colon, he will have a diarrhea.
If the sensitive area is the respiratory he will have a sinusitis,
bronchitis or laryngitis or pneumonia.
If the sensitive area is the liver the expression will be through that sensitive area.
So for her the sensitive area due to hereditary reason from her mother is this area.
The breast.
That’s why con acted as if you have a cold or an influenza or a diarrhea or a cystitis,
you take a remedy, the cystitis is gone but the basic organism is untouched.
So it needs a remedy in order to lift the first layer.
She took several remedies that did nothing actually. The first layer to be lifted is,
in her case, med. She has enough information in her case for med.
Which is this information? You remember? Tumors in the ovaries, coldness of extremities.
It is very interesting in beef steak, in the repertory has been noted med
is one of the remedies for desire for beef.
Salt desire, obesity, desire for tobacco, approach of a storm is another point.
She is worse on the approach of a storm which is also covered.
Phos, also, yes. Phos was also a possibility.
You remember I made a remark to her about testosterone?
I said you must have very high testosterone.
How did I get it? From the way she spoke.
She was like that… No, lyc. Stram, yes but no lyc.
- I think that desire for beef should be out of the repertorization
because in Argentina is very common.
- Ok, we take it out. We take it out, see what happens.
The result will be the same. She does not agree.
Argentinians are eating mostly what? Sheep.
- Is part of the regular diet in Argentina but not all the persons in Argentina eat meat.
- But she said it very strongly that “I have desire and it’s the only desire for meat.”
That you can use it actually because she said it so strongly.
It is different than “I like beef”.
“I desire beef and this is the only meat I like. All the other meat, I don’t”
then you maybe use it as a symptom. Ok tumors in ovaries.
And a lot excrescences coming out with little tumors, let’s say tumors, in her body.
After you have this picture you can fit it with her character, with her makeup,
where she says “I am a passionate person.
When I love, I love with passion”. That is a characteristic of med, as you know.
So, we give med and we take away the passion.
She will become less reactive, more calm and the next remedy underneath
most probably will be calc.
It means after med the feeling of coldness will stay,
the desire for salt will be much less, the desire for sweets
which she does not have now will be increased.
The feet will remain cold, the fear of high places will remain,
I don’t know if it was there.
And also the sensitivity to changes of weather, especially to wet weather will remain.
But she will be on another level.
The potency will be 200CH one day and 1M the next day.
But get it from a good pharmacy, it is very important.
For the guy who said that beef is not a symptom; we took it out.
Still med is coming first.
What is not typical for med in her case, is the fact that she feels the cold so much.
It’s not typical for med that she feels the cold so much as she describes.
But the coldness from the second remedy which is underneath,
which may be phos, calc-p, calc, may be one of these remedies.