It is a meeting place of the whole world here.
Usually with the idea of coming together and bringing peace to the world.
Because the world is in a terrible state at the moment. And we need peace really.
And homeopathy is the most peaceful medicine as you know.
So I believe you heard by Eric an overall picture of the levels of health
and this was an idea which I conceived back in the 70s and I wrote the first things
about this idea in my book “The Science of Homeopathy” that was published in 1978.
After that this idea became more and more clear
and today I can say that maybe we can answer most of the questions
that a medical person may have.
So I believe that you will be having some questions that we can be discussing.
I don’t want to give you some theories. I want to see what is your idea about the levels of health.
How you perceive them , how you understand them
and how you think it’s applicable to medicine in general.
So I’d like to hear your questions. And I will try to answer.
-I cannot yet understand how you can have cancer in level 1, for instance.
Because I think it is an immunological disease and if you are in level 1
you have enough health not to have cancer.
- That’s a good question. This levels of health idea, it’s coming from experience,
not from a theory which I conceived. How came that this idea that level 1 can have cancer?
Back in the 1970s I was giving a class with Greek doctors so one of my students
brought a case he was working in a hospital and he said
“This man – 75 years old or something like that.
I can’t remember exactly the age but progressed age-  has constant cough.
He’s in our hospital and never mind what we give him the cough continues.
So I would like to tell you the case so you can prescribe and maybe I can give him a remedy”.
So he read the case and I said “Peter, I am afraid this man has cancer of the lungs”.
He said “why?”. I tell you the story what he told me.
This man 70 something living in a kind of village in Greece.
Few people there he had an affair with a much younger married woman of the village.
They had an affair that was secret.
At the certain moment the affair was disclosed and everyone in the village
knew that this man had an affair with that married woman.
In the analysis of the case I said to him “Peter, did you ask him when this started?”
and then he told me that story. He said it started after the revelation of this love affair.
Men of the villages, usually healthy people without much history behind
and he was not smoking, good organism… So all this made me believe that the shock,
there was a shock in the life of this person, so strong that his organism could not overcome it
and as an outlet developed this tumor in the lungs.
I said this is why I say that this man has cancer. I am talking about 1970-1971.
And homeopathy was new in Greece but still I had a lot of medical people studying under me.
So Peter he said “Wait a moment“, he went to another room opened his bag
and he pulled out the X-ray and came back with the X-ray now
and said “Yes, that is true. He has cancer.”
So the case was a clear Sulphur case and what I realized by that time was
that even very healthy person who did not have a lot of drugs before,
who had not damaged his health very deeply, even such a person
if he is faced with a strong stress he may develop cancer
but the difference will be that in such cases the cancer is curable.
The cancer of the level 1 is curable, why?
Because the organism gives a clear picture of the remedy
and the immune system is in good condition and can overcome it.
This is the reason why you may have heard especially from India,
people of India are of this type,like the villagers,
clean from medication, chemicals, so strong organisms
and the Indian homeopaths they have a lot of such cases cured.
And once the see 1-5 cases cured they get the idea that homeopathy cures cancer
so they start advertising here we cure cancer and people come… It’s not we cure cancer.
We cure cancer of the 1st level. Once the cancer develops in levels 7,8,9 forget the cure.
Also, you may have heard that there was a spontaneous remission of cancer, like a miracle.
Somebody goes to a spiritual person and he prays to his Buddha, God, Christ, whatever
and the cancer stops, even cured. Cancer level 1, all these cases.
You see, so, what happens is that the stress we can take we can manage with a stress.
That means the organism can work out the stress.
You see, because you lost your loved ones, your erotic companion… Ah, big shock.
Then what you try to do, you try mentally and emotionally to overcome the issue.
And you try, you think different ways.
“He was not worth it”, “He was telling lies”, “He was a liar, he was a terrible person.
Forget it. I want to forget him.”, this kind of thinking.
And the organism overcomes this through the process finally
and you don’t get the effect of the stress.
But there are some other organisms that never mind how much how much logic,
how much excuses they cannot overcome it.
The moment the organism says “I cannot overcome it” now has to find an outlet.
Now, what the outlet can be… The organism has 2 possibilities.
That means I cannot overcome it, that means the effect is going to stay in the body.
The organism finds which is the weakest point in the organism and the whole stress is directed
towards breaking down that organ which is the weakest
and then the effect will be from developing a serious chronic disease or even cancer.
That’s one outlet, physical body.
The second outlet – you know what it is- mental derangement.
They cannot face the facts so they have to find an outlet.
So mental derangement, that means the organism leads the mental state in such a condition
so cannot think anymore.
Develops tremendous panic attacks, develops serious mental problems,
sometimes goes to schizophrenia, goes to total confusion of the mind so the organism,
has not the possibility anymore to face the stress because is an another state altogether.
Not in his logical mind. Now, see how this is connected with the suicides
which take place after love disappointment, after any shock.
The moment the person cannot face the problems goes and jumps.
The moment that jumps that this the moment of madness, of total craziness.
The moment has reached the point of self-destruction
and the idea is if you want to think a little bit deeper, the idea is always in such cases
that the organism wants to destroy itself.
You must have heard that the autoimmune diseases – the conventional idea-
is the organism against himself. Killing it’s own self. This is the idea, why?
The organism could not face certain problems in life.
You will have also to understand that the idea of self-destruction, what is behind it?
“I am not worth it. I’m nothing. I am not a person who should live in this world etc…”
You have to be very careful now here. Who will say this?
We try to go to the deepest issue the one who says “I’m not worth living”, who will say it?
What is behind? A traumatized ego.
Self-importance that was there before and now is destroyed.
What could be the cure of a expanded ego? What is the opposite? A person how can overcome it?
A person whose ego says “They don’t recognize me, the world does not recognize my values,
therefore it’s not worth for me  living in this world, so I just commit suicide or…
It doesn’t matter, the idea is self-destruction.
So the idea that I am important person which appears to be a valid idea
or an idea acceptable it is this very idea that can destroy the person.
I  am important and something has happened, my wife left me. I am important
and they kick me out of my job.
I am important and they have behaved very bad to me etc. What would be the cure?
Everybody understand of course. The cure is the acceptance of your own inability.
This is the cure. Accepting that I am not such a big homeopath that can cure everything.
Because if I had this idea, I am big homeopath, I can cure everything and everybody come…
Every time there is a failure I will have a big problem.
Oh my god, I could not cure him. Even that simple.
If you expect that you are the best in your job and you believe it
and then proves that this is not so then you are running for a big problem.
So I want to connect this with the idea of the levels.
Now, in the level 1 we have an organism which is very balanced, that means very healthy.
These people are not running this danger I am talking about.
The organism now starts getting weaker and weaker and comes down the levels.
So, as the organism goes down more and more what happens?
The ego becomes bigger and bigger to balance the inefficiencies of the organism.
So actually the people who are having an exaggerated ego are the people
who are having some deficiencies in several areas because of bad health.
If you are a runner, a champion and suddenly you have some problem
and you cannot be anymore the champion and you look to others how fast they are running
you may be going crazy imagining that I am still the champion. And then you need a remedy.
With the imagination replacing what is missing due to the bad health.
So, wait, I will connect it with another idea. The idea of suppression.
You know the idea of suppression, I have a pain and I want to suppress the pain.
I don’t want the pain.
The idea of suppression comes when the ego trying to balance under the circumstances
which are difficult because of the loss of health they try to excuse and finally to hide the symptoms.
I will give you an example.
Somebody comes to the homeopath and you investigate the case and you take all the symptoms
and then you come to the mental/emotional sphere. How you are emotionally? I’m well.
And you can see he is not well, but his thought is “I am well”.
But he has forgotten the mental/emotional state when he was really healthy with joy,
with happiness enjoying things.
Now does not enjoy anything is just in a state of a state “I am just existing”
but that state does not bother him anymore.
Why? Because he has suppressed the symptom which should bother him, he has accepted
and he has suppressed the symptomatology.
So, once the level comes down the cry of the organism through the symptoms is not anymore.
The organism does not cry. The patient I mentioned should come to you
and tell you “My main complaint is not the knee which is painful,
my main problem is that I’ve lost the ability to have joy.” But has covered it.
When a healthy person wakes up in the morning always there is happiness it’s another day,
enjoying nature, enjoying everything that is around.
If you have lost that and you wake up in a depression, eventually,
you forget about the old state when you were a child when you were jumping with happiness.
That was the real healthy state. When you were a child.
What happened? You took the antibiotics, you too the vaccination, you took the stresses of life
and you come to a point where you don't want to face your own problems.
And the homeopath must read through the lines, must look at the eyes and see the sadness,
see the anxiety, see the depression, see the panic, the fears…
And then you have to handle it in order to get the information
what this organism would have said if he had come to you and it was recently that he was very happy
and now he lost his happiness. He would have say “I’m depressed, I’m anxious, I’m angry”.
You see the anger, you say:
“Are you angry?
–No
–Are you depressed?
–No”.
What is this? This is a hiding. It’s a suppression that has been done through our mental ability.
So the suppression that is done through your own automatic systems that are inside
and there is a suppression also done through chemicals.
So when the health has come down to levels, whatever disease imbalance is manifesting
in lower levels do not give enough symptoms for you to prescribe. That is the problem.
If an organism is depressed, depressed, depressed… ten years of antibiotics every day
and the person comes to be treated by you do you believe you can find symptoms?
No, all suppressed. So, if you really understand this theory you will be able to really diagnose
what is going on with a patient.
When you see a patient you’ll understand he’s very sick,
he’s not so sick though he has the same problems, cancer,
but no so sick and cancer but, yes, curable. See the difference.
Ok, you can ask some more questions. What I said today, I’ve never said before.
I don’t remember saying the same things before. So what happens actually,
it depends on your intelligence if you put a question that rings a bell in me
to stimulate me to speak. Otherwise I can give you very simple answer.
Somebody wanted to talk?
-I’d like to ask a practical question, down-to-earth question.
Do you believe that there is more than one remedy at a certain time
that is capable of producing a curative reaction?
-Yes, I’ll repeat your question in order to make it clear to everybody.
You’re asking whether, at a certain moment, there are several remedies
that may have the same effect. My answer is no.
There is a possibility that a close remedy can have an effect.
But the real, central remedy will have a totally different sense in the perception of the person
who receives the correct remedy. His whole organism is rejuvenated. It’s different.
I, myself could not find my remedy.
You see I started homeopathy at the age of 27, I am 80 now, about 53 years.
I could not find my remedy. I would prescribe close remedies to myself.
Somebody [would say] “I don’t believe you”. I’ll tell you it different.
For all acutes, because I’ve never taken any chemical drugs for all my life,
but I had several acutes and severe acutes… all the acutes I managed with Homeopathy
without problem and then if you don’t get the right remedy by that time…
I remember one case I just say it quickly I was vomiting blood and stool with blood
because of poisoning of the organism, tremendous poisoning
and I was a terrible state and I took one remedy of course that didn’t act ,
the second didn’t act, the third remedy acted, cut down the whole thing.
And many times it’s like that.
When I start having an acute I cannot find immediately the first remedy, the second remedy…
but you see the first remedy will bring some changes and then eventually
if you’re not afraid of dying and you know Homeopathy then you’ll always manage.
This is my experience, that’s why I’m still alive.
Because I had a lot of opportunities to die in my life.
But I’ve decided if God wants me to die, I will die but I refuse to go to the hospital,
I refuse to take allopathic drugs. It’s ok.
So if you wait long enough the picture of the organism will manifest the remedy.
But if you start taking allopathic drugs, take some antibiotics you suppress it.
The organism, it is unbelievable perhaps
but with few antibiotics may be totally suppressed a situation
that will never be freed even with good homeopathic remedies.
I had a case of a child 5 year old he had severe pneumonia and was going to die.
He took antibiotics. After that he developed Tourette syndrome.
Who knows Tourette syndrome? It’s a very bad syndrome where people make jerks…
But very severe.
These people when they are in front of others they try to suppress this
and then they go home and the go crazy, like that.
They suppress it because they’re in front of others… Tourette syndrome.
I’ve been trying for the last 30 years to cure this man. Not possible.
I tried everything I could imagine. Could not free him. 5 years old… and he’s now 50.
-What goes on in the organism of this man that he cannot be freed again?
That you, cannot heal him, cannot cure…what goes on with the suppression?
-I do not know. There are suppressions which are much more easy to get rid of.
But there are others suppressions that have been gone so deep into the human cells that… forget it.
-The suppression did it depend on the antibiotic that he took?
On the kind of the antibiotics he took?
-On the kind? I cannot say.
-This is a question I wanted to ask for many years actually coming here
and it comes in the same direction with what you’re saying now.
I have seen several cases of what I call – and not only me but also good homeopaths-
“clear Sulphur case”.
They take remedy, they have great aggravation, there is an amelioration,
there is something going well but they will still have some symptoms like hot feet are there,
the theorizing state is there,
the aversion to shower stays there all the time like years and years and years…
and I was wondering what’s going on?
Is this level of health which requires something else?
Of course other remedies have been given in the meanwhile
but this essence of theorizing, itchiness… It still stays there and I don’t know.
-This is something which I have also faced several times when you have a picture
that looks like Sulphur, Natrum muriaticum.
You give Nat-m. and the keynotes remain in spite of the fact you have given the remedy.
Salt remains...
What I’ve hound out in such cases, in spite of the fact that there is this clear picture,
there is something that prevents the remedy from acting.
And that something comes usually from either an acute or a stress
which is hidden from your information.
For instance, Sulphur especially, because they theorize and they explain everything
and they have gone through an emotional grief which needed Ignatia
but they never took it because they did not know an homeopath,
they managed to put aside this picture of Ign.
And if you give Ign. in spite of the fact the picture is not there,
maybe one keynote Ign. is there, ok, you give Ign. and then you give Sulphur, then Sulphur will act.
I have some such cases which I know. I don’t know if the case you’re talking about that is…
-I had several of them, even cases of other homeopaths whom I trust
and I have seen this and I can’t rely on this
because I have a personal relationship with a Sulphur
and I’ve managed over the years to find out the very deep emotional trauma
which was hidden but then a recent case which I looked after 3 years of treating
and going around Sulph., Lyc. I gave Tuberculinum and had a reaction…
I don’t know it’s not long term right now, so I don’t know if something will change in long term.
But I really have this dilemma what to do. Where to look to change something…
-Yes. For instance, because you mentioned Tub. may be a tubercular miasm is prominent
and does not allow and needs first Tub. and then...
It can be possible. That is why we have difficulty with this kind of treatment.
You’re here because you want the excellent, you want the best
and you have travelled all this way  to see whether you can get the best.
So you are the exception.
The most of homeopaths are happy with giving several remedies at a time and see some effect.
I give 10 remedies, 3 remedies together, 4 remedies together, 5 remedies together
or a bluff myself in giving thin air and comes the person
and tells you “I think, maybe I’m better”. And things are going on like this.
But once you’re dissatisfied with this kind of situation then you say maybe there is another way.
And this other way is difficult.
Because you are trying to find the exact vibrational frequency of the person
within millions, billions of frequencies and stimulate the organism by the correct frequency.
And you need all the information possible.
And in the meantime the organism by having a medical history has hidden the information.
When you go to 7-9 levels information is hidden. Does not flow, does not come out.
You have to dig it out and there are the most chronic conditions.
And you may be battling for years with some people just
because they feel a little bit better here and there, they stick with you and you try.
My advice in such cases is give a lot of placebo. Even if the person complains.
You have given 10 remedies in the last 2 years and you see no real effect, give placebo
and find out what is the truth about the reaction of the organism.
-In such cases of Sulphur relapse or not really improving,
I was thinking about the behavior or lifestyle that produces the relapse
maybe a life partner that brings the same miasm…
-That is another story.  What you say is correct.
Which means you may give the right remedy but the lifestyle of the person is such
that brings a relapse very quickly.
You expect that remedy 200 you have given will last at least 6 months
and in 3 weeks there is a relapse.
In such a case you will see first a good reaction and then a relapse.
That means the person is drinking a lot of alcohol or the person takes drugs, hashish.
Many young people think that if I take hashish is normal, no problem. There is a problem.
In such a case your remedy must have shown a very good effect in the beginning.
-What you asked first about the Sulphur or Natrum muriaticum with the clear picture
and the good reaction, aggravation, amelioration etc.
but still there are some keynotes like hot feet, theorizing or desire salt,
I want to ask is this a disease to be cured?
If someone likes salt being Natrum muriaticum or theorizing if he/she is happy
and there is no previous very serious problems.
Maybe it’s something very little sign that the organism needs to be in balance.
Is it to be cured or not?
- I don’t know if I understood your question but let us say a person has a symptom theorizing
and you give a remedy and you expect stop theorizing from the one day to another,
this is not correct.
First of all, in order to consider a symptom theorizing,
because it’s a matter of judgment, what do you think is really theorizing
or he has some points in explaining certain things.
Theorizing as a symptom it is like this when a person comes and you ask a question
and the person starts talking, explaining, saying this, saying that
and after a quarter of an hour talking, talking making different theories about  this,
about that, then the idea of theorizing comes to your mind as a symptom.
But if you ask him “What do you think, why you are sick? Why you are in such a state?”
and he explains to you in a logical way,
gives you a theory why he is so sick, “because, as a child, I was mistreated by my parents
and my mother left…” and gives you a story… this is not theorizing. Theorizing is pathology.
I had a case recently. I saw privately a case and I put a question “What do you have?”
and she started talking about all kinds of things, jumping from one place to the other…
So she know Homeopathy, she knows Materia Medica and then I did not know how to say,
she would be offended she needed Lachesis, so anyhow,
I told her “Take a dose of Lachesis” she says “Me, Lachesis?”. I said “Yes, this is what I think”.
“Do you think that I’m loquacious?
–Yes maybe when you were talking to me you were loquacious.
–Only to you!”. You cannot imagine the lack of self-observation in such persons.
Then you realize, because you let them talk, talk, when he is going to stop?
Of course if you don’t have time, the next patient is waiting, you say “Ok, thank you.
Take Lachesis, go”. But it is true.
The person who is under examination and who has such problems like theorizing
they don’t realize it themselves because they feel they have to say this.
They cannot stop doing it. But it will be excessive to the point where it is impressive.
Then you can take it as a symptom. Then you give the remedy.
Then do you expect to stop theorizing? No.
You expect to reduce this excessive theorizing tendency.
So still will keep on theorizing, searching etc. but will be reduced definitely.
And people who are living next to them, if you inquire, they will confirm.
“Yes he’s not theorizing so much anymore”.
But will not stop because each person has its own personality
and this belongs to the personality traits, personality points.
You’re not going to change the personality, of course.
We don’t change personalities of the people. But if you are under Stram.
and you want to bite and to kill…
This is not your personality, of course, so give the Stram.
and the person will reduce its aggressiveness but still will be an aggressive child.
But not to that extreme. Speak.
Which part of India you come? Gujarat? And you? Bangalore, the best place in India.
I like Bangalore. The best climate.
-In the explanation of levels of health, when we get acute under…
I’m having the question regarding changing the remedy
when we need to give an acute remedy there are some indication
and when we need to give a chronic remedy there are some indications…
Now as for the basic qualifications of vital force, the vital force is unintelligent.
The moment we give an acute remedy it will react in that way,
the moment we give a chronic remedy it will react in a chronic way, right?
So my point is when we should change the remedy, how much time we should have in our hand…?
-Between acute and chronic or generally?
–Between acute and chronic.
Suppose the acute medicine is working in that case, is it right to enter with the chronic one?
-You see the experience shows that in the upper levels of health
the best way to give the chronic is after the acute.
After the acute the organism is in a sensitive state and will give out more clear chronic symptoms.
So that is your best time.
You wait 1-3 weeks and then this is the best time to prescribe chronically.
But if the person is in –let us say- level 6.
In level 6 you may expect the acutes will follow one another. You will have a lot of acutes.
So if you have been treating a person without acutes
and suddenly he starts developing acutes that’s different.
Then you wait, don’t touch again the chronic case
because most probably this person will develop another acute and another acute
and he will be coming to you with acutes.
Before you have prescribed correctly for all these acutes
you will not have a clear picture of new his chronic condition,
from level 6 bringing to level 5 for instance.
The good thing for you in India is that the cases you see are mostly physical pathologies
and this is so nice to treat because you find the remedy quite easily.
But the moment this has been suppressed and you will be getting this problem more and more
because of modern medicine there, they people they start taking antibiotics,
cortisone etc. you will have more.
The moment this is suppressed and modified
and the problem goes to the mental/emotional state,
during that time you will have bigger problems.
By the time I was living in India in the 1960s the cases were all very simple…
Unfortunately they will destroy your race as well. Our race has been destroyed already,
the south America still is good – not Argentina so much
because Argentina has a lot of antibiotics.
But Venezuela… How they destroy these people… They don’t realize what they’re doing.
The craziness is this; you give vaccination, you destroy the health in general
and you push the imbalance towards mental/ emotional states.
Then because of that people are living longer.
Because if the problem goes to the mental/ emotional the body remains intact
and does not die so in the statistics it appears here we have raised the mode of life.
Yes, but making crazy people, with Alzheimer, with neuromuscular diseases,
multiple sclerosis, all kinds of autoimmune diseases etc.
You don’t realize this? No.
-I have a question but before I want to mention I just heard this terrible statistics
that 50% of people in the 70s and 80s in the West suffer from various degrees of dementia.
–It’s unbelievable.
–I have a question about the Sulphur case.
Some people were saying that the symptoms of the disease are very very deep, hidden.
Some people will say it needs a syphilitic remedy then. You don’t agree?
-That is true maybe but which one? Ok, they need a syphilitic remedy
but just to give Syphillinum to everyone is wrong.
I have seen some bad reactions from Syphillinum giving it just like this
a guru in America he knew something like Homeopathy…
There was a medical doctor who became my student and he was telling me “Any newcomer”,
he was coming to the ashram he would receive a dose of Syph. 10M, a dose of Med. 10M,
a dose of Tub. 10M and a dose of Carc. 10M.
And several times to clear up the case. After that people became zombies.
I could see people losing their ability to think.
It’s not simple, just throw remedies, high potencies without knowing what you are doing.
It’s terrible.
-Do you think because of that humanity is undergoing a deeper miasmatic disease
that is why people just from the start being not level 1 but lower level in general
because of that suppression, miasmatic and hereditary conditions,
it’s not that I agree with this…
-It is correct what you say. People start in a low level from the very beginning,
from their birth.
The more we wait with that situation, the more people will be born on a low level.
But how do you cure this? How do you treat that? That’s another matter.
We have a tool which is fantastic. We have the symptoms of the patient to guide us.
If you forget the symptoms and go into a theory and according to that theory
you give this or that remedy you may forget about curing people.
- Just a question about a personal case that I had.
He’s a patient 21 years old and he’s got a cancer in the tongue
and being so young I finally gave him before he was operated
and his tongue has been almost removed and he had a plastic in it..
I just wondered in what level of health was this guy.
He’s 21 years old, he’s been healthy…
-Is he still alive?
–Yes he’s still alive, 6 months…
And his finally gave him Kali cyanatum it was the only specific remedy for that.
I mean there are a lot of remedies…
But what’s your opinion of o person being so young with such a cancer
what level of health is he? A,B,C,D?
-If the remedy is not clear then belongs to 8 or 9 level.
If you manage to treat him and bring out a clear picture
then the first thing that you will see is developing a very high fever.
Is not…?
But it’s very interesting that I have also said many years ago
that all diseases are of inflammatory type. Chronic and acute.
Because inflammation is the way to cure.
The organism cures through inflammation.
What becomes an acute inflammation if suppressed
becomes sub-acute inflammatory process
and the organism does not have anymore the strength to develop really an inflammation.
And tries, sub-acute…
That’s why you get the inflammatory processes in rheumatoid arthritis,
the inflammation in the joint, lupus erythematous, the autoimmune diseases.
You get exacerbations and reductions.
-In rheumatoid arthritis having exacerbation is good?
-If he has a high fever there is a possibility of cure after that.
These are simple things that centuries of medical knowledge has not brought out.
And they wait for me to say, I couldn’t believe it.
Sometimes when I said things I said it with timidity
because they thought what are you talking… Somebody will come up
and say how do you know?
And I remember a few years later one student of mine, a medical doctor he found a research
in which they said schizophrenia was of an inflammatory type disease.
And he said “Teacher, look! They have found out what you were saying a few years ago “.
And now they realize more and more this kind of process
which is going on but they don’t want to stop the process of suppressing inflammation.
“Inflammation? Take anti-inflammatory drugs”.
-It’s the same with the cardiac diseases, you noticed after arteriosclerosis,
in females we have a lot of heart attacks and then they found out you need to reduce the fat
and the cholesterol and they have heavy remedies to lower this cholesterol.
Now they found out that actually there is an inflammation. The same idea.
- Now they will find out of course.
Because these things that I have said are all observation from real life.
-I just also want to comment on that. Quite many years ago
I read that it is an inflammatory condition of the blood vessels,
it doesn’t matter that they know that.
Even if they know they still fight the cholesterol, it doesn’t matter.
-I’m just wondering with the levels of health the first states the upper are inflammatory
and as you said so often if this is suppressed by medication and it gets deeper and deeper
and the body starts from inflammation and the starts the next level in the chronic disease
is when you have like psychotic appearance. Later if you suppress more and more
and the health goes down it starts α self-destruction.
And you said this morning where we were talking about the suppression,
the self- destruction that this syphillitic this is found in Hahnemann
when he says you have the miasm where you walk, where the organism goes through
and it is very similar, isn’t it?
-Very similar. The problem with the idea of Hahnemann is that you cannot really
because you suspect that the person had in his ancestry syphilis automatically give
without taking the symptoms give anti-syphilitic.
One thinks anti-syphilitic is Syph. the other thinks it’s Merc.
and the third thinks it’s Aur.
All kinds of remedies are there from which you choose according to the symptoms, of course.
But this is the idea of Hahnemann because he had observed it.
What I have said is in accordance with the ideas of Hahnemann. Absolutely.
That’s why they accuse me of being… you know George is talking about Hahnemann, old stuff.
-It’s still not clear between the period we should leave before changing the remedy.
-I do not understand because of your accent. You have to speak more slowly, like me.
-How much time we should give between changing the remedy?
-Depends on the emergency of the case you treat. If you treat an emergency case
and you give a remedy that has not acted you can change it after a few hours.
If you treat chronic cases and you want a time for observation
the least time will be 1 month.
Once you see something is going on then you wait and then you wait...give placebo.
Many times after a month they have come and they told me I’m the same
but I don’t take it as such I want to really be sure he’s the same.
So I inquire and if I see especially a mental or emotional symptom
which is better I don’t care if he has psoriasis, eczema or stomach pain
which is the same I will wait one month more to see whether this amelioration is really
because of the remedy and therefore will bring about the cure of the physical body.
OK. In the next days in the afternoon we will see a real case
and we can have time to discuss about a real case. I don’t know the case.
I have never seen it. And usually I never know about the case.
So I have the same information as yourself. So we are on an equal level.
Thank you.