- What was the original?
- Compulsive tobaccoism, obesity, I don’t remember… and the pain in my back.
- The remedy?
- Med.
- Fear of insects, fear of spiders, cervical spasm, cannot support injustice,
perspiration on scalp during sleep. Is it still there?
- No. First it changed to the chest and then no more perspiration there.
I have perspiration now in my feet.
- And the perspiration is offensive?
- I could say so. It depends on the shoe that the tendency is to be…
- Sexual desire increased?
- I don’t know, I don’t practice.
- Also you had cysts in the ovaries.
- Yes.
My menses are regular now since 7 years ago it became regular but I didn’t check it any more.
- Before menses?
- I had amenorrhea for almost 2 years, then 6 months since I was developed at the age of 12
until 32-33 I never had menses in summertime for instance. It was very irregular.
- But now are regular.
- Are regular since I took I don’t know what remedy, because I didn’t know what I was taking,
because my homeopath didn’t want me to know. So some remedy switched that.
I never had a problem again with that.
- How is the cervical…?
- It was worse and worse not only the cervical but the lumbar and dorsal pain
and I couldn’t sleep as I put in the e-mail, I had to take some medication at some point
because I couldn’t sleep for a month. Not able to work.
- Did you write me?
- Yes, 3 times.
- And what did I suggest?
- You only suggest me something in the first e-mail
that it was “don’t take anything, maybe later I’ll give you thuja”
because the first reaction to the remedy was to be plenty of warts.
I was with 1 or 2 when I came here and after I took the remedy,
in less than a month all my face, my palms and in the chest also, here in the neck,
some of them still persist but some of them were falling from the night to a day.
- But you did not take thuja.
- No, I took your advice at that moment then I began to face a big depression.
I was very depressed, very upset.
- Why?
- I’ve been through a lot as I put you in the e-mail,
a definite end of relationship with my family and my closest friend for more than 25 years
and I cut everything.
I shut down my practice in Uruguay. That meant about 2.000 or 3.000 patient per year.
And it was very hard for me to take.
- You stopped your practice?
- I cut everything.
- Why?
- Because I didn’t want to see my family anymore and they live in Uruguay.
- That means they did an injustice to you.
- Of course. It was happening before again and again
but I couldn’t cut the relationship because I felt guilty. Always feeling guilty.
- You put the guilt to you.
- Yes.
I think they manipulate me because I always put the blame on myself.
So that’s why I wrote to you in the first e-mail that it was outstanding to me
to be able to cut bad relationships that were toxic to me without guilt.
That was new in my life.
Then I realized I have a lot of symptoms of med I didn’t tell you but since I was born.
That was the main good effect of the remedy.
I didn’t understand it at that moment of the depression that it was a good thing for me,
in that moment I could kill myself.
But ever since I cut these relationships I’ve been better, I’m better. I feel better.
That moment was horrible when I wrote to you because my psychologist obliged me “don’t’ do it,
I’ll put you in a mental hospital to get you under anti-depressive drugs”
so I wrote to you because of that.
As I didn’t get an answer and I was in that depressive phase,
of course I felt you didn’t care about me…
- I did not answer? That’s very strange.
- Yes the second mail you didn’t answer, the first neither… Maybe we have a problem.
The first mail I had to ask Maria to ask you, send a mail… It does not matter but…
- Some mails are coming back because of the server, they don’t arrive.
- Yes, I know but in that moment I was so depressed
that the feeling was “nobody cares about me, I prefer to die, I don’t need to be in this world,
and painful feelings...”
- You did not have symptoms of ign during that time?
- I didn’t cry. I felt like I failed. My life is a failure.
That kind of feeling, I don’t belong to this world, I’m not useful to anyone,
nobody loves me and nobody will because I’m not loveable… and that kind of thoughts.
But as I told you I don’t know if it was a manic depressive wave
but after that I began to go better and better and I decided to come here.
First I went to Cuba twice to perform the “Levels of Health” course that was given there
and as I wrote down here, the first time was so depressing for me to see
that for a month I wasn’t able to stop crying because of the sympathetic feeling.
The second time I went there was 3 weeks ago. It was the same people, same country,
same situation, I was laughing and enjoying…
- It’s interesting what you are saying because everything is subjective.
Now you have decided to start again your practice?
- No. Not in Uruguay. My patients are not in Uruguay.
I’ve practice it because I live between 2 countries.
In Argentina 15 days then I flew to Uruguay for 15 days, where my family lives, in Uruguay.
My big amount of patients were in Uruguay
because there I used to work from very early in the morning until very late in the night, every day.
This is better for me, I could take a breath without working so much.
- So at this moment, psychologically you feel better.
- Better. Not well but better. I cannot be well psychologically because I feel so ugly and fat.
That’s a problem for me.
- You put on weight?
- Yes, since I came here last year in May until now I gained about 20 kilos.
That’s too much for me. I don’t want to see myself in a mirror, I’m not able to enjoy…
- Do you have great appetite or you eat…?
- I think I always had the same appetite.
I don’t if this is more than other people or no because I don’t compare myself with the others.
But as I told you the first time I’ve been here, something made the click inside me
and despite making diets or anything I’ve been like this the last 10 years.
But in the last 2 years it was here… The first time I gave up smoking and gained 30 kilos
and I went down then slowly and was like this for 8 years and began to smoke again.
When I began to smoke again I was both smoking and gaining weight.
I came here, last year with the very compulsive tobaccoism,
no less than 40 cigarettes per day… and after I gave up 4 months ago the cigarette
I gained another 8 kilos.
And I don’t know it why I gave up this time but as I told you there
I took by myself staph because I couldn’t support the pain in my back.
And I took empirically rhus-t without any repertorization
because it was much worse from rest and much worse from humidity, wet weather.
- Did you have had calc in the past?
- No, never. Maybe when I was a baby but not since I remember.
- In general you feel very cold?
- I am very cold person.
- And sweets?
- No, I’m not fond of sweets. Much more salt. I eat salt with food.
- So much. Salt with the food.
- Yes I need salt very much.
- What about the fat of the meat?
- It doesn’t bother me but it’s not something like my sister for instance,
she leaves the meat and she eats only fat. No, that’s not for me.
- But you can eat the fat.
- Yes if I don’t see it very clearly.
If I see some fat and it brings me some nausea.
- The eggs?
- I like it but not especially.
- Fruits?
- I don’t like except oranges.
Oranges I love. I don’t like much fruit.
I eat it because I have to eat cause I’m fat and I need to eat fruit but oranges yes.
I love oranges. And Greek oranges more.
- Oranges must be sweetish or sour?
- I like it sweet.
I also began to eat sour things because I lived in Lebanon
and they taught me to eat sour things and I enjoy it.
I didn’t tell you something maybe important.
The first time I came here you asked me about a breast inflammation I had
because I took con in the past because of this breast inflammation.
And this last month it came back. I’m having the same inflammation.
- Were it was?
- In the left breast.
My mother died of an inflammatory cancer of the left breast.
That was without the tumor, only the skin. The same is happening again to me.
- How many years ago you had it?
- I had in 2009.
I had it for a year and then after I took one dose of con it disappeared
until one month ago which came back.
- How is your back now?
- It’s not good because I think I overweight but after staph it is much better.
I repertorized that because I told you…
- Have you ever taken caust?
- No, never.
Only for a flu a couple of years ago caust 6CH one day because all my patients…
it was a kind flu.
- Now the coming out of the warts still continues?
- Yes. I have these and these are new… I don’t know.
Maybe one month ago it was the last one but I am telling you wasn’t one all the time.
- Is there any leucorrhea?
- No, not much.
- Menses are…
- Regular.
- Before menses?
- That’s new for me.
There’s a new symptom. I cannot stand my breast.
It is very painful and I take a lot of liquid inside my body.
So the first day I have to go each hour to the bathroom to urinate
because I have too much liquid. Maybe 3-4 kilos more before the menses.
This is for the last 3-4 months I’m like a medusa.
- You still have this aggravation from peaches? The fruit.
- I don’t have it anymore because this summertime they were very good and I ate a lot.
Nothing happened to my face. I comment that to my friend, I remember.
- This desire for smoke now is still there?
- It went away and it came back since I am in Greece. One week.
I went and bought some cigarettes. Stupid I know. I couldn’t help it really.
- Also you have said that you had aversion to alcoholic drinks?
- Yes still there. Very strong.
- And the sea bathing? The experience?
- It’s the best thing in the world. If you put me there to live, I live there.
- Inside the sea…
- Here it is very cold.
I am a very cold person but in Cuba that is hot they had to remove me from the sea in the night
because I was there from morning till the night. I didn’t want to move from inside the sea.
- So the potency that you took in the beginning…
- Yes Med was one day 200CH a dose and the other 1M.
- And you never repeated?
- Never repeated. Only took this staph in the middle because my pain was killing me.
- You are cold you say?
- Very cold.
- Your feet are cold?
- Yes… are like ice
- Your nails are strong?
- No, after I took the remedy, that’s another thing, I used to have very strong nails and long,
and I cannot…never again.
- Now they break.
- Yes that was a change.
- Is there any kind of tendency for constipation?
- I am alternating from constipation to diarrhea no matter what I eat.
- All your life or now?
- No I think it’s the last period.
Maybe with some of this unknown medication I took.
I reported this kind of thing for 15 days but nothing happened.
But now I am having problems with my rectum first, the fissure that doesn’t go.
That is persistent since I took the medication, doesn’t go.
I used to have sometimes because I was constipated once but it used to be cured.
This is worse before menses but I am always bleeding.
There is no stool without bleeding. No matter the consistency.
- You did not experience any problems with your stomach?
- Yes. I was very bad and I still am with acid reflux. Burning. Reflux in the night.
And maybe I wake up because of this, coughing because of broncho-aspiration.
That’s a problem. I thought it was because of the cigarette but after gave up smoking
it was still there.
- Did you notice any problems with the nails on your foot?
- Yes.
- Entering?
- What are you? A magician? The right toe yes. You surprise me, really!
- I am not a magician. I have just studied very much…
- That’s why I am here. Because you told me so.
If not, if I thought you were a magician I wouldn’t be here.
I want to study so much and know so much.
First when I came you even guessed my hormone levels.
- In your background pathology you have mentioned hypothyroidism,
that was confirmed…? All of your life?
- Not all my life. I was like this.
I was being in a very strict diet, very hypo caloric about 400 kcal per day for 2 years.
After that I was skinny of course
but I couldn’t go to the beach 36C outside without my wool things. So I performed TSH.
And my TSH level was 12. It was very high. I think it was because of that diet
because this diet it is like fashion diet in Argentina
because there is some physician in the TV that gives this horrible diet
many people perform that and I had patients and they all after hypothyroid.
Of course 400 kcal for 2 years you must save energy some way
and I think that was the cost.
- What age?
- The diet that put on my weight again after I gave up smoking…
So it was 2003 more or less. 2004. That means 35-36 years old.
Now what we can say about this case that med has done quite a good job
and the reason for that is mostly the externalization of these tumors,
all these little warts all over the body which is a big release of the organism of course.
And prevention of the tumor developing more serious later on.
So the fact that the organism brings out all these warts
is a kind of protection of the organism for not developing tumor in the internal organs.
That’s the one.
There are several changes of course and the changes point out to the same remedy
or to another remedy or to which remedy…? This is the question.
There are changes which are deep you see the changes that you see for instance in the nails.
That means the calcium is not anymore distributed equally,
normally in the body and that’s why the nails start breaking down.
This is something which is not important, it seems not important
but for the organism is shows a deep change in the absorption process.
Therefore it shows that the calcium is not working properly
and that’s why I was asking questions concerning calc with the obesity, with the freezing…
I was thinking of calc, another remedy you could be thinking with the fissure is graph
which again has strong obesity the problem is that graph has aversion to salt.
Aversion to sweets and salt.
So the decision has to be between calc, graph and a third one sil.
So I am not a magician when I ask her.
The question was your organism goes towards a sil picture?
She just confirmed it, she said “My nails started ingrowing, going inside”.
Because I had several other things which were going on pointing to sil
and the extreme coldness that she feels is sil.
Also sil is the fact that the perspiration went away, went to the feet and became offensive.
So all the changes she has point to sil with one difference.
That sil has desire for salt but is not known for such a strong desire for salt.
But the problem is that she has developed also an inflammation of the mammae
which we have to take care of.  And the inflammation of the mammae…
show me the remedies.
You see sil, graph, calc. The system is quite intelligent more than me.
That’s why they say you are going to produce robots that will be better than humans.
This is the case. Show me inflammation of the mammae.
We see here the calc, should be quite strong here, sil is on the third degree where graph is missing.
So in spite of the fact the obesity is like graph,
she looks like graph still sil is covering more her picture.
Because graph very seldom will describe themselves as so freezing as she did.
Freezing cold. Graph is cold but not to the extreme. Sil is extremely cold.
Feeling the cold very strongly. Complaints from anticipation.
I saw her expecting… She has to go to the bathroom. So I added this symptoms.
It’s not important but it’s interesting that both sil and graph they have strongly this symptom.
What we see here is a little bit strange phenomenon that still has some keynotes of med
like desire for oranges and better in the sea.
I am not sure if better in the sea will be as strong as it was this summer.
- In Cuba I thought it was the weather, that was wet.
But it was much worse I was rigid, couldn’t move mostly in the morning.
The other things were better in the sea like my mood but this was worse.
- Anyhow the fissure also is characteristic of sil as well as graph of course
but what differentiates the sil from graph in her case is the extreme aggravation from cold
on the one hand and on the other the inflammation which has and has to be taken care
of which is not known so much with graph.
Where with sil it’s well established.
So therefore sil 200CH one dose you can take it and you can tell me tomorrow.
- My question is about the warts; if understood correct they are still coming
and is it not an indication to wait because the process is like going on
but on the other hand there is this inflammation of mammae
which is really something serious to look for because there is the hereditary background.
- The remedy med was taken one year ago. So we have waited for a year.
Now we have a new picture. Quite deep changes to show us that most probably this is the remedy.
We are justified to give the remedy.
Because we have enough new symptoms after the changes which point out to sil.
- I have a question. A while ago she took homeo for breast inflammation,
was it a good thing or was it a suppression?
- I don’t know.
- … Because you made an explanation why I haven’t had sexual activity for a lot of years
and that was not good for my type of passionate Mediterranean…
and that made the hormones to accumulate and prepared for a tumor.
And that was a good thing. You congratulate because I took con last year.
-  That means it was correct.
That means also that the organism has more or less under the same pressure.
She has no partner and sexually she is active and there is a kind of outlet in the inflammation.
We’ll see now with sil. What happens.
One remedy has cured one symptom does not mean another remedy
may not cure the same symptom of course.
But now sil is chosen on a much more global basis.
With a lot of more symptoms. Can you tell me?
There is question written here in the acon case… Ok.
She says she would not have thought treating it as an acute the acon case
because there was no fever.
I said the shock is like an acute not meaning fever.
But meaning an acute like to fall down and you are blue. This is an acute.
You take arn and it goes away. Now if you leave it and the blow has remained in the organism
it will become an obstacle for the underlying remedy unless you give arn.
You had a case in which there was an accident, hit the head or the body
and the effect of the accident was not treated correctly. The effect remained.
Now he comes and he doesn’t not have the pains of the accident
but he has different other symptoms.
You think it’s calc, you prescribe, no effect. Graph, no effect, sil, no effect.
And then you give arn because you go back and you say this blow has remained
and this level of the blow that was imposed upon the organism at a certain moment
keeps the organism slaved.
You have to free the organism from this layer and then the calc will act.
It’s clear… This is what I mean by acute in this case. Yes.
- ..Because you saw the person was in group C.
What would have happened? Do you know?
- If the person was in the group C…
- If you didn’t recognize that the person was in group C…
what would have happened? Do you know…?
- When I say acute in the groups I mean fever. Now there was not fever…
If you give low potency still there will be some effect
but not as big effect as a high potency.
Because that was a mental state. An acute of the mental condition.
So it’s not a fever on the body it’s on the mental. So you have to go high.
Thank you.