- This nice gentleman comes from Sweden.
33 years old and the main complaint is sleeplessness for maybe 15-20.
- Or maybe longer.
- From slightest noise impossible to sleep, waking from slightest noise.
And takes 3-4 hours to fall asleep.
- Yes, that’s a big problem.
- Why do you think this happens to you?
What you’re saying is when you were about 13 something happened to you.
- Something happened a little bit earlier. I was frightened when I was little boy.
- At what age?
- Maybe 6-7, I’m not sure.
I was sleeping in my bed and I woke up and I had a delusion.
I saw a man standing with a knife.
I saw the silhouette on the door from inside the room
and I though a man stood there with a knife.
- Was trying to kill you?
- Yes.
I turned around and faced the wall. It was really scary.
- So you turned around and faced the wall but trembling.
And do you think from that incident started the sleeplessness?
- It could be. I don’t like to be alone. And I think it started from then.
- Can you tell me the remedies that you have taken?
You say you took about 20 remedies so far?
- Yes. I don’t know in what order.
- Ok, it doesn’t matter, just the names.
- Phos, stram, calc, sulph, lyc, puls, calad, nux-v, merc, thuja, nat-m,
tub, psor, aeth, staph, sil, op, med, lac-c, lach, caust, kali-c, nat-c, nat-br.
- Three homeopaths gave all these remedies.
- It was one homeopath. One has given the most.
- They gave one remedy at a time or sometimes 2-3 remedies?
- Before all these I also took some mixed remedies.
- By a homeopath or you got it yourself?
- By a homeopath.
- Do you remember what age you went the first time to an homeopath?
- When I was 20.
- And you went for this problem?
- No, I went for my knee. That was treated by mixed remedies.
- And the sleeplessness was there?
- Before, yes.
- Never was affected by any of these?
- No.
- But you said one remedy..
- Yes, one remedy, phos. But it only lasted for 2 weeks.
And I tried all different kinds of potencies.
- When you said first words I just wrote down phos and the first remedy you said was phos.
We’ll see now what happens. Do you remember if you took acon?
- I took it for acutes. Never for…
- Ign?
- No. I never took it.
- So when you go to bed, you’re sleepy or you’re not sleepy?
- I can be very sleepy.
- You turn around and then you become sleepless?
- Yes.
- For 3-4 hours turn around in bed.
- Sometimes.
- And when you wake up you are tired, unrefreshed or you are not tired?
- I’m tired when I wake but as soon as I’m off of the bed, it’s ok.
Even if I sleep 2 hours. I feel ok.
- So, once you fall asleep you don’t wake up till…
- Yes, Many times. I easily fall asleep again after I wake up.
- Have you also taken sulph?
- Yes.
- You did not mention it.
- I think I did.
- Ah, yes. No effect?
- No.
- You have taken sep?
- Tell me what else do you have.
- I have a ganglion in the wrist. A small one.
- Do you have pain in the wrist?
- Yes, very much.
- Pain in which wrist?
- In the right one, also in the left but not too much.
- In the wrist.
- Yes.
- In the knee also you said?
- No. Right and left wrist. But more in the right.
I think the pain in the wrists is worse when it’s cold.
- But you’re not sure.
- No, I’m not sure.
- When it’s wet?
- No.
I have more pain when I have used the wrist. Doing massage or carrying heavy things.
- You are doing massage.
- Yes.
- Your legs in bed are also restless?
- No.
- In general you just turn around, all the body, and not the…
- Usually I start on the back and I finish on the back, I sleep on the back.
In between I turn around. All sides, without a problem.
And I’m thinking a lot about everything…
- During the time of sleeplessness?
- Yes.
- All the good or bad things come to you?
- Both.
And in the summer I have also allergy.
- You mean July, August?
- June and July.
- These 2 months. And you have allergies or hay fever?
- Hay fever.
- Never asthma?
- No.
- You are an athlete. You like gymnastics.
- Yes.
- The lacrimation is acrid. And in the night my eyes they stick together.
That’s the whole year, not only in the summer.
Maybe it’s because the dog is sleeping in my bed. And I had a very severe pain in my anus.
- What kind of pain?
- Cramping pain. It comes about 2-3 times a year.
And the last time I had it was very severe, I almost fainted. Cold perspiration.
- It extends upwards the pain or it is local?
- Yes, it is local.
- Like a cramp? Like constriction?
- Yes.
- Very severe?
- And every time it happened at a specific hour in the morning…?
- Only in the night. The severe cramps come always in the night
but sometimes also very small cramps before stool, during the day also.
But the severe pain cramps is only in the night. Sensitive to cold. I get pain in my throat.
- Cold and wet? Or only cold? You don’t realize the wet. The drafts?
- I don’t like drafts…
I like it here because I’m very warm but usually I don’t like drafts.
Even if I’m hot and there is wind or drafts, I don’t want.
- What do you feel?
- Feverish.
And pain in the throat. I have a lot of dreams, several times every night.
- What kind of dreams?
- Many times I dream that I am being murdered. I am about to die.
I can feel life is running out. That I can be shot.
- You parents were separated?
- No.
- They live together.
- Yes.
- You have brothers and sisters?
- One little sister.
- And you have been rejected by your parents?
- No, I don’t think so. Not rejected but maybe not so much loved...
hugs and kisses and telling “I love you…”
- Swedish are not very…
- No, we are not like that.
- Your sister, you have a good contact?
- Yes.
- And was any incident, where the parents they left you as a little child
and you got afraid?
- Not that I remember.
Once they were about to separate.
- What age you were?
- Maybe 10-11.
Maybe smaller, I don’t remember. They didn’t.
- But did you hear them fighting?
- No.
- Do you sigh sometimes?
- Sometimes.
- Fruits you eat?
- I like bananas.
Maybe it is because they are easy to eat. But I also like some apples.
Not too sweet apples because then I have problems with the teeth if they are too sweet.
- Have you taken rhus-t?
- I don’t think I’ve taken this only for acutes. I also took it for lumbago. It didn’t help.
- You have fears?
- I have a very big fear of snakes. I don’t like snakes. I usually dream of snakes.
- What else? Fear of being alone?
- Yes.
I think it’s because of the fright when I was a little boy.
And there have also been a couple of other frights in my life.
Maybe 10-12 years ago I was in a bad company with bad friends and we went by car
and one guy was driving and we were not going together.
I saw they were looking each other suspiciously and one person behind me took out a gun
and put it in my head.
- He put it to your head and then he said anything? Either do this or what…?
- He didn’t say anything.
- Wait a moment, I didn’t understand. You were in a car.
And the person who was sitting behind you… You were driving?
- No. I was in the front seat but I was not driving.
- He was alone in the back.
- Yes.
- So just to show off? Why he did this?
- I don’t remember.
- How old you were?
- Maybe 10-12 years ago. Maybe I was 20.
- You were 20 and he was?
- Same age. There was also another time…
- No, wait a moment. He put the gun and he didn’t say anything.
- No.
- Swedish?
- Yes.
- You don’t talk very much in Sweden. Quite closed.
What did you feel?
- I don’t remember.
But what I remember is that the thing that happened to me
when I was a boy has affected me most.
- With the dream?
- No with the person.
- You think you were awake in the night?
- I was awake.
- But it was not a real person.
- No there was this silver on the door that looked like a knife and then I hallucinated a man.
- With your imagination you made it?
- Yes.
Maybe there was one I don’t know. I can’t say for sure. But I hope there wasn’t.
It must have been  my father.
- Maybe it was your father?
- I hope not.
- You felt it might have been your father?
- No, I don’t know.
- Later on you thought maybe it’s your father?
- He didn’t have a knife. The knife was only the silver.
I saw the silver on the sides of the door and then I thought it was a knife.
But also I have pain in my lumbar region, very much when I’m standing too long
or walking too slow. You know, window shopping.
Also when I’m lying too long in bed.
And also pain here in the side but not so much now as before.
- Like a cramp?
- No like sore pain. When I’m running, jogging or walking fast.
- When you do exercise, after the exercise?
- No, just walking or running.
- You feel good after the exercise?
- Yes, very good but only after I when I am at the gym. It makes me feel good.
I don’t have to go out to walk or do anything else.
- When you are doing the gym work then afterwards you feel good.
- Yes.
- You are careful with your food? You are health conscious?
- You don’t eat junk?
- I eat a lot of chocolate. Too much.
- What about salt? How much?
- I don’t use much salt but I could use. I like it.
- How much is your thirst?
- It’s different. Sometimes I am very thirsty sometimes I drink one glass for a day.
- The water must be cold?
- Yes.
- From the refrigerator.
- Maybe not from the refrigerator but from the tap.
- But not much.
- When I drink I drink a lot. Big glasses.
- How many glasses? You can drink 3 glasses?
- No, but maybe one of half liter. I always stop day by drinking one glass of water a day.
- In your younger years did you do something that affected your conscience?
Do you understand what it means?
It means you did something and you felt wrong.
- Yes. You want to know?
- Yes, if you can say.
- I did a robbery.
- At what age?
- 20 maybe.
- And they caught you?
- After 4 years they caught me.
- But did you hurt somebody during the robbery?
- Not physically.
- You didn’t fight. You didn’t encounter some other people.
- No but I used to.
- To fight?
- Yes. But that was long time ago.
- With what?
- With my hands.
- I mean by Japanese fight or boxing or just fighting?
- What do you mean?
- Like karate?
- I did tae kwon do for 10 years. Boxes and kicks.
- So you are a dangerous guy.
- No.
I don’t want to hurt anyone. I don’t like to fight. I used to but not any more.
I like to train fight.
- You like to train yourself or you like to train others?
- No, to train myself.
- To be ready in case somebody attacks you.
- Maybe not for that but I like it.
But I don’t want to fight others if it’s not controlled in the ring…
- When they caught you, they put you in jail?
- Yes.
- For how long?
- 4 days. It’s not so long.
- And you felt very bad about it, because they caught you.
- No, I think it’s good they caught me because it was always in the back.
- You were carrying it?
- Yes.
- And the others? You were alone? They caught the others?
- They caught two. One is free.
- They caught you and another one.
- Me and two others.
- You were 4.
- Yes.
- And the other… You did not give his name.
- No. I would never do that.
- You weep easily?
- Very sensitive but mostly when I am alone.
Weep most often when I am happy, when I’m seeing things on TV,
people helping each other or doing nice things.
- You never got coff?
- No. I never drink coffee.
- You never drink coffee. You don’t like or because of homeopathy?
- Both.
- If you drink coffee you become overexcited?
- Yes.
- You cannot sleep the whole night?
- I’m calm in my nerves but I cannot sleep. I am not restless but I cannot sleep.
- The whole night you can stay awake?
-  I think so but it was a long time ago I drank coffee.
- Your mind is running fast? That means you lie down and you think this and that…
- I don’t know. I can be very lazy also.
Just lying on the bed on the couch and do nothing.
- Without thoughts.
- Watching TV and reading a lot homeopathy every day, several hours.
- In Sweden everyone is allowed to practice homeopathy?
- Yes.
- When it was the last time you had the last high fever?
- 6-7 months ago.
- How high?
- I’m not sure, maybe 39C. It felt like it. I had illusions.
- You never check.
- No.
- Before this if you remember?
- A couple of years.
- Again high fever?
- Yes.
- Your left eye is watery. Is coming some… in your left eye?
- No, I don’t think so.
- What else?
- I don’t know. I love animals very much.
- You said you were affected when I killed the fly.
- A little bit. When I see a fly on floor that is on the back I turn it on its feet again.
- That means you cannot watch the killing of even a fly.
- Yes, I can. When I see an animal suffer that suffers really much then I’m crying.
I also like sweets very much. Chocolate.
- Sweets and salt.
- Chocolate.
That’s what I like the most. And ice cream, chocolate ice cream.
- Are you affected at all by thunderstorms?
- No.
- You like thunderstorms?
- What about dark in the room where you sleep.
- I want to have some light but I cannot sleep with too much light.
- If you are in a high place and you look down you have a problem?
- Yes.
- What? You feel fear, vertigo?
- Weak in my knees. A little bit vertigo.
- If there is a balcony? Still? You don’t feel good.
- I don’t like it.
- If you are expecting for an appointment you will have diarrhea or frequent urination?
- Maybe frequent urination today but not usually.
- You are very fastidious.
- I can be. Sometimes I can be lazy;
I want others to be it for me. I want to have a clean home and everything should be in order.
Maybe it’s not always in order but I want it to be.
- You had ear infections?
- Yes.
- With antibiotics.
- Now in sleep do you feel any saliva is running out?
- No.
- But your gums are not in good condition?
- I think they are.
- If you get excited from an emotion, you get very excited?
- I think I can be. Before going here to Alonisos or travelling I get excited
and make a list of what I should take with me, make a mark for everything.
I like it. In the mornings I have my routines and I’m doing that and then I go by a boat
and I’m drinking my hot milk chocolate, always the same thing. I like it.
- But the milk you like?
- No, but hot chocolate I drink because it’s chocolate.
- Do you have any aggressive thoughts?
- I can.
- Concerns what? Killing, hitting?
- I’m a peaceful person but only if someone hurts my family I think…
- You’re married?
- No.
- You have a girlfriend?
- Yes.
- Whom would you consider your family? Girlfriend or your real family?
- All of them.
- You feel protective.
- If something happen I want to help them.
That’s how I got in trouble also many years ago, I helped my friends.
Some other guys came with guns another time.
They came and looked for me but they didn’t find me because I helped a friend.
He was in a fight and I helped him.
- And you hit the other guys.
- Yes.
- And they wanted to kill you afterwards.
- It doesn’t matter who it is or how many people it is I always help my friends
if they have problems.
- If somebody says “thank you” to you…
- I can be very sentimental.
- You can cry during that time?
- I try to control but it’s mostly my patients they thank me. Then I am sentimental.
I never cry when they say “thank you” but I can cry. I have to think of something else.
- You hair stands up. This is what you wanted to say.
- Yes.
- I want to ask you if you are jealous. You feel jealousy very strongly?
- No, a little bit. It depends on the situation.
- Can you tie something around your neck?
- Not too much.
- You don’t like it.
- But I can have a turtleneck.
- Can you have a tie?
- Never used.
- Only Greeks wear ties?
- I never had the upper button here but I can have a collar.
- So you didn’t exactly tell us what you want to do when you have those aggressive thoughts.
You did not specify.
- It’s not often. I’m not an aggressive person.
- So you just sometimes if somebody has hurt you only then you have…
- No.
- If there is somebody who has done something wrong with your family
then you have thoughts of hitting, killing, how far your thoughts could go?
- It depends on the crime but if the crime is severe I could kill them.
- Your thought. You will not do it. I hope.
- No, I won’t. It is not often. I promise.
- You never got hyos?
- No.
- Now I want to ask you something more private. Is it ok?
- No problem.
- Sexually, you are normal?
- I think I’m normal, sometimes.
- Sometimes you are normal, sometimes you are not normal.
- Yes. Sometimes is more, sometimes is less.
- With the same girl or you change girls?
- Same girl.
- For how many years?
- 15.
- For 15 you have the same girl. You are not married. You could marry, she doesn’t want?
- Yes she wants but it doesn’t matter.
- It’s indifferent because in Sweden is not important whether some people are married or not.
- Maybe only for the insurance.
- We have some Iranians here, their hair will stand up when they hear like this.
- I will not marry in a traditional way, maybe in Vegas.
- You mean Las Vegas in these little quick ceremonies.
- Yes.
- I had a patient, he had an helicopter.
So I was in Berkley, he said I’ll come and take you with the helicopter to Las Vegas
because he was staying there. He takes me there with the helicopter, we land in his garden
and then we go to the Las Vegas… this crazy thing I’ve never seen in my life.
Except of the marriage and all this kind of things, the casinos...
Anyhow. But he likes it. You like gambling?
- No, I’m not gambling.
- Now you may ask me what are these questions have to do with your remedy.
I’m trying to avoid making a mistake.
Because some people will ask me “Why didn’t you ask this why didn’t you ask that?”
So I am asking the questions the people would like to ask.
If somebody wants to ask a question please do it.
- Hi. Have you got an aversion of quarreling with somebody
are you afraid of quarreling and having…
- I don’t like to quarrel. I want peace.
- He wants peace, he said it very clearly.
But if somebody does something wrong with his family he can kill him.
-… has influenced my thinking a lot.
- … he was a great homeopath.
- He pointed a couple of thing about op.
I would like to ask whether this gentleman can remember with absolute clarity
the first young shock he had when he woke at night.
Can he remember that incident as if it happened yesterday? Very clear to this day?
- Yes, he said. He is very clear to this day.
-[…]
- Yes, correct, but opium has been given.
- What potency?
- 1M.
Or 10M or maybe 1M and 10M.
- I would try in low potencies.
- No.
- Everything was in high potencies. Every remedy.
- Now I will tell you a few remarks concerning op.
You have to remember that op is a remedy that primarily has sleepiness.
This is the main aspect of op. They will sleep very easily and without even a reason.
Sitting there, they can fall asleep. So this is the main aspect of op.
It very seldom that op goes to the other extreme and becomes sleepless.
So this is one point. The second point is that op belongs to people
who feel or give you the impression who feel very happy inside.
It is a remedy which has a self-satisfying sense. “Good. I’m feeling good.”
That is why in our books says; He says he feels good, while he may be very sick.
May be very sick, maybe you expect he is suffering a lot and he is, he says “I feel good.”
But the idea with opium therefore is with a person who easily falls asleep
but just get the connection with the comatose state. This is a deep sleep.
This is a sleep which is in the extreme that means he cannot wake up.
That is why in comatose states we prescribe op, the first remedy we are prescribing is op.
And she is right when she says if you have…
I’m sleeping without cover with this bloody weather and I got a cold but it doesn’t matter so,
ok, I will not postpone the seminar.
She is right when she says that if somebody has a big shock, terrifying shock,
it can lead him to states of op. Op is one of the remedies that is indicated with sudden shock.
For instance, if at this moment there is an earthquake, you may be moving in your seats,
don’t get up, sit there quietly, there is no problem if that happens
because the building is anti-earthquake, it’s built specially for not falling but some of you,
you will go to stage of either op or gels or acon, which are the main remedies after a big fright.
Some of you will sit and it will be ok.
George says ok, it’s ok. Some will remain with a shock “My God! I am dying”.
That feeling can bring about an op state.
I’ll give you a very characteristic reaction of a fright and on op state.
I was fishing with my nephew, my nephew is 40 years old.
We were fishing on a small boat, 5 meters, and I saw a huge boat coming against us,
so I stand up on the boat and I make signs so the captain will see me and change course,
cause they were straight upon us.
It was full of tourists but the captain, being a Greek, he was driving on the back of the boat,
he was driving with this bloody thing but he had next to him a German woman
with whom he was flirting very heavily at the moment.
So never mind, I saw some people making signs for him to change,
he was so busy with the lady next to him and he didn’t pay attention.
So, actually my nephew was sitting on one side and I was sitting on the other side of the boat
and the big boat was coming.
And comes exactly on the place where my nephew was sitting hitting us
and the last moment he jumps out so high, he says to me “I saw the people on the big boat from up”.
I was on the other side the boat turns and I come under the boat
and I’m pushing the boat not to get under the boat.
And I’m pushing the boat as much as I could and I was saved.
In the meantime when he jumped out he shouts me: “I was saved!” I didn’t hear even.
Later on he told me. So I can be at ease he was not killed.
Anyhow, everything was outside of the boat except of me, I stayed on the boat.
Anyhow some petrol was there, jumped and get the petrol out
and finally he stopped 20 meters away and he turns around to pick up what is left from us.
Then I said to him “alright, we are saved, it’s ok.” We brought out the broken boat;
it didn’t sink because it had some places which doesn’t sink. We brought it out,
we left it and we went home.
I’ll tell you also another point; he had a little dog, he had brought with him.
This dog was always with him and he was at our house.
I walk first in my house and he is coming about 10 meters away from me
and I see the little dog barking entirely in a fright.
As he comes he says hey… the dog goes back, the dogs goes up the stairs
and the dog stops against the door upstairs and urinates. A great fright. We don’t pay attention.
It’s summer 7 o’clock in the afternoon when it actually happened.
He went to bed and slept from 7 o’clock. 9 o’clock the next day still deeply asleep.
10.00, 11.00, 12.00, 13.00… I go there and wake him up
and said “Do you want something to eat?” he said no.
He has a fever. So I brought a dose of op, 10M and gave it to him. The next day he had recovered.
This is the typical type of reaction of op. I give you this idea just to get the idea of the op reaction.
He didn’t feel anything because when we came back home,
as we walked to come from the sea to my house,we talked.
I asked “Are you afraid?”
– “No, I’m ok.”
- “Are you sure?”
- “Yes.”
So I was in peace that he was ok.
Actually the shock was so deep that he went into such a deep sleep, almost like a coma,
because of the fright. And it was a very interesting phenomenon for me to observe the little dog,
who was so connected with him being in such a fright. You couldn’t imagine the fright of the dog.
Something was happening. Most probably the dogs are watching, seeing the etheric body.
Do you know what the etheric body is? Who does not know what the etheric body is? One person.
You take the complete course and you will find out. We are talking about op.
Is this man an op case? Yes or no? No.
It can be an acon case? Why not? I’ll tell you the ther case.
They are very sensitive individuals whose nervous system is in a state of…
The idea is because the nervous system is in a state of excitement
the noise feels as if it goes through the body.
That means there is a noise and they feel pain in the body.
That is the typical ther aggravation from noise. They feel so much the noise
as if something is passing through their body and leaves a pain in the body.
That is the ther sensitiveness to noise. So he does not have this kind of noise.
So, acon, why not acon?
Acon is a remedy which can start a state, a pathology after the life has been threatened.
After somebody has threatened the individual “I will kill you. Give me your purse. Give me your money.
Give me your money quickly…”
That state can create such a deep fear that never leaves the individual
but what is the pathology that would develop in a kind of acon? What is the pathology?
You have to see the peculiarities of the remedies,
you have to see the organism went towards the acon state or in other state?
He had a shock that’s true.
If the shock went towards the acon state what we would have observed in him?
– Panic.
– Panic. Panic attacks.
That means in such cases the shock stimulates a part of the brain
which concerns itself with protection.
We have some mechanisms that say “here is a danger! Do this, do that”
There is a portion in the brain, there is an area in the brain which concerns our protection,
how to protect ourselves in a case of danger.
Now, in case the danger is fatal, that means I am going to die,
like in an earthquake or with the pistol, then this area is like a wound.
It remains in the brain like a wound which is stimulated every time there is a similar situation.
If the person finds itself in a kind of a similar situation the brain remembers it
It’s like opening that wound and then the panic attack comes.
If somebody has started panic attacks when he entered a lift and the lift stopped in the middle of nowhere
and became enclosed and the fear that “Now I’m going to die because I cannot call, I cannot find a way out etc.”
The moment he gets the shock, they come out; they take him out eventually, every time he goes into a lift, the panic starts.
Therefore, he will avoid the lifts, but sometimes he will go to places where he will think “Now I’m enclosed, I cannot get out”.
Then it’s a similar situation, that situation will bring about the panic attack.
Because he simulates the condition under which his life was threatened, in the same way.
Therefore, for Aconite, which has a strong fear of dying…
Ok, I’ll tell you something. If the shock is for Aconite, the fear of dying must be there.
That means “I’m going to die right now”, that means a panic attack, which is not the case.
and this is how you should answer me as good students you are.
This is how you answer me why not acon. Now slowly I’ll bring you to the solution of the case.
What about rhus-t?
He is cold, he is restless, likes gym, likes movement, motion… You are always asking questions.
- He said that he doesn’t like milk.
- Yes, that’s very good.
That’s why I asked him “You like milk?” He said no. Rhus-t is very much fond of milk.
They can drink 3 kilos milk a day. If you let them they will drink and drink a lot.
So this is one thing. The other thing is that… Now you tell me what is against rhus-t?
I’m not going to say everything myself. He wants cold drinks, ok that’s also a little bit…
In the morning he said “I feel tired but as soon as I get up I feel good.
It is not that after moving for ten minutes, then I feel good.”
He feels immediately, that is not rhus-t. Rhus-t wakes up in a stiff condition.
The cervical region, the back, the legs they are stiff.
He has to move for half an hour and then becomes better. But I forgot to get a point about rhus-t.
The way he sleeps.
He says “before I sleep I turn. If I sleep in the back I find myself always in the back.
That means during sleep there is no restlessness. He stays right there.
That is not good for rhus-t, if you want to give rhus-t. Rhus-t is restless during sleep as well.
This is the kind of surgical analysis of the case in order to come closer to the right remedy.
What about phos?
Phos he said it was the only remedy that affected him but was given again and again without effect.
So how come and why? The reason is that most probably phos is the second remedy.
His first remedy has not been found.
His second remedy which is underneath is phos but not a complete phos yet.
We need to give the first remedy to take out the first layer and then the phos becomes more clear
and then we’ll have a deeper effect. You are not impressed.
George talks whatever he likes, like this… No, I’m thinking all this time for everything.
I’m trying to reconstruct now. But one thing nobody asked me, why I ask…
- No she is not allowed to talk. If I know she knows, she’s not allowed to talk.
- I was wondering why you asked about the animals?
You asked him “Would you cry if a fly was killed”
- That was for phos. To confirm the sensitivity of the phos. Sympathetic. Not carc.
Let me see if you will find. Why I asked about the coffee.
You were not impressed that I asked about the coffee.
I ask something that should have impressed; why the hell George asked this question?
- You asked him if he sighs a lot. And he said no.
- He does a bit. He says sometimes. No, the impressive question was…
- You asked him if he is weeping when he is thanked.
- Yes. No.
- You asked about conscious…
- Yeees! Which country you come from?
- I’m French but I’m here with the English group.
- This is the question. What was the reason why I asked him about his conscience?
Why I asked him how he feels about his conscience?
He has something that bothers his conscience. Why? Nobody asked this question.
How come that I reached after a lot of questions I have asked,
I reached the state where I thought most probably
there is something bothering deeply in his conscience which does not allow him to let it
and go deep into sleep. Very simple.
And he was quite brave actually, I mean you will not get a lot of guys that will confess what he said.
But why he did it? You know what he thought by the moment he said it.
Because you remember he stopped for a while, he thought and I was quiet not by chance.
I was quiet for a reason, because I could see his reaction. There was right, the question.
What I was waiting? I didn’t want to bring him into a difficult situation
where I would ask him to tell us and then you remember he told us “Do you want me to tell you?”
I waited to see whether there was such a need from inside. It’s not typical and it’s not easy.
This kind of taking of the case is not easy at all to undress such a person.
And I usually do not intrude but I have to know what is useful for me to know to find the remedy.
And to differentiate between the one remedy and the other.
Because you can see 20 remedies have been given, correct?
All these remedies are having a basis, that means the one
who was prescribing was a good homeopath. But he was prescribing near, not exact.
The homeopath which prescribed is here? Anyhow it doesn’t matter.
So in the end of the story is that then I come to the realization there is something
which is deep bothering him, does not allow him to rest, to have real peace inside
because “there is something which I have done very bad, why did I do it, I was very stupid…”
But this does not appear as a logical argument within himself.
It appears as a subconscious problem that is there as a background.
He is not arguing with himself,
his conscience is now on a background making comments about him, what he did.
Not logically. It’s a background noise, it’s a noise and this noise does not allow.
It’s under an overexcitement of the nervous system which has remained open.
Now, I’ll bring you back to the idea of acon. I’ll tell you acon or op. How they will react.
Acon will have panic attacks, op will have sleepiness etc.
I come back now and I ask a question and I say “When I see that there is a stress, shock
and the shock does not go to this area in the brain, but what produces is sleeplessness,
is the main problem, when the shock with the overexcitement produces sleeplessness.
I got a fright and as a result I got sleeplessness. Which can be the remedy for this?
Show me the symptoms. Ok he has put 20 symptoms, how many? 20, ok.
Fear of being alone in the night, fear of snakes, tossing about in bed, weeping when alone,
weeping from joy, agglutinated at night, eyes.
He put all the symptoms in this bloody computer which sometimes imitates my mind.
Now show me the VES. Which is the remedy? Coff is the remedy which is needed.
Wow! I don’t say it myself only, this bloody thing is saying the same thing, right?
Show me now out of 20 symptoms how many symptoms are covered? Only 8 symptoms yet.
This says the remedy you have to consider is coff.
Coff in line how many symptoms it covers?
Tossing about in bed, weeping from joy, coryza in cold air aggravates, constriction in the rectum,
sleeplessness from abuse of coffee, waking from slightest noise, air draft aggravates
and cold aggravates.
I want to show where is standing in the flat repertorization something very interesting.
Ign is for flat repertorization. Nat-m, lyc…
Where is coff? Number 14. Ign, lyc, nat-m, sulph, ars, calc, phos, sep, chin
and all the rest… number 14.
But the VES says, watch out because this guy has some keynotes of coff.
When he’s nervous system was agitated by shock, the result was sleeplessness.
And he says if somebody thanks me… Coff is very excitable, they can cry with thanking them.
He said quite a lot and he said “I never took coffee. Because if I drink one cup of coffee…
I drank once 20 years ago and I couldn’t sleep the whole night.
See how sensitive is with the coff. Show me the symptom, aggravation from coffee.
The use of coffee aggravates, brings sleeplessness. Cham, nux-v and coff.
Nux-v was given for the same reason but this coff what will do?
It will cover the first layer not the whole of the case.
It will put him to sleep maybe we take a coff and maybe he sleeps for 3 days,
he will be very happy, I don’t believe but anyhow.
The coff will take out the upper layer and then underneath will come up.
Either the Ign if he has held inside grief or right away phos.
This is how a homeopathic analysis should be done to find the remedy.
Difficult case for students and for me as well, for teachers also.
So I was struggling quite a lot.
By putting away not this not that… you end up with the best possibility
and then suddenly I was confirmed.
I’l give you now the remedy, the coff, the potency that he must take for coff.
What is your idea? I just want to know.
Who will prescribe let us say CM? 50M? 10M? 1M? 200CH? 30CH?
The most it was between 200CH and 1M. He needs a very high potency.
He needs a 50M potency. It will take him 3 days to sleep. 3 days. 50M.
He needs a high potency because it was a stress
that brought about this stress in the nervous system.
- Come I want to give a follow up on your case. Coff. What happened?
- Maybe a few hours after I took coff there was a pain in my right testicle
and for maybe 10 years ago I had a kick at this place
and it didn’t feel so good for a couple of days, by that time.
- And you had a return of this pain after?
- Not until now, no.
- Now after coff… you have a return.
- Also today but it goes a little bit. And yesterday evening,
I’m not sure if it was the coff or if it was the wine, I never drink wine,
I’m sensitive to wine I think, but maybe it was the coff picture also.
I drank half a glass of wine and fell asleep maybe after 20-30 minutes
and I slept really good for 5 hours.
And then a bird above me at the same time every morning at 6 o’clock
- Same bloody bird.
- But I could fall asleep again. I couldn’t the other days.
- So the wine did a good job!
- Yes.
- Any change in your psychology?
- I’m not sure.
- Ok, we’ll see. Ok, thank you. For the sake of the class.
You see I didn’t want to say yesterday that he will go into a comatose state of sleep.
After seducing the excitement of the nervous system how long it will continue
and when the next remedy will be ready.