- We can start. You read this report yourself.
- My daughter was born in October 2011 by caesarian operation
because the delivery was very long, non-progressing
and the contraction was slowly subsiding.
After 12 hours the physician decided for an operation.
- You speak too fast. Slowly please.
- Ok.
After 12 hours the physician decided for operation.
She was born according to schedule 3,95 kg APGAR score 9/9/10. She was symptom free.
Except few café au lait spots but nobody told us that anything is wrong with her.
The café au lait spots became more visible and their amount gradually increases.
- How many café au lait spots she has now?
- About 50.
- They’re increasing every month.
- Yes. After 2 months she had about 50 café au lait spots, I think now it’s more.
We didn’t count.
- But you saw some more, some new.
- Yes.
After 2 months she had about café au lait spots and we started to search “what is it?”
and we found out that it could be sign of neurofibromatosis type 1
which is calling also von Recklinghausen syndrome.
Then the neurologist confirmed this diagnosis according to the specific symptoms
which are multiple café au lait spots and frecklings of a specific kind.
He also found out that the head of our daughter has very slight tendency
to fall to the right side but it was 2 months ago and now it seems to be good.
It was very slight it was not something serious.
And neurologist said he was not sure if it’s part of the disease or if it is normal
because it was so slight… Normal in this age.
According to him it might be but it doesn’t have to be a symptom of this disease.
Also we found her left leg about 1cm longer than the right.
This disease does not have a specific picture in every patient
and can have all kind of troubles. Some patients have signs which are very mild
but other may develop very serious problems.
The child is psychologically very good, very calm, very happy and always smiling.
The only problem from the very beginning was that she had problems falling asleep
just in the evening.
- She has a problem? What is the problem? Not falling asleep?
- Yes. She cries.
- She cannot fall asleep in the afternoon?
- Just evening.
- She cannot fall asleep at night?
- Yes.
- She cannot fall asleep that means she stays awake and cries.
- Also in the early months she was extremely sensitive to noises
that caused frightening and screaming. I gave her just one remedy, carc.
Because of sleeplessness in the evening
and because we both have family anamnesis of cancer.
My father developed cancer in 45, the mother of my wife developed cancer in her 40s.
Both of our parents had skin cancer and I gave her a carc. 1M and it was in February.
After carc 1M she had 2 days aggravation of the mood, she was screaming
and after that the sleeping was good. Until now she is sleeping, there is no problem.
But the café au lait spots are multiplying.
- Also she developed this lump on her head, we don’t know what it is that.
- Maybe wart, we don’t know. Nobody saw it. It is very small.
- A little growth.
- You can see it.
- It’s like a hard pimple.
- But it doesn’t disappear for a month and a half it’s still there.
- It grows?
- No. But with her condition we are not sure…
- You’re afraid.
- Yes.
- She is good otherwise?
- Yes, she is lovely, she is nice.
- No restlessness, she loves people, no problem. But here in Alonissos
because maybe it’s the change of the environment, she is more…
- She screams but is not… She just likes to scream I don’t know why.
- She is smiling and now… without reason, you know…
- She cries?
- No, very rarely. Only when she is hungry.
- A lot of salivation?
- No. Only when she has teething.
- She likes to eat everything? What does she eat?
- Everything that she grabs she puts it in her mouth.
- You breast feed her?
- Not anymore. I did it for 2 months.
- Why?
- I didn’t have enough milk, so we gave her more…
- Baby powder milk with water.
- That’s all she has. Egg? You give her any egg?
- No.
- Any fruits?
- Yes, apples or bananas.
She likes sweet more. She eats anything we give her actually.
I gave her a lemon the other day and she ate it. Just to taste it…
- She was screaming and during the lunch… My wife was just “take the lemon”
and she calmed with the lemon.
- But she may be calm with anything. She likes to taste things. But lemon was interesting.
- You tried lemon again to see if…
- No, she licked the lemon like it is…
- She enjoyed it.
- Yes.
- Very strange. Which leg is longer, the left?
- Perspiration during sleep?
- Not specific.
Sometimes when she is in the cradle and it’s hot she is really very very perspirated in the neck,
but normally not. It’s not a rule.
- I know when she wants to sleep, it’s only at night or in the evening,
she puts her thumb in her ear and scratches her ear.
You can see that her ears are… there is a little bit of blood because she does this.
- Itching in the ear, on the left?
- Both ears.
- This is only at night or during the day time too?
- Only at night when she wants to fall asleep.
- The fontanelles are closed?
- Not fully but she is 7 months old so it’s not…
- And also she has this… in her head. Our doctor said it’s normal but…
- These red spots. Now it’s disappearing slowly.
- We go inside to discuss the case.
- Ok. Can I be there?
- Yes.
Ok, which is the remedy? She has one symptom, itching in the ear. That’s all.
So we prescribe a remedy for itching in the ear.
The analysis is very short because I don’t want to bother you. Carc. was correct,
that was 2 months ago. The child is sleeping well.
The main problem with the child was sleeplessness, irritability before falling asleep.
It shows the whole imbalance in the organism as far as symptoms are concerned,
it was only the brown spots and the disturbance in the sleep
which we could use as guiding symptoms.
Due to the hereditary predisposition.
He gave carc and carc is supposed to have produced these café au lait spots
and therefore carc is correct and we must not change it. We must not touch this case.
If you touch it, you can make a damage. You’re disappointed. That’s it.
What may happen is that after some time, after a few months,
a year or so the child will develop some indications, some symptoms
that can guide us to the next remedy.
But to touch her with a remedy while we are in the dark, it is stupid, we should not do it.
It doesn’t matter how much the mother or the father pressurize you to give a remedy,
you give placebos.
- Can I ask you, the fact that the café au lait spots are increasing…
- It’s a good sign because it’s the externalization of the problem.
So maybe she will go through with a mild type of the problem.
Don’t worry, it will stop and eventually after 6 months to 1 year they will stop coming down
and becoming less and less prominent. I hope everything will be well without any more...
But we are in touch.