This is the case of a 36 year old lady, married
and her main problem seems to be the fear of pregnancy.
- Fear of everything.
- She thinks being pregnant is a weird, frightening process.
She scares that this is one-way road. No turning back. And also her vision of babies is different.
When she looks at them she sees them like they are immature human.
- Yes, not cute for me. As immature, not to talk, not to walk. Needs to be grown up.
- Have you studied medicine?
- Yes I am a gynecologist also, obstetrician.
- Were you a good student?
- Yes very good.
- I can see it. She has serious fears while she is alone.
In your studies in order to memorize it was easy for you or difficult?
- Easy. Very easy.
- Fear of airplane all the time, fear of death, fear of losing her mind, fear of insanity,
fear of losing loved ones, fear of being closed… of being enclosed you mean in a narrow place?
- Yes.
- Like in the elevator, do you enter the elevator?
- When you are alone?
- Yes.
- You work in the hospital.
- Fear of tunnels. When you go through the tunnel you start having panic?
- Yes, when I’m alone.
- If somebody is next to you?
- No, nothing.
- You hold him?
- No, no fear.
- When there’s nobody her heartbeat goes extremely up.
- I stop the car at the beginning of the tunnel and I take the medicine if I don’t see the end.
- You fell you’re enclosed now, you’re going to die.
- Die or getting insane. And also with bridges. Same thing occurs with the bridge.
- When she drives on the bridge…
- … fear of earthquake, fear of dark, fear of elevator, fear of airplane,
her heart beat increases rapidly, she gets in panic states and cannot fly without medication. Xanax.
- With airplane, a company is not working, alone or with someone I fear the airplane.
- You feel panic.
- Panic, going insane, not to get out, what I am doing?
- Confusion.
- Very confused.
- Cries like a child and cannot control, she wants to get out of the plane.
- “Wait, wait, wait” I can say…
- And she takes Xanax.
- When did you meet each other?
- 2 years almost.
- And you married straight away.
- 6 or 7months later.
- But you had other girlfriends before.
- Yes.
- And also you had boyfriends?
- But when did it start? These panic attacks. What was the first experience?
- Panic attack started at the age of 17 when I was beginning studying for an exam.
- When did it start?
- 17.
- In Turkey?
- Yes.
- In the age of 18 in Turkey we have the university exam. To enter the university.
One exam. If you pass you go to university if you don’t pass you have to wait one year.
It is generally high stress for everybody.
- That time started. You have taken before a kind of medicine to take the examinations,
to make your mind clear…?
- No, no medicine before that.
- I hope you have discussed everything because I will put some difficult questions.
- Yes go ahead.
- Have you used marijuana before?
- No.
No cigarette at all. I have not touched cigarettes at all.
- No marijuana, no drugs.
- Just alcohol. Social drinker. Once a month.
- Alcohol affects her easily. If she drinks 2 glasses of wine, she relaxes very easily. Highly relaxed.
- You can ask everything… He knows everything.
-  I believe. Now what I want to know is… the life up to 18 you had any serious disease
or infectious disease or epidemic…? It’s written here. Medical background.
Surgery?
- After that.
- Appendix. When the appendix was operated?
- 32.
- When she was 32.
- No serious diseases, just smallpox, mumps.
- You had smallpox?
- Yes, in the childhood.
- As a child? No chickenpox?
- Chickenpox sorry! Mumps. Long period of bronchitis.
- What were you doing for bronchitis?
- Medicines.
- What kind of medicines you were doing for bronchitis?
- Syrup.
- The first bronchitis came with fever? You remember that fever? You never had fever?
- No I had. In my childhood. I remember the cold things here and here.
- What age?
- Before 17 but I don’t remember. Maybe 7 or 10… In elementary school.
- And after this bronchitis then you remained with a kind of a chronic bronchitis?
- Stopped in the childhood. No bronchitis. Nothing.
- And your menses came at what age?
- 12. It’s regular.
- And premenstrual syndrome?
- Very bad. Only psychologically.
- But you are irritated, you are depressed, you are anxious, you are angry? All of these.
- Yes. Character changes almost 70% with the period. I am a different one.
- Different? A bad person?
- Anxious and depressed.
- Weeping, crying very easily.
- Highly sensitive and can cry easily.
- But not dysmenorrhea, no pains at all.
- Menses last for how long?
- 5-6 days.
- With a lot of blood?
- Not a lot.
- Which is the day with the most blood?
- 2nd, 3rd.
- The blood is clear, bright blood?
- No. Dark.
- Dark and with some clots?
- Yes. Not black but dark, brownish.
- And it is not stringy?
- No.
- Can I say something? Before the age of 17 my psychological period is difficult.
Not for the physiological one but the psychological because my parents were fighting.
Every night my…
- Let me explain this because this is a thing we have discussed.
During the age of 5 and 6 she witnessed her mother cheating on her father with another man.
At the age of 5.
- I saw and I didn’t tell anyone but she didn’t understand I saw her and also…
- She also was talking with a new man, and as a child at the age of 5 she did not understand
therefore in front of her they were kissing and she didn’t take her as a person.
She thought she wouldn’t understand.
- Her mother thought she was too young.
- Exactly.
And this continued 20 years with different men. It started from the age of 5 until the age of 25.
Nobody told her not to say to her father anything but she decided herself
not to tell to her father anything and after a while at the age of 20s
her mother took one of her lovers and introduced to her like a friend, like a normal thing.
And this time at the age of 25 she said to her mother…
- Not to hear, not to see, not to get any news about this part.
Told my mum not to tell me anything anymore.
- But 20 years between 5 and 25 she lived with this kind of pressure.
Knowing everything, hiding from her father, hiding from everybody
but a part of time she was a friend of her mother like sisters but when the time changed,
when she grew up, at the age of 25, said “This is too much for me.
I don’t anything to hear about anything, just don’t tell me anything”
but she knew her mother was continuing because of her mobiles…
But 20 years there was high pressure. This is what we think.
Now if we look behind this is what we think, this is one of the serious psychological things.
- Let me understand. When this bad psychological state
which you had since childhood at what time became unbearable?
At what age? 17, 18, 20 after 20?
- After 20. 24 maybe. Stopped the relationship.
- Gradually you became worse and worse… Claustrophobic.
- After earthquake. 1999.
- 25. Because at the age of 25 it is the same year, maybe with one year difference,
there was an earthquake in Turkey.
She was at the age of 25 after the earthquake her fears about death and losing her mind increased.
- Losing my mind started with earthquake. Just this fear.
- Anxiety after fright.
- This is the only one fear of my fears, that starts with earthquake exactly.
I know the time. I see the people like creatures. I see world like this…
- You saw the world  becoming very small.
- And the sky comes on her.
- Cannot open my eyes because I see the things not that before…
I can’t understand what is this… did not recognize.
I took the medicine Xanax 4 times daily at that time.
- At the earthquake.
- I went to the psychiatrist and said I can take this.
- You have taken several remedies. How many?
- 4.
- Which remedies? You have not written here.
- First one is lach.
- Then?
- Stram. Arg-n. Hyosc. Med.
- One dose. The jealousy is also very high. Number three it’s in the paper.
- With all your lovers you were jealous?
- Yes.
- You were imagining things or you were jealous with a reason?
- No.
- He looks another woman.
- No. Imagining.
My imagination runs a lot. I imagine a lot. I’m not speaking.
- You were thinking it was very easy to cheat on you.
- Yes.
- She can see or she can assume every chance I can cheat on her.
Yes, because again I think when a person at the age between 5 and 25 is growing up
in this kind of family environment is very sensitive cause
probably she experienced many different ways of cheating in her childhood,
therefore she is imagining, she is assuming everything that can happen.
For example if I go abroad for a work trip, job, business trip for 2 days..
- She has to call you 20 times...
- No! I’m just thinking and press myself not to tell.
- She tries not to call me but those 2 days she cannot sleep.
- Just thinking things. But not to tell him…
- What you are experiencing.
- Yes. After he comes, yes, I say.
- But now I know. After the journey I know what is coming after.
- Arrhythmia and tachycardia. You have arrhythmia.
- Yes, sometimes.
- Missing beats.
- Yes paroxysmal. I saw the cardiologist, perhaps it is atrial tachycardia.
- And the cardiologist is worried about your heart?
- No.
- He says…
- No. It’s psychological.
- They couldn’t find any physical or biological substances. But it goes really high.
- She became more quarrelsome, premenstrual… more jealous,
more fragile that her social life is affected, she has migraine attacks during this period.
The premenstrual period, you get headaches?
- Yes, headaches. Not all the time.
- Where?
- Here.
- On the left side.
- Yes.
- Fragile, very sensitive, weeps very easily for personal matters, can be childish,
has very high perception. You are intuitive? What do you mean perception?
- I can see everything, I can hear everything, I see, hear…
- Your hearing is very sensitive or your eyes, you can see well. Your five senses are increased.
- Yes. Also sixth sense increased.
- That means you perceive, you are intuitive.
- Yes. She is like a radar. She is very sensitive to the high volume voice,
even when you are talking normally can be destructive for her. High voice is destructive.
- Do you have a good appetite?
- So and so.
- Thirst?
- Yes, it’s normal.
- For cold water?
- Yes.
- Very cold?
- Yes I can drink it.
- She likes cold water. She can’t drink normal water.
Winter and summer from the refrigerator. Even in the winter. And she loves salt.
- That means you take the salt before you taste?
- Yes. Always.
- As for appetite, we are very similar. She cannot eat hot, spicy food, pepper… Zero tolerance.
- How about fish?
- Yes. Some sort of fish.
- What about oysters?
- Yes, she likes.
- What about meat?
- So and so. Normal.
- Sweets?
- From time to time she likes a lot.
- In premenstrual periods I have high appetite.
- And high desire for sweets.
- You like ice cream?
- Not much.
- You are not afraid of thunderstorms?
- No.
- She is afraid of almost everything but thunderstorms.
- I can see I can be with…
- And you are not afraid of ghosts or supernatural things?
- Maybe I am afraid but…
- Didn’t think about it before. She cannot eat sour food. Zero tolerance.
Vinegar she doesn’t like. No tolerance.
- What about at your sleep? You sleep right through the night?
Do you wake up during the night?
- No.
- You sleep right through. And in the morning you wake up refreshed?
- Sometimes.
- Most of the times?
- Good.
- Also if she needs to wake up in the middle of the night, like three o’clock the telephone calls
and she needs to go to birth, because she is a doctor, she wakes up fresh and very quick.
Not sleepy, just fresh. And she is not a type of a person that she sticks in the bed.
You know some people, they just like bed, but when she gets up, she gets up.
She is not like sleepy. She gets up really quickly.
- Fruits? You like?
- Yes.
- Which fruits? All kinds of fruits?
- Yes, can be.
- Oranges?
- Yes, we eat oranges.
- Bananas?
- Yes.
- Do you grind your teeth in sleep?
- I don’t know.
- You never heard?
- I never heard.
- You sleep very deeply.
- I sleep very deeply in certain hours... When I sleep, I sleep deep.
But when I wake up, I wake up.
- When the meat has some fat you will take it?
- Yes I can take it. Lamb chops I can.
- You are affected mostly by heat or by cold?
Do you feel the cold very much or you feel the heat very much if you are bothered…
- Both actually, I don’t like very hot places and I don’t like the sun too much.
I don’t like cold places but when I’ m at home when it is cold I don’t like to wear…
- She turns the heater on.
- The home should be like 24-26 degrees.
- What age did you put this mark?
- 24.
- What was the idea that your friend told you “do it”?
Or you decided?
- Yes.
- What is this?
- Butterfly.
- There are 2 tattoos there. The first one under this one is a dragon, under this.
And I don’t like it.
- And you covered it with the butterfly.
- This is the filema written free, it is my name Ozgul, in Turkish.
- And dragonfly is her Chinese horoscope sign.
- This is the dragonfly and this tattoo was like first and her name was written there, free.
And one year later she changed it with the butterfly.
- You never expected I will ask this question.
- We learn.
- Of course.
- In sleep do you have any salivation?
Saliva in the pillow?
- No.
- Any perspiration around that area?
- During sleep, no.
- Do you have any problem with the stool? Do you have a bowel motion every day
or you are constipated?
- Sometimes I’m constipated, when we travel sometimes and also I’m shy about doing this thing,
when he is at home, I cannot. If he goes away I can freely, yes.
- Very interesting.
- And also one thing we wrote down here… she likes to control everything.
- Everything, every one. Every event, every person should be controlled.
- Every person?
- Yes, she wants to. She wants to know everything, what’s happening, how happens.
- Yes I’ m curious.
- High level of curiosity. Especially I think this is related to jealousy in relationship.
She is not jealous for example about cars, about money, about material things.
For example she doesn’t want an airplane, a new car, but…
- But she wants to know where you are.
- All jealousy is on person nothing about material things or job or money.
- Are you self-confident? About your job?
- Until an age I was very self-confident about myself.
Until the age of 25 I was like “Wow! What am I?” after that something went downwards.
Maybe the earthquake, maybe the relationship…
- Your first relationship with a man was at what age?
- 17.
- Full relationship?
- Yes.
- You enjoyed it or it was not a good experience?
- Yes, I enjoyed it.
- And you had a cystitis after that contact if you remember?
- No. I don’t remember that.
- But you have frequent cystitis.
- Yes.
- When did it start? The age of 20?
- No, maybe 30.
- The cystitis is with pain or discomfort?
- Discomfort.
Like, I can sit all the day. If no job I can sit there and warm things here and wait.
- And this can come by itself, the crisis of cystitis?
- It starts near menstruation, approaching menstruation.
- Cold bathing affects?
- No.
But maybe my feet are always cold; summer, winter, always.
- But cystitis comes…
- Often with stressful conditions.
It will come. I think of something bad, psychologically in deep and it will come.
- Stress increases.
- Can I add something? I got pregnant. In the past.
- But now you take precautions.
- Yes, protection.
- You have never had free sex by chance…?
- No I have intrauterine device. When I was pregnant I was very nauseous
that I didn’t see a patient in my job period time. I thought I could jump from the window.
It was very bad nausea, no medicine could control me.
- The thing is she cannot control anything she cannot return back makes her anxious,
makes her nervous. For example she cannot get in the boat
because she thinks this is not under control.
Because the boats in the sea she cannot come back if she want it.
She cannot get on the plane because she is afraid she has no control.
If she changes her mind she cannot get out of the plane, she cannot get out of the boat.
Pregnancy more or less the same is like one-way ticket.
If she changes her mind after 4 months, she cannot get rid of it.
Anything that is not controlled by her makes her terribly nervous.
One or two things we may like to add if you are ok.
- Nail biting. Also perspiration in the genitalia, after bath it perspires a lot.
- Perspiration is offensive?
- Not smelly… high sexuality.
- How high?
- High. As much as we can.
- Every day?
- Yes, couple of times a day.
- Do you have an orgasm?
- Yes.
- You know what is an orgasm?
- Yes, she is a doctor.
- Many times women do not know what an orgasm is.
They don’t have final satisfaction and they need constant stimulation.
- I did masturbate when I was at the age of 4-5.
- She did her first masturbation at the age of 5.
- I remember doing it very frequently.
- With your hands? Or you were pushing…?
- With my hands after 18 but before like crossing the legs.
- One more thing. After our experience we have some notes.
For example if she walks down the steps she cannot walk with 2 legs.
She always needs to put the left leg on the front and slowly.
- Like you will fall.
- Yes, but with speed, I put my left leg 2-3 steps down, always left.
- Normally I go left- right-left. She does it left- left- left.
- You will have to get through my secretary, you will have to get my e-mail,
so you’ ll have to write a report, stop coffee, stop all medication
and then you write a report in 2 months.
- After finishing the remedy.
- Yes and for her also. So I can know how to continue.
- Perfect.
- What’s the remedy?
- What’s your remedy? I don’t know.
- If I tell you now the class…
Now this is an easy case, so therefore I will let you study it
and in the afternoon you will give me your decision in a little piece of paper.
And I will do the analysis and see, who is a good student..
No with a name, we don’t disclose names here. We are learning.
I learned a lot today with this case and yesterday,
every day if you do this kind of homeopathy you will learn.
Because this is a big issue with this case, not so easy. We will see.
Did you like the case?
- Yes.
- Was it interesting?
- Why it was interesting? When the patient is open and communicates
then there is a reciprocal energy that’s going back and out.
That does not make you exhausted.
But if the person is closed and does not allow expression
and you battle to get the information to help that person… it is very difficult, very tiring.
With these two very nice people, on a certain level
that means they are quite healthy though with all these fears…
This case seems easy but it is difficult.
Who wrote plat.? Who wrote ambra grisea? Who wrote acon? Who wrote phos? Who wrote staph?
Who wrote nat-m? Who wrote hyos? In between. I see the problem.
I thought 80% would write the same remedy but I was wrong. It was equal.
Different people wrote different things.
I will have a problem because this case appears to be quite clear. It is a clear case.
Here you have a baby who is sexually very active,
so with this idea I understand some of you prescribed plat.
Now let’s see whether the plat continued to be right through the case or what has happened.
Between 6-21 year there are some changes and she becomes more and more anxious,
more and more phobic, claustrophobic especially.
There is a symptom which I thought you would have taken notice
of much more than you did and that symptom it was if you understood,
that she could not have a stool unless she is alone in the house. Even her husband is going away.
That is a symptom of ambr-g, so definitely there is plat, there is the possibility of ambr-g,
shall we give plat or ambr-g? Or phos? She had some symptoms of phos, not complete phos.
because her main problem at the moment is the fears.
Fear of death, fear of being closed in a place, panic attacks.
But she says when I ask her “When these panic attacks started really?”
she said “It was the day I was in the earthquake”. So during this time we must consider
that something new overwhelmed the organism and created a new state of mind.
She says: “I was almost crazy, I didn’t know where I was.”
A big change in her mental state due to this fright.
So ailments from fright should be considered as a symptom you have to take into consideration.
So ailments from fright, do you have some symptoms?
Ailments from fright; we have several remedies on very high level.
Forth level, which is; acon, op and stram. So the fear is in such intensity you cannot ignore it.
Not only the fear is strong but it has created a new state of health.
Therefore you have to consider it as something acute that happened
and established a new state of health.
You should not go away from these remedies here.
The next thing you ask is which of these remedies have fear of narrow places?
Going into panic in narrow places? There are two out of them.
Mostly two, acon and stram, not op. Op is gone.
So your choice should have been between these two remedies.
Now, what is another element which is very strong in her mental state? Which is the symptom.
Fear of death. Acon is in the 3rd degree, stram is in the 1st.
Stram does not have actually real fear of death.
The remedies that have very strong fear of death are ars, plat, acon should be on the 4th degree
together with ars and plat. Make a note.
So between stram and acon fear of narrow places, panic attacks,
you know that acon has tremendous panic attacks that cannot be controlled.
They get into panic attacks that there is no control, even if somebody is next to them
the moment that the panic starts, it doesn’t matter. She just wants to fly away from the situation.
It’s a remedy that creates tremendous panic attacks. Show me the explanation for acon…
Acon is the first of course. It has fear of airplane, very strong. You see that in the 4th degree.
Ailments from fright, fear on tunnels, before menses aggravates, fear of the dark,
fear of death, biting nails, desire for water, palpitations, weeping mood,
fear of insanity, hearing acute.
Clairvoyance, irregular pulse, headache during menses.
Acon therefore covers most of her syptoms.
So we were lead to acon because of the beginning stage
but then we found out acon is supported very well by her symptomatology.
I will tell you another secret today, concerning hi and low potencies.
She is in group… In what group would you place her? Group 1, 2 frequent acutes? No. Group 3.
So she is in group 3 because we consider this a mental case
where the immune system has been severely suppressed and oppressed, cannot have an acute.
When she had an acute she was much back in her life. So therefore this is group C.
In this group I really mean I will give acon 50M. She is amazed. You don’t understand, yes.
I give 50M , I like your reaction, you have to react,
“he tells us this now he tells us that, what’s going on…” What we said this is an uppermost layer
which I consider as an acute. I’m not prescribing there for plat which is much deeper.
If will go to her childhood we may find plat. Those of you who prescribed plat…
Plat, if it is given now it will change the case, simply. Will not help.
Will change the symptoms will appear, this is less… that is more…
this is changed but not real change.
So you have to unravel the case by giving the first remedy
which is the remedy for panic attacks which fits very well.
But that remedy is not going to touch the underlying pathology.
The underlying pathology is quite deep. Why this deep pathology has happened?
First, because the hormonal system of the child is overbalanced.
The estrogens etc. are in tremendous excess, she could not control it she had to masturbate,
she had to release the excessive sexual energy that was coming from the imbalance.
If you go now at this stage and try to touch that point, it’s too deep
and the acon will not allow you to do anything. First get rid of my fear,
of that tremendous shock which I had.
And if you get out the shock then we may be able to see underneath.
What are we going to see underneath? Nat-m. Maybe nat-m maybe something else. What else?
What do we expect to see underneath? Staph. I’m not sure.
There is a remedy most probably that will come. I’m not sure.
But most probably the remedy that comes second to help her will be ambr-g.
Show me now in the line of the repertorization. I will explain to you a little.
Ambr-g is the second remedy. Now how many symptoms she has?
Ambr-g has aversion to presence (of strangers) cannot have a stool, desire for salt,
palpitation in the heart, fear of insanity, perspiration in inguinal region.
You see therefore you have a remedy which contains two keynotes of this case.
One is that she cannot have a stool in the presence of anybody,
the second is perspiration in the inguinal region. Very interesting.
You see fear to have a stool which is connected with some kind of sexual activity is withheld,
cannot be seen, does not want to be seen with ambr-g.
We are theorizing now but anyhow I can tell you how a child,
who is so much aware of her sexuality withholds later on in life an act
which is connected somewhat with the sexual function. How is it connected?
Do you understand my English? You did not hear it quite well. I can see it in your eyes, ok.
Be careful what you think…
Well, I said that the fact that she cannot have a stool in front of anybody, even her husband,
it is a sign most probably that she is withholding an action
which is similar or near to kind of sexual act because she was aware of her sexuality
and she was also aware of what happens because of the sexuality.
So the combination, you remember you don’t follow now.
The combination of not being able to let loose because I do something
and I connect it in my little mind with what I saw in my mother.
She understood everything, what was going on, she was watching, she knew everything,
she is doing sex, I know sex etc. and you are doing something with another man
and she knows everything.
And that combination between the intensity of her sexuality and at the same time seeing,
realizing what sexuality can lead a person to do, she knew, my mother is doing something wrong.
That most probably brought about a new state of health.
So if we had this child as a patient at the age of 7-8 we would say, sexuality is excessive, plat.
And most probably it would be balanced.
But now the child was left without treatment
and the fact that she knows all this secret about the sexual things which are happening,
most probably she is withholding. It’s “no, I don’t want to be seen”.
Most probably the second remedy will be ambr-g. and possibly the third remedy will be plat.
- …
- Yes it is very interesting that ambr-g has such strong symptom.
This symptom for ambr-g is a strong keynote. Then hyos, you will see hyos, show me hyos.
Hyos is the third remedy you will see… how many symptoms? 12.
Ambr-g has only 6 covering but has 2 keynotes of the case. And the system says “be careful”.
Hyos has 12. Now see phos. 15 symptoms. Yet you give phos. Nothing.
- So how does this system tell you to “be careful with ambr-g”?
- Because it contains two keynotes of the case. If you look at ambr-g it contains 2 keynotes.
One; cannot have a stool, the other is the peculiar perspiration in the inguinal region.
No other remedy has that.
- But how does.. you said the system tells you to…
- Just because it shows you that in spite of the fact that it has only 6 symptoms out of 20,
still you have to be careful about that. Because it comes quite high.
It could have been first even. So if you see, then you have to decide of course
and then you go to the M.M. you see, it fits or it doesn’t fit and you give it or you don’t give it.
Bringing up in your attention remedies who are not having all the symptoms.
- During the earthquake she told us that she had a delusion that things are going smaller and smaller.
- And came over her.
- And this is a symptom of plat. How can you explain it?
- No, no it is not a symptom of plat. It is different.
What she says is the whole world became small and came upon her and overwhelmed her,
so it’s not a matter of looking something as smaller than what really is. But plat is underneath.
- What about the fear of pregnancy?
- Something also that I have to explain and to say is that after acon
the symptoms of acon will be reduced very much and some other fears may remain.
Fear of death maybe remain, but not as panic attacks.
She may still have fear of death; she may still have fear of bearing a child.
- I have a question about the levels of health
because the frequent cystitis she has every 2 months, I thought it was group C.
- That’s a good question, yes. So what do you say? I’m in a difficult state now.
When I say acute, I mean something, an infection that has high fever.
In those levels, group 3, there is hectic fever or no fever at all, some infection is there
but the organism does not have the strength to get rid of it.
After acon she may develop frequent cystitis with fever and then we have to treat.