He was born a normal child and he developed autism after when he was a year and a half.
He was immunized and shortly after that he became severely autistic.
However, even before that there were certain…
- What were the vaccinations?
- MMR.
- That’s all. Previously he had other vaccinations?
- A few. Not all. Because we were postponing everything. I don’t like vaccinations.
- Why you were postponing, you were afraid?
- Well I don’t like vaccinations at all but I couldn’t find a way to get rid of it
because I knew in Canada it’s not a law but I couldn’t find a way to evade this.
Everybody was telling there is a paper but I couldn’t find how to get the paper.
So… when he was at the age of 3. He didn’t have after that any… so I was postponing…
- So that means he had some at the age of 6 months?
- Yes some.
- Can you give me an idea? What exactly happened with the vaccinations?
- He only had one reaction…
- When it was the first vaccination and what was the vaccination?
- I think he was 2 months old but I don’t know what, I have it at home.
- Usually in Canada 2 and a half they do a diphtheria vaccination.
- For tetanus?
- Tetanus and diphtheria. That’s what they do 2 and a half.
- That was 2 months. Then again?
- I don’t remember. I have a paper but I don’t have it with me.
- But he didn’t react to them really.
- There was a preparation on the organism by these vaccinations.
And the 3rd time came the vaccination and the organism broke down.
It does not break down like that. The last vaccination what was it?
- MMR.
- And it was an anamnesis? It was given before this and repeated?
- No. It was the first time that he got it.
- And it was one and a half year old.
- Yes.
At that time also I stopped breast feeding him so, his was breast fed until 18 months.
He got rubella and 2 months after that he got his first big fever treated with antibiotics.
- You gave him antibiotics.
- She. She is the doctor.
- Is she a doctor?
- No, the doctor gave it.
And then we went to Serbia because we are originally from Serbia
and my husband’s mother died and then we went back to Canada.
The kid got again throat infection, again treated with double antibiotics.
After that I noticed something, he was lost.
- So there was a vaccination. Then after the vaccination there were several times tonsillitis.
2 times or 3 times?
- 3 times.
First before Serbia and then after Serbia. In between 6 months.
- Three times tonsillitis and the last time you said he needed double vaccination?
- Double antibiotics.
- Because the fever would not go down?
- Yes.
- Also the trauma, she mentioned to me that when she stopped breast feeding he became very sad.
- She?
- No, the child.
- He never reacted to it and it surprised me because I went to a friend 2 days,
I came back and he never – he loved breast feeding- and he never reacted.
And I felt terrible because we were sort of talking to each other,
I was asking him “Are you ready to cut off”.
So we cut it off and then he just didn’t react to it.
And I found that very strange, I felt I had betrayed my child
because he didn’t react to something that he really liked, he never asked about it.
So he suppressed his reaction.
- When you cut the breast feeding there was the vaccination.
And after 3 days you stopped? Or after 3 months you stopped breast feeding?
- Before. He was 1 year old when she stopped breast feeding him…
- No, a year and a half.
- He was a year and a half when you stopped breast feeding him.
- Exactly.
- Then he was vaccinated. How long after the cut off?
- Maybe a few days, a week or two weeks the most.
- And then the tonsillitis, when it came?
- So this was July 15th, tonsillitis in the beginning of November, that’s 4 months.
- 4 months later he developed severe tonsillitis.
Very high fever?
- Yes.
- Very high, 40C-41,5C.
- Ok.
Given antibiotics for how long, one week?
- Yes.
- Then you went to Serbia.
- Yes, it was emotional a very big thing, he really liked the grandma,
he was playing with her on her bed. She died from cancer
so the day that she went to the hospital he was crying. He knew she was going to die.
He was crying when she left.
- By the time that you went to Serbia he was already 2 years old.
- Not really, it was December when we went…
- 22 months.
- Yes.
- Has he started talking already?
- No he was late. Late talking. After that he started diminishing.
He started talking before that…
- You told me at 9 months he talked.
- Yes.
- Ok, when he was one and a half year old, when you cut breast feeding,
you were communicating by words with him?
- Yes.
- He was saying “yes”, “no”?
- He could understand what you were asking?
- Yes.
I would say to him “Bring the bottle” and he would go to other room and bring the bottle.
At the age of 4 my son couldn’t do that anymore. He had words.
We were reading a book, the cow says “moo” and he knew all that.
- You must tell that to the medical authorities.
- I know.
- They don’t want to listen. There were a few problems before with him
because he started teething very early. At 4 months he got his first teeth.
And then his teeth at the age of 2 crumbled. In that period they were also getting bad.
- And the teeth fell off at the age of 2?
- No, crumbled. Like lots of cavities.
Especially the fore front that he got at 4 months.
So when he was one year old all his teeth were out. He had all teeth at one year.
- Ok, then?
- When I first saw him in the beginning of 2008 he was not communicating with anybody.
He was just running around in circles, making noise
and she said “I cannot communicate with my son. I cannot get through.” And she was crying.
- He was by that time 4 years old.
- No, 3 years old.
- And you started giving…?
- No, first I didn’t know what to do, just running around.
I repertotized her, I gave her staph and she is just one remedy per se.
- You gave to the mother?
- Yes.
I do that with babies too, I give them the mother remedy first.
He also had staph symptoms with the teeth. They were all covered with yellow stuff.
- She was not breast feeding.
- I know. May be the right thing to do.
He reacted to staph, he started sleeping through the night, so after
that I thought about some more. I gave him carc.
So he was doing very well on carc and half a year later I gave him tub.
He had lot of allergies, severe. And he is grinding his teeth,
he is very restless at night and sweaty…
- But he has no teeth, how he was grinding his teeth?
- No, they were there, just crumbled.
- No, when she said all his teeth were out she meant at one he had all his teeth.
- Coming out not fall off.
- They were there just crumbled. He still grinds his teeth sometimes.
- I would like to say about allergies. I think he was a month and a half old.
From my husband’s side his younger brother had eczema when he was a little.
Extreme eczema as a result of food allergies but they never tested him.
So he developed first a serious eczema at a month and half,
my mother in law gave him a little bit of chocolate…
- At the age of 1 and a half he developed eczema?
- Month and a half.
- All over the body?
- Yes.
- And what you gave?
- Of course they prescribed cortisone and well I knew that cortisone is of course bad
so we did put some times, not all the time and then I was testing him through me
because he was breast feeding.
I would test him through me for the allergies meaning I would exclude milk for a week
and then watch my child. So by he was 5 and a half months
I had a list by testing him and he didn’t need any more... like nothing.
He didn’t need remedies. So that’s what we did.
- But how do you know that it was not suppressed by the cream already?
- Because it was never coming out. Because if I eat something it goes out. It was like really bad.
- Again?
- Yes, again and again it comes out.
- Yes, but after the final going away of the eczema,
did it come out a month later if he ate something allergic?
- I didn’t eat anything.
- But sometimes you may have accidentally eaten something.
- Definitely that it comes out. For example he was also allergic not only in food but perfumes.
If a lady comes with a perfume and touches him he gets eczema.
If the detergent is really strong and he scrubs on the detergent he gets eczema.
But that’s not very bad because you can wash it and it goes away.
The problem is when he gets the food inside and to the inhaling of the perfumes.
- And eczema came many times through when I started treating him.
His eczema was so bad as if he had 3rd degree burns.
- During your treatment the eczema came back?
- Yes. He had fevers like when I first gave him carc and tub and he had not very often,
every 3 months or so, extreme fevers. Like 40C and more.
- With tonsillitis.
- No. Mostly cough.
Tonsillitis never came back. But between the fever or after the fever he often got eczema too.
And fevers were very long lasting and often after the fever he would also get better mentally.
He also developed infection in his mouth a few times. I gave him merc, bell,
puls he reacted very well and his fevers… He stopped drinking,
he became extremely clingy to his mother.
- He was very attached to me.
- His father is a severe man, is very detached?
- He is a lyc but he is a very nice guy. He is very nice
- You like him?
- Yes, very good parents.
- No, he is not detached.
He likes his son but he just didn’t know at the beginning,
before lyc how to play much with his son. Now it’s different.
- He always had this this cough as he would get in the acute, there is a lot of mucus.
But last year, exactly before the day I came here he started having severe dyspnea.
First time, last year, a year ago.
And ended up in the hospital, so eventually and this is what is…
- They gave him inhalations?
- Yes. Right here, you see, mentally he is so much better every time after most of the remedies.
He would get so much better.
- That’s the only one that we have given him some times.
- He had one dose at that time of the cortisone…
- It contained cortisone?
- No, that one doesn’t.
The only one that doesn’t contain.
By that time he ended up in the hospital last year they gave him one dose of cortisone
to swallow, not to inhale. And plus cortisone liquid and it changed his behavior
but Helen gave him a remedy.
- After the cortisone did you notice any change in his behavior?
- He was like hyper! You couldn’t stop him. Not any more though.
- The most important thing I see here.
As he gets better and better mentally, his asthma gets worse.
Antimonium worked for almost a year, last year.
Though there is a little bit of rattling still there left. Then it stopped working.
Then the picture started changing more often like in May he was an ars,
because he developed very burning discharge
and some other symptoms for 3 weeks ars worked perfectly then it stopped.
Before that phos worked probably for almost a year.
Phos had a tremendous impact on him, mentally and emotionally.
But since last year asthma episodes started getting worse.
So now they have to use inhalers every time there is an episode of asthma
because he cannot breathe and so I started using these remedies more often.
Right now he is on antimonium which worked about 3 weeks ago,
so now he is on antimonium 200CH and 1M once a day.
- Is he coughing?
- No, but you can hear him wheezing.
- Sometimes.
- Now he is really good.
But what we noticed when he started getting remedies often, like every day, a certain amount,
he got better. He is better mentally. But the remedies are shifting from 2 weeks to…
- Antimonium did stop working last year, totally.
And now it works again. And also tried puls last time. It did not work at all.
And he doesn’t have high fevers any more. He does not have these high fever episodes anymore.
Last month he had 37,5C.
- 38,5C.
- Mentally we’ll see him…
- He still has this…
- Can he respond easily to the questions?
- He may not appear especially when he is anxious but he understands everything,
he knows everything.
When we were in Athens last week they went one way from the hotel to wherever they go
then they wanted to take another route.
He had never been there before and said “No we go the exact same route”.
He knows everything and he is extremely sensitive to… not even criticism.
He is very afraid his mom is very angry at him.
So if she just raises her voice just like that he is so scared
“Why are you angry at me? What’s going on?” he wants to please her all the time.
- He says it or he looks like…
- No, he says “What’s wrong mom? You’re ok?”
- He needs approval.
At school when they say “Well, work and we will tell mom you had a good day at school”.
That is a motivator, the approval of mother.
- All the time.
- All the time. Of both parents.
- Overboard, you mean really all the time makes you tired
and y “Oh, you’re so good, you have done so well”…
- Yes, you have to tell him all the time that.
- If his father is strict with him he doesn’t get scared or upset but if his mom is…
- With mom it is worse.
- The approval he needs from you only or from his teachers…?
- From everybody but mom is the highest.
- However sometimes he gets into the periods when he is very upset at her.
She leaves for work without telling him then she comes back. He goes into his room,
closes the door and doesn’t want to talk to her. And she has to beg him for forgiveness.
- I have to tell him “I’m home, I’m sorry. Let it go.” Apologize.
- And another thing he does to punish them both if they don’t let him swim for the entire day,
he is not happy with his parents he soils his pants.
- As a punishment to us.
Yesterday we didn’t go swimming because it was so cold and he loves beach and water
and he would punish us by soiling his pants. Makes his statement.
- So he holds a grudge against somebody.
If you are not nice to him. There was a cousin that wasn’t nice to him.
9 months he wouldn’t see her. If she is in the room he behaves as if she doesn’t exist.
It’s not as extreme anymore but he holds a grudge a lot if somebody is pushing him away
or pushes him down, offends him.
- And a few times he had very close friends.
They left and he suffered so much, I gave him ign a couple of times.
He became very sad and depressed.
- But it’s understandable because he doesn’t have many friends.
People don’t connect easily to him and when he has people who have patience,
because he is very smart and he can give a lot but he just cannot communicate as much,
then of course he gets upset if people go away or they don’t pay attention to him.
- He gets stuck on one food often and he eats one thing for a long time.
- He wants to eat only one food?
- No. He wants to eat spicy salsa or spaghetti.
- Everyday spaghetti?
- Not every day but he is like narrow-minded with food.
He wants 3-4 things. He can eat maybe 50 but he wants now 5 things only.
So I always have to push into new stuff sort of “which you want? What you want?”
- You have another child?
- No.
- She is afraid to have another.
- You’ve had enough with one.
- It’s not enough. I’m scared for him, for me, it’s our struggle.
- One is ok but why don’t you have another child?
- No, she is afraid that he is going to be autistic and that’s what I say, it won’t, right?
- They told you that the other child may be…?
- No.
- There is no such a chance.
- You see? I’m trying to persuade her to have.
- You are healthy, your husband is healthy.
He was born healthy. He was made sick with the vaccinations and antibiotics.
That’s very clear.
So everyone who will be hammered by all these introduction with the chemicals
into the body will break down. There’s no problem…
- Can I tell you about his eating maybe?
- His eating habits.
- Maybe he doesn’t drink water at all. He drinks juice, orange juice...
- Aversion to water.
- Yes. And he doesn’t crave bread.
Now here because he didn’t have much and craved a little bit of bread
but at home he doesn’t want bread.
- Doesn’t like sweets. I didn’t like when I was a kid but he really…at all… nothing.
- 3 times.
- This is very unusual in Canada not to like sweets for the kids.
- His father likes sweets.
- Always. A lot.
- Is there any other peculiarity about his…
- Well, he doesn’t like to try new food…I put tomatoes
because he likes everything of tomatoes… Like salsa. But not the fresh.
Everything made from tomatoes he eats but not the fresh tomato.
It’s just the way some things are made.
- His feet always sweat and are smelly sometimes.
- Offensive?
- Yes.
It’s offensive but they are often wet. Whether he has fever or not.
I actually remember giving him sil at one point during the fevers.
- Salt?
- He like salt.
- That means he adds salt.
-  No. He doesn’t add on his own.
If I put on cucumbers lots of salt he likes it he licks it. He likes salty.
But he doesn’t ask for things yet.
- Meat he eats?
- Meat, yes.
- Sausages?
- Not anymore.
He used to like sausages but not anymore. No daily. Just meat.
- When the meat has some fat in it he likes it?
- I think he is ok.
- He’s not picky at that.
- Likes cold food. I warm it up, I put it and he waits.
- That’s another reason I gave him sil.
- What do you say?
- He’s very anxious.
- Well sometimes he’s scripting from the movies that he likes and he picks up the sentences
and he’s like repeating them.  But his understanding now is way more…
Now in this situation he knows he is being observed. And he’s like anxious.
- He’s hiding. He’s observing other people.
- When it is safe at home he can communicate way more.
- He articulates properly.
- He speaks and reads and writes and does presentation at school
but he’s just very nervous now.
- Plays by himself. You know autistic children cannot play with themselves.
He can say with himself and be creative. Plays and uses his imagination.
Plays with other kids too.
- Eggs he eats?
- No.
- He’s allergic to eggs.
- Allergic but you think he likes them? You don’t know.
- After tub he started eating cheese.
- …
- Dairy allergy was cured by tub.
- Something peculiar. He likes to open holes.
When there is a hole he puts and he makes it big so he tears it.
- He touches his genitals often too.
- That started maybe 2 years ago. Off and on. Sometimes more, sometimes less.
But it’s still there.
- Also he likes the sensation on the skin from something soft.
He will take a blanket and put it in his pants or shirt…
- Or squeezes. He like rough games…
- In the summer he likes to walk undressed?
- No.
- When he goes to the toilet he goes by himself?
- Yes he can go. Sometimes we go together but yes he goes by himself more and more.
- Does he play with the stool?
- No he doesn’t. I didn’t see him play. Never.
- I don’t think he likes actually mud. I like to paint. He doesn’t like to paint.
He doesn’t like to get dirty.
- He will ask her to wash his hands.
He used to play a lot in the sand and then he would just wash his hands. He doesn’t like them dirty.
- The sensation of sand calms him down.
- Has he shown any aggressiveness towards some other children?
- No, never. He likes to have people, to console them if they are crying, to say “it’s ok”.
Big empathy. So he likes to put fingers in his mouth.
- He puts his fingers.
- Yes, not all the time but occasionally.
- He loves music and dance. Water, fishing, beach. Loves water, sea, ocean.
- You mean the sea water or in the swimming pool.
- Anything.
- Is he sleeping by himself?
- No.
He sleeps beside us. On the side. He was sleeping in another room when he was 1 year old.
We put him in another room because he was breast feeding all the night. I couldn’t sleep at all.
- Teeth grinding?
- No, he was breast feeding in the night and then in the first year
we put him in a nursery in another room and he was there for almost 1 year.
And then Helen told us that maybe he needs to be with us and then we put him back to our bed.
But he was not waking up all night.
- He was ever afraid of the dark? You had to leave a light on?
- At that time I don’t know. I think he didn’t like it definitely being alone in a room.
But we always put a light on, there was always a little light.
- A small one.
- It wasn’t dark completely.
- You are now working, yourself?
- Part time.
- What kind of work?
- I’m teaching at the college, interior design. Like inside architecture.
- You studied architecture.
- And she is a painter too, she is an artist.
- You like to paint.
- She just said that he wakes alone when he wakes up in the morning and it’s dark, it’s fine.
No problem
- He likes gardening with mama, flowers…
- Have you ever given him a lemon to see how he reacts if he eats the lemon,
desires the lemon?
- No.
- It’s hard to test new food on him because he doesn’t like to try.
- Oranges?
- He loves oranges, yes. And orange juice. He drinks orange juice like water.
- Fresh orange juice?
- Well, no we don’t make it, we buy it.
- You don’t have fresh oranges in Canada?
- He eats fresh oranges.
- Fruits? Other fruits he likes?
- When he was 2 years old he ate everything. Green… everything.
I was making everything for him because he was allergic.
So after that he started the picking. Now he eats lots of cucumbers. Me too.
Oranges and bananas, sometimes apple, but he can eat all the fruit.
He was eating before, he just doesn’t want to eat them now.
Watermelon, oranges and sometimes banana.
- He accidentally hit my leg with his leg just slightly.
But he thought he hurt me so he wanted to kiss my leg.
And I saw that he was going to kiss my dirty shoe and I said “No, don’t!”
and he got scared of my reaction. Closed his ears and crawled under the bed.
So you cannot talk even a little bit loud to him. When she is upset or cries, he is very upset.
- Sensitivity to sound but it was really bad at one point last year actually,
when you left for Greece and after carc.
- He got much better after carc.
- He was much better after that. Now it is just high pitch noise.
- I don’t think he is scared I think it just hurts him; he has sensitivity to it. I’m not sure.
- In autism it’s common that they get overwhelmed with everything.
With him it’s mostly with sound. He wants harmony around him that’s for sure.
He doesn’t want any problems, anybody being hurt, anybody being angry or sad.
- He doesn’t like his food to be changed but he loves to travel.
So he loves the change in a big but not in a small level.
It’s like he needs a little of around him to keep him calm to keep him out of anxiety.
But we told him about Greece and about airplane and bus and boat.
And he was so excited, he wanted to go. He enjoyed the whole trip.
But when we got in Athens he asked for orange juice, his orange juice.
I told him “No orange juice.” He said water is ok.
He wants his little meals to be the way he likes it.
But he likes to travel, he likes to see new places and people.
So he has that adventurous side of him.
He likes running. As auto stimulation, in a room sometimes he goes like back and forth,
not as much. Before it was in circles.
- As a stimulation or to calm down?
- That one yes, to calm down.
- He is riding a bicycle.
- But if he runs too much he starts having some asthma symptoms.
- Ok?
- Ok.
- Thank you.
Ok, first of all I must say that the improvement from the original state is quite impressive
and most probably is due to the 3 remedies out of those you gave, the carc,
the tub and the ant-t.
The question is what I see at this moment, what is the most probable picture.
It’s not a clear picture. There are several possibilities like caust, hyos, pall.
There is also a possibility, asar is a possibility but I don’t know how it will develop.
Now, what is the way to come down to the most probable remedy at the moment?
Which is an interesting feature of the boy from what we observed.
He has some strong symptoms of caust. But what impressed you?
Looking at the child what impressed you?  Yes?
- I noticed that he was very restless. Obviously he was anxious at the beginning when he came in.
He wanted to hide when he came into the room.
But then he started peeping out from behind to see what was going on.
And afterwards when he was more comfortable, he was more outgoing
and he was performing his dinosaurs, trying to spy you out.
So he came over quite open as far as he could, concerning his condition.
Communicative, but he always went to the safe base of the father or the mother in order to hide.
That’s the external only.
- It’s very interesting for me to see how much usually the mother,
almost never the father is identified with the children of that type.
The mother tries to understand and to explain and they need to explain why the boy is running.
Because there is a logical explanation that the boy will not do something beyond logic.
And they need that and they identify themselves so much.
- He was singing all the time.
- Who, the boy?
- The boy.
- The voice of the mother?
- No, nobody noticed that during all the interview he was singing.
All the interview he was like this.
- Yes. Is this correct Helen?
- I think he was kind of whimpering. He was whimpering into his mother.
- He was singing or making noise?
- He moans a lot when he is sick. His asthma or cough or whatever.
And he moans in sleep and he moans when he is sick.
- What is the moaning, lamenting? You can use it. Put it twice.
- If something happens like after one really bad asthma episode his mother said “Ok,
you’re safe now”.
And he cried and cried. He gets into pieces and cry for a very long time.
- His mother says “You’re ok”,
- I think it was after this trip to the hospital. Cause he couldn’t breathe at all.
He gets very bad. So she said “You’re ok now, you’re safe now.”
And he started crying.
And he does that from time to time if something happens he will cry and cry for a long time.
[…] He wasn’t affectionate when I first saw him. He became like that later on.
This is when I prescribed phos.
So when I saw him being affectionate with such a difference that was a year and a half ago.
- How he was?
- I suddenly saw an affectionate child. He wasn’t like that at all at first.
He was only in himself just like a little animal.
- There is a big improvement there is no question.
- But when I saw him being so affectionate I prescribed phos
and he got much better with phos too.
And phos worked on his asthma and for a long time and then stopped.
- For me watching him the most impressive is the antics, what he does with the grimaces,
he is making antics, with play and all that.
This is what in our repertories seen as playing antics. Put this. Show me the remedies.
Hyos is the only capital and bell. But this is a characteristic of hyos actually, quite strongly.
What you saw is what we know hyos is doing. And grimaces also another expression.
Playing antics means he is performing.
Ok hyos is there as one so therefore show me the…
Hyos seems to be the indicated remedy especially why?
Because he says lately he is touching his genitalia.
That was confirmed by the mother quite a lot. So if we see the symptoms covered by hyos;
handles genitalia, grimaces, aversion to water also.
It’s interesting that hyos has aversion to water.
And grinding teeth during sleep, moaning, perspiration rattling, sensitive to noise,
asthmatic respiration and desire to hide also with playing antics. Desire to hide was combined.
From this remedy missing the fact that he has aversion to sweets so strong,
which I would like to have, the oranges desire, the aggravation from eggs, foot offensive,
caries, discolored. What I would to have aversion to sweets that comes from the mother also.
It’s almost a hereditary thing the aversion to sweets.
So it’s quite deep, maybe later on I will go to caust with the affection
and the sympathetic element will remain
but I think hyos is going to help further the development of the child.
After that the aversion to sweets will remain.
The sensitivity to others and the sympathy will remain most probably
and I don’t know what effect will be with his allergies. He has an allergic asthma.
It’s quiet severe, I don’t know how much hyos will control this or you will need the next remedy.
Most probably will make the asthmatic condition better but he would need another remedy definitely.
And most probably he will need caust as the next remedy.
But at this moment where the shyness, you see no shyness at all he is not shy, he can perform,
he can do whatever he likes. He doesn’t care what you think.
That kind with playing the antics and the grimaces and all that
and the touching of the genitalia plus the other symptoms brings us to the idea of hyos
and what is the potency? You see the child was damaged by vaccination and antibiotics,
the combination actually. And that is why you were able to bring up such improvement.
Children who are born straight away autistic are very difficult to improve.
But it they’re damaged through antibiotic or vaccination
or the combination it’s much easier to have some good effect.
I believe this child can be quite improved and maybe at the age of 15-16
he will be almost normal.
- They didn’t see him when he was not anxious. There is a tremendous difference.
Then he was a little animal, now he is a human being.
- It’s amazing what homeopathy can do in such cases where no other treatment
as far as I know can have such an effect.
- I wanted to ask if he had a very big desire for oranges…
- Yes, med is also a possibility.
- Also the mother said when they didn’t allow him yesterday to go to the sea
because it was cold. He punished them because he really wanted to go.
- Also another thing with hyos is, I forgot, this stool. To have stool is a hyos symptom.
- But he didn’t say about stool if I understood well. He said that he makes…
- It’s an explanation of the mother. This is just nonsense.
A normal child would punish by doing that… It has to be a symptom.
Either there is another explanation.
He wants to punish, he has stool… Of course the fact that he allows a 7 year old
to have a stool it’s a symptom.
- But did she say stool or soil?
- Soil.
- She said soil.
- It’s the same. Stool.
- Is it? I didn’t understand that.
- I like this explanation. The mothers explain away everything.
“He does this because of this, he does the other because of that”.
In fact you have to see the whole picture.
It’s a child that plays antics, that touches his genitalia, he has stool,
not controlling his stool and then becomes a picture.
She thinks he does it under certain psychological pressure. Whatever the pressure might be.
- Hyos had a strong fear of water.
- Fear of water? No, he said aversion to water. Does not want to drink.
- He loves to play with water that the mother said and hyos has strong fear of water.
- Also a lot of other remedies have fear for water.
The fact that a symptom is missing from a remedy it doesn’t mean anything.
- It’s not missing. It’s just the other way round. Someone can have fear,
someone is loving the water.
- Yes, but what’s the problem. There is no problem. That’s natural to like the water.
He just simply does not have fear of water he has aversion to water.
- But it is also his sycotic background that he loves the sea…
- Yes correct. Most probably later on he will need some med.
I didn’t want to embarrass the couple asking whether the father…
You asked? Denied. You don’t think.
- No I just said the sycotic background is from the mother who is staph all the way.
Staph treated her depression, her neck pain, throat, everything.
She was a kind of a child.
She might have contributed to his problems because she was really an abused child.
At the age of 13 she would clean the whole house and prepare food for her parents.
And mother would come and say “Why didn’t you clean this? Why didn’t you do that?”
So at the time he got sick there was a very very difficult conflict.
- You belong to the feminist movement.
- The potency you can start with 200CH.
You give every day 200CH for a few days, see the reaction and then if he’s better
and then worse, then you may repeat as long as long keeps on playing the antics
doing all this kind of performance.
When that keynote is gone most probably you have to search for the next remedy
which most probably I think it can be caust, can be med, can be pall, can be asar.
High fever. Because he has high fever we consider him to be treatable, curable.
Just because his immune system has the possibility of developing a high fever. He’s curable.
Level 5 or 6 you can say.  The fact that cortisone interfered during this that was bad.
But you immediately saw the reaction the boy was chaotic immediately. Can go to level 7 quite easily.
- Why do you consider pall?
- Because he needs so much approval from others. That is a characteristic of pall.
And if that remains. Of course it’s just an idea. The most probably is caust, med.
- For this little boy he had his teeth at 4th month and he was talking at 9 months
so he was really early. You understand?
- He was talking quite early. At 9th month.
- And had his teeth at 4th month. Do you consider this is a factor of sensitivity?
You know what I mean? He’s early in his development, maybe also in the brain system,
so maybe he can be touched much more than any other.
Because a lot of children have antibiotics and vaccination and they don’t have anything.
- That’s correct. What you are saying most probably has a relevance that means
because the organism was fast in developing he had some certain extra sensitivities
and because of the interference of the vaccination
and the antibiotics brought the whole organism down.
- From your experience can you please guide us in what case we should go with X potencies?
In what cases we should go with centesimal…
There is a lot we read in the books who prescribe X potency multiple times.
So far until now I have not received any final standpoint from where we should go on X,
or should go centesimal…
- When you want to go low we may go to X. 12X, 8X, 9X.
If you want to go very low you can go to quintecimal potencies which are very light.
1 to 50.000. These are very light remedies and you can repeat them always. Like Patel. LM potencies.
But in my experience I don’t have to use LM potencies so…
If wanted to go low I go to 6X. Very low. 6X is the lowest.
- In that particular case if we go to 1M then to 10M then to 50M then to CM.
Still the same remedy is indicated…then?
- MM. Million. Tell some pharmacy to make you one million.
- So my question is I know a case of…
- Actually the old times the used to give these remedies. It’s not a joke. But what they did.
They put a jet of water and then they had the potency and the jet of water
went into washing out all the time and they had calculated
that if they let it for instance for 3 hours the water that goes in and out
within 3 hours it’s 1 million times. Still, they say it worked. I don’t know.
- After CM… I know a case of motor neuron disease it is a case of caust
I started with 200CH I raised the power. Now it is on CM.
I give him CM whenever he has some exacerbation of the problem.
Otherwise I stick to the placebo. Now I am stuck up.
Indications are the same but I don’t have a higher potency. So what is your opinion on that?
- Take the CM and potentize it a few times. Just to make it a little bit stronger.
And if that doesn’t work then you can start all over going back
and start with repeating 12X frequently.
- So in that case Erik has taught us that high potencies antidote low potencies.
So suppose, if a patient comes to us and we have given him CM potency
and if he comes after 6 months or one year should we start with CM or we can time from any time?
- You can start normally from the last potency.
- He has already taken CM but he comes after 1 year.
- After 1 year you give again the last potency. That was CM.
Also concerning his question that this child has not fear of water
therefore you will not give hyos. This is not correct, why?
Because in 100 cases of hyos perhaps the fear of water will be in 2.
All the 98 cases they have no fear of water. 98% do not have fear of water.
- Once again I have a doubt here because I see that you don’t take into consideration
a symptom that was very clear… Because hyos doesn’t have these 2 symptoms.
- You are speaking a little bit fast for me. I did not take into consideration that…
- 2 symptoms; ailments from antibiotics and vaccination. Hyos doesn’t have them.
- So what should I have given?
- Stram because stram has both of them. Stram has all the rest; the antics, the grimaces...
- Stram is much more aggressive. We are talking about aggressiveness.
He will hit, he will provoke, shout, he will see nightmares. It’s another picture.
And fear of the dark, strong.
Ok, thank you.