So in this session you have the opportunity to ask any question you like. Anything.
So I would like to hear your first… What would you like to know? You can ask anything,
if I’m married or not married… Ok take this and the other also and yes…
You distribute it to the people. 2 to 3 questions only. Just remember this.
- Only 3.
- Because later on you will remember “I have another one”.
- Ok. Great.
- Be careful. So first. Just one, then we will go around and then you have again.
- Sure.
- Ask the most important.
- As in the case of nat-m which you have given 50M.
He has muscle pains and joint pains.
In our country one of the very important common reasons is B12 deficiency.
So my question is; you said that we cannot allow supplement
because it changes the symptom picture, remedy picture.
- Yes.
- So in our country almost 60% of the people are vegetarian and nutritionally deficient.
As you said we really have a lot of poverty in our country.
What should be done? Either giving a remedy and nutrition supplementation
or what should be done to avoid that because just to give vitamin B solves the problem.
But again we’ll have B12 deficiency. So we need to prescribe.
But what should be done in order to do all these things?
- There are 2 things. One is to give supplements and the other is to give the homeopathic remedy.
Together it’s not good to do it at the same time.
So what you do is; you take the case, prescribe the remedy, see that your remedy was correct.
That means there was an initial aggravation, then an amelioration.
And then the person stays more or less well but still he feels tired.
Then you can think of supplement. But first you have to see the reaction of your remedy.
Otherwise you will not be able to know “Did I give the correct remedy? Or I gave the wrong remedy?”
So therefore you can do supplements but afterwards and after you have seen
what your remedy can do.
What happens many times is that the correct remedy will make the organism
absorb the microelements and vitamins that needs much easier.
And that’s why it’s rejuvenated the organism.
So, if you don’t know what to do in a case, you’d better choose the supplements,
give all the supplements.
And if supplements do something and strengthen the organism
then maybe we’ll have a better picture.
But if you do it together you will never know what you have done. This is the right thing.
Of course the right thing is done very few times in life.
But I have to tell you what the right thing is. Ok?
So if you can do it or you cannot do it it’s up to you. You choose.
But I have seen that people who are deficient of a particular… of calcium or phosphorus
or calcarea phosphorica, you can see in the laboratory examinations their deficiencies.
You give the right remedy and the deficiencies start balancing without supplements.
But now, if you don’t find the remedy what will you do? You’ll give supplements.
You’ll also give the remedy, you’ll do it together but... I’ll tell you the secret.
The secret is; insist in trying to find the correct remedy. You give wrong remedy.
Ok. You observe. The organism will give you a response to your wrong remedy.
But if you wait long enough the response will go towards the right direction.
Take for instance the case to which I prescribed bac in the beginning.
He was crying “I’m aggravated!” No, you were not crying.
He says “Your remedy did nothing. It just aggravated me”
He just wrote it in a very polite way.
“Your remedy just aggravated me. Done nothing.”
Now you know you have given a remedy which is close.
That means it has aggravated, it has touched him.
And now what is the new picture? This is the new picture.
And then the next remedy I gave him was lyc. And “Dear George, your remedy it’s…
I’m worse actually. Thank you.”
But in the meantime he has described what was going on in his organism.
I knew he is very sensitive and then I perceive within his symptoms the idea of arg-n.
And I say ok, take a few doses, low potency.
He takes one dose of arg-n and then he writes “It’s a catastrophe!”
he says “I got worse and now on top of it I have tonsillitis with high fever and what shall I do?”
And then I’m anxious and I say what can I do? Hep, I think. No? Lach.
My mind stuck in hep. Take lach. “I’m terrible. I have pain, I have fever, I’m exhausted,
I can hardly work. I stopped working. I’m lying in bed, I cannot do anything etc.”
I should have said ok, take antibiotics”.
But I know if I tell him “Take antibiotics” his organism is finished, destroyed.
So I battled that certain moment. I have never telephoned a patient in my life.
So I call him because he was “I’m dying!” I thought “Oh! My God!”
You see if you know some pathology; there is a tonsillitis
which is called “Ludwig tonsillitis” [Ludwig angina] Do you know this? No.
This is a tonsillitis that leads you to death. You can die.
Many people have died from this kind of tonsillitis.
Tonsillitis but so severe that nothing can stop it. So if you know what is going on
and I knew that…
And I don’t know what’s going on because I can’t remember now, he had a mononucleosis?
I can’t remember. And then I think again and I say “Check it out.
Tell me if this is mononucleosis.” He says “I cannot get up and go to check it.”
I said “Ok, take nit-ac.” He takes nit-ac, he says “Within a few hours the fever dropped
and then I started recovering” and 2 days later he goes to have the checkup.
It’s very late now. The laboratory tests will be changed totally after 2-3 days.
So, what I could do? This is one example which you have in front of you that’s why I mentioned it.
You can imagine I have been through hundreds and hundreds and thousands of such cases in my life.
And I had to face the situation. Sometimes here in the class there were people with heart attacks.
I had to face the situation. What can I do?
In America when I was teaching in Esalen, in that weird place. Do you know Esalen in California?
Who know Esalen in California? Only one knows Esalen.
It’s the worst, the most weird w-e-i-r-d… I don’t know he is an English person,
he can tell me how to pronounce it.
Hundred people have come from all over the world and we had intense teaching.
We started 8 o’clock until 6 o’clock in the evening and people were under big stress.
So, one student got a brain stroke, he was going like this.
The class got very excited “What will we do?” I said “Out! Everybody!”
Otherwise the noise cannot allow you to see and to think properly.
And there was one that was pulling out Bach remedies that remedy and I said “Wait”
So I observed and I saw a few signs of gels I said “Give me a dose of gels 200CH” I put gels 200CH.
I waited for half an hour. He started coming back and I said to the class “Ok, come now.”
He stayed in the class and continued the lectures.
The energy was so great. Once you lose your mind you cannot think.
But again I’m talking about… this was 32 years ago.
I had quite a lot of experience by that time but not as much as I have now of course.
And I was lucky I think. And helped by the higher forces… whatever.
That all this never happened an accident.
But the main thing is, first of all I have studied very much.
The second is that I never compromised.
Sometimes I speak Greek in order to find the Greek word while the English word is this.
I remember the Greek word. I never compromise.
If I don’t know what to do; maybe it’s acon, maybe it’s lach, maybe it’s gels,
maybe ars, bring all of them. Give it to them. One of them will act. You hope.
It may act but it may not. And then I confuse the case.
Once the case is confused try to find the remedy… Especially in such severe situation.
The way you learn, the best way is to see a real case. To see a case of crotalus cascavella.
Then you’ll never forget it.
I was lucky because I was able to see these pictures again and again
because I did not mix the remedies.
If every time I have given 2 remedies, never mind 3 or 4. 2.
How could I know this picture belongs to this and not to that remedy? Finish.
All the information is gone. So, next question.
- Can I ask a question?
- Who is speaking?
- Brigitte. There is a lot of information in the literature about remedies
and it’s so outstanding but how you suggest we would take onboard new information?
I mean there are for example provings happening all the time around the world,
new information accumulating. How you suggest we use this information?
- I’ll tell you something about the new proving. First I must tell you that
when I started homeopathy it was 1960. I came back to Greece in ’67.
During all these 7 seven years I was in different schools trying to learn
but I was studying very much.
There were no new provings.
There was Kent’s Repertory when I returned to Greece and I started treating people.
Using the Kent’s Repertory, Kent’s Materia Medica and Boericke Materia Medica
and Materia Medica Pura and few other books. The success I had was unbelievable.
It was created a whole movement in a few years.
Medical doctors started coming to learn saying “What is this?”
In no time I had a center with several medical doctors who were working with me.
Only with this information. I did not need any new provings.
Do we need new provings? The answer is yes.
But with one condition; as long as this proving has been done properly.
What do I mean? In order to create symptoms on a prover you have to give in quantity enough
as to create a kind of a poisoning of the prover. You have to give enough material doses.
And if I give to the whole class… I have a remedy and I give in material doses to every one of you.
Every day you take 5mg of this substance.
Eventually the most sensitive of you to this substance will come and give me some symptoms.
You will say “I woke up with headache.”
Another one says “I had also headache” 2 or 3 coming first up
because they are the most sensitive to this substance. Then you continue the proving
and after a month or a certain period you stop the experiment and then you collect the symptoms.
But then the symptoms are real symptoms, not imaginary symptoms.
Then you continue the experiment in this way.
Who was the most sensitive of the group who developed first the symptoms? 3,4 out of 100.
You take these 4 and then you give a high potency in order to see what a high potency
in a sensitive person to that drug can do. And then you record it.
And then you collect this information which cannot be more than a few hundred symptoms the most.
Not thousands.
And then you apply this; if you have seen that in most of the provers
there was pain developing on the right hypochondria.
That means it affected the gallbladder in its function.
So, when you have a problem with the gallbladder and other remedies
do not fit you may now try this new remedy. What has happened really is a different story.
With people who supposed to prove new remedies.
There are some who say “You don’t have to do a proving.” What to do?
“Just imagine it. Imagine what this remedy can do.”
I say “Oh! My God! If I give you and I say “Tell me what the remedy pall will do. Imagine.”
Each one will think pall is a kind of precious metal and so the men must feel very precious…
Nonsense.
So this kind of proving… If somebody tells me here are the provings,
out of imagination of course I say “This is rubbish and disgrace for science.”
Totally out.
We come to more serious people where they give one dose of 30CH to 10-15 people
and then collect symptoms of that dose and create a book. And the book is called… this remedy.
It’s a whole book with thousands of symptoms.
I say “Wait a moment.” I give many times a wrong remedy and if it is a wrong potency
the patient comes back and tells me “I’m the same” and I try to find something and I find nothing.
In your proving you gave 1 dose and you created 30.000 symptoms.
So I investigate. I said “I want to know how this happens” And I found a girl,
a doctor actually who was in the group. She says “I will tell you how this happens.
Because we are in a group in a hotel.
We take the remedy and when we come out of the hotel and we start discussing.
“How are you?
– I think I have a pain on the right.
– Oh!
- I think also.
–What about dizziness?
– Oh, yes!”
And one between another they exchange ideas of what is happening with the remedy they took.
In the end of course there is a lot of stories of what happened with 1 dose of hydrogen 30CH.
I still want to investigate because I don’t believe anything from the beginning,
never mind what you tell me. But I will listen and I will investigate.
So an Italian group comes and they say “We want to make a proving.
We are a group of Italian medical doctors. Would you be the head of the…
Give us a remedy?” I said yes. I asked these men with the hydrogen.
“Can you give me the hydrogen 30CH; I need it for my use.”
So without telling them anything I said “This is the remedy. You try”
they tried the experiment every day they took this
and after a month they came to the conclusion nothing has happened. Nobody has really anything.
“What was the remedy you gave us?” They demanded they said “You must tell us”
I said “Hydrogen” They said “What? Hydrogen is not free. How can you give hydrogen?
How can you catch hydrogen? The moment it comes with… it becomes water.
What are you talking” I said “Wait, calm down. Here is the book.
You see these people they claim that by taking hydrogen 30CH they have created a new proving”
So there was a big argument and I completely lost credit with this group of Italian doctors.
They said George is really crazy to give us hydrogen for proving. We lost our time,
we lost our energy. The proving was funded by somebody and lost his money because of that.
But I investigated it. And I found out that the provings as they are done,
they are not reliable.
Unfortunately. Because they are not properly done.
And if you don’t do a proper proving… Ok hydrogen may have no symptoms, we can forget.
But a lot of other poisons and thing like that they will have definitely symptoms.
So they say “George, you don’t like us to do provings”
Of course I like you to do provings but do it properly.
Don’t tell me that you give 1 dose of 30CH and you collect 3.000 symptoms.
Do it properly. You want to give a poison? Give a poison, give it in a very small quantity.
Eventually you will create some real proving. So the way that modern… I don’t believe.
I have criticized that and maybe eventually some people will do it properly.
I am sure we will have some reliable provings
but up to now I don’t know very many reliable provings that you can use.
And after all you don’t need them.
My success which I had the Kent’s Repertory it was so great that created a whole movement
and imposed homeopathy upon the medical profession.
Medical people are sending their family, themselves,
their patients to homeopathy, to my students.
Greece is a very conservative country. It’s not like England, everyone does whatever he likes.
You don’t have to be a medical doctor you can practice.
Holland you can practice, never mind.
In Greece you have to be a medical doctor before you give a prescription. It’s very strict.
And yet there was a university. They gave me the degree of professor of this university.
Unbelievable because professors of university given an honorary degree
were another 2 persons in the whole history of Greece.
And they gave it to me and everybody shut up. Nobody spoke.
Why? Because of respect they have for homeopathy. This great respect.
Where this respect comes from? Because of the result, nothing else. So new provings.
Absolutely as long as they done properly.
The problem with homeopathy is that as you understand we are dealing with energy.
We have entered a state of medicine which is not anymore the material medicine.
It is an energy medicine. Therefore it’s something immaterial that cannot be seen.
So, nobody can check out what we are doing.
Because of this all kinds of imaginations
and all kinds of phantasies have inserted into homeopathy,
pretending that “Now I have found another way” How is such people still survive
and they can hold a kind of clientele, of patient?  Because of the placebo effect.
There is what we call a placebo effect.
So, if you tell the patient “Come, I’ll cure you” and create a situation
and then you give him something with the belief that something is happening, he feels better.
And that keeps the patients with such people who give wrong remedies.
Sometimes these people they give a right remedy as well so there is a real cure as well.
… Sankaran… and all these people they found new ideas.
You look like an animal you have to get animal remedies.
One time I had the German group and it was a follow up of a German with asthma.
And I presented this to the class, the man.
I presented the case with black man with mustaches.
I said to the class “Tell me he needs; a vegetable remedy?
An animal remedy? Or a mineral remedy?” The whole class “Animal”.
I said “Let’s see his follow up.” I went inside I asked … “Very well, my asthma is gone.
One year it had gone after…” I came back to the class “What was the remedy?” Belladonna.
Which means in Italian “beautiful woman” actually. He needed bell.
Why should you search for an animal remedy to give him? For God’s sake.
After an hour of investigation she said “I took my husband to one of those people.
Finally he asked my husband “Which is the bird he likes?” among the different questions.
So my husband said “Owl” he wrote owl 10M.
After an hour and a half of investigation he asks what is the bird you like
and he prescribes the bird. He is beyond my comprehension.
She was a medical doctor who took her husband to him to be treated for something quite serious.
All these kind of thing have given a very bad name to homeopathy
and also an attack on homeopathy has started based on such nonsense.
And it’s going to grow and these people are giving ammunition . They don’t attack me.
Nobody will attack me because they know they will get the answer.
But if you say such nonsense…
Another one says he found the cure for AIDS. What is the cure for AIDS?
He says “Here in that disc. What do you do?
You put that disc on your dvd-player and you listen to it day and night for a month.
And if you listen to this day and night you are cured in the end of the month.”
For God’s sake. If you do such things and you call it homeopathy, classical homeopathy…
What can you do. Wait India, you are impatient.
- This discussion about meditation actually it came in the same direction I wanted to ask
because I practice in the middle of a community of Yogi meditators, religious, new age people.
I practice in Thailand and Thailand has a very big tradition of meditation
so there are people who come there especially for meditation and they spend months in meditation.
And one of my biggest problems actually when I deal with these people
is to separate between their beliefs and their real symptoms.
My question came in the direction of spiritual practices and influence on our health.
A few year ago actually you brought this a little bit up during the complete teachings
there was a discussion about conscience, consciousness
and mind which went a little bit into that direction but then you got sick and we couldn’t finish.
And I left with this question since a long time now about what is your opinion.
What criteria we can use.
- You are asking about the role of consciousness in disease…
- How can we distinguish when it comes to such practices between the voice of the conscience
and the voice of pathology?
- I will tell you something. I have written a paper on this issue.
- You gave it to us a few years ago, 3 years ago the complete teaching…
- I wrote a paper and I sent it to the British Medical Journal.
They had several departments. I sent it to one of the departments and they rejected it.
“Forget it. We cannot publish it”. Then I sent it to Medical Hypothesis another medical journal.
They kept it for several months. In the meantime the British Medical Journal they wrote back to me
and they said “We think we made a mistake, please submit again your paper”.
But I had submitted to Medical Hypothesis. It took 6-9 months before they made a decision
and they rejected it.
And then I thought “Ok. I will re-submit it to the British Medical Journal.”
And I don’t know for what reason, while they asked me to re-submit it,
because it took long time perhaps to re-submit it, they again rejected it.
Now I am going to send it to another medical journal
because I consider this as a very important issue.
The compromise of the idea of conscience, your conscience, once you compromise disease starts.
Disease starts in a very subtle way.
That means like something undermining your whole system slowly.
And then a stress will come of course. And then the disease will manifest.
But has been prepared by these underlying undermining of the conscience
because of some compromise we did at a certain time. This is big problem for humanity.
I consider it the biggest problem that humanity has at this moment
and not humanity as a whole.
Not everyone, not Indians and not so much the Chinese or not so much the primitive,
or not so much the Indians the red Indians or the South Americans.
They are coming very fast to the idea of compromising their conscience as well.
Compromising for what? For some kind of remuneration.
Making money, taking position, power, etc.
The moment you made a compromise it is like a natural law that you cannot get out of.
You cannot bypass it. It will affect you.
And you know I have been treating spiritual people like you
who were around Krishnamurti in Switzerland.
What have I found out about these people it was that most of them they were sincere seekers
but very ill. Very deeply sick. Sick in their minds.
They were trying to understand Krishnamurti, what he says.
He says “Be aware. Be now. See what is happening at this moment.
Don’t think of the past, don’t think of the future, live the present”
and they were trying to get to the state where he was describing,
the state that he was living himself but of course all these people
who followed him were very rich people. People who were coming from all over the world.
They have done quite a lot in their lives, whatever they have done, compromised a lot
and now finally they live in hell.
And hell is the anxiety state or it is the inner state which never gives them peace.
Now they try to find peace finally.
They got the money, they got all the position,
they got everything that materially was possible to get but they lost one thing.
The joy of life. Very sick. I was treating most of them.
Because they knew I was treating Krishnamurti and they were coming to me to be treated of course.
And I took their case and I saw their histories and I saw how sad people they were,
how they have lost totally the joy of life. They could not.
It’s like a very rich person he can have anything. “I want to fly…let’s go to Honolulu.
I take my private airplane, we go to Honolulu and there we find something.”
They find nothing there in Honolulu. They cannot find anything. Honolulu is within themselves.
They carry their unhappiness in Honolulu. But they have compromised their conscience.
- My question is mostly about how to distinguish the sincere ones from the pathology.
Because I see people who are obviously gone with clairvoyance…
They come to me because they think I am open-minded doctor.
I know this is pathology but there are situation where I really don’t know how to take.
There is a praying which is sincere or there is a pathology.
I have seen you a lot of times taking clairvoyance out, not a pathology.
Sometimes you take it as a pathology and sometimes you don’t.
- Unfortunately is such that is very deep.
Once you have compromised your conscience the pathology
has undermined your very existence as a human being. You do not respect anymore yourself.
You know there is an anxiety “I have done wrong.” And that overwhelms you all the time.
And that goes very deep. This is what I have found out. You see the nice couple of Turks.
No problem. No compromise.
“I have done this. It was wrong. I recognize I did something wrong” Can be cured.
The people who are not aware of that they try to escape by going to a guru
and listening and trying to find out how can I be happy again?
That’s a very difficult situation to cure. You cannot get symptoms in such people.
Unless there is a purity inside the organism, the organism cannot give out pure symptoms.
Gives symptoms which are confused, mixed.  He has a whole list.
- In a period of 5 days, in this 5 days course I filled up 236 pages.
This is what I wanted to have in my life which I received from you and doctor Erik.
- Thank you.
- We should say thank you to you because we need you.
The purity you have into things it is extraordinary.
Practicing homeopathy at this stage I have 3 questions which really bothers me a lot.
I’ll ask one by one.
First is when a patient comes to us under some allopathic medication, and he’s on steroid
or antibiotics… It will make  a lot of constitutional symptoms masked.
In that respect we should be able to..
- You can do nothing. Forget it. Send them back to the conventional doctor.
You can do nothing. If people are full of medication you can do nothing actually.
Forget it. Another question. One more.
- Well I think Sir in modern world more or less they are all getting allopathic medication.
- No that’s not true.
- Let me make clear myself. The point is when a patient comes to us to a homeopath.
He has gone all around without any solution then they come to a homeopath as a last option.
And the say homeopathy is the hope for hopeless. We are not magicians.
So this patient is taking allopathic medication…
- Stop the medication, give homeopathic remedy.
- How sir? This is the problem. Because we cannot stop antiepileptic drugs, we cannot stop steroids…
- What you are asking is a whole lesson of 2-3 hours. Now this is just the last 2-3 minutes.
How can I answer?
- Fine, sir. My second question is….
- Oh forget it! You see the reaction?
- I would be very happy if you were answering with one sentence.
Because I really suffer from it, this is my suffering, you will give me my remedy.
Sir actually in levels of health when we see an acute developing after a remedy…
In treatment we always are used have aggravation and then amelioration…
- Not always. Most of the times but not always.
- So the point is we say that is there is aggravation it’s very good
but there may be an aggravation or there might be a not perceptible aggravation…
- It very good when there is aggravation and then amelioration. Then you have a cure.
If you gave only aggravation it means that the remedy was not correct, just aggravated,
it was close, it aggravates,
then you wait for the next remedy.
- Aggravation does it mean always perceptible aggravation?
Or sometimes the patient cannot understand
because in acute vital force is always in such a turmoil.
Little aggravation of the problem may not be able to be justified.
So we should consider that aggravation means conceivable aggravation or not?
- Helen in correct. All these are answered in the e-learning. Take the e-learning.
I suggest if you really want to have the information, you have to take the e-learning.