50.The style that Hahnemann writes is very detailed.
He writes in such a way that he wants to leave nothing outside of the meaning of
the paragraph. Therefore if we take it word by word we are going to go very far and
it will take very long time.
That's why I try to summarize the meaning of the paragraph and in paragraph 50
he writes that Nature cures by similar, that's why cure is actually by symptom
similar to the disease.
Paragraph 51, "This therapeutic law is rendered obvious to all intelligent minds
by these instances, and they are simply sufficient for this end.
But, on the other hand, see what advantages man has over crude Nature in her
happy-go-lucky operations. How many thousands more of homoeopathic morbific
agents has not man at his disposal for the relief of his suffering fellow-creatures in
the medicinal substances universally distributed throughout creation!"
Do you understand what he says? Who understands? Tell me.
-He says that nature only randomly cures by similars and it's very rare but we
have many more homeopathic drugs available so we are lucky.
-Nature can cure accidentally a few things. But we have in our disposal
thousands of agents, that means remedies, with which we can cure diseases.
"In them he has producers of disease of all possible varieties of action,
for all the innumerable, for all conceivable and inconceivable natural diseases,
to which they can render homoeopathic aid - morbific agents
(medicinal substances), whose power, when their remedial employment is
completed, being overcome by the vital force, disappears spontaneously without
requiring a second course of treatment for its extirpation, like the itch - artificial
morbific agents, which the physician can attenuate, subdivide and potentize almost
to an infinite extent, and the dose of which he can diminish to such a degree that
they shall remain only slightly stronger than the similar natural disease
they are employed to cure". This is one sentence.
For Hahnemann it was very simple. He is doing this all the time.
He gives tremendously big sentences. Now you tell me what he says.
He says that we have at our disposal thousands of such remedies and also potencies
in such a way as to choose a potency that will be stronger than the disease and cure
the disease. The idea of the potency being stronger is fixed in his mind.
This is quite interesting from our point of view because he was experimenting
with low potencies and yet he says that the remedy can be attenuated
to an infinite degree.
That means he understands that the more he attenuates the dose
the more powerful it becomes.
"so that in this incomparable method of cure, there is no necessity for any violent
attack upon the organism for the eradication of even an inveterate disease of old
standing."
This phrase, just immediately after he has the idea of being stronger,
he says the means through which we cure are very mild.
"there is no necessity for any violent attack upon the organism for the eradication of
even an inveterate disease of old standing; the cure by this method takes place by
only a gentle, imperceptible and yet often rapid transition from the tormenting
natural disease to the desired state of permanent health."
By the time of Hahnemann diseases were much simpler and his experience was that
with one treatment he could cure a chronic condition.
This idea is not valid anymore with the condition of health of contemporary people.
In paragraph 52, "Surely no intelligent physician, after these examples as clear as
daylight, can still go on in the old ordinary system of medicine, attacking the body,
as has hitherto been done, in its least diseased parts with (allopathic) medicines that
have no direct pathological (homoeopathic) relation to the disease to be cured,
with purgatives, counter-irritants, derivatives" these are the means of the then
conventional medicine "and thus at a sacrifice of the patient's strength,
inducing a morbid state quite heterogeneous and dissimilar to the original one."
After this discovery of mind, he says you don't have to attack the organism
with such violent means, with which not only you don't cure the patients
but you create on top of it, parallel to the disease, another artificial disease due to
the medications that you are using.
You see how contemporary he is? When he was writing this, he was considered
totally out of any comprehension of his contemporary colleagues.
"to the ruin of his constitution, by large doses of mixtures of medicines generally of
unknown qualities" He says they attack the organisms with mixtures, with chemicals
of which they don't even know their origin.
"thus at a sacrifice of the patient's strength, inducing a morbid state quite
heterogeneous and dissimilar to the original one
[...]the employment of which can have no other result, as is demonstrated by the
eternal laws of nature in the above and all other cases in the world in which
a dissimilar disease is added to the other in the human organism,
for a cure is never thereby effected in disease, but an aggravation is the invariable
consequence."
So no cure can happen in such a way and only an aggravation.
"therefore it can have no other result than that either"... he repeats the same idea
again and again. So once you understand the meaning of one paragraph...
Each paragraph has a specific meaning but Hahnemann wants to make it very clear
and he repeats this idea again and again in the same paragraph.
You don't have to go through it and remember everything which he says.
He concludes that there are only 2 methods one with similars and one with the
opposites. And he says that the opposites never bring about a real cure.
"True, mild cures take place, as we see, only in a homoeopathic way - a way which,
as we have also shown above in a different manner, by experience and deductions,
is also the true and only one whereby diseases may be most surely, rapidly and
permanently extinguished by art; for this mode of cure is founded on an eternal,
infallible law of nature."
What he says is that cure can never happen with giving medicines which have
an opposite effect. This is not always correct, of course.
What happens is that in conventional medicine the means that we have discovered
are much more subtle and not as crude as those used at that time.
What happens by using antibiotics, which is the main method of treatment of
any kind of inflammatory disease, is that once the person is attacked by an agent
and there is an inflammation we have 2 possibilities.
One is that the antibiotic will suppress the acute disease
and will exterminate the causative factor whether it is bacteria or microbe etc.
After that the organism will try to get rid of this invention of the antibiotics
so he processes the chemicals and if the organism is strong enough, he can
overcome it and can reestablish the original condition in which he was.
But if the organism was not strong enough, then he can never overcome it and
the organism is imprinted with a new disease which will remain for the rest of
the life of the person.
So strong organism can overcome treatment with antibiotics.
Weak organisms are going to be destroyed and either die or remain in a state of
chronic disability.
When Hahnemann says there is no other way but the homeopathic
this is not absolutely true. What is true is that there is no other way
which can cure with such a mild way as the homeopathic remedy. That is true.
On the other hand we have to understand that the diseases that we see today
are of such deep nature that many times we cannot cure
with Homeopathy as well.
So there is a group of diseases today that the human race is suffering from
that cannot be cured with Homeopathy.
Even very good Homeopathy, all kinds of Homeopathy...
We consider them to be incurable. Kent had also realized this and in
his observations he had said that if you see that you give a remedy
and there is an immediate amelioration and after a few days there is a relapse
this case is considered incurable by Homeopathy.
We saw a case this morning which is actually in this level.
I told you about the other case almost identical to this with the difference
that the one I was talking to you about it was a girl of this style, very thin,
but her knees were so big with a little leg and tremendously swollen.
What happened with this girl after 9 months the swelling went down,
the body became more muscular but even 9 months later the swelling
had remained. That means the deformity could not be reduced to
totally normal condition but the girl could run, could do anything without pain.
What is the difference between this case and the case I saw?
When I saw the case I described to you, it was coming from a hospital
under heavy drugs, cortisone and methotrexate and therefore the organism
gave out a clear picture.
That's why I said here about the child. Let the child go to the hospital
and find out what happens. It's not going to be cured.
In the beginning the cortisone will show an effect on the inflammation
and the child will move a little bit better.
But as the organism will have a secondary reaction after the cortisone,
then there will be an explosion. Then the pains will be much more,
the cortisone and the methotrexate need to be increased.
After a period of time they will realize they could do nothing.
Now they say come here to treat. I don't know if they say it.
Maybe there are some people who may say that.
But they do not realize that this kind of harassed organism is not a strong organism.
It's an organism which has been weakened in its very deep defenses.
Such an organism cannot overcome it.
The problem with conventional Medicine is that they put all cases with the same
pathology and the same level together. They think it's Ok.
If I treat a few cases and they have recovered (kind of), all cases will recover.
No, not all cases will recover. There will be cases like this one that goes to
the hospital and they will soon find out that she cannot be cured.
Unless... what? Who can tell me?
If this child is given cortisone and methotrexate and she is improved
for 6 months, what will happen?
In order to get a skin eruption it has to happen that MTX contains a substance
which is homeopathic to the case, in which case she will have a correct reaction.
She will have the wrong reaction. That means the problem will be pushed on
the mental/ emotional level. This girl will remain a wreck mentally and emotionally.
As long as the girl will remain in a state of fears, panic, anxieties, depression
the pains will be remaining less.
But if the organism is strong enough will bring back again and again
the inflammation to the periphery, to the joints.
After the hospital has given up and the child returns,
the picture of the remedy will be much more clear.
After the heavy treatment the organism is like nullifying all the effect of
the homeopathic remedies.
The homeopathic remedies had several effect, she was very aggressive,
give Stram., the aggressiveness is going down.
Then there was a depression, you give Aurum and it comes out.
All these symptoms were suppressed in a way, after the conventional treatment
they will flare up and will show a picture which can be leading and you may give
the remedy and the action will be there.
I believe that Sulphur had the best effect and maybe could not wait longer.
If you waited to see really the next remedy, maybe waited 2-3 months,
the next remedy will be apparent and then there could be a process.
Instead the parents were pressurizing and you can give a remedy to counteract
certain symptoms but not the disease.
"[...] The homoeopathic way is the only proper one, because of the three possible
modes of employing medicines in diseases, it is the only direct way to a mild, sure,
permanent cure without doing injury in another direction, and without weakening
the patient. The pure homoeopathic mode of cure is the only proper way,
the only direct way..." He repeats the same idea again and again.
"the only way possible to human skill"
"The allopathic method of treatment utilized many things against disease,
but usually only improper ones and ruled for ages in different forms called
systems. Every one of these, following each other from time to time and
differing greatly each from the other, honored itself with the name
of Rational Medicine."
By that time the conventional Medicine was called the rational Medicine.
Totally irrational actually... Today we have the same problem.
They say we accept only the medicine which gives evidence.
Evidence- based medicine. Rational that time, now evidence-based medicine.
What is evidence-based? Evidence-based is when there is evidence that the patient
is cured. Then you have an evidence that this is correct remedy.
What they mean is that if you can show me in an experiment that the particular
chemical drug can kill the causative factor this is evidence-based medicine.
Evidence means I can see that this drug can kill these bacteria.
And ignores the fact that there is another method that cures the patient.
Evidence-based medicine is not interested about cure or not cure.
It's only interested if you can prove to me and I can see it in the microscope or
in a way that this drug can kill this morbific agent. Totally irrational.
Paragraph 55, "The second mode of employing medicines in diseases,
the allopathic or heteropathic, which without any pathological relation to what
is actually diseased in the body, attacks the parts most exempt from the disease,
in order to draw away the disease through them."
He means here that there is a part which suffers, which is the liver, and says that
you attack another part, which is the blood, bloodletting.
They thought that by letting the blood the disease will go away...
"Soon, however, the public became convinced that the sufferings of the sick
increased and heightened with the introduction of every one of these systems
and methods of cure if followed exactly."
That means if the doctor who does the bloodletting or applying the different
therapies of the time did not realize that his patient is getting worse, that patient
would die and he did not realize. He says you have to draw all the blood.
Draws, draws, draws... all the blood and then the patient is gone, not the disease.
That was the idea. That was the experience. That's why he writes that.
"The third and only remaining method of employing medicine in diseases, which,
besides the other two just alluded to, is the only other possible one, is the
antipathic (enantiopathic) or palliative method, wherewith the physician could
hitherto appear to be most useful and hoped most certainly to gain
his patient's confidence by deluding him with momentary amelioration.
But I shall now proceed to show how inefficacious and how injurious this third
and sole remaining way..." So he refers here to milder means of treating
which are having an effect, which is for a short period of time.
They show amelioration and the doctor is very happy and then he says
"deluding the patient by this momentary amelioration".
"it is certainly the only one of the modes of treatment adopted by the allopaths
that had any manifest relation to a portion of the sufferings caused by
the natural disease; but what kind of relation? Of a truth the very one
(the exact contrary of the right one) that ought most to be avoided if we would
not delude and make a mockery of the patient affected with a chronic disease."
He talks about the partial amelioration of a chronic condition by using means
which are milder than some other ones that could kill the patient.
This is something which happens today also with different systems of therapies.
Today we have hundreds of different ways of therapies.
Some of them are able to bring about a kind of partial amelioration.
If you meditate and you are an excitable person, it will do good to your heart
and your heart will calm down.
If you take some herbs that will have an effect upon the different parts of
your body and there are aromatherapies and too many therapies that today
can have a partial effect and show a partial amelioration.
But in the same way a partial amelioration could be by the similar, not the
Similimum, the similar homeopathic remedy.
If the remedy is close enough, it can have an effect for a week or two...
"In order to carry into practice this antipathic method, the ordinary physician
gives, for a single troublesome symptom from among the many other symptoms of
the disease, which he passes by unheeded, a medicine concerning which it is
known that it produces the exact opposite of the morbid symptom sought
to be subdued, from which, agreeably to the fifteen - centuries - old traditional rule
of the antiquated medical school."
He actually talks about the herbal medicine here. The effect of the herbal medicine.
The medicine which call the grannies-medicine.
He means that through tradition people learn that certain herbs have a specific
effect upon a specific disorder. And he says the doctor does not pay attention to the
global symptomatology of the patient. He takes one symptom, for instance,
if the prostate gland is swollen and there is no way to urinate, then there are some
herbs that will facilitate the urination.
If there is some sand in the kidneys, there are some herbs that may be used and have
an effect in cleaning the kidneys. This is what he means.
But he says out of the 3 methods, the best one and the most effective and the mildest
is the homeopathic. Today still remains valid what he says.
Paragraph 58, "If in estimating the value of this mode of employing medicines,
we should even pass over the circumstance that it is an extremely faulty
symptomatic treatment..." He goes on criticizing this kind of treatment
which treats one symptom by a mild herb.
Paragraph 59, "Important symptoms of persistent diseases have never yet been
treated with such palliative, antagonistic remedies, without the opposite state,
a relapse - indeed, a palpable aggravation of the malady - occurring a few hours
afterwards".
He says again the same thing. You give this palliative, after a while there is a relapse
and the relapse may be even worse than the first time.
This is something we have observed as well.
If a disease has been suppressed, when it comes back as a relapse,
the relapse is much more intense than the original state.
If you take multiple sclerosis and cortisone is given and while the person
could not walk or walk with difficulty, within 2 days he starts walking normally.
But when the relapse comes, it's much more serious than when he started.
Then you repeat the cortisone and then he starts walking again.
The 3rd or the 4th time every patient with M.S. realizes that they should stop
taking cortisone because finally the relapse is always much worse
than the beginning.
What is the difference with homeopathic treatment - does Homeopathy cure M.S.?
A few cases can be cured. If we see the case from the very beginning, we can cure.
But it has to be within 6 months or 1 year.
If the damage has been done in the plaques, then what happens is that
due to the edema which is formed due to the plaque,
the cortisone reduces the edema and the pressure goes away and the nerves
work better. And that is why there is this kind of amelioration.
But in the meantime you have weakened the immune system, so next time
it cannot produce the same reaction.
It takes cortisone and while cortisone is needed for a week in the first place
then it needs two weeks of cortisone, then three weeks, then five weeks and
the relapse or the final distraction is much faster with people who take cortisone
than people who avoid cortisone.
There are some people who can avoid cortisone, who decide that cortisone is not
good, they take it one time, they see the bad effect and they stop, they don't take
it again and they try other means; acupuncture, homeopathy etc.
Such people will live longer.
People under cortisone will go fast.
Do you want to ask something? You don't have any questions about all these things?
Hahnemann gives an example here which is interesting.
He says "For a persistent tendency to sleepiness during the day the physician
prescribes coffee, whose primary action is to enliven; and when it had exhausted
its action the day somnolence increased". So those who drink coffee they know.
They drink one cup of coffee and they become more alive but after 2-3 hours
the whole organism goes down and the sleepiness becomes much stronger.
This is the reason we forbid our patients to drink coffee.
Because how does this liveliness come? By stimulating the nervous system.
So coffee stimulates the nervous system and produces this effect with the side
effect later on which is much worse.
So there are people, especially mentally working people, that they have to work,
scientists, journalists, they have to work mentally and drink a lot of coffee. Like me.
You can check. I leave it here and see it's not coffee. I leave it on purpose.
They drink 10 coffees the day to be able to continue with their intellectual work.
And this becomes an impediment for the homeopathic treatment.
It counteracts the action of the remedy. You know the German scientist who came
to take an interview from me... it's a scientific magazine.
She came to take an interview with me and she wanted to make an experiment
after we had a lot of discussions.
She said can you give me a remedy to see whether you can produce in me certain
symptoms that you claim that you produce?
I said Ok I will do this. In the meantime... there was an interview for 3 days from
morning till nights. This kind of interview.
She was a biochemist and she was the head of scientific department...
We ate together, we talked a lot etc. So by the third day I knew quite about
her organism. She did not know, of course. She would take the salt and put.
She was closed. My conclusion was that she needed Nat-m.
How is your relationship? Do you have a nice man? No, I don't have.
He has left her! I said Nat-m. I will give you this little sugar, you put it in water
in your house and for 20 days you take a sip from that water. That's all.
Ok I will do. But with one condition.
If you want to see an effect, you will have to stop drinking coffee.
She says I drink 10 coffees a day in order to do my job. I will not be able to do my job.
I said I think you will be able to do your job. So she took it.
In the meantime in the envelope I wrote - in case the remedy was not the exact
remedy she needed to be cured and it was close - the symptoms that she might
have after the 200CH taking every day. I wrote that you may have a headache in
the morning...
I wrote certain symptoms I thought maybe will come because of the repetition,
the proving. About 9 months later we met in Berlin in the Congress.
Where in that congress I have been given this little car, and she came for a follow up.
She says nothing happened with the remedy you gave me. I said nothing?.
But I see that you feel quite well, not only that, but today that you woke up at
about 4-5 a.m. - and it was 11 a.m. when we met - and you still feel so good,
in spite of the fact you have not slept. She said, yes it is true. I went to bed at 4 a.m.
I said this is due to the fact that I gave you a remedy that I thought it will cure you.
And you have been doing all your job all these months without drinking any coffee.
Yes. How do you explain that?
She said why accept that this little powder brought a cure to me and not say that
I am feeling well because I stopped drinking coffee?
I said I understand you are a scientist, you like experiments and therefore we will
do now the next experiment to find out whether it was due to coffee or not.
Very simple. If it is because of the coffee then... I told you that if you drink coffee
the action of the remedy will stop and you agreed.
If you drink coffee because it will stop the action of the remedy, you will come back
to the terrible state you were when you came to interview me. Will you do it?
She said no.
We wrote an article, she said you may understand, it is a scientific magazine.
We cannot come out and praise Homeopathy. So we have written an article which
was balanced but in the end it will be a little phrase saying maybe there is
something in these sugar pills.
And they did write an article of that type which I have it.
But it was a big struggle. You know how easily she could find a way...
Why not, I stopped coffee. I told her, Ok why don't you drink now,
if you want to find out really, drink 1-2 weeks of coffee and you come back to
the previous state. She was beaming with energy and she was so well.
When I saw her the first time she was depressed... Now she was beaming.
Since you are a scientist, do it. She knew very well actually but you see
immediately the human mind, how she found out an excuse.
That is why I have said no coffee when you take homeopathic remedies.
"[...]  for frequent waking at night he gave in the evening, without heeding
the other symptoms of the disease, opium, which by virtue of its primary action
produced the same night (stupefied, dull) sleep, but the subsequent nights..."
He gives different examples. " [...]The old school physician rejoices that he is able
to reduce for several hours the velocity of the small rapid pulse in
cachectic patients with the very first dose of uncombined purple foxglove
(which in its primary action makes the pulse slower)."
I don't know what foxglove is. It may be a kind of herb. Digitalis?
How do you know? You concluded it or you know? You know the name, Ok.
So giving Digitalis of course reduces the palpitation but then you stop
the Digitalis and the palpitation comes back.
Paragraph 60, "If these ill-effects are produced, as may very naturally be expected
from the antipathic employment of medicines, the ordinary physician imagines
he can get over the difficulty by giving, at each renewed aggravation, a stronger
dose of the remedy..." As I said before every time there is a relapse, he has to give
a stronger dose... It's unbelievable how accurate he is.
"whereby an equally transient suppression is effected"
For the time being there is a suppression and when the remedy stops
the suppression goes away.
Paragraph 61, "had physicians been capable of reflecting on the sad results
of the antagonistic employment of medicines, they had long since discovered
the grand truth, THAT THE TRUE RADICAL HEALING ART MUST BE FOUND IN
THE EXACT OPPOSITE OF SUCH AN ANTIPATHIC TREATMENT OF THE SYMPTOMS
OF DISEASE; they would have become convinced, that as a medicinal action,
antagonistic to the symptoms of the disease is followed by only transient relief,
and after that is passed, by invariable aggravation..."
What I said about the child? The moment they will treat the child with heavy drugs
the relapse of the child will be quite severe and during that time the picture of the
remedy might be quite clear. You have to be careful.
Paragraph 62, "but on what this pernicious result of the palliative, antipathic
treatment and the efficacy of the reverse, the homoeopathic treatment depend,
is explained by the following facts..."
Paragraph 63, "Every agent that acts upon the vitality, every medicine, deranges
more or less the vital force, and causes a certain alteration in the health of the
individual for a longer or a shorter period. This is termed primary action.
Although a product of the medicinal and vital powers conjointly, it is principally
due to the former power. To its action our vital force endeavors to oppose
its own energy. This resistant action is a property, is indeed an automatic action
of our life-preserving power, which goes by the name of secondary action
or counteraction."
He says every medicinal agent will cause an effect.
And that is called a primary action.
During the process of the organism coming back to normal
there is another stage which he calls secondary action.
So the first action is the stimulation and depends on the dose
and after the organism has reached... it's like a pendulum.
After it has reached this side, then the organism will go back until it comes to
the original state. This is the first idea of the proving of remedies.
This is how he is going to describe the proving of the remedies.
"During the primary action of the artificial morbific agents (medicines)
on our healthy body, as seen in the following examples, our vital force seems
to conduct itself merely in a passive (receptive) manners, and appears,
so to say, compelled to permit the impressions of the artificial power..."
First the organism accepts it and permits the action. It's passive.
And then gets angry and reacts.
"acting from without to take place in it and thereby after its state of health;
it then, however, appears to rouse itself again"
The organism gets up, reacts and we have a secondary action "to develop (A) the
exact opposite condition of health (counteraction, secondary action ) to this effect
(primary action) produced upon it, if there be such an opposite, and that in as great
a degree as was the effect (primary action) of the artificial morbific agent on it,
and proportionate to its own energy."
When you take a chemical drug, the organism has to accept it
and this produces certain symptomatology.
After a while the organisms tries to get rid of the action of this drug
and produces another set of symptoms which he calls secondary symptoms.
"or (B) if there be not in nature a state exactly the opposite of the primary action,
it appears to endeavor to indifferentiate itself, that is, to make its superior power
available in the extinction of the change wrought in it from without
(by the medicine), in the place of which it substitutes its normal state
(secondary action, curative action)."
This secondary action, that means the reaction to the invader, he calls the curative
action. This is the basis of the disease, how disease is produced.
There is an invader, whether it is chemical or psychological or biological.
And the organisms accepts it and feels suppressed but there is a point when the
organisms reacts back. I'll give you an example.
There is an invasion of bacteria. The organism accepts it.
And for a period of time these bacteria are increasing in number
until there is a critical point.
At the critical point the organism decides that now I have a situation
which is dangerous and I have to react.
This time is when we perceive the actual symptoms of the disease.
Actually they are not symptoms of the disease, they are symptoms of the
defense mechanism reacting towards the disease. Is this clear?
Another example. Let's take another invader.
Let's take the action of a stressful information.
There is somebody who comes and tells you your son had an accident
in the streets half an hour ago.
With the information there is something you feel.
Primary action. Fear, anxiety, different feelings and sensations.
Now the organism has 2 possibilities. One is to admit this stress
and accommodate it. What I mean is being able not to react immediately.
You keep your control and you deal with the stress and either the stress will
leave nothing because you dealt with it, you overcame the results and your organism
is detoxified.
There is another situation where your organism will not be able to deal with
such a stress and he will mobilize a defense mechanism that will have to
accommodate the stress within the organism.
Accommodate the stress means that if you have a weak stomach,
you will start having nausea, eventually heartburns, vomiting and finally
a tumor or cancer.
In another organism it means that after the stress there is severe palpitation
and heart infarct. On another organism there is a skin eruption which manifests
3 days after the stress with psoriasis all over the place.
At a certain moment there is an invasion and there is the reaction from
the organism. And the organism either is able to counteract the invader and have
no side effects or will have side effects which we call disease.
Now he has psoriasis, gastritis, M.S., ulcerative colitis...
This is how disease is produced but what manifests as symptomatology is always
the reaction of the organism in order to accommodate a stress to which is weak
in facing it completely and get rid of it.
If I cannot face it completely and I cannot get rid of that stress...
I lost my loved one... if I can accommodate it and I can cry and go over it, no problem.
If there is a weakness in me that I cannot overcome, then the weakness will be
shown upon my weakest point in the organism.
Heart, stomach, kidneys, whatever.
In the same way the proving is done.
We take pure organisms, which are in good condition and we give some amount
of drug which is for the organism a foreign thing.
So we actually poison the organism slowly to see how he will react.
In the same way that disease is produced, in the same way we produce
an artificial disease through taking a drug every day.
The primary and secondary reaction for us they don't have to be separated.
Both consist the action of the remedy.
So whatever symptoms a remedy is producing in the organism
these symptoms we write down as a reaction of the organism.
The proving is nothing else but the effort of the organism to get rid of
the foreign substance that we inserted in it.
That's why it is very dangerous what some people are doing
thinking they are doing a proper proving.
That means taking a dose of 30CH and then start recording symptoms.
Most of the time this is wrong and it's a matter of imagination more
than actual fact. In order to have an effect on the organism,
the organism must receive a substance which he considers it as foreign and
dangerous and has to get rid of this. To have the secondary reaction.
Secondary reaction is when the organism tries to get rid of what we inserted in it.
In order to recognize this you have to insert a large enough dose.
It's not the potency. We will explain later on.
Hahnemann created a problem with this later on when he speaks about the high
potency that you can give to a prover but he adds one sentence which is very
important. He says, you can give a potency to a person and see a proving
if he is sensitive enough to that drug.
-In the case of the invader being the stressful news what is the secondary reaction?
The expression of grief or the pathology i.e. a stomach ulcer...?
-You want to say the example. Which example? Of the microbes?
-The stressful news. Your son...
-When they tell you something which is very bad for you to hear
there is some primary reaction. You shout, you may laugh nervously...
But the organism is not able to control this stress.
That means the organism is affected quite deeply.
So the primary reaction is the shouting, the nervous laughing etc.
The secondary reaction is when the effect comes upon the brain and
there is a depression. That is the secondary reaction.
There is a panic attack, an anxiety and stays in the organism... that is a secondary
reaction. The primary reaction was to be hysterical. You fell down and you had a
hysteric fit. Then you get up and the organism faces the stress and the stress is
so big that you cannot overcome by natural reactions.
And then the effect stays in the organism. But the effect you cannot see it.
What you see is only the reaction of the organism.
What you see is the panic attacks which come every time that there is something
that reminds you of that time of stress.
If in the time of stress, there was a sound, a cock shouting,
the organism connects the two and when there is a cock making that sound,
then there is a panic state. That is something encoded in the organism and
it is a reaction of the organism in order to save you from killing yourself
because the stress is too much, I cannot overcome it (the organism).
So it has found a way to side track you from death, from dying.