In paragraph 44, he is asking the question if two similar diseases are met
in the organism what happens?
Do they go to different places and the answer is given in paragraph 45.
He says, "No! Two diseases, differing, it is true, in kind but very similar
in their phenomena..." What does he mean by that?
He says two diseases which are different in pathology
but similar in their phenomena...
Do you understand? Can anybody tell me what he understands of that?
There are different pathologies but if the overall symptoms are similar
the remedy is the same. I will give you an example.
You have a case of gastritis with heartburns
which needs according to the symptoms Nux-v.
because of heartburn and different other Nux-v. symptoms.
And you have another case of spastic colitis,
which the overall symptoms indicate the same remedy, Nux-v.
Though the pathology is different "but very similar in their phenomena
and effects and in the sufferings and symptoms they severally produce,
invariably annihilate one another, whenever they meet together
in the organism." What he means here, still we do not see today.
As I said before, this cannot be seen by us because we quickly stop
the disease by some medication and so we do not allow time for
another disease to come and cure the previous one.
In his mind the understanding has come how diseases are cured.
So he observes this phenomenon, which we cannot observe anymore
but for him suddenly comes the light. This is the way nature cures diseases.
Later on he will find out that remedies produce similar symptomatology
with diseases and when a remedy is producing a similar symptomatology,
then that remedy can cure the disease.
This paragraph has no other meaning, he explains his way of thinking
before he arrives at the conclusion, that in order to cure a disease,
nature cures this way, therefore the natural way to cure is the way
I am going to tell you later on.
This is the meaning of this paragraph and if you take it literally
you may not understand what he says.
"invariably annihilate one another whenever they meet together
in the organism; the stronger disease namely, annihilates the weaker,
and that for this simple reason, because the stronger morbific power
when it invades the system, by reason of its similarity of action
involves precisely the same part of the organism that were previously
affected by the weaker morbid irritation, which, consequently,
can no longer act on these parts, but is extinguished."
In this paragraph he gives an explanation but the explanation is not correct.
He has an understanding but is it correct? We can discuss about it, we'll find out.
He says when a similar disease comes into the organism,
then this similar is stronger.
First of all how do you know it's stronger?
He presupposes that the next disease that comes, which is similar, is stronger.
Why? It could be weaker. And because it is stronger, it occupies the places.
If the previous disease was occupying the liver, now the new one which is similar,
comes and occupies the liver itself
and therefore annihilates and extinguishes the previous one.
But what happens with the new one? He does not say.
It's an understanding that he has but his understanding on this point is not correct.
I will explain to you why I say that and what actually happens.
"because whenever the vital force, deranged by the primary disease,
is more strongly attacked by the new, very similar, but stronger dynamic
morbific power" he assumes that the new is stronger.
With this logic we would have to admit that the similar remedy,
which we give and cure the condition, is stronger than the disease.
But this is not true because the potentized remedy cannot cause such
a damage that a real pathology, a real disease can cause in the organism.
We cannot say that the potency we give is stronger.
Later on he will say that the potency is stronger than the disease.
And therefore it's a kind of fight between them and the stronger
annihilates and extinguishes the weaker.
This cannot be true.
These issues have never been discussed. Either some people take this
for granted "this is the Bible and it is finished" or some others say
" I don't understand the Organon" and they don't even read it.
We have to read the Organon with logic and with experience.
Otherwise we will not understand the real treasure that it contains.
If you stay with that in your mind, stronger and weaker disease,
dissimilar is stronger...
there is something which is left inside as a question mark.
You feel something is not correct.
"is more strongly attacked by the new, very similar" he repeats the same thing
"but stronger dynamic morbific power, it therefore now remains affected
by the latter alone, whereby the original, similar but weaker disease must,
as a mere dynamic power without material substratum, cease to exercise
any further morbid influence on the vital force, consequently it must cease to exist".
It makes no logic here but he was not in a position yet to perceive what was
actually happening in the organism under the homeopathic remedy.
But he had noticed that when 2 dissimilar diseases are met there was a kind
of annihilation of both. It does not say "the stronger stays".
He says the stronger and the weaker are both annihilated...
I will complete and then you ask.
It's interesting now he had written this all along in the fifth edition
and he seems he was not happy with what he had written.
So he comes in the 6th edition and he adds "or (in other words), the new similar
but stronger morbific potency" he introduces the idea of potency now.
"controls the feelings of the patient and hence the life principle
on account of its peculiarity."
He's trying to understand himself what was going on.
"The new similar but stronger morbific potency controls the feelings
of the patient and hence the life principle on account of its peculiarity,
can no longer feel the weaker similar which becomes extinguished."
That means the potency of the new similar disease is such
that controls the feelings of the person.
Here the feelings have a different meaning, the actual thing that he wants
to say is the sensation of the patient.
And since it controls the sensation of the patient therefore
"controls the life principle on account of its peculiarity" of the new disease.
The new disease controls the feelings of the patient
and for it was never anything material, but a dynamic - spirit-like - affection.
The life principle henceforth is affected only and this but temporarily
by the new, similar but stronger morbific potency."
The life principle is affected only temporarily.
So he has to explain how a stronger influence extinguishes the weaker
but it doesn't stay itself.
He runs into great problems and he cannot explain it.
"The life principle henceforth is affected only" it is absurd
"and this but temporarily". It is affected only for the time being.
"by the new similar but stronger morbific potency".
And later on he will give examples where he'd seen this phenomenon taking place.
You want to ask.
-I don't understand well. Can you give us an example?
Like something in your practice why Hahnemann is not right?
-Here there is no matter of giving examples. It's a theoretical matter.
Hahnemann says that a stronger disease similar extinguishes the weaker.
This is his explanation. He has seen this happening in nature.
This is something which he has observed.
He thinks that this phenomenon takes place because the second disease
is stronger than the first one.
And I say this is wrong. I will explain it to you.
I will give you an example but this is what he says here.
This is theoretical explanation, he has seen a fact and he gives his own
explanation and understanding. With my logic this is not correct.
Why? Because there are missing several things.
First of all how come that the stronger disease that affected
the organism does not stay?
If I have a drug that can suppress, extinguish pathology,
then I can say that this drug is stronger than the disease
and extinguishes the symptomatology of the disease. This I can say.
But what we know today is that if this drug is stronger than the disease
then this drug will put its stamp on the organism.
This we know it to be true because we know the side effects of all drugs.
All drugs which are given for extinguishing the disease
are stronger than the disease and they suppress
whatever pathological manifestation is there.
-I want to point a question that 3 paragraphs later, in paragraph 50
Hahnemann says the disease after that stays, he never says that it goes off,
he just gives this example here but after that says that some of the disease go
if it is morbid it goes. Some of the disease stay.
When they are similar, the stronger disease stays after that in the organism.
This is a disadvantage of this way. The question is why you think it is not right?
-How else can I explain? I have already explained.
When there are 2 dissimilar diseases, the one suppresses the other
or they find different places where they stay.
In conventional treatment the drug which is given is always stronger
than the disease...
Wait, if you don't understand this try to listen to what I say
because I cannot repeat too many times.
The disease can be extinguished by a stronger drug.
-But the drug is not similar.
-Here he says that if the disease is similar, it's stronger.
So my argument is not that it doesn't work...
this works but not in the way he explains it.
It does not happen in the way he explains. It happens in another way.
I will explain to you now what is the way that happens to cure
the disease by a similar remedy.
-I understood this paragraph in that way. If somebody has a sore throat
that will be cured by Bell. but while he is in that process, he has also meningitis,
he will also be cured with Bell.
So the meningitis is the most dangerous disease and will override the sore throat.
Both are cured with Bell. This I understood from the paragraph.
-No, it's another thing you are saying. It's different.
I will give you now the explanation.
What is the explanation of the similar and how it acts?
When there is the manifestation of a symptomatology due to a disease,
this manifestation is what we call the overall symptoms of the patient.
So the symptoms of the patient what do they represent?
They represent bad guys that appear the headache, the fever and all that?
All these are bad things happening in the organism?
Or the organism in its effort to cure itself produces these symptoms?
The symptoms are the effort of the organism to cure itself.
Imagine that there is an immune system behind the organism
which is stimulated by the bacteria, virus and in its effort the organism produces
fever, headaches, pains, inflammation etc.
So what we observe in the organism is its effort to cure itself.
Is this logical? Do you understand it?
Is anybody who says no I don't believe it? Symptoms are accidental?
Symptoms are organized by an intelligence in such a way as to counteract
all the imbalances, electrochemical reactions which are happening in the
organism under attack. The defense of the organism is the manifestation...
How do we know that the organism is defending himself? By the symptoms.
The fever is necessary. Streptococcus needs in order to die to bring the heat
of the body more than 38.8 C. sometimes 39 or 40C.
And then it is extinguishing the microbes.
But now the fever comes down, as the culture of the microbes in the organism
has died most of it, the fever comes down.
As the organism becomes cold again there are some guys which have remained
alive and they start multiplying again and start multiplying quite fast.
Next day you observe the fever is quite high, the organism has to go 38.9 or 39.3 C.
The 3rd day if the organism is sensitive towards the attack of particular bacteria
is going to be 40 C and then it becomes dangerous and then we have different
kinds of other phenomena.
But definitely what the organism is producing is for his defense,
otherwise he will die.
If you can imagine that a microbe comes into the organism
and the organism does not react, the body will be eaten up,
he will just dissolve after a few days, eaten up by the microbes.
The organism must react, there is a danger,how? By symptoms.
So all the symptoms are the means through which the organism defends itself.
You have to be very careful here.
Unless you understand this point you will never understand how it works.
What is best? To suppress the symptoms, because there is high fever,
anti-fever remedies, there are tremendous headaches, some painkillers and
at the same time there are some affected joints, anti-inflammatory drugs
to be allopathically treated, to suppress all this reaction of the organism.
As a result there are side effects etc. and the disease is going bad.
What is the best way to do it? If you give a stronger drug, this suppresses it.
What is the best way to do it?
You take a case of chronic headaches or menstrual problems,
severe abdominal pains together with vomiting, all kind of symptoms...
Twice a week I have a headache, I go to bed for one day and I am finished.
And then next week again, 4-5 days I'm alright...
This indicates that the organism is not balanced. Something is going wrong.
The organism tries every time through these symptoms to cure itself.
It's making an effort and then it gives up. I don't have enough energy,
ammunition, means to bring about a total cure.
Next month another crisis and then again another crisis...
Imagine this organism that through such symptoms tries to cure itself.
But every time fails to bring about a final cure.
We come and we take the symptoms and we base our prescription
on the symptoms trying to fit the remedy to the symptoms.
To make the remedy as similar as possible to the symptoms of the organism.
And then we give the remedy.
Somebody who is logical will say, if you give a remedy that you know it produces
the symptoms of your patient, you will kill him because you will augment,
you will increase his symptoms.
If the disease produces some symptoms and you found a way to give a remedy
that has similar symptoms, you give the remedy and you produce
a tremendous aggravation that may kill the patient.
This is what Hahnemann was doing. He gave doses 1X, 2X repeatedly
but these were similar remedies so the aggravations he produced were
quite frightening.
So he tried to cure and almost killed the patient.
So he says wait a moment I will reduce the dose to 1/10 and then again
so 2X or 3X, again he saw aggravations.
Then he reduced more and more until he reaches in the later years
the idea of potentization and also the constant reducing of the material
of the remedy he was giving.
As far as strength was concerned this was a weaker and weaker similar disease
he was giving.
Why when he gave 1X-3X he saw the aggravation and he was feeling
he will kill the patient?
So himself later on, he will write all this and you will read it, he said when I gave
these low potencies, I saw aggravations... and then I reduced the material dose.
That means by reducing the material dose, he made the new disease weaker
but this weaker disease was better acting.
I have given you all the facts for you to understand what has happened.
What is the explanation of the cure of a patient with a similar remedy?
Can anybody tell me?
-I know from your explanation, the remedy because it is similar to the disease
produces an aggravation in the sick patient and that stimulates
the defense mechanism and causes a healing reaction...
-But why stimulates in the healing reaction?
-Because it produces an aggravation...
-And why it produces an aggravation?
-Because it is similar.
-Because it can produce a similar reaction to the organism.
We make a proving and then we write down the symptoms.
Then the disease comes and we say this disease looks like Belladonna.
Because we have tried to see what Bell. could do, if stimulated
the defense mechanism. If you drink drops of Bell. 1X, which is a poison
and there are some poisoning cases of Bell., the symptomatology is similar.
What you are actually doing is by giving the homeopathic remedy
not only you do not suppress, that means I give you a stronger and annihilates.
No, on the contrary you give the remedy, you increase the symptoms first.
That is why we have the initial aggravation and we say very good.
When we see the initial aggravation, that means we have hit the remedy exactly
and the organism is in a good condition to produce a reaction,
to increase the symptoms.
It was needed that the organism is stimulated, as if it was given extra force
to produce this aggravation... you will see aggravations in chronic headaches
which are terrible.
Patients will say I never felt so bad in my life, for two days I was lying in bed
with headaches... It means that the mechanism is exactly opposite than
what it is explained here by Hahnemann.
The remedy increases the reaction of the organism by giving the extra force
which is missing in its natural state and therefore cannot have an explosion,
an aggravation, a healing crisis.
A healing crisis is nothing else but this phenomenon.
You give a similar remedy, produce a tremendous aggravation
and then the cure comes.
But if you give a stronger remedy, you may suppress even with a similar remedy
you may suppress some symptoms.
If you give a remedy, which is similar to a portion of the totality,
not the Similimum, just similar, you can suppress with the homeopathic remedy.
In which case would happen what he thinks and says here...
A partial suppression may take place.
For instance you have a case with headaches on the right side.
You give Chelidomium but Chel. is not really indicated in the whole
but it covers this local symptom. It is going to suppress this.
It is going to take away the headache on the right side.
For one month there is no headache, next month the headache appears
on the left side.
If that was true, then we could suppress all the time and we do suppress
by the wrong remedy but not entirely wrong.
If it is entirely wrong, it will do nothing. But if it is similar, it may suppress.
Then this can happen. Do you understand the process? Is it clear?
Helen, don't monopolize the ...
-But I had a question like 10 minutes ago. To me this is the most difficult part...
of homeopathy. What is a disease? Disease is not the symptoms, right?
Not all the symptoms are produced by the body to fight the pathogen.
Some of the symptoms are produced by the pathogen itself.
-No, I will explain it to you. I will give you an example so you may understand.
When you have an influenza, the symptoms of the disease are
the high temperature and also the pain in the bones.
All else is something else.
You cannot say that this is due to the disease and these symptoms are due
to something else. Everything is due to the disease.
But the disease is nothing else, as we can understand it, but the manifestation
of symptomatology. This is representing the manifestation, the externalization
so we perceive it of the imbalance.
You may call it imbalance, disease, dysfunction...
By disease you may think only of microbes or bacteria, it's not only that.
It can be stress, it can be anything.
The stress produces a host of symptoms that can remain as a chronic condition.
That means the organism is like encoding. In order to counteract the fact
that I lost my job, I produce a state of panic attacks, depression, anxiety.
So this is the defense of my organism in order to survive.
Otherwise I have to kill myself. All these symptoms are to prevent us from dying.
This is our defense. Now because I have encoded in me that because I do not
have the job, I must have (the organism decides) anxiety and confusion and
I lose some of my memory and a host of symptoms.
If the organism has decided to have these symptoms,
they will repeat themselves again and again because through this
the organism tries to cure itself.
I will give another example.
If you lose a beloved person, what is the first natural reaction?
You cry, you weep one, two, three days... What is this weeping for?
It is to get rid of the sadness and the deep sorrow and the pain inside.
And you weep one month, two months, three, four, five months...
even a big loss is controlled. Why? Because the organism is healthy
and allowed you to react in the best possible way.
Take now another organism who is not so healthy. What will he do?
He says I lost my mother whom I loved very much but I could not cry.
I felt this stricture here but I could not cry.
He comes 3 years after the death of his mother and he gives you the symptoms
of his stress and you say Ok take Nat-m. and the whole thing is solved.
Because you know the constriction and the sadness... and the picture fits.
How much salt you take? I started taking a lot of salt. Why?
Because the chemistry of the body has been unbalanced and now the Natrum
which is needed to nourish the nervous system is not enough.
Because of the imbalance the salt I take is not absorbed, so I don't have
enough salt. Sometimes I take salt and I eat it to complete the loss.
This imbalance, how you bring it back? By giving a remedy which has produced
similar symptoms.
That means the person that you give Nat-m. in such a case
what is the most natural reaction that he will have?
If he was having headaches, he will have strong headaches and the next thing
is, he will break out into crying after 3 years for 2-3 days.
That will be the 'lysis' of the problem. Because you stimulated the organism
with similar symptoms, with a remedy that produces similar symptoms,
you brought out the aggravation and then the 'lysis'.
The fact that he does not give an explanation of how the remedy works,
it does not mean anything, neither anything is lost from his genius.
But we have to look upon and to understand what we are reading and
that's why you are here, to hear the explanation. You want to speak.
-I wanted to ask... you said I think in this paragraph that Hahnemann says
in the beginning by giving low potencies or remedies close to their crude form,
he brought about strong aggravations almost killing the patient.
And I remember this in several paragraphs in the Organon.
He said you have to potentize, to raise potency.
We know that actually if we increase the potency, especially in severely
sick patients, then we can bring about severe aggravations.
That's why we give low potencies. These two things are opposite. That's the question.
-That is correct. Later on we will see that what Hahnemann meant
by aggravation is totally different than what we mean by aggravation
when we say from high potency.
I think you understand this.
Now if you ask, why we give 200CH, it lasts only for 3 months and then
there is a relapse and then you give 1M and the amelioration lasts for 6 months
and then back... Finally you give 10M and it goes away.
This is the potency, the force with which you have to stimulate the vital force,
the energy of the body it needs a great force to react.
It is like somebody who has something which is heavy, under this heaviness
he throws some things and then they come back. They don't go...
Until he goes so nervous and throws away with great force,
then they never come back.
It is an idea which I brought into Homeopathy and later on I remember
I was talking with an American. He was writing this idea.
I said yes but you don't mention that I have brought this idea.
He said you brought the idea? This is common sense.
It's common sense but nobody knows until I have explained it.
After that it's common sense.
-I wouldn't like to open a debate that could maybe not finished until the end
of the night but I think we cannot doubt that Hahnemann noticed that
the final effect of a given dose is stimulating the defense mechanism.
But he has a few problems to answer the question how it works.
Because we observe the facts and we have maybe to put a theory
despite the fact that Hahnemann agrees that we don't need any theories.
I would like to go back to the paragraph 1 and especially not forget the
aphorism 9 in which he says that when there is health, it means that the vital force
is undisturbed and the disease is only a mistuning of the vital force.
And in paragraph 1 he says, I summarize a little bit, our goal is to cure sick people
and that biology does not obey the same laws than in organic matter.
And he says that we'll never be clever enough to understand what are
the mechanisms of life, of disease and so on.
Putting all these items together, he says that there is a fact, certainly inside
the vital force is mistuned and the only way we have to know that is by
the symptoms that we can notice.
To cure we have to explore the properties of every disease, of every
artificial disease, which we call remedies, in the way that we cannot
understand the way of the mistuning of the organism.
This is characterized by the set of symptoms.
So coming back to his own explanations, it's only a force that can act on a force.
Exactly like the geometry in mathematics. We have the direction and the intensity.
When you give the remedy, we can assume it's a kind of force acting on
the vital force and we understand that the only way to have after the action
the reaction of the body we have to stimulate it by a stronger force.
-That's correct. What you are saying is that the vital force which is
the central intelligence of the body decides what to do, always.
What kind of reaction will be there will be decided by the vital force
which is behind all the mechanisms.
We call it immune system, reticuloendothelial system, hormonal system...
all these are the conglomeration of defenses of the human body.
All these are regulated by an intelligence which is behind all that system.
And that system decides how much will raise the hormones, how much will raise
the red blood cells, the white cells... it is an immensely complicated system
that I think nobody can ever understand how it is regulated.
But what we can only know is the manifested effect, which are the symptoms.
Sometimes we can understand the physiopathology of a symptom
but not all symptoms. Never.
-In the last example you say to give to the patient Nat-m.
But I have to ask you why not Ign.?
-Why not Ph-ac., Lach. also? I just brought it as an example.
-Because Hahnemann in paragraph 210 he distinguishes mental diseases
and he said to treat mental diseases like an acute and then we have to give
the antipsoric.
Before we treat with an acute remedy and then with an antipsoric.
My question is about the method that you use...
-A mental remedy, a remedy that has more mental effect.
Why I did not say Ignatia and I said Natrum muriaticum?
Nat-m. has also emotional and mental symptoms, as well as Ignatia.
There are differential symptoms that separate Ign. from Nat-m.
But when I gave an example and I said Nat-m. is just... You don't always
give Nat-m.
Most of the times you give Ign., as you say.
If I say always give Ign., all will give Ignatia forgetting that some cases
are going to be Nat-m. or Staph. with similar symptoms.
-My question was because Ign. is not an antipsoric remedy and Nat-m. is antipsoric...
-Who told you that?
-Hahnemann puts Ignatia in Materia Medica Pura and Nat-m. in the chronic diseases.
-No. That has nothing to do with psoric and syphilitic...
If there are Ign. symptoms you have to prescribe Ign.
You cannot say that I think this person needs a psoric remedy.
Therefore I do not give Ign. because it is not a psoric remedy. I will give Nat-m.
You must not say that. Because if you do, you will make mistakes.
So forget about the idea of miasms when you prescribe a remedy.
A remedy is needed when their symptomatology is on the patient.
That's a rule that if you don't follow, you will go wrong.
Because you feel this is a syphilitic patient.
Because his teeth is like that and because his face is like this...
and because he is washing his hands frequently and because he is spending
a lot of money for nothing.
When he comes to me and he gives me symptoms of Lach., I will give him Lach.
Ignoring the fact... I can see the syphilitic symptoms, not giving Syphilinum
because of that or Mercury or any purely syphilitic remedy.
Until after a year or 2 or 3 during the treatment, he will manifest symptoms
of Merc. or Syph. But when he comes and has symptoms of Lach., I will give Lach.
When he comes and has symptoms of Med., I will give him Med.
He is syphilitic why you give Med? Because he has Med. symptoms.
You have to be careful with that because there is such a misunderstanding
in these matters and people are teaching others the wrong way.
It's a pity that Homeopathy which can be so effective is not effective because
of wrong teachings and misunderstandings of what Hahnemann said
and what can actually this healing method do. It's a great pity.
Anyhow it was explained properly? I see in some of your eyes some elements
of not comprehending what I have said.
This is something which either you understand or you don't understand.
Do not be afraid to say I do not understand, explain to me again.
Because it is a basic idea.
-What is difficult to understand is that Hahnemann was wrong, just to say it.
-There is also possibility that he meant the force should be stronger,
no matter what the material substance is. The dose doesn't matter.
-Yes but ...does not occupy the place... He gives his own explanation.
His understanding is such that the new disease occupies the places of the older
similar and extinguishes because it occupies the place...
All this kind of explanation for somebody who reads it, will not understand it.
I am sure. When I was reading... I read the Organon in 1960.
I read this book and I can tell you I've never read it again
and I am just reading it again now after 50 years.
But this book contains a treasure of medicine. For those who understand it.
The fact that I analyze this paragraph and I say maybe he has a misunderstanding
is nothing. Why we should make a religion out of that saying this is the Bible?
It's more than a treasure because you will see later on the ideas
which are produced, they are unbelievable.
-I understand what you are saying when we give one remedy and what happens
but what we just read now in nature when two similar diseases meet
(aphorism 45) what exactly happens?
Because when he says that nature, when he is giving the example of smallpox
and cowpox, one goes away but what happens to the other one
I am not able to understand. Although we don't see it today, what do you think?
-First of all today we don't have the experience he was having but I think
the same thing happens.
Maybe he did not notice the initial aggravation.
If the two diseases met, he did not notice or has not been told to him that
on the first day there was an aggravation when the two similar diseases met.
That means the defense mechanism, the vital force was mobilized and got rid
with a crisis. This is my explanation.
This was a good question because I've never thought, I just understand it now.
Another paragraph? Ok, another paragraph.
The other paragraph is not so interesting. He gives some examples of which
we are not knowing today. And he mentions the authors of the different examples
that he gives. It's quite a huge paragraph, if I read it all it will take half an hour.
As I read very slowly but the understanding is that he gives...
"The measles bear a strong resemblance in the character of its fever and cough
to the whooping-cough, and hence it was that Bosquillon noticed,
in an epidemic where both these affections prevailed, that many children
who then took measles remained free from whooping-cough during that epidemic.
They would all have been protected from, and rendered incapable of being infected
by the whooping-cough in that and all subsequent epidemics, by the measles,
if the whooping-cough were not a disease that has only a partial similarity to
the measles, that is to say, if it had also a cutaneous eruption similar to what
the latter possesses. As it is, however, the measles can but preserve
a large number from whooping-cough homeopathically, and that only in the
epidemic prevailing at the time."
This is not exactly the right example but anyhow let's have another word.
"Smallpox coming on after vaccination, as well on account of its greater strength
as its great similarity..." let's find another example.
"How often does smallpox cause deafness and dyspnea!
And both these chronic diseases it removed on reaching its acme,
as J. Fr. Closs observed."
The example he gives is not in favor of his explanation.
Smallpox affected the deafness which was there and dyspnea.
"And both these chronic diseases it removed on reaching its acme".
But what was happening is that smallpox is primarily a disease which manifests
on the skin. Therefore the deafness which was there as a chronic condition
and dyspnea through the manifestation of an eruption on the skin
were ameliorated. This is not a similar or dissimilar disease.
It's a matter of manifestation of the problem on the skin level, so strong,
that internal diseases are cured as we all know to happen.
When we give a remedy and then a manifestation on the skin takes place,
we say "very good" because it cures the internal problem.
This is a weak point for Hahnemann but it doesn't matter, we don't have to stick
very much to this, neither here to what he says ...
measles bear a strong resemblance to whooping-cough...
Paragraph 47, "Nothing could teach the physician in a plainer and more
convincing manner than the above what kind of artificial morbific agent (medicine)
he ought to choose in order to cure in a sure, rapid and permanent manner,
conformably with the process that takes place in nature."
All his argument is to say that the only correct means to use in treating diseases
is the similar remedy.
Paragraph 48, "Neither in the course of nature, as we see from all the above
examples, nor by the physician's art, can an existing affection or malady
in any one instance be removed by a dissimilar morbific agent, be it ever so strong,
but solely by one that is similar in symptoms and is somewhat stronger,
according to eternal, irrevocable laws of nature, which have not hitherto
been recognized." This is clear.
Paragraph 49, "We should have been able to meet with many more real,
natural homoeopathic cures of this kind if, on the one hand, the attention of
Observers had been more directed to them, and, on the other hand,
if nature had not been so deficient in helpful homoeopathic diseases."
What he says is actually what I said before. He says it was through observation
which was missed all along with any other physician that they did not find out
how nature cures.
It was due to my observations that I found out this law and this could have been
much more obvious if we could have much more examples.
As I said today we cannot find any examples but during their time the diseases
were plain at the moment, were much more free to do whatever they like
with the human organism.
I have talked too much in my life and my vocal cords are becoming less
and less helpful.
Paragraph 50, "Mighty Nature herself has..." You see the idea of Hahnemann...
He uses an expression "Mighty Nature". You see his perception of Nature.
He understands what a wonderful thing Nature is. He wonders about Nature.
He meditates upon the effects of Nature especially on diseases.
"...herself has, as we see, at her command, as instruments for effecting
homoeopathic cures, little besides the miasmatic diseases of constant character,
(the itch) measles and smallpox, morbific agents which, as remedies, are either
more dangerous to life and more to be dreaded than the disease they are to cure,
they themselves require curing, in order to be eradicated in their turn
- both circumstances that make their employment, as homoeopathic remedies,
difficult, uncertain and dangerous..."
Well, he says it will be nice that we could give a disease for another but
that would have been very dangerous. We cannot give one disease to cure another...
I think you are tired and with all these we have to go to a lighter subject like the one
we discussed in the morning.
Those people who do not like to hear they have the permission to go...
Somebody put the question and said what about concerning homosexuality?
What about the old Greeks who practice a homosexual life?
And what we know in countries where the contact between man and woman is
very prohibited unless they have been in a marriage, the practice of homosexuality
is also quite used. This is different than homosexuality.
The fact that there are hormonal needs that need to have an outlet
in the young age, the young people have a hormonal level quite high and they have
to have an outlet for such a hormonal function.
Therefore they practice primarily masturbation and as secondary outlet
they find, especially if people are overcrowded, overpopulated or
if there are boys staying together in one place like a hostel, you may get some
incidental - what appears to be a - homosexuality. It's not homosexuality.
It's an outlet of a hormonal excess that has to be detonated.
These boys when they come in the correct age 21, 22 they get married and
they are very active, as they tell me, when I was in India for instance.
Indians are sexually very active people.
There is no effect because they had some homosexual experiences in their
young age. Of course, there might be some, especially of late, that because
of predisposition they may continue to practice homosexuality.
This is one part but homosexuality is a much more complicated issue that
I don't want to go now and expand in all the different aspects of homosexuality.
But what I said this morning is a part of an explanation for homosexuality.
The ancient Greeks were like the Indians.
I know because I have spoken a lot with Indian people while I was in India.
I treated them, they explained to me, they told me exactly what was happening
and this is my experience. So in countries like Pakistan, India, Arab countries
maybe, Afghanistan maybe...
On the other hand today there are people who don't feel any attraction
for sexual act. That means the hormones are in a very low level.
They feel no attraction, they have never felt an attraction and these people can
end up going into a monastery. They're the most happy in a monastic life,
devoting themselves to the cultivation of their spiritual part.
But at the same time in monasteries end up some people who have been
disappointed from life and they don't want to live anymore in this world.
They feel it's very painful, so they leave and they go.
These people who were having love affairs, who were sexually active,
heterosexual (straight), they go to the monastery and there maybe some other
things are happening... I don't want to go into details.
The homosexuality that may develop after that it's a matter of conditions and
surroundings and environmental factors that may lead or not...
but what I say is that definitely the hormonal imbalance in an organism can dictate
the sexual behavior of the individual.
When they come to us and we give the homeopathic remedy,
this balance comes back and the person behaves normally.
As Helen remembers, when I was in Berkeley in California, I was treating a case of
a woman 27 and during the consultation she told me "I am a lesbian".
I said to her then "you have to know that if I give you a remedy, you may become
straight". She got angry, she said "What do you think? I am lesbian by choice.
Close the circuit." The class was in another floor.
I turned off the circuit and I explained to her.
She said "Ok, I will take the treatment. Turn on the TV".
I turned on the TV and I continued taking the case.
And I go down to the class. What has happened in the class?
When the girl said turn off the TV, on the receivers they were down,
the people turned their receivers off but they didn't know after that,
they had no communication that the case was continuing.
So they remained with the TV turned off without knowing the continuation
of the case. Then I go to the class and I see a very hostile class.
I pretended I don't understand and I start explaining the case
and why I wanted to give this remedy.
Before 5 minutes one of them gets up and says I am offended because I am also
a lesbian and with your behavior...and I leave. So she left.
I pretended I am not influenced and I continued the analysis of the case.
After another 5 minutes another one gets up and says I am also a lesbian, so I leave...
I said to myself that something is wrong.
I said to them "did you attend the continuation of the taking of the case?"
They said no. Because we turned off the TV the moment she said to do so...
And nobody knew what happened.
The girl was so happy with the taking of the case, the explanation that she donated
to the Clinic where I was teaching, a few thousand dollars by herself.
Just because she was so happy I took her case.
Then I told them that I had to tell her because if she was lesbian by choice,
she may not want to take the remedy. So I had to tell her.
So I explained it and everybody was happy.
2 months later she comes for a follow up and she says I am married with a man,
not with a woman. "Are you happy? - Yes I am happy". This is the experience.
Of course I had a shock. And like Helen, Roger Morrison said
"George don't talk about homosexuality, because here it's a big issue."
I said I don't criticize but I also say that these people born homosexuals
cannot do otherwise because of their predisposition in which they have been
born. You cannot blame them. But this is not the only group.
There are several other groups that they do not have the excuse.
I had other cases, they had confessed to me.
Rich boys with a lot of money and good looking.
They said "Why not? We wanted to experience". That is not homosexuality.
That is different. Because if you have a lot of offer, you are a good looking,
rich boy, every woman wants to have sex with you in order to catch you.
They feel that. Then the instinct becomes dull, they are not interested anymore
on having sex with a woman. Because it's missing the feelings of being in love.
I remember a man who said to me sometimes I wake up in the morning and I look
in the bed next to me and say who is she? He was having sex all night with that girl
with he was sleeping with and he was wondering... I never knew this woman.
He was describing to me... If you continue to do like that, you may try other things
as well, very soon. And he tried of course. Not homosexuality. He did other things.
The instinct was blunted, blocked.
You want to remain alive. I said to all the young people to take it easy.
Don't go with the first woman they offer you...
Within one day they meet and they go and sleep together.
For me that's totally wrong. For both people who are doing this. Why?
Because in this way they will blunt the emotions.
In the end they will have no emotions, only sexual stimulation, nothing else.
Unless there is this connection of feelings, spiritual feeling, you feel friendly,
you feel connected... how can you have sex?
Young people think it is clever if they do it. They destroy themselves.
As I said many times I am not preaching celibacy. On the contrary.
But don't overdo it. That's my advice to you.
Why all the Indians when they laugh they are full of happiness?
Because they practice austerity.
We don't.
Any question? You have 3 minutes for questions?
Are you English? Russian!
-I wonder if you can give your opinion for using isopathic remedies.
There is a book written by Smith on autism where he says you can treat using both...
and then also use isopathic remedies from the vaccines. You have much better results.
-You want to hear my real opinion or...?
I will explain to you what happens with isopathic remedies.
There is something right and wrong in there.
But I need to explain to you more and I don't feel I have the energy.
He has a short question, short answer.
-Because you started with Ancient Greeks... For many years I wanted to ask you
and I am still confused. Believe me I appreciate very much what Ancient Greece
has done for civilization and I have read a lot about this. I just want to understand.
You said about young people, their urges, homosexuality...
Young people, hormones...I totally agree.
But in Ancient Greece and in other civilizations there were important figures.
There were people who were very much appreciated.
Philosophers, orators who also had sometimes these kinds of...
You understand? This is my question. They didn't have this urge. Wise men.
They should be wise men.
-I understand. You say that because of Socrates.
Socrates was supposed to be one who could have sexual contact.
He was a very ugly man but of course he was a genius and he was a very
fascinating teacher, extremely deep.
And it was natural that his students would be fascinated by such a huge spirit.
That is true. And sometimes some things have been recorded
but I will tell you something.
Even if such practice that has been recorded, it was very rare but it has been
exaggerated in our society to justify our present situation.
To say, look at the ancient Greeks, they were doing the same.
They were not doing the same. It was under this condition, the spirit, fascinated, etc.
He was attracting the young people of his time.
Greeks are absolutely genius in killing all the genius people who come from Greece.
It is like a curse to the race that they should kill any great spirit.
The reason I am still alive... You understand I am not a genius!
Otherwise they have promised me several times they will kill me.
But the promise has not come true.
-You are lucky.
I must also say that I believe that this era around 300- 400 B.C. this was the acme
of human civilization and so many ideas have been produced.
Those ancient people have written down almost everything about freedom, justice,
all kinds of philosophical issues, revolving around the human life.
It's unbelievable. I am not a scholar of this. I just have studied a little bit.
It's amazing if you study this. A civilization that had reached its acme.
After that it starts a degeneration of the human race.
Today we are in the bottom of degeneration. We have totally steeped down to
the total degeneration. This is my theory.
After that what is going to happen...? I don't know. We'll disappear as a civilization.
The south Americans will come to north America...
Don't tell me to give you predictions, they will be very depressing.
You will go home very depressed. But it's very disappointing
the condition in which we are as human beings.
If you see the way that wars are performed and what happens in wars
it is unbelievable. We are not humans, we are beasts.
What intrigues me is that the point in the brain that can bring you to heaven,
next to it, is the point that can get you to hell and can become either an angel
or a beast. It's the same point in the brain that changes the connection,
the synapses, I don't know what happens...
Tremendous change and you see the human beings and you say
"My God! I cannot believe!"