In paragraph 40, Hahnemann says, I just add a few thing and few ideas...
Hahnemann says that if there is a new disease, which is dissimilar, not similar with
the one existing... "[...] the new disease, after having long acted on the organism,
at length joins the old one that is dissimilar to it, and forms with it
a complex disease, so that each of them occupies a particular locality in
the organism, namely, the organs peculiarly adapted for it..."
What Hahnemann writes here is a very advanced idea concerning of what was going
to happen in the world 2 centuries later.
He says that when there is a disease, let us say there is chronic high blood pressure
and after some years there is some other chronic condition, which stays for a while
and then the 2 together join and form a new entity.
This is the idea of what we battle here to separate concerning the layers of remedies.
You know in these cases that we see here mostly are complicated cases and
we try to find the uppermost layer.
What actually we try to do is to separate what belongs to a deeper problem that
was there and what has been added afterwards.
Many times we say that this remedy will take care of some of the symptoms
and later on another remedy is needed where the deeper, older disease will
come up to the surface and has to be treated with another remedy.
It is an observation which is really made by a genius by that time 250 years ago.
And I don't understand how people today they want to practice Homeopathy
without understanding these basic issues which are here.
There are some teachers they say "Why do you need it? It's Hahnemann. Old stuff.
You don't need it." Unless a homeopath understands what is written in the Organon
and what I have said based on the Organon, there is no possibility that anybody
can cure a complicated case in which the organism has been tortured by influence
of different diseases and drugs combined to cure the one or the other disease.
So in order to connect paragraph 41, "Much more frequent than the natural diseases
associating with and complicating one another in the same body
are the morbid complication resulting from the art of the ordinary practitioner..."
He's ironic here "[...]  which the inappropriate medical treatment
(the allopathic method) is apt to produce by the long-continued employment of
unsuitable drugs..." He says something which is prophetic.
He says apart from nature itself, which can affect the organism with two
dissimilar diseases, and each one will take its place in the organism, will affect
the heart, the kidneys and will affect also the skin or the respiratory system.
Apart from these which can happen in a natural way much more frequent is
what the doctors are doing to the organism through inappropriate treatment
which they give and create new complex disease.
He considers that the allopathic way of treating diseases is dissimilar...
Since two dissimilar diseases do not extinguish each other, in the same way you have
a disease and you have a dissimilar drug, which is given to combat this disease...
These two now will form a new disease in the body.
Which is actually what has been happening all along with conventional medicine.
Most of the conventional medicines are dissimilar to the disease, which is supposed
to be treated. Therefore invariably they will create a complex condition
in the organism and each one will occupy an organism or an organ or a system
to which they have preference.
What he says is that there is no way to treat really any chronic conditions
with allopathic medicine.
With medicines which are not similar to the disease.
"[...]the constant repetition of the unsuitable medical agent will create a new,
often very tedious, morbid conditions which might be anticipated from
the peculiar powers of the drug."
He was talking with an experience of the drugs used then, which were much more
crude, not refined. Today we are using much more refined drugs and therefore
more dangerous actually.
Why they are much more dangerous? Because they are quickly able to suppress
the disease, do not allow the organism to have a chance to react and
the new disease which manifests will be occupying an organ which will be vulnerable
to such drugs.
Because the new drugs are subtle, they are going to affect the subtlest part
of our being, which is the nervous system, central and peripheral.
If you carefully read this paragraph, you will understand what has happened today
in the world.
The drugs that have been used all along these years have pushed the pathology
towards the central and peripheral nervous system and has created a society
which is sick on a very deep mental emotional level.
This is what he actually says. By constant repetition. He's so careful with his
expression. He says if you repeat frequently a drug, it will definitely make a damage.
You see why it is so difficult that this kind of teaching is difficult to be taught
in a medical school with conventional medical people.
Because you can imagine a teacher going in the class saying if you give antibiotics,
cortisone, chemotherapy you are going to damage the organism.
And the other teacher will come and say in order to save your life
you have to take these drugs. You understand the real problem in diffusing
Homeopathy and being accepted on a bigger scale.
Also from this paragraph you may understand that the idea of giving a remedy
for the totality is not valid anymore for contemporary people, especially those who
have been vaccinated a lot, who have been taking a lot of drugs and who have created
in their organism a complex...
So when they come to the homeopath, he must understand what this vaccination
has done, what was the formation of the problem after this particular drug
that was taken and what happened later on with an acute condition that came
and was treated wrongly and was suppressed etc.
Then you have a complex so complicated and you have to be so careful to treat
the uppermost layer, so the next layer underneath can manifest itself,
give you more information and the 3rd and the 4th remedy...
and then the organism feels relieved.
You see how many times you give a remedy and the patient comes and says
I'm the same. But you take carefully the case and you see some changes
and you see also some new symptoms that have appeared.
For the patient means nothing. You expect after you have given Arsenicum
underneath is a layer of Phosphorus
and you have based your prescription in a few keynotes of Arsenicum.
One keynote of Arsenicum is the thirst, sipping, usually with hot drinks.
They like hot drinks because they feel very cold.
And you have given Arsenicum and he says there's no change, I am the same.
You say what about the thirst, are you still drinking like this?
He says, no I can drink half a cup. This becomes very important for the homeopath.
A little thing like that. And the next question is the water you want must be
in room temperature or it must be cold? Lately I need cold water.
This indicates that the underlying layer of Phosphorus which you expect
is coming up, whether it's completed or not, it will depend further on
the investigation, but these little changes show that your first remedy was correct
in spite of the fact he says I am the same.
He is the same but unless you examine properly the case how can you untangle
such a complicated issue that has become through all the vaccination, the drugs,
the pollution, the recreational drugs that young people are using today, alcohol...
Is the alcohol a drug? No, but the alcohol can produce a case which is alcoholism
which is a disease with specific symptomatology.
Which disease has occupied more the liver.
But this person before alcoholism had hay fever.
And now the hay fever after the vaccination has become from time to time dyspnea
or asthmatic condition.
And due to vaccinations or anything that was affecting his organism,
his kidneys are affected as well.
You see 3 parts, the upper respiratory tract, the liver and the kidneys are affected
in that person and if you investigate you may find exactly what has happened
in the history of the person.
But you have to investigate, with this information in mind.
If you don't have this information, if you don't know how disease is produced
in a human organism, how can you investigate in a chaotic situation?
I have rheumatic pains, I have hay fever, I'm an alcoholic... You're lost.
The problem can be solved like this if you have read the Organon. Of course not.
The Organon is a part of the knowledge. The other part which is equally important
is the knowledge of Materia Medica.
And then the combination of the knowledge of the layers and the knowledge
of the M.M. gives you the possibility to clear up the case.
You may say what you tell us is so difficult, how can we do it?
And that is why we have what we call the repertorisation.
The repertorisation was necessary from almost the very beginning of Homeopathy.
We had computer system through repertorisation and I'm sure Fred will tell you
how repertorisation was done initially with the hand.
I remember one of my first cases when I was in South Africa in 1960 and there was
a nice girl. I liked her. I was flirting and told her to take her case.
It was a big thing to impress her. Then I started repertorising because I had only
Kent's Repertory and with my hand I repertorised the totality.
I could not make out anything. Then I started repertorising, eliminating
repertorisation. I worked so hard and I slept, I could not make out.
On waking in the morning at 6 o'clock without repertorisation, it came to my mind
the remedy is Ignatia.
Because I had made all this work, I had studied the M.M. already quite a lot.
I knew the remedy. She was cured.
But after that she became of no interest to me.
Ignatia is hysterical and very sensitive.
If they come back to the normal, there is no interest.
In paragraph 42 says, "Nature herself permits, as has been stated in some cases,
the simultaneous occurrence of two (indeed, of three) natural diseases
in one and the same body..."
He had already noticed this. This is impressive because most probably
what was happening in his time, it was that he received all cases that were incurable
during that time, so he was receiving all the complicated cases of the time.
During this time where most people were healthy and the organism by itself
whether given a remedy or not they recovered spontaneously.
But those who did not recover could not be cured by any kind of bloodletting,
or the mercury that was given and all these different heavy drugs.
So he was receiving all the complicated cases and that's why he was able to do
this observation.
Nature herself permits in the same body 3 different diseases.
"[...]This complication, however, it must be remarked, happens only in the case
of two dissimilar diseases [...]and cannot cure one another, but, as it seems,
both (or all three) remain, as it were, separate in the organism, and each takes
possession of the parts and systems peculiarly appropriate to it."
In paragraph 43 says, "Totally different, however, is the result when two similar
diseases meet together in the organism, that is to say, when to the disease already
present a stronger similar one is added.
In such cases we see how a cure can be affected by the operations of nature,
and we get a lesson as to how man ought to cure."
This is something that he could have observed only himself.
Today we do not see this because nothing is left to exist in the organism for long
enough, so another disease will come someday which will be similar and cure.
This observation is not in our experience. We don't know it.
But in his time it was happening because they could not suppress immediately
the one or the other disease.
Paragraph 44, "Two diseases similar to each other can neither repel one another,
nor suspend on another, so that the old one shall return after the new one has run
its course..." So he concludes that if there are 2 dissimilar diseases, if they come to the
body, the one will run its course and suppress the other, which is already there and
once this runs its course and it's gone the next one will manifest.
We don't have this experience either in our contemporary cases.
We do not see this because we have such wonderful drugs.
What the wonderful drugs are doing, when things are happening like this...
Somebody has a colitis and he tries to cure it and takes some spasmolytic drugs
and then one day he gets a pneumonia, treated with allopathic drugs and then
because of the suppression of the pneumonia the person develops
an asthmatic condition.
He has now asthma and colitis. What happens for a homeopath who sees such a case?
You search for the remedy and you may see several remedies indicated.
This is a possibility. But there is another possibility.
If the organism is strong, his immune system is in very good condition and
it can happen that both the asthma and the colitis need the same remedy.
So you give the remedy and then the person comes and says my asthma is better,
my colitis is better with one remedy.
That indicates an immune system which is quite strong and also indicates the person
is going to live for many years.
Also indicates that if that person is careful with his organism and does not misuse
his organism by staying awake at night, by drugs, by all the kind of things that we do
today, especially the younger people, we can see later on after a year or two
the underlying layer as well.
That means one remedy has acted beautifully, has relieved both pathologies but
still the organism because it went into this condition it means he had a predisposition.
Can we try to find what was the underlying remedy, which was even beyond the
Calc. Carbonica or beyond Phosphorus or whatever remedy, Arsenicum you gave...?
Is it possible after Calc.Carb. there were small problems that indicated
for instance Sulphur? It is possible but many people they go away
and they will be happy with Calc. and they will never come back.
When later on they will develop some itching in the skin and some little anxiety
and irritability and the itching becomes quite strong and then there is some kind
of eczema, they forget the homeopath and they go to the dermatologist, they take
a cream and they fix it.
This layer, the underlying layer, is the layer on which it was possible to develop
the spastic colitis through stress that the person went through and needed
Nat-m. or Calc. but there was no homeopath to give Nat-m. at the moment
so he remained with the spastic colitis and spasmolytics that he was taking for years.
Then the pneumonia came and it was not treated homeopathically.
It was treated allopathically, so this was suppressed and then the asthma came.
In most of the cases will be complicated. Different remedies needed in order to cure
but even in a case where the remedy that you will give covers both the pathologies
there is the underlying remedy that if it can be found there is no danger of people
having a relapse on the colitis or on the asthma.
If you do not give this underlying remedy, the possibility is always under stress
to have a relapse.
And what will be the relapse? The same sensitivities that he had before,
the colitis is coming back...
But you have to be careful because he will come after 2 years and say that I was well
but now I had a stress, my wife left me. I love my wife and she left me.
And my colitis is back.
Then the most probable is that you look at your notes and you see Calc. has cured and
you give him Calc. Carb. It's not always like that.
It might be that this time because the manifestation of symptoms are not exactly
the same for Calc., now Ignatia is needed first.
The organism has been weakened all these 3-4 years, he needs now the Ignatia
which takes away the sadness, keeps the colitis, the colitis becomes worse and
then comes again the remedy which you have given before, the Calc. Carb.
I understand it is a little bit difficult.
-What if this underlying layer that is the base of all the pathology is not clear to us?
We cannot see the remedy. We just wait...
-Yes wait. The idea of Hahnemann was that they are layers due to 3 basic miasms.
Psoric, syphilitic, sycotic. He considers the psoric miasm, as the deepest and the oldest.
Which is true. Syphilis manifests in the world quite later, while manifestations
on the skin we have from the very old times.
The miasm or the layer which will manifest on the last portion of the treatment of
a person will be of a miasmatic character akin to the psoric miasm.
That's why I said that you may need Sulphur which is underneath but it's not
recognized, it's not given and therefore the relapse will be of the same type
as before, colitis.
You may say a miasm can go away with one remedy Sulph. or whatever?
No, you may need 2 or 3 or 4 remedies before you can eliminate a miasm.
You will see if you treat people for long periods of time...
Usually the homeopaths have such possibilities because the person has been
originally benefited and therefore he comes back to the homeopath and
the homeopath has the possibility to see the different miasmatic predisposition
coming up as the time goes by.
That is why you may see that you have treated a deep pathology
and you have used Med., Thuja, Nat-s. basic sycotic remedies.
And as the symptomatology changes, the person comes with great irritability
and you treat with Nux-v.
After a year you lose the patient, he does not come, he is under stress
and he is depressed.
And you see the depression is of Merc. type and you give Mercury and some
changes are there but still the depression continues and he has suicidal thoughts.
You give Aur., suicidal thoughts are gone, the depression is ameliorated.
After you have treated a person for the sycotic condition, remedies that will come up
would rather belong to the syphilitic miasm. And you may wonder how is that?
I treated him for a pathology and it was quite severe and I helped him.
Now under stress instead of the original pathology coming back
the depression comes. Is that a deeper state?
If that happens it means, no, the original pathology was of a more severe type
than the manifested, later on, depression which needed Merc. and Aur. to be cured.
That means the original pathology would kill the patient.
The life of the patient was in danger. So it was a very severe condition.
Now under stress what is left in the organism is the next layer which is of
a syphilitic origin, it's activated and it brings out symptoms of depression.
You give Mercury, Aurum-Muriaticum, Aurum-Metallicum...
This can happen especially with cases you treat from childhood with
severe problems and the children are really in danger.
When they are 20 they come and they tell you that I don't feel well,
I'm depressed and you investigate and whether the girl has thought of suicide
and she may admit that she has made an attempt to suicide
not in a serious way, not jumping from the Acropolis but...
And then you say why you did that? And you find out that it is because of
love disappointment. The syphilitic layer brings up a psychological condition
that the girl falls in love quite easily and without control.
As a result she has an affair and because of full-blown erotic passion,
the other person gets tired quite easily and after a while he says goodbye.
And then she overcomes this and falls in love again and the same scenery is produced.
The 2d or 3rd time she will commit suicide. She is going to an Aur. state.
Most probably not Aur.-Metalicum but Aur-Muriaticum.
But still this is the syphilitic layer underneath which gives imbalance in that area.
The sycotic layer gives a passion which is much mundane, more physical.
Testosterone is high even in women. And explosions...
You will see in their love affairs they hit, they attack, they make a lot of scenes,
very much aggressive.
When this layer is gone and the syphilitic layer has come up, the physical passion is
reduced and it takes a direction which is not absolutely normal.
When the syphilis layer is manifesting in a person affecting the sexual sphere,
then the desire of the person for having contact, is not going to be the normal contact
between men and women, it twists the instinct and in order to be excited
it needs kinky sex...
In order to be stimulated, when the layer which is manifesting is of a syphilitic
condition, they are not happy, they are not satisfied with normal sex.
They need something different. There comes sadism, masochism, homosexuality...
all the deviations from normal sex.
They are driven towards this direction. They have not a choice.
It's driven to be because of the layer which is affecting the sexual sphere
and there in this area of the sexual sphere...
That when the syphilitic miasm is active.
That finding could be not a partner of the opposite sex. it can be a partner of
the same sex. These tendencies are inside the person. They fight them.
In that inner fight in order to find an outlet to the suffering, they turn to religion
and they find the outlet "unless I get out of this hell" there is an outlet for merging
or contacting the Divine.
If the person is on a syphilitic layer and chooses to have a partner, whether it's of
the opposite sex or even of the same sex, because of being not balanced the person
inside him, what happens is that he projects to this connection his own desires.
That this partner is the best for me, he is absolutely the perfect human being
and that, one day, leads to a tremendous disappointment because they found out
he was not what they thought. Because of the syphilis underneath.
And because they project it with their own imagination. Things do not really exist.
The disappointment is very great and they are lead to suicidal thoughts or suicides.
That is why I was saying that in order to be able the young people at the age of 20 -25
to really fall in love and to enjoy this, they have to be healthy.
Otherwise it is dangerous for a person, who is not balanced in his innermost self
and who is under the influence of sycosis or syphilis, to fall in love really in the way
where you give everything to the other person, you hand over.
In a love affair, when it is full, you hand over your life to somebody else.
If you do that and you are not balanced, you are in for trouble.
What's going to happen? Is your heart going to break down or is your mind going
to break down? Are you going to commit suicide?
It depends on the miasmatic condition on which you are under, which turn will take.
Perhaps you have heard me saying that if somebody had gonorrhea, at the age of 20,
and at the age of 48 there is a heart attack, I have said that this is due to the gonorrhea
because the sycotic miasm affects a lot the heart as an organ
and the weak point is the heart for a person who had gonorrhea.
At that age of 48 he is married, he has children. At 30 he was married.
He has now children that are 14, 15...20.
But due to the excessive sexual desire
that the gonorrhea has produced to this organism he is prone to
fall in love with another woman. Around that age 48, 49, 50, 52.
In such a case the action of the heart becomes full.
They need in order to support the strong passions that have arisen, the heart works
in full speed. That is the time when there is a heart infract and death occurs.
This is the full explanation why people with gonorrhea at the age of 20,
if treated wrongly, it has been suppressed and especially if there is no condylomata
manifesting after the treatment...
If condylomata manifest after the gonorrhea treatment, it's a very good sign.
The heart is spared. But if you keep on suppressing the condylomata and then
the heart will give in. When will it give in?
When it will have to give a full force of blood to the system.
When you see a person whom you desire very much and you have a passion,
the palpitation is tremendous. That is the dangerous moment.
How much important it is that these miasms, the syphilis, the gonorrhea, psoric
are not staying in the body? Which is the system that can help eradicate this miasm?
Only Homeopathy. Which kind of Homeopathy?
Not the Homeopathy where you prescribe 20 drugs or you have crazy ideas,
take this crazy remedy or another.
This is a matter of creating a scientific investigation where you are trying to understand
what has happened right through in the life of a person, what has been created as a
complex within the organism and try in a scientific way to get rid of the layers
one by one. And it is not good either to say "You are syphilitic, take Syphilinum".
No, you take Syphilinum, if Syphilinum symptoms are there.
But unless these symptoms are not there and you take Syphilinum, you damage
yourself actually. Especially if you repeat. Or take Med. Unless Med. You take Thuja...
You have to have the symptoms of the remedy. That's why I'm against of those people
who teach when I have a case I always start with Tuberculinum
because tuberculosis is usual in our society and then a dose of Syphilinum 10M
and then Medorrhinum 10M and the Psorinum 10M.
When I was in America they told me there was someone who was giving these
remedies regularly and he was an Indian guru by the way.
Who would say to a new comer, give him a dose of Tub 10M or several doses
and then if the person still remained alive, then Syph. 10M for a period of time.
To clear up the miasms. The medical doctor who came and told me this because
he was forced by the guru to do this because he was the medical man responsible
in this big affair with this guru.
Then I explained to him and said most probably these are the symptoms that you are
getting now all these people. He says exactly.
They were doing proving of these deep remedies upon all the people and as a result
they had total confusion in the organism.
He brought me cases that I could not make out anything.
-When we have a case like a Med. case. A man who had gonorrhea in his youth and
comes to us in older age with severe heart problems, under heavy allopathic
medication and he is a clearly a Med. Case, what potency can we use of Med.?
-The highest is 200CH, better 30CH.
-Daily?
-If there is a heart problem, first you give one dose. See if there is any reaction and
if there is one and then he is better for 20 days, then next time you may repeat more
times.
-Even daily? Because of the allopathic medication which antidotes the homeopathic
remedy.
-The one dose, if the remedy is correct, will give a result but the result will remain
for 2 weeks. Then you start again and you give every day.
-There is no fear of suppression?
-No, but it depends on what the pathology is.
If the arteries are closed due to arteriosclerosis, then you have to go slowly,
not to produce a big reaction.
-Can we give the remedy less often?
-As long as he takes the allopathic drug.
If you can reduce the allopathic drugs, you may reduce the homeopathic as well.
-If I understand you correctly, you said in syphilis if there are layers of miasms in
the body, then they will be like that syphilis in the very bottom and
if you remove it from the bottom, then sycosis will come up.
A while ago, I think last year you said you know how some homeopaths believe that
tuberculosis is made out of syphilis and psora or syphilis made out of psora
and sycosis and I remember you said this is not true because then if you give
something to treat tuberculosis, then syphilis would come up.
Isn't that what you said?
-Yes, that's correct. I just simply refer to the 3 miasms.
Actually they are not only 3 miasms. The tubercular is a miasm by itself.
-They say for example that tuberculosis is made out of psora...
-No, I cannot say that. I gave the definition of the miasm.
The definition is that you have to have an infecting agent first.
Then you have to have the fact that this infective agent stays within the body
and when he has children, the children get the predisposition to the disease.
This is characteristic of syphilis and gonorrhea and also of tuberculosis.
And then we can call it a separate tubercular miasm. For all practical purposes.
What else can be a kind of a miasm? If there are such sequences.
That means an infective agent that stays within the body and transmits to
the new generation and then this pathology of the new generation is given
the original remedy that caused and cures,
then you may say that this is a miasm.
But you have to have the infection, the possibility to transmit it
that means staying in the genetic predisposition of the person and give it to the
children and the children have to be treated and cured by the original agent.
If that happens which is true, it happens with tuberculosis
then we can say we have another tubercular miasm.
But I don't know which other pathology we may consider as a miasmatic condition.
-Before you said that the case of the colitis and the asthma, if it returns because
his wife left him and colitis reappeared, we have not to give Calc. but Ign.
This is because of an acute disease.
-Exactly. On chronic state there is an acute, you have to treat first this and
then the chronic.
-And then the layer of primary psora.
-Which country you come from?
-Italy. I have another question. You say that it's not a choice to have a partner.
-It's a compulsion. It is like a compulsive tendency that cannot be resisted
when the syphilitic action is there and the person is under this and affecting
the sexual sphere, it's a compulsion. They need to do it in this way.
-But we can say that for all mental symptoms? That is not a choice?
-Yes, sure.
-So irritability it's not a choice.
-Irritability is not a choice, angriness is not a choice.
It's something that leads you to hit the other person...It's a hormonal mixture.
-It's like an automatic response.
-Yes. Also our social behavior is a matter of hormones, a matter of miasms.
-I have maybe a strange question but I want to see your way of thinking.
I very much agree with the idea that if you have a syphilitic background, it will be
this kind of distorted sexual attractions, homosexuality...
On the other hand we agree with the idea that animals and especially
the wild animals are healthy. They select by nature...
I've seen several times in movies with biology subject homosexual tendencies
in animals like frogs, deers... How could you explain this?
-There are different ways to explain. I don't know if you know this experiment
with pesticides that was affecting the behavior of animals becoming homosexual.
No pollution, yes I'll go to that.
Because what happens today, let's say the perversion or the sexual preference,
it is exploding. Everybody knows that this is a phenomenon that is absolutely
diffused all over, especially the civilized societies.
Why these civilized societies? What is the difference between the civilized society
having such a percentage and the primitive societies they have very little percentage?
What is the difference? It's in the fact that we have damaged ourselves quite deeply
on that level, especially the reproductive area.
Now why they found such animals also to have this? This is a possibility.
That's why when the organism is disturbed by a miasm, then it can take this way.
There is a possibility in the nature of living beings to be.
The more civilized, the more the tendency. What is the tendency?
From a spiritual point of view, it is the tendency of the humans to get away from
this incompleteness with which we come to this world. We need the opposite.
So what you may be asking is a society in which we will not have
this problem of being incomplete. What could be? A society where the 2 sexes
would be equally active in the human organism.
So spiritually the tendency is to feel complete in yourself.
Is there anybody that does not want to hear? ...  what can I do?
We have to decide whether we talk about these issues as a matter of information
within a group of specialists, as homeopaths, or we hide and we bypass this issue.
And the issue is whether what I say is correct or not.
If it is correct, maybe accept it. If it is not correct, then reject it.
You may have the possibility to disagree with what I say.
This is not correct for these reasons.
I understand that this may be a sensitive issue but giving at the same time
the information and the explanation of what is happening.
Perhaps you did not understand that what I said is that this tendency of
a human being having inside both sexes is a spiritual state that may reach humanity
in 2000 years.
And goes through that state at this moment which is not really the best state but
the tendency is that the human being must free himself from suffering.
And the suffering is because we are not complete.
We need something to complete us. For a man it can be a woman or for a man
can be another friend or for a woman it can be another woman...
But this is the need and I say that in this need you are going to have some problems.
When the other person, whom you trusted so much will tell you bye-bye,
I don't agree with you.
That means you have projected in the other person qualities that there are not
there. You are going to treat patients and you must understand
what you are treating and why there is a blockage...
Unless this is clear, how can you find out and help?
If somebody is over-sexed, especially a woman, she is in tremendous need for
sexual contact, nymphomaniac, can I speak about nymphomaniacs?
Why not? If a woman is driven by her hormonal imbalance in that state,
you are going to help her by giving a remedy that will reduce her sexual pleasure.
You get a woman who needs Platina, she comes there for headaches she does not
tell you about her sexuality.
You did not ask, you did not know. You give Plat. and when she comes she says
what have you done? My pleasure is gone. I don't need so much sexual activity
anymore. Ok what do you want? You want your sexual activity and your headaches
or you want a better balance with no headaches and less sexual activity?
I had such a case. She said does your remedy have to do with the reduction?
I said no. This woman she called me about a month ago and she said
can you please give me the remedy you gave me for the headaches?
I was feeling so well. But it had reduced her sexual activity to the extent that
she complained the next time she came here. She is in my age.
She says give me this because I have the anxiety. She says I have taken the remedy
several times but the last time I took it, it didn't work.
I asked what potency you took? Take a higher potency now. You cannot avoid that.
You cannot say Ok I like it and I don't want to lose this pleasure...
You are going to bring about balance to the organism as a whole.
If this is not accepted, then this is not the fault of the homeopath.
-If we say that mental and physical symptoms are automatic response
to external information, can we say that psychosomatic medicine cannot exist?
-No, wait a moment. Psychosomatic medicine, I don't know exactly what you mean.
But the fact that a psychological state can be transmitted into the physical body
this is a fact. If you say psychosomatic medicine is this kind of treatment,
I don't know what you mean.
-I mean that mental symptoms can cause physical symptoms.
-Yes mental symptoms can be transformed into physical symptoms. It is fact 100%.
I thought it was a kind of treatment you mean.
But whatever treatment, if a mental symptom is transferred to the physical body
is a correct treatment. And vice versa.
If you treat the physical and goes to the mental, this is not correct treatment.
So psychosomatic idea of medicine is correct.
Treating is correct when it has the right direction. From deeper to more outer.