She has found the question that we had concerning caffeine from coffee and
caffeine from tea. Why the one is very active and the other is not?
She went to the Internet where she found the answer. The answer is...
-... that caffeine is like adenosine that bring the induction in producing adrenalin
and not adrenaline and so it excites the nervous system.
The caffeine in tea it happens that if we infuse the tea in the water for 2 min.,
we make the extraction of caffeine and so tea is an excitant.
Instead if we infuse the tea in the water for 3 or 5 min., we extract also
tannin combined with caffeine that inhibits the action of caffeine.
So tea infused for 3-5 min. or more is not that excitant like coffee.
-Thank you. That was a big question for me, I did not know the answer.
Because many times people will say tea has also caffeine... I say I don't know.
But it does not act. I thought it was the process of preparation because we fry
the coffee grounds and I thought maybe that activated the caffeine to the extent
to be much more active.
But what she found out is the absolute answer to the problem.
If you take out within 2 minutes, the tea can be dangerous.
That means the tea will have extracted only the caffeine.
If you take it out there is no tannin coming out later on and the tea stays
with caffeine. That means within 2 minutes if you take it out the caffeine is active.
When you leave it for 3-5 min., tannin is binding with caffeine and neutralizes
the effect of the caffeine. She found this on the Internet. An Italian study.
By a homeopath? No. It's a very good explanation. I can use it.
Everybody has this Boericke translation and I have a different translation and since
we are having a problem... Do you find it difficult to attend? Let me see.
Paragraph 78, "The true natural chronic diseases are those that arise from a chronic
miasm, which when left to themselves, and unchecked (not treated) by the
employment of those remedies that are specific for them, always go on increasing
and growing worse..." A chronic disease always when is left without treatment
becomes worse and worse.
"not withstanding the best mental and corporeal regimen" without being affected by
the best mode of life, mental or physical.
"and torment the patient to the end of his life with ever aggravated sufferings
[...]for the most robust constitution, the best regulated mode of living and the most
vigorous energy of the vital force are insufficient for their eradication."
What he says is that even if the organism is in a good condition, that means in the
Level 1, once the chronic disease has started will continue till the end of the life
undermining and degenerating constantly the organism.
Paragraph 79, "Hitherto syphilis alone has been to some extent known as such a
chronic, miasmatic disease, which when uncured ceases only with the termination
of life."
My brain jumps...Syphilis when untreated will continue until it kills the patient.
"Sycosis (the condylomatous disease), equally ineradicable by the vital force without
proper medicinal treatment, was not recognized as a chronic miasmatic disease of a
peculiar character, which it nevertheless undoubtedly is, and physicians imagined they
had cured it when they had destroyed the growths upon the skin..."
Likewise sycosis is such a disease that can be chronic, it cannot be cured and wrongly
the doctors thought that if they eradicated, suppressed, cauterized the condylomata,
which sycosis has a secondary stage, they thought they had cured the disease.
This was not true, which is correct.
Paragraph 80, "Incalculably greater and more important than the two chronic miasms
just named, however, is the chronic miasm of psora" like the 2 other miasms there is
another miasm which is equally important,
"which, while those two reveal their specific internal dyscrasia, the one by the
venereal chancre, the other by the cauliflower-like growths, does also, after
the completion of the internal infection of the whole organism, announce by a
peculiar cutaneous eruption, sometimes consisting only of a few vesicles
accompanied by intolerable voluptuous tickling itching (and a peculiar odor)..."
in the same way that syphilis can manifest with the chancre and sycosis can manifest
with the condylomata, psora can manifest with a skin eruption and even if the skin
eruption is very mild, it's only a little bit of itching and a few vesicles.
"the psora, the only real fundamental cause and producer of all the other numerous.."
So he considers the psoric miasm as the basis of the other 2.
That means that if the humanity had not been affected by the psoric miasm,
which was the first, then we may have not been able to be infected by syphilis or
sycosis. The psoric miasm is the basic miasm, he considered it as the most difficult
to eradicate and he considers it the basis of all diseases.
Here comes a great philosophical problem which is why humans are prone
to diseases. Why do we have to fall ill in the first place?
Couldn't we live a certain period of time without diseases? It would be nice.
The question arises, if psoric miasm is the basis of syphilis and gonorrhea,
what is the basis of the psoric miasm? What is behind the psoric miasm?
What happened and humans became prone to skin diseases in general?
Something must have happened.
You feel hot? Who feels hot? Who does not feel hot?
I thought I need a dose of Puls.
The question what brought about the original psoric miasm is a question that cannot
be answered in a scientific way.
It can be answered only as a projection of an idea and a possibility but never no one
is going to prove that the original people were doing this or that in order
to have such a fate. But still I will give you a few ideas to think about it.
Take for instance, I am sure you have seen a lot of documentaries with primitive
people, like the Amazonian people, very primitive living in groups in the bushes.
We have to imagine that humanity has started from this primitive state and we are
the end result of a process of health and disease and here we are and we take an
account of what we have managed to be.
If you ask a basic question, are we happier than those poor people in the Amazon?
The answer may be not in our favor.
I have seen that the primitive people are much more vital, happy, joyful than we are.
This is one fact. There is another fact.
We have a tremendous range of diseases, what we call chronic diseases,
complicated problems. These people, they don't have.
There is another fact also that we live longer, our span of life is longer than the
primitive people. Their average life is 45, our average life is 75.
It's not correct? Do you know the statistics? You don't know...
Nobody can hear you. Not even myself.
-Hunter gatherers which is the proper name for the people, not "primitive",
when we were hunter gatherers whoever is in that stage right now, they live
long lives, some of them they die from infections of course, because we do know
that some of the people they live for a very long time, they have elders who are in
their 80s and 90s...
-I don't mean to say that there is nobody from these people who do not live up
to 80 or 90. I mean to say that the average span of life...
-That's a myth.
-This is not correct what I say? The average span of life of primitive people is between
40 and 50 years. They die because of acute diseases and epidemics, snake bites...
so definitely our average span of life is longer than the primitive people's.
These are the facts.
There are no facts but there is a myth; which is the myth?
People who live beyond the age of the primitive people, the myth says it was a couple
Adam and Eve who lived in a paradise.
And the myth says that these people were very happy living in the paradise.
They were happy under one condition that they will not eat a fruit from the tree
of knowledge.
These people were not supposed to eat from a tree that will give them
knowledge, because knowledge will take them from paradise to hell.
This is something strange to think, how come knowledge can take you from the
paradise to hell?
What is this knowledge, the first knowledge that they became aware of?
They did not know up to a certain time and suddenly they became aware of
a knowledge. They became aware that they were naked.
-They became aware that they were naked after they've tasted it.
-She's correct in a way... She doesn't say the whole thing.
They became aware of their difference in the sex.
They became aware that I am a man and she is a woman.
Before, this knowledge was not there. That means not that they could not see,
of course they could see, but suddenly they realized that I am not a complete human
being, in order to continue to exist I need another part which is the other sex.
And that knowledge brought about a sense of shame.
So they cover their genitals because this awareness of the difference between sexes
brings about the first sense of shame.
So they have eaten from the tree of knowledge, that means from now on they are
going to investigate and to make research, double-blind research...
they are going to investigate in order to find out why is this and why is that and
then the snake comes and gives the apple to Eve and says if you eat this you will
know quite a lot.
If you put all these together, you have to come to a conclusion that
the original knowledge feeling the separateness of the human being, who is not
anymore connected to cosmos, because before they were living in paradise.
Paradise is not only what you see, the trees... you can put any depressed person
in the best environment, he will not change, the paradise is inside, is a feeling of
connectedness. I do not need anything, I am complete.
But I am complete, I'm innocent, I'm near the state of animal.
Animals they don't separate sexes. They are not shy to have sex in front of you.
But can't we have sex in front of everybody? It's impossible to think it because
there is a sense of I am doing something wrong.
So from the moment they start thinking in this way,
there is automatically in their mental/ emotional make-up a seismic impact.
So the origins of what was going to come later on as a kind of internal disturbance
with an external manifestation of diseases, it must have started on the mental
emotional sphere, with the idea of men being incomplete and not anymore
one with the Divine, one with Cosmos.
If you see now the history of diseases, you will see that most of the diseases in
the ancient times are diseases manifesting in the skin with a prevalence of leprosy.
Leprosy was the prevalent and the worst skin eruption.
We may have to understand that the basis of the psoric miasm is this knowledge
that we are alone and we are not protected and we are not safe anymore.
And these feelings eventually will create an internal imbalance which will manifest
as a psoric miasm upon which different other infectious diseases will come and grow.
-I thought the feeling of being isolated is a syphilitic miasm.
Isn't it a syphilitic miasm and not a psoric? The feeling of being isolated...
Is it of syphilis or psora?
-No. This has nothing to do. Even if you go through the Repertory and you see
"abandoned"...
I'll show you something since you talk about this isolation, rejected, forsaken.
If you go and see "forsaken", the feeling of isolation, which remedy you seek there?
You see Psorinum, Pulsatilla is also a psoric remedy.
What you are saying is not correct in this manner, that symptoms, as other miasms
are complicated, are similar and the difference is that the symptom is more or less
the same but much deeper.
If there are 3 miasms complicated, you may have a symptom which appears in syphilis,
sycosis or psora. The difference will be that this symptom will be much more deep
and difficult to treat. If the person is psoric it will be easier to treat.
If the person has had syphilis, gonorrhea coming along in his ancestry, not that he
himself must get syphilis or gonorrhea, then the symptom will be much more difficult
to cure. But the symptoms can be similar.
I just showed you the feeling these people have, forsaken feeling, I am alone,
my mother left, my mother rejected me, the idea of rejection, the people
who were rejected from paradise.
I have never spoken about these things because they are theoretical, but since we
are speaking about theory, it's good that you may meditate upon these ideas.
-May I ask something about the problem that you have said before
about the lack of connectedness, the lack of being connected.
Have you seen from your experience that people who have cancer,
mainly women with cancer in the sexual organs, have this feeling?
Because I have 4 cases of young women around their 30s and 40s with cancer of
uterus, cancer of breast with metastasis, another cancer of breast with metastasis,
and pre-cancer condition in the uterus CIN 3.
4 of them have this problem, complete lack of connectedness with the other sex
and other people. Is it accidental?
Because according to my poor experience it is not an accident.
-These feelings of being isolated, being disconnected, abandoned, separated
these feelings are of deep, negative effect upon the organism.
Whether they will end up in a malignancy, I do not know but definitely they will
end up in some kind of severe chronic condition.
Couples that they love each other for many years and the one relies upon the other,
the feeling of security is there. I have somebody who cares about me,
I have somebody whom I can trust and can turn to him in case of trouble.
These couples live much happier and longer.
Such couples are very rare to find in our western societies.
Most of the people after the first enthusiasm within 2-3 years they become like
strangers. And then naturally the person will look for something to replace what
was there before, so they have another partner and another partner...
These people can have 3-4 marriages but they can never be really happy.
They can be happy for very short period of time.
But the couple that stay together for a long period of time 50 years,
they are living longer than those who separate and they try to find another partner
and another... The big secret for staying together is that
especially the woman must not have multiple sexual experiences, multiple partners.
Many years ago the idea was that if you don't really enjoy life as a young person and
you don't have a good time and then once you have the experience,
then you get married and you stay with a partner. Forget it, it will be the opposite.
You cannot stay with the partner, you will divorce, whether physically or essentially.
You may stay together but you are separated, it's my enemy, I stay because of my
obligations, I have children... I have nothing to do, not even sex nothing.
They live together in the same house. This is not what I mean separation.
Separation will come if the woman has multiple experiences. Men also...
I'll talk about men as well.
What I want to say is this that in my experience couples especially in countries
where the social conditions do not permit man and woman coming together before
the marriage, there the marriages last.
In countries where there is freedom in expressing the sexuality from the young age...
In America if the girl is 14 and she had not have sexual experience, the parents think
the girl is sick. They think something is wrong. I was asked to treat.
"Our daughter stays in the house, does not go out with boys..."
When I speak to the daughter she was perfectly sane, she said I don't have the urge
to go with a boy. How can I go with a boy, because my mother wants me to?
I don't feel like going with a boy. If I fall in love with somebody, I will do it.
That, which was the healthiest response, for the American culture was sickness.
The fact remains therefore that if there are no multiple experiences of a woman
before marriage, then the marriage will last. They don't separate.
Especially when the man falls in love with a woman and marries that woman,
this couple will remain forever without any problem.
They don't dare going out of that connection. That happens today less and less...
Because the experience we have is such that does not allow us to trust each other.
Not only trust but feel, especially on the part of the woman, because a woman she's
27, she has not been with a man...
The society makes her feel that something is wrong with her but the woman is not
mature enough to go with a man. And the woman has to be very strong in character,
facing the society which says, "Didn't you marry yet? -No, I did not marry - Why?
-I dind't find the right man. If I find the right man I will marry".
That simple answer is never given.
This kind of couples will stay together but it is very seldom today that they find
the right person, the right man or woman.
-Just to see your way of thinking. If Adam and Eve originally were complete
why they were still created to be different? Why this difference was needed
if they had the same internal state? God had foreseen that this will happen...?
-This is going even deeper in the investigation.
-We want to see your thinking.
-There are theories after that, the role of humans etc. but I don't want to go into that.
I want to give you facts. Except of the myth of Adam and Eve but this story was
written by somebody. Somebody thought about it and wrote it down.
Somebody who has written this most probably understood in depth the problem
of the humans and he has given some information many years ago.
5000 years ago, he has devised this story.
From there on whatever information we have we use and we try to understand.
What is our place in the Cosmos, why we came?
And you will see if you take this fact, they were in the paradise connected...
and then you see the evolution of the humans, as we come today to understand
who we are, that still today the most of the educated western people are looking
for happiness and to be back in paradise.
How? Either by a perfect relationship, if possible, between a man and a woman or
a perfect relationship with the Cosmos. If they can enter again the original state
that was the paradise state but now WITH the knowledge of what is good and
what is bad and better don't do this.
The original people did not know why, they had no knowledge.
If we have the knowledge, that in order to find again the paradise, we have to follow
certain patterns that will lead us there, then we will be in paradise WITH knowledge.
Then we cannot fall back into that hell.
Actually the society we created is a society of hell.
Coming back from the original to the end with knowledge.
People that have knowledge, joy, bliss, the feeling inside them that they are
connected to something much bigger that nothing can separate them again.
I have to do this and that... In the future societies will be totally different than
they are today. There will be societies with totally different attitudes.
Once the societies have understood the real meaning of sexual play and
understanding and how this should be coupled with the feelings of connectedness,
if they understand this, they will never allow in a society somebody to have sex at
the age of 14-19 but it will be more after the 20th.
And until that time the society will be giving to the young people all the facilities
to feel happy and to be creative and to be working for others in the fields
or in the industries or in producing.
Once this young generation comes of age, if they have not played around with a lot
of partners, they will be able to recognize who is the real partner and then they will
be immediately connected and feel happy in that connection.
There will be a totally different society than the one we have created.
-The problem of lack of connectedness that some people have leads to certain
pathology. This lack of this emotion can be cured by homeopathic medicine?
Because it is something that comes very early in the life of the individual.
Can it be reversed?
-I will tell you. What happens is that in a family you have mother,
father and children.
The moment that these parents realize their role in how they should raise their
children, what they need, they need to feel secure, love and at the same time to
be independent.
If the parents give this kind of upbringing to the child, this feeling of
disconnectedness will be minimized.
If the parents give the sensation to the child that is not wanted, it's a burden to them,
I have also to stay in because I needed to go to the cinema, theater and I have you...
If they just say it once, the child will perceive and will start the anxiety about the
feeling of rejection and of disconnectedness, as they grow up they cannot anymore
feel the trust.
If the parents treat a child like that, the child will go out to find another mother,
sister or brother, very early.
Whom they find? The first person who is nice to them "I like your eyes..." or
"You are beautiful" etc. They go to sleep together and they have sex.
Just the boy says you are beautiful and I like you and they go and have sex.
That is the state of the society in which we are in.
What is promoted is, at least in America, which is the paradigm of the world,
you are 12-13 get out of the house and live by yourself.
If somebody feels so unprotected in the society, will try to survive and he will do
things that are not according to his conscience.
So he will do things that will bring more and more the possibility and
the predisposition for chronic conditions.
Children today go out and take drugs because they are unhappy, they take a drug,
makes them happy for a while and more drugs until they die.
You know how many deaths there are because of drugs?
This comes from a society which is unjust, unfair, which looks only for material gains,
looks only for money, money has become the god, but money separates people
between rich and poor.
And the more the difference, the more this separation, the more the anxiety,
the more the insecurity.
Today in Greece in the last 2 years we had 3000 suicides because of financial
reasons. They cannot pay their debts. They shoot themselves,
they jump from high places.
Because the society says do you have money? Yes. You are somebody.
You don't have money? You are nothing.
They push us to that state believing that globalization is a nice thing
where everybody will be happy. Nobody will be happy.
Even the rich will not be happy because they have too much and the poor will not
be happy because they have too little.
These are the facts and they cannot see it unfortunately.
Homeopathy cannot do anything.
Hahnemann went as far as the basic miasm. Psoric.
I will tell you something that you can remember.
The feeling of anxiety actually is the same symptom as in the physical body the itch.
If you have itching, it does not leave you alone, you have to scratch.
You go to bed, you sleep for a while 2 hours, you wake up and then you scratch
and you become despaired.
If you push this inside, it will bring up an anxiety that will come the same hours
that the itching was coming.
If you were scratching 1-3 a.m., the anxiety will wake up in the night without any
reason. It is like somebody is scratching your soul. There is no peace.
There is inside something which they cannot explain what it is.
Nobody can explain this. Then we have the development of psychotherapies,
they try to explain.
They say when you were young, you hide this and that and you're rejected but I will
tell you. Suppressed skin eruption especially an eczema or an eruption that has
a lot of itch and you need to scratch, this person will develop anxiety of the
worst type. Not depression. It is the same thing.
What is the reason for anxiety? He has suppressed the eruption, he goes to the
psychotherapist because he cannot live anymore.
He has this anxiety and he tries to find out deep causes of what happened in the
young age... most of the time... Helen don't overdo it. Wait.
The psychotherapists instead of understanding that the anxiety is only the result
of a suppression of a skin eruption, he goes for psychotherapy 4-10 years.
He comes to you and you give Staph. the itching comes back and the anxiety is gone.
He says I have been doing 10 years of psychotherapy and nothing happened.
You gave me 1 dose of Sulph. and now the anxiety is gone!
The skin eruption comes back. Helen, speak out loudly.
-OK, say the eruption was suppressed and asthma appeared.
Will that person still have anxiety or asthma will take care of that,
the suppressed itch?
-No, the itch will not always create anxiety. The itch can go to the lungs and create
a dyspnea which will come more or less at the time of the itch.
If the itch was coming when you go to bed or you sleep 2 hours and then the itch
wakes you up, the asthma will come between 2-4 the time that the original itch
is created.
The young children of older times like 50-100 years ago,
the most diffused skin eruption was the scabies.
This is what the scabies are cause of the psoric miasm according to Hahnemann.
Who knows what scabies are? We can communicate.
Hahnemann in paragraph 80 continues to say that "I may say innumerable forms of
disease, which, under the names of nervous debility, hysteria, hypochondriasis,
mania, melancholia, imbecility, madness, epilepsy and convulsions of all sorts,
softening of the bones (rachitis), scoliosis and kyphosis, caries, cancer, fungus
nematodes, neoplasms, gout, hemorrhoids, jaundice, cyanosis, dropsy,
amenorrhea..." he mentions all kinds of diseases.
"defects of the senses and pains of thousands of kinds, etc., figure in systematic
works on pathology as peculiar, independent diseases."
So he says all these diseases are originating from the psoric miasm.
Here are a lot of questions. Why since we have one basis, psoric miasm,
why we have so many differentiations in diseases?
Why not all of us have the same diseases, if we have the same basis?
What differentiates one person to get a disease of the nervous system and another
to get a disease of the lungs and another one to get a disease of the kidneys?
Come here.
-I have a question. What do you think about the note of the paragraph 80?
-In these paragraphs, in this 6th edition, there are some editions especially
in the notes which I'm not sure they are originally from Hahnemann.
Most probably Melanie has put her hand to that as well. Cherchez la femme!
"I spent twelve years in investigating the source of this incredibly large number
of chronic affections, in ascertaining and collecting certain proofs of this great
truth, which had remained unknown to all former or contemporary observers,
and in discovering at the same time the principal (antipsoric) remedies,
which collectively are nearly a match for this thousand-headed monster."
You have a question on that? Question for that?
-Yes, what do you think about the anti-psoric drugs?
-What he means here is that he observed that he treated this kind of diseases
he mentioned with a bunch of remedies.
For instance he noticed that I treated asthma with this and that remedy, put it
together, then I treated the other disease with this and that remedy, put it
together. Finally he put together a bunch of remedies which he called
anti-psoric, because according to him these remedies have cured the psoric
manifestations of the patient. That's the one.
It is not like he says give an antipsoric. He says select from these remedies
the right one for the case and maybe you will be able to cure.
There is another question? You have noticed a little bit further?
"the true physician can now select for his curative agents those whose medicinal
symptoms correspond in the most similar manner to the chronic disease he has to
cure; and thus, by the employment of medicines more suitable for this miasm,
he is enabled to render more essential service and almost invariably to effect
a perfect cure." I will read the whole paragraph...
"How much greater cause is there now for rejoicing that the desired goal has been
so much more nearly attained, in as much as the recently discovered and far more
specific homoeopathic remedies for chronic affections arising from psora and the
special instructions for their preparation and employment have been published;
and from among them the true physician can now select for his curative agents
those whose medicinal symptoms correspond in the most similar manner to the
chronic disease he has to cure."
What he says is that now I have discovered that the main problems
which I mention "chronic diseases" these could be cured with this bunch of
remedies which I have prepared and I have also potentized and they are ready
for the doctors to use and they must rejoice that there is a way of treating
chronic cases. Take your Organon.
-Can we go back to the question you were just about to answer before we divert it.
You were just about to answer why we have so many differentiations in diseases.
The one person gets one in the nervous system, the other lung disease, the other
kidney... Could you please answer that? You were interrupted.
-I put the question, not the answer. I said naturally I have to ask you this!
Otherwise you will accept something on the face of what I say...
Since the basis is the same why such differentiations?
All the systems are affected in different people with different way and in a different
intensity. Why is that? It is a question. Not the answer.
The answer... I don't know.
You can think and you can tell me.
But the predisposition is exactly, he says, the psoric miasm.
It's the predisposition that brings out the disease. Therefore what happens there?
Thank you. I look nice... What is your question?
-Many times as you said when we give the right remedy a skin eruption comes up
but this skin eruption, the aggravation can be really strong, the skin cracks, it starts
oozing and the patient becomes very much liable to staphylococcal infection,
how long do we wait for...
-For as long as you withstand all this turmoil? That is a big question.
The thing is that when the manifestation of the skin eruption becomes worse and
worse, the symptoms become more and more clear.
So there is a time when the organism will give a picture for the next remedy.
It needs another remedy of course but it has to be the correct one.
It's better to wait as long as you can see now I have 2-3 keynotes of a remedy and
I have a general condition as well, then I give this remedy and then the skin eruption
will disappear within...
I remember a case in Celle, who was in Celle? You were in Celle!
There was a case of a skin eruption and I waited until I was sure about the remedy.
So the patient came in Celle in Germany, I took the case, the remedy was Pulsatilla
and I said to the class the itching will stop tonight. For months she was scratching.
2 days later I said to the doctor in attendance to call the patient and to report to the
class. She said the itching stopped immediately after the remedy.
But you have to wait. Do you remember this case? No.
It was a small boy if I remember well with neurodermatitis.
-If in a case like she mentions, the skin eruption comes after the remedy,
if the patient is in a better level of health will it become like an infection...?
-It can have an infection. It can be quite severe infection because the cracks are
deep and especially the women deal with things in kitchen where they put their
hands into different... I remember a case she came she had asthma, I've given
the remedy, then there was a tremendous eczema with cracks, said ok, placebo,
wait, and then one time she comes with fever 39 C.
The whole arm was swollen and red, she was going for septicemia, I had several
doctors working in different places, I took her to the kitchen because all the other
rooms were filled with patients, I took her, I asked 2 questions and I gave
Sulphur 50M. Goodbye. I remember it was Friday night.
And I go home in the night and as I recall all the cases and I recalled the case
and I said to myself what have you done?
This case if the remedy does not act, she will go to septicemia and most probably
until Monday she will die. Especially if she believes the remedy is correct and
the remedy is not correct... I couldn't sleep. I turned around and Sunday comes
and I can't sleep. I was exhausted.
I went on Monday to the Center and there she comes suddenly.
She says look the eczema was almost gone in 3 days.
The redness and the swelling was gone. I said Thank God!
I prayed 2 days for her not to die. You understand in a situation where we have
a government that was dictatorship, police was the absolute governor.
If they had accused me, they would put me forever...
Genius, you don't like this situation... 50M, one dose cured the case.
I remember this case and I know when I see this, get away from anything that
can infect your hands because it can be quite deep, the infection. Thank you.