Before I start going further I would
like to hear any kind of questions
that you may have, something you did
not understand, so we can go ahead.
-I have several questions regarding the
remedy. One has to do with coffee nullifying
the remedy I'll go with that first and then
I want to ask about tea and other things
that antidote the remedy... For the coffee you
said she took Nat-m. yesterday in the case...
-The case of the journalist. Yes, she used to take
10 coffees a day in order to continue her work.
-She said if the
coffee will antidote...
-These people, if they continue drinking
coffee, it is not possible to work.
You can forget about it. So she attributed the
amelioration of stopping drinking coffee.
That is why I said if you now drink coffee,
then it will antidote the remedy I have given
you and then you will come back to
the exhausting state you were before
where you had to drink 10 coffees a day in order
to perform your work to which she did not agree.
It would be interesting. I know what was
going to happen because I have seen it
with a lot of patients. The moment
that a patient comes and has a problem
he will stop drinking coffee. He takes
the remedy and he becomes well.
So he feels now I am well I can drink
coffee. And the moment they start drinking
coffee, they come back and I asked her
because the remedy has acted very well.
So I said what happened and you
relapsed in 6 months or earlier.
Did you drink coffee?
They said yes.
Then I give again and again they drink
coffee and then they relapse again.
Perhaps the 3rd time they stop. And
then I see they remain well after that.
This is one circumstance in which I realize
the coffee antidotes the treatment.
There is no question about that.
There is another possibility where after
several relapses because of drinking coffee
and after the person was swearing to me the
last time he will never drink coffee again
because he was relative and I said I will not
give you any more if you keep on drinking coffee.
So finally I gave him the last time
and 2 or 3 years later he called me
for something else and he said I have
been drinking coffee the last year and
I had no relapse of
the original case.
It was a severe sinusitis
ready to go for operation.
So Kali-b. stopped that
entirely and he was quite well.
After a few months he started drinking
coffee. 6 months later back the sinusitis.
The 3rd time I told him if you keep on
drinking coffee, I will not give you a remedy anymore.
After the 3rd
time he remained well.
A year later he tried drinking coffee
again and it was not a relapse.
But when he called me, maybe 4-5 years
later, he called me because he had
a urinary difficulty...so I said do you also
have vertigo? He says how do you know
I can't believe that you know I
have vertigo, yes I have vertigo!
Take a dose of Conium and for years now,
he is in my age, he is not bothering me.
So you know very well what
happens with drinking coffee.
Drinking coffee sooner or later
will antidote the treatment.
There are some teachers who say
you can drink coffee, no problem.
I said to these teachers have you
ever given the right remedy?
Because if you give wrong
remedies, there is no problem.
You can take coffee or whatever you like.
The condition will remain the same more or less.
If you have given a remedy which
affects a little portion of the disease
then drinking coffee will have no
difference. They will remain the same.
But if you bring back the whole balance
in the organism, the organism becomes
sensitive to any kind of chemical drug.
And caffeine is a chemical drug
which stimulates the nervous system and the
continuous stimulation will definitely
bring about a relapse.
This is a fact.
George says don't drink coffee, no with
my treatment you can drink coffee.
How is that possible? She had another question
I think, just wait. Tell me the second.
-Tea and chocolate they also...
-Tea also has an amount of
caffeine, as everybody knows.
I don't know why the caffeine in the
tea is not as effective in stimulating
the nervous system as the coffee which
is burned out, which is prepared.
Coffee grounds which have been fried. How
the frying had activated the caffeine
quality in the coffee, I don't know.
What I know is that if you drink coffee
with caffeine, you will have a relapse
if you have the correct remedy.
With no correct remedy it doesn't
matter you can drink whatever you like.
-Does decaffeinated coffee antidote?
It is Ok to take decaf?
-Perhaps it will antidote a few cases
that have sensitivity to the tea.
There are some patients they say if I
drink half a cup of tea I have tremendous
palpitations. These patients you
have to stop them from drinking tea.
Whatever is the chemical that may be
using and have an effect on the organism
and they know it, you
have to stop it.
If some person says I am very sensitive to
vinegar. If I drink vinegar I am destroyed.
You have to stop it. Even simple substances
are causing a tremendous reaction
to the organism, you must stop it because
you give the remedy, the organism tries
to bring balance. This takes time.
Takes from a few days to a few months.
In this period of time the organism works
in order to bring about a total balance.
In this process you enter with a stimulant
which is sensitive to the organism
and it is antagonistic.
The one goes towards one direction for
cure and the other goes to the opposite
direction destroying
the organism.
That is why you have to stop all irritants
that may affect the human organism.
-There was this journalist she was
drinking 10 cups of coffee every day and
I observed that people drinking 2 lt of
coffee a day, when they just take it away
they get a lot symptoms
like headaches.
Sometimes I wait before I give the remedy
till these symptoms are less or gone.
But you gave Nat-m. You gave
the remedy for 20 days?
-I told her to take a little bit. Here
you have to understand my problem.
She is a scientist, she has come from a
very serious scientific magazine and
I don't want to have problems. She
says let me have an experiment.
But if I give an experiment and cause a
problem to her, she will come out publicly
and say these people are killing people.
She comes out and says I have now suicidal
depression so he caused me a trouble.
He knew he could cause me trouble,
I did not know and he still
agreed to give me the remedy.
I was taking a chance by giving Nat-m.
Because she could accuse me for having
a lot of symptoms if I was not
exact and it was a close remedy.
If the remedy was not close there was
no problem, would have no effect.
But if it was not close? So I wrote
you would have some headaches etc.
but I did not write you may have suicidal
disposition which she might had.
I did not know because I did not take her
case. Because she says I don't want to
be treated. I want to see whether when
you say there is proving of the remedy
if this remedy will give me the
symptoms that you are recording.
This is what I want to see.
You see how difficult it was.
You have to understand also one thing
that when you talk on these levels
people do not accept nonsense. If you
talk nonsense they will say go to hell...
And it's on my shoulders to try to
prevent what bad things can happen
for Homeopathy and
to save this system.
In 1960 when I came into the scenery
when I tried to investigate I saw only
French Homeopathy. And it was a bottle
with 20 remedies for different pathologies
and people who would prescribe 10, 15,
20 remedies... That was all that existed
and Homeopathy had a very bad
position in the whole world.
Then I started fighting
and people fought back.
Even now people are fighting back George
is this or that, George is old-fashioned...
I want to see who is
modern-fashioned.
I went through periods where the
homeopathic pharmaceutical industry was
against me very overtly.
I remember the director of a French
company asked me for a meeting.
So he calls the director of [company] and
says I'm going to have a meeting with G.V.
And I am flying to London to see G.V. He
told me himself, he said don't meet him,
kill him. I don't believe he really meant
it that he should shoot me but that was
the idea behind.
In 1983 I was in congress in Washington
D.C. and both his parents were there.
And one of them said to me doing
like this we should kill you.
I said why? Because if we follow
your system, we will go bankrupt.
Do you realize how serious it was and I
had to manipulate all this situation and
to persuade that it was to their advantage
if I taught and homeopaths were effective
in their treatment because the prestige
of Homeopathy will rise and automatically
their sales will increase.
But all this was taking me a lot of
effort and still people are attacking me...
For curing people. Not the allopaths, the
homeopaths I mean. This is the situation.
This stupidity is beyond belief. Because
before everyone who is a homeopath
wanted Homeopathy to have a prestige,
otherwise they will totally exterminate
Homeopathy. They
are very powerful.
They can just wipe us out
if we don't have effect.
And most of the so-called homeopaths
today they don't have an effect.
They just give remedies here
and there without real effect.
They can have some effect, few cases
may be responding but they think...
Some people will say, I don't have to
give the remedy, actually if I think
the correct remedy, the person will
be cured and things like that.
I meditate, I don't need to
take the case, take Staph.
And this is supposed
to be Homeopathy.
I have to get all the impact. Because
when they call me in Germany in
Bonn Medical School the professors say
come and speak to the medical students.
And from the time they invited me to the
time I was there, they investigated what
Homeopathy is. And they hear that there
are people who prescribe zebra because
if somebody likes blue and white like
her... You must take zebra. Not only that.
So when I arrived, they said wait a
moment before you go to the auditorium to
speak to the students we have to put some
questions. I said yes, what questions?
Two German professors one pathology
[internal medicine] professor and the other
one psychiatry professor. One woman and
one man. Very serious. Not like me.
And said we hear that you give remedies
because people look like an animal...
We hear that you prescribe
this with these indications.
If somebody wears a pair of trousers
with this... They knew more than I knew by
that time of the different nonsense
that was going on all around the world.
And I had to explain to them that I
am against this even more than you.
They seemed to be persuaded. Then fortunately
I had a journal in which I had written
my attitude towards this.
It was a European Journal of Homeopathy, I
was publishing that Journal by that time
and I brought it to them to read.
And they said come and teach.
But all these, thousands of such things in
order to support the right Homeopathy and
in the meantime some people come around
"I am a teacher", you are a teacher but
what do you teach? It's not a matter
of being a teacher, everybody says
I am a teacher of Homeopathy,
because there are no standards.
What you teach is the main thing and
what is the effect of what you teach?
I call somebody from America to teach
here, I don't want to tell his name.
He comes and the first thing he
says is I don't agree with George.
People come back and say what the truth is.
You brought a teacher who says
I don't agree with George because of
this and that reason and then whom to
believe, yourself or the other
teacher which you brought?
I called another teacher, he comes and
says that George says there is an initial
aggravation. I have never
seen an initial aggravation.
George says that there might be a possibility
that old problems they may reappear.
I've never seen problems
of the old coming back.
Where is my position?
What should I say to the students?
And then they go back and start fighting...
I don't know if I answered your question.
-I have a question related
to the antidotal influences.
What is your experience with people
who are drinking coke, coca-cola?
-It's the same. Coca-cola has less
effect but the coke that contains together
with the caffeine has
a stimulating effect.
Some people drink one glass of Coca-cola
and they cannot sleep the whole night.
These people it's dangerous
if they are drink Coca-cola.
Coca-cola definitely to some people
especially if they drink 2-3 glasses a day,
sometimes they drink the whole
bottle... then it will antidote.
But you may say Ok then we have to live in
a sterilized world. It is not like this.
Because the pollution also if you
are exposed in a lot of pollution...
If you live in the center of Athens or in a
town with a lot of pollution and you have
a lung problem, you are going to have a
relapse much easier than somebody living
in the island here. That is
true but what else can we do?
Each one has to protect his
own self as much as possible.
-I hear frequently from my patients that
they are swearing that coffee doesn't do
anything with them because I explained them
that everything that has a stimulating
effect is not good. And they swear because
they don't want to give up the coffee,
that is has no effect any coffee.
What is the best argument?
-That is true. There are some people who say
I can drink coffee in the night and then
I can go to bed and
sleep immediately.
It is true that coffee has no
sensitivity towards their organism.
Such people that there is no real effect of
the coffee upon their organism before the
treatment, they may continue but we don't
say that in order to protect the patient.
Even if they tell me there is no effect, I
have to doubt because if there was no effect
why they don't want to change
it to tea or something else?
There is something that pleases them and
this pleasure maybe is not excessive or
is not lubricating their minds but still might
be some effect. And they cannot stop it.
-I also forbid them the coffee because of this,
I say even if you don't feel the effect,
it might have an effect.
-This is also my experience.
-The next, what I very frequently hear
George, is that the people who deal with me
ask me for how long I must stop the
coffee... One week, one year, one month...
-That's another question.
-I normally say to them as
long as you have complaints.
-That is true. What I usually say to
them; you have to stop for 3 years.
If they stay well for 3 years and after that
they start drinking coffee and they relapse
and they come to me I say in
your case you needed 5 years.
So next time you stop it for 5 years.
This is the argument.
For how long do I have to stop? Because
some people as soon as they finish
the treatment they start drinking coffee.
I don't take remedies anymore.
-I normally make a compromise with them
and say Ok stop it for 1 month at least
and if after drinking coffee you write
down that you drank one at least to have
a proof that the remedy
was spoilt from this.
Sometimes I cannot say for 3 years because
it seems too much challenge for them...
-My experience is that some people who
are kind of bon viveur, rich people...
They say Ok forget George, they drink
coffee and when they relapse they come and
they tell you the remedy has not acted just
for this period of time I was somewhat
better but then I relapsed totally. I
know they have been drinking coffee.
You know how many times people think I read
the minds of the people, it's not that.
It's my observation. I know the psychology
and I understand what each one is doing
and what is thinking etc. I said
Ok you have been drinking coffee?
One time. I said not one time one
time a day. Yes Ok one time a day.
Not one time a day. Sometimes
you drank 2 coffees a day. Ok...
But they come and tell you the remedy did
not act because it acted only for a period
of time. They think
they can bluff me.
And there is another group of people
who come and say there was no effect.
What about this and that...? And then they
say this I don't remember I had this.
And I said to them now you have to decide,
you tell me you are totally the same
and I believe you.
But if you are better, the remedy is correct
and I have to continue with the same
remedy and you tell me the remedy had no
effect, I will try to find another remedy
for you. That means I will be searching again
out of 2000 remedies for the next one.
But if that which I gave you was really the
correct one, I will search for 2000 months
every time you come giving you the wrong
remedy because we will have missed
the correct one. So what do you think now?
Are you the same or better?
He says Ok don't
give another remedy.
Because you realize it's not the same but
since he is not totally well he thinks he can
tell you a lie and you can believe them
and you will give them a better remedy...
There was a question also from another
student here. He says in paragraph 46,
there is place about vaccination.
Could you explain this?
Hahnemann says about positive
effect of vaccination, does he?
In paragraph 46, he does not say about
vaccination. Later on he will talk about it.
But what has been misunderstood about
vaccination and Hahnemann is this.
That Hahnemann was treating epidemics
during his time that were very much
in action, the children epidemics, and he
had found out that if he knew the genius
of the epidemic, he treats 1,2,3,4 people
and out of 4 people three needed Bell.
And then he treats some more
and out of 10, 7 needed Bell.
The genius for this epidemic is Bell. So
he gave Bell. to many other people and
he found out that there was a
minimizing of the epidemic.
The people who took the Bell. were a
small percentage of the other population
that fell sick. And he said that this is a
preventing medicine, a homeoprophylaxis,
they called it later on and they
made a big thing out of that.
Some people said we will give you Thuja,
so you are protected from smallpox.
We'll give you another remedy and
you are protected from chickenpox.
We'll give you another to protect
you from whooping cough.
Without the epidemic I will give you now,
there is no epidemic, and this-what I gave
you-will protect you when the epidemic
comes, don't worry, you will not get it.
That is totally wrong. Why?
Because the potentized remedies are acting
once the symptoms are in the person
then on the power of the fact that the
symptoms are manifesting, then the action
of the remedy can be curative. Otherwise
you take a remedy which has nothing
to do with your present
symptomatology.
The organism , the most it can do, if
there are proving symptoms after a month
or two I will get rid of that
symptom and return back to normal.
Therefore there is no logical reason for
a remedy that I took two years ago will
protect me now from malaria which
is an epidemic at the moment.
Now what Bell. was doing during the time
of the epidemic ,it was for those people...
If you take Bell. and there is an effect
of the epidemic, scarlet fever, whatever
but you keep on taking the Bell. so the
scarlet fever or whatever the epidemic is,
as soon as it manifests the first symptoms
you are taking the correct remedy
because the genius of the epidemic is Bell.
and reduces the effect and the overall
progress of the disease.
So the action is curative
again, not preventive.
By the time there is the epidemic, you know
the genius epidemicus, you may give it
to your friends, population and maybe
some of them will be spared or will go
through the epidemic
in a mild form.
These are the facts. Otherwise we will be
attacked in bluffing people, telling lies to
people and of course the responsibility
which they can accuse us for doing such
a thing is tremendous. Who takes the
responsibility? Shall I tell the people instead
of vaccination give Bell.? To all
the population and will be saved?
Two people will die and
the third one will be me.
So irresponsible ideas of that
type manifest again and again.
Influenzinum i.e. is a remedy that if you
give it during an epidemic it may protect
some people but what happens?
Let's say you give Influenzinum
to your friends or to your group.
The thing is today, who is
able to have influenza?
Very few people out of us because we are
sick chronically, we are protected from
having an epidemic by the
fact we are sick enough.
So you cannot attribute the non-effective
of the influenza to the fact you gave
Influenzinum to the people. Sometimes
people ask me for Influenzinum to protect them.
Every year it protects me, please
give me this, I know he is quite sick and
I say you can take it. He
will be protected of course.
But if I treated him and I know the level
of his health, I will not tell him take
Influenzinum to protect you because
I will not be sure about it.
But I'm sure if I know
how sick somebody is.
-I would like to say something to the
question you gave before, when you asked
what shall I say to the students if they
hear from one teacher one thing and
from me the other thing. I think it's very
easy to remember your first words from
the four-year course, you first told us,
you should believe nothing you hear
from me, just listen, go home
and look whether it works.
I can tell you it really works, if you
consequently follow the rules of Homeopathy
and I think the other teachers may be
ameliorating something in their patients,
but they have never
seen a real cure.
-Well, she stood first in the examination
on the first examinations we had for
the four-year course ,
because she understands.
Once you understand, it's easy to follow but
if you get the knowledge in a superficial
way and you say well, let me try this and that
and then you meet with the first difficult
case, what you are going to do to different
other methods? Then you will be lost.
This is for sure. But if you insist, even
if you lose a patient, it doesn't matter.
You say, I cannot treat you,
I cannot find you a remedy.
Like yesterday you saw this example, in front
of you, I said I don't know the remedy.
Do whatever you like, I cannot take up this
case. I lost this case but really I did not
because I stay with
my principles.
What I want is that I always tell the
truth and I don't bluff anybody.
This is very important for the
conscience of a homeopath.
Because it is so easy to bluff the patient.
There are people who say crazy things
to the patients and they
believe it and they go and do...
I don't want to mention now but in the
end the patient is totally the same.
There is no difference in their
health and they are desperate.
They go away and say Homeopathy
does not work. He promised me...
Can you imagine that people will
maintain that you don't have to give
a potentized remedy. What you have to
do is to write in a piece of paper
Lyc. 10M and put over this paper a glass of
water and this paper will boil the water
and will potentize this water
and it becomes Lyc. 10M.
Then you give it to the patient to drink it.
That is maintained in a public discussion.
People do not get up and say you
are totally out of your mind.
What can I say?
And then when in England the Minister of
Health wants to extinguish Homeopathy
from the national health
system... what can people say?
Can you get up and argue? You have said this.
Can you argue now, you are a charlatan
and should be kicked out from the
NHS if you maintain such things?
Is this correct or not? Unbelievable
things that I have to deal with.
And yet there are
people who believe.
-It's not the Minister of Health
who wants to stop Homeopathy.
It's many other people attacking. It is the
BMA and the reason they're attacking us
is not potentizing 10M by one piece
of paper but our basic principles.
They are attacking things like potency,
Similimum, the foundation of our profession.
It's not just based on nonsense. We
are being attacked for root causes.
-I have attended all these process.
What happened with the parliament and
what the arguments were. Who were
the people from who the parliament
maintaining Homeopathy
should be kicked out.
I have attended the whole
thing and I have it all...
If you like I can give
you all the data.
But the question for me is
not that, who accuses us.
Of course the medical association will
be very happy to get rid of Homeopathy
Of course the pharmaceutical companies
will have their own people in
the government and they will push them and
go along and kick out but all this is
based on the fact that there is no effect
and that people are bluffed and the NHS
is paying money for nothing, for no effect.
This was the argument.
Why should we be spend
money on nonsense?
They can come to me to show me what is
nonsense when they bring me 10 cases
and I ask them how much you spend in
your life for your health and how much
you would spend now that I will treat you
and find out. They don't come to me.
And they maintain with the arguments
which have been promoted by such people
irresponsible people and they have the
arguments, they say what is going on here?
We just spend money for nothing. It
is not a matter of who accuses you.
Because the pharmaceutical industry
has a network that can affect even
the Prime Minister. They have no problem.
If the matter becomes very serious,
it's a matter of money, whether
it is 1 million or 1 billion.
They can do whatever they like but the
basis and the arguments on which they base
their decision to kick out Homeopathy from
NHS is based on what kind of nonsense
we have publicly
said and exposed.
-The real reason why the remedy that is...
when a glass of water is put over a piece
of paper where the remedy is written, the
reason it doesn't work is that the remedy
is written in Latin. If you write it in
Greek, it will work...It's been proven...
-For us perhaps this thing about the piece
of paper or remedies sent with energy
looks like nonsense. But for the other
people what we say about potentization of
remedies and very small quantities,
all this also sounds like nonsense.
So that's the problem. What I think we
should do focus on is to produce evidence
about clinical results. And that's
what would convince people eventually.
And what I also would like to say
about evidence-based medicine,
the whole concept of it isn't actually to
find the exact mechanism something works.
It is about clinical evidence. It is about
clinical trials which show that something
has statistically these results. So we
shouldn't be against evidence-based medicine.
It's not exactly the mechanism in the
laboratory. It's about clinical results.
-You are right. We are not against EBM,
we are in favor but we say EBM should be
based on real cure. I don't think you are
right in saying that's all they mean.
They mean, tell us the mechanism
through which you bring about...
-About EBM. It's very standardized. They
have several categories of evidence from
A to E. I don't remember exactly but it
is like A evidence comes from prospective
trials, B from randomized controlled
that means with placebo, C comes from
a well-known teacher on a subject
and he has results with something...
This is called evidence
categorizing C, not as good as A.
It's very standardized,
with EBM.
-They have standardized but what my
argument is that we can show evidence
in curing people.
But in order to do that, we have before
to agree what is to cure a person.
Therefore a person who is mad and is
treated by Homeopathy and now has a
duodenal ulcer is an
evidence-based cure.
We have to agree that the parameters for
the quality of life are considered as EBM.
We have several papers if you go to
science direct, if you go Pubmed,
you will bring down a lot of research
that shows effect of homeopathic remedies
but this research has been based
on wrong idea of research for us.
In the last gynecology Congress that was
held in Athens, we presented a research
which is going on in "Helena", the
gynecology public hospital, in which women
over 40 that have tried all kinds of
different methods could not get pregnant,
through Homeopathy they were so many,
about 70% of them they had an effect,
they became pregnant.
Such a paper is based on 1 to 1 individual.
That means we did not give one remedy
to all of them. They say give one remedy
to all of them and if you have an effect
then we will accept it.
Why don't you accept the fact that these
sterile women had the possibility
to become pregnant under
homeopathic treatment?
When you send a paper like that they have
a lot of arguments against such a paper.
Because it is not according
to the standards as you said.
Randomization and all this kind of
standardization which they have imposed.
How can we prove it? What we
can prove is the evidence.
Out of 10, 7 had become pregnant. The
number is small... We need more numbers.
How many do you need? 40. Ok we will do
with 40. Oh yes but... 1,2,3,4,5 parameters
were not correct, they
will always find...
And that is why I mock
with this evidence.
They come afterwards, after a double
blind study has been done, and criticize
the study and they destroy the study
but in the meantime the remedy
which was selected to become the
curative agent has been distributed
all over the world.
But there is a study afterwards that
says the research was not correct,
the people who did the research were
paid from the pharmaceutical industry.
These people... nobody criticizes that.
That is true because you are very good.
She was the first to enter the Medical
School and she stood first in graduating.
She's a genius. She
knows quite a lot.
-I didn't understand two
things about yesterday lesson.
I didn't understand that in a list of
symptoms obtained by a proving of a remedy
in a person, how can we distinguish
primary effect and secondary effect
of the remedy?
-That is a good question. You
don't have to extinguish.
Actually you have to record the primary
as well as the secondary symptoms
from a proving and that becomes
the picture of the remedy.
He says in the primary effect there is, in
Opium i.e., constipation, in the secondary
effect the organism
comes and has diarrhea.
So Opium can be indicated both
in constipation and in diarrhea.
So you have to record all the symptoms
from the very beginning you start a proving,
you have to
record all the symptoms.
Initially you will record primary symptoms
and as you go along you will record
also secondary symptoms.
-Ok. And the other question is I didn't
understand the reason why if a person
ameliorates a bit after a remedy and then
he gets an aggravation we can define him
as incurable. Why?
-This is an observation of the old masters
especially Kent who was really a healer.
He was treating thousands of patients
and had a lot of experience.
He noticed this phenomenon that once you
give a remedy in a deep pathology and
there is amelioration and then
aggravation, you have to be careful.
If now you give another remedy and instead
of initial aggravation there is an
amelioration and then a relapse, that
indicates once it happens 2-3 times that
the patient is incurable
according to him.
But he also said something
else to which I do not agree.
That if there is an aggravation, the
aggravation can be so great that maybe
the patient will end up dying. I have
said that not all cases are like this.
There are cases in which there was a long
aggravation, the patient's life was really
in danger, but during that aggravation if
you observe, you can see the next remedy
and then you can give it and
then you reverse the process.
But that very long aggravation like
expected in the case you saw yesterday,
we have to wait 2-3 months and the
child will remain in bed and shouting...
But then eventually the picture of the
next remedy may appear, will appear...
and if you give it, then it starts
the other process of amelioration.
Which Medical School
have you finished?
-University of Bologna, Italy...
-Because in Italy there are some very
good Medical Schools and some very...
in the south...
I expected that
from you... I can see.
-I still have some questions about
vaccination. It seems that around the world
according to everybody many diseases have
been eradicated, for example in the USA
we don't see polio, except
from unvaccinated people.
I know you mentioned last time, that
people who are harmed more strongly by
the vaccination are the ones who would
have been most susceptible to that
particular disease. But still if
nobody gets it, it is doing something.
What is it really doing?
-Actually I didn't get the question.
Can you repeat it please?
-How do vaccinations work? We understand
they are harmful but they seem to
eliminate these diseases all over
the world. How does it work?
-There are several issues. It's a big subject
to analyze it properly. But I will summarize.
At this moment the western population,
Europe, America, Canada are not candidates
for epidemics. The reason is they
are all very sick chronically.
There is no possibility that
an epidemic can spread.
If by chance there is one or two sporadic
incidents, such sporadic incidents they are
not coming to the forefront and only the
hospitals may know what is going on.
Why this epidemic does not
spread if there is an incident?
The reason is that all the people around
that person who got sick are immune
to such an epidemic because of
their own chronic problems.
So it cannot spread, it cannot go from one
to another because there is no possibility
to get infected.
That's one reason.
The second reason is that
epidemics manifest in waves.
There are periods where TB is raving, killing
lots of people and the wave came down
before the manifestation or the
discovery of the vaccination.
It was coming down according
to the statistics.
So you will see there are natural waves
of epidemics, which after there is a peak
they will go down by themselves
even without any vaccination.
And this we observe in areas where people
can be affected like the Asians and
the South Americans are the people to
which these observations are valid.
There you will see a wave coming, killing
people and then it goes away and doesn't
come back or it comes for 1,2,3
years and the 5th year it is gone.
They are coming back again
after 10 years or 15 years.
If you do not take into consideration all
these factors, you will not be able to draw
conclusions which are correct.
Because you think, smallpox has been
eliminated, is it due to the vaccination?
The argument can be that the vaccination
attributed into the bad health of
the people so they could not, because
of the bad damage done, they could not
anymore get the smallpox or
any other acute disease.
If we really wanted to have the real facts,
we should observe populations like India,
Pakistan, Asian people ... in how
the epidemics behave there.
And we will see that there are times when TB
is coming up or when an epidemic comes up.
In India I have been told, I have not
seen the facts, that in the older times,
before the war , that they left a
city without smallpox vaccination.
In India smallpox was active and
another city was vaccinated.
The epidemic came in both, the city with
vaccination and the city without vaccination.
The number of deaths was similar.
What do you say about that?
I heard while I was in India in the colleges,
I do not have the real facts but if that is true
that is something that we would
have to explore to see really whether
in a strong population the vaccination
actually is effective or not.
Because my theory of vaccination is that
the vaccination which is given to a strong
organism is rejected, the
effect does not stay.
There is a reaction with an abscess and
the person is not immunized anymore.
He comes back to the original state. That
could explain why the deaths between
the one city and the
other were the same.
Because when the epidemic came, the
people who were vaccinated, most of them
were ready to get it again because they
got rid of the effect of the vaccination.
Why was the same? Because you may say,
the population
that was sensitive to the smallpox,
in the city of vaccination
should have been protected more than the other city.
But what could have happen that those
who were vaccinated
and got rid of the vaccination,
maybe they were left with a sensitivity to the smallpox.
Then they would be easy victims like
an unvaccinated person even worse.
So some of the people of the vaccinated
city became sick because of the vaccination
and could not get it. But the numbers
were the same because the city
which had the vaccination and the people got
rid of the effect of the vaccination
were maintained with an extra
sensitivity to the smallpox.
That is why the deaths were
equal in these two cities.
These are arguments that
could be investigated.
They are difficult things to investigate,
I understand, but before we come to conclusions
and say look at the
population, look why at Sabin
what has done for poliomyelitis... It saved
but what is the cost?
Is the cost a similar disease like M.S.
which is expanding like an epidemic today?
Is the cost? Maybe we have to examine
it before we come to conclusions.
Vaccinations have affected and
saved, question mark, in what way?
Genius, what do you say?
You gave up your genius quality?
I'll tell you something. This is not the
idea of reading this and going over.
The idea is really understanding in
depth so you clarify the issues.
So if you are clear, then you can give the
answers when somebody is challenging you.
What Steven has said now is a question
that has been put to me so many times
by so many allopathic doctors.
When you give an answer which is
logical, they stop and think.
But if you say well I don't
know, you leave a black whole.
Somebody who has not spoken yet.
-I have a question which is lying
in my head, maybe for 3 years,
I sent you an email, can I read it?
This question is concerning how
patient's personality is influenced by
his predispositions? Let us say we have one
clear cut case Level 1 for instance Calc.
The patient produces a very clear picture
of Calc. symptoms and in the state of
a sensitive balance of health, he has some
personal traits which we have connected
with the constitutional
type of Calc.
We can say this is a psoric
patient and is very healthy...
but I have a
hypothetical question.
If this patient before is born,
inherited different complex of predispositions.
For instance sycotic predispositions and
it's logical when the disease will manifest
in these patients the other
remedy (Calc.) will be indicated.
But I absolutely cannot understand in the
state of health of this patient with
sycotic predispositions, why these
predispositions will influence the personality?
-Wait a moment. You made a mistake
thinking that a person is born as Calc.
but you suppose also that this person has
a predisposition for sycotic miasm and
also has a predisposition
for the syphilitic miasm.
There are several things you are asking. I
thought you were asking a logical question
which you'll say if a person is born
as a Calc., then what do we consider
as his symptomatology if
he's in a balanced state?
That means when his pathology will manifest
at what age,
with what provocation if he is balanced.
He's born, he's healthy, he's balanced
and now at the age of 20 he has a stress
and there is a manifestation of Calc.
symptoms.
The traits of his personality how can be
influenced by the fact that he is Calc.?
Further if he has underneath
sycotic miasm and syphilitic miasm
how all this mixture
will end up?
I confused you because you didn't want to
ask this, you were asking something else
which I did not understand
but it doesn't matter.
Now this can be a question to which you can agree
and everyone would like to hear the answer.