Paragraph 88, "If in these voluntary details
nothing has been mentioned respecting
several parts or functions of the body
or his metal state, the physician asks
what more can be told in regard to
these parts and these functions,
or the state of his disposition of mind,
but in doing this he only makes use of
general expressions, in order that his
informants may be obliged to enter into
special details
concerning them."
He says if you have not asked or he
has not spoken about certain areas
the doctor should ask about such areas
especially concerning the mental condition
and disposition and put the question
in such a way, in a general way,
so the patient may elaborate
on this by himself.
Par. 89, "When the patient (for it is on him
we have chiefly to rely for a description
of his sensations, except in the case of
feigned diseases) has by these details,
given of his own accord"
It's very important.
If somebody will voluntarily give information,
that information you underline it.
It is clear information so you have to
underline it and you have to rely on it.
"... of his own accord and in answer to
inquiries, furnished the requisite information
and traced a tolerably perfect
picture of the disease,
the physician is at liberty and obliged (if
he feels he has not yet gained all the
information he needs) to ask more
precise, more special questions."
If the patient has given "a tolerably
perfect picture of the disease"...
If the patient has given more or less
a complete picture of his disease,
the doctor is obliged to ask more
precise information about his disease.
Par. 90, "When the physician has
finished writing down these particulars,
he then makes a note of what he
himself observes in the patient,
and ascertains how much of that was peculiar
to the patient in his healthy state."
If the doctor observes something on the
patient, for instance the patient is sitting
all the time and moving and is restless, is
making gesture, tics, closes his eyes etc.
he must ask him since what time do you
do this? Do you remember when you
started being restless? When
did I start getting restless?
One time I did an
experiment with the class.
I said I have been teaching (the Greek
doctors) you for years and now I want
you to write down all my symptoms.
What you have observed as symptoms.
It was a total failure.
One he observed correctly and
he wrote down my symptoms.
All the others were projections
of their imagination.
The best way to teach Homeopathy would
be always to have the people around
and the patient and for everything that
I observe, I could ask each one of them
to tell me what do you observe?
Sometimes I come in the class and I say
do you observe the eyes of this person?
Yes. What did you see?
In his eye there is a great sadness, how
many in the class saw sadness? Only 10%.
But for me it is so obvious.
How can you not see it?
Observation is a
matter of detachment.
That means the doctor must never be
attached to the patient in any way.
Because here enters a nice woman and
you are a man and you like women and
immediately your natural
instinct is to like that person.
From that moment onwards
forget taking a correct case.
You cannot get an
objective case.
You are going to write down your impression
about this person. How nice she is...
One time one of my doctors in Athens, they
were giving me their cases in the night
for me to prescribe on the paper. So I
prescribed very quickly, I read and I prescribe.
I have to prescribe 30-40 cases at the end of
the day. I read this, it's a nice young man,
(she's a very good looking doctor) so I
understood from the paper they like each other.
So I wrote her you have to re-take
the case and stop flirting with him.
She retook the case and she was amazed
to find out that this was a manic
depression case. Where it was a simple
case of a nice man who had some itching
in the nose... Nothing! There
was nothing in the case.
Why this man came to be treated?
When she really investigated, being detached
and observing, she found out he was
mentally very disturbed. These people who
are bipolars, manic depressive cases...
in their manic state they are wonderful
people with a lot of fascination for others
because the energy is flowing and they
can be so expressive and can say things...
And unless you sit back and realize they are
overdoing it because it is very obvious
they are going over the board in their
expression, you realize that they are
mentally disturbed.
So in order to take a good
case, you have to be detached.
Detached does not mean that you are
not interested about the case.
You are interested about the case but not
about the person as an erotic friend.
You are interested about his passions,
his disease and you want to help him.
If your mind is concentrated on this
line, you cannot fall to the other side.
Because a lot of patients especially women
towards men they try to seduce the doctor
by playing nice.... They perceive immediately
whether a doctor likes them or not and
then they handle it. And once
they get involved, a homeopath...
A M.D., doesn't matter. He knows that in
duodenal ulcer he has to prescribe that
medicine and finish.
But for a homeopath who tries to
understand the picture of the pathology
in a human being, understand how deep it
is, you have really to be on your guard
all the time. And immediately you perceive
that the woman tries to seduce you.
So you handle it,
otherwise you fall.
And then you fail... As I
was saying to Frederick...
We were talking before and I said to
him how is it possible that Homeopathy
in Greece is going upwards all the time, how
is it possible that we have 3 hospitals
carrying clinical research with the consent
of the doctors in the hospitals,
the directors of the hospitals. 3
public hospitals are running this.
We have a University where M.D.
can get a master's degree.
How is it possible that the media, the
media are crazy for me to go to media
and speak, you know how many invitations I
have received, I said no, I don't come.
How is that possible that the Greek doctors
at this moment who are my students,
one of them is Katie, they have no
problem with their patients
during such a financial crisis in Greece and the
patients are paying from their own pocket?
All the Greek patients going to Homeopathy
they pay from their own pocket.
They don't rely on insurance.
All my old students have become rich. How
is that possible that in England
things are going down, in Belgium things
are going down homeopathically.
In America, even in Germany.
They tell me in England a lot of homeopaths
are closing down their practices, 50%.
But some good ones will stay.
Homeopathy relies on the prestige which
is produced by those good homeopaths
who have effect. How can you have an effect
if you do crazy things,
if you have crazy fantasies, if you play
around with the patients?
This is a science, which I consider the highest
in the field of Medicine, but requires
personalities that are quite complete in
their understanding of the human suffering.
Speak out.
-I want to ask you about the detachment
you said before between the patient and the doctor.
Does it include only
erotic emotions or also friendship?
Sometimes there is a problem and the
doctor must stop taking the case...
-Sure. To treat a friend is equally difficult.
Because your old-time friend has an idea about you
and you have an idea about him
and you can't see him as a fresh new case.
This is the difficulty also with treating
your wife, your children, mother and father.
This is a real problem as well. And the
biggest problem is treating yourself.
Because it's very difficult to see objectively
and to see that these are the points
which are pathological and do
not belong to the personality.
I have a personality, if you take my
personality and you describe it
because I took that medicine, it's
totally wrong.
But there are some points in my mental/
emotional structure which are gone beyond,
then you have to
find out and use them.
Shall I put you in the test of
observation and write down my symptoms?
...which is something I actually need... I
don't see you are willing to do it.
-I know something from
yesterday; heat aggravates.
-Heat aggravates. Desire for hot drinks. This
is an impression. I like cold drinks as well.
Another? Sensitive to draft.
Correct, especially when I have
a cold or I am under an acute.
Michael? I thought you
want to say something...
A problem with digestion. Yes,
I have said too much actually.
Desire chocolate. Sweets, in general
and meat. Moving my right leg.
-As far as I understood you have sleeplessness
when you are excited in your mind.
-Especially when I have a crowd
here waiting for me the next day.
This is something which I have
all along the years of my life.
Only this year I managed to control it.
That's why I am still alive I think.
I sleep quite well now for
the last 9-10 months.
I was never able to sleep when I
had something important to do.
Good observations.
-You hate flies.
-Yes, that is true but not to the extent
I pretend to do it because I am playing with that.
A good observation would have
been you pretend you do not like flies
and you play with that. That
is a more deep observation.
Because when you have to sit
down for almost 2 hours here...
the span of attention of a normal brain
is 10 minutes, then stops and then again.
The normal course of a lecture should
never be more than 45 minutes.
We made you sit here -because we want
to give you much information
- 2 hours in a row without interval.
This is really criminal.
Therefore I have to say things to enliven
you, stories...
Otherwise serious lecture for 2 hours every one
will be sleeping in the end of the hour.
The observation should not be desire
warm drinks, easy dehydration.
I dehydrate easily
and I need liquids.
In 1980 there was here a meeting of
all the people
who do research in the
homeopathic world.
I brought them all here, I
had a rich patient
who paid their expenses and
we had discussions.
During this time Alonissos
had no ferry boats,
there were some boats
coming from time to time.
I took the responsibility to invite
the people here and between them
it was Benveniste.
We had discussions and one night at
about 1.00 a.m. somebody comes to
my house and says Benveniste has a
heart attack. And he's lying in a room
in Roussoum without telephone, without the
possibility of having any transportation
to take him to any hospital and Peter
Fisher was here, he is the editor
of Homeopathy in England.
-He treats the Queen.
-Yes he's treating the Queen now. Then Dr.
Elliot was Queen's physician
who was here then, Dr. Reilly was here
and about 20 - 25 people were here.
Anyhow, 1 a.m. they come and tell
me Benveniste has a heart attack.
It's Peter Fisher, Dr. Reilly, they woke
up and one more, I can't remember, and
myself we go back and I see Benveniste is
lying there, he knew that he had a problem
with his heart, he was M.D.
he understood.
He had a heart infarct, he had pain and he
was lying totally immovable in the bed,
with pain, closed eyes and at 1.30 a.m. I
asked his wife, she gave me a little bit
of information but I
had what I could see.
I said to Peter and to
David he needs Ars. 200CH.
Immediately there
was a reaction.
He does not move, no restlessness,
where did you find the Ars.?
I said you did not see his eyelids. They
were trembling, he had them closed but
trembling constantly. You did not
observe that being a medical doctor,
he knows the problem being in an isolated
place, he has a heart attack, he does not
have access to any hospital, so he feels
his time has come and that he will die
in Alonissos and he keeps
totally imnmovable.
Because being a M.D. knows that in
a heart infarct he must not move.
You must keep quite. No matter how much
pain you have, the best thing to do is not
to give extra work to your heart,
so you have to stay still.
That is why. I said he has great anxiety
about his health, he has fear of death,
there is restlessness but the restlessness
appears only in his lids, the time is 2.00 a.m.
we know the aggravation time for Ars. is
between 1-3 a.m. give a dose of Ars. 200CH.
He took the Ars. 200. I waited until he
fell asleep and then I left at about 3 a.m.
Then we had to meet the group at 9 a.m.
and I passed to see him before going to
the group to see how he is because there
was no possibility for him to move.
It was 7.30 a.m. I was without sleep. I asked
the wife how he is, she said he is still sleeping.
I said this is a
good sign, he is not dead.
I left and I came to the class where
we met and there was great anxiety.
In the group nobody spoke. All the
responsibility was with Mr. Vithoulkas,
he treated the case. You
understand the situation,
nobody accused me or said anything but still
I felt the heaviness of the atmosphere.
In the meantime he had asked, when we
were there,
to leave immediately with the first boat
the next day in the morning,
to get a ticket so he can leave Alonissos and go to Volos.
I think it was about 9.30 a.m. when we saw
him coming to the class to participate
in the discussion. He says I feel quite
alright now and I am not going to leave.
He had the possibility
to leave Alonissos.
Not only his heart infarct was resolved
but his anxiety and the fear of death
was minimized. He continued and stayed
all along till we finished the week
of the works we had to do without
any problem and then he left.
If I did not have the observation and
if my observation was not correct and
I did not put things together, I could
have given all other remedies except Ars.
And maybe ending up in a tragedy or
in a very bad fame for Homeopathy.
This is how I learn with my master Mr.
Hahnemann., I learned what to do.
When I read the Organon I thought it was
the easiest book to read ever in my life
and the most interesting.
When I asked the Germans later on, my
students, they said Organon
is very difficult book to understand.
Long sentences, obscure ideas.
For me it was unbelievable. I was in state
of excitement when I was reading it.
And I read it right through
one time and never again.
From time to time when I had to teach,
I will open one paragraph and maybe
I will speak. But never read like I
am trying now for a second time.
In the beginning and in the end they
say to complete the understanding.
Paragraph 90, "When the physician has
finished writing down these particulars,
he then makes a note of what he himself
observes in the patient, and ascertains
how much of that was peculiar to
the patient in his healthy state."
It is true that next day I ask
Benveniste about the restlessness.
He says internally I felt very restless but
I knew I should not move and that's why
I was keeping so quite.
So you have a chance to ask
whatever you like now.
On the Organon, outside of the Organon,
anything that comes to your mind
except of one thing...
-I wanted to ask the following; we had a
very interesting topic with Mr. Schroyens
concerning the topic when two opposite
symptoms occur in a patient and normally
I have the impression...
-Two opposite symptoms
in the patient?
-Yes.
-Can you give me an example?
-2-3 weeks ago, I had a patient that she
said to me that when there was cold
and wet weather she hated it and she had
some pains in the back and everything
is aggravated from cold and wet. After 5
minutes she told me in general she has
aversion to heat and she doesn't like hot
weather and she's aggravated by being
warm in a room. First I saw a Rhus
tox thing and then Pulsatilla.
When I repertorised I can go to this
or what we said today to this point...
The truth was that in this case I thought
the uppermost layer was Rhus tox because
cold was bothering her the most and below
there was a Pulsatilla thing from her older
state. My question is now this can
come very frequently like this.
-You answered to the question. The
question whether this is frequent or not;
this is not frequent. But it is a fact it can
be aggravated on one set of symptoms and
can be ameliorated another set of
symptoms with the opposite conditions.
This can happen but
not very frequently.
-So you mean it is more frequent that
this is existing in one remedy that
the opposite symptoms
are present.
-It doesn't necessarily need to be in one
remedy but what is necessary for you is
to evaluate which is the most disturbing
at the moment and give it more importance.
And if you give more importance, underline
it, then most probably the remedy that
has the symptoms will come up.
Underlining means giving importance to this
because the patient is suffering a lot
from that group of symptoms. There is
another group of symptoms still but not
so severe. This would be
underlined once or twice.
-This can be an
underneath layer as well.
-Yes. It does not have to be covered
with one remedy both situations.
One situation will go away and the other
situation will stay for the next layer.
-When I see the opposite symptoms, I see
this in a patient having different layers,
an uppermost and the underneath layer
coming half a year later maybe.
But how can differentiate clearly when
there is somebody who is having this
in one remedy... or if it is two layers
above this possibility or only one remedy
and the other another
possibility.
-I told you. There is a possibility that
both opposite situations are covered
by one remedy. That
is one possibility.
There is another one, the uppermost
layer is covered by Rhus tox and once
Rhus tox is gone then
the other layer...
or rather I'll give another
example which is more clear.
You give Pulsatilla and it takes away the
aggravation from heat and in 6, 9 months
there comes a set of symptoms
which need Silica. Freezing cold.
So Silica will take care
of the underlying layer.
Sometimes the patient may say under
certain circumstances I feel bad
when there is a draft but still you
decide Pulsatilla is the uppermost.
Give Pulsatilla, then it goes away. Then
it comes the draft and the coldness
underneath, give Silica... Thank you.
You said the answer.
-I speak Russian. We discuss the
theory of psora by Hahnemann
and I wanted to ask a question
about the treatment of scabies.
I had several patients that were
treated by me homeopathically
it was a very long and tormenting
process for the patients.
But yet afterwards they got better.
They were cured.
-For how long did it last?
-It lasted for several months. After
the potency 50M they got cured.
But recently I read
an article by Burnett
that was called the retake of
psora theory by Hahnemann.
He writes there that it's absolutely
tormenting treating patients by this dynamical treatment
that the patient skin should
be allowed to be treated externally
by some ointments creams...
What do you think about this?
-Scabies is infecting but it infects quite
healthy individuals. Usually children.
Children which have good constitutions
are infected by scabies.
Because scabies is a local infective
agent, it does not give general symptoms
as reaction of the organism and it's
very difficult to find the remedy.
In the meantime the problem is first the
suffering is tremendous because the itch
is great. The second problem is that the
whole family is in danger of getting it
as well, so you have to fight with time
and you have to find quickly the remedy
and cure it. If you don't find it, you may
try for 2-5 months, then the whole family
is infected by scabies. And scabies
have eaten up different places.
That's why because we cannot find the
remedy, we have to rely on the disinfectant
because there is an effective cream
for scabies which can kill the acari.
I don't know how much this kind of
treatment can affect the body in general.
I believe it is going to affect it.
To what extent I am not able to say.
Because again the same problem with
contemporary people, they cannot be
infected by acaris. Not healthy
enough to be infected by acaris.
But definitely once you are affected, a child
which is affected and by the old times
they had quite strong treatment for that,
it was 60 years ago they had a strong
ointment that they used to use
and suppressed the scabies.
Then it would produce
the psoric miasm.
Burnett most probably had the same
problem as I have when I meet such cases
that unless you find the remedy quickly
the people will not tolerate it.
They will go and get the remedy.
-Concerning this question, I am thinking
about what kind of damage is done
with killing the bacteria. Because
logically when we have infected skin and
we apply something some ointment
which will kill the bacteria,
there must be some kind of inflammatory
process which is now unknown to us
which will lead to the secondary
psoric manifestation.
-I don't understand
the question.
-What is the mechanism of secondary
manifestation when the primary infection
is suppressed?
-I don't know the internal mechanism.
It's so complicated.
It's within the sphere of the infinite,
the processes inside the body
which are taking place.
What I know also is that when
you are treating i.e. ringworm...
Who knows ringworm? Ringworm is an
acari also which starts with a pimple
and then this pimple expands in a circle
and the itch is great and it expands...
If you do not treat it homeopathically
and you treat it allopathically
you are definitely going to have the
manifestation of psora, that means a kind of
a chronic condition which
will be quite severe.
I have seen that again and again.
But the mechanism, I do not know.
-3 things. The first is one
thing I will share with you.
There is an Italian doctor who made
studies about the terms used by Hahnemann
like scabies or [Italian word] or lepra and
what he found is that scabies was used
as synonymous of itching.
So in this way of view the acute of psora
is the manifestation of small vesicle with
pus and itch...
But in this way of view the scabies
was not the clinical problem
but it was synonymous
to itching.
So the origin of psora was psoriasis, not
scabies for this Italian doctor because
he made etymological studies.
Doctor Angelo Micozzi. If you want
I can write all his explanation.
-He's an unknown fellow.
-In Italy he is not.
-I don't agree. I think
it is totally wrong.
I am not sure psoriasis is a pure a psoric
miasm. It's more syphilitic and psoric
at the same time. Scabies is...
at least what Hahnemann means...
because the scabies were manifesting in
very old times. Psoriasis I don't know.
You are entering the internet and tell
me when psoriasis was first diagnosed.
-Because in his study he found that lepra
was used as a synonymous of psoriasis.
-Of psoriasis?!
-That's what he found. We know lepra but
there was also called lepra vulgaris
which was in reality psoriasis. There
was lepra as we know it and
there was also lepra vulgaris
which was the psoriasis.
-First time I hear such a theory with
which I do not agree initially but...
-And I came here to Alonissos with
two questions about the Organon.
If you think there is a way to
translate the word "vital force"
into a modern language.
-What do you propose?
-It's really difficult because there is a
scientific theory about complex systems...
What I propose is that vital force are
all the rules that govern our organism...
But I don't know...
-In my understanding the vital force is a
neutral energy that permeates everyone
and because it comes through our
bodies, we shape it and we use it.
It's a neutral energy that comes
through us, animates the body,
we shape it through our actions
and we transform it from neutral
to something else which may be...
-Vital force interacts
with our organism...
-We say it is bioenergy. It's another term
that you can be using but the main thing
is to understand what it is all about.
All this is theoretical unless you have
the experience and which
is the experience?
The experience is to have seen a whole
formation of energy coming out of
the person who is dying. We may develop
sensitive lenses and the moment of death,
that the body separates from the energy, we
can film this exodus, this externalization.
And then people will say yes we knew all
that. But before we find the correct lenses
to film this, people may have
different ideas about it.
-And the last question. What do you
think about the note in paragraph 31
where Hahnemann speaks about what he
thinks about the dynamics of diseases
and he used the word
"metaphysical".
-Par. 31 Ok. I will
read it for your sake.
"The inimical forces, partly psychical,
partly physical, to which our terrestrial
existence is exposed, which are
termed morbific noxious agents,
do not possess the power of morbidly
deranging the health of man unconditionally;
but we are made ill by them only when our
organism is sufficiently disposed and
susceptible to the attack of the
morbific cause that may be present,
and to be altered in its health, deranged
and made to undergo abnormal sensations
and functions - hence they do not produce
disease in every one nor at all times."
If you want me to explain
this, I can tell you this.
He says the inimical forces, whether
they are material or psychical,
that means the natural causes of
disease, do not have an unlimited power
over the organism.
That means once a disease comes, it does
not mean that all of us will be sick.
But it will depend on our structure
whether we will accept to be sick or not
and he wants to bring this in
contradistinction with the drugs which have
an unlimited action
upon the organism.
That means any drug, if you take in large
enough doses, will produce some effect
on the organism. But the natural
disease does not have this power.
You have to have a predisposition
in order to be infected.
-Do you think that this is the reason
that antibiotics are suppressive?
-Exactly.
Who wants to speak? The time
is in a meditative mood.
-I want your opinion
about a case that I had.
I had a young woman who was divorced,
was around 45, who has adopted a child
in spite of the different opinion of her
boyfriend and she visited me because
she has a great loss of weight. She
has lost over 20 kilos in 2 years.
She was depressed because she was
pressed by her mother to divorce him,
her boyfriend didn't want to adopt the
child and be the father and I thought
that something bad has happened
to her because of her pallor.
-Stop here. I want you to tell me what you
understand the pathology of this woman
may be from the
description so far.
What can be the pathology of a woman
aged 45 who is having a conflict with
her boyfriend and also emotional problem
with the mother who is pressurizing her
to divorce this man and the man does not
want to adopt the child and the woman
has found herself
in that conflict.
What is the organ that most probably
will break down and will not function?
Correct, the thyroid. Most probably
the problem is the thyroid.
-I suspected that beyond the emotional
pathology something was deeper.
Because I thought of anorexia nervosa.
I suggested a psychiatrist examination
and an examination
from an internist.
The psychiatrist confirmed my suspicion
that beyond emotional pathology
there was something deeper. The
pathology wasn't only emotional.
The internist who examined her suggested
further laboratory examination.
This was normal. I suspected
that something wasn't real.
After some months a pediatrician
called me and told me that this woman
was dying of cancer. The diagnosis
of cancer was 3 years ago.
That means that she lied to 3 scientists
and when she had adopted the child
she had the diagnosis of cancer and I
cannot understand why this woman lied
to 3 doctors... She knew that and she
didn't tell me or the other 2 doctors.
And she wanted me to help her.
-Where was the cancer?
-The cancer was in breast and she
had metastases all over the body.
-So she knew her diagnosis.
-But she didn't tell me, nor to the
psychiatrist, nor to the internist.
And now the child is under the care
of the grandparents who are 80 and
72 years old. That means that the
child is the victim of all this.
The father went away. Why did this
woman tell lies to 3 doctors?
-It's very simple.
She wanted most probably to have the
child and if she said I have cancer
nobody would give her the child. No
organization will give a child to a woman
that is known to have cancer.
She may die after a few years.
But if she did not have cancer I would expect
that the conflict will be on this area,
which is the area affected by emotions.
Helen was correct.
Next? You still have 35 seconds for
a question. Greeks are active.
-Suppose that a person has some
symptoms that are covered by a remedy
that has not been
discovered yet.
So he goes to the homeopath and
he gives a close remedy and then
another remedy which
is again close...
-If he is a good homeopath
slowly he may bring about...
-That's what I wanted to ask. Is there a
possibility for this person to be cured?
-Yes, but it will
take much longer.
-Even if the totality
is not there.
-Yes, I believe. But it
will take much longer.