Paragraph 73, "Acute diseases likewise admit of division into several classes.
The first are those which attack single individuals; they are occasioned by hurtful
influences to which the patient happened to be exposed.
Excesses in sensual enjoyment, or deprivation of the same; violent physical
impressions; exposure to cold; overheating; excessive muscular exertion; physical or
mental excitement, etc., give rise to acute febrile diseases.
They are, however, in reality but transient aggravations of latent psora,
which returns to its dormant condition of its own accord, provided the acute disease
was not too violent and speedily relieved."
He tries to give an explanation of simple acute diseases, not the epidemics,
the individual diseases. He says these are transient excitations of the predisposition
usually of psora - the miasm psora - because we have a predisposition due to the
psoric miasm, acute manifestations can come after an exposure to cold, after a lot of
drinking alcohol, overheating, excessive exertion, mental excitation...
this is the most interesting excess in sensual enjoyment or deprivation of the same.
I don't know how an acute condition can develop after excess in sensual enjoyment
and even more deprivation of the same.
Deprivation of the sexual activity, that means the organism has a lot of hormonal
activity and cannot find an outlet, this can cause a febrile state.
I am not sure, I have not seen, maybe it exists but he mentions it
and I don't know under what conditions these people were living at the time.
What I may suggest for this is that if some young people are engaged in constant
sexual activity to the limit where they are totally exhausted most probably because
the organism is exhausted then will manifest a common cold or an acute condition.
But to attribute this to the deprivation is not understood.
We know deprivation of sexual urge gives a kind of symptomatology
which is many times akin to Conium.
If for one reason or another the person, especially the woman, cannot satisfy
her sexual appetite, then the most probable is to develop vertigos of no origin.
The labyrinths are Ok, there is no real focus for the vertigos and the vertigos are
quite strong and especially when lying down, when getting up from bed, when turning
in bed.
When you have this kind of vertigos together with deprivation of sexual urge...
In our books we say than Con. is indicated in women who have lost their husbands.
So they need to bring back the balance on that level, they need a dose of Con.
If you don't give Con. to such women, they cannot get over the problem,
whatever it might be. So Con. is a remedy not for acute.
Hahnemann says here they develop a febrile condition which as I said I don't know.
The excess of sexual enjoyment, we have other remedies, we know quite a lot of
remedies. The leading remedy is Platina but also Origanon, Stram., Hyosc., Bell.
They have excessive energy in general which affects the brain and they produce
the impulse of the individual to have sexual activity, a lot.
And the sexual activity is not satisfying them. Never mind how much
sexual activity they may have, they want some more, some more...
I remember a case with cancer with metastasis all over and when I realized that it was
a case of Plat. I asked her whether she was used to masturbate.
She said 40 times a day. It's really excessive. Why is that, it's another story...
"in reality but transient aggravations of latent psora". Attributes them to psora.
This is not absolutely accurate.
Today most of the organisms are coming from a background that has been affected
by gonorrhea, syphilis and by TB, so you cannot say only from psora but it is a way
of saying that such a condition is transient and it is going to go away.
"The second class includes sporadic diseases which attack several persons
simultaneously in isolated localities. They are engendered by meteoric or telluric
agencies, to the morbific influence of which, only few persons are susceptible
at a time." He goes very far. His observation is really impressive.
Today science has confirmed that the activity of the sun, when there are sun
explosions, are connected with the manifestation of certain diseases and epidemics.
For a man to write this in the year 1800 is really impressive.
And this is also something that a homeopath can notice.
I have noticed since many years that when you have a lot of patients to see,
not one or two a day but 10-20 a day or more, then you observe the prevalence
at a certain period of a certain pathology.
People come with ear problem, arthritic problems, stomach problems.
And it is true that I had this idea and then I found out that it has been confirmed
by science that this phenomenon happens.
"Next to this class come the epidemic diseases, which attack many persons at the
same time; they arise from the same cause, and individual cases resemble each other;
these diseases usually become infectious when they pervade crowded districts,
where they create fevers of a distinct kind; and as the cases of disease are of like
origin, they are also alike in their manifestations; but if left to themselves, they will,
within a limited period, terminate in recovery or death."
This is the definition of the acute. Never mind whether there is an epidemic or not.
When you have an acute, you have a bronchitis or a bronchopneumonia,
this will end either in lysis, if you let it alone, or in death.
The percentage of death is different for different febrile conditions.
Influenza has a percentage of deaths, bronchitis has another and
bronchopneumonia another and pneumonia has another.
In any case all these cases they have a prodromal period, an incubation period,
then we have the manifestation of the crisis and then we have the lysis either
by death or by cure.
I will say something now you may jump of your seats but unfortunately I have to say.
If humanity in general has been left alone without medications,
it would have automatically regulated what today we call the problem
of over population of the planet.
Automatically the epidemic diseases, the acute diseases would have killed so many
as they are born.
And the actual number of people living would be almost the same number
all along the years.
We have entered into this process of nature by our intelligence and we have
disturbed the overall balance of population in the planet.
What is it going to be the long term results of such interference, I do not know.
I do not know whether this interference will end up in extermination of the race.
There is such a possibility according to my understanding.
See the difference if Homeopathy was left alone to treat all acute and chronic
conditions. It would have 2 results.
The people would be much happier in general. The people who would stay alive.
And a lot more people would die. So a regulation of the population of the Earth
could be with a natural system of healing and automatically the population would
stay healthy with healthy minds.
What was happening in ancient Greece where all these ideas came down and were
distributed in the world and we could have an ideal world where would
prevail not the war but peace, not hatred but love.
Because if you give me Nux-v. I am not so much excited and attacking
and I can control myself and I can hear the other point of view.
But if I am in a state of Stramonium, I will not listen to anything.
And from such psychotic conditions as we have brought ourselves through the constant
suppression of diseases to the CNS, then the world will be much more balanced.
They would understand that the war is not in favor of anybody. But why there is war?
Because there are some minds which are sick.
What did they want these minds which are sick?
They want control, power, money to use for power.
Let us say, I will give you today 10 billion euros...
Do you think you will become more happy? You will be excited for one hour or two
and then you will go into deep depression and anxiety on how to increase these
money or how to keep these money. You will be the most unhappy people of the world.
I treated a lot of very wealthy people and I know what I am saying to you is a fact.
They have the appearance that they are happy.
I remember one who was telling me that he wanted to give a lot of money to
somebody who said why do you give me this? I don't need it.
But he says please take it. He said because I wanted to feel that I have done
something to feel some emotions. That I did a good thing and gave it to this person
and this person was very happy and I gave happiness to a person, maybe I could move
something in me, as far as feelings were concerned. Please take it.
I told you three cars have been given to me as a present.
The first car was given to me by a very rich man, one of the richest in Greece.
He came here to be treated and drove with him in my jeep, I had an old jeep.
He says has it any brakes? I said yes don't worry I have brakes and we can stop.
Then he called his secretary and said send George the blue jeep... it's from him.
I said thank you. I had no problem.
I have treated these people and I have seen their shortcomings.
He said to me I want you to promise that if I have cancer ever you will give me
something to kill me. We don't have such remedies. We have remedies only to heal.
The idea that he could go in suffering after such a luxurious life...
This is also interesting, we have to note, that the nature has its own laws of natural
selection. Therefore it has allowed certain diseases which we call epidemics to
be contagious. If there is an over population and there is an epidemic, a lot of people
will be infected and will die through the epidemic. So it's a natural selection.
Nature had to have some means to reduce the population and to keep the balance.
The epidemics were the tool of the nature to keep the number of the people living
on the earth in a balance state and increase but not an explosion of population.
Here we have an explosion of population.
The last 50 years from 3,5 billion we have come to 8 billion people.
It's a tremendous explosion. Due to what? Due to medicine.
So the question is why you don't like medicine if you can save so many lives?
The question is philosophically if you take it and you see the long run of this issue,
you end up in extermination of the human race.
The other way, natural selection, but you have the healing method that brings more
and more health to the people, eventually after 3-4 centuries
the human race is rectified, is becoming healthier and healthier.
The people who live, live in a healthy state and
a healthy individual cannot run into war, into crazy things...
cannot kill each other for a few arguments or for a few euros...
You see how wrongly the whole set up of the earth has been perceived and
everybody thinks medicine is correct because it saves my life.
Vaccination is correct because it eliminated smallpox... they don't see the long-term
effect and they don't see the underlying degeneration which is due to such practices.
If I put this lecture on the internet, I will make Homeopathy very popular.
But at the expense of my immediate termination. I like to do it.
My disease is this that I am provocative...
This is part of a disease of course, it is not totally healthy.
If you know what you are doing is going to kill you and you do it, then you are not
totally healthy even if what you did is saving the humanity.
Genius, you agree? Shall I put it on the Internet?
-No.
-Who says yes? 3,4...7. You want to preserve myself. I will not be preserved in any case.
For other reasons. Not because they will kill me.
But Homeopathy will become popular.
The idea will be discussed by all the media and will be in favor and against...
People who are controlling us, they will think what a good idea maybe we have to do it...
but we ourselves will take the real medicine so we can stay alive and all the others...
Since a long time I have this idea of writing an article on these matters.
But I have avoided so far. I don't know if... I can use a nickname?
By the time they want to find out, immediately they will find out who it is.
"It is a matter of regret that we are still obliged to count among chronic diseases
very common affections which are to be regarded as the result of allopathic treatment,
and the continual use of violent, heroic medicines, in large and increasing doses.
Examples of that kind are: the abuse of calomel, corrosive sublimate, mercurial
ointment, nitrate of silver, iodine and its ointments, opium, valerian, Peruvian bark
and quinia, digitalis, prussic acid, sulphur and sulphuric acid, the use of purgatives
persisted in for years, bloodletting, leeches, issues, setons...
[...]During this exhausting and deleterious treatment, the vital force is compelled,
in defense of life, to alter the entire organism.
Accordingly, it diminishes or increases the irritability, or sensibility of various parts..."
In this phrase he says something which if you are careful you should ask me a question.
The allopathic medicine of the time diminishes or increases the irritability.
The question you should ask is when the irritability is decreased isn't it a good thing?
They idea here is that the natural tendencies, parameters, qualities of the human
organism are different for each other. Some people are easily angered,
some others are more calm, some are very calm they never get angry.
There is a natural state of the human in healthy state which contains irritability,
certain amount of anxiety, concern for others.
Hahnemann knows that and knows that the increase of irritability or the diminution
of it is a pathology. Therefore we have to understand that each one of us has certain
qualities. One is very fast in his mind, perceives things very fast, the other takes longer
time, both are healthy.
If the natural irritability of a person becomes excessive, then it becomes a pathology.
Then you have to decrease and the remedy will decrease the excessive irritability.
Many times you put the question. What do you mean by irritability or anxiety?
Anxiety and irritability are possibilities our brain has in order to cope with life.
If we did not have the possibility of fear, you see a lion and you go to pet it and
he eats you up. Because there is no fear. If there was no the possibility of fear.
When there is no possibility of fear a lot of outrageous things could take place.
You are not afraid so you are in the brink of a wall and then you fall.
Therefore fear is needed. The moment that fear becomes a burden,
a limitation to your life, then it becomes pathology.
The moment that the anger becomes so great that becomes a limitation to your life,
then you need treatment. But you need the anger to react.
An organism who does not produce anger ever is a dead organism
and that means this organ or the place of the organ of anger which is a part in the brain
has been dulled, killed, exterminated due to chemical drugs you have been using.
See how simple it is? 250 years ago this man had perceived that, exactly.
It is a phenomenon which I have not seen in any Nobel Prize winners who are
supposed to be big minds. Big minds discover an enzyme which is going to be...
for the future of humanity if we cultivate this enzyme and give it back
to the organism, then we will have excessive results...
This never happens... the alternative Nobel Prize is more important.
There is a reason I say that.
In order they would give me the Alternative Nobel Prize, they were observing my life
for 7 years. And the idea is on this Prize how much you have benefited humanity.
Have you already benefited the humanity? Then we will give you the prize.
The Nobel Prize is not... whether you benefited or not it's not important.
What's important is to discover something new. I've told you many times.
The last, the 7th year they asked me for a report, what you have done this year and
I said to my secretary don't send them, they are never going to give it to me,
don't send the report. That year I was elected to get the Prize.
It's not the money because the money is a quarter of what the Nobel Prize is.
It's much less but it's the prestige that gave a lot of promotion to Homeopathy
and that was important. Anyhow the Nobel Prize is also good.
"[...] If not entirely prostrated, it is gradually and abnormally deranged,
according to the individual character of each drug.
During this exhausting and deleterious treatment, the vital force is compelled,
in defense of life, to alter the entire organism."
He says, if you inject things in the organism, the organism in order to be kept alive
it has to rearrange things within the organism. It means a multimillion changes in
the electrochemical, biochemical structure of the organism.
They have to adapt the bad function of the liver which is not producing this particular
product which is needed for the kidneys.
The kidneys have to rearrange themselves, the heart has to rearrange itself,
the calcium, the potassium has to be rearranged...
When there is a kidney failure, the kidneys are not functioning...
What is one of the most common side effects?
One is anemia which is produced and at the same time the increase of the potassium
in the organism which can bring a heart attack.
All these rearrangements were due to the fact that the person got gonorrhea, that
was treated through antibiotics and finally another gonorrhea and again antibiotics
and finally the breakdown of the kidneys. But in the meantime the organism tries
to survive and rearranges. Why does it raise the potassium level?
You understand that he has seen exactly that.
The organism has to rearrange in order to preserve life, so the person will not die.
And this is what we are practicing all the time. We inject, the organism rearranges
until one organ or another breaks down and that's the end.
"Accordingly, it diminishes or increases the irritability, or sensibility of various parts;
it produces hypertrophy or atrophy; softening or induration in certain organs, resulting
eventually in destruction, or, at least, in organic lesions (deformities) of external or
internal parts. These are some of the results of the efforts of nature to protect the
organism against complete destruction, to which it is exposed by the constant renewal
of aggressive treatment with pernicious substances."
Paragraph 75, "Instances of ruined health, resulting from allopathic treatment, are very
common in modern times. They constitute the most pitiable, and incurable of chronic
diseases..." He says something which is really scaring.
He says if somebody has taken repeatedly this kind of treatments,
eventually he becomes incurable.
"and it is to be feared that remedies will probably never be found, or invented for the
cure of such condition, when they have reached a certain degree of severity."
He had the same experience as we have when in the end stages of pathology
we cannot see the remedy. He says remedies will not be found.
Not these I know so far but even in the future. If you find more remedies, you will not
be able to find remedies that will cure damage done by chemical drugs.
You want to ask a question? Sure. If you want to ask a question, you have to ask.
Otherwise if we proceed and some questions stay in your mind, there is no meaning.
You come here to clarify, if you are interested. Can you come here?
Whoever wants to ask a question will come here to be a famous person
who will be videoed and will remain in the history of Homeopathy!
When you put a question, that means you contribute to the teaching
of a future medicine, which is going to overwhelm the world.
So you will become famous all over the world!
-I want to ask, Hahnemann says here that by allopathic treatment which leads
to chronic diseases, there is no healing treatment...
-There is no remedy that can heal such a condition.
-But I want to ask. Yesterday the small girl...
-The Still disease.
-She was sent to be treated by allopathic treatment and then she comes again and
can she be treated after that?
-I said that in this condition because it's progressed too far, we cannot discover
the indicated remedy. The remedy cannot be found in this condition.
Therefore we have to face the problem with the parents.
The parents say what shall we do? The child is in pain. You have to tell them what to do.
If you tell them I cannot do anything anymore, what they will most probably do is to
take the child to the hospital and the hospital will treat the child with violent medicine.
What I say further than that is that maybe due to the many remedies given,
the actual symptoms are masked and if through the giving of strong drugs, we can
kind of nullify or neutralize the effect of the homeopathic remedies given so far,
the child will come to a much more difficult condition.
She will be given drugs and after a while there is going to be a relapse.
That time when the relapse comes, there is a possibility we may recognize a clearer
picture in which case we may enter again starting the treatment.
I don't know if that will work. Most probably the child is incurable as far as
Homeopathy is concerned. But the child will remain alive, will not die but with a lot
of problems, mental, emotional and physical.
Especially if the physical problems of that child are eliminated,
she will have tremendous problems in mental and emotional condition.
If she is not treated homeopathically, she will go.
Now mentally/ emotionally she is quite... she was present, she was aware.
Mental and emotional state was perfect.
Let me see her after the allopathic treatment.
-I have an objection concerning the emotional health of this child.
Because she had a big aversion to her mother. It's a big emotional issue for a child of
7 years old. So I don't think she is emotionally healthy.
Perhaps this issue which we didn't emphasize very much in the analysis
is connected to her problem. That's what I think.
-I won't argue with you. But I still have to tell a few things concerning the depth
of the pathology. If the pathology goes inside into the mental and emotional,
you will see a totally different child altogether.
That will never be satisfied... depression, anxiety, panics.
The fact, you are right...
Let us say a person who has disgust.
Once she saw the fly going inside, she will never touch this.
I also don't feel nice if a fly is inside but my disgust is natural.
Her disgust for her mother is natural because her mother has behaved in such a way
that she has hurt her tremendously. I don't know details, maybe they can tell us,
but must be a mother which is a real... bitch.
Why does she like this particular cup?
I don't want to go over the time because I know you are...
-The old homeopathic schools all they say is that camphor oil can spoil
all the negative problems from wrong remedies...
I even tried it myself in case of pains with wrong remedies and really felt a relief
as if the pressure has gone away. This might be a solution.
-This is true. Either coffee or camphor could be used as antidotes.
But in this case she needs a really powerful shake in the organism to bring back
the original state. Camphor or coffee will not be sufficient.
This is my impression but this is also my experience.
I've seen this happening that after they have been taking allopathic drugs,
they come back in a very bad state, then I am able to see the remedy.
Paragraph 76, "It is only through homoeopathy that providence has vouchsafed to us
the means of curing natural diseases; but not those chronic external and internal
lesions and deformities, wantonly forced upon the human organism by unskillful
treatment, and pernicious medicines."
Hahnemann was claiming much less than we claim today that we can cure.
He said whether we have a deformity or we have internal lesions,
then forget about cure.
"...wantonly forced upon the human organism by unskillful treatment,
and pernicious medicines."
He says whatever has happened in an organism... that means he has tried and
found he could not cure. People who have taken a lot of the derivatives of mercury,
of opium, morphine he was not able to cure them anymore.
But it's very strange. When you talk with conventional doctors, the first thing
they will ask you is Homeopathy can cure cancer?
Wait a moment, before you reach cancer, all this hierarchy of diseases
you are not interested to cure? You are interested to cure only the cancer?
What is your results on cancer? Nothing, I don't cure cancer.
What about all the others? If you can cure cancer, then we are interested.
"Nevertheless, if proper measures are directed against the chronic miasm, perhaps
lurking in the system, the vital force might still be made to undo much of the mischief,
provided it had not been weakened by treatment to such an extent as to prevent it
from being undisturbed for a sufficient number of years, required for the
accomplishment of the enormous task." He says his experience is this.
When he has met with such cases he used other measures like correcting the food
intake, the mode of life and give the possibility of the organism to react, so he can bring
out some symptoms, on which he can base the prescription and sometimes it can...
He doesn't say cure anymore he says "might still be made to undo much of the
mischief".
I read from another 6th edition but a good translation by C. Wesselhoeft M.D.
This was published in 1917 by Boericke and Taffel in the U.S.
and it was an expensive book and then Jane Publisher produced the one that you have.
With Boericke translation which is different than this one.
"The art of healing is not, and never will be perfected so far, as to enable us to rectify
the countless ill effects so often observed after allopathic treatment".
This child which we saw he had all the kinds of vaccination, all kinds of antibiotics etc.
To undo this he was trying the poor man, he is one of the best homeopaths in
Germany, he was trying to counteract the damage that had been done.
The damage is not only what you see. You see the deformities.
The damage is in the system. The whole organism is damaged by this interference.
I will make another prediction that the race, because we are different races...
South Americans, Indians, North Americans, Canadians, Greeks, Germans...
The race will adapt the soonest Homeopathy as main treatment will be the one
that will survive finally after 2000 years.
After 2000 years few people will remain in the planet and these people will be using
only Homeopathy. It's easy to make such a prediction.
Who is going to live 2000 years to say George you are wrong.
But what is written now, it can continue for thousands of years.
Another 2000 years about the humanity will take before it can correct itself
with all the atrocities and the mistakes and the stupidities they have done.
I don't want to go into politics because...
I will read one more paragraph 77, "The name of chronic diseases does not apply to
those which are produced by constant exposure to avoidable noxious influences;
by indulgence in habitual excesses in eating, drinking, and various kinds of health
destroying debauchery; nor to those diseases which result from constant want of
the necessaries of life; unhealthy dwellings, particularly in marshy localities;
diseases peculiar to the inhabitants of cellars."
Here Hahnemann is not very accurate, I will tell you why.
"diseases peculiar to the inhabitants of cellars or other confined places, suffering
from want of fresh air and exercise; nor those which are the result of overtaxed
body and mind, or continued mortifications and trouble."
So he says you cannot call chronic disease, a disease which comes from overdrinking
that means from alcoholism.
If somebody lives in an unhealthy environment and he is sick because of that
you have to take into consideration, in order to understand this, two things.
First that most probably what he means here is that you cannot consider it as a chronic
condition, as long as once the conditions change, they will come back to health.
I don't know if he will say later on but this is most probably what he means.
That means as long as you have a pain in the knee because of the wetness in a cellar,
unless you bring out this man to the sun and live a normal life, if the organism can
by itself restore health, this is not considered a chronic condition.
But if this condition continues for some time... this is recorded, that's my problem.
Everyone will see I was playing with the flies! You excuse me because we have to
laugh sometimes. If you are very serious all the time, you will go to sleep.
If this condition continues for a long period of time, it will trigger the chronic
predisposition of the organism and then we will have the manifestation of a chronic
disease due to alcohol or bad living in an unhealthy environment etc.
There is a point where the organism in order to counteract or to survive has to bring up
a defense. This defense triggers the second line of defense
which is triggering the predisposition which is genetically ingrained into his body.
Hahnemann does not say exactly that. He says, this you cannot consider
as chronic but we must have in mind that if they continue too long,
they will trigger chronic conditions.
"Provided there is no other chronic miasm pervading the organism, unhealthy
conditions like the above, will vanish of their own accord, under an improved mode
of living, and they do not deserve the name of chronic diseases."