I think there is a question here.
"If a patient comes with chronic eczema and he were not in homeopathic
medicine previously, when we prescribe correct remedy to him, where do you
see aggravation generally? What kind of aggravation we may expect?"
What kind of aggravation we expect in a case where there is no previous remedy.
A person comes straight away to Homeopathy with an eczema to be treated.
The aggravation you will see in the eczema itself. And it can be one of these cases
where you can see really the aggravation in front of your eyes is with the eczema
patients.
First of all the eczema becomes bigger, then the itching for 1-2 days is more and then,
if the remedy is correct, the eczema will start going out from above downwards.
The eczema may all here on the arm and will end up the last months in the fingers.
This is the right direction. You are absolutely sure you have given the right remedy.
But there is an aggravation definitely.
Something else you have to be careful that these people who have severe eczemas,
they usually use creams to cover the itching and the eczema and before giving the
remedy, you have to tell him to stop the creams for a period of time, you may need
even one month without any medications before you see the real extent of the
eczema.
So he has to stay without any medication for 1 month and then take the remedy.
Otherwise you will have the following problem; you know you are expecting an
aggravation after the right remedy, then he stops the medication and the next day
he takes the remedy and there is aggravation.
Now after a month you don't know whether the aggravation was due to stopping
the cream or because of your remedy.
And then you have to wait 2-3 months to see that the eczema is not going well
in order to understand the remedy is wrong and you have to change it.
Come here. Everyone must come here so he can be on the video.
-What about if there is pus, they got an inflammation? When they stop the cortisone
if it is a severe eczema to see and the pus is coming... It's inflamed. They scratch...
-If stopping the cortisone you see a big aggravation, you give the remedy.
You don't have to wait for a month. That means the organism is strong and will give
out immediately, what was suppressed will come out immediately.
That is a good sign actually and you can give the remedy straight away
upon the aggravation, after stopping the cream.
-Also then what is your experience concerning potencies?
-Potencies in eczemas don't have to be very high. 200CH is a good potency for
an eczema, 1M and in relapses you may have to go higher.
But starting with 200CH is a good idea.
-I have 2 questions. The first is if people, because you said that we know that skin
eruptions are good, what about people who get artificial skin problems, for example
bee stings, have edemas...So are these people more protected than others to have
the pathology expressed on the skin?
Because they are stung and they have edemas. So these people are more healthy?
-When somebody is stung by a bee it can have a little pimple with a little pain and
scratch, it can have a bigger aggravation and can have also (some allergic people)
a total reaction and they can die. There are different reactions to the bee sting.
But as a general rule, if somebody has been bitten by a bee and has not died
that means he had the typical reaction, it is a good thing for the organism to be
bitten by bees. The problem is not to be bitten by 20 bees at the same time.
That is not good.
-The honey producers for example are bitten...
-They are immune usually to the bee sting and also they usually have a good
healthy organism. The beekeepers are a strange phenomenon...
All the beekeepers I have met they are balanced, down-to-earth people
with good emotion and happy life.
I am talking about the beekeepers who are fanatics. They like the bees very much.
These are the people whom I found out are good people, with good heart,
good organism, bitten by bees many times, no problem and it's good for them to be
bitten. I have bees also and I have been bitten several times and I am careful now
not to be bitten by the bees because maybe they will bite me around the eye and
my eyes will be closed. So I don't want to come here and you are scared.
One time I was bitten by the bee and I had to travel the next day to Holland,
where I had a seminar. I was bitten by the bee and the swelling was terrifying,
it closed my eyes and I said to the secretary I have to leave tomorrow but it's not
possible, I have to have an excuse because people are gathering after 2 days
in Holland for a seminar and I cannot go.
So please bring the camera and take my condition because it was becoming worse
and worse. In the meantime we found the camera, we prepared everything and
then while she was filming me, she said I see through the camera that it's
going away, because I have taken Apis before.
We wait, we take another picture later on, if it stays. Later on it was gone and
I travelled and they could not see anything. Apis helped me very much.
Apis is a very good remedy for that, as you all know.
And I can confirm it from my own experience.
-My second question, if we have an acute incident and we have a clear picture
of a remedy but suppose we don't have access to a remedy and we let the organism
go through the acute by itself.
Is it better to leave it like this or is it better to give the remedy?
Because sometimes we have a flu and we say Ok I won't get a remedy,
there is a clear picture and then it goes away by itself. Is it as good?
-It depends. Sometimes if the organism is weak, if you let an acute run,
it takes all the energy and there is a relapse.
If the organism is strong, there is no problem. You can let it go.
-Even in the second case where the organism is strong, is it better to leave it without
a remedy or is it better to give a remedy, since you have the picture?
-Give the remedy. There is one more question.
The caesarian section is very often done where it is not necessary.
How does the C.S. influence such babies? The C.S. often produced because of pelvic
presentation of a baby.
This breech presentation is something that you cannot avoid and maybe they have
to do it, the C.S. There are many times where a remedy given a few days before
birth, turns the child in a very impressive way to the right position.
And this is done mostly by Pulsatilla. Puls. has acted many times, this is our experience.
We are conducting at this moment a research in one of the public hospitals
in Athens but we don't have enough cases.
The Greeks who are here they can hear and send some cases of their own.
When there is a breech presentation and the time of birth is approaching,
it has to be over 34 weeks, they can send it to the "Aretaieon" where this program
is running.
-I have given Puls. in two occasions 200CH one dose and within 4 hours...
Both times it worked. The positions changed.
-I say this but I will tell you an example. How this information can be used wrongly.
A pregnant woman went to a Greek doctor, she had this problem.
He says don't worry I will speak to the child and will turn.
He gave the Pulsatilla and the child turned.
The patient thinks we are magicians. Ok he got the information, he can use it,
but use it properly.
Neither I said in every case of breech presentation this will happen.
It will happen in many cases, not in every case.
So he was so sure he will speak to the child, so the child will turn.
The trauma of the child because of this incision on the mother and I have not
information to tell you for sure that children are traumatized and have this or that.
You have. Can you speak? She is a pediatrician.
-There are studies which say that children born with C.S. have more allergic diseases.
Eczema, asthma, disorders in learning and attention and behavioral problems and
above all the most important thing is that with C.S. the brain of mother does not
produce the hormones that are necessary to bond with the child.
All these children cannot be bond with their mother and the opposite, the mother
cannot be related to the child. So we have many people who are not connected.
-Thank you. I like the passion. She is always passionate...
In my experience I have not connected that... why the child is born with this or that.
That's why I ask. This is very good information what she says.
That the mother will not go through the whole process, so the hormonal balance
will not be completed, it will stop in a way if the child goes out prematurely.
I have heard cases where they said that the gynecologist was busy because he had
to go to a party at 11 o'clock and the woman had to deliver until 10 the latest.
So he gave some injections and the woman delivered at 10 p.m.
There are such cases, it's not me who criticizes,
everybody criticizes this kind of behavior.
Italian, come here. What is your name?
-Sara. My question is if we give a homeopathic remedy but we don't see
an aggravation, but all the symptoms go away in a small period,
how can we distinguish between a suppression or a good remedy given?
-That is a good question.
If there is a suppression, the relapse will be within a few days.
That means the amelioration will last 10, 15 days and then the whole thing will be
back. If what you said is correct, because you said all the symptoms are gone,
that means that the remedy was correct when all symptoms are gone.
Because in partially indicated remedies, not all symptoms are gone,
some symptoms are gone.
All symptoms are gone that means without aggravation, it means the person belongs
in the uppermost levels 1,2 where the organism is quite healthy, the pathology is not
deep and there is no perceptible aggravation.
There is always an aggravation but they don't pay attention in these levels.
They say there was no aggravation.
But as the levels go down and the pathology becomes more serious,
then the aggravation is there.
When they tell me I have never seen an aggravation, there are two things.
Either you see very healthy people or you don't give the right remedy.
Either of the two is valid. You have to see the aggravation.
I should read to you, according to what you said, an email I received, just saw it today.
He says I am not in Alonissos, he's a person who is coming to Alonissos, I should cry,
but I do not cry because I have the Vithoulkas Compass and the effect I see with V.C.
now confirms what you have been teaching all along with aggravation,
with symptoms coming back. Now I can see it.
Of course he is a homeopath since 15 years but he had never seen
the initial aggravation, symptoms coming back, so he is surprised.
He says my god this is a fantastic tool.
When I hear people saying you drink coffee, there is no problem... No more questions.
Paragraph 81, "The fact that this extremely ancient infecting agent
has gradually passed..." Infecting agent probably he means scabies (psora) because
scabies is the skin eruption that is infecting.
"...  The fact that this extremely ancient infecting agent has gradually passed,
in some hundreds of generations, through many millions of human organisms.."
He claims here something which is unbelievable but unfortunately it is true.
You see Medorrhinum and you suspect he has been infected by gonorrhea
so you ask were you infected with gonorrhea? They say no, your father? No.
So yet the infection could have been a few generations behind, a bad infection
that remained in the genes of one generation after the other. This is what he says.
The scabies, the psoric miasm, which has been suppressed, remained in the human
organism for millions of generations.
It is difficult to perceive this aspect but I am afraid it is true.
"...and has thus attained an incredible development, renders it in some measure
conceivable how it can now display such innumerable morbid forms in the great
family of mankind, particularly when we consider what a number of circumstances
contribute to the production of these great varieties."
You remember my problem was, now he had a problem himself, he says how and
tries to give an answer. How comes since we all have the basis, which is the same,
the miasm, we have such a variety of pathologies? Let us see what he will say.
"Some of these causes that exercise a modifying influence on the transformation
of psora into chronic diseases manifestly depend sometimes on the climate and
the peculiar physical character of the place of abode,
sometimes on the very great varieties in the physical and mental training of youth,
both of which may have been neglected, delayed or carried to excess,
or on their abuse in the business or conditions of life, in the matter of diet
and regimen, passions, manners, habits and customs of various kinds."
He puts himself the question that I was putting yesterday and he gives the answer
how comes it is because of environmental circumstances and also educational,
how the people were raised by their parents, depends on what direction
the pathology will take when it's manifested.
"...great varieties of chronic diseases (secondary symptoms of psora)"
So all these pathologies are considered as secondary symptoms of psora.
"...besides the indescribable diversity of men in respect of their congenital corporeal
constitutions, so that it is no wonder if such a variety of injurious agencies,
acting from within and from without and sometimes continually, on such a variety of
organisms permeated with the psoric miasm, should produce an innumerable variety
of defects, injuries, derangements and sufferings, which have hitherto been treated
of in the old pathological works, under a number of special names, as diseases
of an independent character."
So this is one of the most advanced ideas of Hahnemann.
He dares to say that though the background is the same due to different factors
the direction of pathology takes different ways depending on the character
of the upbringing, of the environment etc.
There is something else. Now, you have to connect it with that.
You know that all individuals are unique. No one is the exact duplicate of another.
There is a proof for that.
Fingerprint, correct. If you put your fingerprint it doesn't fit with anybody else's.
That means every organism, 8 billion people are different from each other
and that's why the fingerprint is different from one another.
Because the fingerprint most probably is the overall picture of the structure
of the organism. Showing the character, showing the disease, the health etc.
The fingerprints if studied maybe they could reveal better than the genetic code
the predisposition to diseases.
I give ideas for the researchers.
Now I expect that somebody will have an objection. Which should be it?
Many times I've asked myself what is the difference between my observations
and the observations of so many millions of doctors who have not discovered
what I have observed. What is the difference?
I found out a few years ago that I never accepted anything they told me or they
taught me before I pass it through my own critical mind and see whether
that was really logical or it can be true or not. So I told you an idea.
I said 8 billion people are different from each other. We prescribe individually, we say.
Therefore we should have ideally 8 billion remedies for each one of the individuals
of this earth. Is this correct? No, what I say is logical.
If we maintain that we treat on the individual basis and not on a massive basis,
that means we find the individual remedy, the remedy that the organism needs,
so do we have so many remedies... Boericke Materia Medica has 870 remedies.
And some different people they have added and make it 2000-3000 remedies
that we may say we have available. In practice we use 250 remedies
with a probability of 1 in 10000 to go over these 250 remedies.
So what happens? Why people are cured?
I put these questions myself but I don't know the answer.
I left you with a problem. I understand.
Paragraph 82, "Although, by the discovery of that great source of chronic diseases,
as also by the discovery of the specific homoeopathic remedies for the psora,
medicine has advanced some steps nearer to a knowledge of the nature of the
majority of diseases it has to cure, yet, for settling the indication in each case of
chronic (psoric) disease he is called on to cure, the duty of a careful apprehension
of its ascertainable symptoms and characteristics..." I lost track.
It's beyond belief the train of thought. I have to read it three times before
I can follow it. "...is as indispensable for the homoeopathic physician as it was
before that discovery, as no real cure of this or of other diseases can take place
without a strict particular treatment (individualization) of each case of disease
- only that in this investigation some difference is to be made when the affection is
an acute and rapidly developed disease, and when it is a chronic one; seeing that,
in acute disease, the chief symptoms strike us and become evident to the senses
more quickly, and hence much less time is requisite for tracing the picture of the
disease and much fewer questions are required to be asked, as almost everything is
self-evident, than in a chronic disease which has been gradually progressing for
several years, in which the symptoms are much more difficult to be ascertained."
In a few words he says that before the discovery of the psora things were different.
Now we have discovered the remedies that could affect the effects of psora.
The effects of psora are of 2 types; one, acute diseases, mostly he means
epidemics which have similar characteristics and (two) the chronic conditions
which they do not have similar characteristics and they need more careful
individualization. He says in acute diseases we have similar symptoms and maybe
we can find 3-5 remedies that fit this acute.
But in chronic we have to search much more because the difficulty is much greater
in finding out the individual symptom that each one has in chronic diseases.
Paragraph 83, "This individualizing examination of a case of disease, for which
I shall only give in this place general directions, of which the practitioner will bear
in mind only what is applicable for each individual case, demands of the physician
nothing but freedom from prejudice and sound senses, attention in observing
and fidelity in tracing the picture of the disease."
He says in order to find the individual picture of the patient
the first thing you have to have in mind is that you should not be prejudiced.
By prejudice he means that...
A doctor knows that when you have a cough the lungs are suffering.
So you have a cough, you have a bronchitis. That is a prejudice.
That means because you know certain things, you project them and you do not
observe objectively. You do not wait to see really what is going on with the patient
in order to find out which are the individual characteristics of each case.
You say Ok I know. The same thing we are doing projecting many times especially
those who like the psychoanalysis of Homeopathy...
You see Homeopathy allows you to psychoanalyze, project, say
I am sure this person had no fears but I am sure he has fears because
when I asked him if he has fears, he moved his head to the right.
There are people who are doing this. This is a prejudice.
This is not looking upon the facts in an unprejudiced manner and with good
observation. "...freedom from prejudice and sound senses"
that means you should be logical
"attention in observing and fidelity in tracing the picture of the disease."
Fidelity, that means you don't write down symptoms that the person does not have.
Sometimes you want to make a picture of Calc. and you say...
I remember some cases that were brought here with teachers from different
places. There was a teacher from America and she had the case on the video and
she was investigating the case and she would say you have this symptom and
the person would hesitate to answer. You have the symptom, don't you have it?!
The person would say I think I have. That is very nice!
You can do anything you like and then conclude that the remedy was Nat-p.
Let's now see the follow up.
She says you are better. I can see you are better.
Maybe yes, I am better. You are better! Yes I am better. It's unbelievable.
I said why do you have to ask so many times you are better?
Let the patient say whether he is better or not. Maybe he wants to hide he is better.
There are other ways you can find out if he tells you lies but if you push an idea to
the patient, he is in a subordinate position... That means you are the authority and
he does not know anything. So if you say, I am better that means the doctor knows
better, maybe I am better. And if you push this idea, you push everybody say
I'm better... This is not fidelity and it is not sound senses and you are in the clouds.
Par.84, "The patient details the history of his sufferings; those about him tell
what they heard him complain of..."
It is a part of investigation that we don't practice, calling the relatives of the person
and ask them to tell us how he behaves.
It is something that Hahnemann had realized that it is an important part of
case taking. I have a very recent example of a schizophrenic boy who was sent
to me from Europe. His father is in a big position in Europe.
With his mother and the boy. I talked with the boy, I took the case,
I talked to the mother, the mother gives me some information
and I say Ok I could not make out really the case, so I said most probably the remedy
is this. I wrote back to his father who is a medical doctor.
Not a homeopath, the opposite, does not believe in Homeopathy.
But it does not matter. I wrote to him this is most probably the remedy.
You take it in this way. But I would like to know if you can give me this, this and
that information. He wrote me back and as soon as I read the information
I sent an urgent message don't take the remedy, there is a mistake,
I will give you another remedy. So it was very important.
The mother, like all the mothers, brought a child who is totally autistic and they
presented as if nothing is wrong with the child. The child is so good and
he is never sick and he is so healthy.
You need the details of the pathology. You cannot get it because the mother has
this protective attitude and not to say a bad thing about the child.
That the child who is 14 years old still soils his pants because he does not know to go
to the toilet, for instance.
They hide facts of that type. This mother did not tell me.
The father says this child several times he has attacked the mother, has hit badly
the mother, he goes out in the streets, he fights and hits the people, he sees
mirrors, he breaks them... All these was hidden by his mother.
How could I prescribe? And the father fortunately, when I wrote to him
I suspected Stram. but I prescribed Phos. I suspected maybe there is a possibility
of a Stram. case. Then I asked the father specific questions.
He says he is terrified from dogs. I said Ok forget Phos. take Stram.
So Hahnemann knew the importance of taking information from relatives.
Here it's very difficult when a grown-up somebody comes... You cannot call
the brother, the mother etc. to give you information, they cannot come
from Mexico please come and tell me if your son is aggressive or irritable.
It's not possible but the right thing is this. Call and get an impression.
"...of how he has behaved and what they have noticed in him; the physician sees,
hears, and remarks by his other senses what there is of an altered or unusual
character about him."
When a person gives his case and he gives his mental emotional symptoms,
when you say describe me your character, very few people can be objective and
give you objective symptoms.
Then what you have to find out is what out of his normal character is now
abnormally strong or on the contrary has been diminished.
If he says I used to be perceiving things very fast but now my mind is dull,
you have to take it into consideration.
But if a dull person says I used to be dull but now - like the Verat. - my mind is active
and thinking all the time... And this is what we consider as pathology
on mental/ emotional level, what is gone out of the normal of a person.
But the normal of the person is not the same in everyone.
Not everyone is irritable. There are people who are not irritable at all.
But there are people who are angered with the least provocation.
If you say you have been all your life like that, that means this is the character.
But if he says after the 25th year I became intolerant, I cannot accept any kind of
offense. If somebody offends me even a little bit, I close up and don't want to see
him, I leave etc. This is beyond his normal. Then you take it into consideration.
He says here if you understood "what there is of an altered or unusual character
about him" that you have to write down.
"...He writes down accurately all that the patient and his friends have told him in
the very expressions used by them." This is also something very important.
To use the same expression and have it written and then when you reexamine
he will say an expression in the beginning of the taking of the case like...
I'm terribly irritable. You reexamine now. How is your irritation? Still there.
How much? You have written "terribly irritable person".
You examine here and you see he is not that irritable. His expression is much different
than when he said I am terribly irritable person. You have to take that into
consideration. Sometimes you will be lead to wait on a remedy because of a remark
of that type. Because the irritability is less, because the depression is less.
Though he says I still have the depression, a month after I've given Aurum, you still
have the depression but how much? The patient does not want to misguide you.
But he is eager to get rid of the problem as soon as possible.
So he is eager to give him another remedy that will take away what he is suffering
from. So he tries to persuade you to give him another remedy.
If you do it, you lose the thread.
"Keeping silence himself he allows them to say all they have to say, and refrains
from interrupting them unless they wander off to other matters."
He comes to such details. He says call a friend of his, ask him what do you think
about your friend, how he behaves and the person starts saying how he sees
his friend. He says if the patient tries to interfere you say shut up.
Don't allow him to talk. Let the other person talk unless he wanders, instead of
talking about his character, he goes to the football game we had with Germany
and we lost and Germany won... What about your friend? He likes soccer, my friend
likes football and now he is sad most probably because we lost from the Germans.
No, wait a moment, stop him. Otherwise you let him talk without allowing
the patient to interfere with the observations of the other person.
That can only happen with Germans.
With the Greeks it would be very difficult. Me? I am like this?
Do you really believe that I am like that? I never thought that you have not
understood me all the life we are friends! This kind of reaction is of no use.
"The physician advises them at the beginning of the examination to speak slowly,
in order that he may take down in writing the important parts of what the speakers
say." He goes into such details that look ridiculous but actually in practice they are
very useful advices. Wait, because I have to write everything you say.
"He begins a fresh line with every new circumstance mentioned by the patient or
his friends, so that the symptoms shall be all ranged separately one below the other.
He can thus add to anyone, that may at first have been related in too vague
a manner, but subsequently more explicitly explained." It's unbelievable.
He says write one symptom in a line so you have space to add more explanation
in case there is later, they come back to the symptom and they explain.
This kind of detailed person he was.
Most probably he did not have the heavy load of patients that we have to deal with.
There was a time when there were 10 doctors working and I had to go from one
consulting room to another and in 3 minutes prescribe by 10, it makes half an hour
when I start again. It was very difficult...
-I have one question about aggravation.
What is your experience, do you see aggravation in acute cases?
-That means you were not listening all this time...You have all the time this in your
mind to ask of the acute case is aggravated or not...
I shall give you the answer in order to peace your mind and attend the rest of
the lecture. Say it again. You want to know the quality of the aggravation
or whether there is any aggravation in the acute?
-Because my experience is that sometimes when the acute is intense
there is no perceptible aggravation and the patient is...
If we have a patient with very intense, acute complaints, for instance high fever
or intense pains and we give a remedy, the patient goes immediately towards
amelioration. But sometimes when we have a case of something intense
like colics in children, sometimes that is quick and very intense aggravation.
My question is if you have the same experience in acute cases
that there are some cases that is not perceptible aggravation.
-That's correct. In some cases there is no perceptive aggravation... but what
may happen is for instance in a case of influenza, where there is 39 C fever,
there are pains, headaches etc. You give the remedy and you find out that for
an hour the headache becomes much more, while at the same time
the fever is dropping down. This is correct.
In acute cases especially if you give the remedy at the peak of the acute disease,
you will find no aggravation. If you give the remedy before the peak,
you will see the patient will feel the aggravation.
We can go to the next generation.
Par. 86, "When the narrators have finished what they would say of their own accord,
the physician then reverts to each particular symptom and elicits more precise
information respecting it in the following manner; he reads over the symptoms
as they were related to him one by one, and about each of them he inquires
for further particulars, e.g., at what period did this symptom occur?"
On this paragraph it is based what we try to do with the computer (Compass)...
That means when you have some basic symptoms, you will be able to ask more details
about that symptom. That means the program will give you the questions;
he has thirst, you notice "I'm thirsty" you go back and the system will give you
5 questions concerning the thirst, is thirst for large quantity...?
He says you have the main symptoms, you go back and you tell you are thirsty.
Are you thirsty for cold water? Are you thirsty for large quantities? Small quantities?
The Compass will do exactly that. We are programming all the time improving this.
"Was it previous to taking the medicine he had hitherto been using? While taking the
medicine?...at what period did this symptom occur? Was it previous to taking the
medicine he had hitherto been using?" Because he had the problem to separate
symptoms that belonged to the drugs the person he was taking already and
his natural reaction of the disease.
So whether the symptom he relates now was before the drug he was taking or it's
after the drug? That means that symptom belongs to the drug and not the disease.
"What kind of pain, what sensation exactly, was it that occurred on this spot?
Where was the precise spot? Did the pain occur in fits and by itself, at various times?
Or was it continued, without intermission? How long did it last? At what time of the
day or night, and in what position of the body was it worst, or ceased entirely?
What was the exact nature of this or that event or circumstance mentioned -
described in plain words?" Hahnemann describes the real situation of the real
circumstances in which he was living. And these were the circumstances.
People were suffering mostly with physical diseases and he was trying to find
the peculiarities in the modalities of the physical problems. That's why he insists so
much in the physical symptoms and what are the details of such symptoms.
Today that all the diseases have been pushed most to the mental/ emotional side
we have to get information from that side as well, combine it with the physical
symptoms. The work that we have to do is quite different now.
First of all we have to study a different Materia Medica than Hahnemann was writing
because that M.M. was only mental symptoms. Did not constitute a whole.
So when Kent came he gave a whole picture. Like when he describes Puls., Nat-m.
Later on when I came I gave more information about mental/ emotional
symptomatology and then all crazy people added all crazy things.
You can imagine if somebody uses his imagination instead of facts, what he can add
in the M.M. He can add a whole lot.
When I was teaching in America, I was telling if you continue with this idea of using
imagination and not the real facts... What they were doing is...
They got a case of Berberis and they talk with the person and the person has his own
personality and gives the characteristics of his personality.
They write them down and when they go to a seminar they say Berb. will be like this
and they describe the patient who had a kidney problem and because there was a
characteristic of the type of pain that goes around you gave Berb. and the pain went
away. But this has nothing to do with the characteristics of the personality of the
person who had said my personality is this or that and never changed.
Because personality traits do not change. What changes is when I am a person,
who is easily offended by nature, if this becomes extreme, then it is a problem.
Then when I take a remedy this extreme sensitivity to offense goes down.
Still I am easily offended. I don't say I am totally different.
Unless he was totally indifferent before and he became very easily offended
which can be also.
But you have to realize that if you treat a case and you have written down
all the characteristics of that person and then you go and present the characteristics
of the person as the characteristics of the remedy, you can imagine what happens.
In 10 cases of Berb. that you will have 10 different personalities describing their
personality without you realizing these are not symptoms but only characteristics
of the personality and you go in a Congress or a Seminar and you give it out as
information about the mental/emotional picture of Berb. and you describe
the characteristic personality of the person who is healthy in that respect,
he has no problem on the mental/ emotional level, he had only pain in the kidneys.
If you do that you can understand what it is going to happen in the M.M.
It will be a total confusion, every M.M., every remedy will have all
the symptoms existing in the earth.
Paragraph 87, "And thus the physician obtains more precise information
respecting each particular detail, but without ever framing his questions so as to
suggest the answer to the patient..." You have this. If you say to the patient
you have this, the patient will say most of the times, yes I have this.
The best thing is ask; are you thirsty or not? You give a chance to tell you the truth.
"...so that he shall only have to answer yes or no; else he will be misled to answer in
the affirmative or negative something untrue, half true, or not strictly correct,
either from indolence or in order to please his interrogator".
Some people give an answer. No, I did not ask you, suppose that you are thirsty
say, yes I am thirsty. Are you thirsty? Yes, I am thirty. And you see the eagerness
yes, I am thirsty. You see this does not sound correct.
How many glasses do you drink? I drink 3-4 glasses a day. This is no thirsty.
But he thought if he gives you this information in a positive manner, it will help you to
find the remedy but actually it does not help you, sidetracks you to lose the remedy.
"...from which a false picture of the disease and an unsuitable mode of treatment
must result."
This kind of interrogation is really thorough but on the other hand
if you go and follow it in a very typical manner, I will tell you what happens
because I have the experience with all the doctors working with me.
In the Centre we had some doctors, we specified 1 hour for taking the case.
2 of them they specified 3 hours for a case. They said to the secretary for me
when you arrange a new case give me 3 hours. So they wrote everything.
I went to read the case to prescribe. Because I had to read the case and prescribe.
I almost invariably did not know what the remedy is.
While others they have understood that the most peculiar are the things
which are concerning us and guiding us and had underlined the peculiarities of
the case and I go and I see the underlines, I just have an overview and write
the remedy. The other one, I tried hard, many times the remedy was wrong.
Yet it was a typical, exact, detailed case taking. So you have to combine.
Later on in paragraph 153, he will explain the importance of keynotes.
So we are looking for keynotes together with the overall picture.
There is another problem. Today we see cases with a lot of layers.
That means each layer underlying pops up one of its symptoms.
So you may have the main layer uppermost but popping up few symptoms of
the underlying layers and we have a big problem because the cases that we see
are such that have deep pathology on a mental/ emotional level.
So if you start writing down everything, not realizing then all the different layers
become one report without differentiating.
You don't have the impression that now this symptom is important and
I have to write it down and I have to take notice of that symptom.