Paragraph 65, It's the after effect and the curative effect. This is understood.
Primary effect, secondary effect... The primary accepts,
the secondary is the reaction of the vital force and these are the symptoms
which are developing during the reaction of the vital force.
But for a proving we do not separate primary and secondary.
We take down everything and this constitutes the picture of the remedy.
"Examples of the first instance referred to are familiar to everybody.
A hand bathed in hot water is at first much warmer..." He gives an example.
You put your hand, first you burn, then it becomes red, then the secondary effect
is to become white. If you put your hand in hot water.
"A person heated by violent bodily exercise (primary effect) afterwards feels
chills and rigors (secondary effect). To one who was yesterday heated by drinking
much wine (primary effect), today every breath of air feels too cold (counter effect
of the organism, secondary effect)."
And he goes on giving examples of primary and secondary reactions of the organism.
"A conspicuous opposite or after effect is imperceptible during the action of very
minute homeopathic doses of alternative potencies in a healthy body although
minute doses when closely observed may be seen to produce a perceptible
primary effect the living organism sets up only so much counter effect as is required
for the reestablishment of the normal condition."
Because if you give a potency there is no material substance so the primary effect
is not perceptible. What is perceptible? It's only the secondary effect.
So when you take a homeopathic remedy, for instance you want to do a proving
and you take a dose of 200CH or 30CH. You will feel nothing.
But if you are sensitive to this, after a few hours, days, you may have
some symptoms of the proving.
But the primary effect is not there because of the minuteness of the dose.
-So we prescribe on both primary effect and secondary effect, right?
-All material drugs have primary and secondary effect.
The high potencies can have secondary effects in a proving.
-But say if it's a virus infection and the virus had an effect, we take both.
Whatever virus did and whatever body responding to the virus, right?
Or say a person was bitten by a snake, the snake venom affected the body
very strongly...
-The primary effect is the pain. The secondary is when the blood is poisoned and
then becomes swollen.
-Why is it not a primary effect of the venom of the permeability of the blood vessel?
-He calls it primary and secondary because he has noticed that in certain drugs,
if you take a drug, the primary effect could be this, the secondary effect could be
the opposite.
-We prescribe on both, right?
-We prescribe on both because we have the picture of the proving from primary and
secondary effects.
The MM is consisted of primary and secondary effects.
But do not pay too much attention to this, it is not important.
It doesn't differentiate anything in the prescription of a remedy.
Hahnemann is very precise and he wants to put everything into order and
that is why he says all that.
"These incontrovertible truths, which spontaneously offer themselves to our notice
and experience, explain to us the beneficial action that takes place under
homoeopathic treatment; while, on the other hand, they demonstrate the perversity
of the antipathic and palliative treatment of diseases with antagonistically
acting medicines."
He continues to hammer the idea don't give palliative remedies.
Try to give a remedy that covers the totality of the symptoms.
"We learn from homeopathic cures that after the extinction of the natural disease
there is up to linger in the system a remnant of the drug disease and gendered by
the minute doses of medicine required by this method of cure and which were
just sufficient to overcome and to supersede dissimilar natural disease
by the similitude of their symptoms."
What it means here? According to his experiments and his ideas,
his method of prescribing by this time he was prescribing low potencies.
Sometimes the low potency due to the sensitivity that the remedy has to
the organism will leave some effects of its own on the patient.
He will call this aggravation later on.
"But we also learn that this remnant of drug disease is very transient"
but what is left over as a result of the remedy given is going away.
"and vanishes easily and quickly on account of the extreme minuteness of the dose"
because the dose is very little this effect is going away.
"This prevents the vital force from being aroused to a greater degree of
counteraction against this slight artificial effect that is required for the restoration
of feeling to the standard of health."
This prevents the vital force from being aroused...
He says the vital force because of the minuteness of the dose is not interested
to be aroused and counteract the effect.
That's why the effect will stay for a while and then it will go away by itself.
This is what he means here.
"That is for the purpose of complete recovery the vital force needs to make but
a slight additional exertion to overcome the effects of the medicine
after the extinction of the disease."
Still underneath is his idea that he has given a similar but stronger disease and
his idea is that once this is stronger, it's going to leave some effect on the organism.
And this little effect because of the minuteness of the dose will be transient
and the vital force has to do very little effort to get rid of what is left over from
the remedy that was prescribed. Has anybody understood? Genius?
"In the antipathic (palliative) mode of treatment, however precisely the reverse
of this takes place. The medicinal symptom which the physician opposes to
the disease symptom (for example, the insensibility and stupefaction caused
by opium in its primary action to acute pain) is certainly not alien, not allopathic
of the latter."
He speaks with his own experience by that time.
What was the main painkiller they had at their disposal? Opium.
So he had noticed the effect of it. The primary effect of it is to make the person
stupid, so he does not understand anything, not even the pain.
On account of this the patient does not feel the pain but he says later on the pain
will come in a greater force. Therefore Opium has not actually cured the pain.
It suppressed the pain and in the effect of the Opium, the organism will make
a big effort to get rid of the Opium effect.
He compares the 2 systems. One we give very minute dose and if something
is left over because of the dose, the organism makes a small effort and gets rid of it.
If you prescribe with the idea of opposites, you will give Opium, you suppress
the pain, you suppress the whole organism actually, the organism does not feel
the pain but later on the effect is gone, the organism gets rid of the effect of Opium
and the final effect is the relapse of the pain.
The Organon is a book that was written during that time where all this kind of
treatment was used and he had to write in a German way which needs details
to be persuaded and he writes mostly these details for his colleagues who were
going to criticize what he was doing.
And that's why he goes so meticulously.
The important points in the Organon are few.
But in any case whatever he says is absolutely true, even he had no idea of what
was coming later on as chemical drugs.
He gives all the background of what happens today when people are taking
chemical drugs. His observations were the observations of a genius.
"The extinction of the disease symptom is in this case to be accomplished by an
opposite drug symptom which is quite impossible.
It is true that the antipathic medicine acts upon the same diseased region of the
body and with the same degree of certainty as the homeopathic medicine selected
on account of its similar morbific effect but the formal being an opposite to the
symptom of the disease it only obscures the latter and render is imperceptible for
a short time". Again the same idea.
You give the opposite, you push the disease and then disease comes back.
"The vital force perceives no disagreeable sensation neither from the symptom
of the disease nor from that of the opposite drug during the first moment of the
effect produced by the opponent palliative because both appear to have cancelled
or to have dynamically neutralize each other the benumbing power of Opium seems
to neutralize this pain."
He just talks about the obvious thing and how Opium...
What he says actually is that Opium is not a curative agent.
It's an agent which suppresses the disease for a while or the pain and benumbs the
organism and then the pain comes back.
"During the first minutes of palliative effect, the vital force feels as if in health
perceiving neither the benumbing effect of Opium nor the pain of the disease."
For a while the patient feels he is quite good. This is what happens today...
And how dangerous it is. What is an equivalent of what he says here
with what we know to happen in our modern societies.
What drugs?
-Recreational.
-Mostly heroine.
Those who take heroine they feel so well for a certain short period of time.
They feel so good on the top of the world and then of course there is a relapse of
their sadness, depression and bad feelings to the extent that they need another
dose and another dose... until they die.
It's not the same with antidepressants? This is a good question.
What is the antidepressant? It's a drug which has been regulated in each dose
to stimulate the brain in producing opiates, serotonin but in a controlled way.
If you give, from these antidepressant drugs, a huge dose, it will be like taking
heroine or like taking opium in big doses.
But the difference with the drugs is the controlling of the dose.
That's why the psychiatrists who prescribe these drugs usually they say
it is not going to act immediately.
You need a few days before you can feel the effect.
They say keep on taking it though there is no effect.
For 2-3 days the patient feels no change. Why? They want to raise the amount
of opiates - morphine or whatever- derivatives of opium, most probably all of these..
until the level is raised in the blood to such an extent as to create the desired effect.
That means to substitute the normal flow of serotonin in a human being
who is in joy or in happiness.
I am not an expert in this but anyhow I have a general idea.
What I know is this, students who want to excel in their examinations
they used to take, I don't know if they do it today, but 50 years ago
they used to take ephedrine and the mind became so lucid and all the information
comes and they can write fantastic exams.
As a result such persons they are damaged for life.
They can become even psychotic eventually, they are not able to concentrate.
They have what they call an attention deficit disorder.
For these discoveries that neurophysiology has done the recent 30 years
which are quite impressive how the brain functions and how you can interfere with
the brain. I remember perhaps 50 years ago they were doing experiments with
electrodes where they connected them in the brain and they stimulated the brain
to produce happiness.
That means they have found the place in the brain which is responsible
for these feelings, I don't know exactly which place...
but they have found, they put the electrodes and they stimulated and the people
were in happiness.
If they did that for some period of time, the persons could be damaged for life.
His observations are nothing else but what we know today to be the effect
of heroine. Heroine is a derivative of opium.
Can you repeat please? It's a derivative of opium.
-Heroine and morphine is a derivative of opium.
-Can I ask you a question? Why so many teenagers commit suicide when they are
put on those serotonin reuptake inhibitors... why are teenagers different from adults?
More of them commit suicide then.
-Teenagers who take what? Antidepressants.
-Why do you think?
-I don't know. This is the first time I hear these statistics. I have to think about it.
But if it is true I don't know. But it is a well-known fact that if somebody is on a
psychotherapy with such drugs [talking in Greek searching for the right word]
...Ok, during the therapy with drugs.
It is a well-known fact that for a certain period of time, when the person comes out
of the depression, that is the time they commit suicide. This is an established fact.
Now if you say why, it is very easy to get the answer.
The answer is the same as we say all along that a symptom is produced in order
to save the life of the person. Any symptom, anxiety, depression is produced
in order to prevent a much worse situation.
It's the defense of the organism. So the organism says put this person
in depression, otherwise he will commit suicide.
Now you come in an artificial way and you take out the depression.
You bring the person face to face with the problem that brought him
to the depression. If the problem had not been resolved and they suddenly face
again the problem in reality, they cannot stand it and commit suicide.
That's the explanation. Is it clear?
-I have a question for the ephedrine you said. You said 50 years ago students
took ephedrine for being better in the exams and you said they destroyed...
-They destroyed part of the brain. This is a general rule. I want you to understand.
You stimulate a portion of the brain, if you stimulate it too much,
you make it work that point, you force it to work but in the end it may be
destroyed totally. It's like a machine overworking full speed and you burn it.
So you burn the area of the brain which you force through a chemical to overwork.
-My question is that is there any chance by homeopathy to recover?
-It's very difficult.
-Because on the other side there are so many students I know they take Ritalin
or cocaine and things like these to pass the examination and a lot of them have
been using marijuana where they were pupils in younger age, so they have a lot
of problems to concentrate and they sit there and they get mixed up totally.
So now in Germany I know from a lot of my patients and my sons they take Ritalin,
you know Retalin?
-I know. I also know that in Germany they force the children if they are restless
to take Ritalin.
-I am just talking about those students later on they really take Ritalin for
better result for their studies. So what happens to those people?
-I'll tell you. The difference is again the regulation of the dose.
That means they regulate in such a way they will not burn out the area of the brain
towards which these chemicals are acting. If they overdo it they will burn it.
Whether a ADD child will take Ritalin for 2-3 years regulated in doses
and then continue without it, it's possible to be treated and cured.
But if they burn out a child through excessive doses, it's very difficult to recover.
No more questions.
Paragraph 70, "After these premises, the following points must be admitted
as true: 1st. All that a physician may regard as curable in diseases,
consists entirely in the complaints of the patient, and the morbid changes of
his health perceptible to the senses; that is to say, it consists entirely
in the totality of symptoms through which the disease expresses its demand
for the appropriate remedy; while, on the other hand, every fictitious
or obscure, internal cause and condition, or imaginary, material, morbific matter
are not objects of treatment."
The only things that you have to treat are the symptoms
and there are no behind the symptoms a disease which you must treat.
In reality what he says is that a disease manifests only through symptoms
and the senses perceive these symptoms and the totality of these symptoms
are your guidelines on which you will prescribe the right remedy.
"2nd.This change of health (discord of feeling) which we call disease, can only
be changed back to the normal state by means of medicines, the curative power
of which, consequently, consists in their ability to alter the state of feelings; i.e.,
in the production of peculiar, morbid symptoms, recognized most distinctly
and purely by testing these medicines upon the bodies of healthy persons."
So this change in the health which we call disease can only be cured
through remedies which have produced in the healthy person similar symptoms.
"3rd. According to experience, natural disease cannot be cured by medicines
producing by themselves, in healthy persons, a morbid condition dissimilar to
and different from that of the disease to be cured. It is, therefore, incurable by
allopathic treatment,
and even nature herself never cures natural disease by super-adding another disease,
dissimilar to, though of much greater intensity than the first."
So the only way to cure is by medicines which are producing similar effect.
If they are dissimilar, then they cannot cure.
"4th. Experience also teaches that only transient relief is procured by medicines
inclined to generate in a healthy person, an artificial symptom which is the exact
opposite of certain symptoms, peculiar to the natural disease to be cured.
And we also learn that such medicines can never cure an inveterate disease, without
always creating a subsequent aggravation of the same.
On this account this antipathic, palliative process is entirely inappropriate
in its application to chronic and serious diseases."
What he says is that first of all why the organism cannot cure by itself
a chronic disease?
Because he does not have the possibility to produce a similar disease as he calls it
to produce a medicine by itself to cure itself.
Therefore there is always the effort of the organism through the fits of the crisis
in chronic diseases, there is an extra effort of the organism to cure itself.
Also if you give an antipathic remedy, you are not going to cure.
So he will drive to the conclusion that the only method of cure is the homeopathic.
"Experience also teaches that only transient relief is procured by medicines inclined
to generate in a healthy person, an artificial symptom which is the exact opposite
of certain symptoms..."
"5th. The only really salutary treatment is that of the homoeopathic method,
according to which the totality of symptoms of a natural disease is combated by
a medicine in commensurate dose, capable of creating in the healthy body,
symptoms most similar to those of the natural disease."
So he tells all the previous ones not this, not that, chronic diseases cannot be cured
and the only way to cure is with homeopathic treatment, with drugs which have
produced similar symptoms to the disease.
"And as diseases are only dynamic disturbances of the vital force, they are
overcome without additional suffering, and having been perfectly and
permanently extinguished, they must cease to exist.
Nature when left to her own resources, furnishes examples in the form of
accidental cures; as, for instance, when a new and similar disease is added to
the older one, this is permanently extinguished and cured."
He brings again the idea of Nature curing by the similar. This is not the only way.
What we know today is that automatic cure can happen in an organism
under certain circumstances.
One is the placebo effect, sometimes you may see impressive cures, very seldom
but still you can.
Another situation is when people believe very much in some gurus or saintly people
or some people with supernatural powers and they go to them, they prostrate,
they pray etc. and due to this faith the organism can be aroused and can cure
a chronic condition.
A chronic condition also can be cured, several times I had the opportunity to see
it, when a mother has a child which is very bad and seems he's going to die and
the mother prays to God... whatever is her belief...
that power of praying can cure the child from one hour to the other.
What is this? A similar disease has come? No.
It is the fact that we are all connected on another level and a good wish for
the other people is of great power. A real good wish is of great power.
You cannot imagine how much. Like the bad wish it can kill.
What they call the black magic... It's a bad wish, bad feelings for another person.
That's why it is so important that the humans understand the idea of forgiveness.
You see, if they have done something to you and they have hurt you...
If you can forgive that means in yourself you don't hold any grudges, any ill feelings.
They did whatever, they try to kill you they try to do this and that, forget it.
If you really forget it, then there is no problem.
But if inside you, you keep the hatred of that particular person whoever it might be
every time you see him and you want to kill him, then you have a problem.
And the problem needs what remedy?
Needs Hyoscyamus. It has these feelings of wanting to kill the other person,
Hyoscyamous desires to kill. How is connected Homeopathy with that level I am talking about?
It is the energy level on which we all float and we are connected.
You cannot imagine.
You may be in America and something happens to your son and you wake up
in the night and say oh my God something happened to my son.
Then they call you and they say he had an accident. This is so common.
-What about the person that receives the hate of the other? What happens to him?
From the chronic hate of the other?
-He has to do more work than others. He has to do more inner work than others.
You have to work internally to control yourself. You cannot control the others.
The others will keep on doing it. The only thing we can do is to work in our
inner state and understand how harmful it is to keep negative emotions
and it is very good, very healing to ignore.
People who ignore are the most happy. [speaks in Greek]
There is an expression in Greek which says "he is a donkey".
That means he is a person who does not take into the heart any kind of abuse or ...
he is a mule.
The thick skin people are most of the time happy. This is very strange but it is true.
Paragraph 71, "Now, since it is subject to no further doubt, that human diseases
consist merely in groups of certain symptoms..."
This means natural diseases are nothing else but groups of symptoms.
This represents the disease. If somebody has no symptoms, he says I'm well.
He will never go to the doctor and it is strange.
In the ancient Greece where most of the people were healthy
for someone to be going into the so-called doctors it was a shame
and he would hide it because most of the population were healthy people
with healthy ideas.
"...diseases consist merely in groups of certain symptoms, and that these may be
extinguished, and the system restored to health only by means of a medicinal
substance possessing the power of producing artificial, morbid symptoms,
similar to the disease (whereon rests the process of every genuine cure),
the business of curing will depend on the solution of the following problems :
I. How does the physician gain the knowledge of disease, necessary for the
purpose  of cure?" How logically he leads to the idea of the disease being
nothing else but the manifestation of symptoms so he says the main problem is
now first how the physician gains the knowledge of disease,
necessary for the purpose of cure. He gathers the knowledge of the symptoms.
"II. How does he gain his knowledge of the morbific power of drugs,
as the implements designed for the cure of natural diseases?"
He learns that through these symptoms we have this type of disease
and then he learns that by giving certain remedies to a healthy person
you gather information for each substance and
"III. How does he apply these artificial, morbific potencies (drugs) most effectively
in the cure of diseases?" The 3rd is how to apply these agents to the
symptomatology that he has gathered before.
"Regarding the first point, the following may serve as a general illustration.
Diseases peculiar to mankind, are of two classes.
The first includes rapid, morbid processes caused by abnormal states and
derangement of the vital force; such affections usually run their course
within a brief period of variable duration and are called acute diseases."
I don't know if for the first time or it is a knowledge already that there are
two types of diseases according to Hahnemann.
One is acute diseases and the other type is chronic diseases.
"The second class embraces diseases which often seem trifling and imperceptible
in the beginning; but which, in a manner peculiar to themselves, act deleteriously
upon the living organism, dynamically deranging the latter, and insidiously
undermining its health to such a degree, that the automatic energy of the vital force,
designed for the preservation of life, can only make imperfect and ineffectual
resistance to these diseases in their beginning, as well as during their progress."
In a child you give a vaccination and the child feels the prick and that's it.
You forget about it but at this moment has started an imperceptible process
of degeneration of the organism, which will end up one day or another,
maybe after a year or 10 years will end up in a serious chronic condition.
He says, the organism does not recognize these first imperceptible changes
in the beginning, so it does not take action.
Therefore no symptoms or suffering. The disease progresses in a subtle manner.
And then it reaches a point where the organism understands the danger and
suddenly is aroused and it sends its defense forces to the point
where the main problem is located.
This is what he says here.
Similar thing happens with acute diseases.
In acute diseases we have what we call a prodromal period
in which the organism understands very little that something is happening.
As this prodromal period is coming more and more, then eventually there is a climax
and the organism this time arouses all possible defenses.
And there is very high fever and even there are concomitant symptoms like
excessive perspiration and the inflammation in the bronchi...
When the inflammation is in the bronchi, that means there are seeds of the microbes,
of the virus, of bacteria and then the blood mobilizes the defenses and tries to block
the expansion of the morbific agent and creates a lot of mucus.
If the mucus will stay, the person will die, he cannot breath anymore.
As a second or a third line of defense the organism mobilizes the coughing.
It's necessary in order to save the life of the person to get out the mucus that
was gathered there in order to limit the expansion of the microbes.
So you see how unwise could be to give anti-inflammatory drugs first or to give
sedatives for the coughing, codeine and things like that.
You reduce the coughing, you reduce the fever and as a result instead of
the bronchitis taking 5-6 days, it's going to take 20 days to recover
or sometimes can never recover. It can become a chronic asthmatic condition.
The homeopathic treatment does not suppress anything.
What it says to the organism is I will give extra energy so you cough more, you bring
out more mucus and so therefore the whole organism will become more balanced
as a whole and not as a local effect of the medicine.
All this idea is very logical. He proceeds in a very logical way.
Of course there are some points which need to be explained.
"...the vital force, designed for the preservation of life, can only make imperfect and
ineffectual resistance to these diseases".
If the vital force is left alone the resistance is imperfect and it's not effective.
Therefore what we do? We give extra energy to the reaction and then
we give the necessary energy for the organism to overcome the disease.
And that is why you give an energy, a 30CH dose and there is an amelioration and
in a few hours there is a relapse, then you give 200CH, more powerful stimulation
and then you need to go to 1M and then 10M before the disease is extinguished.
Actually what you are giving, when you give the homeopathic remedy, is an extra
power to the defense mechanism. But that power is directed in such a way that it is
of the same quality as the defense mechanism.
As the vital force at this moment fighting through these symptoms.
You give a remedy you know it has produced similar symptoms, then there is
an increase on the symptoms, there is an initial aggravation.
This is why we say initial aggravation is very good.
Because you gave a power to react the organism, to get rid of the disease.
I think this is enough.
After giving indicated remedy if new symptoms appear on skin which were not
old skin symptoms of that patient is the case going ...
I don't understand who puts the question?
After giving indicated remedy if new symptoms appear on skin, which were not
old skin symptoms of that patient, is the case going to the right direction?
Most probably it is going to the right direction.
Of course it will depend on the type of the skin eruption. The idea is this.
You are treating a chronic condition of a patient who has certain suffering and
then you give a remedy and then there is a skin eruption that was not there before.
If the skin eruption is now much more suffering, maybe you have stimulated
something... I don't know such a case but I can imagine.
If the skin eruption is minor, it's very good reaction.
If the skin eruption is not an aggressive, malignant eruption the case is Ok.
I would like to know what are your thoughts on effects of contraceptive surgeries
like tubectomy or vasectomy on body and mind. You put me difficult questions.
This means a woman does not want to have further pregnancies and they tie
the fallopian tubes. And what its effect can be on the body and mind?
All organs they have their own place in the organism.
To take out an organ or to nullify an organ in this case, it cannot be a good thing.
There is definitely going to be a side effect.
What kind of effect would be in a woman that does this, I cannot say.
Because maybe it compensates.
If the organism is quite healthy, she can compensate.
Definitely there is going to be an effect.
It used to be very much in fashion in my young age when tonsils were affecting...
to take out the tonsils. It proved to be a very bad thing.
I remember I was 11 when I took out the tonsils, I was in a bloody hospital in Athens
during the German occupation. It was 1943, it was during the war, in the hospital
there were no injections, nothing. I went there and almost cold blooded, he started
cutting, it was a traumatic experience.
It was in the basement and said go up to the 1st floor to your bed. So I went like this.
I did not faint and managed to go in my bed but this cost me the rest of my life.
You may not want to know how. I am not going to tell you now.
But really I had to fight a lot. And I know people who have taken out their tonsils...
it's not so simple. They are the guardians of the respiratory system and they are
the first to catch up microbes, be inflamed and stop the disease up there.
If you don't have the guardians, then the disease will go inside much easier.
So it's not simple to cut whatever organ.
You say how people live without their thyroid gland, they take out the thyroid and
they take replacement of the hormones and they can go on living.
But closing the fallopian tubes, you cannot replace it. The ovaries keep on functioning.
Where are the ovaries going? How they are killed inside the organism.
Lots of complication could happen and could take place.
Most probably the mind is affected as well, I don't know how
but it's not possible not to be affected.
It is not good to take away the organs like the bladder.
They say "Take it out, no problem!"
-Concerning the removal of the tonsils, in my country it used to be
when I was a child and 10-20 years before many of them don't have tonsils.
Almost every child who repeated 2-3 times tonsillitis they removed it.
I was lucky, I have them still. In the cases I have seen the last years
there could be an interesting study to be done.
I have not seen so many cases but in the cases I have seen it's like a connection
cancer cases and severe autoimmune diseases 8-9/10 do not have tonsils.
This is what I have observed very clearly. Only a few hundred cases, may be thousands.
I don't know. This is one.
And about the other issue, the fallopian tubes are bound so the eggs won't go out
but it's the same thing the fallopian tubes are out of action.
This happens very frequently nowadays in my country, even without the woman
knowing after the birth if she has 1 or 2 children, the doctor does it.
It's an abuse but this is how things happen. Because they say you have 1 or 2
children it's Ok, I am making you a favor by doing this.
I have seen female patients who have come for treatment after these operations
with a lot of pathology starting from simple heat flushes till I have seen 1-2 almost
suicidal cases. Only after this operation. This is the only causative factor.
Nothing else happened in their lives. But most of them had something like menstrual
disturbances, heat flushes and 1-2 severe cases I have seen.
-It depends on the predisposition of the organism whether such an intervention
will have a severe effect or a milder effect. It will depend on the sensitivity of the
organism and the predisposition but definitely this was not a good practice.
Concerning this matter from my understanding the healthiest way of having
prevention if they don't want children is the condom for a woman and man.
The next is IUD the Intra-Uterus-Device but still it can inflame the uterus and
it can cause a set of bacteria.
-If the autoimmune disease is connected to the removal of the tonsils then since
this organ cannot be replaced there is no homeopathic cure for this disease?
-No homeopathic cure... There are cases in which the fallopian tubes are closed
because of inflammation. They get inflamed and they close.
For this there is a possibility for cure.
The fallopian tube reactivate the old inflammatory process and opens it up.
But if you close mechanically they tied it, you cannot open it again.
The only thing is if there are side effects upon this action, you may reduce them
with homeopathic remedy. He was saying for flushes of heat or hyperhidrosis
or anomalies in the menses, pain during, before or after menses.
All these can be regulated with the homeopathic remedy.
But still they will remain as a traumatic point in the organism.
-But my question was about the autoimmune disease as a consequence of the
tonsils removal. So tonsils are removed, you cannot replace them.
Does that mean these types of autoimmune diseases cannot be cured
homeopathically?
-Some may be cured, some may not. It depends on the level of health.
If an organism is weak and they take the tonsils out and then on the top of this
there are antibiotics... it's going to be an incurable case, eventually.
-What about tumors that obstruct or push an organ or they obstruct a function
like big fibroids that push other organs? Is it against the homeopathic rules
to operate them?
-If there are fibroids which because of their size, they close the entrance through
the fallopian tubes, then it will be Ok to remove that portion that closes and free
the ovaries to come to the uterus. It will be Ok.
-I had some cases in the past history they had their fibroids removed and within a
few months they had them grown again and even bigger than before.
-That is true also. These cases could end up in malignancy.
If there is a tendency for malignancy, you will see them immediately coming up.
Many times I have cases where a woman comes and says I don't have a child.
I will commit suicide. In such cases you are permitted, if you cannot handle it
with Homeopathy and a surgery can take away the obstruction,
I would advise to do it.
-And then come back with good homeopathic treatment?
-Yes, continue with homeopathic treatment. I think I told you about a case I was
treating for 5-6 years with a uterus that was so full of fibroids, it was like a stone.
So the idea of having a child was forgotten.
After 5 years of treatment for different things she was a "customer".
She was coming for a checkup etc... One day she became pregnant.
With that uterus the gynecologist who knew  had said to her before
that you cannot have a child. But I did not know that.
So I asked her when she told me she was pregnant... I don't want to tell you to
sit down quietly in a bed, it's very easy to detach.
So I advised her to go to the gynecologist to get an advice so he could take
the responsibility telling her staying in bed, don't move.
She went to the gynecologist and he said no problem, continue your normal life.
She called me and I said " did he say normal life? She said, there is no problem.
I could not say anything because he was the specialist.
So she was continuing, the 3rd or the 4th month she went into a car and she went
in a road with bumps. When they returned home it starts...
So 5 a.m. her husband comes to my house, knocks the door, he says my wife
is bleeding. I took the symptoms and I gave him some medicine.
In the morning no pharmacy was there but I gave my own medicine.
Get this medicine and go back. In the meantime he called the gynecologist.
The gynecologist he had such an attitude that it was unbelievable.
He said to her, reserve a place to the hospital where I operate, he indicated
the hospital and if I save your life, you will be lucky.
I told you you cannot have a child. But that it was told 10 years ago.
They call me and said that the gynecologist said that we have to go immediately
to the hospital and if he manages, it's so urgent, the bleeding was so much,
that if I save your life you will be lucky.
In the meantime 5- 5.30 had started with the medicine, 7.00 now...
I said between 5.30 and 7.00 the bleeding was the same in amount or less?
He said I think it's less. I said Ok, don't go to the hospital.
They constantly called me to be in touch. 13.00 they called me, now I have been
in their place and I know the telephone is not in their bedroom it is only in the hall.
So she calls me and tells me the bleeding is very little.
I said you are not in bed, she said no... I am going to have an abortion.
I said no, go back and lie in bed and don't move at all and just keep me informed.
I am talking about 1969- 1970, I am talking about a 50 year old case.
She had a very healthy child. Of course she never had another.
The uterus expanded and remained expanded. It could not contract anymore.
It was like a stone and eventually she had to remove the uterus.
But the child is 50 years old and she frequently comes to Skopelos.
They have a house and they come. But we have seen such things happening.
Can we every time do the same? I am not sure.
Neither I treated the uterus, I was treating the whole person.
The uterus together with the person got better, more elastic, managed to expand
and she was a happy woman.