-This is not my patient but who is your doctor?
-...I have heard that Homeopathy may have some result of helping people with the same
disease who keep functioning almost normally by using this kind of terrible medicine.
-Can you repeat because I do not understand?
-He just said that he has heard that Homeopathy can help this type of illness.
-Has he taken homeopathic remedies already?
-He has taken two remedies. He is taking Rhus tox right now and before he took one other
remedy… What was the other remedy you took?
-Arnica.
-So he is 54 years old and 6 years ago he developed larynx spasms and one year ago he
noticed some minor difficulty with his voice, as well as mild weakness in the left arm and
the left leg. So he started to get some weakness.
-In the left side, left arm and left leg.
-This was one year ago, you started to get some weakness.
Can you stand up for a moment?
-It’s a bit hard.
-Can you walk a little bit, so help him to walk.
-No, I’m OK.
I have a brace in both ankles. What it would be like if you didn’t have the brace.
-My left foot would be very dragging…
-In order to study this case, as the information comes in, you have to be looking in the
Repertory for every information that comes in. The fact that the disease starts from the
spasms in the larynx, it becomes peculiar and therefore we see through the Repertory,
which are the remedies which have an affinity with spasms in the larynx.
We go through there and we see Belladonna, Gelsemium, Ignatia, Moschus are mostly
and then Agaricus, Antimonium crudum, Arsenicum, Bromium, Chelidonium, Chloralum,
Coffea, Cuprum, Iodine, Lachesis, Manganum, Magnesia phosphorica, Opium,
Phosphorus, Sabucus, Silica, Tabacum, Tarentula and Veratrum.
From these remedies we get a first idea. The next thing we look is which of these remedies
have an affinity with the neuro-muscular system and they can cause paralysis and spasms
and we see that Agaricus, Gelsemium, Cuprum, Magnesia phosphorica, Lachesis…
You get an idea already of some remedies. The fact also that he says that the disease is
on the left side quite prominent, he speaks about the left side quite clearly.
This fact plus the fact that the whole thing started from the larynx and then we know that
Lachesis has these spasms in the larynx, so much so that sometimes from these spasms
they suffer quite a lot.
I make all this thinking now and out of all these remedies that I see through this Repertory,
I prefer Lachesis at this stage. Already we have been given with the first symptoms some
information, which leads us towards Lachesis mostly.
With this thinking we continue to investigate without trying to influence the case in favor of
Lachesis or anything like that. Then you observe what else? In this case you also observe
something which is very obvious. What is that?
-He writes about his case.
-Is that the obvious? The very obvious is the speech. What is the speech?
We have difficult…
It’s not stammering. Trembling, see unintelligible, Stramonium.
Most probably it means during stammering. Stramonium is one of the main remedies for
stammering, especially if it is aggressive stammering, where the person really battles.
Let’s do some differential diagnosis also, so you learn something.
Stramonium really is a remedy which is an upheaval inside, tremendous energy inside that
can not come out and the energy is aggressive. Therefore the stammering also of this
person is not like that. It will never be like that.
This is a stammering you will see in which remedy?
You see it in Mercury mostly. The Mercury is subdued and sweet stammering, it is not
aggressive, where the Causticum can talk like that but the moment he gets angry, it can
not come out. Then he talks normally and then he stucks when the emotions come.
With Stramonium is another thing, you really… You look and you say, my god how he
suffers to bring out the words.
You see grimaces, that is a Stramonium. This is differential diagnosis just to one symptom.
So you get to know the nature of the remedy in this way.
He is not a Stramonium, he talks like that but why? Why he talks unintelligibly?
Because of his disease. The effect on the nervous system and the cerebellum and the
speech has been affected. Therefore we try to find the most close rubric that is to his case.
Difficult is the most close.
-Tremulous.
-It’s not tremulous. Let me see difficult speech.
The main remedies that appear in difficult speech are Belladonna, Crotalus, Gelsemium,
Lachesis, Natrum muriaticum, Opium, Stannum and Stramonium.
Here again in this rubric remedies have been mixed for different reasons.
Stannum has difficulty in talking, why? Because of exhaustion.
If you would say, I’m not well, this can be Stannum with exhaustion and not being able to
bring out, to talk, it can be Stannum. With Stramonium here the difficulty is because of the
tendency that the person has for stammering.
With Opium it is a speech that you hear in a kind of semi-coma state. It’s difficult,
unintelligible, you don’t understand and then with Lachesis we have this thick talking, as
we call it. There is a difficulty in articulating, in pronouncing the words and the sounds.
Here we have a difficulty in speech, which brings to my mind again the idea of Lachesis.
We’ll see.
-Since this time of weakness he has been a gradual strength loss of the left side and
worsening of the speech and swallowing, difficulty in swallowing.
-Difficulty in swallowing, when it started?
-One year ago.
-I have to tell you that when the spasm started, I became more careful with my eating,
smaller pieces, drinking slowly, so not to choke. I think it has stabilized up to a certain point.
-It stabilized to a certain point, it’s not continuing to get worse the swallowing.
-Maybe I can explain it. It seems to be that…I’ve seen other person and among them…
In my case I only seem to lose some power but I still have some left,
the same thing with my neck and as far as my speech is concerned,
my speech has been not deteriorating  it is much more in these 6-7 months…
-Another area.
-Can everybody hear what he said?
He says that he seems to get worse to a certain point and
that he was stabilized but then the weakness would start in different part of the body and
that get worse for a while but he says comparing to other patients he is doing quite well.
-Yes.
-Because he still has some strength in arms and legs and speaking.
-Ask him how does he feel psychologically?
-I think more good things than bad things.
-Psychologically you feel happy?
-Not happy but it’s not as bad as I would have thought it would be.
-You remember the remark I made? Also you will see him he is not depressed at all.
He is optimistic, his disease is doing rather better and he is optimistic.
-He says he also notices a tendency to easily cry or laugh inappropriately. Like he will cry
very easily or laugh very easily but this is supposed to be typical for the disease.
-Take it, crying alternating with laughing.
We look at this and then we see another remedy, which is Mercury which could be a
possibility…alternating with laughter. Stramonium.
-He has some muscle wasting.
-He has the typical wasting of the feral muscle, you can see it.
-His sensory nervous system is OK, the nerves cells are degenerating in the spinal
column. That’s all. He had a bad accident in 1958 when he was 21 years old.
When he was 21 years old was an explosion on a boat and he was traumatized by this.
-Where?
-Mostly my leg.
I was in rehab center for 2 years, mostly pain.
When it happened I didn’t have due to the explosion my muscle…
to the bone and damaged this and it took for 4-5 days got me to a hospital and
in those days I didn’t’ have…
-There was an explosion and the muscles and the bones and it took 2 years to recover
from mostly pain. You didn’t have any weakness after this accident?
-No and I did work very hard all my life.
-He has been well all his life?
-That’s what he says.
-He worked hard all his life.
-What was his profession? Sailor?
-Traffic manager, I had to work physically as well but I did work with my hands.
-He worked with his hands and muscles all his life. Coaching, teaching sports and ski.
She says stress provokes headaches and difficulty in speech.
-So at this stage he gives some information about his disease. It is now very superficial, I
would say what we know about him. We do not know much about what took place.
What we know also is that such a disease can not be triggered unless there is an exciting
cause, unless there is a stimulation of the organism by some kind of stress.
What kind of stress took place in his life in order to manifest this severe disease, which
was in his DNA, it was genetically there but what triggered to come forth, to be
manifested?
My idea is that such a disease has to have quiet a strong stress mostly psychological.
Did he find himself especially in a situation where he was paralyzed by deciding this or
that? That is a situation where it can paralyze somebody and the stress of not deciding
can bring about some kind of condition or did he have a series of antibiotics or did he have
a series of chemicals? Did he take drugs? Has he taken any narcotics? Any drugs?
Has he? Can anybody tell me?
-Yes.
-Not narcotics of that type. The persons who take recreational drugs, don’t speak, I do not
know, have I spoken to you before?
-No.
-I have an idea whether he took this kind of drugs or not. What do you think? I want you to
see your observation. Who says no? Who says yes? The no are in favor.
He had never taken these kind of drugs.
-Except from smoking cigarette. I don’t smoke anymore for 7 years.
-He could have taken LSD, in such situation, he could have taken sedatives like Tavor,
Valium and things like that could have brought about that kind of situation.
-What about alcohol?
-Does he taken alcohol just by observation? How much? He has taken alcohol, there is no
question. I mean a fair amount. This is not difficult to see because we see all his life.
This type of person will not take recreational drugs. Do you know why I say that?
Can anybody tell me why he has not taken LSD and cocaine and things like this?
-Hard working.
-Responsible job, proper?
-I don’t agree.
-Clear mind.
-Clear mind, you are closer to what I think. I think psychologically is quite healthy, down to
earth, a person who enjoyed, having a woman or two…Enjoy life in a natural way I would
say, so he would not need this extra stimulation which these drugs offer and that’s why I
say with certainty he has not taken but alcohol yes. Why? Because I see his color and
because every Canadian drinks.
-The French Canadian.
-Even worse.
Now we try to see what really happened and started this kind… and we go back to his
memory and I would like to ask him what has happened in his life 6 years ago?
You cannot remember.
-The problem is that nobody is sure that it started at that time.
10 years before, I’ve had things happened to me all my life, I was very lucky all my life.
-You are married?
-Yes, twice.
-You have children?
-I have two grown up girls that are married and a young son 8 years old.
It was a very happy thing.
-I want to ask you something else. Why did you divorce your first wife? Because you had
found already the second one?
-No. I found the second one 15 years later. You have to understand that at the time of the
divorce I was working 18 months in South America, 8 months …
-As a sailor?
-No, as traffic port manager.
-But travelling on a ship from port to port?
-No, I travelled by plane for 6-7 months, then go to another place and the first wife got
very tired to that and she found someone else.
-He says, he may have had other girlfriends as well before the divorce.
-He might have.
-They are still friends.
-With his wife, the first one.
-When did he marry the second wife?
-14 years ago.
-And the son was born 9 years ago?
-Yes.
-Which means for three and a half years you did not have a child?
-Four or five years, we wanted to have one but god wanted us to wait again.
-I see. Now are you still married with your second wife?
-Yes.
-During that time after your son was born, there was no problems between you and your
wife?
-No problems for sure. The only thing that happened around that time, I’ll be very frank
with you was a very happy thing. I won …
-He won a quarter of a million dollars in a lottery.
-That’s a big stress if you don’t expect it.
We would like to know a difficult question now. Now the questions start to be a bit difficult,
it’s OK.
-I’ll do my best.
-We would like to know , whether when you had these contacts in different ports with some
women, did you ever have any venereal disease?
-Yes. I can tell you, no and on top of that… and the disease has never…
-He says most of the places he was belonged to the second parallel and this disease that
he has now has not been not diagnosed in that parallel.
-Beside multiple sclerosis.
-He is asking if you ever had gonorrhea, syphilis.
-No, I had to treat people because I was taking care of the crew and I never had.
-Did you get antibiotics for something?
-I had penicillin for operation, I’m sure they gave me antibiotics.
-He thinks he may had antibiotics when he had his gall bladder operation.
-Are you sure you did not have any venereal disease? Urithritis?
-Pain in urination.
-No, I’m very lucky but no, never.
-I’m saying that in those days venereal disease was not as frequent as they are today.
-30 years ago things were quite different I think.
-His father to what age he lived?
-My father died 82 years old.
-From what? From old age.
-He had been suffering from hardening of the arteries and he had an operation and didn’t
survive.
-His mother?
-My mother died 43 years old.
-From what?
-I believe from lung cancer or some kind of cancer.
You have to understand I was not raised by my parents, I was an orphan.
-So he was not raised by his parents, he was an orphan. He does not know his parents.
-I know my mother until 8 years old, then I was raised into an orphanage. I never lived with
my own father.
-Your real mother do you know how old she lived for?
-It’s the same mother.
-When did he win the lotto, how many years ago?
-It was about 1986, about the same time, it started 2 months after.
-Two months after winning the lottery, he started getting some symptoms.
-About the same time. The main thing is 6-7 years is that they found out that I had this
spasm, so this is a symptom of the disease. Maybe cancer, maybe other things happening
that I did not notice.
-Before that, did you ever wake up in the night thinking that your larynx is closed and you
can not breathe?  During sleep did you ever wake up, as if you could not breathe?
-No, but this is started to happen with the disease, I was choking in my sleep because of
the spasm. Never before, it started in 1986.
-And it was happening during your sleep?
-Always.
-Yes.
-Maybe you are getting somewhere.
-You see his face how it is litted up, he says this man he understands, he starts to believe
that I understand things. He says how did he get that? You see the reaction?
Therefore the symptom is reliable.
What he says, you have to take into consideration seriously because you know very well
the action of Lachesis on the pneumogastric nerve when it is paralyzed and there is a kind
of spasm on falling asleep or during sleep where
he wakes up in fright thinking that he will choke.
What else do you observe?
I observe that most of the Canadians are dressed like me, with a tie and I see that he
wears no tie and I would like to know why?
-Lachesis.
-Why you do not wear a tie? Because you do not like to be tight here or because you do
not like the tie or you do not have a tie? What is the reason for not wearing a tie?
-I have all kinds of suit but I don’t wear them. This is me.
-That’s you, you do not like to wear a tie. If you wear a tie, you will feel restricted?
-No, I do not bother.
-You could wear a tie and feel comfortable but out of belief, you believe that it is better to
not wear a tie, is that correct?
-I believe this is better.
-Simpler.
-This is terrible.
-He says he doesn’t bother him to wear a tie.
-Yes I know. So he says he doesn’t bother but he does not. You never wear a tie?
-Yes I do. I have to, for my work sometimes, I have to go to see the banker or my boss or
to see the accountant. So from respect to him I have to…
-When you wear a tie, you want it loose or tight?
-As you can see it’s very tight.
-No, this collar is not tight but…
-This is the kind of shirt I would wear. If I may say when I do wear tie, it’s a tie from all the
way through.
-Can you imagine now what he is thinking when he has such a serious disease talking
about a tie with him? He says, strange questions these people are putting to me.
Strange people. Still he is not in a position to think. After all this is finished, then he will
start thinking.
-No, I’m thinking.
-You are thinking already.
-I was before I came here.
-Very good.
Something else I want to know.
Before your disease in relation with your wives, girlfriends you were jealous sometimes?
-No. I couldn’t care less. I’m not possessive of anyone.
-He is not possessive of anybody.
-You are not possessive out of character or out of philosophical belief?
-I guess out of character. I never care about these things.
-He says he is not very materialistic, he doesn’t care about his house, his car, he is not
very attached to material things.
-I like to work 7 days the week. This is what I like.
-He likes to work 7 days the week.
-I still do. I still do.
-The women were jealous with him?
-I don’t think so. I can’t talk for them.
-He can’t talk for them but he doesn’t think so.
-In company with other people you are loquacious, talking, participating or rather reserve
and quiet?
-I have no problem socializing but I’m not very great talker. I love people but I don’t...
-He loves to be with people and he seems to be OK in conversation. He says he is not a
great socialiser.
-I don’t have too many friends, 3 or 4 real friends.
-How much alcohol do you take?
-We are talking now or before? I never was a heavy drinker but I had a couple of beers,
first of all only Heineken, nothing else and maybe a scotch or two…
-You had two drinks every day?
-No, one beer.
-One drink per day?
-Sometimes none.
-Did you go through a period where you were heavy drinker?
-I had to tell that since 1974 I have not taken a day off, I’ve been working 7 days the week..
-Since 1974 he works 7 days the week, so he doesn’t see how he can be drinking very much.
-Maybe I take a few days here and there.
-Does he have any pains, any cramps?
-They happen sometimes in my leg, while I sleep only, never during the day, when I sleep
yes and in my left thumb if I have to put a bit more strength my fingers I have to bring them
back.
-He gets some cramp in the hands when he has to do something with strength.
-But in the legs it’s only in the night, I wake up with a terrible cramp.
-So to resume the case until now, we have symptomatology of Lachesis, on the physical
level. In his pathology we can not confirm Lachesis. He denies he is bothered by tight
collars, he denies having any kind of jealousy and …
He denies to be loquacious, so the constitutional symptoms of Lachesis are not there.
But the last thing he says is that I have cramps during the night, this for those who may
know Lachesis, is a Lachesis symptom because Lachesis suffers mostly in the night and
mostly in the first part of the night and when he wakes up in the morning.
Lachesis wakes up in a bad mood and you ask him, how do you wake up in the morning,
how do you feel in the morning?
-I feel great.
-Very good. That’s what we want to hear.
-Now I feel even better because I’m glad to be alive.
-He is glad to be alive so he feels very good.
-I never had any problem in waking up in the morning.
-You wake up and immediately you can jump out of bed.
-Now?
-Yes sure but before always?
-Yes I never had any problem whatsoever.
-In what position do you sleep?
-On my right side.
-Always, all your life on your right side?
-Yes he will have to say yes, most of his life.
-I don’t feel OK on the left side.
-What bothers you?
-I haven’t noticed. I can’t.
-Yes but you feel something if you lie on the left side, do you remember?
-No, I can’t feel relaxed.
-He can’t let himself go into sleep.
-Maybe it is something that I made up myself.
-He is quite a gentle person. He likes people being affectionate with him and close to him.
-Of course, who doesn’t?
-He likes people being affectionate and close to him.
-How do you know?
-I sit here, I can tell. Is that right?
-I came with you.
-How would you describe your psychological state?
-I tell you quite frank, I’m even surprised myself how I reacted to this. If someone would
ask me that question 2 years ago, I would be upset and shooting myself right there on the
spot but now…
-It’s even better than before psychologically?
-I would say yes because I’m functioning well.
-Psychologically and mentally. You see?
When the disease has somatised totally the mental-emotional level is left free and he is
more happy and more optimistic and he is able to cope with his disease much better.
If somebody would tell me 2 years ago in what state I would have been, I would think I
would shoot myself but now I can tolerate and I believe he is quite happy.
That’s it.
The fact that he sleeps on the right side, does it mean anything to you?
To whom it means something? Let me see the hands.
To the others it doesn’t mean anything?
All his life he says. In the left side he feels something which does not let him relax and go
to sleep. He cannot give an explanation why.
Cramps in the night in bed, can you show me this rubric?
-Calves and the foot.
-Sulphur, Calcarea, Lycopodium, where is Causticum?
-I was a very happy man and got very lucky.
-He says he may have got gonorrhea even though he didn’t have any symptoms.
He may have been a carrier but may not have had it or whatever.
-Is that possible?
-We are searching for this cause especially with syphilis where this symptomatology is
similar to the third stage of syphilis, where we have the tabes dorsalis  which is neuromuscular manifestation of syphilis.
Definitely in order to get to that stage, you have to get the primary and then the secondary
and then you may have to go into that state. This is lacking from his history which means
that genetically there is a predisposition for the disease which appears after great stress or
excitement perhaps.
Perhaps the fact that he was over enjoyed with the lotto, winning the lottery, it acted as a
catalyser or trigger for his pathology.
-He said it was 2 months before.
-The symptoms of your disease came 2 months after winning the lotto?
-I think so, it came about the same time.
-He said after.
-Was any pressure on you for the money to give it to somebody or to do certain things?
-I haven’t done anything with that. There was no pressure. I didn’t need the money.
-You did not need the money.
-You still have it?
-I haven’t spent anything.
-How did you feel when you won the lottery?
-Nothing. I was very happy but nothing ever changed.
-Do you remember that maybe the first night you did not sleep the whole night or things
like that?
-No, I slept very well.
-Do you have any possibility in your work to be poisoned by any metal, especially lead?
-Yes, there was at one point quite a few years back and as a matter of fact…
Apparently in the… where I did my military service there have been 4-5 cases of people
who were on the same sub-marine. It was a British sub-marine from the world war two.
-He was in a sub-marine in a study concerning the…
-4-5 cases of people in the Canadian navy who came with the disease…
-4-5 cases with the disease of people who worked on the same sub-marine.
Probably you were exposed to. There was a lot of fuels, diesel fuels?
-Yes, of course.
-Diesel is full of a lot of toxic metals, it’s very toxic.
-This is why they put us …
-On the same sub-marine. They were only two sub-marines of that kind but nothing really
came out of it.
-There was only two. There was some exposure to diesel fuels over a long period of time.
How long?
-I served in that sub-marine for 8 months.
-What year?
-I believe it’s 1961. I will have to check.
-That’s OK.
-Did you get weakness when you were there on that sub-marine?
-I never had any problem.
-Was any major shock or fear or fright?
-Sure, when the ship blew up I didn’t have … but when I woke up I feel all the pain.
I’m sure it was all kind of stress.
-Later on did you have any shock, like fear…?
-The shock came about 4 months later.
-4 months later after the explosion.
-… into another ship and because of the… I couldn’t work for the first year…
-It was a shock when they told him he will never walk again. You got over the shock?
-Obviously.
-There was a shock when he was in an explosion 21 years old and it took him 4 months
to feel emotionally the shock, to realize that he may not walk again.