The convulsions are not anymore the same as they used to be.
Most probably the child has gone to another remedy.
But you will tell me after six months it has gone to another remedy?
Yes, it can go to another remedy because the condition is most serious.
Most probably if they repeat now the remedy will not have an effect.
Actually the remedy may aggravate the situation because you are prescribing a remedy
which is not anymore indicated but still was the remedy of the child.
And therefore the child has a specific sensitivity towards that remedy.
You have to be very careful in this case now, to say there is a big change here,
he says convulsions, he calls them convulsions but one convulsion from another type of convulsion
is a different story. Now you have to be careful, not to make the mistakes here.
From here the mistakes can start. We started correctly, Cicuta.
The whole class agreed, found the remedy but you did not find it the first time.
Now we give more information, so we make it more easy.
Now is Cicuta? This is the question.
-Two weeks later on the 13th of February as convulsions tended to be still deteriorating,
also he was the stronger convulsions that was coming, so I gave a dose of 200
and once again nothing happened over a period of two weeks.
-You see now? He gives 12, he gives 200, nothing, of course nothing.
This is a different picture all together, how do you expect the remedy to act?
If you go according to the symptomatology they have said before, you see Kent is saying
if the remedy has acted, try it again.
Even if the symptoms do not agree so much but you have to have
certain of the symptoms agreeing, if you want to act, not just give it mechanically.
I will tell you a case where you can give it mechanically.
You have a mental case and you give it and he is doing very well
but eventually he has a boil developed or a tumor develops
and there are no symptoms to guide you to a remedy because of the tumor
and the other symptomatology is gone. And you have only local symptoms
which do not indicate any remedy. Now what are you going to do?
It’s a situation where the tumor develops; you may allow it
because you do not have any symptomatology and because the remedy has acted before,
you may be allowed to repeat that potency that you repeated last time.
Here what we have to do is to take into consideration the type of convulsions
and find the next remedy, what remedy is indicated.
So Cicuta is going to aggravate the situation.
-In the 13th of March I would have given the 12X and I gave the 12C and once again
there was a continuing deterioration.
A continuous deterioration, do you hear that?
-Through the winter his general disposition was one of irritability and a little bit of crying,
restlessness, a little bit of problems at night with sleeping.
So he’d wake maybe 2-3 times in the night and it was very difficult to pacify him,
we had to carry him.
You see how the picture has changed? In the beginning in the night when he wakes up,
he is very happy, now he is very aggressive and irritable
and you can not pacify him in the night, big changes. You cannot say take Cicuta anymore.
-As I said before the (?) went away to be redness and roughness of the cheeks
and a small (?) rash of left cheek.
Also he has this tendency to flash up very much and he flashes up quite a bit in the convulsions.
I need to prescribe on the 5th of May and that was Tuberculinum 200.
He prescribed Tuberculinum. He took the initiative and prescribed Tuberculinum for the child.
-Without checking with you?
-Without checking. Why should I give Tuberculinum?
-For the first time in March he started to sleep through the night
but what happened was the convulsions then got worse and took a rigidity.
So it was the first time that he actually had this rigidity.
You see how he pushes it forward, inside, inside again. The same process is going backwards.
Now he makes a few more mistakes. You will see the whole picture coming back.
You will see the automaton again. It’s not very difficult to bring back the state.
You see how sensitive we have to be, how intelligent, not to throw remedies here and there.
You see the result. You say, make this better, make this worse, make this better,
eventually you come back to the joby state by what you have done.
After two years of treatment the same situation.
They can easily come back, the child, to the same situation.
-It got worse and took a rigidity which was for the first time
that he actually had this rigidity in the convulsions.
-(?) in September (?)
-On the 20th of the 3rd I gave another dose of Cicuta 30.
This seemed to precipitate more convulsions and…
Do you hear that? This is mathematics. If nobody will tell me,
I would say I will tell you the reaction and I would quote the same words. Why?
Because I know the child has a sensitivity to Cicuta, Cicuta is not anymore indicated,
the child is in a sensitive state, it’s going to affect him.
-So there was no (?) and the other stage he was getting to the point
where he had been-not as frequently as before - on (?)
and so the state of the convulsions at this point returned to where
it was being drawn to a fit, he was fixing up
and then he was slowly extending all his (?) very rigidly
and as he extended you could see the look on his face which was
staring eyes, a lot of twitching and jerking of the facial muscles,
especially around the mouth and often the jaws went over to one side
and also a lot of flickering, twitching and
jerking in the eyes and clenching of the tooth…
-Here is the remedy now. He quoted, he said symptoms indicating the right remedy now.
What is the right remedy? Just repeat a little bit.
-…slowly extending all his (?) very rigidly (?) and as he extended you could see
the look on his face which was staring eyes, a lot of twitching and jerking of the facial muscles,
specially around the mouth and often the jaws went over to one side
and also a lot of flickering, twitching and jerking in the eyes and clenching of the tooth.
At that point (?) he was very extended, this is a difference
that we found in the convulsions now, before he was going to a fully extended position (?).
Now what’s happening is he is reaching an extended position but the head is not going back,
rather at that point when the convulsions ceases, the jerking
that is occurring right through the convulsion becomes less (?)
After a period of 30 seconds of relaxation, he then goes back
into the extended position like this for a short time with no violence
but the breathe once again is held back by the jerking and then he would come off
and after that the (?) very deeply.
-(?) to breathe, just continue (?)
-(?) constriction in the throat.
-His feet will be like this but the whole thing extends like that, it’s a very rigid,
the (?) is tremendously rigid and the extension is slow and rigid and the face and distortion…
The eyes (?) and I think (?) to the right side.
(?) where before there was actually going back a sort of arch (?) and before there was the (?)
Put the next follow up, all the information, they call me on the telephone.
I’m not taking the case here, somebody else who is taking the case and sent the tape
and I saw the tape and we call on the telephone and on this information
and what he told me, I prescribed Zincum 200.
And there is the last follow up which comes a month later and they sent it to me
just a few days before I arrived here and I will give you the latest news,
which I know by telephone just before I came here.
That’s beginning of August.
I think he is doing better.
Many are not so much enthusiastic.
I will give you the follow up, you can see the whole follow up in the afternoon.
What I want to give you is the latest news about him.
About 7 or 8 days ago I received a telephone call from his father
who said that the child had high fever, had auscultatory sounds in his lungs indicating bronchitis,
gave me symptoms of Sanicula.
I wrote Sanicula because of certain symptomatology or the possibility of Bryonia,
the child took Sanicula with no effect, Bryonia with no effect,
after two days they phoned again, it was a very high fever over 40,
the child was not going into convulsions.
In spite of the very high fever but the child was looking really exhausting,
he could not eat anything, he had difficulty in breathing
and I understood he had a kind of bronchopneumonia.
They gave me again the symptomatology of the child and I prescribed Belladonna
and just one day before leaving from here, he called again and said he is much better
with Belladonna, repeated 2-3 times, the fever was going down, the child was coming up,
eating a little, drinking and again going back to very high fever, again Belladonna,
again better and that was the situation when I left for Aedipsos.
I told him in case of great emergency to call my secretary
and he could tell her to try to find me.
So far I have no message, I left Thursday, today is Tuesday.
Let’s hope that everything has been OK but what is important in this case is that now
the child has what we expected to have. A severe, acute condition.
After that condition if you see the child, you will see tremendous improvement
and the child may reach the point where all the children are in that condition.
We hope to be able to show, to demonstrate that within 2-3 years
but the child will be back to normal.
It gives us all the possibilities to believe that this has a possibility
of coming back to normal where in the beginning I had great reservations
concerning the prognosis of the case because of the pathology.
But here we see really on deep anatomical pathology,
what can be the effect of homeopathic remedy
and can be the effect of correct homeopathic treatment?
Because you see at the same time correct and wrong homeopathic treatment
and you see the effect. One goes downwards, the other goes upwards.
Do you understand why I talk about Homeopathy with such passion.
It’s not the first case I have seen.
You have seen this case, another case, another case, a dead man who rose up!
Almost things like that. Now what do you expect me to do? They say George is fanatic.
I don’t know how much fanatic.
Someone who is fanatic would go outside shouting all over the place. Wake up.
Here is a system with fantastic possibilities, you just throw it to the gutter,
where University to teach, where do you go to learn? You have come from all over the place,
you should have one University in each country to be able to teach and to learn this science
and nobody does anything and that really gets me.
Because I don’t want to show you only successes, I told you a failure we had with the case
with cancer and I’m going to show you another failure which we have with a man,
because you like to see some failures, right? You love it.
So I will show you a case where we failed, failed, failed
and I will let you evaluate the situation.
-In this case why did we give Zincum?
-Why Zincum? Because I like Zincum.
The way he described…
Zinc is much more important for convulsions but what he said,
he said the twitchings are so prominent and the distortions…
-Agaricus?
-Agaricus also but not to that extend and I can’t remember now
because we spoke on the telephone and he gave me some information and I can’t remember
but with this information also I would have given Zincum in contra distinction to Agaricus.
Agaricus can be indicated but it’s not as deep as Zinc.
Zinc is a much deeper remedy when the nervous system is involved.
Where Agaricus more peripheral nerves.
Here it is not only peripheral nerves, it’s the nerve endings.
It’s also affecting the system on a much deeper level
which I would prefer Zinc for that reason.
Also I conjecture that there is a kind of skin eruption in the whole situation.
We have depression of skin eruption and we have convulsions.
The skin eruption is coming up and this is very much Zinc and not Agaricus.
Zinc is having symptoms after suppressed eruptions. It is one of the main remedies.
So I can see the connection between suppressed eruption and convulsions.
-George, you mentioned normality. Normality for a Down child or normality for…?
-Normality for a Down child. I don’t claim that we cure the child and will become normal.
It will become a normal for a Down child.
-(?)
-Tomorrow morning will read this and I will tell you why not this and that.
Read the Oenanthe. What page it is? Page 479.
You want to read the pieces?
Red spots, wait a moment. Don’t take that as a red spot, this is an eruption.
In this child we have the appearance of an eruption.
It’s very good, you pass, good idea but I’ll give you some more explanation perhaps for Zincum.
First of all here what it means is a red spot, it is a discoloration, it is not an eruption.
Here we have the appearance of an eruption, which withdraws and comes out
and goes back and comes out and as it goes outward and inward,
we have the appearance of convulsions or twitchings or whatever.
So it appears to have a connection between the eruption and the convulsions.
Now if we want to know which is the main remedy that has twitchings, convulsions,
chorea etc. after suppressed eruption, it is Zincum, not Oenanthe. So that is one thing.
The second thing is that when the main point…
You have convulsions but the main point was the convulsions
and the frightfulness of the convulsions. That was the main point.
Now the father suddenly says, a lot of twitchings in the face,
stresses an another point all together.
Therefore the emphasis should be on that point.
Which is the remedy that produces a lot of twitchings?
And then he says, in the night the child was calm and was happy.
Now in the night is screaming, moaning etc. and we know that Zinc,
I have described to you in the Zincum how the child is irritated in the night and screams.
Screaming, great irritation in the night, screaming in the night, the irritation is so much
that the child will not be able to stand and move, especially his legs in Zincum,
but here what made me decide on Zincum and not on Agaricus and not on Oenanthe
and not on another remedy is the fact that we have these three points.
We have convulsion with facial twitchings. Who has seen this Zincum boy?
You remember how he was doing this?
From that point then it goes bigger and bigger and bigger until we reached the convulsions,
until we reached facial twitchings etc. and you saw the character of the boy.
Irritated and you see it in children, especially children who have vaccination,
after Sebi vaccination for poliomyelitis.
After vaccination for poliomyelitis you see Zincum side effects,
where the child becomes irritated, it is very irritable, it’s screaming,
it’s not in peace at all and they scream like…
It’s something which frightens you, the screaming of Zincum in the night.
In this case where we have a really deep pathology,
the atrophy of the cerebellum is confirmed by the scanning of the brain.
To have an effect on this level, you have to give the right remedy.
Forget an effect without the right remedy.
In little things you may have an effect without the correct remedy,
you go around, around and eventually he is OK.
You have a sciatica and the remedy is Kali iodine and you never give it
and you give Lycopodium, Lachesis, Colocynthis, Gnaphalium, Nux vomica.
Nux vomica is around now because it is about 15 days and every 5 days a remedy
and it’s walking now but if you give the right remedy never mind how severe it is.
If it not a slip disc, if the disc has not broken and pressing, if it’s a real sciatica,
it has to come back within a few days, 2-3 days he has to walk with the right remedy
but with the wrong remedy he will walk after 15 days. It goes around, around, around.
In this case you can have an effect, he is not going to walk with the wrong remedy.
You have to go deep and get the right response from a deep level.
Here the cerebellum is shrinking; he was going to stay like that,
the child was going to stay paralyzed the whole of his life and in a few months
to make that child stand or walk is a miracle.
For me that I know Homeopathy, I know the effect of Homeopathy, still I say my god
what possibilities we have and we do not know.
What is most pleasing for me is to see the laws, we have principles.
They telephone and they say, he has pneumonia severe, very high fever.
He has over 40, no convulsions? No convulsions.
The child is very peaceful, it is exhausted most probably
but what it happens you have to understand all these things to appreciate
and to understand what you are doing.
An organism is accepting an inflammation on a level.
If it accepts an inflammation on the meninges, it’s going to be a severe inflammation.
If accepts an inflammation on a lower level, on a cerebellum, cerebellitis is lower
but still is very severe.
If accepts an inflammation on the lungs is better than the cerebellum
and if it accepts an inflammation on the tonsils where usually we have children with good health,
you see fever 40-41-42 and still they are alive and then tonsillitis.
It accepts the inflammation, does not allow the inflammation to go on a deeper level.
What is going to happen with that child that accepted the inflammation so deep,
as it comes up, it’s going to accept and inflammation on a level which is better
but still it’s going to be severe. And this is the situation we have here.
And we have to manage. During the acute treatment I gave two remedies
that were wrong most probably, Sanicula and Bryonia. And the third remedy acted. That’s no good.
It may delay the progress of the case in general.
You have to understand that, acute manifestations are not separate from the chronic conditions.
As the person progresses in chronic conditions, we have acute manifestations.
Progresses more, another acute manifestation, progresses more.
This is a whole organism who is progressing, who is doing that.
At the point where you don’t come with the right remedy, it may still be severe,
like the case I mentioned to you with the cancer, metastasis etc.
As it was coming up, the heart was giving because the cancer on that level was pushed down
and the heart gave in. The heart gave in? You have to give the right remedy.
Otherwise he will die, the child if it doesn’t get the right remedy, it will die.
It will go to pneumonia and die.
It’s very severe still, it is in a serious condition.
That’s why you have to understand now this is serious, be careful, don’t just throw remedies.
This is a case where you can not afford to say by telephone, take that.
You will say why you did it? I can not fly to New Zealand and prescribe.
-Yes you can!
-I know but I don’t know if I will arrive dead or alive in New Zealand.
It’s 25 hours of travelling, I can not take it but that’s not the case.
He is meaning another thing of course, not for the child, for other children…
But you have to have in mind all these things and when he tells me,
I have kept him one hour on the telephone, asking all kinds of questions,
still the picture may not be correct.
When I ask you to describe this child, you describe it in a different way, each one of you.
No one gave me the main points which I wanted, which I looked.
And it’s very important for those that supervise others.
When a case is not going well, they say bring me the case, I want to see the case.
It’s a different picture all together.
I wanted just to tell you a little story, just to show you the importance
of seeing really the patient.
I wanted to go to Mount Athos in Greece. Mount Athos is a mount where all monks are.
It’s a great tradition. There it was a monk that I wanted to see very much,
I have heard he is very sick and accepts nobody.
So for years I had in my mind I want to see this man but he is sick
and he was really very sick.
At a certain point I received a telephone call from one of my students in Thessaloniki.
He says, would you help me with a case? Yes, which is the case?
This is the case, this monk.
I wanted to help him naturally because I wanted to see, he is the spiritual head of Athos.
It’s something special, I put all my attention, he told me and I can’t make out, head or tails.
I suggest three remedies for him.
He goes and gives all the remedies, one after the other, quickly
and later on I received a telephone call, no effect, pains, pains, he can’t walk, he
lies down, he is paralysed. He said, would you come to see him? I said, of course.
I take the plane and go to see the old man. I enter his cell, it is almost like a cave,
a little place, he was lying down there because he could not walk and I see the scenery.
What I see? What I see it’s a Sulphur picture.
And there is an eruption and I knew it, he had an eruption before.
He was (?) the eruption.
Is the eruption still there? Not as bad as it was before. It was withdrawn with cortisone.
Father put cortisone, all the doctors that went to visit him and prostrate to him,
say put cortisone and he was putting cortisone of course, he did not know,
the whole thing was inside.
Of course we had told him already to stop cortisone and all that but no effect.
We talked about not his case, what shall I ask a monk? What do you ask?
Are you afraid of dying or something like that?
But it was like an enlightenment, I wanted to help him
and I had prescribed three remedies already, no effect and as soon as I entered,
it was like a light.
He said, my legs are swollen, his stomach was perforated
by all the medicines he had taken before, the eruption…He says,
do you think if I shall walk again?
I said, not only you will go but you will go for pilgrimage to that monastery.
I had no idea that this place was four hours away from the monastery.
He says, I can’t get out of the cave, it’s four hours.
I said, god anyhow the next time I come you will come to meet me outside.
So I said to the doctor Sulphur low potency to come up slowly with low potencies.
I went back to see him two months after and by the time I arrived in the monastery,
he was outside doing something and he came to meet me, just for the prophecy
I said next time you will meet me outside.
I don’t know if he had been yet to the place that I promised him.
I didn’t promise, I just said it like that but he went to Mount Sina.
Mount Sina is near Egypt and he went for a pilgrimage there.
It’s now 4-5 years and he is doing fine. He is 76 now.
But it was just one look, why? Because I saw the important points.
And it’s not that I did not pay attention or you did not hear the symptomatology.
It is what we know about the different remedies, this remedy gives emphasis on that point.
And that is how we prescribe finally and we decide.
Oenanthe very good prescription, Agaricus very good prescription,
Arsenicum not a good prescription, Calcarea carbonica not a good prescription
but Zinc is the best.
-Is it possible to use this information with (?)
-Not to base your prescription on that.
You can take it into consideration in your analysis but not base your prescription.
Here in this case I don’t know. I would not have considered it strongly.
I can’t remember now. I tried to find out but the parents could not remember anything.
We didn’t discussed about this.
The child dropped and the child appeared to have no effect from that drop.
I think the child was given Arnica, something like that
but can we take into consideration, perhaps not.
We can not prescribe upon this information because we do not have really hard facts.
The child remained unconscious for one minute.
One minute is all right but the child nothing happened, they just picked him up
and children fell like cats.
Yes it is indicated (?) but I do not mention it because I do not take it into consideration.
Because somebody will get up and say, wait a moment, nothing happened to the child.
-Are the Down children more sensitive than normal children?
-I don’t know. I don’t think so.
No he was not.
The child was vaccinated before or after and the answer is no.
-(?)
-They were living under some power lines and there is a theory lately with the power lines.
-The father always mentioned big convulsions.
We saw yesterday the tape (?) I got the impression that the child had very small fits.
The child was sitting there (?)
-You mean now? You mean on the follow up or the initial?
-On the follow up.
-We can put it back and we see it.
-Why do you say (?)
-I have just explained that. The organism in order to accept a disease on a deep level,
like this kind of condition, needs a defense system which is compromised
and then accepts a disease.
Why a child that is playing normal and is normal comes down with encephalomyelitis?
And another child playing together he does not?
His immune system is prone to develop this severe condition.
So the child, as he progresses in health, his immune system becomes stronger.
He will accept a kind of same seriousness in a less serious organ.
-The lung?
-The lung. It could have been the kidneys, yes.
But I don’t say definitely lungs. I could have said a urinary infection.
I don’t want you to understand that he would definitely had a pulmonary problems.
He could have a urinary infection.
Put back.
The intention is to go and get it. This is very important.
The contact with the outside world is established.
You see the cerebellum is not functioning properly.
I have not seen that.
-He smiles.
He seems to become more and more secure.
He is trying to do it himself, he understands that they want him to walk.
It’s very interesting.
How many have seen the cerebelitis case? The Ignatia case. How many have not seen?
A similar, not similar this is much more severe, but a similar case of paralysis
due to the cerebellum, walked in the third day, got up and walked.
These children they relearn how to stand and how to walk because they lose it completely.
It’s like starting from the very beginning to walk, this is three and a half years old,
it’s learning now at the age of 12 months, how to walk.
-It can walk at 2-3 years.
-Yes but in this way can walk at 15 months.
-No they never walk in 15 months.
-In this way?
-No, when they start they are usually 2 or 3 years.
-The usual children can start walk in one year. 13,14 months,
in 15 months onwards the Down children can start doing this. 15,16,17 not three and a half.
But anyhow this child would never had walk the whole of his life with the atrophy
of the cerebellum would never had walk.
I would like you to see another case that will do that.
It’s not that he walks, he does not walk. It’s the fact that he becomes a human being again,
this is the main thing but the cerebellum definitely is functioning again
and this is the main thing again.
I hope to be able to show you this child at the age of 5 or 6
and he will be a normal Down child, where it was an autistic child, totally autistic child.
What improvement is, these children are sensitive to infections, very sensitive.
They get severe, frequent infections. You may bring them to the point
where they do not get so frequently infections. They eat better, they feel better,
their mind functions better but still they remain with the congenital problem.
For living?
I have not so much experience. I will not tell you I have seen 100 cases.
I have seen a few cases of this.
She says that they never have an IQ more than 40 and they can never write.
Let’s not go to that argument because we all know that we have several groups,
several severities of the disease.
What we are concerned here is how to find the right remedy and do whatever is possible to do.
What we are showing with the video is what is possible to do, if we prescribe correctly
and the remedy is correct for different reasons and this is the result if we do it correctly.
Anybody else?
-A question about the cancer case?
You said that the bones (?) metastasis quite quickly (?) how long (?)
-It depends on the organism. You can not say after 3 or after 6 days or a month.
You can’t say.
When we have a metastasis case, we usually get it when they are metastised
either on the brain or the bones. When these cases come to us they say,
can you do something? So my experience is that these cases they will die,
if they come to that stage.
You can not cure them completely and have them living for another 10 years.
But my experience is that the pains are reduced from a few days, let us say after one week
or within a month, in this space of time they are reduced and they appear to be doing well.
There is a time where there is a relapse of the pains.
If the relapse comes, then its’ much more difficult to control
because you need to change remedies etc.
And you control it and then relapse, more difficult.
Then there is a point where you will need to give pain killers, derivatives of morphine.
In that moment, as soon as you start the morphine you have a dead person, the pain continues,
it goes steadily up, stronger, stronger, stronger, more the morphine and they die.
This is the pattern which I have experienced with cancer cases.
I had a case with a big tumor, metastasis and diffused.
She came after a year, she says I’m all right, no pains, nothing.
A year later it was a relapse, severe pains again, I could not control them, morphine,
in the hospital, 10 days she went away.
I have a case now in London from a hospital, I don’t remember the hospital,
an English hospital who are treating her and she came to Athens to be treated,
metastasis on the bones and the brains. Several points in the brains
and several points in the joint here.
It was eaten up the bone, she came with…
I said I’m sorry I can’t do anything, this has too far gone, metastasis on the brain
and metastasis on the bones, too much pains and she was taking pain killers.
She said, no I had a message from god that you are going to cure me.
I said, I can’t cure you, never mind the message, you have the message
but I don’t have the means to cure you.
No she says, I’m positive and she (?) through my secretary in London,
I refused the case and she went through a friend and another friend and they pressed me,
I did not know she was the same woman.
When she came I found out she was the same but I had refused.
I said no, I can’t give you she was taking chemotherapy and she was taking pain killers.
I can’t, forget it and she said, no I’m telling you that god has told me,
she was absolutely positive that god had told her…
I said maybe the fact that she is so assured, maybe I have to do something.
I took her case and the doctor we took the case together is here.
I took her case and Platina came out clearly.
I said god, maybe the message was right because usually in such cases
you do not get a clear picture.
So I prescribed. She said, what about the chemotherapy?
I said, if you take together with chemotherapy maybe the medicine I’m going to give you
is not going to work.
OK, then I stop the chemotherapy and I stop the pain killers.
I said, you can’t stop the pain killers and you can’t stop the chemotherapy.
She says, why? Because the pains are going to be so severe
that you are going to jump out of your bed.
She said, no if you say that it is going to interfere, I will stop. I said god.
She was there convinced absolutely, she had come, actually she had told my secretary
she will pay 10.000 £ for one visit.
She was a rich woman but I said never mind if she pays me 1.000.000 I can’t see her
I said to my secretary. She telephoned again and I said forget it
and then she tried with a friend and she was there. That is the whole story.
She was so convinced that if I see her, she will be all right.
I said maybe what they call autosuggestion, maybe I should not take away her hope
but I could not promise anything. She says, you are going to treat me?
I said, no and I have to say it plainly no I can not cure you, it’s too far gone.
No, I know you will cure me.
Immediately she stops pain killers, stops the chemotherapy.
-What potency?
-High potency 1M and I gave low potencies as well 12, at the same time, one every day.
She calls me after a week, I said how are you doing? Fine she says.
What do you mean fine? She says, I’m fine. You don’t have pains? No.
How is your appetite? Oh it’s great.
You mean you are eating? Yes, I’m eating, I put on weight.
You put on weight within a week? Yes.
How is your general state and everything? Fine. OK call me after 15 days.
She calls me after 15 days, when I told her to call she would call immediately.
She calls after 15 days, she is doing fine. Initially I told her I want to see her after a month.
After a month she comes there without the stick, better appetite, looking different person.
I said go back, we continue. One day I receive a telephone call
and she was screaming on the telephone. I broke my rib she says.
How do you know? I don’t know how it happened but I’ve broken my rib. (?)
She said no but the pain is severe, in the whole night I have not slept,
the pain is tremendous and I’m sure I broke my rib. I said, you did not break your rib,
it is just the cancer pains, I told you.
You said, you are going to stand the pain, now stand the pain.
Now morphine again. I said OK, try again Platina 1M and if within 24 hours
the pains will not stop, you will have to take morphine again.
She tries the Platina and the pains stop immediately and while she was taking Platina 12
and the pain stopped immediately.
How do you explain that?
The cancer is better? She said I’m better, what do you think am I going to be cured?
I said I don’t know if you are cured but what you are telling me that you are better,
the remedy is acting, you have more appetite, more energy…
In London I saw her after three and a half months. She comes without a stick,
she was jumping, she said, I’m dancing now.
In the meantime in the hospital they monitor her.
I said they have to monitor you, so they give me the feedback from the hospital.
Every time she would go to the hospital, they say no, no you are having cancer,
you have to understand that you have cancer, you can not be cured.
She says, in the hospital they told me I can not be cured. I said, well they are right.
The doctor of the hospital writes a letter to the doctor with whom I have seen the patient.
He says this patient has stopped taking her chemotherapy,
while she was doing sympathetically well.
When I saw her she was doing sympathetically well with the chemotherapy.
Now four months, five months later where she does not take any chemotherapy,
there is no pain, the appetite is better because she had nausea and all these things,
now she is not doing well because she is not taking her chemotherapy.
And in the letter there was a threat that her homeopath had stopped the chemotherapy.
Now you come to my position after all this.
They do not know anything of what has happened, what pressure was under, medical pressure,
whatever you want it.
And then they want feedback. They said, why don’t you give us statistics?
How can I give statistics when you write letters of that type.
She was doing sympathetically well when she came on that chair, she was eaten up.
I said to her, I never told you to stop. He writes that I told you to stop the chemotherapy.
She says, yes but you told me to stop.
I said, I do not tell you to stop, I said the remedy will not work with the chemotherapy
and you decided to stop the chemotherapy.
She said that’s correct.
It’s correct but it is different story by saying to the doctors in the hospital
that I told you to stop the chemotherapy.
Anyhow she gave hell to the doctors as well. She was a powerful woman and the hospital,
in the credit of the doctors finally, they telephoned a clinic
in which I’m connected as an advisor in London and they said,
we are interested to send cases to see what you can do with the alternative therapies
that you are doing there.
But I had to tell her to start again the chemotherapy.
I said, no you start again the chemotherapy.
If she dies, she will die because she started the chemotherapy?
I do not believe that the case is cured, even the reaction I believe that we can not say
that the patient is cured.
Cancer, when it reaches that state, we can ameliorate the cases.
we can make them feel better, we can make them die better but they will die.
And if she had died with (?) Homeopathy, then it’s a crime
but she should have been dead 3-4 months ago. Already she is alive one year now.
- (?) die with chemotherapy?
-It is all right if they die with chemotherapy. Nobody to be blamed.
But I have seen cases with metastasis on the brain, they don’t live more than 3-4 months,
3 months finished and she is over a year now and she is still alive.
Now in the beginning of July she started chemotherapy, so let us see what happens.
-What is the idea of 1M and 12? What is the idea that it should be given 1M first?
-It’s experimental. In cases that are severe, you give a remedy high potency
and it gives a push but the pathology being too gross, brings back the case.
So are you going to give a push on high potency all the time? Push, high the pathology,
bring them back.
It’s something which we can not predict.
With the child with the atrophy of the cerebellum, I could not predict that he would walk.
If I had predicted that, I would say after 5 years.
Yes, when it has a relapse, I wait very carefully.
The problem with Homeopathy is the second prescription.
The second prescription is very important because that is the time
where mostly make the mistakes.
Cicuta, give it again, give it again, then Tuberculinum,
you see again the Tuberculinum what it has done for the child.
It spoiled the case completely, totally.
This boy can regress into the state in which it was originally.
And then I would like to hear an explanation, what took place and I believe this boy
if it has taken a scanning, his scanning for the cerebellum it will be normal
in two years the most, in one and a half year,
in six more months cerebellum must be in its place back.
And these Down children never stay for long periods of treatment.
You treat them for a period of time and then they disappear.
At least I have not attended cases for a long periods of time to see what happens
on a long treatment, on a correct treatment and it’s difficult to find the remedy with the Down
children, it’s very difficult because the organism is not strong enough,
is not giving out strong symptomatology.
Why we say in Homeopathy a case is incurable? Why?
If we find the remedy, the right remedy is going to act. How long is it going to act?
If the liver is destroyed at 90%, we have cirrhosis of the liver,
you are giving the right remedy and you are going to have a good reaction.
It seems that it’s functioning but after a while everything is back, why?
Because the organ is destroyed.
Now push again. How you are going to push? By high potencies or low potencies?
So you try first with the low and then if you need you go high.
When I had a real relapse of the pain in Platina, I again prescribed Platina high.
If I had given Platina high 1M constantly to overcome the pathology,
she would come in a relapse and I would not have any means to face that,
where I did not know whether this is right or wrong.
I’m telling you my ideas, you experiment with them, you try them out and give me your feedback.
Don’t expect me that I will give all explanation.
I’m not god that I will tell you this is what it is. I do not know everything.
I’ve given you my experience. That’s why when you come to my lectures,
you try to get my experience, that’s all.
You go to all other teachers, wherever you can learn, to the books
and you take everything from everybody and make your own assumptions
and your own final decisions, what is right and what is wrong.
I don’t want you to treat me as somebody who said… George said that.
Yes George said that, OK but it’s his opinion, his understanding and his experience.
That’s all I want you to understand.
It is my experience and I’ve given it to you, you try, you experiment, you find another way.
I went to India, they invited me there to give lectures and many doctors came
and I said you are talking about not repeating the remedy.
I’ll show you, she pulls out pictures of (?).
All these cases have been cured by CN potencies every day. For how long? For
months. 6 months, 7 months. What shall I say?
This is his experience. The only thing I said I would like to see these cases
and examine them myself, how they were in the beginning and how they are now, the cure.
And if I’m happy with what took place, I will change my mind and I will try it myself.
But if somebody wants to do that and believes that this is the right thing,
I said another experiment.
I said, you come to me and I find for you the remedy, your remedy
and this remedy you take in CN for three months. First yourself.
You take it for three months yourself and then if you have good results, give it to your patients.
Then I will believe that you are honest in what you say.
But you come to me, don’t take any remedy that has nothing to do with you.
I can take for proving any remedy but it’s not going to help.
But the right remedy given in a high potency 4 months, I believe it’s going to do some damage.
I have not done it myself or to anybody.
-So you think it was necessary (?) to give the 12?
-Yes I thought it was necessary but maybe it’s wrong, I can’t prove that it is right.
-(?)
-We can’t hear you.
-Can we use auxiliary means like herbal medicines and low potencies in different remedies?
-From my point of view I would say no. It doesn’t mean because I say no, you don’t do it.
Please go ahead and do it but for me it’s very difficult to understand the logic.
If I give high potency or low potency, there is a kind of logic.
Because if the high potency does not work, the disease is in low potency,
maybe the low potency will work and these cases are severe cases.
She was going to give up morphine.
And she would go home and would scream from pains.
I had to cover the case in every way possible, that is my logic
but also if I give another means, herb or other, how do I know which remedy has really acted
and how to proceed after that? This is a problem.
You see this case Cicuta. He gave Tuberculinum, he gave Cicuta again
and I said it’s going to do some wrong. But if I did not know
that have given in the beginning Zinc, Agaricus, Cicuta… Then what shall I do next?
On occasion of your question, I take the opportunity to express some ideas.
Don’t worry.
If I would give morphine? Yes.
-Potentized morphine?
-No, never.
I have not tried and I do not believe that it can act as a palliative,
a high potency of morphine.
-Taking the doctors to Court?
-Yes, I got this paper from this lady the day afterwards, then I knew better.
I said, that is the games you are playing? Now you give me this paper and she signs.
She says, I will sign anything.
Also I’m not in a problem because I never charged anything anybody. I just give advice.
Still all right.
Roger has a case from the time he was studying with us in Athens, a case of (?)
-(?) He took one dose of chemotherapy and he became (?) and I think you had said,
I remember the case.
how the (?) became better and he said from chemotherapy and you asked
what chemotherapy did he take and he says (?).
-Did you hear that story?
It’s very interesting because Roger said how is that possible
that chemotherapy would make him better mentally and emotionally except of the real,
physical problem and I said what was in the chemotherapy? That’s very interesting
because I’m in inquisity.
In this chemotherapy was his remedy? He goes and asks him and he says, Platina.
It was an oxide of Platina.
-(?) and he had symptoms of recurrence of the tumor and (?)
He was in NY going to all houses with homosexual and all (?) died from (?)
-You see we can not claim that we cure cancer with Homeopathy.
This we have to understand, if we go outside and we say, we cure cancer by Homeopathy,
between us we can discuss such cases but if we go out and we say we cure cancer,
they will attack and they will vicious and they will be right
because we don’t have the right to say, we cure cancer.
There are some cases of cancer which are cured in question mark.
I had another case that I had, as soon as, I went back to Greece in 1967
with cancer of the breast.
She didn’t want to be operated and they said, you have to operate, otherwise you die,
you know the doctors.
She came to me, I said I can not treat you. In ’67,
as soon as I came to Greece immediately to treat all the cancer cases,
then they would put me in jail.
She said, no I will die but I will not have an operation.
She persuaded me to treat her.
I treated her, a few years later, she went back to the hospital and said,
will you please make a biopsy to see what happens?
They did the biopsy, they said it’s not cancer.
She said but it was cancer and you advised me to cut my breast. They said, never.
She puts out the biopsy and says, here it is. Signed by the same man.
No, it was a mistake.
I continued to treat her. In 1984 I think, she had a relapse. From 67 to 84 she had a relapse.
I treated her, she did well. In 1986 she died from cancer without me.
She went to another town, she had another treatment, I heard she died from cancer.
Can we say we cured this cancer even if the doctors say it was a mistake
or anything like that? Can we say we cured it even after almost 20 years.
She still had a relapse after 20 years, so we can not say…
But you say, 20 years is good enough.
If I was able to promise that also, I would say yes we give it 20 years
and it is great but we can not, there are cases and cases and cases.
-You go to die from something.