-He is now 5 years, he becomes 6 years old in November this year
and he has enuresis nocturna.
-He has what? Enuresis.
-…It comes out, I’m not sure about this, measles and after this following scarlatina
and it started about 2 years.
I started also in this time to work half the day and there was another person who
was looking after him 5 hours the day. Before…
-During pregnancy?
-During pregnancy and also during the first years.
Then we discovered myopia, the right eye is not looking straight and he has myopia
the eye doctor wanted to give him a contact lens but he didn’t want to do it.
We had to hold him very strongly and after 3 times we tried to give him this lens,
he told us now we can let him and he will sit quiet and we can put this lens to his eye but
after this he started to stutter. After this holding he was crying first, he didn’t want to
get this contact lense and he started to stutter.
-They tried to put contact lens on him and he was very irritated and after this he started to stutter.
-Then he has a herpes simplex going out about after 3-4 weeks of sun and also problems and difficulties.
-Tell me what do you think about the character of this child? He is a nice child?
He is cute. It’s a child who creates sympathy towards him or repulsion?
-Sympathy.
-He tries to interrupt his mother.
-He tries to interrupt his mother. What it means? He has a strong character.
-Not shy.
-He is not shy, no. His look is a timid child? No, he is outward.
Perhaps too much outward? We don’t know.
Enuresis, why he has enuresis? Did the mother said anything that explains the enuresis?
-She started going to work.
-Family trouble during the pregnancy and the first year. So why he has enuresis?
Because he feels insecure. There is an insecurity.
Why do we have enuresis in children? Because of insecurity, one reason and they feel
that they are not loved or they have been frightened.
-Did she not say that it only started when she went to work?
-It’s not very clear but it’s a fact that there are some family problems and the child is left
with another woman and there is this scarlatina which intervenes  and
as a result of this complex we have enuresis.
At the same time the mother started to work
and the child stayed in the house with another person.
That means the child was three and a half when enuresis started.
That means a reason and when I say a reason it might be the insecurity which can be
created mostly by the feeling that the child is abandoned and it’s not loved or a great
fright that can take place. This child is very much afraid for something, afraid mostly
that his life will be taken away, he will be killed and then you see the enuresis.
When the child is punished aggressively by the parents, especially the father who is more
aggressive usually and in America the mother who is more aggressive usually…
You are looking for troubles.
One of the parents can be very aggressive and can grasp the child, I’ll kill you, don’t you
ever do it again.
Then that shock can create enuresis. Next day enuresis can start.
Or the child may consider in his mind that I’m not loved, I’m left. Then enuresis.
And it has to have a predisposition the child towards enuresis and then this predisposition
will manifest with a provocation and the provocation can be also severe disease that it is
going through.
I think it is the same thing. It is the predisposition of the child and the child most probably
one way or another feels insecure and continuous. But this problem is many times
hereditary. Many times you will hear the story that the parents will say or one of the
parents, it’s the same like me until the age of 11 I had enuresis. You may hear that
usually in these kind of stories. In these kind of stories usually you will not hear that story.
So you can not tell me anything more about his character?
-No.
-Let us hear about his character a little bit.
-Sometimes he is very aggressive. For example in the table if he dislikes something,
he tries to pick with the fork or to pick the knife and should get very angry and
then I say he has to go in the other room and just cry there and then after
sometimes he comes from this room and he takes the sword and says I cut you in the throat.
-The mother says the child is many times aggressive. He takes something and goes into
… with the fork, the knife and the mother says, if you do that out and the child goes out
and then he comes back with a sword and says, I want to kill you now.
It gives a description of the child, this is the child. You will say, the child is playing.
Yes but another child is playing in another way, he plays in that way, if he plays and how
much he plays because in that child we will see the aggressivity developing so much and
so overt and outgoing the aggressivity in children. They will be very aggressive.
They will hit, very aggressive, outside aggressivity where in another remedy we’ll see an
inside aggressivity, which I have described like in Hyoscyamus, the children in
Hyoscyamus because of jealousy.
The jealousy has been so great inside them, it has killed their emotions because they can
not tolerate the suffering that the jealousy brings on. They almost stay without emotions
in a world of madness and I have described these children how they will obey.
They will be good children, they will obey everybody but the aggressivity will come from time
to time to the extend that these children can kill somebody.
I described you in a position where there are two children playing and the one is very
jealous of the other and they are playing in the swimming pool and nobody is there.
And the one is standing in the swimming pool and Hyoscyamus will go back, will see
nobody is there and just pushes the little one into the swimming pool and then looks.
The child of 3 years old can not save himself and Hyoscyamus will think coolly, should I save
him or not? I think he is going to be drown, I think better go to my mommy and tell her.
Mommy, I think there is a problem. But coolly, you see the emotions of the child are
terrifying inside, this child will obey, will be nice but at a certain point the aggressivity will
manifest in that cool, blooded manner.
Here the aggressivity is overt, it’s another remedy, he says I’ll kill you.
And the mother says, I smack you, throw down this, kicks first and then it throws down
and then he runs. Maybe this is the kind, we’ll hear.
He understands what she is saying.
-He is very angry. If I put him again in the room, he tries to bite me and kick me and scratch.
-Did you hear? He will bite the mother, kick her, do something.
It is inside, the child cannot control all these reactions.
Which is the child who is behaving in this way? Let’s see more.
You see his eyes, he perceives what is going on. That now mother says
I'll get you, wait until outside.
-He had problems with his ears. He can’t hear enough for 2-3 weeks and then it goes away.
It can be only a reflection of also water, maybe.
He has fear in dark, he doesn’t like to sleep in the dark.
-He does not like to see the dark, in the dark is not happy at all
but you see here he looks quite sweet.
-He doesn’t like to sleep alone. When his brother is not there, I have to sleep by him
because he is coming in the night and he doesn’t want to sleep.
He doesn't like to drink milk. After milk he has very soft stool.
-After milk soft stools, diarrhea after milk you will find it.
-And he has a very [bad sound] he doesn’t get so much sleep and
his brother is 6 years older and he has no [bad sound]
He is a very strong [bad sound] during first sleep.
-You see how sweet, they behave very sweetly these children, they are very sympathetic
but when the time comes… they attack and they are very sympathetic children.
Usually they are the children which everybody likes, they say what a nice person until
their instinct comes and they hit and the violence appears. But it’s not constant violence.
Constant violence we have when this remedy develops into deep pathology and you see
very great violence. It is characteristic of these children to be sweet, to be liked, they find
a way to be liked and then suddenly they attack.
-In the kindergarten he is more big and strong and the boys are afraid of him because he
has such a strong energy to bite them and to do everything else and the children are afraid.
-All the children are afraid of him, he will hit them.
We have to stop because I have to close the circuit.
So we continue with the case yesterday. The child is a very interesting child, a lot of energy.
These children they have a lot of energy, too much.
Tarentula children, Veratrum children, Stramonium children they have a lot of energy that
they have to spend and in a different way, the most destructive, which is destructive energy.
The most destructive are the Stramonium children. They have a lot of energy that comes
out in fits of anger and the fits are so strong and uncontrollable that they can do harm.
Even the children.
The Tarentula children can be very active in moving about, up and down, they will spend
a lot of energy in motions and they will do all kinds of mischievous things.
The energy which comes with the Stramonium children is energy from the subconscious
I would say and unloading of the subconscious. The subconscious mind takes over,
they have no barriers.
The Tarentula, the energy is physical energy, they go into fights all the time, they are in a
state of tremendous energy which is produced and it has to be spent all the time.
The Stramonium children are not like that. Energy is produced in fits and then seduced.
They may even go to sleep, when they sit down without doing anything, they go like that.
They can be very passive, you think they are very passive, the Stramonium.
The fit comes… passive.
Tarentula a lot of physical energy, energy which is coming all the time, it is like
burning up energy, inside.
With the Veratrum, the energy is mental. It is as if there is a lot of mental energy,
a lot of thinking. It is also a kind of restlessness but the energy will be on a mental level.
Thinking all the time and thinking which is not productive, thinking…
if they are in a position to think because later on in pathology they become completely...
If you see artistic children who are Veratrum, then the energy is not so much mental anymore
but it becomes also physical and there is a lot of action and they want to keep busy
with something, which has no meaning but they want to keep busy with something.
The Stramonium is frightful to look upon during the crisis while they are very cute children
when they are out of crisis, cute, nice, sweet. You won’t believe.
In our books we describe all this violence of Stramonium and then somebody comes to
your office, sits there, he is so nice and he says, how can I give Stramonium?
He is so nice and in the book what I’ve read is blah, blah… I’m giving you the real picture.
For instance, in the consulting room the Stramonium will move very little, like this child.
We have some kind of restlessness. If that was a Tarentula or a Veratrum would go all
about like a machine; mostly Tarentula but the Stramonium a little bit of restlessness or
no restlessness at all.
Sometimes when they sit there in the chair, they will sleep in the chair in the consultation room.
But when the crisis comes, you see no control, they become another person all together.
And Stramonium children sometimes will be very sweet all day, never aggressive,
the parents will describe them as very passive children, nice children, with no real problems.
Maybe they will just urinate during the night but the aggressiveness will come out during sleep,
the subconscious will take over them during sleep.
During that time, they wake up every night almost, with frightful images, frightful dreams
and they wake up and they are voiceless and you see their eyes full of fright.
And they stare and they scream and you say, I’m here what happened? You are there
and they keep on looking. They look an image, which is in the dream and continues,
while you think that the child has opened his eyes. They do not see the reality.
They see what is in their subconscious. What is in their subconscious?
The fears that have been created due to stresses. You will tell me the stress is enough
to produce a Stramonium child?
Sometimes if the stress is a lot, it can produce, just by the stress without the child being
really Stramonium child. You give a tremendous fright to a child and in the night, it wakes
up terrified, seeing monsters, seeing snakes, seeing people that come to get it, if they
can describe, usually they don’t remember but that remains all the time until they are
pacified and they go back to sleep. They do not really come out of that state.
This kind of description, if the parents will give it to you, even if the child is very nice, very sweet...
These children have no problem during the day.
Such children, as I said, can become Stramonium because of fright. The other children
that are Stramonium they need a little bit of fright, they do not need very much, they just
need a slap one time, they wake up or they see some frightful things, they observe
outside in their environment. The father grabs the mother and the child gets the fright.
From that moment onwards, you may have the ignition of the situation.
To ignite something is to start fire.
It is an interesting thing also to observe in Stramonium children, that we are talking about
in this case, it’s very interesting for me when I realized it eventually, that they have a kind
of meditative mood and also some kind of, when a child maybe understands more than you.
You know these children? They don’t talk, they stay serious and maybe he understands more than me.
They give you that impression.
With Tarentula is another thing all together. Yes, its’ aggressive also.
With Hyoscyamus, I talked to you about one state of Hyoscyamus yesterday.
It’s not all the Hyoscyamus children they reach that end stage, this is quite deep stage when
they remain without emotions, cool. There is another stage where they are quite violent,
expressing violence as well the Hyoscyamus children but not to that extend that
we have been talking about.
With Stramonium they express anger, they express jealousy and there is a tendency to
strike, a desire to hit. With Hyoscyamus we don’t see the realization of the desire, as
much as we see the desire. You see the difference?
The organism does not have the energy really to come up and really strike.
Where Stramonium when the impulse to strike comes up, nobody can stop him.
It’s the same thing with grown ups,, they have to put them on a straight jacket.
Otherwise they will hit a lot of people. The energy is aroused and the energy is aroused
in all mental cases but mostly when we have Tarentula, Hyoscyamus, Stramonium, in
these cases, mostly Tarentula. The Tarentula has tremendous power which overcomes…
I remember a case, he was a man working for a bank, the Bank of Greece and you know
in the bank there are offices all over the place.
If somebody on the fourth office had or he thinks he had insulted him, he said I did not
have the time to go through the corridor and find him. I would jump over 1,2,3 and grab
him and say, what did you say? The power when you see it, that kind of thing.
He was supposed to be a sane man living in the society among others but nobody dared
to insult him after a certain period of time. After Tarentula he says, I can’t believe it,
they make jokes and he says, I don’t react, what has happened to me?
There are so many facets.
What I try to give you is main ideas that run through the remedies.
And if you get these ideas, then you recognize but it is not possible for me to give you all
the possible modifications of all the remedies in every situation, neither I can remember of course.
The only thing that remembers is this bloody machine that we are involved now.
Let’s see a little bit of that.
-He can also [bad sound]…
-You see how sweet he is?
Sit down. Sit there.
You try to aggravate them, you can not aggravate them. You shout, the time has not come.
If the time comes, you don’t have to aggravate them, they just jump and they hit you,
nevermind what. You don’t have to shout, you just have to look at them and they look
at you and you understand they are coming, the instinct is coming, you feel it. I’ve been
hit by children like that. I came to the house and they hold the mother and they look and
then suddenly they surround and hit. Then I played games, I pretended nothing
happened to see how it will go about, it won’t pacify them. If you go against them, they
will attack again, if you are very calm, it doesn’t matter until the crisis is over, until what is
inside is finished.
You see now? I shout at him, he is very nice. He will sit there.
I can’t speak his language.
It’s OK, let him fight.
Enough, sit down.
You see how lovable they can be? They are affectionate, very sweet until their time.
-Is he crying?
-He pretends he is crying.
Sit down. I will smack you.
-He doesn’t want you to see him crying.
-Why? He is looking nice when he is crying? He is very cute.
You are very lucky.
Sit down there. You understand what I said?
[Bad sound]
You are angry?
-Yes.
-You want to hit me?
-Try and see what happens. I hit you back.
-Yes.
-Sit there, good boys sit there. You will sit, I’m telling you.
-No.
-Why?
-Because he wants to have…[bad sound]
-You lie to me.
-He wants to go out.
-Why?
-He forgot his bread.
-And he wants to go out, just now he remembered his bread?
-OK go and get your bread.
You see if I had managed to irritate him, he would immediately go and hit his mother.
Maybe he would not hit me but he would go to his mother but it’s not his time.
It’s the sweet time for Stramonium.
They understand very well, they have a perception because they have strong feelings
they perceive very easily what is taking place around them.
He perceives that I changed, never mind I shout, he knows I’m playing, he doesn’t take me seriously anymore.
In the beginning he was not certain, he almost made a mistake.
-OK go and get your bread.
-I have to go with him.
You see this child looks like Baryta carbonica. He holds his mother, he doesn’t look, he is shy,
you can make a story if you don’t know the real picture.
The Stramonium can be affectionate, can be sweet. You make it as a Baryta carbonica child.
The Baryta carbonica child will sit exactly like he sits, it is a grown up child,
he will hold his mother and he will not look at you.
That’s the main features for Baryta carbonica but Baryta carbonica will never be violent.
-Is he afraid of animals, dogs?
-No, if they bite him yes.
-He likes to swim in the sea?
-He likes but he is also afraid to go into the deep water. He can’t stay.
-How is his sleep?
-He sleeps well.
-He is not restless when he sleep?
-No.
-He doesn’t wake up in a nightmare, shouting, screaming?
-Not very often. In this time, these 5 weeks, he was crying.
-Have you ever you or your husband frightened him?
-Yes.
-What he did?
-He told to my husband please stop now and he comes to me.
-He is more attached to you?
-Yes.
There is another point with Stramonium that you have to know.
Imbalance in the human body goes up and down. It can change levels.
When you see that same child can become quite controlled in his behavior and then you
may start seeing the disturbance on a more peripheral level in the nervous system and
you will see grimaces, different kind of grimaces and the child is normal emotionally.
But all the time, what is this?
Like Agaricus also, it’s similar. It is more aggressive.
Stramonium is… I can’t reproduce everything.
Different ticks, quite strong, quite frequent and eventually you may see movements
where the whole nervous system is involved like choreic movements, not chorea.
You can see chorea as well but before he reaches chorea state, just the previous stages,
if you can imagine.
-More in the adults?
-More in the adults but in the children also.
Especially when they are real Stramonium children and they have a severe fright.
I had seen a child, I had seen the scene in front of me, it took place when the father
grabbed the child because it was not listening. Come here, no. Come here, no.
Come here now. No, I will not come. The father grabs the child…