-Before your disease were you ever depressed or suicidal?
-No, I loved to live.
-What it was like to be in an orphanage when you were 10 years old?
Why you were there?
-Because my mother couldn’t take care of me anymore. She was out in the country.
-His mother was in an Indian.
-She was Red Indian. American Indian.
-What it was like to be in an orphanage? Do you remember your emotions?
-Hell.
-Why?
-You were 13 years old when you run away. Why it was hell? What did they do?
-Just read the newspaper.
-It was a lot of sexual abuse in these places, they’ve been finding out about and physical
abuse in these orphanages.
-Now that you remember this and you wanted to cry or no?
-Yes.
-Some crying came.
-Did you have any feeling, any constriction in your throat?
-Yes, of course.
-Do you ever experience any kind of a lump in your throat, like if there is a lump that you
try to swallow and the lump stays?
-Almost permanently a sensation of a lump, I have to do many times. I’m not doing it too much
because the therapist teaches me how not to do it. He told me not to do it.
-To take it away he has to swallow the sensation of the lump in the throat.
-Do I answer your question fully? Yes I don’t want to talk about it but the reason is not
that, it is that you may not be familiar but there is a big enquiry going on now and I’m part
of the group who is suing the government.
-He is part of a group that suing the government right now because of what happened in
this orphanage. So I don’t want to speak too much about it.
-Can you say what is going with the emotions?
-Because of the treatment that was going on there, I was not aware of what they were
doing but someone came to see me and say, why don’t you join us to help us with new
people. I said OK.
-He finally agreed to be part of this group to take on the government.
-For me the past is the past...
-He tries to forget the past.
-It is the way it was then and if people didn’t like it, the only way was to jump over the
fence and run. Life is like that. The disease is the same thing.
You don’t ask for it, it just happens.
-For legal reasons you can’t speak right now?
-No, I could speak but I want to stress that I had forgotten about all these things but all
these meeting we had, start meeting about this bad treatment, I wanted to forget this and
now it’s more than what they did then…
-It didn’t hurt so much at the time but now when he hears other stories it hurts a lot more.
-You have kids, I don’t want this thing to happen to them and now people are talking,
they are crazy about them and this has been happening for 25 years,
maybe it is still happening, there is nothing I can do about…  and nobody is doing anything.
-Nobody is doing anything so that’s why you’ve decided to participate?
There is still happening.
This type of abuse that was happening in this orphanage, it’s still happening.
You are concerned about that?
-Of course I am. But I don’t think it has any bearing.
-You don’t think it has any bearing.
-No, because all these days my feeling about this, I didn’t know about it. If you are born in
a cage and they bit you then that’s life.
-But I think what I had to go through in there prepared me to be what I am…
-That prepared him and gave him the guts to do something in his life.
-I don’t think it has any bearing of what is happening to me today.
-He doesn’t think it has any bearing with the way he is today.
-Not to say I’m quite conservative. I just said that’s me and maybe someone can do
something.
-I see.
-When the people started asking you to participate in this and you started reading the
stories about what happened to other people, when was this?
-Some of the people involved, came two years ago, there was an enquiring and for some
reason some documents had to come out. One of the guys there, he is a friend of mine,
he said I know you know some people in the right places, can you help us? I said I do
whatever I can. So I phoned some people and they did something about.
-He called some people in the government.
-There is a lot of news about this kind of situations. When did you first read about it?
-For 5 years now the case is coming out. Now it’s coming out every day.
-Do you recall your feelings when you first started reading about those cases?
-I did not want to talk about them. The way I look at it is maybe different like the way I
took the disease. People tell me that I’m crazy but to me the abuse and my view I’ve
been involved with the case, life is not an easy thing. Maybe for you it was but for the
poor people they have to find the way. Life is tougher and tougher and like now I’m
always happy to be sick and have a pension for the rest of my life.
So I’m not through of what happened in the past. I don’t think it hurt me that bad.
-When it was originally diagnosed that he is having ALS, does he know the laboratory
Tests were done that he had and have any idea about the findings?
-Yes, it’s all here if you want to read it.
-Does he have the laboratory picture?
-It seems to be 80% conclusive, not 100%.
-Did they do a scan of the spinal cord or just the blood tests?
-He has been to 5 specialists.
-All of them have agreed?
-They all agreed?
-Yes, they all agreed.
-Nobody knows my doctor,
his name is Jeffrey Ruben and he is probably known as the best neurological doctor
about the disease, to show you...
He didn’t know then but he gave me a name and it was my doctor but they sent me to
other people.
-He says it is very conclusively diagnosed that he has an ALS.
-Did you ever have any skin eruption, any eczema?
-About 10 years ago, I had a small spot on my nose, it wouldn’t go away like sun paper
but then it went away.
-Just by itself? You didn’t put any cream or cortisone?
-I’m against all these things. I didn’t take any medication until now, nothing. Not even an
aspirin.
-Except of the cramping. –Yes.
-They just come and go.
-They had prescribed me something to control the laughing and the crying but I didn’t
take them because …
-He is not taking any drugs.
-Nothing, I’m OK. I look OK. I’m only handicap.
-Does he have any nightmares or dreams about this time?
-That question has been asked at least a 100 time. No.
-He has no bad dreams about the past, no nightmares.
-I’ll ask some more questions concerning his reaction to weather, whether is a person
who feels very much the cold or very much the heat. How is your reaction to weather?
-I prefer cold weather.
-I want to ask your desire for any kind of food. Do you have a desire for food?
-Fish.
-All kinds of fish?
-Anything that comes from the sea. Of course salt.
-Strong desire for salt.
-Salty things like salty sardines?
-Yes, I love them. Any kind of sardines I will eat them. The best ones are the Portugese.
-When you are in a restaurant and you are eating before tasting your food, will you take
the salt and put salt?
-Yes.
-Very good, we start all over again. What about meat? You eat meat?
-Yes, I would prefer pork.
-Do you like the fat which goes with pork?
-Most of it.
-That’s why you eat it… You like to have some fat.
How much thirst do you have? Are you very thirsty, you drink a lot?
-Not very thirsty. Now I drink because I’m a bit stressed, this is not something I do every
day.
-He has an aversion to beef and to meat in general, he doesn’t like meat.
-Unless it’s alive.
-Do you mean…?
-Women.
-He likes women. Of course who does not?
-There are some people.
-Tapioka he doesn’t like.
-What?
-Tapioka. Do you know Tapioka?
-No.
-It is a kind of a pudding.
-Forget it.
-Terrible.
-Sweets? –Not very much.
-Ice cream? –Yes.
-Every day?
–No. After a good meal.
-What about fears? Do you have any fear? Fear of dark, fear of being alone in the
house, fear of thunderstorms, fear of animals, fear that somebody is behind you, any
type of fear, fear of high places?
-Nothing.
-Can you zoom on his thenar [thumb], on his left. This is typical, as you know, of ALS.
Anybody that wants to ask some questions? To look for something.
He wants to look at the tongue.
Why do you bite the tongue? Don’t bite it, let it without biting it.
-It makes a spasm by itself when he puts his tongue out.
-I can’t do it.
-Is any salivation in the night during sleep?
-At one point I used to wake up and be very very dry, now I do.
-But not excessive?
-No.
-Anybody wants more questions?
-It was any trembling?
-No, the tongue seemed convoluted like in a permanent spasm.
-Your thirst is for cold drinks?
-Yes. I would prefer my beers coming out from the cellar.
To answer his question…
-Fibrillation of the muscles, there is a little bit of fasciculation in the tongue and the
muscles like when you go to grab something.
-I have to be careful. I’m lucky. For some reason it works, not always.
-You told us that cold weather... I’d like to know if you are worse …
-Are you worse in warm wet weather or dry wet weather?
-I feel better in cold weather.
-What is the worse for you? Dry hot?
-Hot and humid. I have some difficulty in breathing. The breathing is part of the disease.
-If I was a stranger on the street and met him and showed that I felt sorry for him…
-If people are sympathetic towards you and give you consolation,
does it a fact that effect you either way?
-First of all if you were in the street and you would be sympathetic to my disease, I would
be very surprised because almost nobody, even some doctors, know about the disease.
Secondly I would appreciate very much your concern.
-We have to thank you for your presentation.
-Thank you very much.
-This case reminds us of several remedies. Lathyrus sativus, Plumbum metallicum,
Thalium, Causticum, Lachesis, Cuprum, Cocullus, Natrum muriaticum, Ignatia…
What is the remedy? I’d like to discuss the prognosis of the case first. Is he gone?
This disease is like most chronic diseases, they appear in different forms of severity.
So if you go to the books and you read about ALS, they will give you a span of at the
most 5 years of survival. This kind of disease has 5 years of survival because then the
cerebellum is affected, there is no way of breathing or for swallowing and they die.
Sometimes they put them on artificial respiration and that is how they may survive a few
more years. Another characteristic of the disease, for those who are not familiar very
much or they don’t remember very much of their neurology, is that the disease on the
latest stages starts having severe cramps.
So a characteristic whether this kind of disease has progressed to a further stage, to a
progressive stage is the amount of cramps that they get. They get tremendous cramps,
which are very painful and they usually have to take a lot of pain killers, which speeds up
the process of deterioration and then they are finished.
So the prognosis is really very bad. He has progressed already to a progress stage of his
disease and so the disease is in its last stage.
But in his case there is a ‘but’ and if I had seen another case in that stage, I would give
very little hope for improvement, even little improvement and the improvement could only
be around the idea of pain. The pain could be reduced.
Not in his case. In his case I’m a little bit more optimistic, why? Can anybody tell me why
I’m more optimistic about this case?
-Because so far, so good and he is a lucky guy.
-I don’t go by luck, if I go by luck maybe I find that I don’t have luck but the mind is clear,
so this could give a good prognosis. In a way you may be right.
-I was going to add to that also that because in this case the disease seems to get to a
certain stage and then stop and it’s almost like the body itself is limiting the disease
process.
-Unfortunately by itself the vital force will not hold very much because it is a progressing
disease, a chronic disease and even if it appears to be for the last 6 months, as he says,
a kind of steadiness, still we can not hope for that reason. There is another reason for
which I’m a bit hopeful.
-If I understand well, he hasn’t taken any medicine.
-Yes but in this kind of disease there is no allopathic medicine.
For pain he could have taken some medicine.
-His medical story seems clear, he didn’t have any strong disease, he has been a healthy
person up to now.
-There is only one reason why I say there is hope and the reason is because his remedy,
the indicated remedy is clear.
Many times I have done predictions like that in front of the camera, so anybody could
catch me and say, what did you say? Look. So if I take chances like that…
That means the remedy is clear. Out of the remedies which I mentioned, which one or
there is another remedy perhaps, outside of these remedies which is the real remedy?
That is the problem I pose in front of you to solve it for me.
I used to play tricks in old times where I’d take one remedy, I’d prove that this is the
remedy, the whole class would agree and then I’d say no and then take another remedy,
prove the remedy and say no.
What we spoke in the beginning, where we said, it depends where you put your focus of
attention.
If your is on the wrong place, then you may draw the wrong conclusions.
I will give you an example and you will understand what I mean.
In this case anybody can argue that this a case of Natrum muriaticum? Why?
Because the man has been through a lot of grief, because he lost his parents, he had
been incarcerated in the orphanage, he had been molested and hurt and there is real
feelings inside him.
The moment that he spoke about this experience, his emotions were choked and with the
desire for salt so strong, grief with salt, salty grief as we say, Natrum muriaticum.
But there is a silence in him, he went through this grief and he did not complain, he did
not say anything to anybody.
And there is a constriction in the throat and there is a lump in the throat and there we
have Ignatia.
And there are fumes that have gone into the body and most probably quite a lot of lead
and this person could have been poisoned by ingesting a lot of lead because of the
exhaust gases where we live in our societies and because he had been exposed there.
We know that Plumbum causes syndromes similar to what you have seen.
And Lathyrus, if you read Lathyrus, so we learn a little bit Materia Medica, it says
affects the lateral and arterial columns in the chord, does not produce pain, reflexes
always increased, paralytic affections of lower extremities, spastic paralysis, lateral
sclerosis, what we he has, infantine paralysis, extremities:
tremulus, tottering gait excessive rigidity of legs, spastic gait,
knees walk against each other while walking, cramps in legs, worse cold and cold feet,
can not extend or cross legs while sitting, myelitis with spastic symptoms,
gluteal muscles and lower limbs emaciated, legs blue; swollen. Is this case?
Would you prescribe Lathyrus?
If you really know the Materia Medica, you go through a lot of remedies that look like but
what is the Similimum? What is the remedy that will touch such case?
This case will never be touched by any other remedy except of the Similimum.
You have to find it and if you find it there is a possibility of improvement, not only he will
steadify in its condition, where he is now and live for several years more but there is a
possibility for improvement.
How much improvement? I would say 30% which means you reverse the process of the
disease. Fantastic, he may live another 10-15 years if he doesn’t antidote your treatment
which is tremendous.
How his leg will be? Much improved, walk better but what you will see definitely and you
will compare with this picture that we have today after a year that his speech instead of
being worse, will be much better This is a typical speech he has.
Of what remedy?
When you look upon the case, there are so many symptoms for that first remedy that
comes to your mind that you can not go to another remedy. Which is this remedy?
Phosphorus.
How many symptoms you have? Seven. Show me this.
What is the remedy?
Lachesis. The remedy is Lachesis, a left sided affection with the constriction in the
larynx without being able to either swallow, when he says I jump from bed because
I’m choked typical Lachesis symptomatology.
Then he said he has a lump in the throat from which he swallows. You did not take into
consideration that symptom. He had a special training to stop doing that because the
feeling of the lump was there all the time and he had to have a special training from the
specialists to overcome this and the lump is there, swallow the lump, the lump comes
back.
So the sensation not ameliorated by swallowing, Lachesis is very prominent. You can not
go away from Lachesis, what is against Lachesis?
He sleeps on the right side, he can not sleep on the left but he is not loquacious.
Why he is not loquacious and why he is not jealous?
I’ve spoken about loquacity of Lachesis and I have said the loquacity of Lachesis comes
about mostly in women. Women like to talk, when there is a Lachesis woman there is
something lacking in her and this is replaces by a desire to talk, to talk is to communicate.
The desire to communicate in Lachesis is a substitute for a woman who has suppressed
her sexual desire.
Lachesis as a remedy is a remedy is with full emotions, full sexuality and a woman who
does not express that sexuality because of withdrawals, things are taken inside and are
choked here, in the area of the thyroid, the emotions are choked. They do not express.
If the mental state is affected, then we have mental symptoms.
In this case the mental state is not affected. In spite of the fact that he has been through
a lot of suffering in his life, we do not have pathology on the mental level.
So if you search for jealousy, you do not search for jealousy like normal jealousy, who
is not jealous, tell me who is not jealous? Put up your hands. One, two, put up your
hands. I’m not jealous and I know because I believed that I’m not jealous all my life.
To be jealous is normal in what conditions? If you are in love with somebody.
Then jealousy manifests. Jealousy does not manifest just by itself.
So if you are in love, then you come and tell me if the woman is interested to another
man whether you are jealous or not.
But if you are in a normal condition, that means if you are in love you are mad, but if you
are in a normal condition and you are healthy, you are not going to be jealous.
In Lachesis the jealousy is pathological. That means there is no reason for Lachesis to
believe that this man is going with another woman but she believes it. I’ve seen you.
When did you see me? When husbands of Lachesis women talk to us, they will say the
jealousy is insane because I have never done anything to provoke her jealousy and yet
she is jealous all the time. That is pathological jealousy.
When we are seeking for pathological jealousy, we have to see that kind of pathology.
But if the man is not in a love state, he may not show jealousy at all, if he is normal.
Another state in Lachesis is when you have Lachesis withdrawn inside, feelings inside,
then what happens is the jealousy also goes inside.
That means is not shown and instead an indifference takes place within the person.
Then you see a total indifference but underneath is the snake of jealousy.
It goes like a snake inside, eats him up, can not tolerate that feeling and then jealousy
feelings go away and are replaced by a state of indifference.
That can be Lachesis as well.
This man, if I ask him are you jealous, he says no I’m not. Is this going to hold me back
from prescribing Lachesis? Why? Not only that. I know that if somebody gets in this kind
of state, then mentally usually is better. So mentally I consider him quite healthy.
Maybe you are surprised but mentally and emotionally this man is quite healthy.
The fact that he has been through all the suffering in the orphanage…
Did you hear what he said? He said by that time I did not pay attention, I thought this is
life. What is there? And if you take it in this way, you can not get sick. If you accept...
Can you imagine in Russia, she comes from Russia, all these people suppressed by the
Russian police? It’s totally going to jail, going for years in closed places, they would be
very sick. Yet if you see some documentaries with them, you see how healthy still they
have remained.
Why? Because they have accepted, this is the government, what can we do, this is life.
For us to put us unjustly in jail, we’ll get sick within 24 hours. Why? Because you can’t
accept it but accept it. Go to jail, say the rest of my life here, no disease.
For him it was the same thing. It was acceptance, therefore I can not go and give Ignatia
or Natrum muriaticum. How do I understand that? From what he says. This is the man,
what he says, I evaluate what he says.
And I see all the anger that comes out. There was anger for what has happened but
afterwards. After they have come and approached him and told him, look what they are
doing to the children. Look what they are doing and this anger is expressed in action. He
takes part in an investigation and he says I want to help so that these people will be
punished. His anger is expressed. Therefore I don’t see pathology there.
The pathology is so close to the pathology of Lachesis and the organism is giving
pathology on physical level. So do not try to find pathology on the mental-emotional in
this case. Be happy and I’m very happy with the pathology that is given on the physical
level and I prescribe a remedy, not because of his pathology but because of the totality of
the symptoms in the physical pathology.
All the symptoms he relates are pathognomonic symptoms of his pathology that
constitute in the whole, keynotes of Lachesis.
In this case I focus on the information and I see the information is unique, it is peculiar.
Peculiar to what remedy? It happens to be all his symptoms peculiar to Lachesis…
How can I go away from Lachesis? I have to give Lachesis.
The wasting of the thenar muscle, this is again on the left side. So we have a wasting of
the muscle of the left side, which is again Lachesis. Lachesis covers that beautifully.
There is no problem with that.
-You give Lachesis repeated because it is something that might be very progressively
improved. So are you going to tell him to take it once the month? What do you do?
-That’s a good question. In such a case where we have such severe pathology, we may
have to stimulate with lower potencies and more frequently.
Usually I would like to stimulate with low potency, let us say 12X or 12C every day for a
month or two. But I have seen that Lachesis repeatedly given many times produces a
kind of proving, it’s easy to prove the symptoms of Lachesis and that’s why in this case I
will try a high potency 200 and if I see that there is improvement and then there is a
relapse, even if the relapse is after a month, there is improvement for one month and
then starts the relapse, I will repeat. But I will go about in this direction.
If now the Lachesis 200 does not give the expected results, then I will go lower in 12 and
I will repeat 12C, this is the hundred dilution, every day going up once, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16,
17, 18. I can go as long as I see some improvement, I can continue. If I see aggravation,
I will stop, wait, see the amelioration and then again.
-I’d like to make a little comment. This muscle is called dorsal interosseous, I don’t think it
matters. This is the thenar muscle.
-Very good. But this is the typical muscle, the dorsal interosseous but the thenar also is
affected in this disease. Both muscles are affected. Monkey hand.
So can you send me a follow up of the case after 6 months after this treatment in a video
where you make him walk, talk and ask him questions, how do you feel in all this respect
and then I can advice you further? So it’s a pity to lose such a case, just by making some
mistake and the improvement which I foresee that he may have, does not come.
It is one of the worse diseases of the human kind.
-Can you repeat the dilution as to how you would give 200CH?
-Repeat the 200 again, just one dose, wait and then repeat again and then wait.
Don’t be too much in a hurry to repeat.
-So you wouldn’t take the 12CH after that, like after the 200CH you would not go for…
-No unless there is no effect from the 200, for two months you wait, you see no effect,
nothing. Then you start with 12, 13, 14…
-Thank you.