I want to give you now a case and a remedy, it is a very well known remedy.
I’m no kidding, it’s a very well known remedy.
This is a 67 years old lady who came on 1978, beginning of 78.
-January?
-I say beginning because the date of the first interview is not written, so I look at the
second interview, which is the 4th of April, so it is the end of February.
Always you are concerned with the dates. It’s only him who asks, interesting.
It says that at night when she goes to sleep, she feels a noise as if somebody is breathing
on her face. She hears a noise and she feels the breathing and that goes down to her
stomach that starts pulsating. That symptomatology started 3 years ago.
She has tremendous nightmares where she sees ugly people making love to her and
frequently now she hears a voice in her ear to say names, John, Paul and this happens as
soon as she lies down.
Forgets very easily, she says I go to the kitchen to take something and as soon as I am in
the kitchen, I forget what did I come here for, forgets names of known persons, of relatives,
friends.
Her hearing is very bad on both sides and she has noises like bells and buzzing noises.
That is worse in the night, when she lies down.
She has stitches in her heart region and she has itching on the genitalia and on the
elbows, with intense itching and scratches until it bleeds, underlined 3 times, worse in the
night underlined twice and worse in the morning underlined twice and worse in warm
underlined once.
She is very much aggravated by heat underlined 3 times but cold weather brings up pains
in the ears. She is generally better in the sea underlined 3 times, cloud weather brings
about sadness.
Appetite is good. Everything she can eat but if she eats eggs she will have headaches and
allergies, desires milk, desires sweets underlined twice, drinks normal water but if she
drinks cold water, then she has pain in the stomach.
Sleeplessness, many thoughts that keep her awake, sleeps on the right side, feet are cold
and numbed.
A very well known remedy, don’t forget that, otherwise you make mistakes.
Very easily irritated underlined twice, no jealousy, weeps very easily and that relieves her
underlined 3 times, wants consolation no underline.
Fear of thunderstorms underlined twice and fear of loneliness.
Fear of dogs underlined once but she was bitten once by a cat.
That’s interesting she has fear of dogs but she has been bitten by a cat.
She did have the anti-rabies injection by that time.
Perspires a lot in the head and the perspiration is very offensive.
In the past history there is malaria which is not said when and
there is gonorrhea again in young age but it doesn’t say at what age.
That’s the case and this time I have not kept any information.
As far as her diagnosis is concerned what is happening allopathically?
She has acoustic delusions, she hears voices, she has other delusions feeling that
somebody is breathing in her face. If you put all this together, what she has?
-Arteriosclerosis.
-Arteriosclerosis, that is what it must be, putting together all the symptomatology we have
arteriosclerosis case. You don’t agree? What do you say?
Tell us. Can this be a mental case? It looks as if it can be a serious mental case of
schizophrenia?
You have to put down the loss of hearing in both ears, the loss of memory, forgets very
easily, the delusions together with the nightmares.
This symptomatology for me will indicate definitely an arteriosclerosis state, especially the
nightmares.
If you see a continuous series of nightmares in old people over 70, you expect a brain
stroke, soon if they don’t go into a strict diet, if they don’t take Homeopathy, especially if
the blood pressure is high.
Has anybody found that first symptom, somebody is breathing in her face?
After all this elaborate thinking, see what has happened.
She comes a month later, on the beginning of April 78 and she says I am the same and
she describes again the sensation.
She says I feel when I lie down that something is walking on my forehead, she describes it
in a different manner and then it starts a buzzing in the ears and
then I have a pulsation in the stomach, and then on the umbilicus.
There is a slight difference in describing the sensation but one month later she appears to
be the same, not worse and she is better if I put some warm application in umbilicus.
Many times I have been impatient but something is fluttering in the left ear.
The itching had been much worse and still is the same as before.
The buzzing in the ears, the noises in the ears continue.
Still she is aggravated by heat, now it is underlined twice but she says the fears are less,
she had fear of loneliness which is very strong underlined and fear of thunderstorms.
I don’t think she is talking about fear of thunderstorms but maybe.
Sleep comes easier but on the whole I feel more strong and psychologically I’m better.
What is your assessment here?
What are you going to do? Desires and aversions are the same.
-Wait.
-Who wants to wait? Who is in favor of waiting? My good students.
Very few homeopaths would wait like this and would try to give something else. The
sensation has changed now, let’s give something, whatever it is.
-Maybe we wait too long.
-Sometimes that is a bad thing.
So we lost that case, she didn’t appear again, so the report ends here but I believe she
must have been better and that’s why she didn’t come back.
-She would be one of those people that would drop a level?
-Yes I think so because it would be no big aggravation. She may stay and I think 78 is
already 4 years, maybe she would still wait if she did not antidote.
-1M.
-You don’t have further records but I believe it’s a good reaction.
Nobody wants to challenge that statement?
You are convinced that she is going to be well?
-No.
-Why don’t you say so? It’s because I say she will be well, you believe it?
-Nobody wants to argue.
-I don’t think that…  really bothers her… She says she is psychologically better.
Who can believe that?
-Who can believe that?
-No aggravation.
-You can’t expect her…
-There is some pathology underneath the symptoms, it’s going to take some time
before it’s fixed.
It did get worse but after a time, a month, the skin is still quite bad.
-It is unusual to give 1M to somebody at that age?
-Not unusual.
-…Do you expect that any psychological or emotional problems would get worse first?
-Yes definitely. What is due to the pathology I would expect to take some time though, I’m
sorry I think I missed one phrase. She said she didn’t hear anymore delusions, she had no
more delusions or voices.
-Ahhh.
-Now you are more sure?
My opinion is that she must be well, otherwise she would have come back.
-The nightmares?
-Yes that’s another information, sleep is easier but she still has the dream that somebody
is after her and that she is fighting with him.
After that information are you sure? Who is sure that this lady is doing well?
-Today?
-Very few.
OK, the lady came back…on 5th of July 1982. It was 1978 the first time, 4th of April the
second visit, the third visit is on 5 of July 1982, it’s 4 years and something.
She says the 4 years and something I’m doing very well but there is a relapse and she has
exactly the same thing.
She says again I have the feeling of human breathing and I heard a noise on the left ear
and that had started slowly since a few months ago when I had a breaking of my leg.
She broke her leg, she went to the hospital and she took some medication and slowly she
started deteriorating.
Eventually the whole thing came back, the itching is as it used to be.
Frequently I have bad mood and I don’t want to do anything, I’m lazy and I complain about
my complains, memory is bad and again I weep very easily. Fear that something may
happen to me if I’m by myself. Acoustical delusions again, sleep does not come easily
from excitement and thoughts. Lying on the left side I have dyspnea, the hearing is bad
Desires and aversions: desires fruits underlined twice, rice underlined twice, cheese
underlined twice, meat underlined twice.
She loves the open air underlined 3 times and feels the heat underlined 3 times, loves
the seas underlined twice, fears have come back.
Now what shall we do? Do you think we shall change the remedy or give the same
remedy?
-The same remedy.
-That’s a big decision.
-How can she relapse within two months time?
-Not too months, a few months after the broken leg. She broke her leg…
5-6 months is a good space of time that she can become again…
You see the clearing of the arteries will be of minimal time just to free her of her
symptomatology. It’s not the arteries are free and then they are again. It’s just enough to
free from a few symptoms and then within a few months that process can reverse,
definitely within 5-6 months.
She looks again like Pulsatilla, especially with the desire for cheese that has been added
now. If you see desire cheese Pulsatilla is there. Again it looks like Pulsatilla and what
shall we do? Shall we now try Pulsatilla? This is the question.
Between that choice that you have a little bit change in the case, it will change you in
another remedy, the rest is practically the same. Are you going to change the remedy?
-No.
-The rule is no. If your remedy has helped and has helped in this case tremendously, this
woman must have been a woman of these types that don’t go frequently to doctors,
otherwise she would have relapse much earlier and she kept a kind of balance all these
years and she was free of symptoms.
She didn’t jump a level and you can see now real reaction but that kept her going quite a
lot and that’s enough for a lady who kept 67 and she comes at 71, 4 years free of
symptomatology is good, I don’t think she could do better with another remedy.
I’ve given 1M because there is a relapse due to medicines she took, there was an
antidotal process.
There is one more symptom which comes to confirm.
It is now that she has burning of the soles in the feet and uncover them.
Burning of the soles is not Pulsatilla, burning of the soles of the feet is Sulphur.
Many people don’t have the experience and they understand and they don’t enjoy this kind
of analysis.
-No, no, I went back and I repertorized the whole thing very carefully and it’s really from
the repertorization and the original case, Sulphur is a little stronger but Pulsatilla…
-I’ll give you a hint, because it was a skin eruption involved. When I have exactly the same
situation between Pulsatilla and Sulphur, then I take the pathology of the one in favor of
the other. I say this is the remedy which produces more easily the skin eruption. It is
Sulphur, not so much Pulsatilla, that is the only differentiating point.
-She says scratching to bleeding.
-But I brought you another case yesterday scratching to bleeding and you noticed that
there was nothing in the Repertory but that’s why I bring you these cases.
Teaching means that you have to learn something from these cases and you can add it
in your Repertory, you can add Sulphur strong, capital in this rubric.
You see we are obsessed with the Repertory and outside people they call us fanatic, he is
a fanatic, Kent and all. Yet I believe that I see things objectively as much as I can and I see
also the work of Kent as much objectively as I can.
Kent brings his Repertory and the work of, I think 3 other doctors that have started this
work, it’s not his own personally. He supervised quite a lot and gave his own experience in
the Repertory but he could not have done everything and the Repertory is definitely lacking
information.
We need eventually to add up, like this you can add definitely.
Already today you saw two cases. I will not open the Repertory to see whether Sulphur
when scratches it will bleed. It will bleed because of the nature of Sulphur.
So therefore we will not rely on such information.