Also I want you to comment on his movements, what do they indicate?
-He is very much involved with himself.
-Not exactly. What do they indicate?
Is it impressive that the movements that the child does, are practically duplicating?
They are specific movements he keeps on doing.
Therefore there is a pattern in his movements. Is it a pattern? Can you see it?
There is a pattern. If you video and you keep on the video for five hours,
the same pattern, the same motions, the same movements will be there.
What does it mean from a pathology point of view?
-That there is some action.
-There is an inflammation in the cerebellum, there is a kind of process going on
in the cerebellum but further than that it indicates that the freedom of the child
has been lost and it has been reduced to an automaton. This is an automaton we see.
So the more we have the disease on deeper levels, the less we see the freedom
of the person to the extend that a human being can be reduced to an automaton.
It’s like a machine which goes on perpetually.
This is the picture that we have here.
I say all these things through the scanning, through the observation to understand finally
the depth of the pathology of the child.
Then when we see the first sign of improvement, we know that this is a sign of improvement.
Now this is a sign of improvement, not that, not the cough, not the convulsions,
not the motions.
All the motions have changed, he doesn’t do it anymore this way, he does it that way.
It means a shift in the symptomatology, it doesn’t mean an improvement.
If you see that, you can’t say the remedy has acted. You just say the remedy
has not acted, what is next? What shall we do next?
And only when you see certain signs and we said the signs should be signs of contact,
the person comes back to life, to human being. He must have some contact.
-You feel that he has a problem with seeing objects.
-I personally don’t think he has a problem on seeing objects;
I think it’s a problem here but it’s not that big problem because he has astigmatism
in both eyes. I think he sees objects but he doesn’t relate to them.
He just doesn’t understand and respond to what he sees.
The fact that he sees certain things, he sees me crossing the room to bring his food,
so there is stimulation of the eyes.
-You have to tell that he might be seeing blur because when he reaches for things, he…
-He can not judge the depth.
- No, he was trying this.
-Before the whole thing started, six months, there was no problem,
he was trying in different circumstances.
-You see before six months, before the whole thing started, he was able to reach things
and touch things. You see how the disease has been affected from that point onwards.
-There is no problem. He was trying in different circumstances.
-Before these six months.
-Before six months we didn’t consider that he had a problem because he was responding
to everything that he should do.
That’s what I feel it’s more understanding of these things.
-Does he make sounds?
-Not sounds but …
-He doesn’t articulate.
-No.
-What’s the main sound that he makes?
-He does “aaaah” like that.
-Moaning?
-No, it is not moaning, he is very passive. He is restless but passive.
-He moves all the time?
-Yes and if you hold him he wants to move all the time.
-The general trend is to move, most of the time he has to move.
-The tendency is to arch. But when he goes to convulsions first he does that
and then he arches, he reaches?
-It’s not so much the arch.
-Just the stretch.
-Yes, the extension, turning to the side.
I think seeing his eyes, to come out of the shock is strong
and the face is very much contorted.
-It is terrible to look.
-Yes.
What he is saying now is very important.
What we see, the eye turns to one side, there is a strong strabismus
and the face is very contorted.
The remedy has to fit this kind of picture. This is the idea.
It was OK for a Down child because they know it is a mongoloid child
and they expect very little. So when they see very little, they are very happy.
This is how I perceive the information, not that the child was completely all right.
We’ll hear about that. Dentition? I think they will say.
-Very terrible to look. Dreadful.
Horrible to look in the convulsions.
-He gets goose bumps.
-During the crisis?
-Yes.
When this happens, he goes and puts his back…
-He has a tendency for hot forehead he is a boy that kicks off his clothes.
I went this morning and his body can be freezing to touch but here it can be very calm
but here it’s always hot.
Have you found this description in the Materia Medica?
-I found it with epileptic convulsions and worse in hot room better in a cold room…
-Yes, which is the remedy?
-Bufo.
-So turn to Bufo. First we spoke about Stramonium. Now there is another idea of Bufo.
So for those they do not have the Materia Medica, it says acts on the nervous system
and skin, uterine symptoms marked, lymphangitis of septic origin, symptoms of
paralysis agitans, striking rheumatic symptoms, arouses the lowest passions,
causes a desire for intoxicating drink and produce impotence, of use in feeble
minded children, prematurely senile, epileptic symptoms, convulsive seizures occurred
during sleep at night, more or less connected with the sexual sphere seem to come within
the range of this remedy, injuries to fingers, pain runs in streaks up in arms,
mind anxious about health, sad, restless, propensity to bite, howling, impatient, nervous,
imbecile, desire for salt, feeble minded. What about this remedy? We discussed this remedy.
Do you agree with that remedy?
-No.
-Why you do not agree?
-Better at night.
-He is better at night but he has the convulsions during sleep.
This is one point that may not fit so much.
-Impotent sexuality.
-Difficult to judge in this kind.
-The actual convulsion…
-Here the type of convulsions are not described. Then we have to go and find the type of
convulsions that we have in Bufo to see whether we have the convulsions that are horrible
to look upon with the distortions and the eyes going with strabismus.
Bufo seems a good prescription and if she was in the class giving examination, she
would pass the examination because we can not always make a prescription but we
make a logical prescription, the most logical that we can find. So it is a logical prescription
though for the one who is more experienced perhaps, this type of convulsions are too
aggressive for Bufo.
Bufo is more passive convulsions I would say and less distortion with the tongue
protruding most of the time.
If that was a Bufo child he should have stayed in the whole interview with the tongue out.
In Bufo there is a kind of thickness around the lips.
The lips actually can be very thick and the tongue is protruded.
You see sometimes in the street some people who have very thick lips and they come
with this protruding and the impression of the whole thing is here, in that area.
Why that area?
Because Bufo says, lowers the sexual instincts, makes a human being concentrated,
having all the time his mind upon sexual matters.
Now the mouth and the tongue is an expression, it is an organ which is used in sex,
kissing etc. So the appearance, that we can see in Bufo, we can not see the genitalia,
it is an excessively sensual mouth.
And when a human being has been abandoned to sexual pleasure, you may notice that
the tongue protrudes.
Protruding of the tongue is a sign of abandoning yourself into sexual pleasure.
I’m sorry I’m talking about these matters and some ladies here who are really disgusted
with the matter but we are talking completely on medical subjects and
therefore you should be able to perceive all these things.
Maybe but it is not, it has nothing to do with that kind of protrusion.
If I was able to give you the impression...
You see the eyes become half, the lips are thick, the tongue protrudes,
it’s a whole thing that you can see and you say now this is a Bufo case,
with action on this area.
-It’s not in the Repertory.
-Bufo? Yes sure. Sure you relate it, Bufo is one of the main remedies for that.
-Cicuta virosa?
-Let’s go to Cicuta virosa now.
It says, the action on the nervous system producing spasmodic affections, hiccoughs,
trismus, tetanus and convulsions give the pathological picture calling
especially for this remedy, whenever this is further characterized by the more
individual symptoms of the drug.
Among these are the bending of the head, neck and spine backwards.
And the general action of the patient is violent with frightful distortions.
That means the one who observes the person he says, it’s frightful to look upon him.
You see the information is here.
Violent, strange desires, sensation of internal chill, moaning and howling,
does absurd things, marked action on the skin, mind delirium with singing, dancing
with funny gestures, everything appears strange and terrible, confounds present
with the past, feels like a child, stupid feeling, melancholy with indifference,
mistrustful, epilepsy, moaning and whining, vivid dreams, head turns
or twisted to one side, eyes;
when reading letters disappear, pupils dilated, insensible strabismus underlined,
objects recede, approach and seem double, effects of exposure to snow spasmodic,
affections of eyes and its appendages, strabismus periodic, spasmodic after a fall
or blow, periodic strabismus, stares persistently at objects, convulsions
from concussion of brain, thick, yellow scabs etc.
Spasms and cramps in muscles and spasmodic going backwards of head, curved limbs,
can not be straightened, nor straight once bend, back bend like an arch, jerking,
tearing in coccyx, especially during menses, modalities: worse from drafts, concuss,
tobacco, smoke.
Suppressed eruption causes brain disease. Elevated eruption at large.
Face distorted horribly but he says also horrible, frightful distortions;
that’s enough. So the remedy was Cicuta and it was given Cicuta CM as we said.
-Another thing is that it makes blue face, the reaction of the remedy it was said.
-…
-Idiotic, imbecility…
Not in this child, it’s not aversion to company, it does not have the possibility,
the means the senses are not available. You put this, he does not see it,
he does not judge depth…
What you have to fit is the whole picture.
The whole picture as we see it and perceived with the frightful distortions,
that’s why I made it a point in the beginning.
Then the head turns to the one side, it’s frightful, it’s difficult to unlock the convulsion.
-It’s typical, it’s not the convulsions that turn to the one side.
-Yes but it is not only the bending back, it is the strabismus...
What it means “conversion”. You go and stick to conversion and you go wrong.
What is the main action of the remedy upon the nervous system?
Paralyzing certain muscles and convulsion to some others.
This is the idea. In what way?
In a frightful manner. Where mostly? On the face. What it does? Brings on strabismus.
Very prominent, as he discussed it. Very frightful, the whole picture.
Because if you see in the Repertory Cicuta, you may find it is worse with cold air.
But you may find it convulsions on cold air, you may find Cicuta as well.
We do not prescribe on one symptom, we prescribe on totality and we see really
this remedy fits the totality of this patient.
Convulsions alternating with vomiting.
Very good, that’s a keynote that should have triggered those who do not know Materia Medica,
should have triggered them to Cicuta.
There is a difference to Oenanthe. What is the difference?
I don’t know, I have not seen so many cases in Oenanthe crocata to be able
to discriminate. Let’s go and see.
They first gave CM and then 30 because first they got hold of CM and then 30.
So they gave both. Anyhow the child had a severe reaction definitely.
He stopped breathing.
-Have you given?
-We may have a feedback before we leave this course.
-On Sunday.
-Cicuta, what potency?
-30 and CM.
-Both?
-Yes.
-Three days ago?
-Do you want to give a feedback?
-He is having fits again but he stopped for three days and then he is having fits again
but they are not so intense.
-He continued to vomit, it might be a little bit more than before but not much.
-On Friday you will give the whole story. Give few days to see.
You don’t expect anything in three days, what can you find out? There is no change.
This is on six or seven days during the course.
-On Sunday and Sunday night he had two consecutive fits at midnight and then
for the next two days he was clear of fit and another symptom came back.
He started to retain urine.
-He started to retain urine?
-Yes, before it was having six times the day and then it cut it half, so about three times.
This is an earlier symptom.
-How much earlier?
-Maybe six or eight months, it’s been off and on.
The vomiting increased and he was free for two days and then suddenly the fits came back
and they started to become more intense and then yesterday we had a problem
with his breathing coming back after he had the fit.
-What did you do to bring back the child?
-Just picking him up and smacking him to try to shock him.
-How did you hold him? Upside down?
-I wasn’t there, she said she was hitting him on the back and just…
But he reached a state where he became quite blue because she didn’t know what was happening.
Now last night he had one fit and we got out of it quite quickly and  there was no problem.
-Wait a moment. Sunday took the remedy, Monday and Tuesday no fit, Wednesday had
the big fit where he turned blue, then it was the day before yesterday.
-No, I came on Tuesday.
-No, today is Friday. You came yesterday?
-Yes I came yesterday.
-Or the day before that?
-Yesterday.
So they started increasing on Wednesday…
-And when they started increasing, I felt they became very severe, then he turned blue,
then I sent you to get some oxygen. Because he was getting small attacks but still
he was getting bluish, you said.
-No he didn’t because we didn’t get that far because she was watching…
-You stayed the whole night watching the baby?
-We were sleeping very lightly, we got the baby between us.
So he has only had one fit last night and I think maybe we didn’t even need to air,
I think the breathing had come back all right. That was my feeling.
So that’s the situation.
Do we have on this follow up, which is one week later, several days later,
have we have information to be able to evaluate whether the remedy is acting or not?
-He had an aggravation and the aggravation was in the picture of the remedy.
-Yes, anything else?
-An old symptom came back.
-So there are some signs, some indications during this follow up we’ve just seen,
that maybe we hit the right remedy. The reason we say that is because there is really
a severe aggravation in the convulsions.
The fact that he retains urine now is an old symptom we are not really actually sure.
The only information we have it’s an aggravation, it is too soon to evaluate such a case.
So once you have chosen a remedy and you have given a remedy, you are not going and
prescribe another remedy. When he is blue you prescribe some Arsenicum or
some other remedy to help him and this is wrong.
It is better you give something to help him rather than prescribe homeopathic remedy.
Let us see the next follow up on 20th of October, that means one and a half month later.
- Hold the hands so he can focus on the face and see the eruption.
Give me a short report of what took place since Alonissos, that is six weeks ago.
An immediate report you have given already in Alonissos. First he had a big reaction,
where he was suffocating…
-When we got off the island, I felt he’d be moving, getting progress of the worse all
the time and that the reaction that we got on the island was more of the still worsening
rather than a big reaction to what it had and by the time we left the island the situation
was just continuing with fits but not so many of them.
-By the time you left the island already the attacks were reducing?
-They were reducing, they weren’t as many of them, they retained the violence.
-But in the beginning they were very violent after the remedy, he became blue
and could not breathe etc.
-This continued. We still have a situation occurring where we got to stimulate
him to breathe.
So nothing happened with the 12X Cicuta. Initially we got a good reaction
for 4,5 days and then…
-What was the good reaction according to you?
-He was down to one fit the day and it seemed to be decreasing in intensity.
-One fit the day?
-Yes and sometimes none.
-The most important was that the intensity very much decreased.
-And then after 4-5 days, it came back with a strong intensity again.
At that stage we continued with the Cicuta three times the day and we raised it
to four times the day and it continued to get worse.
Mainly they were coming on waking which is  in the mornings for about a day
we tried to carry out six times the day and then we really saw a strong elevation
to irritation and we stopped doing it. Since we stopped it continued the improvement.
So continued from here just giving him a dose once the fits became violent, we decreased
from three times the day, to two times, to one. The old symptom of regurgitating food
has become very strong.
-During that time now?
-Yes and he is very happy when it appears food and the exterior is not bothering him.
Over the last few days we’ve had the recurrence of some quite violent fits
and yesterday he had five.
-It increased the intensity with each one during the day.
-The last three days or something. The last time we gave him a dose of Cicuta 12X,
straight after he had two violent fits and I thought that maybe was the response to Cicuta.
-When was the last time you gave Cicuta?
-Four days ago. One dose.
-You kept on giving every day? You saw the fit, then you gave one dose,
then the fit became worse.
-Yes.
-And then you stopped. You didn’t give anymore.
About this rash it came how long ago first time?
-It began after the Syphilinum but the Cicuta intensified it but it’s only bright when
he is not fitting. If he is fitting, it changes bright and color.
-It was on the face, it began under here originally, it moved here and after the Cicuta
it came over here and spread down to the shoulder. It continued to stay there until
it got worse and what it looks like, it looks like the rash that he had on his genitals
has gone into his face and except same reaction that has come upon his face,
is what happened on his genitals.
-Are you sure this eruption was similar with the genitals?
-I think it’s very similar.
-It’s not constant, this is like pimples. The other one in the genital was constant.
-The skin becomes tight, it peels off and you can see he cracks around his mouth.
It wasn’t pimples on the genitals.
-You see you tend to oversimplify things.
-And he is also vomiting.
-So at this moment the rash is not very bad.
-No.
-A few days ago it was very bad.
-Yes.
-But it didn’t bother him?
-No, then he was very happy.
-What other observations do you have?
-He is more sensitive to Cicuta, he is more responsive of stimulation
and he is on the overall happy.
-But would he respond if you talk to him at all?
-No but he watches with his eyes.
-What about the restlessness?
-This time was with the fit because as I observed him…
-Now the restlessness, always when I talk, I talk in comparison with the previous and
after the remedy. How is this restlessness now? Just give me this impression first.
-It’s just as bad, it can be just as bad.
-It is or it is not?
-When he is not having a lot of fits, he sleeps well, he is not restless.
As the fits come back again, he becomes very restless.
-So there was a time of 10 days when he was not restless and now
he is becoming restless again.
As restless as before?
-Yes.
-…he still has those very restless times. I can’t tell you whether is as often.
-I believe it is.
-What about his food? Any other changes that you have spotted?
-No, the only changes is his awareness of his surrounding, that’s the only big change.
He still regurgitates food and we have days without any regurgitation and other days
that he is having lots of fits usually. He also stopped urinating for a while after Cicuta,
he was only having two or three urinations the day which is an old symptom.
-One thing that did come up after we left Alonissos, we took the boat to cross to Italy
and he woke in the middle of the night and he vomited and he looked like he was senseless.
It was just a.. but he has done this since 2-3 times in the evening…
-No, 2 o’clock in the morning. It’s really late. Vomiting.
-Does he suck his fingers?
-No…
-Does he try?
-He would after a fit, he comes up and goes “mhhhh” …
-Before he goes to sleep?
-It’s a little crying or a little something.
-The fits also are quite different than we talked to you about… and he doesn’t have
so much violence in the initial pattern and he throws back and it’s a strong…
So this is six weeks later as you heard. What do you think is happening?
She says that the reaction is good because of the aggravation and the skin eruption,
which has come out and also the fact that he is more alert.
-He tries to make contact.
-Can we believe the mother?
-Yes.
-My question is can we believe the mother? The mother says the child is more aware.
This is what we like to hear. She does not know, she said something very important.
This is the most important thing she says,
can we believe her?
-Yes.
-Then I asked again how much aware? I want to find out exactly.
Do you remember that point? How much aware? This is very important.
Not yet showed much difference that they will overtly say yes.
Therefore still we have some reservations, apart from the fact that we see a struggling
within the organism to bring out the disturbance. The disturbance is on different levels.
It is on the skin, on the nervous system, on the central nervous system,
on the cerebellum and there is a fight of the organism to rearrange all that
and to bring them out,
to bring out more to the periphery the disorder.
When we hear he is more alert, it’s great.
But what pleased me most you have not said it. In this interview there was something
that pleased me more.
He said he is happy, yes I heard that but I said I do not have objective confirmation.
The eyes go… still it is doubtful.
He looks to the camera yes but all this you may say you conjecture.
Crying after vomiting…
-The restlessness and the automatic movements if he has no convulsion.
Also he has pimples on the face…
-What you may see is, did you see the restlessness as it was?
He was picking up his foot and eating his foot.
Did you see that in this?
-No.
-No, not at all. You may say we didn’t see enough.
What is important for me here are two things. When the mother says he is more aware,
this I like and the other important thing which I like is when the father said
that the contortions are not so frightful anymore.
This is very objective because the parents every time they see the child in such a turmoil,
they get the feedback immediately. They are sensitive to the child, they perceive.
Now suddenly they see all the contortions are not so much, that means there is a relief
on the parents looking upon the child. That means the whole picture has ameliorated.
Therefore because of all these points, because of the aggravation, because of the
aggravation of the skin, because of the awareness, then I can believe the mother and
because also… testing the mother, I have seen before as I mentioned, that she is
a person that you can rely. When she says this, most probably it is this.
So here we have a case that is improving and we have to wait and see what happens.
-…Where did the start the getting the 12X.
-I said the 12X they could give in case the convulsions they become strong.
I gave an indication of a kind of relapse in the case.
The child is not under my care all the time. He is in New Zealand, in India,
in Alonissos in Greece, there is difficult communication.
I have to give some indications when the child has convulsions, try 12X.
I don’t want to go high, why?
Because I suppose that they will give the remedy without real relapse, so I go low
and I say OK you can use repeated doses of Cicuta 6X in case he has a relapse?
But how these people can understand what is a relapse?
Here it is very difficult for us to assess the situation, never mind for them.
Therefore I give them a kind of indication and say in case of a relapse
give a low potency.
This is the idea. Under the circumstances it is the best that I thought
that I could do for the child.
It is not so important in this case, the pathology is so deep that you may say
even 3-4 times the day during the convulsion period. What I was always afraid is
that the child may go into convulsions that are quite strong and he can not breathe
and we have an accident. So I have to give some indications of what to do.
But I was afraid to say give a high potency because I needed the high potency
in case of real relapse. Then I would use the potency. Oh now we have a real relapse,
it’s going back again, eating his foot, making the same movements, the distortions are
very bad again. Now it’s the time, now give him 1M or 10M.
I will hold this high potency to use it appropriately.
In the mean time I’d given a solution to the parents to use little stimulation in case
they feel there is a kind of relapse.
I’m explaining to you the logic behind my decisions.
It’s not the ideal thing that I would like to do.
What I would like to do ideally, the child is in the hospital and we observe him.
OK he has a little bit more convulsions, forget it. Then we continue
without giving any remedy.
When there is a relapse and I know what it is a relapse, then I would prescribe
a high potency because we started with high potencies, very high potencies actually.
Actually here in this case in a case of relapse, we have to go very high.
-CM?
-CM was given because they did not have any other remedy and they gave CM.
-When you say in a relapse just go high, you mean CM?
-CM yes, in case we know that the remedies have been potentized properly.
That’s a big question. A 10M or 200 many times is stronger than 50M.
That’s an experience. So when we talk about high potencies, unless we are absolutely sure
that the remedy has been potentized 10.000 times, 10.000 in 1, 10.000 in 2 yes then
we know what we are doing. But in this situation we have now the potencies are from
50 years ago that they are sent all over Europe and they circulate CM.
Now what happens with these remedies nobody knows exactly.
I see some people are tired, maybe we have a break and then we continue.
-No.
-You judge according to your own vitality, there is somebody else there
who is just falling asleep. He tries hard to keep his eyes open and he cannot.
I have to keep my eyes open until I die! And when I die, you will find out.
- All the emphasis is at that point. where before… it was on the initial part…
-These few days that he is worse again, the fits are quite strong?
-Yes.
-The first three had the full grand mal fit very violent, as violent as…
-And he hasn’t have any today.
-He has vomiting today.
-This cracking of the corners of his lips?
During the whole interview, which lasted quite a while, you will not see the child
not  even once bending down and doing these movements that he was doing in the beginning.
Which shows that the irritation of the cerebellum has almost subsided by the time
and maybe there is a regeneration process now starting.
You remember the cerebellum was shrinked and maybe he will be able to walk
at some point, I don’t know.
My observation by that time was that the child did not have at all the automatic
movements that he used to have in the first prescription.
And that’s why we see a whole round improvement in the child within these six weeks,
which is very impressive for my understanding finally.
- …so tight, his mouth like it’s wrinkled…
-A face crack.
-A crack in the skin.
I will tell you something else, another observation.
You see the child so less irritated with his nervous system, if we had seen that
but at the same time the child was aware before and now he is not aware anymore,
that’s a bad observation.
But they say, the child was aware before and now you see like that and no movements.
That’s no good, that’s not a good observation. If the child is better mentally
and it’s better in his peripheral nervous system as well, then we say OK, he is doing well.
The same observation can be bad one time and good the other time.
You don’t say the convulsions are not there, he is better. No, what you want to see also
is the mental picture, unless it comes back we have done nothing.
It’s not that we stopped movements, no. The child might have been worse now.
The child must be aware, that’s the first thing.
What the mother has said is very important.
Continue.
-When he sleeps, is he restless in his sleep?
-We wake me up two, three times during the night.
-He sleeps well, that’s something I’ve noticed but as soon as the fits become strong
again, you can see because he becomes restless. Last night he was awake for a long time,
maybe three times in the night.
-By the time I saw him he was having 4-5 fits the day. Since he took the remedy,
I see quite a lot of 1-2 fits sometimes none, so in general we may say there is an improvement
but still it’s not all right.
It’s no bad the situation, what we have to do is to continue with this.
What we have to do is to give Cicuta perhaps 12C, a little bit higher, just one dose,
in case there is a relapse. For instance now, as I understand, there is a peak
for two days and it’s coming down because today no fit.
Most probably it will go down  but the fits maybe apart one from the other, the periods.
So we do in the beginning of the relapse, the first or second day, you just wait
for one day or two days and then you give a dose only. And then maybe he does
an aggravation and he will come back again and then maybe for a few days no fits.
In this way we shall proceed and eventually…
This is very difficult to predict what exactly will be the pattern and I just give
some indications, how to use the 12C in case there is a relapse, not to give it immediately
but wait until you really see a real relapse. Not immediately with the convulsion 12C, no.
The idea that we have to give constantly medicine is wrong.
The more we are able to wait on cases, the more impressive results we are going to see.
We don’t have to give repeatedly the doses.
I’m talking about a repetition now because of the seriousness of the situation.
He may go into spasms and he can’t breathe and the parents will say, George said
we must not give him anything and then he dies and then they say, George said
not to give him anything and he died.
I just interject an information about a case that some of you saw, a cancer case,
that you saw cancer metastasis on the bones in Alonissos last year.
There was a cancer case, it was given Medorrhinum and she had a severe reaction
towards Medorrhinum. There was a fusion, the pleura was full of liquid
and it had to be taken away because she could not breathe. She was taken
to hospital in Athens and the fluid was taken away several times and the patient seemed
to be going down, though the bone pains had stopped. But the collection of fluid
in the lung was so great that she could not breathe and she had to be relieved
by taking out the fluid.
So it was taken to Athens in the hospital and then we were in communication.
Eventually there was a point where the patient started feeling better.
She started eating, having more energy, she got up, she walked and every day
she was feeling better, no pains.
Even the father, the whole family was there, the father who was very hesitant
in the beginning whether the remedy had done anything, he telephoned and he was
in a great mood and he said, she is doing fine, thank you very much.
A few days later I received a telephone call and said, she died.
What happened? She woke up one night with severe pains on the chest.
Three o’clock in the night, so they thought these are the cancer pains
which are coming back and did not want to wake me up. And that was a heart attack.
And it was a case of Lachesis, the way that they described the pains.
It was a case of Lachesis and the patient died by 5 o’clock in the morning,
it was an extensive heart attack. The doctor was called and eventually he diagnosed
the heart attack and the autopsy showed an extensive heart emphract.
And they said George told us not to give any remedy.
I don’t think any remedy would have saved her at the moment but perhaps the correct
homeopathic remedy, because it was a case of Lachesis what they described to me,
when the pains are coming towards the throat and the patient wants this very open
and it extends to the left arm, especially when there is a constriction felt
in the throat during the pain, that is a pain of Lachesis.
I was very sorry for that case, first of all because she was a very nice girl,
for those who saw her and what I was very sorry of course is that we were not able
to show this case as cured.
It was the last stage where she had been treated from the hospitals in Germany,
she was brought from Germany to Greece, she was a Greek working in the University
in Germany and she was treated there several times with all the kinds of treatments,
with a metastasis, the last stage of cancer and she died with a heart attack
and that’s very unfortunate.
You will tell me maybe even if they had phoned you, they would not have time to take
the remedy and to have time to act but anyhow these are the facts, I’m giving you
the feedback and I’m saying that you must be careful.
Somebody else from the States he had a patient and the patient took a remedy
and after the remedy he developed a lump in the throat and said, George said not to give
a  remedy. The lump was cancer and he was taking from my practice because he did not
diagnosed cancer and he said George said it’s OK if this is reaction, this is OK.
No, George does not say these things. George says, you better be careful because
I can not imagine all the different possibilities that may exist in your practice
and you have to be careful and aware of what you are doing.
I can only show you here under a specific case what is the observation,
what is the evaluation.
Next follow up.
-It doesn’t work the 12 and we may go to 30.
We have now a follow up that was taken in England, not by me, by somebody else.
The case was taken in the end of September, what you saw is in the end of October,
six months later, now you will see a follow up on February.
-This is the situation George since we saw you in October 87 and your instructions
were to give 12C Cicuta.
So when we got here we gave one dose of Cicuta and the convulsions may be stopped
for ad few days.
After nine days they came back again and I repeated the 12 a couple of times
with no results.
At that point I waited for a while and in the 26th of November instead of giving
the dose of 12C that acted well, I gave one dose of 30 and there was no change
for about a week after that.
On December the convulsions stayed still and they didn’t come back again.
They begin to come back in the middle of February. At this time when he got
the 30 of Cicuta, he begun to get a lot of coughs and colds and then virtually
went continuously through winter.
There was a terrific discharge and cough in the chest but this discharge was smelly
and creamy yellow to green, it was very perfused. On the 24th of December
he got the mumps and swelling for two weeks, I think. From the time
the convulsions stopped, his progress was quite dramatic and quite quickly.
He really stopped pushing his finger into his left eye and this is something..
as the convulsions…
So he pushes his finger very hard in the lower left arm and he exerts a terrific amount
of pressure because you can see his finger gets…
He stopped vomiting at that time and the rash on his face disappeared almost completely.
The genital rash remained, just coming and going.
All the period that the convulsions stayed, the strabismus wasn’t so noticeable,
it diminished quite a lot and he got an improvement in vision and he was able to reach
and take things and not only to reach things but he was able to grasp straight away.
Over that period he begun to crawl and he continued this and he even made a few steps
walking. And also he has begun to think outside of physical stimulation.
In other words he’s begun to respond to us, if I clap my hands he laughs
and at times you will get respond to a smile and get excited.
By the 15th of February, the convulsions returned to a point where I felt
I should repeat this Cicuta.
At this point he was doubling over and going into a fetal position
but there was no rigidity in the convulsion at all. So I repeated 30 in that February.
End of June it was taken.
Did you hear the symptom I was talking about?
Pressing the eye during the convulsion?
It’s interesting what I wanted to mention but most probably this movement
is a kind of automatic relief on the situation, it’s like acupressure.
He was doing his own acupressure.
It’s a kind of relief that most probably he was having and automatically
he was pressing there. What I would say, can you tell me?
You have the story and there is an improvement with no question about it.
The cerebellum is regenerated definitely, he even said he took a few steps perhaps
if I hold him, which is impressive and now he says, the convulsions are coming back
and now he thought that is the time to repeat the remedy.
This is the point I want to discuss with you.