I want to show you now another case which exemplifies another aspect of Arsenicum
and I have chosen three cases.
One which is what you saw, the emotional frigidity, the emotional coldness of Arsenicum,
how cold the Arsenicum feels, how cold it feels in the emotions,
when the emotions go inside and then the physical aspect of Arsenicum
and finally I want to show you the paranoic state of Arsenicum as well,
which is another deep pathology of Arsenicum.
So the second case will be the woman from America.
This case is a quite severe pathology case according to my understanding
for which I have predicted in my analysis of the case as severe aggravation.
It’s a pity that John could not trace the follow up by the practitioner.
This case stayed far away.
This case was coming away from Berkley where I was giving the course;
it was 2-3 hours away and there is the doctor who has attended the case
and he had given a follow up about 10 days later.
But his follow up should be here, we could not trace it.
-This is a case of a 28-year-old female who has arthritis starting in the left foot
about one year ago, October 85.
She started having pain in the metatarsal- phalangeal joint, only the second toe.
Starting with pain and then within a month the toe started to swell.
At that time she was having her 4th month of pregnancy and had a work-up at that time
with X-rays, blood test, everything was normal, X-ray showed little periosteal reaction
but otherwise it was negative.
They finally aspirated the toe and grew out a really rare fungus called  Cladosporium sp.
They see it in Australia, South America, the Aborigines when they are hunting
they step on thorns and they get this fungus and the fungus isn’t supposed
to affect bones and joints, it’s mainly under skin but it has not known effect on joints.
So there was no treatment given at that time.
The consideration for the treatment was amphotericin B.
Because of her being pregnant at the time, they decided not to do that.
The pregnancy itself was a very special pregnancy.
She had had 6 pregnancies, she had 2 miscarriages previously and the pregnancy
before this one was very heavy.
During this pregnancy  she was really concerned about the baby survival.
She was really stressed and she was so much stressed that she was worried she might die.
So the pregnancy was a very big stress.
Then about January right toward the end of the pregnancy,
she developed a rash called herpes gestationis  which it’s not really a herpes virus,
it’s more warts. She did get some open sores but mostly this warts itched and tensed.
When I took the case at that time, the story she told me was that she was worse in heat
and better if she kept cool.
Roger saw her later on and the history he got was that the rash was much better with hot showers
but when I originally saw her, it was better if she kept cool.
She was given prednisone for the rash at that time. She took prednisone for a couple of weeks.
The rash cleaned up immediately but the joints never changed at all
and so she called me in early February and she told me the problem
and said that they want me to have a synovectomy next week,
what can you do for me before next week?
The case I got at that point was that the pain was in the second toe,
it was painful to move the toe at all…
-What I want you to know here also is the subjectiveness of the information.
That means an information is given and one doctor understands she is better from cold
and the other one that she is better from warm.
Why is that?
Because sometimes the information that the patient is giving is an answer to a question
that she has misunderstood most probably and that’s why
when you are going to base a prescription upon a symptom, especially 1-2 symptoms,
see that these symptoms are really there and you have confirmed the symptom.
Repeat the question, take another angle, ask from another point of view.
You are going to base your prescription upon whether she is better heat or better cold,
better you make sure what it is.
You see with the Arsenicum, it is better cool or better warm?
-Warm.
-It depends.
-It’s better warm but I’ll tell you an experience from when I was studying in India
to a little hospital that was attached there. They called us for a patient
who was under severe pain.
The nurse came and said the patient is under severe pain, tremendous pain
and so we went upstairs and saw the patient lying in bed,
holding the back portion of the bed and shouting something in Hindu
and she was perspiring there and there was another nurse who was fanning the patient
and the patient was saying “water” and she was in agony, in pain.
She had kidney colic. When we entered we just saw that picture, this nurse fanning this person,
he is in India, it’s hot weather usually but at the same time I noticed
that the patient is covered by two blankets.
You don’t have the time to ask questions under that stressful situation.
Are you afraid of death? There is a picture, a severe pain, it’s not going to give you information
but what you see is already so eloquent that gives you the whole story of the case.
A person under heat covered with two blankets, that means she is feeling cold in the body,
while the head is so warm that she asks from the nurse to fan her and the nurse is fanning her.
At the same time asking all the time “water”. What is the remedy?
Arsenicum.
Arsenicum relieved the pain within seconds. It was a case that kidney colic could be relieved.
Not all kidney colic can be relieved in seconds.
Don’t expect that because the stone is big in the ureter.
We have a relief even with the right remedy which is of the order of 20-30% of the pain
but not more than that.
Because the spasm of the ureter, it can not break the stone, the stone is of such a shape
that hurts the ureter. You do not expect to cure all kidney colic within seconds.
But if it is possible to pass the ureter with relaxing, the stone will be gone
and within seconds the colic will be gone like it was in this case.
So in Arsenicum when you ask, are you better from cold or warm, it depends what she means.
She thinks about her head and says, I’m better from cold, she thinks about her body and says,
I’m better from warm.
So you have to be aware in Arsenicum and in different other remedies also.
-It was really swollen, it was warm and red at that time, it was better with ice packs
and also better with warm and it was worse with any motion or any jar.
-When you say second you mean next to the top?
-Yes next to the top. I’m sure it was days it shouldn’t have been not so bad
and days that had been really bad, it was come and go. She was more irritable and bitchy
since that happened, she was herself  she describes herself as an active person, a real doer,
she is very self-motivated, a lot of self-confidence and aggressive at least at this point,
when I saw her.
She was very upset that she was sick, she doesn’t tolerate sickness at all, being out of cotrol
and the fact that she was sick with any kind of a problem was…
-She can not tolerate the pain actually?
-The pain and the fact that she was sick, both.
She is very fastidious, she can’t stand dirt and she actually had a germophobia,
she washes her hands all the time, maybe 20-30 times the day she washes her hands.
-You see whatever he has mentioned. Arsenicum fears of losing control.
He wants to be in control of things, that’s why he wants order, to have control.
This is the idea behind, the insecurity on different levels, so he wants to be in control.
You see another aspect of Arsenicum.
The previous one could you say it’s a case of self assurance of self confidence? No.
This one you can say is a case of self confidence, I can do it.
The Arsenicum becomes self confident because he organizes, accomplishes things etc.
but once this order is gone away or something is gone, then they are gone into pieces.
Then comes the anxiety, then comes the fear of death, then come all the catastrophes of the world
and Arsenicum goes into anxiety and neurosis states.
Also the desire of the Arsenicum for cleanliness you will see that it will be taken quite far
and will produce a symptom which we call it phobia of the germs, germ phobia.
Which is a symptom found mostly in Syphilinum first, Sulphur second, Mercury also has that,
Pulsatilla has that and of course Arsenicum, fear of germs, fear of being dirty.
In your book it says washing constantly her hands, only Syphilinum you have there 1 to 4.
You can add Sulphur, Arsenicum, Mercury and Curare.
-It says delusions.
-Delusions is a little bit different. It’s a case of mental.
-What about Ratanhia, you can add?
-No.
The remedies I give you, Sulphur, Arsenicum, Mercury have been repeatedly confirmed
about that symptom.
Where before it was only Syphilinum and everybody would give Syphilinum and many
cases would not be touched. Here you have much more possibilities.
-She puts alcohol in the doorknob. She’s got 4 little children and even with her children
she is always doing this.
She sleeps on the left side, she likes to be by herself. She doesn’t like to socialize.
If she is with people, only with respected people she has respect for.
At that time she had a craving for oranges and thirst but she likes ice cold,
always likes ice cold drinks.
She fears heights which was new, she was chilling one time but she doesn’t like warm rooms
and excess heat bothers her, she would not stick her feet out of the bed at that time.
Her sex energy was absolutely absent.
-You see some symptoms here that don’t sound like Arsenicum, she doesn’t like excess heat,
she sticks her foot out of covers and yet she will take Arsenicum.
What is happening?
Arsenicum is a cold remedy, ameliorated by warm, yet desires cold drinks.
It’s a characteristic, this we don’t bother by desire of cold drinks,
Arsenicum has it strongly but worse bothered by heat, usually Arsenicum will say I love heat,
I sit under the sun, I live by the sun, I sit on the heater, they are really cold
and they want to be warm. What happens here?
Why do we disregard the fact that she does not like too warm rooms?
Because first of all it’s not a very strong symptom, she is not aggravated by heat really.
If she was really aggravated by heat, then we have to think twice before we go
and prescribe Arsenicum but here the possibility is that under the Arsenicum,
after the Arsenicum, maybe Sulphur is lurking underneath that it will be needed later on.
So the coldness that she has is enough for us to prescribe at this stage Arsenicum,
which covers her fastidiousness, her order, her self confidence and we will see how she is
and she behaves and also the fear, she has a fear about germs and the desire to wash
and to be clean.
-At that point I gave her Ledum and I gave her 30C once the week.
I found out that next week …
-You see why he gave Ledum? Because of the pathology, because Ledum is a remedy
that could be thought in uric acid conditions, what we call gout
and this looks like gout situation.
For me it is not diagnosed properly.
I don’t know if any of you got the pathology of the case?
Did you get the pathology, did you understand the pathology?
These severe kind or arthritic conditions with swelling, it looks like uric acid
but it is spreading too much.
Uric acid usually is located in one joint when the uric acid is very high in the blood.
She has also a skin eruption that looks like fungus eruption and for this condition,
she has been prescribed allopathically amfotericin B.
Amfotericin B, do you know what medicine is for? It is antifungal drug
which is prescribed in deep fungus situations when fungus are deep into the body.
It is very powerful, with great side effect drug and why did they think about it?
Did they think as a deep fungus condition?
Maybe but anyhow what she has described is not a simple arthritic condition
or a uric acid condition. It is something else.
It is of those new diseases that are coming up with the medicines that have been used so far,
allopathic medicines, changing the inner defenses, the immune system
and producing new kind of situations in which we have in this case.
So he prescribed according to pathology, Ledum.
With no result of course and with a possibility that he may suppress a little bit
the local condition.
-…nothing had happened and she decided not to have a synovectomy.
So I gave her another dose of Ledum 30 and repeated it the following week
and I started again a month later, no less than a month.
At that point the pain in the second toe became less but now the swelling
and the pain moved to the third toe and she described the pains as burning, stinging pains,
swollen, she felt like the toe was constricted.
The toe was red and warm, so I gave her Apis at that point, which did essentially nothing.
The same history and because next time she came she said to me that
what happens is it will be all right for a few days, it just blow up and so because the burning,
stinging pain was acute, I gave her Formica rufa.
It seemed to get worse and then it came back to the usual level.
When I saw her in April, the third toe now had calmed down and the fourth toe 5th metatarsal
and to the medio side of the ankle, at that point.
So I repeated all the blood tests at the point.
All the blood tests were normal, her SR rate was minimum elevated, it was 24, the average is 15,
her X-ray her feet at that time showed the initial reaction she had,
that was gone and now she had more reaction in the area where she was inflamed
but not in the ankle. The ankle X-ray was normal.
We re-aspirated the joint at that time and didn’t grow anything out.
Everything in the aspirate of the joint was normal at that point.
At that point because she was emotionally healthy and we got a discussion about scriptures
and everything was so cut and dry, so moralistic in her,
that I gave her Kali carbonicum at that point and again nothing happened.
So I sent her to see Roger at that point and this is in June.
The case that Roger got was pretty much the same.
The differences were Nr 1 that her joints were worse cold at this
point and much better with heat and hot showers.
The other thing was that when she had the rash, it was better with hot showers.
At this point when I saw her she was chilling, underlined once,
when Roger saw her she was warm blooded, underlined 3 times.
-But still the local inflammation would be better warm?
-Better warm at this point.
-But she was warm blooded herself.
-When I saw her in winter where she lives, it’s cold then and by the time Roger saw her
in June it was 105, she is much warmer at this point.
Her sleeping at the left side was much more prominent at this point.
Roger had underlined it 3 times, I only underlined it once.
Still craving ice drinks, also creamy, ice cream, bread, pastries underlined 3 times,
oranges 3 times. Bread and pastries, sweet cakes.
-Another point concerning the desires of Arsenicum, if you look at the Arsenicum
you see farinaceous food, what it has desires or aversions?
Page 480, aversion farinaceous food, the Arsenicum and Phosphorus together
they have aversion for farinaceous food.
Both of these cases they said, desire bread and farinaceous food.
Did you see the Repertory is indicative, it’s not final.
It might indicate to you, it might give you some hints, it’s not final.
What is the difference for me prescribing this case and the other practitioners?
He is also quite good, he is not so many years following the teaching but he is quite good
and Roger also took the case and underlined 3 times the worse heat.
I’ll tell you what is the problem. You want to give a remedy and you want to confirm the remedy.
You want to give Sulphur, you say, are you feeling warm? Yes, terrible.
In 105 degrees outside, everybody would say, I’m feeling terrible in the heat
but why you don’t keep on asking whether this is now because of the heat or it is usual?
The usual condition, in which case you would have said, no when I’m in the mountains
I suffer from cold.
If you want to give Sulphur, you are determined to give Sulphur, then…
So you have to be very careful, especially on what you are going to base your prescription.
Don’t rely easily upon an answer unless the answer is immaterial.
-Averse fish, fear heights and fear of robbers. She would look under the bed looking for robbers.
-Look, fear of robbers.
-Arsenicum capital.
-Do you see there? There is a microbe phobia, germ phobia, there is all these other symptoms,
she washes, she is orderly, very fastidious and yet if you want to give Sulphur
you make worse heat and you miss Arsenicum.
The information is there, you just disregard it.
I will tell you this is a great teaching case because this is not an unknown remedy.
If I prescribed Gallic acid, everybody can say forget it, nobody can think about that.
But if we talk about Arsenicum, everybody should think about Arsenicum. Why?
The information is there constantly. What made them not to find Arsenicum?
Do you know what?
They don’t listen, they don’t listen. They listen with preconceptions.
If I see a case and I think she is Natrum muriaticum,
I want to make this case a Natrum muriaticum.
I do not listen therefore, I listen to my own mind, saying ask this question.
Desire salt? Ah yes very good. This is what I’m listening.
I exaggerate a little bit but this is what we are doing.
How do you feel about the sun?
I don’t like, oh very good he doesn’t like the sun but she is hesitating,
you saw her she’s hesitating, you saw her she did not answer immediately.
Tell me why she did not answer immediately,?
These are the questions you should ask yourself because these are the facts.
If you want to make a case Calcarea carbonica, you make a case Calc. carbonica,
there is no question. I can make you any case, anything.
The thing is to empty yourself from what you think, yourself
and let the object come through you and fill you with the right information, this is the idea.
Empty yourself from your conditioning and you will see beautiful information comes.
Don’t interfere with your knowledge, with your ideas about the case and examine.
Why can I see she is telling a lie? It’s not what she says, what she means it’s different.
Why do I say that? Because I listen.
As homeopaths we need the real information, we can not work with false information.
If somebody gives us false information, we’re going to come into false conclusions.
We need the real information, what really happens within the human body.
That aspect you have almost to tell yourself to do it.
Just don’t listen. Doubt yourself. A Sulphur, doubt it until the last moment.
Confirm it again and again and again until you are happy and satisfied.
Don’t jump into conclusions. It’s Sulphur, it’s Lycopodium.
This is where most of the mistakes are made.
I listen and I doubt. You see this case for me, as I hear it from you,
is a clear Arsenicum case but I will ask the possibility of this remedy, of that remedy,
of another remedy to differentiate and then every time she will bring me back to Arsenicum,
then I say OK, Arsenicum.
-Confirmed later on.
-At that point I gave her Colchicum 200C, which essentially did nothing.
Roger and I talked about, because of the modalities of the joints and the fact that
the rash she had was so much better I gave her Rhus tox which did nothing and then I saw…
-Before Rhus tox, it was given Colchicum.
-A month later with a sense of the same case and I gave him Sulphur, which did nothing.
And then the most recent remedy she got in early September was Syphilinum.
She had some changes since the Syphilinum.
Nr1 the bottom of the foot started to swell again that had not been any problem since May.
She also now has developed pain in the right heel, which is new and now a symptom
that had been worse at night. She is no longer worse at night.
-Do you see the changes? These are bad changes now because the remedy is not correct,
it’s changing the symptomatology and if you keep on prescribing the remedy,
you change completely the case, the case will be a mess.
It is destroyed and you say Homeopathy can not work.
But when he goes into deeper levels, he takes into consideration now the microbe phobia
and he gives Syphilinum.
Why? The case has not been studied properly because the information was there.
You can’t say you have intuition. I don’t accept that.
Is that intuition to prescribe Arsenicum in this case?
Everything it has given, it says Arsenicum, Arsenicum, Arsenicum…
You can’t say I have intuition, not to that.
Because he is a more recent student, he does not know yet the remedies etc.
-She gets up on her feet and she’s been up on her feet for 5 hours and it starts to hurt.
-If she is for how long?
-If any period of time, she is out of feet in bed, she is sleeping better at night,
she doesn’t bother at night now but if she gets up on her feet, it bothers her.
She has also some numbness in both of her big toes. A big change in her,
she’s developed a despair of recovery.
-She has developed despair of recovery. You see now?
I showed you despair of recovery on the previous case and you see how strong it is with Arsenicum.
-With the despair of recovery she’s got a lot more anxiety and her self confidence has gone down,
she is starting to wonder now, she didn’t see herself as having emotional problem
and now she is starting to wonder that maybe she is doing that to herself.
-She is doing what?
-Her emotions are causing all this.
Her friends had telling her about the emotions and she started reading books about emotions
and so she’s become much more sensitive. In the last couple of months
she started to weep a little bit more, especially when she thinks about bad health.
It’s really hard for her to have this problem because she’s always done everything to be healthy,
she exercises, she eats right and she doesn’t understand why has this happened to me.
-Another point of Arsenicum. What he says is, she always did everything to be healthy.
Unless you have an anxiety about your health, you don’t do everything to be healthy.
I can tell you that, I know about myself, I always do the wrong things.
So if you have an anxiety, it prevents you from getting diseases and things like that
but you have to have some anxiety inside to drive you into doing everything possible
to be healthy.
Eat healthily, from yourself you know, who cares? Some of you don’t care, you smoke.
A little bit of anxiety is good sometimes.
-I saw you are limping. How long you can walk now with the condition that you have?
-I can go for ever and the pain, it’s getting this the pain level,
in the morning is just terrible.
-In the morning, as soon as you wake up or as soon as you step out of bed?
-Terrible I nearly got my mom’s crοuches last week
because I can’t stand the pain is so bad to the hill of my right foot.
I usually crouch for the first half hour in the morning…
-Did you understand my question? My question was do you have the pain
immediately on waking or after rising and stepping down?
-Waking and stepping down out of bed. In the past I had pain in bed,
sleeping but now that it’s out of the toe I can sleep very good and don’t feel the pain.
-And you feel mostly…
-It’s all in the heel, on the right foot, no pain in the toes,
so when I walk I use the toes, it’s severely in the toe areas, at the base of my toes
and on the outside of the big toe and on the inside of the small toe…
-Unless you walk there is no pain. As you sit there, there is pain?
-If I just sit here I know I have pain in my body but I know when move it.
-What kind of pain it is? Can you describe the pain?
-Because I want to be sure, you describe it very well in your book on page 57,
I can just read that.
-No, no.
-Do you want me to read that?
-No, no, I want you to forget that and describe your feelings?
-All right, you can imagine because I can do this very well if you can imagine.
I want you to imagine getting up and walking away, you are on a bridge about 30-40 feet,
you jump, there is no water, you land on a rock about this big, right on it.
Partly bruised, almost broken, pain on the right foot. It feels just broken, sharp pain.
-You have said about applying warm, it alleviates the pain somewhat or quite a lot?
-I just bother to put my feet in warm water because soaking and it does feel good
and the movement and I get up. When I wake up in the morning
and I go to my kitchen in cold it’s really aggravated.
-You like the cold in general?
-I like cold weather, I’m a cold person. I get uptight in the heat.
-In the place where you live heat is very bad?
-You have to have a pool so you can live. We don’t have a pool yet, so we’re barely living.
At the time I developed this was in a December, when the toe started blowing up,
it was in a winter time and I thought this is going to get better since the sunshine starts.
I know it’s  gonna heal that, just because of the sun but in the summer the heat came and…
-It didn’t but it’s a wet heat.
-It's dry, you just sweat.
-Can anybody describe to me her character, how she feels?
-Maybe she likes you.
-Paranoiac.
If you want to be good homeopaths, do not get involved emotionally with your patients.
When your patient comes, how are you, all this and showing a kind of affection and love
and things like that, no.
You are an observer and you must understand what the defense mechanism is doing
and presenting to you.
You will never understand if you get involved emotionally with the person, forget it.
You like very much a woman when she comes? You better send her to another doctor.
Say, I like you too much, you better go to another doctor. Otherwise you failure.
You are going to fail and a woman who likes the doctor
and because most of you are young doctors, they try to seduce the doctor
in order to pay more attention.
This is the biggest mistake that the patient is making because if the doctor is really seduced,
can not find the remedy. Forget it. I can give you a guarantee about that.
Once you get involved emotionally, you can not see objectively anymore. The objectivity is finished.
I had a case with one woman doctor in our Center, she sent me a case.
It is a young man with certain problems and he is a nice man and she describes the man…
I read the case and I say… oh.
She is a very good looking woman and the patient is coming, he is a very good looking young man.
She writes I had a very good rapport and she reported the rapport she had between her and him,
that was she was reporting. I say, what is the disease?
What he is suffering from, you better take again the case.
Because I saw this was most probably a mental case and she had missed it completely.
So she calls back the patient and they discuss and she calls also the relatives of the patient
and this was a complete mental case, it was a manic depressive case.
He came in the state of mania and they are very nice people and she had a rapport,
she liked him and she wrote it down, he is a very nice man, good looking etc.
She was reporting objectively! She did not see anything of what he was having,
she was not reporting any mental symptom. He had some pimples here and there.
I mean why this man came? Some hints in the case, I said no that is not the case,
this is something else.
Always again and again that’s a fact, so at least you know it. You don’t have an excuse now.
Nobody described to me her character. Anyhow let’s see a bit more.
Why she does this? Why she looks in this way? Try to observe, try to be there.
-It’s timidity?
-In the night when you go to bed your feet will be cold, will be warm?
-They are pretty warm.
-I ask you because you have to learn to observe. Her eyes do they look at you?
You are the examiner, do they look at you straight? Not straight. What happens with her eyes?
Does she look? There is haziness in her look. Her look is not straight.
Why there is this haziness? Why she plays with her eyes? It becomes pathetic, do you see?
What is this?
She likes herself. Does she like herself?
-Yes.
-You can see that. Does she see through? Is she present here now? No she is not.
There is a kind of mist. Why this mist? Because she wants to believe things
that are not there and that’s why she puts up that mist. I’m so good looking.
-Drugs?
-She doesn’t do drugs, no.
She is moralistic, she will not have an extramarital affair, you can see it
but in order to overcome the reality, what is happening as problems in her life,
it becomes a kind of mist, she can not see that, I’m so good looking…
And she does not want to show the problems, she puts up a facade.
-Hot shower and then my shoes on…
-You see the façade? What is this?
-So it was time for you this morning after rising? It was always like that?
-No. The whole thing is ever-changing  I told a few months ago
and it just never stopped changing and the fact that I see little improvement
gives me no hope anymore because it blows up somewhere else.
-Why do you feel about your condition?
-What I feel about it?
-Do you feel that you’ll never get well?
-I used to feel great confidence in my ability to heal myself but I lost it
because I’m not healing and the improvement is not getting anywhere near …
-When you say to heal myself, you meant by the sheer force of the will
that you could really do better?
-Yes.
If one is in good shape and good health should be able to heal himself.
I don’t drink, I don’t smoke, I eat right, I do all these, I had the ability to…
this and I’ve lost it. I might be dying slow I don’t know, I might have cancer.
-You have real fears now?
-Yes I think about that all the time. I probably have and I’m gonna cry.
I can’t get better and it’s killing me not to die than to die in 10 years painfully.
-Perhaps you overdid it. Most probably…
-I’ll kill you…
-I don’t blame you.
-You probably got too much… you probably did too many good things and I’m a rag, that’s not fair.
-But I’m glad we are all learning from our mistakes.
-I haven’t made any mistakes, no. I haven’t learnt anything from that.
You are learning and to learn from that now. I’m just playing humble.
-Do you belong to a religious kind of group?
-Yes, I’m fine.
-And you are fine?
-I’m fine. I’m a well adjusted balanced person.
-Why did she get ill? She did all the right things? What she did wrong?
Unfortunately in this case you are not able to really talk about deeper problems perhaps
that she has faced and it is my feeling, my understanding but I can’t prove it,
that she did not want to see reality, she did not want to see the real problems and face them.
She put up a façade. She tried to make everything in order, to be everything intact,
very correct but in a deeper level, she must be facing some conflict quite strongly as well.
This is my opinion. I don’t say because of that conflict we have the manifestation of the disease.
I cant’ say that either but what I’m interested is how the whole thing
is reacting in mental-emotional and physical level as well.
It appears to me that she is covering up some problems that exist in her life
by trying to put a complete order into her life, by having complete order, doing the right thing.
She is religious, she is sitting correctly, she has a good husband, the family is correct,
the children must go to school and be the first etc.
The organism does not work in this way always. We can not force our organism
to work in such an order but the Arsenicum case have they have this desire to be orderly.
How deep is with Arsenicum, everything has to be in order.
When we say fastidious, do you understand the element of fastidiousness
and how from a tremendous self confidence comes the idea of death into the picture?
How comes the idea of anxiety? I’m losing my health, am I having cancer?
Fear of cancer and then we develop fear of cancer in Arsenicum.
Anxiety about health, fear of cancer, fear of death, which are the main things.
Despair of recovery and at the same time she is having fear of microbes and germs and phobias.
When the Arsenicum will be given, she is going to have a big reaction in her toes
and her inflammations definitely but later on what’s going to happen is,
and I don’t have any more information about the case, but I believe it’s going to break out
with a strong eruption.
Eventually everything will come into the surface and will come as an eruption
and when there is an eruption, it’s going to be quite strong and quite bothering the doctor.
I don’t know how he is going to handle it.
-Do you have a vertigo from high places?
-I have developed it. I didn’t use to. Only extreme heights, climbing a mountain.
Red, dry, cracking, it’s really bad so we went to doctor and I guess that came out…
I don’t remember any specific…  I wash my hands so much because I’m obsessed
for germs and clean house and so I still do that, just as much and I don’t have a hand problem.
-How long you had this skin eruption?
-Maybe a year.
-Only a year?
-Just coming on and off.
-When your feet started hurting you, what is the connection with the eruption?
-It’s six years ago.
-Six years ago you started with the eruption?
-Yes six or seven years. I’m married eight years and it started somewhere
when I got married and somewhere when I got the babies, I can’t remember exactly.
-How many babies did you have?
-Four.
-You can’t remember when it came, four or three years ago?
-After my second baby, that was six years ago.
-And the feet started hurting?
-Last October.
-When did you start washing your hands?
-When I got married.
When I started caring for my own home, cleaning my own toilet, cleaning the house, doing all that.
Washing my hands before make dinner, then used to make dinner,
I used to have my mom making dinner…
-I see. How many times you wash your hands? 30 times or 100 times the day?
-… Before I comb my hair,  before I get the food, after I go to the bathroom, it’s all day long.
-You never had this impulse to do this thing before you get married or you did it very little?
-Very little.
-What this washing of the hands has to do with the marriage?
She said, I started washing my hands after my marriage.
What the marriage has to do with the washing?
-Mental illness?
-Syphilis?
-I think you carry the idea of miasm a bit too far. No. I’d like to hear some other.
What has happened in her marriage? What happened in her sexual life?
Most probably why the situation has come about? Because genetically
she was having the after effect of syphilis.
When this genetic predisposition will appear after a stress…
Why the marriage became a stress? She must have been wealthy before, her father providing,
her mother doing all these works, never did anything.
Then she comes to the marriage situations and she develops that disgust
and this fear of microbes.
Most probably what she says it is right. I couldn’t confirm.
With these cases you don’t play tricks.
She is not in a position to ask such questions, whether she likes the husband
or she does not like him.
It is out of question because all these things have been pushed into the subconscious.
It s not even in her conscious mind I believe.
That’s why I will not push her to discover these things.
What I want to understand is the situation where it has arrived, what is the genetic predisposition
and whether syphilis is there.
Most probably according to our theories, they are coming down through
and therefore choosing an antisyphilitic remedy which confirms again the choice of Arsenicum,
being syphilitic remedy.
But most probably the stress is there and some disgust came about after the marriage.
-After you delivered your baby do you remember getting any medicine to this period,
before getting married?
-No.
-During the first year of your marriage,
did you get any medicine?
-Maybe cortisone creams.
-Why, because of…
-Cortisone for lotion without having an eruption?
-No, I have the eruption and he maybe recommended this type of cream.
-After the eruption but I’m talking before. You were never sick in your life?
-And taking pills for it? No.
-Never you had fever?
-I had aspirin, I had strep and take something for that.
-What? Antibiotics?
-Probably.
-When did you have this strep?
-I had it three years ago.
-I’m talking before marriage.
-I know, I never had taken vacations for anything.
-So you were very healthy as a child?
-Yes.
-You don’t remember yourself being sick?
-No. I got mono in College.
-She got mononucleosis and she went through it without taking medicines.
She talks in a particular tone of voice. It is an American tone of talking
but still there is something that is impressive in her talking.
Can anybody tell me why she talks in this way?
-Tension.
-She is shy.
-She is talking like that. When you talk from here…
What is the difference when somebody speaks from the heart? The voice comes from deeper.
When the voice is… it’s a way of hiding the emotions and what you feel.
Mostly Americans they found this way of getting away with their emotions.
They say, emotions are no good, they talk like that from here upwards, only with the head
and with the voice, not with the heart. This is the idea, the monotonous.
The voice comes only from here, that part. It’s only the intellect.
You can’t do things like that to your system, you are going to pay one way or another.
You can’t constantly suppress your emotions and… I did everything the right thing.
It’s a superficial layer on which you live. The rest of the organism what happens?
You are going to ignore everything and say you are living nicely?
All these grimaces and the way she talks, is a superficial level of life,
ignoring completely what is happening in deeper level.
Now you have the effect, now you come to fix it.
Why do I say that? Because apart from Homeopathy, we give a remedy
and we say this is your remedy, take it.
What we are dealing with all the time are complex problems.
Not just the pain, take a pill, the pain is gone, fixed, no.
Homeopathy has the possibility of making this woman talk from the heart.
You saw the other Arsenicum case? How she talks from the heart eventually?
It was impossible for her to think of talking from the heart, where the voice broke down
and the emotions came and she broke down, she spoke from the heart.
Now the same is going to happen with her but the problem is quite complex.
She has to solve the problem she is facing.
And what is the problem she is facing? Most probably is what she mentioned.
A good husband who provides but on another level dissatisfaction
and we cover this up with…  a voice which is completely at the surface, with a life
which is completely on the surface.
Everything I do right, everything I do right.
I can’t imagine how a person can say, I did everything right. I can’t even imagine.
If there is a little bit of self examination, you will reveal 10 mistakes every hour.
Let’s say she does not make 10 mistakes, she makes 2 or 3 but she does nothing?
You see, she does not see in depth what is taking place and now she comes to us
to be treated and we have to understand all these problems.
And we are going to do, divorce her husband?
No, this is not a solution for her, she will never accept that solution
but she has to understand that not everything is perfect in this life.
That things in this life you have sometimes to make concessions, to make room for others,
to make room for your ideas that come very strictly.
So the task of a homeopath I see it as much deeper and much more profound
than just relieving pains or relieving anxieties.
It is a task of bringing real order to the organism, not external order.
Arsenicum is happy with the external order of things.
There was a big aggravation in this case.
Very severe aggravation and the last day of the seminar, it was actually an aggravation of 7 days,
the last day of the seminar the doctor gave a report saying
that she is starting feeling better in her pains.
In the main aggravation she stayed in bed for several days, she could not get up at all
and by the end of the seminar, it was 7-8 days after giving the remedy,
the doctor has reported an amelioration already.
It was a severe aggravation as it was predicted and everybody can see
that this is an Arsenicum case.
You see the elements of Arsenicum quite strongly.
-Why she got that severe aggravation?
-According to my understanding what she has is a severe pathology.
Why it is a severe pathology? I don’t know, I can’t give a name to her pathology.
But taking into consideration what is happening in the whole organism, the phobias,
the cleanliness, the predisposition that comes from syphilitic background,
taking into consideration the emotional closeness and what has been suppressed,
I feel that all that when it comes out, this pathology is going to be very severe.
It comes out as a state of arthritis, whatever arthritis it may be,
even rheumatoid arthritis is not very severe case but I believe that here we have a case
which is even worse than rheumatoid arthritis.
That’s why I say the pathology is strong and she is going to have a big the aggravation
and she did have.