-I’d like to thank Mr. [name] for his kindness to invite me in this,
I would say, quite successful congress from the people I can see.
And I would like to wish that Homeopathy is really understood in its deeper meaning and
sense and potential that it has and that it will be growing with the time and also that at
certain level governments, not only the Swedish government but all governments will
understand the real good that Homeopathy can deliver to the people and then maybe not
only protect Homeopathy but also try to help in order to spread.
Before I go on with the lecture, which is quite theoretical and maybe boring, I would like
to give you some live examples of the action of the homeopathic remedy upon some
serious cases that we have been dealing with. So I can show with examples where
Homeopathy can be effective and where sometimes it can be aggravating the situation
and also the necessity for great care, great attention on the part of the homeopath,
when he is dealing with cases that are really serious and close to death.
The first case I would like to give you and for those who know Homeopathy they will try to
follow my way of reasoning, why we prescribe that remedy or the other remedy and I must
say from the beginning that the way that we treat is by giving one remedy at the time,
based upon the total symptomatology of the patient and observing the results that they
come after the prescription of that remedy.
So that we may in continuation decide whether we should prescribe a complementary
remedy, another remedy, a remedy that follows well, a higher potency, a repetition of the
same potency etc.
This is a case of a man, a civil engineer, 72 years old and the case is from the14th of
September of 1979.
This man was operated in America, in Houston in Spring Memorial Hospital, for an aorta
transplant. The operation was successful but the patient developed very high fever that
was not amenable, was not showing any tendency to go down in spite of many
antibiotics, high doses of penicillin that have been given with the result that after two
months of continuous fever after the operation, the cardiologist who had operated him in
Houston accompanied him in Greece and put him in a hospital in Greece.
The patient stayed in one of the best hospitals of Athens for another month under the
same condition without showing any amelioration.
Eventually he went into a coma state and the doctors in attendance called the relatives of
the patient and asked them whether they should open the left leg, the veins,
in order to feed this patient, in order to give saline because both hands and
the right leg were swollen up from trying to find the veins of this man and
it was impossible anymore to feed, to give
the saline through the intravenous.
The doctors told the relatives that they did not think they should continue with the case,
they thought it was a matter of a few days, the patient would die within 2-3 days and they
were asking whether the relatives wanted to continue the treatment.
At this stage because the daughter of this man was known to me and a friend, she came
and ask whether Homeopathy could do something for her father.
I said, this is a very good case for Homeopathy.
The man was on the hospital and I did not want to go through the back door in the hospital
and treat the case, so I asked the relatives to ask the doctors in attendance whether they
would agree that I would go there to treat the patient homeopathically, in which case they
had to withdraw all their medicines.
The doctors as you may understand were very happy that the patient will die under
Homeopathy.
After withdrawing the medicines that they were giving, they had reached the point where
they were giving amphotericin B. This is a very virulent medicine that is given for fungus
infections and it is a very strong medicine that has a lot of side effects.
Anyhow the medicine was withdrawn and the condition of the patient was, as I told you,
he was in a comatose state with his kidneys functioning barely, urea was very high, the
clearance of the urine was 9, which indicates a great diminution of the functioning of the
kidneys, the blood pressure was high, the fever was under medicine from 37.8 to 38.2
and once the remedy was withdrawn fever shoot up to 39.5.
When I saw the patient, he was lying, breathing deeply and a very red, with reddish face,
completely immovable, he didn’t seem to suffer in spite of the fact that he was swollen in
his both upper extremities and the leg. He had already developed some bad source from
lying for so long time, he was in a quite deep coma, not in very deep and there was a slight
perspiration, oily face and the appearance of the coma indicated a remedy that is good for
such conditions. What is the remedy then?
-Opium.
-Opium very good. Opium 200 was given and that was in the morning. In the evening
they were some signs, a little bit motion and also some kind of words, they were not words
yet but some kind of moaning coming out.
By next morning the coma was reduced, still the patient was not in a condition to
communicate but if the daughter would speak to him, he would have some kind of reaction.
The fever remained still high but there was some signs definitely that the remedy had
started working.
What is interesting is that in that first night he was restless, much more restless now,
passed a stool, fever in the night 39.6 in the morning 38.8 pulse 124.
Anyhow I will make it more quick.
After 2 days the man had come somewhat out of coma, that means he was able to
communicate, his fever started coming down but as the state was remaining more or less
stable, that means it was no progressing, I retook the case with the help of his wife and his
daughter.
What I did, I asked from them all the information that was available about him before he
went for operation, that means what type of person he was. He was a warm blooded or a
cold blooded case? It was a person who was suffering with headaches, he was suffering
with constipation, he had some diarrheas, stomach problems?
All the details that were possible to elicit from his wife and his daughter.
The idea was in this case to give a remedy that we call, if it is possible to find, the
constitutional remedy, a remedy that will go deeper and will stimulate the defenses further.
According to the information that was given, this man was a hot blooded man, was having
different other problems with his heart, with palpitations, before the operation, he was
easily tired but the details of his case pointed out to Sulphur.
So Sulphur 200 was given and the recovery started speeding up.
He went another 2-3 nights where he was coming out of coma but still in a very confusive
state of mind. The fifth day while the fever was almost practically down, gone, the night
nurse related to me that the whole night the patient was very restless and he was
constantly talking.
Talking in a delirium and talking about words that did not fit a man, a civil engineer of 72
years old. He was a very conservative man and to talk about sexual matters and talking
about some prostitutes, saying words which are obscene.
This delirium was going on. The morning of the fifth day I went to see the case with the
delirium going on all the night constantly. When I saw him he was in that delirium state,
restless, talking, talking and talking in this language as I told you.
Because he was still quite red, the blood pressure was quite high, the loquacity brought
to my mind the remedy which will we call Lachesis.
So Lachesis 200 was given in the case and there was the mistake.
I gave Lachesis, the evening of the fifth night and next day the sixth day I go to the
hospital to see him, he is in a worse state than before. The blood pressure has shoot up to
200, his speech now is slammering, it’s still delirium but the words are not heard and the
man seems to go back.
And as I’m going to talk to you about harmonious and inharmonious remedies.
For me there are no harmonious and inharmonious, there are correct and non-correct
remedies.
The correct remedy will act harmoniously, even if initially brings about a kind of
aggravation. The incorrect remedy may act inharmoniously, may produce a disturbance
or a kind of bad reaction, especially the high potency and more especially if we are dealing
with cases that are in a state of sensitivity and when I say sensitivity I mean patients that
are in a state of great precariousness, they are ready, maybe to die.
In such conditions, we can not afford to make mistakes because we shall have the result
that I was having. In this case he was beautifully, the man was coming out of coma, the
fever was dropping, there was a possibility that he may be resurrected from death and
there on the third remedy, I made the mistake and I gave the wrong remedy.
The wrong remedy produced immediately a reaction in this case, why?
Because it was incorrect but close to the case. That means the remedy was quite close,
it was fitting the case, not absolutely but quite a lot. Therefore it disturbed, it acted
inharmoniously and not curatively.
When you have a case like that, then you have to sit there and think and think and think,
now what are you going to do? The only thing that we can give in such cases is neither
give an antidote or anything like that but finding what is the correct remedy which is
indicated at the moment.
Lachesis was wrong, what was the correct remedy?
If I could find that, I may be able to save this patient.
Apart from the delirium was continuing, as I said, but also I noticed that the hands of the
patient were mostly on his genitalia. So with this loquacity, with this obscene talking, with
the hands constantly on the genitalia which was confirmed by the nurse that was in
attendance, the correct remedy was not Lachesis but it was Hyoscyamus.
The symptomatology is so much in favor of Hyoscyamus that then the redness of the
face can be disregarded. Neither it’s always that Hyoscyamus has a pale face.
Hyoscyamus again 200 was prescribed and soon the patient came out of delirium and
I would just relate this case up to here, I will tell you in few words what happened later,
just to show how the wrong remedy acted in an inharmonious way.
The patient on the 12th day asked to be taken away from the hospital because in the
hospital there was nothing to be done because all the doctors of the hospital had left the
case to me and the only thing that was done with the case he was fed through the nose,
with a tube, he was fed with some crust food, that’s all the hospital was providing.
Therefore was no real reason for the patient staying in the hospital.
The 12th day he asked to go away from the hospital and continue the treatment in his
house. We continued the treatment and after a month of initial treatment where the patient
was doing really well, he had during this period of time another 3 remedies, one of which
was Apis.
After Apis he was given Natrum muriaticum and then Calcarea carbonica.
These are the remedies he had during this month of recovery.
They were 3 doctors in attendance of this case, one was a cardiologist, one a nephrologist
and a general practitioner. I asked the patient to call the cardiologist that was attending the
case in the hospital because I wanted his advice as his ankles were still somewhat
swollen.
The cardiologist went to the house, rang the bell, somebody opened the door and he said I
would like to see Mr Stathopoulos, Stathopoulos is the name of the patient.
He says I am Mr Stathopoulos. The cardiologist said, not you, the patient.
He says I am the patient. He could not recognize his patient that had one month ago in a
coma, in a state of vegetable, he could not recognize him one month later, he could not
believe him.
This is interesting to see the effect of homeopathic remedies and what can bring about as
people believe that Homeopathy is good for little things, if you have a little headaches, if
you have a little of cold, pains here and there, then Homeopathy is good.
No, Homeopathy is a very potentially strong and correct treatment that if it is applied
properly can save a lot of the cases that are going on untreated today and they are going
on suffering year after year.
He is now 78 years old, still going strong, last year actually he travelled to Canada.
His son is there in the University and he is actually in a very good condition, I have been
attending him for a few times during these years, he did not need very much support.