One of the cases that some of you have seen last year in Alonissos.
It is a retarded child, a mongoloid child and with epileptic convulsions.
It is one of those cases that when you see you don’t foretell much about their improvement.
They are very difficult cases to have any kind of improvement.
I will tell you a little bit of what you are not going to see in this
and the people who were there can confirm about it.
The child took a remedy, I don’t want to tell you the remedy now,
you will hear it after you see the case and I said give the remedy to potency of 30 or 200.
Because it was not a regular remedy could not be found.
Eventually telephone calls, different places and the remedy was found and it was given.
The potency that was found and was given, without my knowledge instead of 200, was CM.
CM is 100.000, it was a very high potency and for those that were present
and they remember the case, as I was analyzing another case,
the child had got the remedy the day before, somebody comes into the class
and says the child has a tremendous aggravation, it can not breathe and it’s blue.
What shall we do? It is one of these moments where you lose your mind
and you do whatever you can to save the child because the child is blue, it can not breathe.
It’s going to die in an hour or two, perhaps less.
But knowing what I know about Homeopathy, knowing that the remedy was the correct one,
I thought that if we support the child, with some support, like a little bit of oxygen,
most probably the child will get over it.
Everyone was amazed in the class to see me very cool and say, get a bottle of oxygen and
give him a little bit of oxygen. Everybody was trembling in the class.
The child did not actually need the bottle of oxygen because before they could find
the bottle of oxygen, the child started recovering and you will see now the initial case
and I will show you, when I analyze the case, the different follow ups.
There are three follow ups from last year.
It’s about a whole year now of treatment and I will show you what took place all along the line.
We start the case from the beginning.
Also it is interesting to observe in this case, that the child has gotten different
homeopathic remedies before and you will say a bit better but not real action of the remedy.
When you give the right remedy, it’s another story always.
You give a remedy which is close, does something but the patient returns
back to the same situation.
You may be treating a person for two years and after two years you find he is exactly the same,
as you started. That means he never got the right remedy.
In all cases that are coming to me, usually they are coming after homeopathic treatment
and other treatments and this is the case with that child.
So we’ll hear the story by a New Zealander. The parents are now in New Zealand
and they just sent me last August the last taped follow up.
The husband is studying Homeopathy himself, so he will give the case himself.
-We have two other children, a daughter and we have a son who is adopted.
-So tell me the story what happened? What has been diagnosed as Down syndrome?
What is the problem with the child?
-He has Down syndrome, which is diagnosed and that’s not the problem.
The problem is that at six months he started to have infantile spasms, epilepsy
and from that point his growth and his development came to a standstill
and not just came to a standstill...
-Because most of the students are not English speaking, you have to speak slower and clearly.
You come from New Zealand and have a New Zealand accent as well; have that in mind also
because the whole class will go into spasms.
-I’ll try to speak like a Greek.
-Right, exactly, everybody understands a Greek.
-At six months his progress was almost the same as any normal six month old child
but it just stopped.
-Why?
-Apparently - we didn’t discover this until he was a year old - a child
that has infantine spasms, which are very rare, the development stops.
-But why he had these spasms according to your understanding? You have an explanation?
Why at six months he started having spasms, do you have an explanation?
-No. The only thing that we thought possibly it could have brought it on, was the heat.
It was in the middle of our summer and he had been very, very restless for two days
in the heat and we changed his bed to the coolest spot and he still had no energy
and then the spasms started, two days later.
-OK. Did he have any fever during that time?
-He was not sick at all, I was not concerned about his health, I was just concerned
about the heat.
-Heat seems to aggravate him quite a bit and even now the heat will increase the convulsions.
-So does he get fever ever?
-No.
-So far he has no fever. When he gets these spasms, what he does? Can you repeat?
-Well the spasms have now changed, they have become a grand mal, jerking and..
-Describe exactly what takes place.
-Can I show you?
-Yes.
-It comes up like this, it think it begins here. Everything comes out. (parent demonstrates)
-It is exactly like that. Every time the eyes go to the right.
-The eyes go always to the right and the head turns to the right.
-And the leg is in a real tight muscular position. The other one seems to stay all right.
-The first minute the breathing seems to stop?
-Yes.
-And as starts to breathe, he starts grasping breathe.
-But the first is to come together, to bend together and then expands and he turns to the right.
How long it lasts, the crisis?
-The crisis only a measure of minutes.
-Minutes or seconds?
- Minutes, three minutes but the… lasts for half an hour because he’s sleepy
and he is not completely conscious.
-For half an hour, he is not completely conscious and he has little jerks.
-After half an hour he is back to normal but it takes certain amount of time for him
to really come through it.
-As he comes out, he becomes very tired and sleepy and he would often go to sleep afterwards
but he has a great tiredness and then as he comes more and more out of it,
the twitching stops and then he comes around and is back to his normal state.
-But it always occurs after waking up, so it could after an hour when he wakes up
but normally half an hour after he wakes up.
-In the morning?
-In the morning and in the afternoon, after sleep.
-The crisis happens after sleep?
-Yes.
-And he is aggravated by heat.
-And stuffy conditions.
-It can be hot, as long as there’s a wind flowing over him, he’s ok.
-There is anything else?
-This form of epilepsy has only occurred in the last three days and then started the jerking
and only in the last month he had these grand mal convulsions.
-What remedies he has taken so far?
-You want me to run through them?
-Yes.
-We go back to the 15th of the 2nd 1986 with Epilim and he became really tired,
Epilim which is a form of medication for epilepsy, allopathic, yes
- For one month and then you took him off, why?
-Because he became very restless and he got Opium 200 and it had an effect.
We saw the effect, we saw it was good, so we took him off the medication
and then he got Pulsatilla 200, which stopped the convulsions for one month
and they came back after a session of cranial massage.
- Cranial massage… by a cranial osteopath?
- Yes.
By the way it’s the only time he had a high temperature.
After the cranial massage he got an extremely high temperature, it’s the only time.
We took him to the hospital.
-It put the temperature to about 38 or something.
-Otherwise he never had high temperature. After this cranial massage,
the crisis continued and you repeated Pulsatilla?
-Yes, we repeated Pulsatilla 200 and he got Opium again and it was never taken any higher.
-The second time he took Pulsatilla, no effect and then Opium second time,
no effect?
-No.
-And then?
-Then he got Psorinum 1M and there was no reaction.
Then he got Electricitas 200 and after that…
-Why? Who gave this?
-At that stage we took him to [doctor’s name] in June.
He gave him Electricitas and then he gave him Medorrhinum.
He suffers from a rash in the genital area and the Medorrhinum had a big effect on that,
lasted for long time but now not.
-In the beginning he had a big aggravation in the rash?
-A long term, very bad.
-And then it did not affect the convulsions?
-It didn’t touch the convulsions. After that he got Baryta carbonica 10M.
Nothing.
-Baryta carbonica.
-I gave him a lot of potencies, different remedies. Pulsatilla, Cuprum 6C,
Aethusa 30 and 2.4.5T. This is a potency of a weed killer.
-He was diagnosed by this particular […]
-No effect?
-No reaction really.
We got to a point where he is wasting weight, not eating.
He is always consistently vomiting his food.
-Still today, continuously after eating, he just pulls out a mouthful
and then another mouthful and another mouthful.
And we discovered that in the days that he is more aggravated by this vomiting,
he doesn’t have the same amount of convulsions or he doesn’t have any convulsions.
-If he vomits?
-If he has a bad day, when he is sick all day, he doesn’t have convulsions.
-Otherwise the convulsions are every day?
-Every day.
-From 1 to 3 times.
-But we are not a 100% sure that he doesn’t have the convulsions when he vomits.
-This is an observation.
-Yes.
-Yesterday he was sick all day, he didn’t have any fits.
-What do we see so far?
-Apis.
-What I asked is what do you see so far? You saw a picture here and I’m asking you
to describe what you have seen, what you would tell me. I have not seen the case,
you have seen it and you describe to me.
If you are able to describe the correct points, maybe you will be able to find the right remedy.
-The child is only concerned with himself.
-That’s correct. That’s very correct because still it has not been said
that the child has no contact at all.
If you talk to the child, the child will just pay no notice, doubtful whether he will
even see you, even notice; it’s an autistic child without any contact at all,
on top of that we have convulsions.
But when I ask you to describe what you have seen, what you will say?
I don’t want you to improvise so much, as to describe to me what you have heard and seen.
-He seems to be jerking…
-I do not know anything about the case, I have not seen the case.
You are describing to me the case. Tell me.
-Do you mind if I make a remark? I’m examining you, I’m giving you some examples.
I’m going to make some remarks about what you are saying. Do you mind?
-He sucks his right foot, throwing back himself in the chair and the arms seems to jerk a lot.
-He is salivating quite a lot.
-Blonde headed, blue eyed, chubby child.
-Do you come from Australia?
-Yes.
-We got her.
-Even when he vomits a lot, seems to put on weight.
-Somebody else?
-A child who has epilepsy and at the same time is restless, autistic child, skin symptoms.
-He has almost chorea sometimes.
-If I was going to describe to you the case, what I would have said to you?
You have not seen the case and I’m going to describe to you the case.
I would describe to you what impressed me in the case. I would not use my imagination.
I would describe the same things as I heard.
What I heard and I have seen is that this is a very restless child with jerkings along that
but what impressed me is the description of the child when it has the convulsion.
The description which the father did, where the child makes all distortions and convulsions
and goes into spasm.
That is the description of the crisis and when I’m going to transmit to you the case,
I’m going to say this is a very restless child, without any contact with anybody,
sucking this thumb, having these jerks when during the time of real convulsions,
epileptic convulsions, what we see is kind of terrifying.
When the father describes the crisis, there is something, a feeling in you. You didn’t feel it?
All these convulsions and distortions. And the child is ameliorated by cool air
but what is impressive is the retardation of the child.
The child after six months started being retarded.
He was a mongoloid child, he was with Down syndrome but he seemed to be kind of well
until six months. At six months something took place and the child started being retarded.
There is no communication with the child at all and this is the description
that you are going to search in your Materia Medica, in order to fit the case with a remedy.
You ask yourself what kind of remedy would have this picture?
This is the question we are searching for in this case. What is the type of remedy?
What is the remedy? Have you read your Materia Medica?
Yes, you may remember the remedy. You have not read it?
Search and search, in the Repertory is very difficult to find the remedy.
You have to read the Materia Medica right through. From A to Z.
A, B, C, D, E… nobody continues further than that, it’s impossible.
You have somebody to pour cold water on your head and say, continue, study.
I’ve been studying the whole Materia Medica perhaps for one case like that.
In the first years I read this Boericke Materia Medica, I read it right through when I bought it,
like a detective story.
That’s very interesting, that’s why I never claimed I studied Homeopathy.
I never studied Homeopathy, I enjoyed reading Homeopathy.
But for me you can’t say I studied but to become a homeopath you have to study.
If you don’t enjoy it so much, you have to study, if you enjoy, continue.
When I will show you the remedy that I prescribed and I read it from the books,
you will recognize it. You will say, yes this is the remedy, why didn’t I think about it.
You can’t think of it if you’ve never read it.
And of course to have steady results in Homeopathy, to have results which are consistent,
you will have to know all the Materia Medica.
Otherwise you know how much of the Materia Medica? 10%. 10% will be your results.
You know 20%? 20% will be your results.
You know 40%? 40% will be your results. You know 98%? Nobody knows 98.
Do not think I know 98. I’m close to 80, 90.
Maybe a little bit more than that but nobody can claim that knows all the Materia Medica.
But you have to have studied at least once, to go through Boericke, which is 1000 pages.
You can do it in four days, you go through it.
Also what is important is to perceive the case, to understand the case.
To perceive the case does not mean in this case he is better from cold, better from warm…
Better from cold? Pulsatilla. Everybody knows Pulsatilla. No.
Sometimes we have a remedy that in the book says, better from cold and we find it worse from cold.
Better from cold here and in the books it says better from warm. Worse from cold.
You will not stop on that detail.
That detail is not important. What is important is to fit the whole picture
and in order to fit the picture, you need this perception.
I sit there and I tremble, I don’t know the remedy myself. I look and look and I observe.
I perceive everything, what the father says and what the child does.
And I search and search in my memory. What is this now? It appears familiar.
Retardation, the child has convulsions; what you have not seen yet
because the camera is not yet close, you will also the child has also strabismus.
Continue with the case.
-What else?
-I gave him Ferrum 6C and he got a reaction from that.
He is really continued to come along physically since that point to where he’s physically…
-This eruption when it came out?
-Recently. After another remedy.
-Which remedy?
-I gave him, this is the last time I prescribed, I gave him Pulsatilla three times a day
for two days and while he was under its influence the convulsions got down.
He was very happy but as soon as I stopped, they came again.
After that we took him to another homeopath and she gave Belladonna 200.
-He is testing me. Can you see that? The father is testing me, why?
Why I say he is testing me? Because he says, then we gave
Belladonna and after there is a pause. What he is testing is to say, who gave Belladonna?
It was wrong or something like that. He wants to see my reaction towards Belladonna.
So I do not answer.
I wait to see. He’s testing me, he wants to hear what I have to say about Belladonna.
I want you to observe these things. It is not important at this moment.
What is important is that you perceive. You become sensitive and you perceive
because the human mind is made in this way that can all the time distort
and present another picture and go through the mind and the mind distorts
and again it presents the way it wants to present things.
We are interested in what is instinctive in the health. What is instinctual.
Not what intellectual explanation is given about a certain situation.
We are interested about the right thing, what the nature is producing.
The nature is producing a violent character. It is producing violence inside.
It is a Nux vomica. It is producing anger.
And you will see sitting there a Nux vomica, I think one of the doctors is here
who presented his boss, a surgeon, the head of the hospital.
Flabby, fat, you say typical Calc.carbonica.
Sitting there, worse cold etc. but it wouldn’t suit Calcarea carbonica, so searching and
searching and he had severe headaches that they were bothering him.
But I could not see the remedy and then at a certain point I thought,
maybe that is a case of Nux vomica.
The anger was not appearing at all, he was a calm man, sitting there, giving answers,
very cool, very calm.
I said to him do you get angry sometimes? Are you irritable? He says, no
and then I received a kick because the doctor who was working with him, he kicks me.
Because he was his boss, his director and they were in surgery together,
so he knew him when he was in surgery, give me this tool!
I said, well I don’t mean that you express anger, whether you feel anger inside.
He says, yes sometimes. I feel anger but I don’t express it.
What we need to perceive is that, not what the person says. No, I’m not irritable.
We have to go beyond. That’s why I said here, do you see what he is doing?
You have to see all these things. He is testing me. Why he is testing me?
Because before I passed some judgment on the different remedies.
What about that remedy? What do you say about that remedy?
He wants to know before he gives me the feedback, what happened.
It’s very difficult to play games with me because I have so much experience.
I’ve seen thousands and thousands of cases.
It’s very difficult to play games. It’s better we tell the truth now.
-After that we took him to another homeopath and she gave Belladonna 200.
He wants to play games, you see? But it’s so obvious for me.
For you, you do not take notice in the beginning; you do not know what is happening,
you just sit and it goes through.
But for me I don’t leave anything unnoticed. Nothing passes unnoticed.
I’m not saying I’m doing this, no. I’m saying you have to do that and I’m showing you
in practice what you have to do, how much sensitive you have to become to perceive.
Don’t get ideas in your mind, now he is going to tell me this. This is wrong.
Keep your mind quite open. I said to myself why he stopped?
I put a question to myself and then I get the answer immediately, it’s automatic.
But if I had ideas, he is going to tell me this, I’ll say do you want to tell me this?
He says yes, but this is not an answer. You wait, you wait with a mind
which is empty, empty mind. And you look and you see that is the game.
-He went into a fever, this was a lot 39C and  lots of twitching and jerking,
this was going on for about 24 hours and after that very irritable for a few  days
and then amelioration starts to coming up.
After that nothing with the convulsions. Straight after that he had a flue.
He doesn’t get a lot of acute things. So these are the two things.
That was just before we left to come over here.
-This remark is very important. You will hear it again and again.
He does not get acutes or if they get acutes, they are mild acutes.
One day fever, a little bit of fever, not very high, not severe things.
Children or grown ups who are deeply disturbed in their mental-emotional
level, the nervous system is affected a lot, they will not get severe acutes.
The severe acutes come when the organism has been lifted to another level
and then they get acutes.
If this child there is a time where he will get a real acute, it’s going to be a pneumonia
and it’s going to be life threatening and you expect for that.
You expect if you prescribe correctly and as the child is raising in health,
then the real acute will come and then its’ going to be very severe and difficult to treat
and you have to be very careful to treat correctly.
Because by the time you are treating wrongly this acute, there is a relapse.
You see he makes a remark, just passing, he doesn’t get acutes.
-So these are the two things that come up. That was just before we left to come over here.
At the end of that flue he had that cough and the cough became chronic
and when we got over here, we took him to a homeopath and he prescribed Syphilinum 1M.
-The Belladonna what potency it was?
-200.
-And the Syphilinum 1M.
-Yes and he got cold on top of this cough and in two weeks he got very irritable
and the convulsions went away.
-After Syphilinum?
-Yes and he was just having a few twichings.
This lasted for about three weeks and we came into France which was very hot
and we’ve come back again and it got continuously worse since that time.
-Now the convulsions are becoming worse and worse?
-Yes, that was changing all the time.
You see the story that you hear is after several remedies, where are we? Nowhere.
Can you tell me if you give the right remedy, what you would expect to happen in this child
to suppose that the remedy has acted in a correct manner?
Can you give me an indication what you would expect to have that child to say,
oh it’s improving really?
The improvement has started from a deep level, what you would expect?
-To make contact.
-Very good, make contact.
The child must reach a point where he makes a contact. The child has no contact.
It’s closed up completely. He does not even see, when we put this, he doesn’t look.
The parents say it doesn’t matter how much we make this, no reaction.
They don’t know if it sees. The child is deeply disturbed and what is the deepest part?
It’s the mental. Mentally gone completely.
If the remedy that we give is acting, it has to act in that level first,
never mind the convulsions.
If it acts on this level, the convulsions will be taken care.
That is what we want to improve, to see a child that becomes a human being.
This is a zombie now.
And we try to make it to a human being. This is the idea. Stop the convulsions?
Forget about the convulsions completely, if they stop or they don’t stop.
Give me the contact, give me the child back. The child is gone.
You have an epileptic who is between us, nobody notices, he is a human being, he’s not a zombie.
He has convulsions, all right from time to time he has some convulsions.
That’s why they call this disease the divine disease or something like that.
Because the epileptic fit is very close to a kind of ecstasy, out of the body experiences
of the yogis, the spiritual people etc.
This is not the problem. The convulsion is not the real problem here.
The real problem is that we don’t have a human being.
I give a remedy and I say, the cough is finished, therefore my remedy has acted.
No, this is not the deeper problem.
So we want to see the deeper problem, we want to prescribe on a deeper level,
on the whole picture as we see it, then we have to find the remedy that fits
the picture that we described. Retarded, idiotic child, with convulsions, distortions etc.
We go ahead, see some more.
-Now the convulsions are becoming worse and worse?
-Yes, all the time and that’s really very…
-What can you say about his character?
-He doesn’t react to any stimulation, unless it’s physical, unless you actually touch him,
or throw him.
He doesn’t react to food, but we had X-rays of the brain and they showed totally undeveloped
cerebellum which apparently stops him of being able to respond to visual stimulation.
He doesn’t really respond to any visual stimulation…
-When you try to put food in his mouth, he will open it?
Here we have the actual pathology, we have the anatomical pathology,
where the cerebellum is undeveloped. The only thing is he makes some movement.
When you touch him, there is some kind of reaction, that’s all.
Can we do something with this child homeopathically? I do not know.
We’re going to see but at this moment I do not know.
I have seen things happening with the homeopathic remedy, which are unbelievable.
Is he going to develop his cerebellum, I don’t know.
I’ve seen it happening sometimes. Why sometimes and not always? I do not know.
Do we always give the right remedy and the response was… I don’t know.
How do I know if I gave the right remedy in all cases? Maybe I did not.
Let’s see.
-He won’t respond to a toy even if the toy is…  It takes a lot to make him reach out.
It’s hard work, you can see… He doesn’t respond to us as his parents.
-He is very restless, like that.
- Yes, and after the Syphilinum…
What I want is to make a remark here,  that usually the parents of such children
do not want to see and to face the reality.
My child is very good. If I ask to describe, it’s a very nice child, always smiling.
The child is standing there and they call it a smile.
Always smiling, never a problem…
I mean this is what you perceive and I say, do they really see what is going on?
And unless we really have the picture, we are not able to perceive.
From descriptions I have heard about autistic children and almost everything is perfect
apart from the fact that he doesn’t talk. What else he does?
There is nothing else he does but he does not talk.
So these parents have impressed me because they are quite objective.
Therefore you may be able to rely on their information if they call you on the telephone
and say the child is better.
You give a remedy and all the parents, ah it’s getting better.
Because they want the child to get better and they tell you on the telephone,
it is so much better, to find out later on it is worse.
So these parents impressive, they can give quite an objective evaluation.
No parent can be absolutely objective but they are quite objective.
Continue.
-He is very restless like that.
-Yes and after the Syphilinum it was interesting because […]
he became incredibly nasty and naughty.
-Nasty, when I say nasty, nasty for him is just to be so irritable and very restless.
-[…] All afternoon he had this irritability, he just kept going through the…[?].
-He doesn’t have it anymore.
-Red spots came after the Syphilinum and after the convulsions.
-[?]
-The left eye is looking outwards?
-It didn’t use to, it does now.
-He likes to (be cuddled?) very much and he likes darkness and when it was earlier on
he would sleep from midnight…
This child we can’t be justified thinking about Stramonium because Stramonium
has convulsions, etc. but what they said here, which is against Stramonium?
-He loves dark.
-He loves dark. Stramonium never.
It never loves the dark. It’s one of the few things that we
may say never. In Homeopathy you can not say for a symptom in a remedy, always has to be this.
Because you will find one case that it will not have that particular symptom.
Most of the cases 99% they will have. Stramonium 99% will have fear of dark,
aggravation from dark, fear from dark.
So the child, if it is Stramonium, it has to show some aggravation in the dark.
On the contrary he likes dark.
It’s gone. Stramonium is gone for that reason alone, if we don’t have other reasons.
-He loves dark, when he was earlier on, he would sleep until midnight and from midnight to
the morning he would wake and laugh and play, just playing with himself until the morning
and then go back to sleep… He likes fresh…
-He has an aversion to warm food. He likes all vegetables cold…
-Are you sure there was no accident? He didn’t fall down before the convulsions?
-He fell a couple of weeks before, he fell from the bed but he didn’t cry very much
and it didn’t seem to be any damage.
-He fell off the [?] there is no bruising but according to the medical professionals
in New  Zealand that was head coming out [?].
There is no brain damage showing up on the scans.
-The strabismus formed with the beginning of the convulsions?
-I don’t know… two months old  and he had convulsions from six months old.
-He had convulsions for four months, when you noticed it, not for six months?
-No, he was two months old when the convulsions started that I noticed that it was going outwards.
-How is his thirst?
-We don’t give him a lot to drink because it’s the drink that comes out more than the food.
-He doesn’t demand that and if we give him water…He obviously doesn’t suffer from thirst.
Even in this very hot weather.
-The big eruptions after which remedy started? Three months ago started the grand mal,
four months ago?
-Just how long we have been here? Two months? Six weeks ago.
-Then started the biggest. The last remedy was Syphilinum?
-Yes. Before the Syphilinum, after Belladonna.
-So the big convulsions, the grand mal, started after Belladonna. Correct?
-Yes. And then it begun when it got very hot in India.
In India he got in a situation where he was very, very hot and after this they became strong
and that was about two and a half months ago.
-That was after Belladonna?
-Yes.
-Belladonna was given by a woman homeopath?
-Yes, in New Zealand.
-Now the convulsions will come after sleep?
-Yes.
-So he does have convulsions during sleep?
-So he has convulsions either during sleep or when he wakes up, half an hour after?
-It’s a little bit difficult to be sure because he has convulsions during the night,
so he might be awake until he has that convulsion, so we don’t know if he has been awake,
but at times when he’s awake, he goes straight to a convulsion.
He has also a peculiar symptom on his convulsions. Did anybody remember what is this?
He begins in the head and spreads, except from that, more peculiar.
Tends backwards, more peculiar?
Turns to the right, more peculiar?
Convulsion are better in cool air.
It’s very violent, yes.
The eye goes to the right, no.
Maybe he didn’t say it so far.
Stretches, no.
Right side, no.
Come along with sleep, no.
Terrifying expression, no.
When someone touches him, no.
The breathing seems to stop, no.
That was described I think by his father.
Opisthotonus, no.
Fever convulsions, no.
The convulsions came out when Belladonna, no.
That shows that the treatment actually on the long run is pushing rather the disease inwards,
not outwards.
We see the child does not get a contact and his convulsions become worse finally
after all these remedies. This is not what I’m asking.
I think something which perhaps you didn’t hear well.
To tolerate the heat, no.
Convulsions after sleep, no.
It’s a peculiarity of something the child does during convulsion.
Stretches out the extremities, yes.
Turns to right, no.
Head backwards, no.
Most probably it’s his New Zealand pronunciation that you didn’t follow that sentence.
I think you are tired.
-No.
-You have to have a break.
The respiration is difficult during convulsions, no.
Maybe I heard it only, nobody else heard it.
Facial distortions, yes.
But what he does with his hands? He does something he said.
Maybe I’m wrong, I didn’t hear it well.
He is saying that the child during convulsion he is pressing his eye.
You didn’t hear it?
-No.
-This is very interesting. I thought he said it. Maybe he will repeat it again.
We put it back and find out.
What is very interesting for me, why the child makes automatic movements?
He goes and presses the right eye, the left eye, I can’t remember now.
If you didn’t hear it most probably you will hear it again.
During convulsion he will press very hard one point.
This becomes a very grand characteristic of the remedy of which we did not have
information in the books.
Therefore if we find the remedy that will act in that child, we know that this is a symptom
that may use it, if we see it again in another child or another case.
Pressing in the eye during convulsions, he will press and press his eyes very, very strongly.
You will hear it again and again, perhaps he will say it.
He never said it? All right I give you the point but I made my point.
This is very characteristic, we will not find it in the books but it may be
characteristic of the remedy. It’s a little detail. If you find it, then that is the remedy.