-I am treated by Homeopathy since 1984 and I got the same remedy Carcinosin every two months
in 2 years in average.
In 1983 we were in England for 1 year, in Oxford and then I was very exhausted,
I had severe insomnia.
We were coming for 1 year with 4 little children and I couldn’t sleep for 3 months.
I had 2-3 hours at night and I went to a homeopath and she prescribed me Sepia 200C
and that really didn’t do anything.
In December I had a fracture in my fibula and I was hospitalized for 1 week
and after that operation I slept very well.
In that year 1993 in May I got Phosphorus 200C and by that I felt something, more than before.
-From Sepia and Carcinosin you felt no change?
-Carcinosin I got many times before and I didn’t feel anything.
I had (?) who were very, very difficult, I’ll come to this later but I felt no effect.
I came here because I want a change.
Actually I never had initial aggravation after taking a remedy;
only after the Phosphorus I had skin eruption that is still there in my back.
It is covered like mushroom and this is the only thing that happened.
But I felt better after Phosphorus.
Then 2 years ago, I had again symptoms that I had years before, fear for my son.
He got for the first time his letter from the army to go. This is my oldest son.
He is now 18.
I felt a lot of anxiety around this issue and again insomnia, I was also constipated
and I got again Carcinosin 1M and for the first time
the symptoms really disappeared quite immediately and I felt different for the first time.
-When did you receive Carcinosin 1M?
-2 years ago and that took away those symptoms of great fear from cancer
and especially fear for my child.
-You have fear of cancer?
-Not so much now.
But I used to have that. I got the Carcinosin before because my homeopath was very touched
from my circumstances that both of my parents died when they were 50 years old from cancer.
-Both parents died at the age of 50?
-My father was 51, my mother was 50.
-And how old you are?
-I’m 44.
My father died 20 years ago and my mother died 15 years ago and usually I can still cry
when I talk about that.
-You were born in Israel or in America?
-I was born in Jerusalem.
My parents were holocaust survivors, they were very young then.
In the war my mother was 11 and my father was 16 and they came to Israel after the war from Hungary.
We didn’t hear at home much about the war, nothing. Nothing was talked about the war
but my father especially was very reserved and had tremendous grief.
He expressed that in doing philosophy. He was philosopher.
My mother was very active and dynamic and she did a lot, she was very bright intellectual.
They wanted to have a new family, a new future. They had 5 children.
-They came to Israel after the war.
-You loved your father?
-Yes.
-Very much?
-Indeed.
-And your mother?
-I had special relationship with my mother.
But much more normal relationship, I could fight, I could get angry. I could challenge her.
-But my father was a figure …
-He was a figure you admired or you loved at the same time or mostly admire?
-No. I really, really loved him. And I could feel him very much.
-You could feel his pain, you are hurt of how he died?
-Yes my parents died with us, at home. I wasn’t with my father’s death.
He was invited to Switzerland to give lectures; he was then very ill, my mother was sure
that she could fight with god. She was determined that he will live and he will get over his illness,
he was in the last stages of colon cancer then but he accepted the invitation
and he was lecturing in (?) until a week before his death.
By that time I stayed in Israel with my little brother and I didn’t see him in his last 6 weeks.
-What is your main problem at this moment?
-My main problem is that I would like to shift, I’m too much emotional.
-You think?
-Yes I feel a lot of emotions.
-You belong to a religious group which is very strict.
-No we’re not very strict.
-Can you tell me?
-You want me to describe you?
-Yes.
-We don’t really belong.
We are (?) to find our own way in doing tradition of Judaism and creating our own way.
-Do you feel restricted at all by religion?
-No.
-On the contrary?
-On the contrary, it’s a feeling for values from history that I shift to next generation
with a lot of learning.
-So what is the problem with a lot of emotions. I don’t see a problem.
Everybody likes a lot of emotions, why you want to have less emotions?
-I can cry easily, I can sit with patients and I need to hold myself.
-Not to cry?
-Not so much in those situations, in my clinic I’m more settled
but I’m too much moved too much impulsive.
-Where did you learn English?
-Basically in Israel.
-You understand the meaning of the word impulsive? Impulsive is somebody
who can not hold back his opinion because his emotions are strong and he goes into fights,
he goes into stating opinions very easily, even if it a strong opinion, even if it’s going to hurt others.
That’s impulsive. If somebody is full of love and affection and you express this love
and affection, you are not impulsive. I want you to understand what you are telling me
because this is what I understand by impulsive.
Maybe you have another idea of what impulsive is. What is impulsive for you?
-No, I’m like I said before. I would like to shift some of here, here and not to be so emotional.
-Not to cry so easily.
-For example yes.
-Can you describe a little bit more what is the problem?
When you say to me I want to move some emotions into my head,
so you have control of emotions I believe,
you mean you want to have more control of your emotions?
But can you tell me what kind of emotions you have, can you describe your emotions?
-I didn’t mean it’s negative, I meant it’s over whelming.
-But they are positive mostly or it is fear?
-Not fear, it contains a lot of sympathetic.
-You are very sympathetic?
-Yes.
-If somebody is suffering? Like if you observe the cases here, you sometimes cry?
-Most of the time I cry, I read books I cry, I go to films I cry, yes.
-But do you cry especially when you see pain to others?
-Yes.
-Do you sometimes feel the pain yourself? The pain which somebody is describing?
-No.
-You have children?
–Yes.
-How many?
-4.
-If one of your children is sick, you can handle it or you become out of your mind from anxiety
and what is going to happen?
-I’m not frightened when they get sick but I do have special problem with my older son.
With him I can get very, very anxious if he is not well or now if he is going to the army.
When he was 2 years old, I put him on a swing, with his brother a baby and he fell off
it was in the house of my parents and he had a very severe concussion
and he was in coma for 30 hours.
-And you got a big fright.
-I was in a big shock, it was a trauma for me and this period that my mother was very ill
and I was a lot with her and this was in her place when it happened,
my husband was in the army and I was with the two babies in the hospital
and none really said that he will be alive.
-You were living in a kibbutz by that time?
-No, I’m from Jerusalem and my parents used to live in another city.
So this was a fighting situation for me and things became so intensive;
my mother died after a year and I was with her a lot, I was with her in the room when she died
and since then it was very intensive and I didn’t think much of the pain of my son.
When my mother died I had two other children with me, I was 27 and I had 2 babies
and 2 teenagers in my house.
-Too much responsibility?
-And a lot of care and attention to the war, it was very living situation that I had to take care.
So when my son got this letter from the army, I had again these pictures coming back.
-These pictures of what?
-Of his sight in the hospital that he was in total coma.
-You are still affected by this incident. I see you want to cry when you describe it.
-Yes, very much because with him all the years in the beginning I was very sensitive.
He was the first grand child in my family, he got too much care from my family
and he developed an (?) I didn’t know anything about alternative medicine when it happened
and my brother is a doctor and he took too much care of him
and he had a lot of attention in the hospital. He had some incidents and his (?) was taken out
and after my mother’s death he didn’t hear it. When my mother died he didn’t hear anything.
He had total absence of hearing after several hearing infections
and it was very very intensive and when he was 4 years old, we started with homeopathic treatment
and it became a little better but it’s still until now very sensitive.
When he says, he doesn’t feel well I get very anxious.
And I feel that my thoughts or if I feel negative for him, that can affect him.
So I have this struggle inside to meditate and to be positive and to give him confidence
and he feels this very, very strong.
-He feels the connection?
-He feels my fears and that I don’t support him.
In the army he wanted to go to a very dangerous unit and he didn’t get support from me so much,
I was quite neutral.
So it wasn’t good for him, he was now accepted to the Navy, to one of the units that he
is going to be 5 years in the army and I try to be very positive. I don’t like army.
-How is your energy?
-Very good.
-You have a lot of energy?
-Too much sometimes.
-She is sighing.
-Yes but I never sigh.
-You are pressurized now. Is difficult for you to speak about yourself or no?
Or here is difficult?
-I took some rescue remedy actually.
I was (?) with the child, I had fear to speak in front of people.
In my class I could be totally paralyzed or feeling trembling of heart beating
and in high school I had times that it changed just to the opposite.
I was very challenged in that age, I was very energetic and leader,
a kind of an (?) speaking in front of many people and that was my job in the army too.
Performing, not artistic but lecturing.
-What was the subject on which you lectured?
-It was a very small unit that trained the people to go with the soldiers
and explain them about geology, archaeology, botanical sights where they go and see.
So I could join various units of the army and go with them and then in the break times
I explained them or had to give lectures in some of the basis, all over the country
with a lot of seminars, it was very interesting. And I did it very well.
-You did it very well but you were always afraid?
-I was very anxious before. I always prepared it very well and no,
that time I wasn’t so anxious actually. I did it without that. In the University it came again,
this impossible to talk in front of people, a timidity.
It’s one of the reasons I didn’t complete my (?) in the University.
-What did you study in the University?
-History, archaeology and geography. And I didn’t finish my Master Degree
because I had to be in front of many Professors, the big exam and I just felt I couldn’t do that.
-Have you ever taken Lycopodium?
-No.
-Silica?
-Are you constipated at all?
-Not anymore.
-You like to eat something very much? Salt, sweets.
-I have aversion to fats, I can not tolerate that.
-It gives you a pain?
-Not a pain, a sensation of not comfortable.
I will never eat something that was fried.
-Aversion to fat or worse from fat? You can eat it but then you will the pain?
-I’m vegetarian since age 17. Only the last 2 years I eat some chicken from time to time.
I don’t like meat and I don’t like fats.
-You don’t like meat really or because you are vegetarian and you belong to this group?
-It started like this but now I don’t like it.
I liked it before, when I stopped it was an ideological thing but now I wouldn’t like to eat.
I don’t have that theory right now.
-But the desire has gone. Milk you take?
-Milk no. I like cheese or yogurt very much.
-What else you don’t like? How much salt you take?
-Normal, not too much.
-Fish?
-I like fish.
-You take fish and you like it.
-I like it, I don’t have craving.
-Eggs?
-I like eggs.
-Very much?
-More than before.
-What form? Hard boiled, soft boiled, fried?
-Not fried. I don’t like fried. But I can have it boiled or soft.
-Do you feel cold or hot? Your feet are cold?
-I used to be cold person 10 years ago and I became more and more hot.
-Now you are bothered by heat?
-If it’s closed and stuffed I will suffer very much. If it’s hot outside, I don’t bother.
I like to be outside. If the room is closed, it can be horrible.
-You had any serious disease in your life?
-I used to have (?) infections when I was a child, tonsillitis but not too often.
-Ear problem?
-No. I got injections for rabies when I was in the army.
-Why?
-Because I was near the Jordanian border in the night and some dogs were running after me
and bitten me a little bit but that area is known to have rabies.
-When it was that?
-1973. I got 15 injections in my stomach and actually I enjoyed it.
-Are you claustrophobic at all?
-Not at all.
-You swim in the sea or you never swim?
-I don’t like so much to swim in the sea.
-Why?
-In my childhood I’ve almost drowned. Since then I like the sea but not inside.
I swim but I’m not crazy and I don’t like cold water.
Here I was swimming twice when I came here but it was too cold.
-But if you hear running water, a tap, you have the urgency to go for urination?
-No.
-You understand what I ask?
-I understand but I don’t have any symptoms of (?). No, really no.
-How do you know?
-I read the proving and I read a lot about this remedy
because I was concerned from this treatment.
-How old you were?
-I was 19.
-Since that time it has changed anything? You became more open or closed?
-I really didn’t feel bad. That year I was alone in the country,
my parents had (?) year and I had to take the decision myself.
The Israeli doctors didn’t want to do it.
They were not sure about that and I was going to consult with doctors.
It was one week of not knowing what to do. They took a week.
-Before they decide and then you pushed them to make a decision?
-I didn’t know anything about that and they were so scared and no one from my family was there
and I did this consultation and I decided that maybe I will live less
but maybe I will die in one week.
-You didn’t like to die in one week.
-I didn’t like the idea of one week.
-Now? You are afraid of death?
-I had a lot of fear for death, especially for 10 years after my parents died but now it has changed.
-To what? To another fear or to less fear?
-To less fear, I’m not so concerned with this. I’m more afraid for my children.
-Your anxiety is because of your children now. About your husband?
-Not about my husband, not about my 3 children so much as my older one.
-This anxiety is what? You are suffering at this moment mostly or there are fears?
You are afraid of dark, thunderstorms?
-I’m not afraid of dark, to go alone in the forest in the dark I wouldn’t do that
but I’m not afraid of dark.
-Thunderstorms?
-No.
-Your nails are breaking easily? You bite them?
-No I’m not biting them. They are not strong but are not easily breaking.
-Do you have any other fear? Fear of high places, fear of talking to people, fear of dogs?
-No, I’m not afraid of dogs. I do have this fear of talking in front of people.
If it’s a small group or intimate place I’m not fearing but if it’s a big group, yes.
Even in the University when it was a big class, I could be very frightful
or now we went to the USA and I had to give a little talk, I was completely…
-Paralyzed?
-Not paralyzed but I was feeling my heart beating and it’s ridiculous.
-It is ridiculous? You have a good rapport with your husband?
-Very good. I’m staying here now a month and it’s difficult to be away from him.
-Do you talk to him on the telephone?
-Every day.
-That’s nice. About your thirst can you tell me? Thirsty, not thirsty, cold water, hot water?
-I’m not drinking cold, I don’t like to drink cold. I drink mostly warm or room temperature.
If it’s hot, I can drink cold but never icy cold.
My thirst is changing. I was thirst less I didn’t drink. I pushed myself to drink.
Now I’m drinking more but I can also not drink.
-Your sleep is good now?
-Yes.
-You wake up refreshed?
-I wake up easily in the morning, yes.
-And you have a lot of energy? To study it is easy for you or it is difficult?
-My memory is not what it used to be. I don’t remember so well and I have sometimes
that if I’m caught in my thoughts, persistent thoughts, it can drive me out of my studies
and I can be not there. I need to focus more but I like to study. And I work a lot.
-Do you have what they call daydreaming?
-No.
-Do you see dreams and you remember them?
-I remember some of my dreams but I don’t remember much.
-Do you have a theme? Your dreams do they have a theme, like swimming or flying
or somebody is pursuing you or you are falling?
-The dream I really remember but it didn’t come more than that was that I was myself a wolf
and I was caring in my teeth my daughter.
And when I woke up, I still felt I am a wolf. I had to release from this picture.
-It was only one time?
-It didn’t repeat. Maybe twice, but not more than that.
-How old is your daughter?
-10 and a half.
-Your daughter is challenging you?
-She is special character and she is very strong.
-She likes her father more than you?
-She has a lot from my husband. You mean if she looks like my husband?
-It’s a good way to answer.
-She is very connected to my husband.
-Very connected to your husband. They are very close.
-Do you think you are jealous?
-No, I’m really not at all.
-Do you have the feeling of jealousy? Do you know the feeling of jealousy?
-I know the feeling, I know what you mean but it’s not part of me.
I don’t have (?) feeling of jealousy, I can not connect with this. It’s not me, jealousy.
But the dream of my daughter in my mouth had the impression with more of that I had to rescue her.
That was the impression of the dream. It was very dangerous.
-What was the danger? Do you remember?
-There was a river and we walked and I had that feeling of rescuing my children.
I don’t know what happened to the others but I could rescue her.
The others were not in the dream. That was 2 years ago. I don’t have many dreams.
Maybe it was after taking the remedy, the last remedy.
Because after I take remedies, I have dreams.
I remember them all.
-There is itching in your eruption?
-No, it’s not itching. When I said that I didn’t react to the remedies, I also meant
that I did not have fever.
Always after my body went through physical effort, then it’s when I developed fevers.
So I had one after delivery and another after the other delivery and the last one after my operation.
I had a high fever for 3 days.
-When it was the operation?
-1993.
-And after the operation you felt good for insomnia.
-I felt very good.
-How do you explain this?
-We were in England, it was a very interesting year and I had a lot.
It wasn’t easy to come with 4 kids to a new place and I was very busy and with many guests
and then out of a sudden I could rest for one week at the hospital, in a nice room, read a lot
and not with other people.
It was an interesting experience and I had deep rest after a very intensive month.
-You mean you had a rest in the hospital?
-In the hospital and then afterwards, I was very spoiled I couldn’t move for weeks from bed.
-So you recovered. You were exhausting yourself before?
-Yes and I got a lot of affection from people.
-You like attention?
-I do like attention.
-Your husband is jealous of you? He has fears that sometimes I will abandon him.
-He tells you these fears?
-Yes.
-But you don’t have fears that he may leave you.
-No.
-In this religious group, you belong since childhood or it was a decision later on?
-It’s from home.
My grand parents were very religious and my parents became more independent in this way,
my father was philosopher and he was academic and they were challenging this,
they were asking a lot of question, especially after the war and his writing is about that.
So I came from a very open house whilst my parents and other parts of the family
are deeply religious. I remember myself since age 14 looking for spiritual growth and learning,
it was not connected to my parents. They didn’t like it.
-So in your religion for instance you are allowed to have a boyfriend before you marry?
-From the group I come from, today is changing. Everything became more extreme
but we belong to group which is allowed. Yes I had a boyfriend.
-You had before your marriage?
-Yes.
-Are you hurt by any of them?
-I did not have sexual intercourse.
-That was forbidden.
-Yes but I was with boys and we were together.
-But sexually you were aroused or no sexual place?
-Yes I had this desire but the (?)
-Were you hurt by any of these?
-Yes very much. My first boyfriend left me.
-Because he made another affair with a friend of yours?
-Not a friend of mine but there was 1973 war and the was in the army then
and they were many miles away from us and he knew another girl in that base.
He was in the country for 7 months and then he knew another girl and I was hurt.
-What did you do? How you reacted? Did you close yourself in a room and cried,
you did not cry, you decided to say?
-I cried, I wrote a lot of poems.
-Did you write letters to him?
-No.
-You were too proud?
First it was not any connection, he was away in Egypt for many months
and actually I didn’t hear from him. The letter from him I got afterwards.
I was proud of course, I didn’t have any communication with him afterwards.
-He wrote a letter saying that I have met another girl and that’s it.
-Yes.
-Then you took the letter and you did not cried?
-I cried a lot. That’s what I said. I didn’t close myself. I could talk about this.
-With your friends or your mother?
-Yes, I could talk with her a little bit, they were not in the States. It was many years ago.
-You don’t remember.
-I think I wasn’t so introverted. I had many friends.
-Another boyfriend hurt you?
-No I didn’t have that.
I had contacts with boys but I wasn’t hurt, maybe I hurt somebody.
I knew my husband in the University, we come back to my emotional states,
we fell in love and after one week we decided to get married. So it was very impulsive.
-That’s why you call yourself impulsive?
-In a way. I can make decisions very easily.
-You have no problem making decisions?
-No.
-You have problem looking from a high place, down?
-I can have problem looking from a high place, down.
-What problems? Vertigo or fear?
-No vertigo, uneasiness.
If I’m too close, not from high building but if it’s a cliff,
especially this situation is mostly with my children and I can get very agitated
if my child is there.
Then that is the worse thing and it’s happened to me.
-Did you ever use marihuana?
-No, never.
-It was not allowed in your religion? Nobody would know.
-I was offered several times when I was in a mission in America,
when I was 16 people wanted to give it to me. It never attracted me.
I was very strong in my opinions and my values.
Also in the army there were many situations that were very difficult for a woman many times.
-And you resisted everything?
-Oh yes.
-Army was before marriage?
-Exactly.
-Have you ever been in a condition where you have become very angry?
-Yes. In the past I was very angry and very nervous.
When I was a child 12,14 I could explode easily and even later and recently.
-Now you look very controlled.
-I’m not so. I don’t think I’m getting so angry now.
-If you do get angry, do you get very angry?
Do you remember sometimes when you got angry?
-You mean in the past?
-In the past and now.
-In the past I could be very angry and with my brothers and sisters we could fight.
-Yes but could you give me an example what was your biggest reaction when you were angry?
-It was most of the times more excitement during speech.
-Not throwing things?
-No. Maybe, when I was a child but not so much.
-How much salt you take?
-Not too much, the usual.
-Sweets?
-I like but not too much.
I can have a cake but not chocolate.
-Do you support injustice? If some injustice is happening to you or to others,
is big deal for you?
-It can be a big deal.
-What you will do? You will interfere?
-When I was younger I could interfere. Not long ago we had in our country “Intifada”.
So I found myself going many times trying to release Palestinians
and going to the villages trying to convince the police to do things for them.
-Politically you were active pacifist?
-Not in a political way.
On a human instinct if I knew somebody I could fight for him.
Now I’m not political. My brother is but not me. My main effort is in my clinic.
Individual.
-You like contact with patients?
-Yes, very much.
-You get some joy from this contact?
-Yes, very strong.
-I still don’t understand the problem.
Why you want to be treated. You seem quite balanced healthy;
the only thing is you seem to be that you take long time to answer a question.
Why you do that? Because you think a lot before you can answer it correctly
or because you don’t understand my question?
-I do understand the question; I need to answer more profound.
-You need to think. So you are not impulsive. In your behavior here,
it is the opposite of impulsive.
-Yes.
-Why you said you are impulsive.
-I meant more emotional, not impulsive.
You see me here after a month of being in vacation in Greece.
If you would take my case a month ago, maybe things would be a bit different.
-Or a lot different?
-I can be very stressed and very tensed. I work very hard and I take too much care of my patients
and my children.
I felt a need for a remedy very much in July before I went to America for half a year
because I felt really inconfidence and this want of self-confidence was very, very strong then.
Since I came back to Israel my fear for my son got very, very, strong.
-Now you are here do you feel homesick?
-It was very, very strong two weeks ago and this week I was crying a lot and I wanted to go back.
It was too difficult to be away from my family for such a long period.
-You are here alone or with your husband?
-Not with my husband. He is with my children. It was very difficult and I cried a lot this week
and I thought I will short this seminar and go back.
-But did you really feel homesick? Do you understand the word homesick?
-I understand and I don’t have this.
-You just miss your family.
-I miss my family very much.
-The affection?
-Yes.
-If you were to describe yourself what would you say? How you would describe yourself?
-It’s the most difficult thing. I’m very romantic, very idealistic and with a lot of emotions
and a lot of care.
-A lot of love. You feel that you have a lot of love that you can give others?
-I do and sometimes it is overflowing.
-But this reaction from Phosphorus which you took, it was a good reaction.
Because the eruption is good when it comes out.
-I had a good reaction and I repeated the remedy.
I was suffering a lot from yeast infection, itching in my vagina for long period
and I repeated the remedy and it helped that very much.
I also took the remedy because I was very diffusive and everything was interesting from me.
I did a lot and studied there and here and after Phosphorus I was much more focused
and I could start my studies in Homeopathy.
Before, I did many, many things.
-But did you repeated Phosphorus?
-Yes in 1994 I took again 1M.
-And what happened? Again you felt good?
-That period I worked in a hospital and I think without taking the Phosphorus I wouldn’t be able,
I had so many fears then for health. The Phosphorus really helped me in focusing
and being able to work with people with cancer.
But afterwards I stopped to work with people with cancer and I decided to keep distance.
-The fear of cancer was very strong?
-Very, very strong. After taking last time Carcinosin, it eased.
I had also fibrocystic breast and I had a cyst in my left breast.
I only went to a surgeon from time to time to check it and after taking the Carcinosin it diminished.
-What kind of eruption is this?
-It’s all over my back.
-It’s like a fungus.
-Yes.
-Did you try again Phosphorus lately?
-No.
-This anxiety about your son started immediately after seeing his papers to go to the army?
–Yes.
-And then you started think that something may happen or I have to think positive
otherwise I will influence him?
-Exactly.
-And then it has become a big thing for you this anxiety.
It has become really overwhelming.
-Yes and he had some problems this year.
He felt for a long time weakness and pains in his bones and he was very agitated from this
and he was very scared.
So I felt a lot his anxiety. But the Phosphorus did not bring me any other aggravation.
-If it brings out an eruption is good enough aggravation.
-Maybe I was affected that my homeopath said, you are not Phosphorus.
When I went back to my homeopath in Israel she prescribed me Carcinosin and not Phosphorus.
-But it doesn’t matter what anybody says, it matters what you say and how you feel.
If you feel good with Phosphorus, that means Phosphorus should be repeated.
And then if it does not act, then we’ll see what else can be done
but if Phosphorus has acted so well and now the anxiety about your child is overwhelming,
then most probably you have to repeat Phosphorus.
Pulsatilla is a possibility of course.
-That’s what it came out from my repertorization. But I prefer to…
-To hear my opinion? My opinion is you take first Phosphorus
and if it does not act then you take Pulsatilla.
OK?
-OK.