You took a remedy 1 year ago.
-No in May.
-You took a remedy in May. What was the remedy?
-Ignatia 50M.
-OK, how are you doing?
-Now I’m well but I wasn’t...
After coming home I was very bad but it started the day I got the remedy
I felt a kind of waving feeling in my head. That was the same day or evening.
On Wednesday I had a profused perspiration, especially on my forehead,
on my palms and on my feet.
I was crying a lot in the evening.
-For no reason? You just remembered something?
-No, it just came on, I felt a bit sad. So I went earlier, we were out eating
and I went earlier back and by myself crying. I started to feel very tired.
-The same day?
-No, the day after the remedy.
The next day there were two small blisters on the left side of my upper lip,
there was pressure in both eyes and some pressure in the side of my head.
In the occiput, in the back side.
I didn’t notice it myself but the others said that I was drinking more water
than what I usually do. On Friday I was very hungry.
I ate a lot more than I usually do, I drink much water that day too,
my eyes get more severe (?) I had to close them during the lecture
because it was so (?) to hold them open.
-Like photophobia?
-More like a (?) as something was lying on …
-Something was lying on the conjunctiva.
-During the lecture I kept them closed. My menses started on Monday and that came on earlier.
-How much earlier? A few days?
-No, actually 2 and a half week I think.
Because I had it before I came down here.
But it stopped earlier than it used to do, so it was very profused those days,
it went on but it stopped earlier.
This was the most acute…
-Aggravation.
-Yes, I also had some restlessness in my back and legs
when I went on flying home I nearly sit still. My feet I had to move them all the time,
I had to go from the seat and the legs felt a bit heavy while going upstairs, as very tired.
That went on. I got some kind of numbness in my legs and tightness.
But that was the day after I came back home.
I still had a hot burning feeling in my hands and feet that lasted all that day.
Burning feeling in hands and feet but not so much profused sweating, as I had earlier.
The pain in my hips was bad when I sat down, the pain in my right knee was also worse
and I was still very restless. I was tired so I slept a lot.
Actually I slept all the day the second day after coming home.
-The day and the night.
-Yes.
The same evening when I got home, at half past seven I started with dizziness.
And the same kind of restlessness but I also start feeling a kind of fright.
I can’t exactly say there was something frightening me but I felt a kind of fright.
The day after (?) because then my stomach started.
It started stinking like ice in my stomach and every time I drunk cold water or eat something,
it was very severe. So I try not to eat so much.
-How many days after the remedy? 10 days after?
-7-8 days I think. On Sunday I woke up with a rumbling feeling in my stomach very much
that I’m not used to, still the sore feeling, like it was a sore.
-A wound.
-And the stitching like knife was still going. It was like stitches.
I got also some feeling of pain in Achilles tendons.
In afternoon I had very hard pressure on my head, still the pain on the occiput
and some pressure in the sides.
On the lower back, between the right shoulder and that has actually continued until now.
That kind of symptom. Otherwise the other symptoms are gone.
After a while I felt more calm and I’m still more calm but when I was going in here
I felt the same nervousness.
-Butterflies in the stomach.
-Yes butterflies in the stomach but I also slept more than usual.
Before the remedy I could wake up at 5, 6 o’ clock in the morning
and this summer I slept on Sundays when I’m free, I was not going to work,
I slept until 9, 10 o’clock and that I’ve never done it in my whole life.
So I sleep a lot more. Also I had a little period of going inside myself, I didn’t want to socialize
with others but that was for 14 days and when it went off, I felt good again.
-Did you cry at all after the first day?
-Yes. I’ve been more sensitive.
-More easily tears.
-Actually all my life I’ve been moved by seeing a (?) or something, my tears come easily
but crying in other situation has not been easy for me, but now it is.
Even when a patient does not have good results, I feel that the tears are coming up.
More easily to move.
-Tell me, you finished?
-In July I began to feel a little bit more nervous again. My stomach started a little bit
but not much, my eyes began to feel tired again but it stopped and right before I went down there
I also had these tired eyes a little bit.
-Did you drink coffee at all?
-I took some coffee in July?
-How many times?
-Actually I take half a cup of coffee in the morning.
-Every day?
-Yes.
-Ahh…
-When all the symptoms went away I thought maybe it’s …
-It’s time to start.
-That it wouldn’t touch.
-It wouldn’t affect you.
You must not drink coffee, if you want to stay well, for 3 years. It’s a bit difficult.
But remind me what was the main problem when you came here to be treated?
-I said it was a situation between my husband and me. I had a bad conscience
because I’ve been unfaithful.
-And you were upset emotionally a lot.
-Yes very much.
-That was the main problem, the emotional upset at the moment.
-I felt very sad and guilty.
-But the stitches in the stomach, you had before?
-Not so severe. I felt the sorness but not the stitching never.
-Never?
-No that I can remember.
-Other symptoms that you had there original?
-The eyes I have had before, the restlessness in the legs also. I forgot something, I got ticks.
-Twitchings.
-Yes and it was going all the time when the other symptoms went on for 14 days, I think.
-But how do you feel in general?
-I feel better.
-How much better? What would you say? Let me ask you before you answer.
You started drinking coffee when? In the middle of July or in the end of July?
-In the middle I think because I went to a course in Sweden and there I took some coffee.
-What was your best period between May and now? Psychologically?
-When the most severe physical problems went better.
-Subside, then you felt better. That means by the end of May?
-Yes. End of May, begin of June.
-And it was a good period psychologically also but after drinking coffee you don’t find
that some of the symptoms are coming back now?
-Really I can’t tell if it’s because of coffee.
-No, no I don’t say because of the coffee.
I say, do you find some of your symptoms coming back the last month in September?
-I got a cold and then they started again.
-The eyes started being heavy?
–Yes.
-I see you are sighing, it’s because you are here or you do it also outside?
-I don’t notice it myself. You told me the last time that I was sighing a lot.
-You don’t notice. Did you notice it here?
-No.
-Because you had some anxiety. Now you are more calm but in the beginning
when you started telling your case, you felt anxious and you were doing like this.
-I do that sometimes but I don’t notice it so much.
-You also have said that you had apathy, without any joy. Now it has come back?
You enjoy life?
-Yes I feel more calm and relaxed. I can talk easier with other people.
I think it made me more cheerful.
-Do you eat fruits? You like fruits?
-I seldom eat it.
Once every 14 days, bananas I eat but other fruits not so much.
But I actually I’ve been drinking fruit juices and that something I never drink either.
-What position do you sleep? You sleep on your back or now you change?
-I sleep on my back but I noticed I can wake up on the sides that I have not done for long time.
I actually had some pain in my back, when I was younger,
and my chiropractor told me to lie on my back. But before that I laid on my stomach always.
-And now you turn back to your stomach?
-Also you said you did not like sweets? Still you don’t like or you start liking more sweets?
-I didn’t eat yogurt with honey the last time I was here but now I’m eating it.
I don’t know if that’s a sign.
-Also you have said that you desire always warm food.
-Yes more than cold.
-The water must be cold or room temperature?
-Earlier the water had to be room temperature but now I can take from the refrigerator and drink it.
-Also you had pains during menses in the abdomen? Now how is the menstrual period?
-I haven ‘t notice anything. It has been good but lately I’ve noticed some stitching in both sides.
-Ovaries?
– I think so.
-Also you mentioned that you became irritable before menses. How is that now?
-I’m not being irritable before menses but it was a period when I was irritable.
-When was this period?
-It was in the period when I was not so social. Then I also reacted more aggressive.
-In May?
-No, it was in July.
-End of July?
–No, in the beginning before I went to Sweden.
-What about fear of insects you have? It’s still there?
-Yes but not so. There was a wasp sitting on my feet and I let it sit there.
-It was sitting there, oh my god. How is your desire for salt?
Is it continuing or is the same as before? You put more salt now in your food?
-No I don’t put more salt in my food but I don’t recall it.
Usually when I’m out eating I think always it is too salty but it has not been noticed lately.
So I tolerate more salt, I’m also eating in the evening which I never did.
When I eat in the evening, I eat salt, a kind of meat which are salted.
And I eat more meat than what I did last time.
-Desire for meat is there?
-More. Because I used to eat more fish.
-She has not mentioned aversion fruit I see. The fruits, you don’t remember yourself eating fruits
or years before you used to eat fruits?
-Yes when I was training a lot I ate. I took with me fruits for the competition,
because it was easy and light to eat.
-Do you remember when you stopped eating fruits? Where you were not taking fruits anymore?
What do you say? About.
-I really can’t remember but I have a feeling that there is a period
which I can’t remember very much and that’s the period when my parents divorced.
-What age you were?
-I was 15 years.
-And that period, between 15 and 20 you can not remember?
-It started some of the things from my childhood went away within that period.
I married very early, I was 17 years old and I got a child before that,
so it was a period with many problems.
-And with the first marriage you divorced or you stayed?
-No, I stayed.
-Until the time of all this happened with your marriage?
-Yes, I’ve been married for 28 years.
-You are still with the same man now?
-Yes.
–How is your relation with him?
-Our sexual relationship is not so good but we have a good relationship on other levels.
I think he is the nicest person I even met but he is the kind of man who,
I think, he is doing everything right.
Therefore I also feel a little bit guilty because I do something bad sometimes.
-Do you have any desire with the meat to have fat?
-I had, my father was a butcher and he made many fat things when I was a child.
I really liked to eat the fat but lately no. I actually pick out the fat.
-How you tolerate the sun, especially here?
-Actually I thought if the sun is making something with my eyes
because I don’t have this in the winter time. And when I went down here, it started again,
so maybe it is because of the lighting.
But I was staying out in the ocean, by the sea every summer and it has not affected me that much.
I like the sun really but when it’s getting too hot I stay in the shadow.
And that I’ve done this summer because you had a very warm summer in Norway.
I worked a lot, so I didn’t have vacation, so I didn’t want to go to the sun.
I was sitting in the shadow.
-How many children do you have?
-I have two children.
-What is your relationship with your children?
Is one daughter and one boy?
– Yes.
-With your daughter what is your relationship?
-I think it’s good now. There was a hard period when she was 6 years old
because I went to a school in another town and I lived there in the week
and I came home in the weekends and she changed a lot in that period so I had to work hard
to get a good relationship with her.
-How old is she now?
–She is 22.
-Is she married?
–No.
-You talk to her openly?
–Yes she always come to me.
-With your son?
-Yes, we are also talking a lot.
He doesn’t have to say opinion about the things that I do so we argue a little bit
but we talk a lot. But he is not so easy to talk about his feelings so I have to ask sometimes.
-How is the perspiration? Do you perspire?
-Not much. When I’m training I perspire a lot.
-Where is the first area?
-Face but when I ‘m a little bit stressed like now, I perspire under the arms.
But I never use anything. I didn’t tell you so much about myself the first time I was here
because I didn’t feel like doing it but if it is concerning the case…
-Yes I would like to hear if you like to say.
-I didn’t have a good childhood. My mother was very harsh woman and I was beaten a lot.
-Beaten?
–Yes.
When I was 11 years old, she beat me so much that I couldn’t stand on my own feet.
On that day I told her I will never go to cry again and she beat me
because she want me to feel sorrow but I haven’t done anything wrong. She just went on.
-She beat you with the hand?
-No, with a stick.
Then for two days I couldn’t go to school, it was bruises but that was the last time …
-She beat you?
– Yes.
Ever since I was a little child, maybe I was very …
-Naughty?
– Yes, so she couldn’t tell me but she beat me a lot.
-Your mother is still alive now?
–Yes.
-And she lives with your father?
-No, my father died in 1985 but he worked so much and he was not so much at home
and my mother was very nervous. I think she was very afraid not having a good…
what you call when you don’t manage things?
-Financially she may not be able to manage?
-No. She was nervous not to be perfect in a way.
-She was a perfectionist. She was nervous that not everything will be perfect.
-I was training a lot and she wanted me to perform when we went to some parties
and I didn’t like it but that was the only time she ever showed that I had some value.
-And she regretted, she showed some regret later on?
-No, when I was 17 she told me that she had never loved me, she had loved the two other sisters.
But I thought I was over it…
-You thought you were over it but now it’s coming. It was kept inside all these years, sure.
Your father had shown a particular liking for you, you think?
-He was seldom at home.
-But when he was at home, he would show a preference for you
or he would show more affection to you, so your mother got jealous perhaps?
-Yes, he had a hard temper; so actually he was very harsh but I knew when I had him
because he wasn’t unfair. My mother was unfair in many ways.
I got beaten for things I didn’t do.
-You were accused for things and that’s why you run away with boys at what age, 14?
-My first companionship if I can say, was when I was 12 years and we kept together
until I was 14 but we didn’t have any sexual thing and I had two guys after that
and then my husband.
-When did you first had sexual contact? What age?
-I was 15, right after my parents were divorced.
-Immediately after they were divorced. Did you do it out of despair or…?
-I did it to hurt her because my mother was very moralistic.
That’s the way I’ve seen it afterwards. I knew I hurt her when I did it.
-And you told her or she knew. She didn’t know it until I got pregnant with my husband.
I didn’t tell her.
-You got pregnant immediately.
-Yes I was 16 years old.
-And then she supported you during this difficult time?
-Nobody supported me during that time. Everyone wanted me to take it away.
The doctor, the parents…
-Your father?
-My father said, you have to do what you have to do.
He wanted to support me if I wanted to keep it and he did.
-So you kept it and then you married the man?
-Yes, I married one year later.
-You like dancing?
-Yes.
-Very much. Did you take lessons in dancing, I believe.
-When I was training in gymnastics we had lectures on dancing because the floor exercise,
we had some ballet and some (?)
So when I stopped this training I went to jazz ballet school but I actually never dance so much
but when we are in a party. I haven’t’ dance since we were here last year, so it’s not so often.
-I see. Everybody remembers you danced very much here.
-Maybe that’s because you said it so they looked.
-All right. You like music?
-Yes but that’s something in a way I have turned off. In the mornings I like to have quiet.
My husband turns on the radio, I like the music when it’s on but I never put it on myself.
-And you don’t like it loud?
-When my children play it loud in the car, I tell them to turn it down
but in a period I had the music loud.
-OK. Thank you. You want to say something else perhaps?
-No.
-Is something that you feel you did not say and you want to say?
-OK, next time.
There is a general problem I will tell you. And you will see it eventually.
If in a good prescription you drink coffee, there is a big problem and the problem is that.
After a good prescription, not every symptom comes back and therefore the problem is
when to repeat the remedy.
Is it time when she has good enough relapse and it will be easy if, OK I start to have a relapse,
you repeat the remedy and many times will not work.
And this is a big problem because a good case can be spoiled in this way.
We have to make judgment now whether in her case we have a relapse
or we have the development of a new situation, a new remedy or what do we have to do?
We repeat, we go higher, we give another remedy?
She has symptoms, she has sighing, we saw strong sighing again.
This is one of the symptoms, you remember, on which we prescribed Ignatia
and you can say still it’s there or maybe it’s there.
Maybe it was because of the anxiety of being in front of the class. So there is a symptom.
Another symptom which impressed me was that she still does not want fruits.
She used to take fruits or eat fruits a lot actually because she used to take with her.
Now she does not want to eat fruits yet. Again an Ignatia symptom.
-But she said that she drunk juices from fruits.
-She does not like fruit juices.
-Yes she does.
-No, she never drank before.
-She drinks juices OK.
-Is she going into a relapse yes or no? She starts having some symptoms,
she is starting a relapse, that is what she is saying.
When is going to end that relapse we don’t know and that is the problem at this moment.
She is starting a relapse, we don’t know she is continuing to have a relapse
or she is going to stay like this or even just become better? This is the question.
Is this a relapse? Are we going to repeat? We don’t have enough symptoms.
Maybe she is going back to relapse but it’s not clear. There is another remedy?
Maybe but it’s not clear.
At this stage what is your advice to the patient which you wrote it already
so you can not tell me lies.
-Stop to drink coffee.
-Stop drinking coffee exactly.
The advice to the patient at this moment, must be stop drinking coffee
and she may find without any other help that the organism comes back to normal.
If she stops drinking coffee, the organism may just go back to normal.
If the coffee has just already done a damage, she will continue and if she continues
and she is sighing in this way she does and she does not eat fruits,
never mind the pathology she has to repeat Ignatia.
But the advice here is stop drinking coffee and see what happens.
And most probably in about 2 weeks, she will recover again. She will feel good again.
-What I think it’s really great in this case is that she is doing much better
because now she has a possibility and she has the power to tell us her feelings
while before she couldn’t do it and I think this is coming up.
I think we must really wait, don’t disturb this evolution of the case with the giving again Ignatia
or C12 and so on. It’s very well.
-Correct.
All this grief which has been kept inside all these years, all this grief has to come out
and it was a very good thing that she did that. Because that will release quite a lot.
It will take a load from the organism so the organism by stop drinking coffee
may just go back to full recovery with full enjoyment.
With a possibility that she will go to Natrum Muriaticum but not at this moment.
-I have a completely different question. It concerns coffee. What in coffee is that disturbs?
Is it the caffeine and what about coca-cola and peppermint and chewing gum and so on?
-The problem is the caffeine. The problem also is the level of caffeine in the body.
Every one of us has the tolerance of certain level of caffeine in the blood.
Some of us will get excited with a little bit of caffeine. Some they need a bigger amount.
And some they drink caffeine and they go to sleep and it’s different
but most of the cases cause an excitement of the nervous system.
The circulation is stimulated and then the nervous system is also excited.
That is very bad for the organism, if you do it every day.
With tea which has caffeine, with coca-cola which has caffeine, we don’t raise the level of caffeine.
It seems that through the coffee, just because the coffee is burnt.
I don’t’ know what is in the coffee.
The caffeine is taken immediately in the organism and has an affect
and that affect we don’t like in Homeopathy.
If somebody tells you I drink coffee and I feel nothing, most probably in such a case
there is not going to be a relapse.
Most probably such an organism will tolerate the coffee without having …
The excitement of the coffee is the bad thing.
Anything which excites the system like the drugs, whatever they might be, Tavor, Valium
and all the psychotropic drugs that affect the nervous system, forget it.
-Two questions. The first, the caffeine is the antidote agent, would you advise patients
who seem to have a low tolerance to caffeine to stop drinking coca-cola
and also products that include caffeine such as chocolate?
-If there is somebody who is sensitive to coffee and he tells if I touch coffee I get very excited
of course out, no question.
But in my experience I have seen invariably caffeine will bring a relapse
almost in 98% of the cases.
A big or a small relapse but a relapse.
So therefore coffee is out.
At this moment we must not interfere, we should let the process develop by itself.
You are not going to help the organism to do more. She did quite a lot,
even under the fact that she was in a state of a relapse. You saw the Ignatia state.
Already I was vacillating for a moment but when she gave out the information
that showed a release on the emotional level and so she can unload now, she can discuss.
That’s a process, you live it alone. She may have a consultation, if you are in a private practice.
You say OK I will see you again in 15 days, she will talk more, she will go more into details;
maybe she wanted today to speak a little more about these details
but as here is a teaching situation and not a very private consultation,
we can not go into details which are not useful.
What we understand? She is doing fine with the possibility of relapse.
You cut down the coffee and you let it develop.
-A question to the tea. You said tea is better?
-Tea is better because tea does not raise the caffeine level in the blood.
It’s not absorbed easily. I don’t know what happens.
-But some people say they can’t touch the tea. They get more excited than coffee.
-Some people yes. If they do say, immediately you stop it.
If they do say, with a cup of tea I have palpitations of course.
That means they are sensitive.
-Mint?
-Mint you have to avoid especially in cases of Natrum Muriaticum.
Natrum Muriaticum cases absolutely, no mint.
-Decaffeinated coffee?
-Yes but it is a bad stuff by itself. It will spoil your stomach.
-Will it antidote the remedy?
-No, it will not antidote.
-I have read about strong smelling substances that they do harm to the prescription.
What about this?
-Yes.
Hahnemann himself mentioned camphor, very strong smelling. Camphor seems to antidote
but I don’t have the experience because we don’t use camphor today.
We don’t use much camphor but everyone uses coffee.
If everyone was using camphor as a drink most probably we would know the real effect of camphor.
But now today we don’t use much camphor and of course it’s good to avoid.
And if you have a perfume with camphor, it’s better to change the perfume.
-I frequently had the experience that patients who are running on a homeopathic remedy
go to see their dentist and get some injections and that antidotes the remedy too.
-From dentists, there is no question about that.
There are certain organisms which are sensitive to certain substances.
Now these substances, if they are really sensitive, almost allergic,
even a mere contact with such substance can upset the organism.
Otherwise, especially coffee, you need to drink several coffees before you have a relapse.
Many times I say that theoretically, now you can see it very clearly
because both cases they did the sin of drinking coffee.
-The last time, as we said, you were doing better, you started drinking coffee
and then there was a kind of relapse and then we discussed your case,
we saw Natrum Muriaticum also coming up, in the analysis.
But we didn’t give any remedy, we waited, you stopped the coffee
and now you are going to tell us what happened.
-At first I got aphea in my mouth and my menses come out after 14 days.
I was irritable two days before the menses, I got herpetic blister on my left lip.
-Which you had before?
-I had it before yes.
-How long if you remember?
-I think it was in 1992 and I had it once or twice afterwards
but the year 1992 I had it several times.
-And you treated that?
-No, never.
And it was itching pain in the vagina, it was electric like pain, itching.
Emotionally I felt very vulnerable and sensitive to the surroundings.
I was more secure in a way but all the things got inside me.
In October I went to see a medical doctor because the finger was not good,
which I injured in Alonissos.
-I work with foot reflex therapy and I couldn’t use it, so I had to go to a doctor
to get half of my job. Because then I could use Homeopathy instead for the other half.
He wanted me to take a sample because he thought it was pus in the finger and he took a
needle and he wanted me to take the sample and I got convulsions and fainted for a long time.
-Fainted, because of pain?
-No actually I didn’t feel any pain.
-The moment that he prick you?
-No, no he was having this inside for a time taking out something and then I got convulsions.
He told me afterwards that it was very severe and he asked me if I had before
and I told him no and I fainted again.
-You fainted while you were talking to him?
-Yes, when I got up again he asked if I had these convulsions before.
I told him no and I fainted again.
-You fainted with convulsions or without convulsions?
-Not the second time. The first time I fainted with convulsions.
-How do you describe the convulsions? Can you show me?
-I can’t tell but he told I was cramping all over, shaking before I fainted
and I had to lay in his office for half an hour until I could stand on my feet
and I was ice-cold all over and shaking and dizzy and this went on for two days afterwards.
So I couldn’t go to the job.
-Why do you think this happened? What was the feeling inside you?
The feeling that something was coming out of your body or that something was drawn out?
-I felt that I was going to vomit in a way. I only fainted once
and it was not like the way I fainted. I had to get some food inside which I couldn’t take.
I was (?) and I went to the toilet and I vomit and I had stool and passed out . And I was all the time fainting.
After this I didn’t feel very good. So I faxed here in Alonissos but I couldn’t get an answer.
-You didn’t get an answer?
-So it went over and…
-When you write you always have to write several things
because it is very difficult for me to remember.
-Yes I think I wrote.
-I am the case of Ignatia from Norway where I took this…
-Yes I remember next time.
-Because me and my secretary we are struggling to see who is this patient.
-Why I wrote was because he wanted to give me cortisone and I didn’t take it
but in Norway we have to do what the doctor tells us.
Otherwise we don’t get any money from being away from job
but I decided not to do it and he was good, so he gave me the money.
-Did you tell him why you decide not to take cortisone?
-Yes. He saw that I was practicing nature medicine and in a way he accepted but he said
if you are going over 3 months, you have to do it.
-Over 3 months?
-Yes, if I was going half paid from the government, I would have to …
-Afterwards I had some problems with my sleep. It was difficult to go into sleep.
I was restless. I felt as if I have some hair when you wash your head,
you get some loose hair in the face and especially around my nose.
-Feeling of hair in the face. It was the first time you had that sensation?
-No, I had that sensation when I was stressed in a way.
But this was going on for nearly 14 days.
-And then it passed away.
-Yes it passed away and then at the same time I started to sweat a lot.
I also had that before but not for long time but this was for 14 days, totally wet
all over the body and I had to put my feet out of the cover,
even if it was in the winter time and I had the window open.
Afterwards when this stopped I was generally more cold and also I was more vulnerable
and sensitive in general and all the time.
-That means …
-The emotions were more moving. I think it’s good but in a way it’s a new thing.
-It’s a pain. Nice to have emotions but all those emotions come with pain. I know.
-I also moved to a new house. I worked a lot in the same period,
so it could have something to do with this stressing, the difficulty to sleep.
In January my daughter and grand daughter moved into our flat.
Then I started to get a bit irritable. She is not the girl who is doing a lot of things
and I worked a lot and I came home and she didn’t do anything…
-And you exploded.
-Yes and I had to tell her.
It’s a long time since I’ve done that but in younger age I always exploded.
-With the emotions now more strong you can not hold back.
-No, I cant’. Then I got a period where I was kind of lazy.
I didn’t want to do my homework and I felt I did not so good, I felt I was a bad student.
-Lazy woman?
-Really lazy.
I said myself that I was doing too many things at the same time
when I started to do something, I started with one thing and then another thing
and then another thing and I couldn’t concentrate on one thing at one time.
So I never got finished with anything because they were so many things going on at the same time.
I actually saw that I’m working better under stress because then I had to sit
and do this one thing. So when I’m stressed I feel that I work better.
-Under stress you feel you work better?
-Yes when I have one week limit to do something, I can work, work, work
and I get exhausted afterwards.
-But if you get one month you are lazy 3 weeks and you work only the last week.
-Yes if I know I was having a lecture for some doctors and the government in Norway
are making some rules for nature medicine and I knew that I was going to have it
but I didn’t do anything until the week before.
I have been very sensitive to tobacco smoke even though I smoke a lot myself
I can’t bear it inside, so I have to go out smoking.
-That’s great news.
-Even here in Alonissos I can’t smoke in the room; I have to go out in the terrace.
-Very interesting.
-In February-March I started with a flu and I got noise in my left ear, a clutching.
I actually got it here when I come to Alonissos too but not so strong.
-The first time did you get any medication the first time?
-I’m not taking any medications, never.
-Since you took the Ignatia? No medications. And the potency was 50M?
-Yes. I got pain the right ear, itching pain after this clutching went off I was very tired
I got a burning aphea in my mouth, I had a pain in the tooth flesh.
-In the gums?
-Yes and I got the herpes in the upper lip and that was the first time because
when I got it I had it on the upper lip. My tongue was burning
and I got small pimples on my face like when I got menses when I was younger.
-Acne?
-Yes.
-It’s about time.
-Yes and the flu started with a pain from the neck going up into the front of the head.
But I had since that time…
-And you still have?
-Yes when we are coming to the evening session here in Alonissos,
I start to have this kind of headache. Starting from the middle of the spine, thorax…
-Extending up to the head all around to the forehead?
-Yes, most of the pain is sitting here and in the front.
I also get it when I’m stressed, when I work much.
After this time I had very low energy, after this flu I was very tired
for nearly 14 days afterwards.
It went away and 14 days afterwards I got a new flu but it started with pain from hip to hip.
I was very restless in my foot, I couldn’t sit still for a long time.
It was like the pain I had when I got the first session.
When I got it in the flight I couldn’t sit in the seat.
When I was lying down in my bed the sickness and stitching got worse, from hip to hip.
-On hip joints stiffness worse.
-And I was very tired in my feet like heavy. That was what I had.
-What is the situation now? How would you describe it?
-Before I get here I was very bloated in my stomach, the stool was loose
and I had to go to the toilet twice in the morning and it was like flash, two times.
I have more wanting for cold water, I drink a lot.
-Now do you have this now? This diarrhea in the morning, not exactly diarrhea.
-It is not formed.
-But comes as an explosion.
-Yes.
-What time is that you wake up?
-That part has changed a lot because I woke up at 5 o’clock but now I wake 6.30
and I can lay in the bed without standing up, I couldn’t do that before.
-You couldn’t do that?
-No.
If I woke up at 4 , 4.30 I stood up from the bed at once but now I can lay and sleep.
I never thought I can do that
because my husband can lay until 11 o’clock in the Sunday morning, I can’t.
-Now you can?
-Now I can but not so long.
I started to urinate a large amount and very often and I feel that I can’t empty my bladder.
Sometimes I finished and I’m going away and there is coming more.
And I also feel a warm feeling in urethra. It’s a warm feeling.
I have constant sore throat not a pain but I always feel when I’m swelling.
I have gained much weight which I dislike, I gained a lot of weight.
-How much?
-5-6 kilos.
I also have this stiffness in my lower back and actually I think it’s a little bit changing
from this pain in the head to the back.
-Stiffness in the lower back. It’s gone away from here and it’s more now in the lower back.
-Yes but it is changing because sometimes I’ve got this in the lower back and sometimes
when this comes on, I don’t have this in the lower back.
Something I noticed is that when I’m giving a lecture, my voice get very hoarse afterwards
and I’ve given lectures for many years but I’ve never had it.
-You never had that?
-Not so much.
Menses the last two times have been very little and this time it took a long time
before the red blood came out.
I’ve been going 4-5 days before the flow began and that’s not normal.
-But the flow when it came it was in duration the same as before?
-Yes I think so. But usually I have painless start of the menses
and I can only feel the stitch in my ovary when I have the (?) and especially in the right ovary.
Everything else I think I feel in my left side, so this is a new thing.
And I feel a kind of restless thing. I can go from one place and I can stop and …
what I was going to do and I have to go back again.
I think that’s it.
-That’s it?
-I’ve got a lot of pimples in my back which I haven’t had before.
-You haven’t them before and you don’t like it. Your back is itchy?
-That I had for a long time ago and it was really not good, scratch and scratch
until it is really a sore but it has not been like that, this one not so much scratching.
-You had that before you said?
-Yes in the lower back.
-You never mentioned here that symptom.
-No.
–Because it wasn’t there?
-No it wasn’t there, it was a long time ago.
-How long? You would say 5, 10 years?
-Yes something like that.
-Now there are more pimples but not so much itching.
-Not so much.
-In the region now you have this, is the thoracic region or the cervical and thoracic?
-No, the thoracic.
-And you never had pimples there before, as far as you can remember?
-Yes perhaps I have it once or twice but not often.
-One more thing. When I swallow it stitch up to the left ear
but it’s not always it is from time to time.
-Can you give me an overview of the difference?
How you feel now in comparison with before the treatment?
-More secure but also more vulnerable.
-But as far as inner feelings, I’d like to hear your evaluation.
-I feel better in general, much better.
-Good but what I want to know is how much better, that means in what respect?
I can see your face but it’s not enough. I would like you to express the differences.
-When I talk to people, I talk more easily.
-You are more free to express your emotions, your feelings.
-Yes, earlier I was afraid to express things, I was more alerting but now I can relax.
-Guarding yourself. Now you can relax.
-If they say something I think, that’s not my problem.
-OK very good.
-If you go now to her case and we see in the analysis, in the first part of the analysis
you will say what? When you hear that she got the herpes in her genitalia?
Immediately your mind went to which remedy?
-Natrum Muriaticum.
As she gave more and more information, what was the remedy that was manifesting?
After this herpes, she went into a period where she could not sleep, in a period
where she was very perspiring and feet out of covers, which was the remedy
that came to your mind?
Sulphur.
-You see we are scientists because most of us we agree
that this is the development of the case.
Then you hear the whole story and then you have to decide what to do.
The remedy has been given one year ago I think. Exactly, last May.
It was interfered by coffee, we took away the coffee without repeating,
we let the organism and the organism continued. Why it was that?
Because her remedy it was deep enough. It was very deep.
If this was happening and the remedy was not deep, the coffee would antidote it
and she would need a repetition. In case she was in lower or middle group 3.
She was a depression on group 3 uppermost layer. That was the diagnosis.
But if she was on group 4 upper layers or group 3 lower and you give a remedy
and she drinks coffee, the remedy will be antidoted immediately.
Then you have to repeat, why? Can anybody tell me?
Why the remedies on the lower part can be easily antidoted?
Much more easy antidoted?
-I think because the vital force is not strong enough to sustain it
and we could (?) from antidoting the coffee if it was on the higher levels,
it’s more strong and can rebound faster.
-It’s obvious, that is the reason.
I have told you sometimes when you have some patient going to the dentist
and after the dentist, you see a relapse starting, don’t jump into the picture
and give the remedy.
Wait, it might happen that after the dentist the patient will remain will come back by itself,
without repetition.
Now you know a little bit more that it depends where the patient is.
That this will be better or will stay relapsed depending on the pathology.
And it is a great pity, if you have lower cases with deep pathology, you give a remedy
and you touch the case and it starts a process. Then you interfere with antidotal…
that is very unfortunate because the antidotal effect may not come clear to the same remedy.
Then you repeat and it doesn’t act and then you have problems.
So what shall we do in this case? Shall we give Natrum Muriaticum, shall we give Sulphur
or will give nothing for the time being?
-Who says we give Natrum Muriaticum? Who says Sulphur? Who says nothing?
-OK you are learning. This is the idea. You just let the remedy continue,
you see the action and she will be most probably going into which remedy?
Next remedy what will be? There is any indication? Who wants to speak?
-I believe she turns finally to Sulphur because she begins to (?)
and the perspiration non stopped and cold water.
-She will be going into Sulphur. Most probably the other Ignatia will be going to Sulphur
and I have mentioned that many times Ignatia goes, as second remedy, to Sulphur. Many times.
Usually the complimentary remedy for Ignatia is … Natrum Muriaticum.
But I can tell you that I have seen more cases after Ignatia, going to Sulphur
than going to Natrum Muriaticum.
Ignatia and Natrum Muriaticum are complementary in the grief.
Some grief stays inside there and you have to deal with that grief,
then most probably the Natrum Muriaticum.
But when you have to deal after Ignatia with laziness or different things, then it goes to Sulphur.
-But she said that emotionally she feels more vulnerable
and for me that is clear in Natrum Muriaticum.
-No. This is not Natrum Muriaticum, I will explain to you.
When somebody says, I’m vulnerable it doesn’t mean that he is vulnerable.
Everyone is vulnerable, there is no way that you can ask anybody from us here
and he will say, I’m not vulnerable, I’m strong. Anyone will say I’m vulnerable.
Natrum Muriaticum is vulnerable but he will not say it because he is closed
and hits on the outside. Somebody tells something, he closes more. That is not the case.
I could not see it.
She was expressing, the emotions becoming more alive is a great sign of returning to youth.
Returning back to young age.
-What?
-If the emotions become alive, you hear a patient saying, my emotions are more alive.
You see through diseases and experiences the emotions become less and less
until we have no emotions anymore and we act like robots.
Mentally, this is right, this is wrong, we do this, we do that
and of course we go to all kinds of deviations.
Now you give the homeopathic remedy and you see the emotions become alive.
Strong emotions. Then you have hit the real source of life.
And the emotions actually being more alive indicate … who has live emotions?
Only the children have emotions which are alive. We are very closed
but the child will jump with the emotions, the emotions are alive, strong.
Now if the patient says, my emotions have become alive is going back to young age.
We agree we must wait, the possibility for going to the next remedy is Sulphur.
We’ll have it in mind and we’ll see.
-If this patient, in the time of the flu was here or after the time of the flu,
when she had the low level of energy, then you would have repeated Ignatia?
-Yes sure, I would have made a mistake most probably.
I don’t know, I’m not sure but most probably I would have made a mistake in prescribing.
Because the moment somebody comes and presses you for a remedy, you say yes.
But it is interesting that the acutes which are quite strong are not treated
and yet she is going over it. I don’t know, as I said yesterday,
if we had given the correct remedy for the acute, maybe even the result would be much quicker.
The problem is to find the correct remedy during the acute.
You find the acute remedy correct then the process of healing is speeded up.
But you are tempted to do that every time and because you don’t have enough symptoms,
you make a mistake. And this is the problem.