-How are you Uta?
-Last May I got Phosphorus 1M and I started the treatment here from last year.
In November 20th I took Calcarea Carbonica 200C.
I want to say that I came with two big things that I really want to say them again.
I had a lot of fears that many were not simple fears but some were between illusions
and visions of my child that is going to die or something and that disappeared completely.
It didn’t appear not in dreams, not in visions, not anymore.
I also had presented a symptom of real panic in front of people to talk in public
and you can hear me it’s still excited but it’s much better. Much easier.
So I took in 20th of November the Calcarea, I didn’t take it before but I took the same day
-because I had much irritability and anger at work with my colleagues,
the atmosphere wasn’t easy and I felt much irritability- and I took the Calcarea
and the minute I put it in my mouth I felt much, much better.
It was like something that came from life into me.
I took remedies before, I never felt something like this.
It was very …
-Immediate and dramatic.
-Immediate, direct energy and this energy I felt through all the winter and lot of energy
I didn’t need to sleep much in the night, not as before, not as now.
Now I’m a little down but it was very good energy and much of my stress just disappeared.
I had a premenstrual syndrome, I felt much pain and swollen in my breast.
I felt moods and before the period it was very bad.
For the first period after Calcarea, it came right away with any symptom before
and the menses itself was very good and flowing. That was really relief.
Another thing I mentioned is that I did not get any fever for many, many years
and 5 weeks after I took Calcarea, I had pneumonia.
I didn’t know if it’s pneumonia, I had high fever. Very high fever 40 degrees Celsius.
I had much thirst, my mouth was very dry, I felt pain in my right back before I had any cough.
But my general feeling was not bad at all.
I was in bed, I was very happy I had acute.
-Finally.
-And the energy wasn’t so exhausted. My husband convinced me to take remedy
and my friends suggested to take Bryonia because I had pain while moving
but I really did not want to take anything and after 4 days it’s gone.
I had more cough for maybe 2 more days.
Because of pressure of my brother, he checked me and he said it’s classical pneumonia.
He decided I should take antibiotics and of course there wasn’t any argument.
It disappeared after 4-5 days, I went back to work.
-Your husband is medical doctor?
-Not my husband, my brother.
My husband is academic, in the University.
Since December I was very much enthusiastic about organizing a conference
because you visited Israel about vaccination.
I was very convinced that maybe if I gather some medical doctors and you,
we maybe can bring a cooperation.
My main thing was to take away the Hepatitis B that is given the first day of the child.
I was very busy with this, I had to deal and talk to medical doctors,
to the head of departments in hospital, also in various hospitals.
When you saw me last year I was not in that state of mind to do that
but I had a lot of strength and enthusiasm and it went very good.
In my aspect it brought a lot of interest and people wanted to continue, we had more meetings.
It was quite astonishing for me to talk to those people without excitement
and to be able to organize. So again it was something very good.
-We have to explain actually to the people who listen now that actually
what you did you brought the governmental agency of vaccination together with people
who were against vaccination like myself and some others and we had a discussion
that was quite productive and we listen to their arguments and they listen to our arguments.
It was quite interesting I think the discussion finally.
-Very very interesting, it had a lot of echo, slowly, slowly, not immediately
and they are very interested in research now.
By their conditions but that’s our negotiation about how we can do maybe research
with baby born in the first year.
But I wanted to stress it here because usually I would not be strong enough.
-To undertake such project.
-Especially in communicating with these scientific world. I used to be very frightened.
In the winter I was less sensitive to the cold weather.
We had snow, we had not a severe winter but I was less sensitive to the cold weather
and I worked a lot and I was quite relaxed.
From end of March we had a big family event for my daughter.
We had her confirmation she is 12 years old and I was involved in that with all my mind and spirit
and it was a big thing for the whole day and I had to perform in front of 250 people something like this.
I had felt palpitations in my heart before that. My daughter did it fluently, I had palpitations
but I over came it and I could not believe that it went so deep
and I could express myself from very deep places and it was high spiritual experience for everybody.
It took from me a lot of strength and it was parallel to a crisis.
One of my sons said that he is 15 years old and he had a crisis because of face acne.
I treated him this year and he had some skin problems and couldn’t accept it
and he started to fight with me very directly.
He had deep depression and I just gave up and he went to a medical doctor
and he took his medication and I became very frustrated and sad.
I felt it’s really failure for me, he did not want to go to any homeopath,
that’s why I treated him and I felt very, very bad.
This is still ongoing with much tension with the (?) and I have 4 children
and all together it took from me a lot of strength, energy and I felt much more tired.
When I started to relapse it was beginning of May.
It was very interesting. First I felt again a kind of clairvoyance.
It was a feeling that I sense things in a way I do not like and I do not want
because sometimes it can be connected to bad things.
If I thought of somebody, he would call me the same 5 minutes.
It happened and I did not feel secure about this but it was the first thing
and then the tiredness and then pains in my breast.
-Before menses?
-More than a week before menses.
It was combination when I sat in a taxi and I had air condition on my face and I had these pains,
I thought it’s the menses, then I had very strong flu for 1 week.
It was 3 weeks ago with a severe sore throat, with a lot of salvation, very painful, no fever.
Then it disappeared and I had a lot of chorasea and general flu and then I got my period.
In general my perspiration got much stronger but it also came with hot weather.
I mostly perspiring in my lower part of my body, in my genitals and my feet
that I didn’t have for long time. Now I perspire very much, even with smell.
-You say that your energy is going down.
-Yes, I need to sleep more, usually I need a break when I work from 2-4 o’clock.
Every day I take a break, not because I can’t work but it makes it easier to have this break.
I have much more fears for my children, much more fears than before but they are not irrational,
I want to stress it.
I was a bit frightened because before I came to Greece, I didn’t want so much to travel.
And feeling of failure and I don’t think I can take the exam. It’s very strong fear.
Despair, not even to think of taking exam.
I also noticed during the time since November I had some opportunity to take hikes
to trek in the mountains, that I have quite strong fear of heights.
I do climb a lot, I like it but I’m very afraid when it is sloppy and narrow.
The remedy did not affect so much the tendency for constipation.
I’m not constipated if I take care of what I eat but this tendency is still there, the same.
I have always felt that my bones are not strong and when I train with my son,
he is doing martial arts, when he takes me for training, I feel that they are just broken.
I can break my bones easily, it’s a feeling of he can cause me fracture in a second.
This feeling did not change. It was always, many years before and still now.
I had very severe loss of hair during the winter and I have now since I’m here back pain.
It can be very strong after sitting, when I get up sometimes I can not move
and I’m ameliorated by warm bath, if I put warm application. I did it today and it helped me.
For 10 minutes just warm bath, but it’s very strong.
-I want to ask you a few questions. You remember, you said after stool
always you’ve been feeling good. It’s still there?
-Maybe it’s less but it is there.
-And you say vertigo in high places is still there or less?
-Not less. But in the helicopter I was not afraid. It depends what is pointed.
It’s more climbing, when it’s very narrow and the path is not wide enough, I can be very scared.
But I can climb on high mountains.
-Perspiration in the foot?
-Very strong.
-And it is clammy?
-It is no clammy, it was not in the winter so much. It became lately in May.
-What about perspiration during night on sleep?
-I don’t have that.
-But you said to me that you broke out in a skin eruption.
When did you break out in a skin eruption?
-It started in 93 after I got Phosphorus but this year since last May is even more
and getting spread more and more.
-Also you had quite a lot of trembling.
-I don’t have that. I have more with the heart, palpitations before speaking in public.
Specially with microphone, that is impossible.
-Also fear that something bad will happen. That fear you said it is there but it is much less.
-Yes. It’s not so strong, it is there.
-How is your thirst? For cold?
-Quite thirsty, not for cold icy, not at all and I don’t like ice-cream at all but just water or tea.
-There is any leucorrhea? It is more now than before?
-Yes. It changed, it is not whitish like it used to be.
It’s more yellowish but it’s there and it’s not more.
-Also you have related when you see something like an accident or things
which are wounded people, you were affected very much.
-It is very strong. Not accidents, mostly violence.
Especially now we have a lot of stress in Israel and…
-You feel it?
-I feel it.
-The aversion to milk is still there or you started drinking milk?
-I can drink milk only in warm, a little bit, I don’t like it.
-The finger nails?
-Very brittle.
-Was anytime after Calcarea carbonica that became strong?
-Maybe a bit they became stronger.
-Why do you think you have this relapse? There is a relapse which starts. Why?
Because of this conflict with your son? What mostly took away the energy?
With your son concerning his treatment. You over exerted yourself?
-I think I mentioned last time that I can not be under too much exertion.
Usually this experience I had in April was very special
and it was a bit of ‘catharsis’ for me that I could…
It was the most important female experience I experienced.
It was very high and it was like ‘catharsis’ but then afterwards I felt exhausted and drained.
But parallallely I had this problem with my son.
It’s not so much only the conflict as a teenager or whatever he has but it was a lot of fear.
He was deeply depressed and we were very worried for him.
This morning when I was talking about this, I cried a lot.
Now I’m much more calm but it was very stressful and it’s still ongoing.
He is not well balanced by the remedies he was given.
-But he was given homeopathic remedies or finally he took allopathic?
-He was under a homeopathic treatment all the time and he finally decided to make his decisions
because he couldn’t face the external things that came.
-Yes but did he take allopathic antibiotics or medication?
-He is taking antibiotics now for 1 month.
That’s his decision, that’s his treatment now, we can not interfere with this.
We can not say anything. He decided to do that and he said this is my exciting cause
and I treat my exciting cause.
-I see.
But you told him that most probably he is going to feel bad psychologically later on?
You have to explain to him and if he feels bad psychologically, maybe he will learn.
-Did you ever have experience with teenagers?
He said, I’d rather have cancer than having acne on my face.
-It’s very strange.
-And he is so bright and sensitive and highly intelligent and he wants to study medicine
and I could not handle it.
-But most probably if he takes the right remedy, he is going to break out into tremendous (?)
maybe after the correct remedy, he will become even worse.
You did not expect with the right remedy, first to disappear the acne.
First you will be worse and then he will go better.
-He had no patience and he is impatient in general, so I took it very…
-OK thank you.
One time antibiotics, few doses of this or that can still the organism bring back order by itself.
Another thing that can cause a relapse is a sudden grief that comes unexpectedly
and it can produce a sudden grief, it can produce a new state of conditions
that the patient may feel very bad.
Another condition is of physical over exertion.
In this particular case, in which you have given Calcarea carbonica which acted
and you know that Calc. carbonica is sensitive to over exertion,
you see headache with over exertion, all kinds of problems from over exertion.
You see over exertion aggravation, Calcarea is the main remedy actually for over exertion.
Therefore if you don’t have a full relapse, it’s better to wait.
She is going to go down and down and down, to full relapse,
then you give it a beautiful reaction.
But if you give it in the middle when this is happening you may have a problem
and if you are not experienced enough, you’ll mess up the case.
-What would the problem be, if you do give the same remedy?
-I have to be a prophet to tell you.
-We are all prophet from your wisdom.
-I’m not a prophet. I can not predict. What I know is that you may start having new symptoms
which they don’t even belong to the remedy.
She will lose more energy, she will become worse from this and that.
The organism tries to rearrange itself and in this process,
she may produce symptoms of Arsenicum. Then you give Arsenicum.
The Arsenicum produces symptoms of Bryonia. Give Bryonia
and in 6 months you will find the case confused.
Not from one dose of repetition but if you are unexperienced and you keep on giving remedies
because of this and that reason, then you will produce a case of confusion.
-Yesterday I was more relaxed, I was too tired after the day and I think I did not think,
only when you asked me I thought afterwards what really caused this relapse.
But because I get in my clinic many pictures like this, people come
and I would prescribe again really the Calcarea now because my relapse is on emotional level.
I feel that the main thing in my life is my motherhood and I feel there a lot of pain;
I wouldn’t wait as a homeopath if somebody come to me.
-I understand that. I will speak a little bit more about your case.
-I had the same question with (?) because of my clinical experience
but with her I would maybe repeat Causticum. If somebody comes with such pain
but OK you said no but myself I feel that my relapse has physical expressions
but the background is very deep emotional and it is ongoing.
Yesterday night I had a night mare, a very bad dream.
-About your son I understand but it is better to have one nightmare
than have 10 nightmares together, you and me.
-George I have another question about this rule.
You say if there is a relapse because of exertion, chemical drugs or (?) drugs etc.
if there is a relapse, how long a period of time would be appropriate given that relapse,
maybe for the patient severe?
And very uncomfortable and maybe partial or complete, what period of time can you determine
that the vital force will not be coming back and that you need to readminister the remedy.
-You have to establish whether the case is going down, down
or whether the case is on a statement, that means is on a certain level.
As long as this level stays there, hands off.
If the case goes down, down there is a time where she will show a full relapse
and then you give it. But as long as you don’t see that, it’s better not.
For her case if we are homeopaths, we give placebo.
This is a case where you have to give placebo.
What happens with Hava there are two things which affected her, as I understand.
One most probably was over exertion but the second thing
which affected her was the health of her son.
Because after all still has some sensitivity in this area.
It’s not totally gone, she is not an indifferent mother, she can not be.
Her character is to care about her family, her children, her sons etc.
So there is a sensitivity area and in this area, she has been hit and there is a conflict.
This conflict will take away quite a lot of the energy and this conflict stays.
A conflict is an emotional thing and she feels it in her feelings. She is not happy
at all with the condition because she thinks that her son is going down the gutter
by taking antibiotics for his acne and this is a real problem.
You can not fight with real problems.
If you try to correct real problems of life, I don’t have money and I’m anxious to find money.
You give a remedy, he will find money? No.
As soon as he has a job, the anxiety is going.
As soon as she will see that her son is not in danger really, that his organism
is overcoming it, that her son is OK, she will overcome it, back the organism will come.
Now you try to give a remedy at this point to make what? You don’t know.
She maybe in a relapse but as you all agree, we don’t see a full relapse in her case.
You all agreed about that. Therefore in such a case this is a kind of a rule
that you have to have in mind and you have to observe this rule.
You have a good remedy to a case, keep it as long as you can.
Otherwise you will have problems. I can give a certificate for that.
Now she knows the remedy, she is a homeopath. After all if she becomes really despair
she can always take and she can always call me and I will say, now you can take the remedy.
-What about the fear of the exams?
-This is a totality. If I have to find a remedy, I have to give it to everyone.
I can assure you everyone is feeling the same way, fear of exams.
Don’t take, unless you tremble, you go like this.
If I see you going like this, I will give you Gelsemium but I have to see that.
It’s really necessary and I don’t see that, knowing your character
and in the beginning how you acted.
-Would it be a possibility if you have given a remedy that really acted well
and you have a partial relapse by (?) treatment or anything else similar,
would it be possible then to give the same remedy in a low potency like 6X
so to push it a little bit so that it comes up again?
-You can give even the same potency or lower potency.
What I say is the remedy will act only if there is full relapse;
unless it is full relapse, it will not act.
Low or higher potency. If it is a full relapse, the remedy will act.
But this the idea not to lose the thread of the right prescription.
You got this thread of the right prescription. If you lose it, then it is very sad story.
Because you had a great possibility to relieve the patient and you lost it.
These are the rules, that’s what I’m saying, be careful.
I’m just giving you my experience. You don’t want to learn nonsense of fantasies.
You want to learn my experience, 40 years I have made these mistakes again and again.
That’s why I say you don’t want to make the mistake again.
-(?) you said, each remedy with almost clear picture might give a boost to the organism
because it is already fighting. The remedy is there and (?) are never clear in these groups.
Is it justified to prescribe an almost clear picture which might give a boost to the organism?
-Yes. I think I did not make myself clear.
What I said is, if the remedy has acted as beautiful as that one,
which presupposes that this case isn’t as complicated as Eliza’s case.
Eliza’s case is on another level all together.
Now we’re talking about that level of her condition.
I said, when somebody is on this level, which is a good level,
where the remedy has acted so well, in a partial relapse you are not supposed to give the remedy.
But in Eliza’s case we’re battling with a very complicated situation.
If we get a little bit of a clear picture, we’re justified to give it
because the picture was never clear.
It was this remedy, that remedy, that remedy. Then we had to chose the best possible remedy.
The same with the case of Lachesis that we have seen.
We battle in between the lines. You remember how difficult it is to chose the remedies
but finally by choosing correct remedies, you come to positive result.
For instance, she may have been taken before, Lachesis, the same remedies
that we gave apart from the first, she may have been taken.
But after the first remedy which is correct and the second remedy which is correct,
then it goes on and improves.
But give all these remedies upside down will have no effect.
They will leave the patient untouched.
So the main thing is to find in such cases and you don’t have clear picture.
The last time with Lachesis became like the breathing,
most probably here we’ll have a clear picture.
Now she comes, she says again, I have a relapse and I say, no.
Here we have reached the point where it was a very good action.
Maybe you don’t realize the whole class, how much better she is.
Those especially who have not seen the original case,
you have no idea how much better she is but in my understanding what I know about her
and how much suffering on an emotional level…
When she came, she didn’t come because the head was moving.
She came because the depression was so big and she suffered tremendously.
So if I see the progress, beautiful.
-If I could, I would like to share my experience concerning dental work.
I’ve been speaking with dentists about this, that partially the relapse after dentist work
it might be due to the fact that people take pain killers
that contain hormones of the adrenaline area.
-Are you dentist?
-No, I discussed this matter with the dentists because I had a lot of allergic patients
who had relapses and the same experience I made after other hormones.
-It depends with what the dentist is doing.
For instance if he is trying to kill the nerve for this they use very severe drugs,
like formaldehyde or something like that.
This is the worse. Also when you have an extraction and they get anesthetics, also it is.
But even what they used to use, the oil of (?) even that I found out
that could bring a relapse.
So it was the pain, the anesthetic injections, the killing of the roots
and it was also the adrenaline or whatever they were using for killing the pain.
-Another good sign that we found in this patient was that she had a severe acute
which overcame without taking antibiotics.
-Did you hear that? This was very good.
In case you don’t understand the theory, what are you going to do?
You are going to give one remedy after another, give antibiotics, give this, give that.
You see how useful it is to understand the theory. You can save yourself a lot of trouble.
Also it’s beautiful to see what we teach here are not just theoretical aspects.
They are facts of life and death.
-Concerning this level I’d like to know if there any cases of somebody dying in the family
and then suddenly occurs complete weakness and a big grief in the patient,
are we then allowed to take the remedy that would be suitable for this case or shall we wait?
-If there is a severe grief which causes unbearable pain,
then you have to judge whether this new situation is a situation of Natrum muriaticum
or Ignatia or Phosphoric acid or Aurum or Staphysagria, whatever.
You have to judge at this moment and not take the constitutional remedy automatically.
But if, because of the grief, you have all the symptoms back of the chronic condition
plus depression, yes you take the same remedy.
But if now you have a new symptomatology without having back the chronic symptoms
you take the new remedy.
-In the case there is a relapse that’s only physical and it’s not full relapse
and you’d prefer to give allopathic medicine,
is it possible also to give mother tincture’s that ease pain?
Like (?) for instance.
-I don’t know this.
-It is in Spain.
-What I say is not to take regular 3 times the day a pain killer,
within a week you will cause a relapse.
If for one day you really have severe pain, you can take a pain killer,
you can take aspirin, 2 aspirins. I have found out that out of all the allopathic drugs,
aspirin is the least dangerous to cause problem.
-Me too I made the observation, when a patient is on the upper level
and he got some disturbances from outside and you have new symptoms,
that if you wait the organism has the strength to clear the picture again.
If you go down to the lower levels and there is a stress factor from outside,
then the picture might change to different remedies or you have to repeat the remedy?
-Correct. It is different. The rules for the lower level patients are different.
This case why we establish it and we say this case belongs to the uppermost layers?
Because of the clear picture and clear reactions she had and amelioration.
That’s why we establish this case, we say this case belongs to the uppermost levels.
Now we have to keep it there, not to bring her down again.
-When you said (?) when is a state of good reaction to remedy suddenly an acute pain
or one acute symptom which is coming back, we are going to look for some (?) the symptom
or even treated with aspirin or something.
In contrast to if there are all symptoms coming back,
are you referring into what Hahnemann says psoric and not psoric remedies?
Because he said a non psoric you can use when you have that slight acute situation
or if things are (?) then you go to the psoric remedies?
-No, I don’t refer to that. There is no connection between what Hahnemann was saying.
Hahnemann had an understanding which I may say it was a partial understanding
of diseases of what we have today.
Today we have more complicated diseases and also the theory of the miasm as Hahnemann put it,
I don’t agree. I don’t agree that all diseases are due to syphilis psora and gonorrhea, no.
Therefore in this matter, when he says psoric remedies I don’t believe there are such remedies,
we can call psoric remedies.
Yes there are some remedies where more indicated in skin eruptions, like Sulphur,
like (?), like Petroleum but to call these remedies, put them on this category of psora
you will exclude them from gonorrhea cases where the same remedies will be indicated.
So therefore I don’t agree with the separation of the remedies in psoric and no psoric.