-What you took last time?
-Nothing.
-And you took Ignatia what potency?
-50M.
-In 1 year?
–Yes, was it in May?
–One and a half year ago.
–Yes.
-Last May you got no medicine and now what is the situation?
-Actually I’m feeling well, both emotionally, mentally and physically.
There are small things that bother me physically and I’m going through a very hard time
because for two months I felt that all the dirt, the memories…
-Memories from the past have come back?
-Yes. Sometimes when you see things you get sad and sometimes you think
this is how life is, everything can change, so I have (?) harder.
But these days I feel it’s good because I feel more relaxed.
-It is like going back in your life and making a kind of evaluation…
-It’s like I’ve been aware of many things in the daily life but also things I have done
before which I’m not proud of.
-And you regret it now?
-Of course, I wouldn’t have done today with my knowledge, no, certainly not.
But in a way when that period went off, I had a very good time because I felt more in balance
but I went off and on by saying, you are a bad girl, you are the best one.
-One time this, one time that. For a period of two months this was happening?
-From May until end of July. I’m studying esoteric philosophy and there I have many friends
who also see things that this is something you are going through.
You have to get rid of it because otherwise you can’t go forward.
And I really feel it because now I can see my patients more clearly, I dream very vivid.
-Like as if you have matured, you became more wise.
-And also very frightened for many things actually.
In these two months I can’t express and say I was afraid of this or this or that
but I just was afraid. I get some heartbeat sometimes…
-Are you still with your husband?
-Yes and that’s something I’m very jealous.
-Now you have become very jealous on your husband?
-Yes I realize it when I was travelling down here to Alonissos
because we spoke about another family which the husband has gone two weeks on vacation,
he is actually a doctor and my husband said, maybe we should go out some time
with his woman and I said, oh my god is he going to do that? And I felt really bad.
-But you did that before yourself.
-Yes but this time it was different.
I’ve been a little jealous of him about other things
because I always thought of him as a really nice man, doing all the wise things that I don’t’ do.
But it felt good in a way too.
-In general you feel more balanced and relaxed and not in stress.
-No, I’m not so stressed anymore. I don’t train so much and I like to walk in forest.
Do you want me to tell you the physical things?
-Yes.
-I told you in May that I was getting very warm. I’ve been tremendous warm now.
I’ve always been dry inside of my palms but I’m sweating on my feet and if I walk fast
from back and downwards, my hands are sweating and I’m very warm.
Also in the night I can wake up sweating tremendously.
-During sleep?
-When I wake up I realize I’m wet.
-In the beginning you used to perspire only on your face, as you said.
-Mostly on the face if I walk fast or training or something, I always get wet on my face.
If I’m dancing, I’m wet on the face but I perspire more in hands and feet now.
I thought I was going through the menopause because I had menses when I was here
in May and 14 days afterwards I got it again and then 14 days afterwards I got it again.
One of the menses lasted 14 days and that never happened before. Normally it’s 5 days.
-And since that time you did not have anymore menses?
-Yes but through all this thinking and forth and back maybe it’s distured
because the last one was 28 days as I used to have.
During that period my breast was very swollen, I even couldn’t use my usual bras
because it was so small.
-Swelling. Before menses or during menses?
-Both actually for a longer period than I used to.
-I see.
-I also have more sexual desire.
-It’s good.
You don’t consider this as a symptom? More sexual desire? It doesn’t bother you.
-No it doesn’t. The only thing that bothers me is if my husband has been drinking beer
then I can’t because I can’t smell the smell of the beer.
I told you in May that I have burning pain in my…
-Hands?
-No, hemorrhoids. When I came down here I got a flu, the same evening
when I went to the toilet there came blood and I never had blood in that way before.
-Now you still have the hemorrhoids?
-Yes and it’s actually bothering me because they have burning sensation.
-External hemorrhoids?
-Yes as if there is something in the outside of the muscle.
-Very painful or not so painful?
-Not so painful.
–Just burning, itching and little burning.
–Yes.
-Something else?
-I got eczema in my nostrils and I got itching in my palms with dry spots.
-Dry spots?
– Yes.
I also got itching on my (?) and on my scalp. Once I itched I got a crust but it’s small thing.
Two times during this period I thought I was getting a common cold but I have so much work,
so I took vitamin C.
-And it went away.
-Yes.
-During that period did you eat any fruits? Any desire for fruits, you took fruits, you are fruits?
-Actually I’ve been eating a little bit more because I can pick them in my own garden.
We have plums and I’ve been eating a lot of plums. Apples have not finished yet.
-They are not ripe yet. They call it ripe.
-OK.
-So you have been eating more plums, not other fruits?
-No.
-Did you eat any sweets? You started eating sweets?
-Yes, I’m eating more sweets and more salt.
-More sweets and more salt.
-Also I was going to tell you something because the 25th of August I got bitten by a little insect
which gives the borreliosis and I was bitten at 2 o’clock
and I didn’t discover it until 11 o’ clock in the evening.
Then I felt, all the day, a sensitiveness on my other arm and in my wrist in the skin area
and it was aching in the joints.
At that time I was making food for 34 people in big kettles
and I thought it might be from this work but when I discovered this I twisted it, put it away.
-You took the tick away and there was not any circular (?)
so I supposed that didn’t do any harm.
-I hope.
-But actually I think it has because as I told you I got a flu when I came down here
and I had got feverish and I was sweating a lot during that night
and I went up to one of my colleagues and she gave me a foot reflex therapy.
Then all the aching in my joints went away and I felt good for two days.
Today I’ve been a little bit dizzy and not so good.
The only thing I put on this place was something called (?) it is drops from (?)
-That medicine is used for prevention?
-To clear up the blood actually. I often use it in wounds.
-Like a disinfectant.
-But it’s not really so effective as it was before.
-In Germany it seems you have a lot of this disease? Why, do they know why?
-But it was really big because I often go to the forest and I can see them on my skin
and I just take them away because I always take a bath after going to the forest.
-A blood check. After how long you can develop the blood reaction?
-Immediately and then it changes, if it comes later, they say it’s already passed a long time.
-So maybe you have to check it when you go back to Germany…
-I’m not German, I’m Norwegian.
-Oh yes. In Norway you have the same problem?
-Yes.
-We don’t have it so much here. Only in German people I have seen it.
You say you feel more heat in your body.
-Yes that’s the thing which bothers me
because when I work with the foot reflex therapy I get so warm.
-Did you stay at all under the sun here to see how you react under the sun?
-Yes when I got this therapy, I laid on the beach, I slept for two hours.
-In the sun?
–Yes.
–And it didn’t bother you?
-No. I went swimming.
-In the sea you feel extremely good bathing in the sea or it makes no difference?
-If I’m diving in the sea it feels good, if I have to walk, I don’t like that.
-I see.
-But I like to swim.
I would like to hear who is for the same remedy to repeat?
Who would repeat the same remedy or give a higher potency in this case? Nobody.
Who will think of a new remedy? 6. What remedy, which one?
-Pulsatilla, Sulphur, Lachesis. Who says Pulsatilla? One. Sulphur? Seven. Lachesis? Two.
Shall we give Sulphur yes or no? Who says no Sulphur?
Why Sulphur? She says the desire for salt and sweet is increased.
Sulphur would have desire for sweets mostly.
So there is the Pulsatilla. Why Pulsatilla? Because of the breast.
If you consider the symptoms of menses and the swelling and pain in the breast
and you consider also the increase of salt and sweets, these together make what remedy?
Calcarea Carbonica. But Cal. Carb. should be rather getting cold. She is getting warmer.
She is perspiring more. Again possibility Cal. Carb., possibility Sulphur also.
In order to give Sulphur, you have to have perspiration …
She starts getting in the skin some problems but little problems.
Herself she says, the problems I’m going to tell you are not important.
I feel good, don’t touch the case.
This is the idea. In spite of the fact that you may see she is going to Sulphur
or Pulsatilla or Lachesis, then still you do not touch the case.
But you say, one and a half year ago she got the remedy? Yes it doesn’t matter.
You see a very interesting thing which happens in the organism.
The organism goes back and evaluates the life, it says oh my god I made some mistakes,
I was stupid, I wish I would not have done it.
And this is a good eliminating process, a good clearing. It’s like confession,
like you tell to yourself. What she did, what was happening to the organism.
The organism was pushing her to clear up the past. It’s very good process.
Why should we interfere with another remedy? Let the organism continue its own journey.
There is nothing bothering her. Also the fact that she developed all these skin eruption.
It’s not bothering. If the skin eruption becomes really bothering, really bad,
later on and then she starts scratching and her life becomes very disturbing,
then you may be thinking of prescribing a remedy, not now.
In spite of the fact that she may get disappointed like the other one, she says
unless I get the remedy, I will commit suicide, finish. Forget it, I don’t want to live anymore.
I want the remedy. No, I didn’t mean you.
She says no, no, no. Did I say anything about her? She said, no, not me.
So this was an easy case.
You had enough.
-Then I got sick in Christmas. I started to have some acid in my stomach, I wake up from it.
-You thought?
-No I woke up in the night having this acid feeling in my stomach.
I suddenly had to vomit but I couldn’t reach the toilet so I vomit just all over.
-That was one time?
-Yes but I also got fever. So either I must have been eating something bad
or I don’t know if it was a flu or something.
-You did not eat outside?
-Yes I was in a party.
-You were in a party and how long it lasted this upset?
-3 days with fever.
-And diarrhea?
–A little bit but not much.
-You vomited several times or only one?
-Only that one. Really strong.
-That saved you.
-Yes I think so.
Then I got sick again with a flu in February, then I was really sick.
I’ve never been so low in energy, never.
I couldn’t even read a newspaper but it was because I got Chlamydia after the flu.
-After the flu? Did you have fever?
-Yes.
–How high?
-I didn’t measure it because I was giving lecture when it started and I continued lecturing.
-But next day?
–And next day also.
-But you were depleted from energy and kept on working?
-Yes.
–You didn’t stop working?
–No.
–All the days?
-I was in another town giving lectures and I realized when I got on the plane that I was going sick.
-Why you say you got a flu? How do you know it was a flu and not a cold?
-Because I got this fever, I got aching pain in my bones, I had tremendous headache.
I started to get pain in my eyes, the right eye, like it was pushing outside and…
-…and exhaustion.
-Yes but that came after, when I got home again because during the night I woke up,
I was really, really thirsty and I drank a lot of water.
Suddenly I felt that all energy went away from me, so I had to sit down and then I faint.
So I woke up with the head on the table and I had pushed all the things down on the floor
and when I woke up I went to the toilet and I had the stool and then I faint again.
-You fainted again after stool?
-Yes and then I went to bed and I slept nearly for two days.
-But how could you work for 5 days?
-It was Friday evening, Saturday and the Sunday until 3 o’clock.
-And you went back on Monday?
-No, I went back on Sunday evening.
-On Sunday night happened and on Sunday night and Monday you were exhausted.
How long it lasted this exhaustion. The fever I think I had until Friday
and then my eye got swollen, I couldn’t see through it but I sent a fax down and I was replied
that I would see a homeopath in Norway. Maybe that was because I forgot to tell the case number.
I just wrote my name and I didn’t say that I was the case number for 277.
-I see.
-But I did get a reply that I should see a homeopath in Norway.
Then I went to a doctor and he examined me and that was Monday after one week
and he said I had pneumonia.
And then he took an X-ray and it showed that the left lung was infected.
So then I went home because he wanted me to take antibiotics but I didn’t want it
so I said you have to give me one week and then I tried to fax down that I was this case number,
in case she hadn’t understand me, but I didn’t get any answer and because I was so thirsty
and I was so low in energy, I took Phosphorus C200 and after 2 days I got better.
The only thing that remained was that I had obstruction, when I lied down in the afternoon.
It was difficult to breathe.
-When you lie flat?
-Yes.
And all the time that I had this pneumonia, I had tremendous pain in my ribs as if they were broken,
every time I coughed.
-In the lower ribs?
-No, about here.
Every time I coughed I had to hold it because it was tremendous painful.
The only thing that stopped my coughing in the night
or during the night time was to lie on my right side or on the belly, then I stopped coughing.
But I woke up every night at 3 o’clock coughing and then I had to stand up and drink a lot of water.
That’s why I took Phosphorus.
When this obstruction was keeping on, I felt I wanted to do something and I tried Sulphur C30
but it didn’t do anything.
So on the 7th of April I started in a period to be more sad
and I felt that the house was too small, I felt that I was locked up in a way
and I started to do this again sighing and I took Ignatia 50M, repeated it.
Then I start coughing and (?) the obstruction went away
and I got some symptoms from taking Ignatia.
The pain which I told you about in the hip going down to the leg, got more strong.
I coughed a lot during the day time.
-Are you still coughing?
-Actually I started down here now.
Two days ago I started to cough, I ‘m going to tell you about it
because I got a lot of new symptoms after reaching Alonissos.
But I still drink a lot of water, more than usual and I also (?) in the winter time
that I drink more during the winter than the summer and that’s very peculiar I think.
I drink a lot more of water.
I had a shoulder pain, left sided and the second day my throat got painful
but I also felt I got more energy. I was less tensioned.
-In the house you stay alone?
-No with my husband but we bought this house one year ago. I never lived in such a small house
and the rooms are not open, I feel that it’s in a way shocking me, it’s no good for me.
I like to have more space.
I started also to eat more after Ignatia, I was eating a lot.
The 26th I got some pain in both sides of the ribs as if something was pressing.
And it lasted only for one day. Then I got a lot of acid in my stomach
and that was for one week very strong.
But when I came down here to Alonissos, I didn’t like the heat and usually I do.
I had to go out of the sun after staying there for one hour and normally I can lie the whole day.
I started to get some headaches from the sun and I got eruption from the sun.
All my back has blisters and some part in the front on the chest.
-By staying very little in the sun because you stayed half an hour only?
-No I stayed probably one hour.
-And then you felt tired or you just felt headache coming and then you left?
-That kind of restlessness that I didn’t like to lie there.
-Just generally you didn’t like the sun and you left,
where previously you were lying to the sun for the whole day.
-My eyes started to give some pus in the morning and in the afternoon.
And I started to swell in one gland on the left side and it was painful only when I touched it
and when I turn my head but it’s not painful when I swallow.
Then two days ago I started to get laryngitis, my voice is not good, you can hear it.
But that I had all the winter time, during the lecturing I nearly lost my voice several times.
With Phosphorus it went away and with Ignatia it came back.
I feel a little bit that I’m not so social. I want to be a little bit by myself.
-Tell me something else. How much salt you like?
-During the whole winter I’m eating much salt than usual.
I like the pop-corn, I put salt on it and I eat more salt food but not a tremendous amount.
More than usual and I drink a lot more.
-What about meat with fat in it? Will you take it or you will separate that?
-It depends because if the fat is crispy I can eat it but if it isn’t I have to take it away.
-Always or this is more lately?
-I haven’t thought about it but I have been eating lamp down here
and I have taken away some of the fat.
-Your sleep is good here, is constant or you wake up?
-No, I woke up one night at 3 o’clock.
-You woke up and you started coughing?
-No, I just woke up. It was on Sunday.
-Did you stay for long?
-No, I just went to sleep again.
But I wake up early in the morning. Here it’s at 6.15 and for my time in Norway it’s 5.15.
-It’s quite early which is unusual for you?
-I did that previously but not while having (?) I didn’t sleep so short.
-What about the hemorrhoids?
-Those were also bad when I had this flu. Very bad but actually those were better
from the Sulphur C30.
-From the C30 they disappeared?
-Yes. I haven’t have them since then.
-Very good and what about the menses? Before menses you have said that before menses
and during menses your breast were swollen. Was the last menses
that they were painful and bloated?
-I think they are not so painful.
-What about perspiration? You had perspiration quite a lot and waking from perspiration?
-Yes I have a lot of perspiration but not so much after Ignatia.
Then I was a little bit colder in my arms but down here I had to lay only with the sheets
not a blanket. So I’m very warm on my arms and feet during the night time but I don’t sweat.
-Is it still the bloatness?
-Yes it’s some but not so tremendous, as it was  before because I had to hold my stomach
when I was walking because it really hurt.
-Can you tell me if during this winter something happened in your life which made you sad?
-Yes a bit about this house because I started to talk with my husband about it
and this house was really a thing he bought.
He wanted this house and for me it was a kind of being back because he really wanted it.
-He wanted it, you don’t like it.
-In a way it was OK but I felt that he really wanted it.
When we went around in this house he told, look how marvelous it is
and I couldn’t see it the same way. I saw the outside building was nice
but inside was more closed.
-And you had to put yourself in that situation
because you didn’t want to go against the wish of your husband?
-I thought it will be well. I thought it could be a good place.
-But you don’t feel comfortable there.
-No, not anymore and when I was in Denmark 3 weeks before coming here, I had to say it.
I want to move, I can’t stay anymore and he didn’t reply.
-On the telephone?
-No, I said it to him while sitting and I think he is a bit angry because…
-Because he likes it.
–Yes.
-There is a big problem actually because you feel unhappy in the house but you feel he likes
it and you feel that you can not make a decision.
-I feel as if I’m …
-Right. Thank you.
The acute situation. What happened? Was the remedy correct, yes or no?
-When she was telling that she had that strong headache (?) to teach the other people
and the pressing pain in the eyes and the coughing,
perhaps it would not have been bad idea to take Bryonia.
Because perhaps of not taking Bryonia and working so much it got more difficult
and she developed pneumonia.
-The possibility of Bryonia was there obviously because of the excessive thirst,
the exhaustion and the pain during coughing.
Instead of Bryonia, she got Phosphorus and Phosphorus did something.
After Phosphorus she got Sulphur. So this acute situation was not treated correctly.
There is possibility for Bryonia but Phosphorus, according to what she said,
it acted well and it took away most of the symptoms.
But they were certain symptoms remained which point to another remedy
which is complementary to Phosphorus and which is…
-Natrum Muriaticum?
-No, I’m talking about the acute condition of the pneumonia state.
You don’t know which is complementary of Phosphorus?
-Arsenicum?
-Arsenicum is complementary but it’s not the remedy that she should take.
-Kali Carbonicum?
–Yes.
The remedy that would complement the action of Phosphorus in that acute state of pneumonia,
was Kali Carbonicum.
Because she said, I was waking at 3 o’clock with coughing nobody paid attention to that,
not even her and it was a keynote symptom.
Therefore, instead of taking Kali Carbonicum, she took Sulphur.
What Sulphur did? Sulphur took away the hemorrhoids. That’s bad actually, good for her
but it is bad as a continuation of the case.
We don’t like to see the cough remaining, the exhaustion remaining
and then the hemorrhoids going away but anyhow I believe did not do very much.
Now we arrive at that stage in which she describes her situation.
Do you think she is in grief, yes or no?
–Yes.
–So this is clear.
Do you think that she wants to stay by herself, is true?
–Yes.
Do you think that the increase in salt is true?
Do you think that the aversion to sun is true?
–Yes.
Do you think that Natrum Muriaticum is a good remedy for her?
–Yes!
Very good. So you are a good class.
What potency should she take?
If the grief is very deep, you have to go very high. In her case, you can go very high.
You saw how 50M acted? You have to go very high, 50M Natrum Muriaticum
because the grief in which she is, it’s really a difficult situation.
Her husband, whom she likes and whom she wants to be pleased, has a different opinion
about the house and in the house she feels constricted and it’s a terrible situation.
And yet she can not get out. She said the husband, I don’t like this house.
The husband do not pay attention.
Then there is a grief because she feels the husband does not pay attention to her needs.
You know that she feels that the husband does not care about me, if for a reason like this comes,
is a very strong grief. Therefore 200 will not be enough, 1M will not be enough.
She has to go quite high to relieve this kind of grief.
So for her Natrum Muriaticum 50M is the right remedy because it comes
of course also as a complementary to Ignatia.
But you noticed how much she is sighing. So give first Ignatia and then Natrum Muriaticum?
-No.
-Now the symptoms are for Nat. Mur. and underneath is a symptom of Ignatia.
We give Nat. Mur. and if the symptom of sighing persists after, then we repeat after Nat. Mur.
we repeat Ignatia. This is the right type of thinking for her case.
-She only took Ignatia 4 weeks ago, is it possible it started from the Ignatia?
-Yes it is possible because Ignatia was not needed at the moment
and she has a kind of established a proving.
But what I’m saying is since she has been Ignatia, many times we see like this,
they come in a circle.
Like Staphysagria-Causticum, Phosphorus-Arsenicum and Calcarea-Sulphur-Lycopodium,
they come in circle, they come again and again.
That is why I said, maybe if we see this symptoms persisting, we can repeat later on Ignatia.
Natrum Muriaticum now.
-For sighing also?
-Yes.
Nat. Mur. may take away the sighing as well.
-Why would you think of Ignatia where Nat. Mur. also covers the sighing
and also one of the few remedies that covers sighing with grief?
-This is true. Why we think of Ignatia? Because she has been Ignatia
and the fact that she has a keynote of Ignatia, perhaps it gives you an idea
that maybe under Nat. Mur. there is still some Ignatia, maybe,
to take out all the grief that was there.