-This is a child 15 years old and he was born weighted almost 11 pounds and 2 and half
years old got a flu in combination with diarrhea which never stopped. After several weeks
he was not given milk anymore and the diarrhea symptoms disappeared. From 5 years
old approximately till he was 8 or 9, he had ear inflammation and he was given antibiotics
many times. He has not had ear infections after he got diabetic symptoms 9 years old.
This is very interesting because the report was written before the teaching of the class.
It exactly confirms what it has been told.
His father was a sportsman, Alexander also was a sportsman. Alexander always liked to
stay at home and read and be together with pets, prepare food, find flowers. He prefers
to have friends at home and being with them at home. With the blood sugar level over a
period of time he has been stable between 7 and 10, he is more open for appointments
outside.
His juvenile diabetes was discovered at what age? When you had the first blood
examination and you saw that his blood sugar was high?
-In 1981.
-That means when he was 8 years old and what was the blood sugar during that time?
-25. When he comes to the hospital (?) so they were not sure if he had diabetes or if it
was just an accident.
-And when they became sure? At what age?
-After some days.
-And then they gave him how many milligrams of insulin?
-14 units the day.
-And now how much insulin he takes?
-It depends, about 16-18.
-By injection?
-Yes.
-The last thing they said about insulin is that they try to find a way to give it with a spray.
-He used something which is not a needle but a pressure in the ear.
-A pump. As I see here, Alexander got diabetic diagnosis and he was diagnosed by a
homeopath. At that time he injected 14 units of insulin per day, after some (?) his need
for insulin increased. His symptoms, he sweated a lot. He still sweats now?
-Yes.
-A lot, like you used to?
-No.
-Where do you sweat?
-Here. In the forehead.
-Mostly in the forehead.
-Yes and on the feet.
-Very red in face after sporting, he has always been drinking especially cold milk in the
first years. Always liked smoked fish and meat. Very friend of animals. Likes to read 1-2
hours a day. Alexander got a few fissures. Where did you get the fissures?
-In the rectum.
-Or beside, near.
-And he took Medorrhinum 200, it was the first remedy, 10 in water. The symptoms from
the fissures changed from a big sore and red area to a more limited area like a swollen
ball near the rectum. He had gastric fluid and needed 16 units of insulin. The homeopath
tried Thuja 200, Alexander got pains in his stomach at once. I didn’t feel very fit in
general. The fissure was extremely painful. He was sent to hospital and operated.
It was severe?
-Very severe because I waited some days and went to another doctor allopathic and they
wanted us to go to the hospital but the homeopath said wait.
-It was very painful after stool the fissure?
-All the time. And they said it’s very dangerous and it may go in the blood system.
-He had often inflammation of his throat and had several appointments with doctor Bruce.
He recommended Phosphorus and proposed D30 for 1 week. He was bleeding from his
nose for 1 week and became good again in his throat. In addition the blood sugar level
went down.
So when he got Phosphorus D30 for 1 week, he started bleeding from his nose.
-Yes and every time when he is tired, he starts bleeding, in the night.
-Epistaxis in the night.
After this he gave him Phos. 30 several times when he doesn’t feel well. His body has
reached by increasing the blood sugar level after 5-6 hours and increasing level another
10-15 hours later. He had often given him Phos. when he suffers from flu etc.
So whenever you give him Phos., it seems to act and help him.
-Yes.
-His allopathic doctor is very surprised that he is not using more insulin, than described
above, that’s quite unusual. In January this year Alexander went to another homeopath.
He gave him Bacillinum 200, the blood sugar raised and he got much hurt in the throat.
He tried LΜ potencies and had to take more insulin and felt bad. In February he got Calc.
carb. 200 and then after 30 and LM he became better in the throat, the blood sugar was
stabilized but did not fall. This is the end of the case.
-Yes.
-And here is Alexander the Great.
-Yes but he has had…
-Do you know who is Alexander the Great?
-Yes.
-Who?
No, why do you say yes? Alexander was the great general of the Greek army by these
ancient times 300 b.c., he conquered half of the world. So you can do the same, similar.
Megas Alexandros, Alexander the Great.
So you give us a great problem also, as you know. I want to ask you how do you feel.
-Good.
-Good, happy?
-Yes.
-Do you like reading? -Yes.
-What? Comics?
-Comics and romance.
-Just novels or historic what?
-He likes to read history? No he does not. You go to school?
-Yes.
-What class are you? 5,6, 8?
-9.
-Between your class you are in the front, in the middle or in the back?
-In the front.
-Not sitting in the front.
-Also. Your marks are high?
-Yes.
-Very good. Do you like your hair style?
-It is always like this or it is because in Alonissos you have to be different.
-Always like this.
-Are you shy?
-A little.
-Not very much. If your teacher calls you to tell the class, you will speak? If he tells you
to come up and say, Alexander come and tell us history or physics, you get up and you
can say the lesson of the day?
-Yes.
-You don’t feel timid, shy? He has difficulties in English, find the English word. Do you
understand my English?
-Yes.
-Do you like sweets?
-Do you eat? How much? Does he eat sweets?
-Sometimes.
-He likes very much, he says, I want sweets.
-No, small. Fruits he likes better.
-What kind of fruit do you like most? -Grapes.
-What else? –All.
-But do you like unripe fruits, like green fruits which is sour.
-No, yes.
-No or yes?
-Yes.
-Do you understand sour?
-He eats a lot of fruits all day.
-Is he very active, is he hyper active you would say?
-No but he plays football.
-He has a lot of energy?
-It depends on the sugar level.
-If he is on high level, how is his energy, it goes down very much? He feels tired and can
not think?
-Not so much. Today he had high, 16 when he woke up, in the morning. 12 o’clock.
-He woke up 12 o’clock, why?
-We were travelling yesterday 4 o’clock in the morning.
-He doesn’t do it every day.
-No.
-What time he goes to bed?
-10 o’clock.
-Your sleep is good?
-Yes.
-Can you tell me if you feel better in cold weather or in warm weather, which you like
best? You like in the cold like Norway or you like to be in warm climate.
-…
-You don’t know. You can tolerate, cold it’s OK or warm? You are not bothered by warm?
-Yes, I don’t like it if it’s very warm.
-Then you perspire?
-Yes.
-Where?
-In the forehead.
-OK you remember you told me the first time the same. It’s very important.
Have you noticed if he is anxious about his health?
-He is interested, yes but he has some…
-He asks what is this in an anxious manner?
-Not so anxious. But for a child he comes and say what is it. He is not anxious about this.
-Do you like smoked meat?
-Yes.
-Very much?
-Yes but he likes (?)
-You would say very much? –Yes.
-Fish smoked also? –Yes.
-What is your best food? –Chicken.
-What type of chicken? Any type?
-Grilled.
-Not smoked meat, it’s not your best food.
-No.
-Eggs do you like? –Yes.
-Very much? –Yes.
-What kind of eggs, boiled, fried?
-Fried.
-Boiled you don’t like or you can take?
-I can take.
-But you prefer fried. –Yes.
-When you wake up in the morning you feel good or you don’t want to talk to anybody?
-I feel good.
-It’s true what he says?
-Sometimes when he has slept long in the morning to 10-11, he feels tired.
-Though he has slept longer he feels more tired. It’s true, you can confirm that?
-Yes.
-You sleep in a position on your left side, right side, back, forward?
-Right side.
-Which is your right side? Show me.
-There.
-This is the left.
-Then left.
-This is the left, really that side? Because you said right but you showed the left? So what
is finally?
-The left side.
-Is that, you confirm?
-He changes.
-He had any skin eruption in younger age?
-He has something in his hand, he loses skin.
-What do you mean?
-It’s coming off.
-The skin. Your palm is sweating now?
-No.
-But the skin comes off. A lot?
-Not so much.
-Your nails are strong? -Yes.
-They don’t break. –No.
-Do you bite them? –Sometimes, his father bites them.
-You are his mother? –Yes but he's likes his father. He's very alike him.
-You say you bite them.
-Yes but not all the time.
-Do you know when you bite them? When you are anxious?
-When I feel fear.
-I see.
Do you take normal salt or you take the salt and you put extra salt in your food?
-I take more salt.
-Is that true?
-No. It’s not so much. He says on eggs.
-Only on eggs and tomato?
-No, I don’t eat tomato.
-Oh you don’t like tomato? Now we catch you. What else you don’t like?
-Mustard, sour cream.
-Onions? Raw onions?
-Not raw.
-You don’t like raw onions, why? If you eat what happens?
-I don’t know. I’ll try.
-I don’t think he has tried.
-You don’t have it in your country?
-We don’t use it so much.
-I see. Cheese you like?
-Yes.
-According to you what he likes to eat?
-Cheese and fruit and bread, he eats everything but he doesn’t like sweets on the bread.
We don’t use that.
-Fish you like? -Yes.
-He likes fish? –Yes.
-Very much? –Yes, he likes fried best.
-When you sleep do you have saliva running out of your mouth into the pillow?
-No, never.
-No ear infections at all now?
-Now he get it if he swims under the water. And we are in a plane he has problem.
-He stammers at all?
-No.
-Do you have any fears? Are you afraid of something?
-Dogs barking.
-You are afraid of dogs?
-No, if they are barking only.
-Cats? -No.
-You don’t mind. -That’s OK.
-What about big animals, cows? -That’s OK.
-Only dogs. Are you afraid of anything else? In the night if they leave you at home?
-That’s OK.
-So you are courageous and if they leave you alone in the night and then you have to go
to bed, you switch off the light or you keep the light?
-Switch off.
-Dark, no problem. It’s true?
-I don’t think he has left alone, he has never being alone sleeping but his elder brother
he has been at home, he has not been alone at home.
-Do you smoke cigarettes?
-No.
-According to you what they say, in the class he is in the normal class? In the school he
should be in class 9 and he is in class 8 or back or forward?
-He is forward.
-So in the school they say he is quite intelligent. And you are happy about that?
-Yes.
-In mathematics when he was smaller he got one class higher.
-He likes mathematics. Do you play in theater plays? Do you like it?
-No.
-You are shy, you don’t want to appear in front of the public?
-But here you are doing very well. You seem to enjoy, no problem.
-They ask if he was nervous before all this and he said, I don’t think about it.
-He was not nervous.
You want to ask me some questions?
-No.
-Why, are you afraid of me?
-But you don’t have any question.
-He has one tooth that is not coming out. It isn’t there, it’s missing.
-That’s why he has to close his tooth.
-Yes.
-Except of the insulin which he takes now, you give him other medication regularly?
-No.
-If he gets an acute, who treats him?
-Now I did. When he gets something in his childhood I gave him Phos. but I think I’m not
so good, maybe I go to other homeopath and he gives another one but that’s new and he has not
had acute after that. But I ask if I can give him Phos.
-Can you describe his character?
-He is very gentle and helpful and I don’t have a problem with him because he does what
I like.
-What you like.
-Yes.
-He is not naughty?
-No.
-If you tell him, stop playing football he will come in and stop?
-Yes. He has very good humor. He is joking with me when I say come.
-What does he say?
-He doesn’t make problems, he never make problems. When he was a little boy he was
around the house, he never go away, he was always playing just outside the house and
I was not never afraid of him because he was not and me on the house.
If he does something we don’t like, if my husband is angry on him he doesn’t like that,
then he got angry.
-Then how he reacts, when he gets angry?
-He smashes the door or he won’t speak to us, go to his room and won’t speak.
-He closes the door and doesn’t want any contact.
-Yes.
-If you try to console him and say come on, he doesn’t like, he says leave me alone?
-Like this, strong?
-Yes.
-Do you sit under the sun? Do you like it or you don’t like it?
-Not too much.
-Why? It makes you tired or headache?
-Nothing happens so he doesn’t want to lie under the sun. He wants something to
happen.
-Action? He needs action?
-Yes.
-Do you have any pains, any suffering somewhere?
-No.
-In stomach sometimes.
-Pain in digestion?
-Pain here in the abdomen.
-His stool is normal?
-Yes.
-He says yes, I don’t know.
-You don’t have diarrhea? -No.
-Stool formed? –Yes.
-And you are a very good boy, according to you, you are good?
-Yes.
-And your brother? –Too.
-They are equally good or not so good? What would you say about your children?
-For me all are…
-All of them are obedient, like him?
-No, he is special in that. He and the sister for me. He has a sister too.
-And himself and the sister…
-Yes but mostly him.
-Do you like both your parents, mother and father the same or more you like one?
-The same.
-But your father if he says something, then you become irritable, your mother said.
Do you understand what I ask? Is it true?
-I think it’s because his father is pressing me more direct, more than me, I go around
all the time. I always if something is wrong.
-In your family or his father family there is any diabetes?
-Only the father, he has diabetes when he was 32. He got the same type when he was 32
and that’s very seldom.
-So both they receive insulin?
-Yes but nobody else in the family.
-In your family your parents are alive? –Yes.
-His parents?
-Only the mother. The father died from heart attack and it’s a lot of heart attack in that
family. The mother has angina.