Uta, I want to ask her why she is so emotional, she is crying so much?
-First of all I’m very ashamed that I was crying so much when I was here the last time
and left such a bad impression. I’m not always like that.
Second, I always come in such state if I come in touch with certain traumas in my life.
But I would like to start telling you how I felt after receiving Causticum because in the
meantime I can stop this trembling a bit.
I received Causticum on May 18th and I took it in the evening.
In the night afterwards I had a dream which I already told. It was a dream in which I cleared
things with people from my past, who injured me physically and emotionally.
I also dreamt the following nights very often and very frequently I was dealing with
these issues.
During the day I often had strong stomach pains like stones were in there.
You know this fairytale with the wolf and the 7 goats, when the wolf eats stones?
Like that.
I had dizziness or vertigo sometimes and I was in a bad mood which I don’t have
very often.
On my trip back home I was extremely nauseous, it was so bad that I would never have
been able to manage this trip alone. I was very dizzy in my head and my male friend and
my dear female friend who was also here in this course, they really pulled me through
this whole trip.
Then in the airplane I noticed that the strangers who they were travelling with me and
whom I saw in the lounge and then on the plane, that I didn’t like them all, not anyone of them.
I had extreme sense of smell, I was very sensitive to odors, I noticed many kinds of body
odors, also of perfumes and food smell and it was so disgusting that I could hardly
breathe.
-She is describing now the way back home, right?
-Yes those are the main points concerning the trip home.
At home I felt well again. In my own house I feel well. For me it’s like my third skin.
One week after returning home, I got a cold with pains in my throat and coryza.
I never have fever, also not this time but I was perspiring strong.
The secretion I had from my nose was watery and very acrid. It wounded everything
around my nose. This acrid discharge kept on for weeks, even after the cold and the
actual coryza had gone. Then the throat pains went away.
I often had dreams of former situations from my childhood, just let me say the facts first.
About 5 weeks after Causticum the pains begun. First on my right arm and the pains feel
as if the arm was broken or if as I would have been beaten very severely.
All the weeks afterwards the pains were very strong but they were wandering.
-To different places?
-First on my right side, wrist, arm, shoulder joint but alternating, not at the same time.
The pains are worse at night, I often can’t fall asleep due to the pains.
-The pains still continue?
-Yes and when I do fall asleep I wake again often between 3-4 o’clock in the morning
also due to the pains. Some nights I can not go back to sleep then and then I have to get
up and do something which makes the pains more tolerable.
Now that I have to close one more button on my shirt I feel so warm, heat is also a big
problem.
About 6- 7 weeks after taking Causticum I developed cracks on the corner of my mouth
first on the left side, they lasted for a week until they healed, then on the right side which
continued for 2-3 days and then it was over.
During this entire time I constantly had this acrid discharge from the nose, which was
hurting the surrounding area.
-The discharge was only from one nostril?
-Mainly on the right side. Sometimes also left but most of the times from the right nostril.
The pains were wandering. At first was the right shoulder and later on they moved down
to my left leg; the entire leg and also my hip. I could not sleep.
When I was lying quietly the pains were absolutely unbearable. Also when I was sitting
to write something or to do mental work, I could not sit long. I had to get up and move
my leg.
-With movement in the beginning it was bad and then eventually got better or
immediately with the movement got better?
-In the leg the movement ameliorated it immediately. Sometimes when I was sitting and
wanted to write it was enough just to move my leg away or I would get up and walk
around with the book, in front of me and then I could also read.
Now at the moment the pains are worse in my right shoulder joint.
For a certain period of time the pains were also strong in my hip joints, more on the
right side than on the left.
The pains then were so severe that I already was thinking that I might have a tumor
on the bones. In those times I went through my entire life and I was checking whether
I had settled my affairs so in case I would die my daughter would not have so many
problems with what I leave.
Then I asked myself which tasks in this life I have not yet completed and I found out
it’s many; so I decided I’m not going to die, I’ll stay.
-With this reaction, she is going to live very long.
-I think I told you the main points, if I go through these pages, I have just written pages
pain, pain, pain. The stomach pains reappeared again and again, always for 1-2 days.
I felt stronger mentally. In the time before I came here, before I got the remedy I had
a growing feeling of weakness, of forgetting things, of deteriorating in a way, as if my life
energy was being used up, was leaving.
This weakness has only reoccurred at certain times, not so often and I think then it is
explainable that it was due to much work and night shifts and not sleeping much.
I also felt stronger towards my mother who lives on the same piece of land with me in her
own small house. I can put up barriers more easily now, just to say OK up to here
no further.
12-14 weeks after Causticum I also had digestive problems which lasted about 1 week
with strong bloatedness and the flatulence had a very strong smell and during that time it was
better if I stayed in my house alone.
About 12-15 weeks after Causticum I developed a kind of vulvitis and vaginitis, I had pain
for excoriations, a kind of inflammatory. This lasted for about 4 days and during this
time I was so bruised and I had such pains that I was walking like a captain
wide legs and I couldn’t ride a bicycle.
-Did she have in the past vaginitis?
-Yes I once had it and if it’s important I can look it up now when it was.
-Yes it is important.
-About 6 years ago. Then I received Kreosotum and afterwards it was gone.
This time of course I took nothing.
-Very good. This is the time, I can just say during the cold she could have taken
Arsenicum or something else, or Allium sepa and if she had the vaginitis, she would
have taken again Kreosotum and just finish the whole reaction. That’s the idea.
Once she understands that of course, she goes through and that is when we can
have the results.
-Yes I understood completely and I behaved accordingly.
But I also understood that my homeopathic treatment which lasted for 10 years
exactly it was always making this mistake. It was a process where I kept receiving
remedies for certain disorders, which ameliorated for short time and then the complains
reappeared in a different way.
-Exactly and it was deeper and deeper the whole issue of course, as she grew older
and the resistance became less.
Because if you remember when she gave us the list of remedies, it was more than
50 remedies.
-No it wasn’t 50 but the problem was that my homeopath she didn’t want to tell me
what I received. So I only could retrieve it by going through all my diaries, retracing it
and some I just couldn’t find out.
-But this exactly is what happens in everybody who is practicing Homeopathy at this
moment, apart from that School. Everybody else is practicing, you have a badge of
symptoms, you just take this remedy and finish with the symptoms.
-I also developed itching on my back. Only my cervical and upper thoracic region
It was so strong and unbearable that I constantly had to scratch.
But now it’s gone too.
A sensation in my life happened. When I travelled here to Alonissos in September
As long as I can remember my entire life I always was nauseous when I was in
movement, in motion, being either in a bus or being a passenger in a car, not when
I’m driving myself but as a passenger.
As a child also I could not go on a swing and the worse to be was on a boat.
And this time nothing. Not once.
-I’m just checking whether Causticum has nausea. Very interesting.
-And I tested it again this Sunday. I took a boat trip, on a small boat and again nothing.
Half a century I was always nauseous.
-So she went back half a century. She is suffering a lot now.
-I prefer not to. I never want to go back to this time, never ever.
-She still has to tell us the dream.
-I have strong heat flashes. It had already started a bit before I took Causticum and
I think it has to do with my climacteric period but after Causticum it got stronger
really violent.
-She has become in general more warm, apart from the heat flashes?
-Yes. Sometimes it becomes a problem because I have these attacks of perspiration and
then my skin and my clothes are wet but I can not tolerate cold moist clothing on my skin.
To me it seems, looking at it very carefully, it seems as if I have a bit reduced fears in
some areas but I’m still experimenting with that.
For example with the motorbike I would really like to ride a motorbike and I bought
one for myself at home but I can’t ride it because I have such fears and panic attacks.
It’s as if already I could foresee what could happen to me, so I have these images, I see
myself lying on the ground, smashed and even though nothing happens, I just see it.
In these imaginations, these pictures I have from the accidents, the worse part of it
is the crash and the pain because I’m very sensitive to pain.
In the past, one and a half week that I’m here, I have had the opportunity to go alone on
a motorbike with other people for which I thank them very much because for me that’s
already a sensational and experience to be able to try out.
-Did she use to go on a motorbike in younger age?
-No. I never went on a motorbike in my life. I only learned how to ride a bicycle when I
was 30 years old and that already was connecting with a lot of fears and anxieties.
Now I ride a bicycle without problems.
-What she was talking was a motorbike? When she said I feel... when I ride the
motorbike, was a motorbike or a bicycle?
-I bought a motorbike but I don’t dare driving it.
-But now she had a motorbike herself here?
-Two years ago I had a motorbike here on the island and I had been taking driving
lessons before that because I want to get rid of the fears, I want to deal with them, I want
to confront myself but it’s not possible.
I still have fear sitting behind somebody on a motorbike but I realize now I can deal with
the fact I’m riding with different people and different speeds.
-I understand now.
-And this fear of drowning I can also control better now. For many years in the past
I had this feeling that if I should ever get my head under water, I’m going to drown.
And during the last 10 years I’ve been working on this problem and try to reduce the fear
bit by bit and now on Alonissos I have been swimming for long passages with my head
under the water like a fish and it was great.
-I want to ask a few things concerning her desires for food. Still desire for salt?
-I still have desire for salt but not as extreme.
-Has she developed desire perhaps for sweets now? She eats more sweets?
-Not more than before, I don’t eat many sweets but what I love in the afternoon is a cup
of tea with two cookies.
-What about smoked meat?
-I can not eat any meat at all, nothing and I can’t eat any food that has only been
standing near smoked meat; I can’t eat that even. Absolutely disgusting.
It’s the same with coffee. I have absolute intolerance of coffee.
I can’t feel well even in a room when somebody is cooking coffee.
About 30 years ago I was drinking much coffee. I had many night shifts, I was in
the night watch, I always was very tired but I had to work a lot at nights and I couldn’t
sleep during the day and I was just poring very strong coffee into me, while walking
all the time. Then all of a sudden one day I couldn’t tolerate coffee anymore and since
-Aversion to coffee.
Can she tell the dream now?
-The current dreams deal with issues of my childhood. Every time is the same issue.
The content of the dreams are such that humiliate me; it has to do with the experiences
I made with my grandmother who was deeply convinced that I am bad from the very
root upwards. Even when I was a very small child and she had thought or made up
special punishment measures for me.
-Punishment measure? That means she would punish her according to her behavior?
-I actually never really understood what she punished me for. I always was like why?
What did I do? I didn’t do anything, I always was so good. And she always said, shut up
don’t contradict, don’t ask. So I could never really inquire what this was for?
And if I said, I didn’t do anything, she said, if you didn’t do anything today, it is for what
you did yesterday and for what you will do tomorrow.
It was inevitably every day and I knew it will come every day except I didn’t know when
so I could never really prepare for it. I was just shaking because I knew some time
somehow I’m going to get it.
I had to prepare for my punishments myself. She set me out into the garden where
I had to cut twigs from a tree and bring them in the house and I had to fill a jug with
water and wet the twigs. And I can’t tell, I can’t say.
I don’t want to say, I want to get away from it. I don’t want again and again to catch up
with me. It keeps catching up with me. I also was never allowed to cry.
Nothing was never permitted to go to the outside. We were proper family.
And that’s also a problem I have with my mother because she knew about these things
but she tolerated it, she never protected me. Even today when we talk about it, she still
is convinced, it’s her opinion that what my grandmother did, was correct.
That is was right.
It has led to repeated collapses in the past years because still I can not understand why
my family has treated me in this way.
-She was treated in total injustice.
-You can put it that way and my grandmother forced me after she punished me to kneel
down to kneel down in front of the twigs and to kiss them and to thank them that she is
going through the effort of making me a good person, that she put that upon herself
to turn me into a good person.
-Jesus.
-I would like to stop now because it’s really pulling me down.
-But she does not have to be afraid of these memories because they maybe very
traumatic and very hurting but she has to deal with this issue and understand that this
was not her fault and cry and eventually maybe she will be able to forgive.
It’s a big issue of course but it is too obvious that it was total injustice done to her and all
her problems which developed after that, were because of that behavior.
-I know but I’ve cried already so much and it just doesn’t stop and every time I come
close to these issues I collapse.
-But she will have to do it. She can not avoid the issue. She will have to let herself cry
cry, cry and it will be a time when this detoxification will take place, the catharsis, the
detoxification of the system. And through this, she will regain much more strength and
concentration and abilities.
-Only 12 people were crying. She went out to shout. I don’t have to say many things.
What I may say as a prediction of how this case is going.
First of all we can see that she is going away from Causticum.
That means Causticum is acting and changing the symptomatology.
It is a different case than the previous one.
Most probably she will need another remedy in the future, we’ll see. That is one thing.
The symptoms are changing and most probably we should not concentrate in repeating
the remedy but rather going into a complementary, like Staphysagria or whatever
Colocynthis, it will depend.
But I would like to make a prediction with the constitution of Causticum.
But before going to the constitution, it is very interesting that the constitution was formed
actually by injustice.
I mean total injustice. You can imagine. This grand mother must have been sick person.
Hating, with a lot of hatred inside. She was taking it out on the child.
-Imagine her child.
-Most probably she has been treated it in a similar manner, maybe.
-Causticum must fight.
-Throw a bomb also but you see here the different phases. You see also the
individuality. Though we perceive general trends on remedies, we see the individual
expression of these trends.
Here she can not tolerate injustice but injustice has been imposed on her and has
produced state of Causticum.
-I think I have got the impression that is not so much the injustice she has suffered from
but it’s humiliation. It’s the strongest feeling she has. These diagonal pains which also
has, she takes a remedy, perhaps Staphysagria or Lac Caninum.
-Yes. Staphysagria is a possibility, that’s correct. But when she described and she said
“warum?” that is really the injustice and she does not understand why she is punished.
Then of course she is humiliated as well but mortification, humiliation Causticum comes
as well as a strong remedy for this.
You see also in this case what I have said many times. Prescribe one remedy, take away
reaction is the vaginitis it comes.
Are you going to give a remedy? No. Unless it is life threatening.
If it life threatening, you can not say no. You just try to save the life of the patient.
But in this case, never. You let it develop and now you see, the complains are mostly
on the physical body where she complains about these terrific pains.
The pains are so strong now, she is thinking maybe I have cancer. So the complain
is there while at the same time at the emotional side, a catharsis is taking place.
Come back, again and again and she cries and cries and she will be crying.
That is very good, don’t bother about anything. What is even more important is when
she is able to say to her mother, that’s enough, up to here, I can ‘t tolerate.
The defenses of the body were destroyed by the grand mother.
She said, she had no limits. The grand mother felt no resistance from the child.
The mother is going to feel the resistance. I have enough, just keep to your place.
That is very good reaction and what you expect the best to happen out of this
Where now she has this, she has on the hips; eventually it will locate on the finger joints.
She is going to have all the disturbance that took place all these years, concentrating
upon the joints and in particular the joints of the fingers.
You expect these joint pains to calm down and locate themselves into the fingers.
-Why?
-Because Causticum in particular affects finger joints. And then you will have to decide
whether you repeat Causticum or you give whatever remedy etc.
But don’t interfere with the process.
For instance, you see she is trembling, she is so much loaded with emotions.
Why don’t we give a remedy to stop that. It’s wrong. This is a good reaction.
Like you say the eczema is weeping.
Why don’t we give a remedy to stop the weeping of the eczema?
Which remedies have weepings? Mezereum, Graphites… just give Graphites.
The whipping will stop. It will dry up the eczema.
But then it starts again the problem inside. You see the difference?
-How long you think the pains will go on?
-For years.
I don’t know if we will be able to cure the pains completely. I’m not sure.
But also you will see a resurrection of the emotional side.
All these emotions which are emotions that remember the traumas, once it’s over
she will be rejuvenated emotionally. She will be like a child again.
She will come back to the childhood. This woman will have emotions like a child.
This is what is happening. That’s why I fight. This is not Homeopathy, what you are
doing; you have to do it in the right way; you have to understand and then I fight
and I fight. Why? Because finally I feel it’s so tiring but it is worth it.
And many times you have seen me totally exhausted; still I continue.
I say still it’s worth it because it is the only way that humanity can go through a
catharsis.
Humanity is very sick. We have made ourselves very sick and there is a
possibility of that catharsis and nobody wants to use it. It’ s too difficult.
They cant’ do it. No, it’s not too difficult. It can be done!
-Do you think there is a connection, she has been punished very badly and
she knows these cramps and pains in joints and extremities, as if she was
punished. Do you feel that is the connection between that?
-Yes, what she says, my bones are broken. She exactly describes the symbolic
effect of the hit of the grandmother. Of course she describes the same thing.
And she has to go through. And the organism, the defense mechanism brings it
down now to the physical body and only to the physical. She is going to suffer a lot
with the pains, excruciating pains and we have to watch and say, wait, wait.
It’s unbelievable but what can you do? There is no way to get away.
There is no case, I can assure you, in the West that can go through just like that
a traumatic experience of that type. There is no way, under no circumstances.
Never mind what they say, magic, herbs, acupuncture, whatever.
The process is painful, if it is correct it’s going to be painful.
But painful on less and less deeper levels, more external.
-She even said that the pain she has is like beaten. She even said this.
-Yes broken like I was beaten. Of course she was beaten in mental level but the
defense mechanism is taking this memory and brings it down to the physical body.
More and more.
If you remember in the first time I said, get into the essential, don’t be lost in
details, you will lose the remedy. Who was in the first consultation?
Everybody was here? Was somebody who was not in the first consultation?