-After Ignatia I desire more fruits but it started 7-8 weeks after
and I also got back a strong desire for alcohol, so I was drinking every day
for about a month.
This problem with my spine is very big because there is a curve and the hips are rotated
I have a lot of pain in connection with that, the osteoporosis has been worse
for the last year.
-Did you check it?
-I checked it.
-How? By X-ray?
-Yes and I was hopeful thinking that will be better because of taking several remedies
but I was very depressed after that.
-Are you sure he was a good X-ray, he gave you the right examination?
Because it’s not so easy to see it.
-He compared to the first one and he saw the difference.
After Medorrhinum I have been extra sensitive to voices and noises, very annoying,
so I isolated very much.
I had a period when I had as if the kidneys were swollen and pains in the kidneys.
-How do you know they are in the kidneys and not in the lumbar region?
-I had pyelonephritis before, so I recognized the pain.
I postpone everything, very much, so I’m always late, always in a hurry
and it’s like an aversion to think and work.
-And make decisions.
-Yes, because of this fatigue.
I took a lot of antibiotics when I was younger because of the pyeloneprhitis
and a lot of cystitis and last year I have a lot of falling out of hair.
And the menses I got back some PMS problems after Ignatia, I had earlier.
-The premenstrual which is exactly? You are angry, irritable or weepy before menses?
-More the pains.
-Pain and swelling of breast.
-And I do have a lot of stitching, burning pains in the glands and they are very indurated.
-Have you been in a specialist?
-They took an X-ray and they cannot tell much because it is so indurated,
so it’s hard to see. But the pain is like being stung by a bee.
A lot of my pains are like that smarting and the menses stop when I lie down, always did.
-When you lie down the menses stop and then continue?
-Yes.
-That means, if you sleep the whole night they stop and you had it your whole life?
-Lilium Tigrinum, Pulsatilla, Silica…
Do you have a prolapse of the uterus?
-No, I don’t think so.
I’m still very depressed.
-Other? You said everything?
-I’m not sure, it’s just chaos.
After these dreams it was like a therapeutic thing because I’m not so hateful
towards myself anymore and I stopped biting the nails.
Before I was like scratching and wounds in my hand, I had it for 20 years.
-And you don’t bite your nails?
-Not anymore but I did for 42 years, so I feel all this aggressiveness
and the hate towards myself is better.
-It is released.
-So I think that’s important.
-I think it’s good, don’t give all the information because everybody will know your remedy.
-Tell us what happened? What was the last remedy that you had and what happened?
-I got Ignatia 200 in September but I got Medorrhinum after that.
-And you got Medorrhinum when?
-I wrote you because of sleeplessness mostly and I was told to take Medorrhinum 200.
-What date?
-I took it in middle of December.
-Did you write to me?
-I wrote to Angy.
-And you said mostly I have sleeplessness. Tell me after Ignatia what happened?
-This grief with this young boy that I have been for 2 years, it slowly faded.
So it was good, I had some relief and I noticed the sighing has been better.
And immediately after taking Ignatia I got very much hunger, increased appetite.
For warm food especially and I was craving a lot of sweets and I gained 6-7 kilos.
-You like it?
-Not really.
I have to buy new clothes and I was eating a lot of different things
that I don’t normally do, so I had a lot of digestive problems coming up.
-What did you eat?
-Everything but meat I don’t eat.
-Continue, what else have you done?
-The feeling of hurry was prominent after Ignatia, I was very restless and in hurry.
And I think I wrote that also because you read the whole letter I wrote  to Angy,
so I think it was several more things, not just sleeping problems.
-You don’t have a copy of this letter?
-No.
-Angy must have one.
-I felt more exhaustion and fatigue and this got more strong but I don’t think
I told you last time, maybe I didn’t explain how strong really is, the chronic fatigue.
It’s been more than 20 years and I don’t think it came through enough
and this got worse and worse.
-What got worse?
-This fatigue.
After being in a hurry for several weeks, when I came home I tried like clean up
all this chaos that were in my house and I tried to get myself to do a lot of things
and after 2 weeks I was also caput, exhausted completely.
-And you started not being able to sleep?
-Yes.
That started almost immediately after but sleeping problems has been a big issue my whole life,
but I had been better maybe 3-4 years I’ve been able to be well without sleeping pills and before that
I had it for almost 20 years, I had been on sleeping pills.
So it was a little bit better but now it came back very strong, so I can sleep about 2 hours
and then that’s was it, I can not go back. So it’s exhaustion, it’s worse and worse.
So after a month, I wrote this letter.
-And then I told you to take Medorrhinum. What happened after Medorrhinum?
-The sleep problems got even worse but it changed a little bit, so I did not wake up
after 2 hours, I could sleep up to 4 hours, from 1 to 4 hours but it was such a restlessness.
So it was not 4 hours, I wake up all the time and with pains like cystitis and urithritis.
So I had to run from 6-7 to 15 times to urinate.
-In the night?
-Yes.
-For how long it lasted this?
-It was almost 7-8 weeks.
So it has been 4 months now with the sleep problems, I was very exhausted,
almost feeling I’m going crazy. I can not take anymore but I took no sleeping pills,
I was drinking some alcohol.
-What about now? The sleeping pattern is it better?
-After 6-7 weeks it got a little better but the restlessness is there
and I’ve been having so many nightmares.
And also I had these compulsive thoughts, I was tormenting with a lot of compulsive thoughts.
-Like?
-Things came up, a lot of emotional things, that has been there but it got so strong,
so extreme, everything got so extreme.
-What were the thoughts?
Do you want to say?
-It was like a religious despair.
-Whether you had made a sin?
-I felt guilty of a crime.
-Your mind went to a specific action of yours or it was abstract?
-No, this fatigue makes me not able to do anything, so it’s like throwing my life away.
-But why do you have guilt feelings? Because you are fatigued?
-Yes.
-Are you sure?
-By now I should be able to heal myself.
-How can you heal yourself? It’s easy to say. To heal myself is a big word.
-But…
-Anyhow can you tell me the nightmares, what was the content of the nightmares?
Do you remember? If you don’t want to say something, you can say I don’t like to say.
-I think it’s important to say.
It was mostly being pursued, I have to run away from something, trying to escape from something
and it was so strong because I’ve been writing down my dreams for 10 years
and I usually remember but not like these.
It was so intense, so vivid, so I could have 4-5 dreams every night.
-And all these dreams were nightmares, were frightening?
-Most of them. A lot of them was about sexual abuse in my childhood that came up
seemed to be like suppressed things.
The fatigue got very… These dreams have such an impact on me.
I felt so weak, I can not stand on my legs, I just want to lie in this position and put the cover.
I was nauseous for several days after these dreams.
-After Medorrhinum you mean?
-After the dreams.
-But the dreams, the main theme was sexual abuse and somebody is trying to
come after you or to get you?
-Yes and I try everything to escape, I wake up screaming no, no, no and throwing
with a terrible pain in my neck and I have a headache from that.
-Do you remember scenes from childhood or you have suppressed them?
-I don’t remember anything from my childhood, everything is black up to 15-16 and
mostly after 18. Before 18 I don’t remember much.
-Even now, after the remedy?
-After the remedies I have some flashbacks and I have some things coming up that
I suddenly feel I’m baby again, a child again. It’s weird, I want teddy bears.
-You want protection?
-Yes protection and I sit a lot like rocking.
-Why do you think you feel like that? Do you know? Why you want protection,
you feel like a baby, do you know why?
-Not really but I always felt that I want to manage myself, never seeking that protection.
-And now you feel that need for protection, now?
-Somehow when these incidents come up, I went to bed one night and I felt suddenly
I could not move, I felt I was this baby, I was looking around and trying to get away
from something, it was just a shadow I could not see and after that I just cried and cried.
This is something I feel I don’t want to touch.
-You don’t want the experience again.
-No, I can talk about it but I feel mentally I can but to take the emotions is difficult.
-It’s painful. Do you want to cry now? Do you have the tendency to cry?
-More before I started. And every time somebody wants to kill me and I run and run and people
want to kill me and I get wounded and even if I’m wounded I’m limping and people come after me.
And a lot of dreams when I’m a child, a little girl with all kinds of things done to me,
just seeing a face with a big wound and things like that, mutilating things.
So I don’t want to go to sleep because I’m thinking what is coming up now,
what do I have to face tonight.
-The nightmares are every day?
-Yes but since I came here I slept so little, so I had no hardly any dreams this time
because I hardly sleep.
-What else do you have in your notes?
-I also had an increase of this animal thing, all kind of tormenting the same compulsiveness
came with that, I always had this love for animals but now it was so compulsive all the time
for day and night for several weeks and so it faded and after that it’s gone better.
-So it was a love of animals for a period of time?
-I always love but after Medorrhinum this came so strong and all these things I have to
take small flies who go in the water and they lie there, I have to save them and I take them up
and blow them, all the time.
At my home there are a lot of frogs and I can hardly drive the cars because
I don’t want to kill them, a lot of things like that.
-But now it’s not so strong anymore this sensitivity.
-It’s there but it’s not this compulsiveness and the same with this despair I have
with this religious. It was very strong for some weeks but now it faded, so now it’s better.
I sensed that I had more fears.
-What kind?
-About dogs.
I had a little before but now I freeze, big dogs, aggressive ones and fear of heights is stronger
because I didn’t have so much anxiety and fears before.
-From high places you didn’t mind before, almost.
-Not so much, a little bit, but now fears.
-What other fears?
-Of talking in public and to people, more afraid of people and of suffocation,
especially underneath the water I feel like I don’t have breath.
-Did you swim while you are here, did you swim at all?
-Very fast, just once a little bit. I love the sea, I want to dive but I’m afraid to go underneath
because I don’t feel that I can breathe.
I think that’s it. Another thing I didn’t mention last time, it has become a little stronger.
It’s a pressure in the head and behind the eyes when I’m ascending, if I stares here.
-Like a headache?
-No.
It’s like a lot of blood in the head and dizziness and disturbed vision and I have to stop.
I can hear the pulse and palpitation in the ear, very exhausted.
After Medorrhinum I had a couple of warts, small ones, in here but very small
and a couple of others I have here got a little bigger, moles are changing and itching.
I got back some pain in the right ovary that I had a lot years back
but it was just for a short while.
-You had some stitching pain there.
-And sometimes I’m so exhausted after eating.
-You eat much more now.
-Yes.
-Do you still have the aggravation from sugar?
-Yes, still there.
The aggravation is still there.
-As much as it was before or less?
-I’m not quite sure because if I eat a lot of sugar the reaction is not that strong
but if I don’t anything and take sugar, then the reaction is very strong as well.
-If you take only sugar. Other sweets do you take?
Chocolates?
-Yes.
-No reaction?
-Yes, all sweets.
-Also you had diarrhea from emotional excitement, do you remember?
-No, I don’t remember I told you but yes that is true, I can have that.
I’m much better in fresh air, I can not stand stuffy rooms, the feeling
of not having enough oxygen… but I don’t think I told you so much last time
about I had an injury in my head and the whole spine in 1985 and I fell down 2,5 meters
on rocks and I hit my head and the spine.
-You were in the hospital?
-No.
-You took no medicines?
-I took some pain killers but it didn’t work, the chiropractor didn’t want to touch me
because he said that’s too serious.
-So you stayed in bed?
-Yes, it was terrible for years.
-What did you have? Pains?
-Yes, especially in the neck.
-But you have told us last time that you have a headache in the occiput.
Is that what you mean?
-The headache in the occiput usually comes when I have this headache, when that is aggravated.
-And when this pain is aggravated?
-Very much during sleep and from the nightmares, as if I’m fighting all night.
-How about the coldness on feet?
-It’s still there or your feet are warm now?
-I had a period where it was a little bit warmer but I’m still cold, easily clammy.
-Easily perspire on foot?
-Yes.
-In general you feel cold?
-Yes, definitely. I have 2 big blankets and I use 2 wool blankets and socks,
I’m really freezing cold.
-You use some heat in your room or no heat?
-I turn the heat off during the night because it gets too stuffy.
-And here with this weather you use blankets in the night?
-3 blankets.
-And your feet are still cold, you wear socks?
-Yes but I had some flashes of heat in the night after Medorrhinum.
I wanted to stick the feet out for a short time but then I had to put them back.
So I get very aggravated to take the cover off, even though I am warm.
-You have to be careful because easily you get cold.
-Yes and especially if I sit still, I can get warmer and perspire very easily
if I have to walk a little bit and even slow walk but if I have to sit or lie down, I get cold.
-And if you walk you perspire immediately?
-Very easy. But I feel heat in my head usually, the head is warm and I want it cooler.
-You need the head cooler.
-Yes.
-Are you very fastidious?
-These memory problems I think got worse after the injury to my head.
The memory problem is not any better but I feel better with the confusion, a little bit.
-Maybe.
-But still difficult to concentrate, I can even push myself very hard.
-How is your menses?
-The menses after Ignatia was delayed a little bit and it was even more scanty
and it’s only 1 day.
-How they are now?
-About the same.
-Scanty with clear blood or black?
-Clear blood.
-How is your thirst?
-I drink quite a lot.
I used to drink very little before but it was after some remedy, 2 years ago I took Arsenicum
and after that my thirst was increased but I’m not quite sure.
The last couple of years I’ve been drinking much more than I did before.
I never drink much before and I drink during the night. I have to have a glass of water.
-How many times you wake up now for urination during night?
-While I’m here I’m not drinking so much, hardly at all. 3,4,6.
-But yes you are not sleeping, you get up from 2-6 times?
-Yes, 3-4 times.
-You want to do things, you are still in a hurry, this hurried feeling is less now?
-No, I think it’s still there.
-It’s still there but it’s less or it’s the same?
-It’s a little bit less than after I took Ignatia.
In the beginning of Ignatia this hurriedness was very strong.
-But before Ignatia you have said, you had this hurried feeling which we had underlined 3 times
before Ignatia. Now how it is?
-I think it’s better.
When this religious despair and this animal thing and these emotional things got better,
this hurriedness also got better.
-Desire for sweets, how much, how strong?
-I would put 3.
-That means you prefer to eat sweets than food.
-If I’m hungry it’s faster. If I’m very hungry it’s very fast, I eat something sweet.
-Yes but it’s different. Give me an idea how many sweets you take every day.
-I can easily eat the whole chocolate and I put lots of sugar in the tea.
-How much?
-4-5 or 6 spoons.
-And you say you have an aggravation from sugar and you take all this sugar.
Are you sure you take all this sugar?
-I try not to do every day but…
-How many times you will have a tea in a day? A tea with 4-5 spoons?
-2 times but I have an aggravation from tea so I try not to drink tea,
so I’ve been eating less sugar lately.
-But that’s what I’m asking and you say you eat so much. What is the less?
-I have a problem with my memory, it’s very confused.
-It’s OK but you can remember today did you eat sugar, yes or no?
-Today I had 2 cups of tea with a lot of sugar.
-So you take a lot of sugar. But in spite of taking so much sugar,
you don’t have so much the aggravation from sugar, it seems to me.
-A little less I think but the digestive problems are still there from sugar.
I feel a lot of fermentation and distention, bloatedness from sugar.
-From sugar alone, not from other food?
-Yes, from most food.
-Why don’t you say so far?
You have this bloatedness in a particular time or it can be morning, afternoon, evening?
-No, it’s not a particular time.
-It can be any time and there are some other times when you don’t have the bloatedness.
-No, it’s always there.
-Do you have a lot of gas?
-It’s better but it’s still there.
-Eructations?
-I had a lot before but these are also better.
-Did you ever take Calcarea carbonica before?
-Yes one time and I slept better and this wearing socks and clammy feet was much better.
-When did you take Calc carb, do you remember?
-About 3 years ago.
-What was the potency?
-200 I think.
After Medorrhinum I had some stitching pains in my heart that I had before
but it comes and goes.
-Did you get any acute during that period, any cold, bronchitis?
-No.
-The tiredness at this moment, let us say when you are here, you are not sleeping
how much it is? It’s strong tiredness or in spite of the fact that you don’t sleep
the tiredness in not so excessive?
-No, the tiredness is not better.
-When you sleep do you perspire during sleep?
-Sometimes.
-Where?
-On the back.
-Head?
-Not so much. It’s more like a flush of heat.
-Do you turn left, right?
-I can not sleep on the left side.
-Why?
-Palpitation in the heart immediately.
But I think I feel much more tense after Medorrhinum I think.
-Inner tension?
-Inner tension and also the whole body feels much more stiff.
-Tensing means stiff or cramped?
-Stiff or cramped, I can not relax but after the dreams somehow I felt a kind of freedom.
-Did you analyze your dreams or did you think about your dreams?
-Yes, I did a lot because it was so strong so I could hardly let go.
-Did you connect them with this abuse that you had as a child?
-Yes.
How is she doing?
Do you remember why she came to be treated and how she tried to remember to say something
but the confusion, I was terrified with the confusion.
If we play back the case for those who remember, we will see a tremendous
confusion on mental level.
This was the main thing and where the prescription was targeting, on the mental confusion
and tremendous mental weakness.
Do we have the same mental weakness or now we have a physical weakness?
More she complains about physical weakness.
She responded immediately, she gave clear answers. Only 1 time she said, I can’t remember
but it was not.
For me that I know a little bit more I don’t want to say but this is another reason why she said,
I don’t remember, it doesn’t matter but she said it only once.
In the beginning she kept on saying, I don’t remember, I don’t remember.
-Even her eyes look very different from last time.
Last time she was a little bit in a hurry and she didn’t know where to look
and now she was communicating.
-So what we should perceive is the confusion and the lack of energy on the mental level
going away and of course we have some work to do with her. The lack of energy
is still on the physical level with her, quite a lot but together with this change,
what else is important that came up? What made an impression for you?
She starts to remember and she starts to remember through dreams, that means something
which is very deep in the subconscious is coming up.
And of course by coming up there are some fears which develop but the fears now
are real fears, a dog, heights.
The case is unfolding, it goes towards the right direction.
This was a complete mental case and now we can say it is mostly physical.
What she complains mostly is this chronic fatigue.
I’d like to discuss with you is why still she does not sleep.
-She said she does not sleep but she is frightened to dream.
-That’s her explanation. Is this full explanation?
-No.
-She is afraid of remembering, it’s a kind of protective mechanism of the body or the organism
and I have a question. Some day with the correct remedy, she will be able to remember
and will she then be in such a state that she will also deal with whatever she remembers?
-Yes. Because we don’t manipulate. We let the organism unfold by the help of health in general.
Therefore when she is ready to face the facts and deal with the facts, she will do it,
without any repercussion.
If you force here, by a kind of force, by psychoanalysis she may have a repercussion,
she will modify the issues but if you let her by herself and with the right remedy,
absolutely she will come to the point where she will remember she will face
and she will find a real solution.
I agree also with you that this is a protective mechanism. She is terrified to remember
what took place in her young age and therefore the dream is the first subconscious,
it’s the first level which pushes to the conscious mind some information, which relates to that.
I asked her, does it relate? She says, yes it’s related. Now if it’s related and it’s so vivid
she will have to face it, she is not ready, why? She is not strong enough.
Why she is not strong enough? We gave the wrong remedy?
-It takes time.
-What shall we do then now? You want to give Nitric acid.
In order to give Nitric acid you have to have some keynotes of Nitric acid.
What are the keynotes for Nit acid in this case?
Anxiety about health is one main point for Nit acid, we don’t see it here.
The urine which smells very heavily like horse, the brittle nails, the cracks,
wherever they may be, the distorted nails.
Stramonium with this case? You have fears, first of all the fears are strong fears,
secondly the main fear for Stramonium is missing. Which is the main fear for Stram.?
-Dark.
-Fear of the dark without which the other fears forget it.
Fears are coming and you are missing the main fear, forget it and the fear of dogs,
she says, big dogs. It’s not a big fear.
Stramonium has big fear and then fear of high places, where is Stramonium and then
and then and the rest is not important.
Don’t take little things like a wart here and there or some little itching or a pressure.
A pressure in the head with hot head and cold feet is Belladonna, it’s not Stramonium.
Why not Belladonna. Stramonium is too violent for her in any case.
So you will see what it is. Show the repertorization.
The flow stops when lying down, yes it is characteristic, she had it also
but this is not enough, the hurried also feeling is there.
You have 2 symptoms of Lilium Tigrinum.
How many symptoms of Lilium tigrinum you found there? Let’s see.
How many of the symptoms are with Lilium tigrinum?
Lil tigr has desire for sweets but Lil tig is on first degree.
She insisted and she persuaded us it’s on the third degree. In haste yes, religious despair yes,
sleeplessness is not a very big thing …open air ameliorates, perspiration on feet,
perspiration clammy, weakness.
It’s not a big remedy for weakness. The remedy is Calcarea carbonica.
She will take a dose of Calcarea carbonica, next time we will see what will be the effect.
There was no symptom against Calc carb.
On the contrary there were a lot of symptoms in favor of Calc carb and keynote symptoms as well,
so you can not ignore this fact and go for another remedy.
Lil tigr is a very good prescription, Helonias also if you read especially when she says
with the least movement I have perspiration, Helonias is a remedy for chronic fatigue syndrome
with perspiration on moving but if you are in despair you give Helonias or you give Lil tigr
but here we are not yet in despair. We have the picture of Calc carb
and quite fully I would say now.
The effect of Calc carb is going to be much more different than it was when she was having this,
this and that remedy. She had taken 59 remedies before, between them Calc carb
and everything else.
-Which potency?
She can go quite high, no problem, 1M.