We start to analyze this very easy case.
Is this a case of Phosphorus?
-No.
-But Phosp. they say it’s doing something. In the groups here, where you will place this
case, in which group?
Who says lowest 3? Who says middle 3? Who says upper 3? Who says upper 4?
Who says middle 4? It’s middle 4. If anybody can cure this case, come and tell me.
Incurable.
Group middle 4, incurable. We can do nothing, very little but it will stay like this, the best.
-It’s already a good sign if it would be possible to keep the units of insulin he has to take
stable for a certain amount of years, which will enable him to maintain his life quality over
a number of years.
-But this is what is going to stay. This is as far as we can go. When he comes on that
state, we cannot do very much. From 14 to 10, then again 12 to 15, then 16, then back.
This kind of reaction you are going to see, why?
Is the remedy clear in this case?
-For me this case taking the remedy is clear. In the very beginning he said something.
He very much loves animals, he is a nice child, always very obedient, even when he
plays outside, he immediately comes in when his mother calls him. The father himself
has diabetes and I would give the child Carcinosin.
-The problem is, is this clear enough? If we had a history of cancer, strong history we
could say… The love of animals also in children you don’t take it as a symptom unless
it’s very strong. Love of animals is OK, most of the children they love animals.
-I heard from Geukens School, a study of Carcinosin, that the history of diabetes also leads to
Carcinosin, not only the history of cancer.
-Yes, that is true but again the reading in children where they are handicapped is an
outlet. Therefore, because they feel handicapped, they go into reading much more.
What do you read, I insisted. Comics. Not something serious, not something where we
usual. Maybe he likes mathematics.
Anyhow also the computer comes up very strongly with Carcinosin and we’re going finally
to prescribe Carcinosin in this case and you will see the results, very poor.
Show me the analysis. Carcinosin and Pulsatilla come quite strong, give explanation for
Pulsatilla. Show me Carcinosin.
-Obedient?
-Obedient is an element of Carcinosin when the child tries to please others. They go
beyond their limits to please others, to please the parents, they try to be loved, to have
affection through this kind of being good.
Which other remedies you were thinking in this case?
-Uranium nitricum.
-Uranium nitricum is a remedy for diabetes, just on pathology.
This case is like autistic children, a part of the brain is gone, it is considered as non
existent, like a kidney which is totally destroyed and is taken out. It’s totally gone and this
you can not consider it as disease. With disease we have a process. A disease has a
kind of inflammation, chronic or acute. It’s a process, it’s something happening all the
time. In these cases we have destruction and it’s finished and then another piece is
destructed and it’s finished. You can do nothing. Of course if you catch it in the very
beginning, you may stop the initial destruction, you may stop it in the beginning.
In that state, no. But what made me a little bit angry was the fact that we could not get
symptoms from the mother. Whatever we asked, she did not know anything and you see
also that in incurable cases we don’t have symptoms. Never mind, here we have a nice
boy and we give Carcinosin, this is actually the case and maybe something will happen
not much.
Now if this case had given us strong symptoms of a remedy, I would say the prognosis
is perhaps different, is perhaps lower 3, I would agree. When you come to this level
different remedies will be required. Phosphorus, every time his nose is open, this is
characteristic of Phosphorus. Phos. is acting, is giving some effect, it does not give a
cure, we do not have the possibility with Homeopathy.
-I have some problems assessing the action of Phos. The mother had reported that the
blood sugar level did go lower, after applying Phos. the only remedy which has this effect
and it’s the chronicity of this disease, so why not repeat Phos?
-Because she has repeated it too many times, the mother has repeated Phos too many
times, so we consider at this moment that Phos has done all it could, keeping that boy in
that “good condition” in which he is now. We try now to see whether we can stimulate the
vital force, the defense mechanism by a next remedy. It is not sure at all that it will give an
effect, that’s what I say.
-Is it not possible that the mother maybe chose the wrong potency that did not have
enough stimulation?
-Yes that’s possible but also I’m hearing that the child is bleeding very easily now.
So how much is because of too much Phos also, I have to think about that.
-I have 1 question in general about diabetes. Before, you said if he would had showed
clear symptoms for a remedy, then you would have given a different prognosis.
Have you ever in your experience seen a case of juvenile diabetes being cured by
Homeopathy?
-No, but all the cases of juvenile diabetes have the same picture, no clear picture.
You search and you find this, some effect, you find another, another effect, you give the
3rd, the 4th gives nothing, you go to a 5th, again a little bit of effect, it’s going like that.
And it is important also you understand these issues and we don’t go outside in the world
and we claim things we can not deliver. Because even if 1 case of juvenile diabetes
maybe it’s cured, it is because that particular case belongs to group 3.
But usually they belong to group 4.
So you have the same pathology but actually it is not the same, the underlined possibility
of the organism is different and sometimes you may see, I haven’t seen cure and when I
say cure, I mean cure, I don’t mean less insulin.
-What do you tell the mother in such a case?
-I’ll tell the mother that we can not cure the child but we will try to keep the child in the best
possible condition; that we can do, with good Homeopathy but to tell, come, I may treat
and I may cure is wrong.
-My question is concerning the prognosis. Would the prognosis have been better, would
have been easier if this child had not had already a genetic determination of the diabetes
of his father?
-Maybe yes but when his father has already the problem and you see it in the child
you can’t say, forget it. Especially when you don’t get a clear picture, no symptoms.
This child is free of symptoms. Never mind, you like chocolate, you like the animals, all
these is a little bit of nonsense in cases like that. Let this insulin out and you will see a
totally different picture, it doesn’t like animals, it doesn’t care about chocolate, he just
lies down in a semi-coma condition. Where is the picture? We don’t have the picture to
work with. The real picture of the disease is covered by the supplement of insulin.
You say nice child, forget it. Take out the insulin and you will see how nice it is and how
much irritable it might be, it might be shouting etc. a totally different picture.
Now what we do? We stimulate and maybe hoping we arrive at a remedy picture without
having the terrible situation of taking out all together the insulin, finding out what is
happening really.
And how high it can reach also.
-If you would take away the insulin, you would get a clear picture?
-Yes but who dares to take out the insulin, you see you are criminal if you do it.
-But then could you cure the child?
-I say no. There is a possibility more than it is now. Now there is no possibility.
Then it might be 1% possibility, for 1% you leave the child in a coma state?
You see the same problem that we have with cortisone, with the girl. The girl under
cortisone presents a totally different picture than the one really is there, as a pure disease
state. We don’t know, so we search and we try.
Also not to be mislead by little symptomatology in things like that. You have to have
symptoms where you base your prescription really, on the ground. Here most of the
symptoms are projections. You don’t know. I will give you an example.
Can you understand the psychology of a child who feels that is dependant on some
medication? The psychology will be to be aggressive or to be very nice to those from
whom he depends on? So how is that a symptom or a side effect of his condition?
You don’t know, it might be a symptom or it might be a dependence because of the
condition. So all these questions come to my mind when I take such a case.
Whenever I have tried remedies, pathology wise, Uran- n., Jab., Phos-ac, Nat-s.
the best remedy for me for diabetes is Nat. sulp. out of all these, if you want a remedy
but it will not work in this case. Give it in this case, nothing. Give all the remedies together
it will bring down perhaps for 3 months, then the 4th month you see it up again.
It’s a good teaching from one point of view.
-What you are saying is actually that this juvenile diabetes is not a disease but an end
stage.
-Yes, it’s an end stage.
-And this is its manifestation, there is no dynamic here.
-Yes.
That’s why you will see in such cases, for instance you get these children what we call
mongoloid children, the Down syndrome, whatever you call it; you will see in these
children though they belong in group 4, that means incurable, you can not make a
mongoloid child, a normal child. Though it belongs to group 4 it is a class of diseases
which I did not talk because I do not want, perhaps it’s too much.
Once you have a total destruction of an organ, then you don’t have a disease anymore.
You have a stabilized case and the chronic inflammation process is not there anymore.
Therefore acute diseases may manifest, the chronic infection does not prevent the
organism from manifesting acute conditions. Take a kidney which is in the process of
destruction and you will see the stoppage of acute conditions in a nephritic syndrome.
Let’s take the end stage where the kidney is gone and you take it out and the
inflammation stops, the chronic inflammation condition is stopped.
Then you may see again acutes returning.
It is the same idea which Hahnemann was talking when he was saying, you can not have
two diseases at the same time. If there is one disease process, but we confuse disease
with end stages, where it is finished the organ, the thyroid is finished, they take it out and
you may see again some acutes coming up. But while the thyroid is in the process of
degeneration, then you will see the minimizing of acute conditions. In the Down
syndrome the mongoloid children many times you get these children who are very
sensitive to acutes. They get frequent acutes. This is the reason.
-In a sense they return to level 1?
-No to level 1. They go up a little bit, to level 3 perhaps where they have acutes which are
not severe that kind.
An organism who becomes strong, get the idea of children. The children if they get a
fever is 40-41 degrees, the organism is still strong, then they throw out the disease in a
forceful manner. You get this slowly down the organism and then you get less and less
reaction, the fever becomes less, finally it doesn’t manifest at all.
We discussed the child, we said we give Carcinosin. Now the mother comes and says
the child had some symptoms. Margaret said the child has some strong symptoms and
she reads these symptoms now for the child.
-This is what the mother told me. She said since childhood the child has strong desire for
ice cream, even when he couldn’t not talk yet and he always cried while he was eating
the ice cream and the mother’s first thought is in the stomach but when he could talk he
said he has a pain in his head. In spite of having this pain, he still eats ice cream. It’s a
real strong for ice cream. Another strong desire is cucumber, he loves to eat cucumber.
-Now?
-Always. He eats cucumber and that he can not tolerate cold on his feet and that he gets
throat problems. If it’s raining he gets throat problems also. The nose bleeding he has
since he was a very small child, since 2 years or so and this is why the mother gave him
Phos.
-But still he is bleeding a lot.
-Yes but the last Phos was 2 years ago.
-The mother is here. The last Phos was 2 years ago? But you said you gave Phos for
something recently.
-It was 3 years ago he had Phos but I had given him a year ago 30D when he had throat
problems. Only once.
-The last Phos was 1 year ago?
-Yes.
-And he drinks a lot, 3 lit the day.
-It needs to be cold?
-Look this is what I want to tell you, in Norway they don’t put ice in water because it is
already ice cold from the tap, so he drinks water from the tap
-Accepted.
-And he was tested this winter and he still has some insulin production himself.
Skin in hands and toes falls off and he got Carcinosin in August 30D, 2 times.
-Why you did not write it in your report?
-Because I was little afraid. When he got the Carcinosin, he go very high and very low
from 20 to 2 and when he goes so low, he doesn’t feel himself. And I was afraid of
stressing him with this.
-I didn’t understand.
-After Carcinosin the blood sugar jumped up and down from 2 to 20 and I was afraid.
-Which is the normal?
-That’s another unit and I think the normal value is about 5.
-OK give me this scale now. 5 equals to the previous scale to what?
-The similarity between the milimole and the milligrams.
-5 milimole is about 80 milligrams approximately.
-And level 2 what she says is less than 80?
-It’s less than 80. It’s about 30 I think, it’s a hypoglycemia.
-That means that under Carcinosin the insulin should have been reduced. That is what
it shows here. Do you understand?
-But George she was saying that it was swinging around. It was going up to 20.
-Yes it may swing from here and the third days yes of course it may go up there because
here they say, eat pasta.
-It was not the third day, the same day.
-Without eating sweet?
-With the same as usual, it went down to 2 and then up to 20.
-I don’t believe that. It can not come from 30… Under normal diet suddenly to go up.
When it’s very low, that means people will eat a little bit more sweets, pasta, whatever
and then it comes up.
-George sometimes it happens for no apparent reason, diabetics can be very odd.
-Such differences? From 2 to 20?
-Yes it can happen, they call it the somogyi  effect, you see it in diabetes often especially in
children juvenile diabetes.
-Now never comes down again to that 3? Only under Carcinosin this happened?
-Yes.
-Never again?
I could only imagine that Carcinosin may have acted and he did not need this. The other
thing I don’t know, I have never seen it myself but under Carcinosin it goes like this down
that means you have to cut down the insulin.
-But himself when he is about 4 or 5, he notices it himself and he takes some sweets.
When he is about 3,5 but this time he didn’t notice because it went so fast down and he went
to bed and cried and after he couldn’t remember anything about it. Therefore I’m afraid to
give him this because I’m afraid it could happen with a regulation.
-I hope somebody who knows what he is doing is taking care of the regulation of the
insulin. When we treat either the thyroid or the pancreas with the homeopathic remedy
and there is a supply with the organ, whatever it might be, we have always to check and
regulate the intake of thyroxin or insulin in order not to have some kind of accident.
Because yes under homeopathic remedy it might be a drop, that’s a fact. Then you have
to check it and withdraw the intake of insulin.
-He checks 4-5 times the day. Very often.
Anyhow, find me the symptom.
-I want to say one more thing. It’s not a fissure, it was a fistula in the rectum which was
operated.
-Find me the rubric headache from eating ice-cream, you will see Phos is not there.
It’s another remedy, Pulsatilla is strong for that symptom, you have to remember.
Therefore the child will need Pulsatilla, Sulphur or Carcinosin? Now we have all the
information, Carcin. did this, Puls. did that and Phos. did this.
He never took Pulsatilla OK. Continue with Phos?
-With a heavy thirst.
-With a heavy thirst, desires ice cream strong. The cucumber is interesting for me.
Give him first Phos 200, first.
I have added Phos
-Interesting.
-Give him first Phos 200. If you see a real effect on the blood sugar, drop the units a
little bit and then continue checking, the first few days are very important and then we see
if there is no effect, then we go to Carcinosin 200 and you do the same. You understand?
Very good.
-One question very short. I remember that Mr. Geukens published that Puls can be very thirsty
and the thirst of this child is very great.
-Yes we have Puls, it is a possibility later on, we have it but not yet.
-I want to say one more thing. I understand very well why the mother is so anxious about
this because really this is a life threatening situation, the blood sugar goes down to 2 or
even lower and I could imagine that this Carc because it acts so strongly. But then she
should have a clinical possibility really to check the child to put a needle here with
glucose, she really needs a doctor who works with her.
-But I believe she knows because in all these cases the mothers become nurses or
doctors and they know exactly what they are doing. They can handle really the situation.
But what you say is correct, I say the same thing. When you present yourselves here I
consider that you understand enough medicine so I don’t have to give you advice on that
level as well. On top of that I’m not a specialist on allopathic medicine.
The boy with insulin first, I want to show you the mother has given some feedback
concerning the boy after Phos.
The amount of insulin he was taking before, the units are 18-20. The day he took the
Phos 200 he needed 48, it doubled the amount and the levels were up to 19 here and
next day he needed 47, more than double and the level went up to 23. The third day
44 with level 23, highest level 23 again. Today she said the levels are quite high all of
them, here they are quite high all the levels where the first and second day were up and
down.
So far he had taken 20 units, she says it’s going to be more than double until the night.
There is definitely an aggravation. The question is after this aggravation, shall we have
an amelioration? The mother also now gives a list of symptoms that she says is a new list
of symptoms.
It was late talking, then suddenly he spoke only words, he has perspiration in the night.
Drinks a lot, liked milk but not anymore, desire smoked meat, likes sweet and ice cream
feels restless with stiff pains under heels after exertion, likes the animals, he is
sympathetic, doesn’t cry easily, if things are bad he gets tears in his eyes without crying
ear ache.
-The last 2 months he has got moles.
-Very interesting this information, in the last 2 months out of all that what is more
important is that he got a lot of moles.
He does not like to be in boat and the waves, easily throat problems, perspire feet and
forehead, aggravates by cold and wet, awkward he easily falls, stumbles, loses glasses
can not talk about troubles, gets tears in his eyes but can not tell anything, wake up with
pain in the neck. The mother said this is a picture of Nat. mur. maybe.
You persuaded me instead of Cancerinum to give Phosphorus. Now?
Manipulation. I feel sorry I did not give Cancerinum.
-The difficulty was that on the paper she had, she said he desires smoked meat, then I
put it in the computer and then you asked the boy and he said no. Then I took it out again
so what is it now, is he desiring smoked meat or not?
-He has a desire?
-Yes, yes he didn’t say no. Fish too. He loves bacon and eggs.
-But smoked meat is different than bacon and eggs.
-But also smoked meat and fish.
-Anyhow this is not so important, unless it was very, very strong. Desires salt? He takes
the salt and put salt on his food?
-No, he likes potato chips and so on but he only takes salt on eggs.
-Who doesn’t eat potato chips?
-But he loves it.
-Is anybody who does not eat potato chips? There are 2 people in the class.
If you don’t eat potato chips maybe it’s a symptom because you don’t like salt, then you
don’t like salt.
My first student, a woman doctor she never drank coca-cola, so I could not find the
symptom anywhere, aversion to coca-cola. Then I enquire into the issue of not liking
coca-cola, what she does not like? She says, it’s an American product!
I’m talking back to 67, she says, this is an American product, I never touch it, so there is
different ways of not liking potato chips because if you are health conscious, you don’t
take potato chips. There are different ways that people think, so you have to enquire.
What shall we do now? These are the problems that you are going to face when you
undertake such cases.
-I think we have to wait a little more.
-Did anything else change? Any other symptoms except from the blood sugar do we have
any special symptoms?
-The mother says, there was an aggravation where the boy became very restless, the
whole night was turning, that was there 2 nights and the third night he slept on his right
side. Is this correct?
-Yes.
-What else?
-Nothing else, the first day he was very tired but now he is not so tired even he is very
high blood sugar. I think the blood sugar is very high, it’s difficult for me to get it down.
It’s too high now these 2 days.
-Today especially?
-And yesterday but today he has only eaten once and he maybe another day had taken
6-8 units, now he has taken 22.
-I would rather suggest that the boy again takes the history together with another
Norwegian doctor who translates so that the boy can talk Norwegian and the doctor will
translate it in both languages to and from, so that we really get the case.
-In Norwegian and then translate?
-I don’t think he will say so much more.
-That’s my opinion also.
-I have been to doctor with him before in Norway and he doesn’t say a lot.
-Is he really a nice boy? That means whatever you tell him, he will do?
-Yes.
-Give him Staphysagria. Why he does that? He wants to please you, what do you think?
Always his character was like that?
-Yes but he can joke and he can do such things but he is nice. He can tease the children.
He can do something wrong. Yes he can.
-If he gets upset, what he does?
-He gets to his room and shut the door.
-How long does he stay?
-1 hour or so and he won’t talk about it.
-Does he cry?
-No.
-Never?
-I only saw this when he was small but now since he was 10, I only see his tears in his
eyes and I ask what it is and he won’t tell me and I ask and then he does like this.
-Confirming.
-Yes.
-She made an observation and she does not want to talk about it. She said 2 days ago
he ate lots of chips.
-We sat next, he was there and I was here and he always …
-How much? A packet?
-I think so, he can do that very easy.
-But potato chips is very bad for him.
-Not the worse.
-The worse is coca-cola.
-Maybe I tell you one thing more. We had an accident in home when he was 8 years old.
The oldest son he was playing with the daughter and he get a little knife in the eye of the
brother. By accident. It was almost blinded but he had to take out the lids so the sight is
almost good but it was dangerous that we didn’t know if he will lose his eye or not.
When this happened my boy said it was his finger because he didn’t want to talk about it
and he didn’t want this. They call from hospital and asked what it was and I said, you
have to tell because they must know and then he just run away. I was running after him
and he was lost for about 2 hours and he never talks about it and I have only said he
could do nothing about it but he doesn’t want to talk about it.
I don’t know if it bothers him or not, he never talks about this.
-He never explained how this happened actually? That it was by knife and I did like this?
-No, the little girl was on a little bike and the brother was pushing her and he was going
to play with them but he had this in his hand and he was coming to his place by accident.
He told that later. It was the same day when I push him because the doctor has to know.
I think the accident was after he got diabetes.
-The boy was examined before and no diabetes was found or not examined before?
It was examined by chance or somebody diagnosed it? A doctor, a homeopath?
Who diagnosed it? It was a doctor?
-Yes a doctor.
-And how? By symptoms or by blood?
-She thought that he had diabetes and they sent him to the doctor.
-Why the doctor thought he had diabetes? On the first place? He must has seen some
symptoms.
-Yes, she told him that he has urinated during the night.
-That’s all? He urinated a lot? Why don’t you say a lot? To urinate a night is different
than urinate a lot, coming out. This urination when it started?
-He was always urinating a lot but it got worse. Before he got the insulin.
-Yes but the diabetes in this case is not diagnosed suddenly, unless it’s very special
case. It is a process, in juvenile diabetes is a process and you recognize it after 1,2 years
by some symptoms. First of all great thirst, then much urination. So this symptom much
thirst, much urination when it started? Then we will know when the diabetes started.
When they took the blood sugar?
-He has always been drinking a lot since he was a child.
-So diabetes was there for years and at a certain point it got worse because as the years
go by, these cases go worse and worse. This is the natural development of the case.
-They took the blood sugar at the hospital when he was born and he didn’t have high
level because he was a big boy.
-So they checked. But the tendency was there definitely.
-Was the blood sugar of the mother checked? Because big baby means the sugar of the
mother is high and therefore the baby produces a lot of insulin and after birth he gets
hypoglycemia. That’s why they are so big because they produce insulin during pregnancy
the fetus. He must produce because the blood sugar is so high and that’s why it’s
getting so big.
-But he was very long and a big head.
-What was your blood sugar?
-I don’t know but I think it was normal.
-You never experience excessive thirst, excessive urination, desire for sweets?
-No.
-Why do I make the discussion? Can anybody tell me? Why I do this analysis?
-To get information?
-There is nothing accidental in Homeopathy. Why do I do this? Because there are
certain laws that we have to follow and we know it is like this.
And the law says, when you have an incurable case, you consider it an incurable case
and we have said this is an incurable case and you give a remedy and there is an
aggravation, then you better antidote that remedy. This is observation 7 or 8 by Kent.
He said something much worse, I don’t want to say it because I don’t want to scare you
but you can go to the observations after the remedy in incurable cases and you see when
there is an aggravation, you have to antidote because it’s not going to be an amelioration.
That’s why I brought this case and it has to be discussed and it has to be decided, we
can just let it go, let it go? How far you can let it go if it’s incurable?
-But if you don’t know how many carbohydrates the boy eats, you can’t really check this
you can’t evaluate if this is aggravating or not.
-That is true but the boy is here for 15 days already and the first 8 days he gets here in
these conditions, environment etc. he gets 20 units. We give a remedy and after the
remedy with the same conditions, the units become more than double. Then you can’t
doubt about the action of the remedy, you can not. This is asking for excuses. If I want an
excuse I say, the boy eats badly now. He eats badly immediately after the remedy?
Because the mother says, he got from 8-20 units the day before. He takes the remedy
and he gets 45. So whatever it might be the discrepancies I can not attribute to the
difference on diet from one day to the other. Facts are facts.
-Can I say one thing? I feel it’s a little misunderstanding. He has very easy diabetes to
control at home and he is very fine. The doctor says he is very special, it’s above 7
every time he comes to the doctor, the long insulin and at home he can eat some chips
and he can eat some sweets and he takes a little more insulin and everything is all right.
But now when we begin Phos he tried this 2-3 times and it didn’t work, it didn’t come
down so easily as at home. So we have seen that but today he has only eaten 3 breads
and it comes so high even though.
has created… then again you have to retake the case and see whether you can find a
-I have plan to be talking about the different reactions that you get after the remedy.
Actually I see this is very important because you can not really discriminate what is an
aggravation, where is an aggravation, when it should be kept, when it should be tried.
Anyhow I think maybe we’ll do it in the next seminar these observations, I don’t know.
-How do we antidote in this case? When he is sensitive?
-Maybe with another remedy. It’s not the antidote. You just have given a remedy that
remedy that will improve. Actually the Phos, as you said before, it had improved the
situation, right? Without aggravation? Correct.
Phos was not anymore needed at this moment, maybe later on.
-But when Phos was given it was low.
-Yes but low or high it should not bring such an aggravation. It’s quite strong.
-I saw in Hahnemann, if you get aggravation in chronic, in the beginning it was too high.
-No. When you get an aggravation is very good sign, as long as it’s curable.
I would suggest 2 things in this case, the first is that I would prescribe the Carcinosin
and since you are leaving tomorrow, you can only call from Norway to give a feedback
of what’s happening and then in case this does not control either, then we have to
rethink about the case.
I can’t remember why I changed prescription?
-He liked cucumbers.
-In a case like this would you consider giving Carcinosin in a lower potency, maybe
even considering an LM potency because of the fragility of the case and the possibility
of still further aggravations? With the LM potencies is possible to have the most
amount of control of the action of the remedy of the organism.
-In this case you can not go higher than 200. 200 is the highest. But on the other hand
considering Carcinosin, it’s not a remedy that you repeat frequently, at least I had not
-It is important that after Carcinosin which already he received once, the blood sugar
went up so much and then the class corrects and says, no it went down after the remedy.
-Fast up and down, up fast and down fast, this is what she reported.
-Can you tell us there have been reports in different preparations of Carcinosin.
Do you have any particular one that you feel you will use?
-No.
-They are all the same?
-To me yes, as long as it is Cancerinum not Scirrhinum, from Scirrhus. If the name is
Cancerinum it should be from the same source, this is a matter that has to be taken
care by the pharmacies, not by me. When I say Cancerinum they are supposed to
give me the same substance.
I don’t know that, it’s the first time I hear it. Scirrhinum there is from Scirrhus cancer.
But when I say Cancerinum it is supposed to be from one source.
-Would it be an idea to have him go home tomorrow, have the situation that he always
had, watch the blood sugar in Norway where the situation is the same as always and
then maybe after having the normal life, as it always was, then give him the Cancerinum
and see what happens then because in this situation we can’t really tell.
-You see this is all right telling but actually if he eats only once and he needs 48 units
the situation is not to be left.
And it needs more careful monitor, perhaps. When you go there you check the blood
sugar by this machine. What is your type? It’s a good one?
-Yes, he does it himself.
-This is the case group 4, I would think that there should be in these cases, in group 4
we have immediate amelioration because you can not have an aggravation, immediate
amelioration and then another remedy appears. To do really careful work, it has to be
monitored in such a way that every time with every change of symptoms, we take notice
and we see whether the picture of another remedy is appearing.
After this analysis, before taking Carcinosin, Margaret was given certain information
more. She gave me a list of 10 symptoms like this one here and within these, there
were 2 keynotes of Phos. One was desire for cucumber and the other?
-Strong desire for ice cream.
-If you remember in the analysis I said, it doesn’t matter for that symptom but the
desire for cucumber was so strong and she confirmed, I said most probably and I
changed it.
What can you do? These things with the language and the type of situation we are now
under stress, the same was happening with the girl with the colitis. She came back and
she gave information that was really for Causticum and then it was very clear but her
case was very clear, this case is not clear. If we put the analysis back you will see how
I vacillated to go back to Phos because my impression was that Phos had done all
it could do, forget it for a moment, needs another remedy and then maybe again Phos
again Nat mur or again another remedy. At this moment the most prominent for me was
Carcinosin, that’s why I would like him to take Carcinosin.
-All his energy was gone, he was tired, he did not go out with his friends for a whole
month, he got pain under his heels and knees, so it was impossible to play football.
He tried, after 5 min he had to stop. On the 15th of July he got Pulsatilla 200, all the
pains in the heels and knees were gone, now he had 2 days with his hands, they were
very cold which is a new symptom, he felt tired for some days and then ameliorate and
started to go out with his friends again although they mostly came to the house.
After a month he got nose bleeding in the night, which is an old symptom, he had this
often as a little boy, the nose is stuffed and it irritates in the night and it ends up quite
a lot of nose bleeding. He had this 3 or 4 nights and then it stopped. Two weeks ago he
developed inflammation in his right big toe, it was red, swollen and painful. He had this
many times before, now it was much more severe and painful, I was not allowed to be
near it but he tried to get some pus with a needle, nothing came out, 3 or 4 days it went
away by itself. For a week ago he had some skin eruption on his right shoulder, it was
stitching pain and was itchy and they were little red spots which is a new symptom.
He also has loose skin inside his hands and fingers, the skin fell off which is an old
symptom.
-You see what happens with these cases? The pains in the knees, better, no aggravation
then some other symptoms are developing, then even some skin comes out but the skin
is a little bit of eruption, stays for 1 week and goes away, no real reaction. The organism
is battling and comes back, it can not get it out.
-He loves chicken wings and he can eat them every day, grilled with spice.
But the last 3 weeks he got nausea of eating them and he had to stop, he wants them and
stops because of nausea, which is a new symptom. For 3 weeks now he has been
sighing every day but he is not aware of it. He is spitting during the day, I think he must
have a lot of salivation but this is not a new symptom. He lies restless, not covering
in bed, fears he does not want to go out in boat, which is an old symptom.
Considering the blood sugar, after Carcinosin he comes back to the level he had before
Phos which is 18-20 units the day. With Pulsatilla the first night he woke up and needed
some sugar because he was low in blood sugar. This happens a lot at nights, the first
2 weeks, maybe 3 times the week and he had to reduce his dose in the night with 3 units
from 8 to 5. In the day the blood sugar could be low, more often than before, so he had
to be careful taking his insulin. But after one and a half month, he gradually went back
to the same state as before Pulsatilla. That’s it.
-You see group number 4? Typical reaction to group number 4. He is here, you give a remedy
better for a while, then back, then new symptoms, then another remedy, then you try
again and again and again but you never know, you can not predict. Continue.
-That’s all.
-Pulsatilla 200.
-Yes but he is sighing a lot now, very much.
-So we give him Ignatia.
-I don’t know. Maybe he needs the remedy more often because it helped him.
-The Pulsatilla?
-Yes, he only got it once.
that remedy and you say you have to repeat it but still I don’t see.
Sighing now, a lot?
-A lot.
-He likes to travel?
-No, he likes to travel but mostly to be at home I think.
-And you think that he reduced eating fruits?
-He loves fruits.
-Still eats them?
-Yes.
-You didn’t notice that lately he isn’t eating fruits. That would be a good indication
for instance, a little bit of confirmation for Ignatia but she does not confirm it.
-I don’t think so. He is not alone at home but he reads, he looks at the television and
so on but if he goes with friends, he never phones them, they come to him. Never.
He is troubled to tell about himself even if it is something better, it doesn’t matter, he
-Never, as far as you can remember?
-No. He is bothered by pains and so on, today I have a pain here, a pain there but not
if anything is deeper.
-No emotions.
-No he can’t.
-Calc phos?
-But Calc phos has to be discontent. Is he discontent?
-No.
-Not so much. He never talks about himself and problems, he can not do this.
-What about his friends and how he behaved before? Now he withdraws more, he
stays more by himself or his behavior with the friends is the same?
-He is more by himself.
-When he sees television, when he plays computer, what he does?
-He does, he sees television and plays computer and we have a large family, we are
6 in the family, he is very good in sport, he is the best in the school, in everything.
-In lessons also?
-In sports.
-In every sport he is very good. That’s a contradiction. Anybody has any idea?
When he perspires where he perspires mostly?
-On the head and on the feet, he is sweat on the feet.
-Face?
-Yes in the night and when he is sporting he perspires on his face a lot and he becomes
very red.
-Is it possible that the whole thing has started when he was 3 years old for instance?
-Yes I think so.
-What year?
-When he was 3 years, he didn’t tolerate milk and he was very bad of the milk and he
got a lot of ear ache.
-What I wanted to ask is, is it possible when he was about 3 years old, that you had a
quarrel with your husband and he was in the room. is it possible? You remember such
incident?
-No.
-I can know. We don’t use to have that quarrel.
-Is it possible that you had a brother or a sister who was sick?
-My husband lost his father.
-At the age of?
-It is 13 years ago, he was 2 years old. But he was not so connected because we
don’t live in the same town. My husband was very connected.
-And your husband was affected?
-Yes, very. He got diabetes a year after.
And he doesn’t show it, I’m happy, I go and take insulin, no problem.
-Norwegian way. You don’t even open your mouth when you speak.
-I try to.
-All the Norwegians, they speak with closed mouth so the cold air does not come in.
I have problems understanding Norwegians and Swedish when they speak, always.
It is possible that the child might had a traumatic experience something perceived
instinctively, he saw something. It might be that he saw the father destroyed and crying
and the child…
-He never cried. He does not show it, the father too. Even when the father does
not show, the child is more perceptive to receive the mood of the father, he doesn’t have
to say nothing but he was so little.
-He must be a little bit more than 2.
-It was in April and I have a son who is 13 and I was pregnant when he died.
-You were pregnant?
-Yes with another one, not with him. I was pregnant and he is 13 now.
-And the son is?
-He is 15.
-We can try, it’s desperate case but we can try. It is good if we try this remedy in low
potency, like 12, 3 times the day but every 10 days raise one potency and see what
happens in 1-2 months, whether the sugar level may start coming down.
-Which remedy?
-When he was little he always stumbled, when he runs he is clumsy in a way and he still
is with this now.
-He is still clumsy.
-But he is good in sports, he is in handball and he reacts very fast.
-Quick to react and rapid in execution.
Ignatia 12 for a few months, see what happens.
-In such a severe case los of energy for one month, it’s not such a bad symptom and also
that he developed these joint pains is not so bad, so I’m trying to understand why then it
was changed to Pulsatilla.
-Because if we had a good reaction then after the aggravation, we suppose to have an
aggravation, then we have to see the amelioration, which we did not see really.
These cases, as I described, they change picture. You give a remedy, they will take it.
You will see now after Ignatia, the picture will change but the basic disease will remain
the same, so what we are expecting at one moment, when you will have a reaction from
the remedy, when you have an aggravation in this case, it’s going to be very strong.
It’s going to be something very strong.
-As far as I have understood the process of this case, he had good reactions after Pulsat.
Why do we now change to Ignatia?
-Because, as I explained to you, in this group you give a remedy, there is some reaction
it feels better for a while, then either come back the symptoms or new symptoms
develop. When new symptoms develop, you go along with the new symptoms and you
prescribe for the new symptoms. He brought out some new symptoms, he withdrew more
he stayed more at home, he sighs and these are new guiding symptoms, it’s not a clear
case of Ignatia but you have some new guiding symptoms that tell you that maybe there
is some traumatic experience after which the whole thing started and yes there is.
Now she confirms here that the grand father and the child, I don’t know how much
perceptive he might have been and we know that children are affected very much when
we are not aware, that is true. Now putting all this together…
Of course it’s a little bit of projection to say that the child of 2 years perceived the father
being very sad and the child had a shock, it’s a projection, it’s not good but we don’t base
everything on that projection alone, we base it on the fact that the child started sighing
and the child is also withdrawn, he doesn’t express his emotions. Now with the sighing
all this comes to a little bit better picture than before, not that the picture is clear but it’s a
little bit clearer than before. Therefore you have to go by these guiding things and see
what happens.
-How did you differentiate Ignatia from Nat mur?
-Nat mur will not sigh.
-Yes it has sighing.
-When the main symptom, which she mentions, is sighing then you go. Of course there
are 60 remedies that have sighing but maybe later on he may need some Nat mur but at
this moment with the story, with the withdrawal, with everything she says, we have to
think of Ignatia. But when in a case let's say of grief, when the main symptom is sighing you
first give Ignatia, then you may need to give Nat mur but first you give Ignatia.
Did he have Nat mur before? Phos acid?
-No.
-So we start with Ignatia and see what happens.
-When she was reading this I put some rubrics together and they were mainly Pulsatilla.
Every rubric it came right on top and then I thought it’s clear because the remedy did
what it could, now as we get more information from your report, then as you see, there is
perspiration foot and perspiration head it comes to this. That means it is not clear, it is not
so prominent because it is group 4 but differentiation between Phos acid and Ignatia from
the system.
-He is thinking the same way.
-In cases like this where it is very complicated and confused case, would you consider a
very small remedy like Crataegus.
-I would consider but not Crataegus in this case.
-Even though it’s a major remedy for child diabetes.
-When I’m totally desperate and I don’t know what to do anymore, I will take 5 of these
remedies, give them all together. I mean you can do anything, after you have tried and
no real effect, then you try anything, you may try anything because maybe under
something it will react but what we are trying to do is to bring some order to the organism
so the organism eventually will show some clear picture. The moment it shows a clear
picture you will see the difference. If we manage to do that, this case is a case of group 4
as we said, so this is exactly what you have to expect. Maybe after Ignatia we have a
picture of Nat mur and after Nat mur we may have a clear picture of Phos acid and you
give Phos acid and it’s beautiful.