-Tell us what is your problem?
-Actually I wanted to see you last September because I was in a very big stress.
I’ve been married for 28 years, my marriage nearly broke up.
-When?
-Last year and during this year I manage in a way but I feel a very great sorrow inside.
Actually I can’t be as happy as I want to be. That’s why I wanted to see you.
-When exactly this happened? It was something which was sudden or it was something
that was developing and you expected it and finally happened?
-I work with a man which distressed me very much because he gives me sexual feelings.
I tried to avoid it a long time but he is a very strong person,
I didn’t want to break the partnership, so I broke …
-Marriage?
-No, I didn’t break it up.
I told my husband what was going on and we talked about it.
-You have children?
-Yes two.
-So you told your husband what was happening that there was an attraction there
and you can not resist and all that. Your husband said, forget it.
-Yes, after I told him we got several things trying to be better
but still I feel the sorrow inside because I hurt him.
-Now this relationship with the other man is going on?
-No, it’s over. It is not there for one year but it makes me feel this way, so it is difficult.
-Were you able to cry during all this period or you kept it inside?
-No, I was very hurt.
-Hurt in yourself and hurt in others also?
-More by myself I think. But I felt I wasn’t able to feel things properly.
Like joy, going out, I like to go out in the forest and see beautiful things
but I couldn’t enjoy it. I just worked, worked, worked.
-You feel you are in a depressive state.
-In a way yes. But I try to make myself cheer up a little bit, actually the work does me good
because I work with people and I’m able to help them, so that's good for me.
-Any physical symptoms?
-Every time I go to menstruate I get lumps in my breast.
This year I had very severe nodes on my chest, actually on the left side.
-Did you examine it?
-No, I didn’t go to a doctor. I’ve never been to a doctor except when I was pregnant.
-So you are treating yourself actually all this time?
-More psychotherapeutic, I’ve seen homeopath once and he gave me so many remedies
that I didn’t want to go to him anymore.
-He gave a series of remedies? Did you take any high potency lately?
-Not lately. I went 3 years ago, he gave me Thuja 1M, 50M, Sepia 1M, 10M
Lycopodium 1M, Mercurius also 1M, Phosphorus 1M.
-Plus low potencies?
-We have a teacher in our school who was telling me about the way he worked with low potencies
and he gave me 3 remedies the one after another
but it was D6, D12 and one dose of B30.
-What remedies?
-The one was Thuja, (?) Muriaticum and the third one I cant’ remember.
-How is your general energy? How do you feel your energy after this grief?
-I have to take a break from 1-3 o’clock when I work.
-You work in a hospital?
-No, I have my own clinic. I had it for 15 years.
-And from yourself you took a (?) as I understand, you went for holidays?
I ask you how is your energy?
-My energy is good.
-It has not been affected by this grief?
-In a way, because I don’t want to be with people, as much as I did before.
-You don’t want to be with people now?
–No, I want to go alone.
-You walk alone. Do you sigh a lot?
-I don’t know actually. No one has told me that. Perhaps sometimes yes.
-Do you have any fears?
-Yes I do.
–What kind of fears?
–Many.
–Tell us.
-The one that disturbs me most is being with people who have a high education.
It stresses me a lot.
-Do you feel a kind of lack of self-confidence?
–Yes I do.
-What other fear you have?
-When small insects are coming suddenly…
-… become fearful.
-I swim a lot but I dislike all the things in the bottom of the sea.
-You don’t like?
-I think about it every time I go bathing, when I stay in the beach,
I go bathing 5-6 times in the sea.
-Do you like the sea?
-Yes I like it very much.
-And you feel good in the sea?
–Yes. But actually I’m afraid of the bottom.
-So you don’t like to look in the bottom.
You are afraid of sharks or just of this darkness there?
-I can’t say.
-Are you afraid of the dark?
-I was when I was a little child but my mother (?) to do everything
because she was so afraid so I had to go on, doing everything.
But I walk in the forest when it is dark, so I don’t think it scares me so much.
-Do you sleep well and wake up refreshed in the morning?
-Yes I feel very refreshed when I wake up because if I’m sad or have a hard time,
I go to bed and each morning I feel it’s a new one. So it’s a good therapy for me.
-So sleep is very good for you.
-But I don’t need much sleep.
-Can you tell me what kind of menses you have? They have a lot of blood, less blood,
pains before, depression before?
-Actually I get angry, irritation.
-Anger and irritability before menses and what about crying before menses?
-No. I’m more sensitive in many ways before menses but I’m not crying.
-Could you say it a kind of depression before?
-Yes, more that.
-So mostly irritability and then some depression together with some lumps on the breast.
The whole breast is swollen?
-Very swollen.
-And painful?
–Yes.
-Was any tuberculosis in your family? Did you have tuberculosis?
-They went to examine me when I was 7 years old.
I went to a TBC clinic to see if you have the TBC, it was positive.
So I went to a clinic from 7-11 years old but they didn’t find any TBC.
My mother also had to go through this.
-Your mother also went through treatment.
-Not for TBC but they examined the lungs and …
-Do you have any sensitivity with your lungs? You get easily colds?
-No. Nearly never. I just feel it, it’s coming.
Every time before the menses I feel I’m getting a cold but when the menses is coming, it’s gone.
-Symptoms of cold before menses which they leave you immediately with the flow.
When the flow comes the symptoms go.
Have you suffered with any serious disease in the past?
-When I gave birth to my oldest child, I was so strong, I was a gymnast
and the (?) in the lungs get out to the skin, so it felt like snow in the skin,
it’s called acute emphysema.
But I’ve never had any troubles with it afterwards. Now I feel I breathe less.
-As if you can not take a big breath? You are never satisfied with your breathing?
-No, I have to think about to take a deep breath to satisfy yourself.
Food, you have desires or aversions for different foods?
Do you eat fruits?
-No.
-You are not interested.
-I can take apple from the tree in autumn but that’s all.
-It doesn’t interest you very much.
-Other fruits you will never take?
-Banana I can eat.
-You like them a lot.
-No. I know it’s good and I eat it, maybe 2-3 days but it takes months before I eat it again.
But I like fish very much, the meat of lamp but I don’t eat so much meat. More fish.
I’m not so fan of sweets.
-Salt? Normal, less than normal?
-No less than normal. If I eat peanuts, I always (?) off the salt
but I like more to have a dinner than to have sweets. The warm food.
-You like the warm food.
-I’m very warm.
-You do perspire a lot?
-I perspire a lot when I’m dancing but not when I’m sitting here, I don’t perspire.
-Where do you perspire mostly in your body?
-Under the arms.
-What about the face?
-The face also when I’m training.
-Do you perspire during sleep?
-Yes before the menses. Everything is before the menses.
-Premenstrual syndrome.
Do you sleep in a particular position only or you can sleep in any position?
-I don’t like to lie on the left side so much as the others but usually I lie on my back.
When I was younger I was lying on my abdomen.
-But no so much now.
–No.
I lie on my back with one foot bend up.
-For how many years you sleep in that position? One year, two years or it can be more?
-I did it because my chiropractor told me.
-There is something else when snowing. I also can feel a kind of getting a flu or cold.
I get very dry on my skin, on my lips.
-What else?
-I have a point on my left leg which is hurting me and when I’m sitting for a long time
I get pain in my knee.
-Which knee?
-Mostly the left one. Mostly the symptoms are left sided.
-You said you see a lot of dreams. There is any dream you see repeatedly?
-No.
-What kind of dreams they are? Dreams that they are pursuing you,
dreams that you are falling from high place, do they have a theme?
-Most of them is dreams of nature.
-Pleasant dreams?
-Yes.
-Mostly pleasant dreams?
-As I told you, when I wake up I feel good.
I don’t think the dreams are stressing in any way.
-What about fear of thunderstorms? Do you have any?
-It could be because my mother was so afraid of thunderstorms
that she locked us in to a little room. whenever it was a thunder.
She hosted me to the room beside (?) but she didn’t want us to see the thunder either.
But I can get out in the thunder.
-Not much fear now.
–No.
-In your sleep has anybody told you that you are grinding your teeth?
-No. But I can feel that in the last time when this problem started,
I can feel that I’m a bit tense.
-You are clenching your teeth?
–Yes.
-There is any problem with constipation, diarrhea, stomach problems?
-Yes I feel some acids in my upper abdomen, as if it is empty.
But I think it is because of my smoking. I smoke too much. I’m stressed.
-The acid in your stomach is because of smoking you think?
-Yes because when I smoke lesser, it’s not so bad but when I’m coming down here
I drink a little bit “retsina”. But I can’t do it many days, one after the other,
because then I also fell this acid.
-Do you drink a lot of alcohol?
-No, I’ve never been fan of alcohol because I don’t think I can take so much.
-You can not stand so much alcohol.
–No.
-When you are angry, what do you like to do? You like to express your anger,
you do express it, you shout, you throw things?
-Yes, not so much in the last years but earlier I was expressing. They told me I was …
-Too expressive.
-Yes I really had to …
-…try to subdue yourself. But in the last year you did not express so much anger.
-Not so much.
-Would you say that when this depression started, this problem, there was a time
that you knew from that day onwards or it came gradually?
-I say it came gradually.
-And mostly what affects you now is the fact that you have hurt your husband
or that you have hurt yourself or both?
-My husband has always been a very good man and I don’t feel …
-You don’t feel you deserve him. You feel you’ve done something which has …
It’s all right. You feel quite guilty.
Are you in divorce now or you still are together?
-He is (?) if he is able to forgive what I’ve done.
-He can not?
-Yes but I can’t forgive myself.
-I think now that’s enough.
-Now I believe that as you learn more and more the theory
you are able to clarify every case more easily.
In this case we will see the interesting things, which are happening in this case
concerning what we have been speaking about in the theory.
How this case applies to what we have been thinking about the theory.
In this case, you saw some symptoms of Ignatia.
You saw some symptoms also of Medorrhinum. We saw some symptoms of Phosphorus
and we saw some symptoms of Tuberculinum.
Exactly this is the situation and then we are actually going to decide finally
which is the remedy with which we’re going to start treating this case.
The first question we’re asking is what kind of symptoms I will evaluate mostly
to start treating the case?
Immediately comes the idea of the layers.
Maybe there are a few layers that we have to treat in this case?
The answer obviously is yes. What is the uppermost layer that we have to treat?
Is this clear? Who says it is clear? Only 50% of the class.
Let us say you had the computer…
What symptoms have you used Margaret? Can you show the symptoms that you have used?
The symptoms that she has used, sighing, ailments from grief, can not weep, indifference apathy,
sadness, anxiety of consciousness, aversion fruits, irritability before menses,
want of self-confidence, menses painful, sleep position on back.
If you take this and you repertorize, the remedy … let’s see. I never said what’s the remedy.
Margaret put her own symptoms. Ignatia, Natrum Muriaticum, Nux Vomica, Opium, Pulsatilla.
You have been thinking the same way, right? Who thought of Ignatia honestly?
Very good, it’s 65% of the class. 65 is a good number.
You thought of Ignatia, you looked in your Repertories, still the Repertories will say Ignatia
but some of you who did not say, this is Ignatia, you thought
what shall we do with better in the sea? She is so much better in the sea.
She said it in such a  way, better in the sea.
Find me the symptom, Medorrhinum it’s capital there.
This is something on Kent’s Repertory, if I’m not mistaken,
in the original Kent’s Repertory better in the sea is with small letters.
Who has the original Repertory of Kent? Somebody had the original.
-Amelioration just Medorrhinum.
-On what type of letters? Ordinary?
-Yes.
-On the original Kent we have this symptom which we know to be
so much characteristic of Medorrhinum and eventually he had it with ordinary letters.
Now we found out that other remedies also are better in the sea by experience
and then what we did we raised the Medorrhinum to the third degree
because we have confirmed it again and again and again that Medorrhinum is better in the sea.
So in the Synthesis we have better in the sea.
Did you find the rubric symptoms of influenza coldness before menses, did you find this?
Has anybody this symptom? Who can find it first to get the best marks?
Some they don’t even try.
He got it. What’s the remedy?
-Graphites, Magnesia Carbonica and Tarentula.
-In the original Kent?
-Yes.
-That is another keynote of another three remedies and we have Graphites
Magnesia Carbonica… Magnesia Carbonica is the main remedy for this keynote.
And Tarentula. We get the idea of Tarentula. We ask her, is she very much in a hurry?
-You are a hurry person?
–Yes I think so.
-You like dancing you said, very much?
-I’ve been sporting all my life until 4 years ago that I stopped but I like to move.
-Music?
–Yes, I like music very much.
-It makes you feel better?
– In a way.
If I’m alone I can sit down listen to music.
-She does not want to be Tarentula.
-What? Actually I don’t know the remedy.
-Ah you don’t know. It’ s a good remedy, very much energy.
-I’ll take any remedy.
-Very much dancing, you take the energy through dancing and through loud music.
Wait a moment. Now that we know a little bit more, what is the remedy?
Do we change our mind? Do we give Tarentula instead of Ignatia or do we give Medorrhinum
instead of Tarentula or Ignatia?
These are the questions that should go to our mind.
The other way of thinking is, what about what we’ve been talking
about guilty conscience sigh, depression etc?
What about the idea of this level being Ignatia where the underlined level might be Tarentula?
Tarentula desires dancing… it comes out and then music ameliorates…
and then chorasia is like that.
So you have symptoms of Tarentula, some symptoms of Tarentula you see within a picture of Ignatia.
And then better in the sea, maybe one more Medorrhinum symptom are popping up.
This is the picture where we have to decipher and whether we start with Ignatia
with Tarentula or with Medorrhinum. Or we go Ignatia – Tarentula – Medorrhinum.
Or we start with Medorrhinum. You say it’s the deepest or Tarentula is the deepest
because Medorrhinum can be hear and Tarentula can be there.
Also in theory concerning the lifting of what we call a miasm,
all these three remedies can constitute one miasm.
That means treating this case within 1-2 years where she will take these three remedies
where she will feel better etc. you may find in the end of the third year
that she develops symptoms of Mercury.
So underneath a miasm which we call, this is the psychotic miasm,
here we have the syphilitic miasm, Mercury and Aurum. You may get some depression eventually
which looks like Aurum here and you have treated this and this you have now
symptoms of Mercury or Aurum, still this woman will be living much longer
than if she was left untreated.
Here the Ignatia level it may lead her, if it is very deep, in suicidal thoughts.
We asked her whether she had suicidal thoughts?
(?) that is the rubric.
You see there Aurum very strong, Aurum Muriaticum, Aurum Sulphuricum,
Natrum Sulphuricum, Psorinum and let’s see if we have Ignatia, there yes.
So Ignatia also may have some suicidal disposition.
That means the depression of Ignatia, what we have been talking, it can be of different degrees,
intensity and reaches the intensity where really they just want to die. They want to finish.
This is not the case with her because she is strong.
She has a strong organism which reacts quite good.
-First of all I find Ignatia is all right but why not think about Lycopodium
as a second constitutional remedy because Lycopodium has also amelioration by the sea.
The most important thing she said to us it was this lack of self-confidence
and she has fear of dark, she has this need to move a lot and rankles of the face and so on.
And Lycopodium is very well following Ignatia.
-Why don’t we? Because at this moment is not our job to find the second remedy.
It will be our job after Ignatia. Since I was convinced that Ignatia
is the first remedy to be given, then the second and the third
are just theoretical questions at this moment.
We can not say, I George Vithoulkas solemnly swear that the second remedy in this case
will be Tarentula. No.
I’m just saying you get some symptoms that show Tarentula maybe Medorrhinum,
maybe 100 other remedies.
The moment that you clear from the layer of Ignatia then it’s the time to really deal
and take into consideration all the symptoms, not now.
Now why I stopped taking the case? Because the case clearly indicates
that upon the several layers that she maybe has,
the layer which was forming as the first layer was Ignatia.
Then you can not say, theorizing and all that, no.
Something very interesting which you observe in the case also is what?
-I agree with Ignatia that’s clear but I struggle with the strong problem of her
that she makes a rapprochement of her, there is a strong feeling of being guilty.
That’s a clear case of Ignatia.
-Very good. What is something that impresses you in this case?
You have to use your observation all the time. This is strange.
I observe something which is strange, you have to catch it.
-She is sighing a lot without noticing it herself.
-Yes exactly. The first thing we noticed when she came, she couldn’t breath
and I did it on purpose, I said do you sigh? No. Later on she says,
from time to time I have to take a deep breath because the breath has become shallow.
Many times we say symptoms that will come from your own observations like this
and will become very important.
-I don’t know when but you said once the patient is telling the story in the first sentences.
And this impressed me very much with her because she told the story right away,
She got those tears in her eyes which she suppressed and the first three sentences showed Ignatia.
-Right. But there is another point also of interest to the homeopath.
She said, I have never been able to cry and she cried here, why?
Can anybody tell me why she cried in front of the camera?
Because of the effort. This is a big effort to come in front of the class
and not only in front of the class, there is the camera also,
it’s everything and she has to tell and this excitement which she has,
can not control logically anymore because the excitement is so much that the mind can not control
and she used to be controlling, controlling.
When the excitement is there and then you have to perform, we say OK you act.
Then the emotions are out of control and that is why,
the same way this Chinese lady has said also.
That is out of control because of the situation she faces for the first time.
The possibility to talk about her emotions and in front of the class, under great stress.
-I would like to ask a question. Isn’t this part of the constitution of Ignatia
because in the Repertory we have these two rubrics, thinking about complains aggravates
and (?) during her symptoms.
I think even concentrating upon her problems, this is enough for Ignatia to get to (?)
-There is no question we have enough symptoms for Ignatia to prescribe.
Is this a constitutional Ignatia? I put a big question mark.
She is not a depressed person all her life. She is a person full of life,
enjoying herself dancing, music, not a closed person.
Now, she says, the last two years I don’t want to see many people.
That shows the closeness, she is becoming a close person.
She doesn’t want to discuss, she doesn’t want others to know. She becomes more closed.
She is not so social. This is how the disease progresses.
And from that state, if she is not treated with Ignatia, she will progress to another state
where she may find her physical body being affected.
And the physical symptoms which are mostly connected with menses,
if she had come before, she would have come to be treated for a premenstrual syndrome.
Would you give Ignatia to her, from what we imagine now,
according to the premenstrual syndrome? It seems no.
With the symptoms that she relates concerning the premenstrual syndrome
and the other symptoms in general, which point to a constitutional type,
all the symptoms if you put them together, then you come to the idea of Tarentula most probably,
as more constitutional more deep remedy.
But definitely at this stage you will have to give Ignatia to counteract
this terrible feeling of guilt which is with her.
She seems she has suffered enough because 65% of the class could see the remedy.
Why she did not take it? Because she had to suffer and once she suffered enough
there is somebody who says, OK you suffered enough, take Ignatia and finish the suffering.
That means she has learned whatever it is to be learned most probably.
In a human way we can explain the situation in this way because now the suffering will be less.
If you are a moralist you may say, with your Ignatia you take away the suffering.
Is it correct or not? How do you take the suffering from a person
that has to develop spiritually so you let him suffer. Because she has done something wrong.
No. Our job is to help human suffering irrespectively of the logic
of the morality behind the issues.
We are not gods to judge who has to suffer or who has not to suffer.
We are humans learning a science that can alleviate the suffering.
If this not allowed to be cured, then simply you will not find the remedy.
As we find the remedy so easily, that means this person is allowed not to suffer anymore.
So by taking today, by tomorrow already all this guilt, all these feelings will be…
And on Thursday when we take back a follow up of the case, we will see the difference.
Ignatia 50M, one dose. Ignatia 12 will make her well after about 20 days.
Ignatia 200 after 3 days, Ignatia 50M after 2 days, maybe 1 day, maybe tonight.
-Not a question actually, remark. Last year in the party she was dancing
and I looked at her and I couldn’t take my eyes of her. I didn’t dance,
she was dancing for 2-3 hours until she was completely wet, so beautifully and I said,
this is a Tarentula and I called a Tarentula lady after that evening.
-Very good because I have done the same. I didn’t want to say it
but I had observed the same observation. She was dancing right there in front of the …
-Yes like dynamite.