-OK, this is case on which we had prescribed Picric acid D6 for 1 week,
D7 for another week and D8 for the third week.
So for 3 weeks you took the potency of Picric acid
and that was on May and you started…?
-I started 1 month ago.
-You started in August?
-22nd August but I was supposed to take it for 2 months and go up.
-Tell us what happened.
-I started right away with an aggravation 7 hours later, with stitches in left sacrum
and it was for some hours and went away. After the first day I was chilly
even if it was very warm weather, so it was getting freezing and the feet were very cold.
They are always very cold but they were especially cold.
And I wanted warm creams some soups, I felt tired and bad as if a flu was coming on
and a pain in the throat.
The second day I was feeling feverish but also easily chilled even thought the skin was warm.
I felt chilled inside. Still I wanted to swim in the sea because I felt it was very good.
I enjoyed the swimming.
-In Norway?
-Yes it was a very warm summer.
So the seaside generally makes me feel very much better but right now I’ m very cold
so I have not been swimming. Only once.
-But you stay under the sun?
-Yes I like the sun and I wanted to warm so I was wandering.
And a feeling of weakness not really well started up the second day
and the third day was about the same but when I brushed my teeth the second day,
I started bleeding in the gums and very painful ulcers in the gums and I could hardly eat
and also some blood in my nose, a little bit.
It was like a burning and smarting and very hard to eat and a feeling of paper in my mouth.
-And the ulcers how long they lasted?
-A couple of days, 3-4 days.
But the weakness, I felt very tired and very strong headaches for some hours in occiput
in the base and muscle was very weak so I felt I could hardly stand, I felt weak and exhausted,
I hardly could stand on my feet.
And the aching and sore in the whole body, and they left me, I got back some pain,
I had comes and goes, and it was hard working, stitching pains.
And the problems with the gums got worse and also the headache and I got more thirsty.
Then it went into the lungs similar as the process when I took Phosphorus last time.
-It went down to the lungs the cold and then you started coughing?
-No, I don’t think I started coughing but a couple of days later but the burning pain
in the lungs and also dyspnea, breathing problems and burning pain in the chest
and all the back and behind sternum. And also I started to get some pain in the kidneys.
I had pyelonephritis many years ago and it was a little similar like the beginning
of getting into that.
-How many years ago you had the pyelonephritis?
-I was about 20, 20 years ago.
When I was breathing it was stitching up in the occiput and up to the right arm,
like pain extending up.
And I was very exhausted in the evening and asthmatic problem, hard to breathe.
So then a friend called and after a short while I had to tell her I could not talk anymore
because I didn’t have strength to speak and she could hear the whizzing sound from the phone.
-So she gave you another remedy?
-No.
I felt the fever was increasing though when I tested it was only 36.5, if it’s correct.
-But you felt that you had fever.
-But I never get fever, it feels I can not work out the fever.
And the feeling of intoxicated and that my head was not functioning was aggravated...
-It was strong.
-My head was just like cotton and I went into apathy and a trans-like state
and the appetite diminished very soon after taking the remedy.
-You took 3 times the day or once the day?
-Twice the day.
And the lung problems got worse, so I felt I was worried about pneumonia,
so in the fifth day I just not to take any remedy.
-You did not take.
-No.
So I called her and described the symptoms and 2 days later I got a fax
and you told me to continue because you saw that symptoms were like common cold.
-Yes.
-But I felt it was getting worse after talking with she, so a couple of days I didn’t take any.
-You didn’t take any remedy.
-I got better when I did not take the remedy, those days I felt a little better.
I had some shooting pains up in the vagina and uterus and the right ovary
but I had eaten an apple so I don’t know if it was something to do with it
or it was to do with the remedy.
But dyspnea continued and it was much more the cold that was getting a little better
while not taking the remedy and the lung problem was also a little better.
I can not remember so I have to…
-These notes you wrote afterwards?
-I wrote day by day.
Otherwise no chance and I had a book with me, I just took out big parts.
-All right.
-I think I was very tired but I was a little better day by day but then I felt better,
then I started again with this, after a couple of days.
So it was only 2 days I didn’t take the remedy and after taking this 7
I got much pain in my neck and the occiput which I also had before that
I had to lie down for several hours.
-Because of the pain?
-Yes and then the flu symptoms started again when I started with this 7.
It had been better a little bit and then it comes again.
-It came again?
-Yes and the pain in the kidneys came again but worse and also some burning pains in my stomach
like it was too much acid, similar to the burning pains I hadn’t long seen.
I felt also very dizzy and when I got up I thought the blood pressure was very low
and I had to get up very slowly.
-Otherwise you felt you may faint?
-Yes and the influenza symptoms increased and I got back to the difficulty to think again
and the dyspnea got worse.
-Again the dyspnea got worse, the same thing?
-Yes the same thing with the slightest exertion, I had breathing problems.
Also I was nauseous. And I was freezing cold, I just wanted warm clothes to lie down
into the carpet and aching in the bones and then the depression started.
I got more and more depressed, no energy, no appetite and I went to D8 next week and
the 2 days before I had been a little better with the cold
and then it came increasingly with the D8.
-The cold?
-And the flu and I got a lot of mucus out from the nose and a lot of clear water
and a lot of lacrimation, I could hardly go outside, I was so photophobic.
-The lacrimation was so much?
-Yes and I was so sensitive to the light.
And then I had a lot of abdominal pain and distended and a lot of gas.
-The pains in the kidneys came for the third time?
-I don’t remember. It was like coming and going, when I was coughing and
if I was a little bit cold it was more pain in the lungs and also extended down in the …
and the sinusitis and congestion in the head, in the whole area.
And I got really long period of sneezing and sneezing and sneezing
and I normally don’t too much.
-Do you feel dryness in the mouth?
-Yes because I’m nervous.
It was hard to breathe all the time through the bigger remedy
because the dyspnea was there all the time and breathing it was painful.
-And burning?
-Yes burning pain.
The kidney problems started again. And the feeling of no energy
but worse I got depressed and I got into … I felt apathy and hopelessness and worthless
and no self-confidence and all these things that are normally…
it was very much increased. And it was hard to walk.
-Because of the dyspnea?
-No, no energy.
And the muscles felt so weak, it was hard to stand on feet .
I went a couple of meters, I had to sit down and I was sitting and lying down most of the day
and some suicidal thoughts came back, a lot of apathy.
I didn’t want to live, I was very much back into that. So I stopped the remedy there.
-So you took the remedy 1 more week?
-No, I had the D8 for 1 week.
-And then you stopped?
-Yes, when I was so much into this suicidal thing.
-And then what you felt, how you feel now? How long is since you stop the medication?
-September 12 I stopped the medication and I was also thinking of being able to come here
and in that condition I couldn’t have manage, so I slowly got better
and my appetite increased immediately and the cold was getting better but I was coughing a lot.
A dry cough and almost like throwing up and some itching started everywhere.
But the fever kept on for a while.
-Fever as feeling, not real fever?
-I didn’t check it again, I was exhausted, no energy, no strength but from the 4th day
after I stopped, I started getting better and I also have been getting better since I came here.
-I wanted to tell me how you feel mentally because that was the main problem, the concentration.
-Mentally I don’t think it has changed much.
-It hasn’t change. So you are having the same problems of concentration,
confusion in the mind or you have forgotten perhaps?
-No, I do feel better in some ways because before I started the remedy I went on for 9 days
of fasting and changing my diet and I’ve done that many times and I always feel calmer,
feel better, not so intoxicated.
-Before starting with the remedies?
-Yes, so I did that and finished before I start.
So when I do not eat a certain kind of food I feel more clear, more alert, not so intoxicated.
-But you said that after starting the remedy, you did not eat because you lost your appetite.
-Yes, I ate much less.
-So why didn’t you feel better during taking the remedy if you were eating less?
-I felt the same as after fasting, that part did not change starting the remedy,
it went physical, but it came with the flu I guess the feeling of emptiness in the head,
maybe I don’t know.
-What you are saying now is that you had a reaction with the remedy, all this flu type reaction
but your mind was not affected during all this period, before the remedy or after the remedy.
-No I felt I started clearing immediately after I changed the diet and that was before and I kept…
-But this clearance of the mind continued or no?
-It was not much of it but I had this change with the flu, some days better, some days worse.
-How is your concentration now, here?
-I can concentrate, not always but the forgetfulness is the same.
I have to work myself up, I recognize very much the Causticum case
because it is difficult to put words to it if you are like this all the time
but when you said about to let yourself able to relax, I felt this is just how I feel
because if I do that I get empty. I have to get adrenaline going.
I have to push myself to be alert and I do this a lot when I’m here, if I let myself relaxed
I go off in a dreamy state. So push, push, push.
-It seems that there is a kind of redness in the face and in the neck.
-Excitement.
-You did not have that last time.
-I’m nervous.
-Because you are nervous?
-I think so.
-But last time you were more nervous.
-Yes, maybe.
-This redness you did not know about?
-Sure, it comes fast.
-When you are under stress or under emotional pressure?
-Yes, if I have to hurry, I feel always in a hurry, if I’m late or if the time passes too quickly
and I don’t have enough time, I always … and if I feel these feelings I get all flash.
-Then this flashing goes away or it stays?
-It can stay for a while.
-How long? Days or hours?
-Not days, hours yes and I’m also very warm.
-So your cheeks are warm now? You feel them warm?
-Yes, very.
-Difficult. Do you want to say something else?
-I feel a lot of strain with being always late and I feel I can not keep things in order.
Everything is a mess.
-In your house?
-Yes and everything.
-What else you want to say?
Let me ask you something, do you eat fruits?
-A little bit but I don’t like it so much as before and I don’t tolerate it so much either.
-You have a diarrhea if you eat fruits?
-Sometimes yes and as if not digested properly and also a feeling of emptiness
and hungry after fruits.
-But do you avoid fruits, do you go and buy fruits or you never buy fruits?
-Sometimes, a little.
-What? Apples?
-Peaches mostly and pineapple juice.
-What is your diet, what you are eating mostly?
-I have some fish and try to avoid sugar and coffee and tea,
I can not have tea without palpitation and the pulses strong.
Also after a lot of food I get a lot of adrenaline and I get the same flashes, I’m warm,
stitching and sweat like needles after coffee and tea and also farinaceous food.
So I try to avoid these things and also sugar and bread, yeast.
-Mostly what do you eat?
-Mostly vegetables and some soya beans.
-Are you vegetarian?
-No, I have some fish but not meat anymore, no eggs, no milk but I have feta cheese
and it’s not so good. I have some diarrhea from having milk products.
-Sugar will give you palpitations?
-Yes.
-Do you perspire at all?
-I perspire very easily.
-Where is the first place that you perspire?
-The hands, even if it’s very cold I have to take off immediately when I’m out walking
and head, I can not cover head.
I have to take it off very fast in the winter. I freeze, I’m usually very cold
but the head I don’t want warm, I want to be warm in other places.
I feel very easily congested in the head.
-Do you have any fears?
-For this interview but not really fears, I don’t like to watch down from a high place,
I don’t like to get there, I get the feeling of being drawn towards jump, so I have to stay back
but still I would like to jump from an airplane with this parachute but fears I have to think.
-Fear of dark?
–No.
-Fear of thunderstorm?
–No, I love it.
-Which is the best time for you?
-In the night.
-Up to what time, up to 10 o’clock or you can stay up to 2 o’clock.
-I hardly never go to bed before 3 o’clock.
-And what are you doing from 10 o’clock onwards, you are out with friends
or you are in your house studying?
-I’m mostly staying at home but I can go out in the dark for a walk and meditate,
look at the stars, even if it’s very dark.
-And you feel good in the night?
-Yes, when the sun sets I feel my eyes open and when there is no so strong light
I can see more clearly the objects, I start to wake up.
-Is this the time that you would like to study mostly?
-Yes, I can not even try, before. I sit home and try to study before 7,8,9 o’clock.
-How is your sleep? You sleep right through the night?
-No, I wake up all the time and many times I have to go to the bathroom.
It was a little bit better, I got up less during the remedy.
-Do you have normal bowel motion once the day or you have to go several times?
-I used to have a lot of diarrhea but it went better lately. So I had to go a lot but now…
-So now in the night when you have to go to bathroom is for urination?
-Yes.
-And you drink quite a lot finally of water?
-Yes, after Phos I drink quite a lot.
-This is the way that you drink all the time, just one sip?
-No, I can drink more but not large, not big and not too cold. Then I get freezing inside.
-Fear of death?
-Not so much but I told you last time after an incident, I got some fear
because I experienced a kind of black out because I was suggested to go out of my body
and I could not control, I could not come back and after that I got some fear.
-Do you have another experience out of your body during this time?
-This time, lately no. I feel more centered.
-How you sleep, what position you take to sleep?
-Left side, no right side.
-And towards the abdomen?
-Yes.
-Do you see dreams? What kind of dreams?
-Yes, flying.
-Do you ever see that you fall while flying, you fall down suddenly, you jerk?
-No.
-Flying.
-But not so much, it has been a couple of dreams lately with flying
and also I had before but it’s not that I had a lot lately.
-There is any other pattern of dreams like water, like swimming, lots of water…
-I have dreams with water but there are a lot different things.
-Your dreams are vivid, you remember them?
-Yes.
-During this period did you have a relationship?
-Since last time no.
-You are still alone in the house, living alone?
-Yes.
-And you cook for yourself or you eat outside?
-No, I cook for myself.
-You remember you have said you had condylomata. What happened with these condylomata,
I can’t remember, can you remind me?
-It was almost 20 years ago and it was put something on that was burning it away
and they went away.
-And they never came back?
-They never came back.
-Did you have any warts on your fingers as a child?
-I don’t think I had.
But I have like small ... like often people have in the eyelids… in some places I get
and I have some warts like. And I seem to get a lot of spots.
-You feel more calm now?
-Yes.
-What you were afraid mostly when you came?
-Not to remember. It’s embarrassing not to remember.
-Do you have any feelings by the time of sunset, special sadness or anxiety
when the sun goes down?
-It can be both, suddenly melancholic or suddenly very accelerated, things changing fast.
-Would you say that your inner condition, the moods are easily changing?
-Yes, very. I can laugh and cry the next second.
But I feel that my main problem is the feeling of no self-confidence and worthlessness
I feel that this is kind of blocking me with going on with things.
-This feeling has come because of what? What do you think?
Because of your mother of how your parents treated you?
-Yes, because I felt very strongly I was not welcome to the world.
-The world did not want you?
-No, my parents.
-Your parents did not want you
And it seemed to be hard to…  I thought I’m already over this but it’s hard to let go with it.
-Would you say you are restless?
-Because of the hurried feeling I always feel that I'm late and all the time…
-You feel time passes too quickly?
-Yes all the time, that's why I always feel I can not go to bed because I feel during the day
I can not perform very much, I'm so tired, so exhausted and when the night comes
and I feel better, I feel I have so much to do, to catch up with.
And I try to push myself all the time to be able to do things but I can not hurry too much.
-You can not push yourself too much.
-Yes, I have to do things slowly. If the time is set, I have to meet someone, I get…
-Excited.
-Yes.
-Can you get a diarrhea from that?
-Yes. And if I have to get up early in the morning, I don't sleep very well.
-And the whole night you will be excited.
-Because I'm afraid I'm not going to manage to be on time.
-And that can keep you awake the whole night.
The fruits that you eat, the peaches and pineapples,
you prefer to be ripe and sweet or unripe?
-Before I used to really enjoy unripen fruits but not anymore. It doesn't feel good.
-Can you eat raw onions, they don't affect your stomach?
-Yes, they do but I take a little bit. I get very bloated.
I feel there is a problem with this eating and there is so much food I really don't tolerate.
I hardly don't know what to eat really, either I get very excited or accelerated from the food
or I can get very sleepy, just very tired after bread and food like that.
And the pulse can really double from 80 to 160, five minutes after eating.
-How is your menses?
-My menses are very scanty.
And also I feel the circulation is bothering me because if I sit too much, I feel restless
because it feels like circulation is …I need to move.
-What about your sexual desire? You don't have a partner but do you have the need to have sex,
to have some contact on that level?
-Yes sure but it has been less during this period with the remedy.
-It had been less. Too much less, not at all?
-Yes, I felt quite dead.
-Do you like sweets? You desire sweets?
-Yes, very much but after changing the diet now it's getting more normal.
I feel more peaceful and quite inside because I don't have this craving.
My blood sugar was much up and down and I feel much better; so I don't take any sugar now.
But I used to crave a lot for sweets.
-When did you stop taking sugar?
-Almost a month ago.
-Last time you were here you were still taking sugar?
-Yes.
-Now you don't take at all?
-No.
But I'm much better by moving and also dancing and these things, I'm much better.
It's hard for me to sit still.
-You like motion.
-Yes and because I get freezing cold by sitting, usually, with all this stagnation
in the blood and also a lot of pains from the venous system.
I have to lie down and put my legs up because of the pain. I can't stand still for a long time,
it also starts the pain.
-How much salt you need?
-It was a period that it was increased, I needed more salt but now it's less again.
I think after Phosphorus I wanted more salt but now it's not much but suddenly
I can put one salt but I don't need much.
-What is now your main feelings inside? Can you describe your emotions? You say
they are changing, up and down and you can be very happy or depressed? Something
like that you mean? If you wanted to describe, what is bothering you mostly?
What would you say is bothering you as feelings are concerned?
-Right now?
-Yes, like I'm very anxious or insecure. What is really bothering you?
Not this moment this last month.
-I worry to be able just to come to class, to get up in the morning, to perform.
I'm afraid to over sleep and not be able to attend class in time and things like that.
-Have you ever used cocaine?
-Yes.
-Lots?
-Not a lot.
-Is anything else you wanted to say at this moment?
-Maybe, what is bothering me most is an adult, I got to know a little bit,
I'm singing in a choir with him and he is only 25 and I feel such a connection in the soul
and it's very, very deep and very painful.
And he is so young and it's not possible. It's what is bothering me most, it's been for 2 years.
-For 2 years already.
And you feel that you have a very great feelings for him?
-Yes, as if I know him or it's very deep, it's very different from what I experienced before.
I just met him and on one second I knew it was a strong connection.
-What do you think, he has an interest for you?
-No, there was a little flirting but I told him I feel inside and he was scared.
He is 25, I'm 16 years older.
-You are 40?
-41
But I guess that is the biggest problem now, that grief.
-Specifically for that case, right?
You should enjoy these feelings, these feelings are good. Why not?
Even if there is a desperation.
-But I feel it's blocking me, I don't want to see others, I don't want to meet.
I want to get out of it, I want to move on with my life. It's stealing so much energy.
-OK, we see a little bit more clear this time.
Do you remember the case?
-Oh yes.
-Very well?
-Yes.
-Do you see any difference with this?
-A bit.
-Tiny.
-I would like to see a little bit 5 minutes of the case, so you get an idea also those
who did not see the case.
I want you to see a little bit because when we discussed her case we said,
if I remember well, that this was a very confused case and the confusion was coming through,
as an idea. Was this same confusion now?
I remember the general feeling was one of confusion and I believe in the analysis
I must have said how confused it's the case, no clear.
I felt that the main problem, the main impact of disturbance was on the mental level
and this weakness on the mental level and that's why I decided to give Picric acid, as she took.
She took Picric acid and she had that reaction, which she describes,
which is very interesting reaction, because it was repeated 3 times.
I was tending to say in the beginning most probably she had a flu while taking the remedy
but the second time she took she had the same reaction and the third time she again
had the same reaction.
So we have to admit that this reaction was from the remedy.
Now, as this is a confused case definitely from many points of view,
we are trying with the remedies that we are going to prescribe, we are trying to clear up this case
until we see some light.
In this case definitely there is a level of Medorrhinum, we hear it the first time,
we hear it now the second time, still we don't prescribe Medorrhinum, we prescribe Picric acid
and the question now is, is now the time for Medorrhinum?
-No.
-Still there is a strong symptomatology for Medorrhinum, the suppressed condylomata
indicating very strongly Medorrhinum and the better in the evening it's typical for Medor.
We asked about the sex desire, she says it has gone down rather
and definitely we see the possibility of another layer here, which is Thuja,
especially with the aggravation from onions.
So Medorrhinum and Thuja are remedies that we have to consider.
Then we ask the patient what is your real problem at this moment and she says 2 things.
One is that she has low self-esteem, she does not feel fit for this world,
and we perceive a deep sorrow that comes from the rejection of her mother primarily.
And we are going to close the case and then she says something very important.
I have grief. Why? Because of this young man.
And then we reconsider the case because at this moment this is the biggest problem of hers,
this is what she says.
I suffer because of that situation, you can't say your biggest problem is of this and that,
she says it now, in her conscious mind she says this is the problem and I can't break through that.
This holds me back and I can't progress.
We have to take into consideration since now it is expressed the problem,
it is expressed in such explicit way, we have to take it into consideration in order to progress
with the lifting up of different layers that we are going to do and if we do a good job,
in 2 years you may see a totally different person.
We have to do a correct job, is this a Thuja, is this Medorrhinum, is this Zincum picricum
because there is a restlessness and at the same time a mental fatigue.
Restlessness with mental fatigue, Zinc picricum or is it a case of Ignatia?
-I want to suggest Phosphoric acid.
-He wants to suggest Phos acid.
-She was sighing a lot and deeply.
-Therefore Ignatia. She definitely has the sighing.
-My computer 12 out of 18 rubrics are for Ignatia and there is another rubric,
stays long with disagreeable feelings in the past, so of course Acidum phosphoricum
is an important differential diagnosis but as I understood Phosphoricum
there are no feelings at all and what I feel with her is a deep sadness and a deep grief,
so I would give her Ignatia.
-Phos acid of course is a possibility but if we want to differentiate between Phos acid and
Ignatia, the first thing we will be looking is, the feelings are alive or dead?
Phos acid feelings dead.
Picric acid the mental is dead, there is no power, Phos acid the feelings have no power,
Ignatia has strong feelings which are kept inside and they eat up the person,
is a silent grief but the feelings are there.
As far as we have seen, did we see feelings with her or rather a flat in feelings?
Who saw feelings?
Strong feelings and romantic feelings. It is a platonic love affair, it's something
which she feels quite strongly because for 2 years she can not get away from these feelings.
She says these feelings are keeping me from progressing.
Now whether this has come up because of Picric acid or because of the diet, I will not discuss,
we are not interested at this moment. What we are interested is, do we have at
this moment a better picture? This is all that we're interested.
Are we going to become more clear? Is she going to become more clear in her picture?
And the answer is yes but which is the picture? Is it Phos acid, Med, Thuja or Ignatia?
And we have to differentiate between these and see what should have priority in her case?
What should have priority in her case?
-The grief.
-The grief because she says, I have grief and I have kept it inside and it's a desperate thing
because I can not even discuss the matter, it's not even proper, I'm improperly in love.
What she says is very interesting because she says, I'm in love madly in love
with a person with whom it is impossible to have an affair, so what is the state,
what is this state? What is this condition, in which remedy we meet this?
-Natrum muriaticum.
-In Nat mur we see this grief, this affair, being in love with somebody you can not have an affair.
So here we have into the picture another idea which is Nat mur.
Now the dilemma is, should we start with Ignatia and go to Nat mur?
That means this here will become actually like this. Here is the Ignatia.
Is this the strategy that we have to follow with her? Maybe or we can start with this,
see what happens, then give Ignatia and that is a problem that we have to solve.
-I thought Nat mur earlier, now the physical supports Nat mur more than Ignatia,
the hot palms, the sweating palms.
-No, she says I can stay in the sun, I love the sun and I'm freezing.
This does not support Nat mur, on the contrary.
This is against Nat mur at this moment, I don't know later.
I asked about salt, you remember? What was her answer?
I used to take more, now I take less.
Another point for Ignatia, not so much the food but the way she described changing in her moods,
she said absolutely.
So if we collect the information and we put it together, we  come rather to the idea the strategy
should be in this way.
Not clear absolutely but we have good reasons for prescribing Ignatia at this moment
with the possibility to be followed by Nat mur, why?
Because the grief is very deep and the rejection from the parents, she has received it very strongly.
Therefore I believe that after Ignatia there is going to be a time when she will need Nat mur
to continue with Medor and finally Thuja or perhaps another remedy,
I don't know maybe even Phos will come again.
But at this moment the remedy that we prefer to prescribe in this case is Ignatia 200.