-On the 25th of September last year I got Causticum C200 by you at 4.55.
I went back into the hall, sat down and the lecture began and I had the impression like an icy
cold wind was going through the room, a draft.
Then I realized  that if it would have been a draft, it would have gone on the other direction
and the other hand it was very warm in the room but it was so icy cold, there was a coldness that
was going along my vertex and was taking over the hall out the heat.
That was going on about 3-4 minutes and then I had the impression that I was sitting under
wave of pressure. An enormous wave of pressure, that was coming from upwards down
and would press me down into my seat. Like in a lift when suddenly the lift goes up.
And I had the impression I can’t stand up anymore but I could move hands and legs.
At the same time I had like a strong blowing of a wind in my head but it was going on for about
15 min. and then this wave of pressure would go down slowly, like a line.
When it reached by here for the first time after 15 years I had something that I hadn’t known
anymore, I had a free brain. And then I realized how I had been living for the last 15 years.
At the same time it was getting warm all over my body. I was craving to hold my neighbor and
he said, you are completely warm and when some days later my husband would meet me at
the airport, he would say, you are so warm, you must have fever.
That was the first time in my life that I felt hot, warm. That was the first day.
I was very tired and when I get to dinner that night I realized that I couldn’t see the greasy
sauce of the salad, I had to take any slice of tomato, take it out, clean it properly to take off
all the oily stuff.
The next morning when I woke up I had a very big pimple under my right eye and the whole
front was covered with little pimples  and that was going on for 4 to 5 days.
Every day, every morning a big pimple that was moving from here to there and after 5 days
the pain came on.
I compared it with fireworks. They were sometimes here, sometimes there without any order
without any systematic.
-Mostly in the extremities?
-No all over. Very much in the right chest, then the joints again, the knees, the hands.
The knees pains are always there, they have been on since I guess Causticum has been
acting and I evaluate the acting of Causticum concerning the existence of the pain.
At the same time my visual disturbances got worse. It happened to me when I was sitting
something that I haven’t had before. I said, what is going on? Do they have an earthquake
here, what is going on? Then I went back to Germany and during this week, after Causticum
this heaviness was gradually going down continuously.
After two weeks it was settled down on my legs but to such an extend that I could hardly work
anymore. When the traffic light was so green, I couldn’t manage to get across the road in the
time of the green. I had to stop the car so I could cross the road and I’m a person who is
running from morning till night but it didn’t work anymore.
My children went excited about it because they were used that when they would cry mama
from the second floor, I would jump up or when the telephone was ringing or the door bell
I was running from morning to night. And that wouldn’t work anymore.
In fact Causticum did what psychotherapists didn’t succeed for 9 years.
Finally my little daughter who is 9 years old said, I hate this Causticum.
This heaviness in my leg would go on for about 3 weeks; in the meantime I got warts but they
went back, later on. One morning everything was over. I could run again, I was nervous, I was
irritable, one of the children said, you act like addicted and for 3 days I felt like this.
First I thought what did I do to antidote the remedy and then I thought the remedy started
very quickly, so it ends very abruptly. For quite some time I didn’t think about it but now
afterwards I realized that I influenced the remedy a lot.
For example, once we had an accident in front of our house, a little girl had been hit by car.
When I heard the noise of the breaks, I went outside and said, for god sake where are my
children? And I saw this child in front of the car, I could see it was not my child but I was
paralyzed. In this situation, in the days following, I got quick again.
Some time later I repeated the remedy and it succeeded again and I realized suddenly that
the remedy was acting again even though I thought it had ended long before.
For example, when I had a good case, it was successful with the patient and my practice
and I was telling that in my family, then suddenly these shooting pains would come again.
Then I thought what could have been or what could have done that could antidote or ruin
the remedy? I have to say this, the first weeks with Causticum were like vacations for me.
I didn’t learn, I didn’t do anything, I didn’t do any exertion, I was just hanging out, like
vacations. And it was very unusual for me because I like to learn, even when I was an
interpreter I would learn a 100 vocabulary over night, just for joy.
-What I want to know is what happened with the conditions that she came to be treated here.
The neurological conditions, all this time.
-All gone, no more.
-Because you didn’t say that. You forgot to say that.
-That’s true. They were immediately gone, the visual disturbances first were worse and after
one week they subsided.
My disturbances in talking went on for about 3-4 weeks and then they were gone too.
Then I antidoted the remedy with a case that it really took a dramatic outcome.
I called this patient in the morning and then I got the bad news and when I hang in, it was
finished.
-From the patient?
-From the panaritium she got asbcess on the tonsils. I think I suppressed it.
-She interpreted that she suppressed.
-From one second to the next on that day, it was all over.
-Then what happened?
-Everything was normal again and this neurological disturbances never came back again.
I didn’t mention because I consider it not to be so important because I have a chronic
bronchitis. The two weeks that the bronchitis would come, it would stay for 3 weeks and
then it would take another 3 weeks to go away, to bring out all the mucus and then the
next bronchitis would start all over again. Three weeks after I’ve had antidoted the remedy
I started coughing and that was unusual. I didn’t know that before because normally I would
get rhinitis and my throat would get inflamed and then the cough would start.
I had a slight bronchitis over 5 days and it was over.
-Without medication.
That is good. Now you know why it was good.
-One month later I had a second cold and that time it started with the rhinitis and then sore throat
and then bronchitis all within one week. By that time we’re in the beginning of December and
then in the middle of December I had a terrible stress. I say terrible, it wasn’t terrible at all.
Just one colleague would quit my office but for me was a drama and I was all done.
I repeated the C200. I had again this strong blowing like a wind in my head but it was not
as it is pronounced. Some hours later, the pain started all over again.
That was going on for about 4 weeks and I think the remedy had a hard time because I was
so stressed to find a new colleague.
When the pains were over, one day I came home at noon with an attack of fatigue, of
tiredness, I took a 1M. That was in February.
-But during all this time, never the neurological symptoms reappeared from the very
beginning? It was only the acutes and the stresses?
-Yes. I think that the globules didn’t get dissolved when the pain started.
-Immediately.
-And that was going on for about 3 sec. and 3 sec. later the pain started again.
When I took the 1M I got a little slow again and this is gradually faded away till Easter.
And since Easter I realized I have lethargy in my brain. I do things automatically.
Recently I had a situation like this, I was going for shopping and then I didn’t buy anything but
like everybody else I would queue up and then it was my turn and nothing in my basket
because I didn’t buy anything but I didn’t realize.
Before Causticum situations like that were 3 times the day. And I realized how gradually it
calmed down again but the disturbances are gone.
I had a chronic cystitis but I didn’t really realize because I was always drinking a lot and about
two weeks ago, I didn’t have the possibility to drink so much and in the evening I said,
nothing.
-She thought that cystitis will start but it did not started.
-Nothing. Now I drink about half a liter per day and nothing happens.
Another thing that I didn’t mention is that I do have a low blood pressure. Margaret took my
-Always she had that?
-Yes.
-After Causticum the blood pressure went up a little bit or not at all, it just remained the same?
-I measured it about one week ago and then I had 110 to 70.
-Very good. Is she happy?
-Absolutely. What else did I have? My fatigue, my tiredness got very much better.
Sometimes throughout the day I had like holes, I could do anything anymore, I had to go to
bed and in February before I repeated the 1M, they came up again for the last time.
Now I can manage without sleeping in the afternoon and this is something new.
Another thing you asked me and I never mentioned it before.
You asked me if I lose some drops of urine when I sneeze or laugh and I said it’s not a matter
of some drops, it’s a matter of half a liter. And my sister was coming to see me and she has
the same problem and I always had these accidents when I was with her.
Over Easter I always manage to be on time going to the toilet. The urge to go to urinate is
there but it’s much better.
-What she means is she is not losing anymore urine?
-Hardly any or she manages to reach the toilet before the urine comes.
Another thing that turned up newly is that I clench my teeth.
-She can not relax the jaw?
-I can do it when I do it consciously but automatically I would clench my teeth again.
And I didn’t have that before. That’s all.
-Very descriptive, very dramatic. Thank you.
I don’t have much to say. She said everything.
Group 3, upper layer, going to this layer, we’ll see what happens. This is the idea, very good.
Do you remember that when I was analyzing her case, she was sitting there.
And she thought that I made some remarks for Uta that I had insulted Uta for not doing
correct translation. Then I had to apologize because she was strong.
She said, listen. It’s nice to put it back to see what a Causticum feels when he/she thinks
he sees unfairness, injustice, they can not hold back, they will attack.
She said, you do not know what we’re going through and I noticed this, in her analysis I put
that, you remember?
You have good memory. It was the final touch in her case. Wait.
From last time, no remedy. Causticum C1000 one year ago?
-No, one year ago  I received the C200 and between I repeated in 1M.
When I was here the last time I had reported that I had the feeling that again I was having
these empty stages. Then I went home again and about 1-2 weeks later, the following
happened.
I wanted to pick up a child from school, I was driving the car, I went to school, stopped, got
out of the car and took my child by the hand and I was walking back to the car with it.
Then I went into the car and left leaving the child standing there.
In the mirror I saw the child standing there but I didn’t react.
-When she realized that?
-When I arrived home. Thank god my kids are used to it and they come home with
somebody but the same day I went to my clinic and took 1M.
And it was gone immediately. After the second 1M, I developed small warts.
I had also had them after the C200. They developed around the eyes, they came out and
then they went away again, within 2-3 weeks, exactly the same reaction like after the C200.
-With C200 and with 1M the first time and then again the second time? Now they stay out?
-Now they remain. The way they are now, it’ not much.
-But this is the full? It’s not that they are half out now.
-No, they came out in the beginning and then they went back. So they were fully developed
for a time and now they are in the lower third concerning the development.
-Concerning the development is 1/3 of the full extend?
-Yes. Then the summer went on without any new things happening and when the summer
was finished, at the end of the summer, I realized that something incredible had happened.
I had reported that when laughing I always had a strong weakness of the bladder.
If you remember I had reported that no matter where I was, if I was in a restaurant, in a shop
out on the street, if I had to laugh my bladder emptied itself immediately completely.
Then I realized that this had been the first summer without any incontinence but what was
even better is that this hysterical laughing had also stopped.
I would say that the weakness of the bladder has become even worse. I already feel the
urge to urinate when I wash my hands but I’m not incontinent anymore.
Only then I realized how important this laughing was and how often it had occurred.
When for instance somebody told a joke, I laughed two or three times,
then peed into my pants
at the tenth time somebody had to mention only one word for a joke and it all happened
immediately. Sometimes already just a glance was enough.
I was laughing, I woke up at nights laughing until I almost suffocated.
-Remembering the joke?
-No, without reason. Sometimes I had pains sciatica and I was laughing due to the pain
laughing until the tears were streaming down my face.
And this laughing stopped. That was after the second 1M.
Today I can not understand at all why I never felt a problem with this incontinence.
Why I never discussed it as a problem. I had no feeling of shame with it; it was like
blowing your nose.
-Very interesting.
-When the summer holidays ended, I suddenly had very intense herpes without having a
cold. Usually when I develop thisherpes I always have a cold accompanied, this time not.
-Did she do something?
-Then a couple of weeks later I developed a cold, this time without the herpes. It was a
severe cold and what was special about – usually when our family get a cold, the children
get it, one after the other and the very last person to become ill is me – this time I was
ill right from the beginning, along with them.
This time again a cold without bronchitis. This is new since I got the remedy for the first time.
Twenty years ago they diagnosed me with chronic bronchitis.
The situation today is as follows: Again I have this emptiness in my head. It’s not a feeling
of having forgotten something. If I feel I have forgotten something, then I feel OK because
I can go and look what I have forgotten. It’s a feeling of complete disorientation.
For example, I couldn’t tell you at that moment, is it noon or afternoon.
I had the following situation this morning which happens in different varieties repeatedly.
I was standing in my room all dressed up and ready and then I had to think what is supposed
to happen now? I was holding my key in my hand and my view went from the key to the door
and I put the key to the door and locked the door from the inside.
Then I thought I wanted to go to the Academy and tried to open the door and I realized
no, you just locked it. That’s a typical situation.
I’m not able to make a connection between two situations.
Like I’m standing in the gas station and somebody is telling me your gasoline tank of your
car is empty, we’re not going to get home this way and I say yes and there I am with an
empty tank, I see the signal and I see the gas station but I continue. I don’t fill.
Next to this stage I also had in the beginning severe blackouts, these did not come back.
These disturbances of vision that the ground is moving up and down and I couldn’t walk
these also have not returned.
The only thing I have is the insecurity when walking if the ground is glistening.
Like the last days it had rained, I was a bit insecure.
I make mistakes in talking when speaking, always in the evening when relaxing.
It is exactly the kind of talking mistakes you made the other day, it always has to do with
words that are very similar, like you wanted to say Digitalis and you said Vegetalis.
They are back the 21st of August, I can tell you the exact date.
-What happened? Was any particular stress that took place two days before?
-No.
-When this eruption came out?
-Before school holidays in summer. About 4 weeks after the remedy.
-Was any thing that made her sad because the child did not go well to school?
Little things like that?
-There are permanently some small things going on, nothing special.
I had complained about strong fatigue, especially in the lunch break between noon and
4 o’clock. It’s still the time where I feel tired but it has got a lot better.
What has not changed at all is the intolerance of cooked food, warm food.
When I came here, one year ago, I only was eating raw foods, uncooked.
-Warm food aggravates.
-Then I thought Causticum will take care of it and slowly I started to eat normally again
and again I developed problems with my lymph nodes, the abscesses of my teeth started again
my lower eyelids were very swollen and the problem with the lymph nodes finally got so bad
that I woke at nights with pain and could not lie on the sides anymore.
After that bit by bit I went back to raw foods.
-Does she like raw food?
-Yes but I do like but living on this island here for the time being it means choriatiki [greek salad]
without cheese, morning, noon and at nights and in between eating grapes. That’s it.
-She likes fruits?
-Not especially. It’s difficult for me to tell you any clear food modality because I have such
frustration with my diet. I would like to eat some other things in between.
-Something which is warm, anything which is warm does not like or makes her worse?
-IF buy almonds in the super market sometimes which have been heated, I immediately have
an allergic reaction. My nose closes up. The only modality concerning food I can tell you
which is very clear, is the desire for oysters. I always had that and once I gave in to this
desire and during one meal I ate 70 oysters. The day after 50.
-And she was not sick after that?
-No.
-And it was cooked?
-Raw, with lemon. It’s clear desire.
-When our family eats oysters, I go from plate to plate and collect the oyster water.
After the first dose of Causticum I had a complete loss of my sexual desire and this lasted
for months.
-Now it came back?
-A little bit. It’s not an aversion. I’m just absolutely not interested and I don’t understand
what it’s all about.
-She was interested before?
-I never approached a man like a lioness but it was better.
What I like very much and I think it already happened after the first dose of Causticum is
that I don’t have the feeling anymore I have to dance on many different weddings at once
as we say in Germany. I can easily say no and not do something.
I also stopped making thousands of plans. I usually belong to that kind of people who
constantly initiate some citizens activities and so on.
-Social mostly?
-Not only but usually I don’t carry through them because I don’t’ have the energy.
-So she stopped doing that?
-It was one specific situation and after that it never came back. I studied germanistic.
-She studied German? She is German?
-No I am French. I was driving with the car and my thoughts went around the issue of how
to do with the slow fading of certain grammatic thing. I said that is going to be the issue of my
promotion, of being a doctor.
-Promoted?
-For a scientific publication which later on makes you doctor. Before I would have done
everything immediately to get things started. I would have looked for a Professor at the
University, I would have got my material ready, get ready to write. One of those thinking
was I was standing in a traffic jam, standing there for about 20 minutes. By the time I came
out of this traffic jam, the whole issue was over. Finished.
And I never again planned any of these things anymore. With such things I could easily
raise my blood pressure from 80 to 120. That’s all.
-It’s still like that but that’s something I forgot to write down. When I started coming to
-Can she tolerate something around her neck?
-No problem.
-She has said about injustice, she cannot support it, how does she feel about that?
-That has remained unchanged.
-Also she has mentioned that her tongue sticks to the palate.
-Yes I can remember it was a situation that my mouth was dry but not anymore.
-What about menses? She mentioned that they were intermitted.
It's still like that but something I forgot to write down when I started coming to
you the menses had become very little, only about two days of flow and after Causticum
it came again fully, like it used to. And it went backwards until I repeated the remedy
then it came fully again and then slowly it ceased and then after repeated again.
-How is the last time she had menses?
-Short, two days.
-Period it was in beginning of September?
-Yes.
-Again short?
-Yes, two days.
The same question, shall we wait, shall we repeat, shall we give another remedy?
-She did not put any ointment on herpes?
-No, she did not.
Wait 18, repeat 43, another remedy 1. Higher?
Higher 43.
We agree, this is the right answer.
She has a relapse. She proves also that she goes into relapses. We don’t know why but
anyhow she goes into relapses and anyhow she has some characteristic symptoms.
The relapses are milder and milder and therefore is a matter of the strength of the remedy.
So the remedy has to be stronger, it has to bring out these little warts.
Show me the symptoms that we put. Condylomata, urging to urinate frequently
spasmodic laughing, this should take it away because she does not have it anymore.
Spasmodic laughing that is the rubric actually for her. Eruptions, herpes, lips about
makes mistakes in time, in speaking, transposing sounds, weariness in the afternoon
warm food aggravates, abscess of teeth of roots, raw food desire, oysters desire
sexual desire wanting and can not support injustice, menses scanty.
Desire for oysters and raw food is there?
-Yes, three times.
-No desire for raw food.
-OK we take it out. Let me see the columns. Causticum, Lachesis, why? Explain Lachesis.
Desire oysters is very strong, warm food aggravates also is very strong.
So she has some strong Lachesis symptoms. But we say good bye Lachesis.
It is interesting another small remedy that we have to look. Lycopus which has two strong
desires of hers. They are in Lycopus, raw food and oysters desire.
If you take away from Repertorisation raw food, no change.
Therefore still she is with the symptomatology, she is still on the picture of Causticum
only on a milder level, on a better level but still on Causticum.
Therefore we go higher and we give Causticum 10M this time.
-Did you see the desire oysters in Causticum before?
-If I remember every symptom which I’ve seen, I would be with a head like this.
You know how many symptoms we can be adding in the Repertory? A lot, out of the
cases that we have seen these 50 cases, a lot of new symptoms.
These symptoms actually have to be noted down and confirmed. And yesterday was a
symptom about sea sickness, I said you can put it in the Repertory. That was cured really.
It was very strong as a symptom and very clear and because it belongs to a totality, then you
take it out.
Don’t take symptoms into consideration when there is one symptom, just the change of a
symptom, you don’t take it into consideration but when you have a curative reaction and you
have a clear symptom which is gone clearly, then you noted in your Repertory.
-My husband is Causticum too and he has enormous desire for oysters.
-Yes?
-He can eat 50 oysters at the time.
-But in order to put this a symptom of Causticum, it has to be cured by Causticum.
That means I will take into consideration as a Causticum symptom when she says after
2 years perhaps that I don’t have anymore desire for oysters. Only then I can consider it
for Causticum. Otherwise I will consider that it belongs to another remedy which maybe will
be needed in 2 years time. I have seen desire that goes very slowly away.
Desire for milk and it can be 2 years, desire for salt it can be 2 years before the patient says
I need less salt. Because it’s habit, it’s tastes, it’s different other things which play.
First of all I’m doing fine and this is the first time I come for follow up without having a relapse
on the neurological sphere.
Before it was always so that if I had an acute state, afterwards I always would have a relapse
that I don’t recognize my house anymore or miss an airplane. Since my final follow up in May
after which I repeated the remedy, I had four months in which I had three acute states but
no relapse at all.
First of all when I was here for the last time there was something that I did not report
because it had only happened once and I did not memorize it.
When I was going for walk I had developed sudden stitching pains in the lumbar area of my
spine and I could not continue walking. My husband drove me home, I had problems
getting in and out of the car but then I took a hot bath, it disappeared and I just forgot
about it. In the beginning of June I developed tensions spasms in my shoulder and cervical
area but it got so severe that within three weeks, I was not able to move my head.
Neither to the right, nor to the left, nor down, I couldn’t read anymore, I could only turn
entirely, I could only move like a statue. I consulted an orthopedic physician and he said
I cannot do anything because everything is so tight. I couldn’t even tolerate a massage
because the pain, the tension was so strong. It was shortly before I wanted to go on
vacation and I would have to drive 1000 km with my car.
One night, in the middle of the night I had this panic thought. What do I do? I can’t drive.
And since I always carry Causticum with me, I just took three pills. The pains were gone
within 10 sec. and I regained 80% of my ability to move within about 10 min.
And I went on vacation and I took care of the rest and then I thought I really had 8 children
with me, that was not really the way to relax and recover but then I thought now I will be
better when school is starting again and I’m getting rid of the kids but I got even more
tired.
One day I was standing in my kitchen working. I must have made some wrong movement
I don’t know which one and I tried to redo the whole thing in front of camera.
I couldn’t move anything except my hands and my feet, those were the only parts.
a couple of min. I felt how my circulation was going down, my eyelids got really heavy
and I felt if this continues I’ m going to faint. I could not have called anybody, I couldn’t
reach the phone, so again I took out my little pills of Causticum. I took a couple of pills
I don’t remember how many. Immediately I was back. Maybe it took 1-2 min. and then
I could breathe again, after 2-3 min. the spasms disappeared, the head was free again.
And after about 5 min. I stood up erect.
The dorsal area was free but still I was inhibited in my motion.
Lumbar and sacral region were stiff like concrete.
After the shock I had to sleep for two hours
I woke and the lower region was stiff again, similar the next morning and the next morning
I was absolutely exhausted. The only thought was back to bed.
I took a 50 M and within half an hour the pain in my lumbar region disappeared and after one
hour the pain in the sacral region was gone and after 3 hours I had my energy back.
This was in the middle of August.
Then I felt quite well and suddenly at the end of August it happened again.
Quickly, day by day the energy went down and one day it was so severe that I went back
to bed in the morning because I could not stand anymore.
But I couldn’t sleep, then I had lunch thought it maybe that would make it better and it didn’t
work, so I went back to bed but still I couldn’t sleep and I could sense this is no normal
exhaustion. So I repeated what I always carry with me, a 10M and 5-15 min. later I was back.
That was two weeks ago and since then I’ve been quite well with it.
On my way travelling to Alonissos, just before, I got a cold. The first one this year.
Before Causticum it was one week of fatigue, then 6 weeks of bronchitis, then I had
And the cold I got now lasted for 3 days.
After the cold when it was over suddenly one night I had an attack of irritating cough.
It was so intense, it lasted for half an hour, I thought it was tearing apart my mucus membranes. I just grabbed my little bottle and sniffed at it, it stopped immediately.
In general I would say, I think I’m more hungry than before.
-You put 1 kilo. You don’t know?
-I don’t weigh myself and I’m not as chilly during the night as I was.
After the repetitions of the remedy, I had some symptoms which also disappeared.
One of them was that I had a pain in my joint when opening the mouth, I had a whistling
noise in my left ear and what is new, since a while now, is that I wake in the morning
at 5 o’clock, I’m awake, refreshed but if I get up then, I go downhill again within
half an hour. And if I get up at 7, I’m tired.
Most probably is either here or here.
-She goes back to sleep?
-I go back to sleep, then I wake up at 7 and I get up, then I’m tired.
Her pathology, you remember what I told you in the very beginning of the teaching?
Basically it always has been like that; I had these sudden drops of energy.
Just, before I went down to a much deeper level.
I have the feeling that I would be doing better if I could repeat more frequently.
On the other side I’m a bit timid to repeat these high potencies so much and I just wait
quite a while until I take them and that’s why I have these ups and downs.
-It’s good she waits because then the remedy acts. The picture is there and if she takes
it too early, maybe it will have no effect.
Thank you.
I want to say a few things concerning her case, concerning the groups. 1,2,3,4 where is she?
Is she here? No. Is she here? No. Is she here? No. Yes. Is she here? No. Yes.
The idea is that in spite of the fact of having severe pathology in the beginning.
That you may have severe pathology in all these groups. Here you have cancer, paralysis
everything.
The same you have here. The difference is that here the remedy is clear, the remedy stays.
Here, you need a lot of remedies.
She has severe pathology which is on the nervous system, central and peripheral and the
remedy stays the same when the pathology from the nervous system, central and peripheral
goes into the muscular.
What she describes is muscular cramps of different types. So the muscular system now
takes the impact of the disease, of the focus of the disease; yet the remedy is the same.
So most probably she is on that level, upper second level.
In spite of the fact she was looking one of the most severe cases. She says oh my god.
Yet the remedy was clear. The remedy stays, that is a very good sign.
But you saw how you can, more or less, place the pathology. Because in the beginning
you say, how do we know, how do we place? Immediately you know where it is.
Here you have acutes, she is going to have more acutes. Most probably she was here
and now she is here and perhaps soon will be on that level. The same remedy.
What is your prescription now? Change the remedy?
Another interesting thing is that you see, when the organism is really in a good condition
it makes a clear picture and then it’s very sensitive to the remedy.
She even smells and there is an effect.
You like it to be like this but not everybody is lucky.