-Αt the moment my biggest problem is that I forgot my notes at home. I put everything
down and left it at home. In the last days, I try to remember I put new notes but I don’t
know if they are complete.
First I want to tell you some mind symptoms and then some physical complains and
I think only later on I am going to unpack my real, big problems.
I’m afraid I’m going to cry a lot, that’s why I want to say the other things before so
that they will not flow away with my tears.
For already quite some time I have problems in remembering.
My memory is getting worse. I have a hard time in remembering names and that’s
getting worse and worse.
-Yes in what else she does not remember?
-Sometimes I start to mix up words and letters, when I talk and when I write.
Or I only realize that when I’ve already written it, I say I mixed these two letters.
I should have done it the other way around or when I say something, in the moment that
I’ve spoken it out I realize that I mixed it up.
In my head words are OK, they are right but what comes out is quite a different word.
-I see.
-That troubles me, worries me because maybe there is something wrong in my head.
Forgettable and besides this I have different kinds of pains.
-These are the big problems she mentioned or there is a big problem coming later?
-I sometimes have vertigo when I ‘m tensed or when I’ tired but sometimes just like this.
-When she has vertigo, things are turning?
-Dizziness and for a short moment I’m going from side to side. I have to concentrate very much to be
Especially if there are a lot of different noises in the room, as if my hearing is scattered
and I don’t really get any message anymore.
My ability to see is diminishing too.
-How old is she?
-54 this year. At night and at dawn I only can see badly, I have hard time to see.
Grey colors I can only see very little. I’m afraid to forget something important.
I make a lot of notes and sometimes I forget my notes.
I have pains in the right wrist, when I write and whatever I do from this hand.
It gets better when I apply something warm but sometimes I have to grip it tightly.
Sometimes I have pains here in the middle of the hand and at the root of the hand
so it can hardly grasp anything. Sometimes I have pains in my lower arm.
It feels like I hit it or like somebody hit it or like it’s broken, the pain is to my right shoulder
but not permanently, not constantly and pain in the left shoulder too.
Sometimes here, sometimes there.
The pain on the left shoulder on scapula feels as if it was broken.
Pain like broken or bony pain are sometimes to my right hip, hip joint.
It is as if something working in my bone and aching.
-How many remedies she has taken?
-For some time I’ve been in homeopathic treatment of a doctor and I got quite
some remedies, quite a number of remedies.
-We have to know all the remedies.
-I don’t know all of them because she didn’t tell me although I asked her to tell me.
I can remember some of them. The first was Ignatia 10M.
After this I was crazy for half a year.
-So that means she was worse?
-I was terribly anxious especially when I was moving, when driving a car.
-Under Ignatia?
-Yes.
-And now she is not anxious anymore?
-Much less but I have different fears. When I took Ignatia my worse fear was
when I was driving a car and another car was ahead of me. I was always afraid
that the next moment I would hit him.
-How does she know that this is from Ignatia? I don’t understand.
-I didn’t have that before.
-Yes but we develop symptoms. Does she have any reason that this is from Ignatia?
She took Ignatia one day and next day she developed that symptom?
This has nothing to do with Ignatia.
-No, I took Ignatia and then gradually this symptom developed.
-And she never had that before?
-No, I didn’t have that before but later on, many years later I got to know that when
I was a little child, somebody hit me against the wall.
He pushed me against the wall and I see some connection to this.
-So from Ignatia she did not have a positive action. She had a negative action.
-I see it this way.
-What else she remembers?
-After Causticum I realized that I lost my big fear of dogs. That wasn’t suddenly.
Just I realized that I can pass a dog without being afraid of it.
After Causticum too I realized that my vertigo in high places got very much better
almost even gone. And before all my life I remember that if I was just 1m above
the ground I was very dizzy.
-With Causticum this was gone totally?
-I realized when I was painting the windows of my house, in the first floor, I had to go
outside of the window on a small window pave and that was OK.
-From Causticum she did not feel in general, better?
-I felt the courage to struggle, to fight for myself.
-She never took it again?
-No.
-What potency it was?
-C200 I think. 30 or 200.
-And Ignatia what it was?
-87.
-That was the first remedy Ignatia?
-Yes.
-Can she mention first all the remedies, then I ask?
-Pulsatilla, Natrum muriaticum, Kreosotum from this homeopath and I don’t know
what else she gave me.
-How many other times she took? 20, 50? Any other effect from the remedies?
-From Pulsatilla I had to cry a lot and my knees were aching.
-What year was Pulsatilla?
-Before Causticum.
-1989? Natrum muriaticum she had an effect?
-I was crying a lot but I have a lot of reasons to cry.
-Then Kreosotum had an effect?
-I got Kreosotum because I had colpitis, discharge from the vagina.
-She had vaginitis, she took Kreosotum, what happened?
that I couldn’t walk.
In the beginning of 1990.
-After Causticum?
-Yes.
-Can she remember if this was because of Causticum?
-I can’t really tell exactly because I have my notes at home and the homeopath
didn’t answer me to my request to tell me what I took.
-First of all we want to know all the remedies, second we want to know what was
the effect of each remedy. Otherwise her case is a mess, we cannot proceed.
Actually we have to stop. What is her real problem?
-It’s my childhood, I’ve dealing with a lot of problems and I’ve been working with
these problems. I am at the point where I get stuck. I don’t really know how to proceed.
-What are these problems?
-I have to cry a lot and I have the impression that this problem is eating up my energy.
-Who told you that? She has been to psychoanalysis?
-No.
-Never?
-I did psychotherapy for 2 years but I went in search this psychotherapy because
I was fighting with this problem by myself for so long.
-She went into psychotherapy for 2 years, the problems were there before and
remain after the psychotherapy?
-These problems accompany me throughout my life and after the psychotherapy
I could understand a little bit better but the problem remained.
-There is no change. Can she describe the problems or she does not want to
talk about?
-Yes I want to, that’s why I’m here. Since I’ve been in this life I had real
difficulties. I had a difficult start, my family didn’t have the room and the love to
accept me. I was born during the war time and my mother was very disappointed
that I wasn’t the desired son. I am the second child, I have an older sister.
We were away from the place where we normally lived.
-I don’t want such details. Essential things if she can tell me.
What made her being so sad. It can not be that she was born in the war that made
her sad.
-My grandmother was responsible for looking after the children and she was a very
rough person and she would hit me. I had the impression she hated me.
-What else?
-I was constantly afraid as a child, I never felt secure at home.
-Because of the grand mother? Her own mother she did not protect her?
-No. My mother was working, my father was not at home anymore and my grand
mother was as such.
-So the problem is because her grandmother was hitting her without reason.
-It’s connected to this.
-I don’t understand.
-The problem is that my mother is living near to me since 10 years and I have a
hard time dealing with this and our meetings and our confrontations, I don’t really
know how to deal with this.
She probably wants something from me and I just withdraw from this.
I want to be friendly with her, I want to have contact with her but just on the surface.
Mother is 84.
-What is the big problem?
-That I can’t make myself free from the demands of my mother.
She wants that I’m there for her, that I look after her but this is impossible for me.
-Let’s go to another issue. How she feels? She feels anxious, she has fear of death?
She feels sad, depressed, irritable? What are the feelings inside?
-My mother demands my caring for her and she never looked after me.
She never cared for me and now I can’t give it to her but she demands that
permanently.
-Therefore she has a guilty feeling because she can not.
-I don’t want that, I can’t do this. For me it’s a big feeling of injustice that she wants
things from me that she didn’t give to me when it was appropriate time.
-She wants to punish her mother now?
-No. I just want to be left alone by her.
-That means when her mother says, I have this, I have that, why don’t you come to
look after me, she feels the pain for that and then she wants to withdraw from that pain
or she doesn’t feel anything?
-I don’t want that she constantly grabs at me, I want that if she feels good and she is OK
but I want that other people look after her, so that she is fine and I want that she lives me
alone.
-But why?
-When my mother is in front of me and starts moaning and lamenting and complaining
I only can withhold that for certain time. Then I get very little again and I’m in the old
situation. I’m in despair. I want to leave that early part of my life behind me.
I want to live my present. I want to face my duties and the tasks that come up to me and
I want to live the now.
-Is she married?
-I’m divorced.
-She has children?
-Yes.
-How is she doing with her children?
-I have one daughter, we care for one another and we can live for one another in peace.
It’s a balanced and good relationship but with my mother I have the impression she
demands from me and she is clingy and I feel that it’s a big injustice.
When she complains so much about me then I fall back into my childhood, I get so much
depression.
-She falls back to her childhood means she remembers what was the situation by that
time or she feels like a little girl unprotected and things like that?
-I feel exposed to the violence that my family did to me.
-I didn’t follow exactly.
-That means she is living the memory of violence?
-Yes, these are horrible memories and then I can’t stop crying but it doesn’t help, it
doesn’t make it any better.
-But she feels that they have done a great injustice to her.
In which weather she feels good.
-Not to hot but I like the sun. I can’t tolerate sun on my head.
-What about cold, wet weather?
-I’m freezing when it’s cold but when I’m dressed up warm, I can tolerate.
-I didn’t ask cold, I asked cold and wet. With her arthritis she is suffering or no?
-When I get cold in my body, then I’m suffering.
-In which weather she feels best with her arthritis?
-A little bit of sun and a little bit of wind. Not too hot and not too cold.
I can’t tolerate humid in my body. Any drop of water I have immediately to put away
even in hot summer.
Too in the house my task is to go and see families and sometimes in these families I have
to prepare bath for a little child and for infant and then I have to prove the temperature of
the water with my hand and when I take out the hand, I immediately have to dry it.
But I like to go for swim in cold water. But when I get out of it, I immediately have to dry
myself.
-Does she take sweets?
-Little. But I like salt. I put it on the palm of the hand and I eat where other people would
eat sugar.
-So much. Does she eat eggs? – Little.
-Was any other trauma in her life except of her grand mother hitting her?
-The injustice of the punishments.
-That is the main thing.
-That really can’t forget.
-OK.
The problem with this case is, for instance, the correct remedy was given somewhere in
the story and then it was spoiled.
Then the action of the remedy was destroyed.
This can be a very mixed case. The reason is that the correct remedy was given in the past
and then followed up with all other incorrect remedies and as a result, we have nothing.
Do you understand?
Which is the correct remedy?
-Causticum.
-Causticum was given, she did not realize the homeopath that after this reaction, when she had
this terrific discharge, that is a very good sign. You don’t go and cover it.
And then of course you give the second wrong remedy and the third, the fourth and the
fifth and then you have a mess.
I didn’t want to take the case because taking such a case it will take 5 hours before you
can understand what is going on. 5 hours you need at least.
Then, if you are not experienced, you are totally lost because all the symptoms of the
Materia Medica will be there.
Therefore I had to make … Margaret pushed me to take the case. I said, forget it.
If we don’t know the remedies, we don’t know the reactions, how do we know what is
going on?
Then when I hear she was given Ignatia and she had this, what?
Then she was given Causticum and two symptoms left. It was fear of dogs and the other
one was vertigo high places. These are two symptoms, one is a fear and the other is a
general symptom which can not be affected without the whole organism being affected.
That means the Causticum had a positive effect.
She, herself did not understand, the homeopath did not understand, soon after that other
remedies followed and were given.
Eventually the effect of the Causticum was that she brought out the discharge, beautiful.
You leave the discharge there. If it’s a case like that, you try to cure the discharge?
Forget it. For how long? For 1 year, 2 years, let her have the discharge.
Burning? Yes. Burning inside is much worse.
The problem which makes me irritable and makes me impatient, I have been trying to
teach and teach and finally I see simple, basic things are not followed.
You give the correct remedy and still you can not recognize it. This is very unfortunate.
Then I get very irritable because I know how difficult it is to bring back such a case.
The two symptoms of Causticum are missing now. Fear of dogs and vertigo high places
are missing; what do we have? The injustice.
Therefore what has happened?
-I don’t understand. In these difficult cases which people mess up themselves, your
patience seems endless and in this difficult case where somebody comes for the first
time, you have none. That really hurts me.
-I must apologize. I must give you an explanation.
My impatience came not from her. It came from wrong way of treating with Homeopathy
and my despair was equally big with hers when I saw I can not help her.
Then I got irritated, why? Because I saw why this case is in that condition.
Because of wrong Homeopathy.
I didn’t want to take up the case because it was messed up and then I was irritated that
I could not help, sorry.
Of course it appeared as if I had something against her. No I wanted to help and I was in
despair; that is the reaction.
Then unless I got so angry and shouting, I would never have found anything.
I would just say bye, bye. Because I got angry, maybe I will help her.
So for me it’s not a matter of handling. It’s a matter of being able to help.
And being able to help is not always to be nice.
Sometimes you have to be very aggressive.
Unless you’re aggressive, you don’t get the facts. For 5 hours we can be working there
we get nothing.
Either I had to say, out or I had to act in this way, for her own benefit.
But you are free to act in these cases, as you please.
I don’t ask you to follow my method of treatment and my method of treatment is
individualized as much is the remedy individualized.
Each one has a method and this is the method.
You have not seen me before in this just because you have not seen me in all my cases.
There are several cases in which I have done exactly the same.
Unless I was very aggressive, I would not get anything.
I  would just go on, go on, I would be depleted totally in the end. I would not be able to
help the patient. When I became angry, and I said give me the facts, the facts came out.
I believe in this case also that maybe because of that treatment, maybe she will be
helped.
Now what do you prefer? Nice, nice man, then finished.
Everybody will be exhausted, everybody will know not to give the remedy, what to do?
In the beginning everybody is in despair. What’s the use of that?
Of course I’m in a state of Nux vomica because of too much.
-What potency?
-High potency.
-Concerning the remark that she was made, concerning the injustice to others.
First of all the moment she sat there and she looked.
We have to go back to Causticum I wanted to make you aware.
Maybe I will ask you to find where I describe in Causticum the intensity with which
they look. There is an intensity of look which is typical in Causticum and that is the case.
Did you see this intensity? Everything is there, in front.
And that is typical. When you look at her, you say this is a case of Causticum and then
she tells me that Causticum took two symptoms out, only two symptoms out?
Then eventually it comes out that the discharge was there.
When it was the discharge? We don’t’ know, we don’t remember etc.
But most probably this is what happened and then the idea of injustice where it is unjust
they can’t tolerate, this is whether it is on yourself or on others, this is Causticum.
The idea is they have done some injustice to me or to others, it doesn’t matter.
As we described, it it’s very seldom that you will see the injustice of Causticum in others.
Concerning the sympathy, how do you expect it. Here, I would project.
I will say that most probably the way she treats her mother is because she is too
sympathetic with the mother. She feels too much the pain and says, I can’t take it
anymore and she leaves. That is why she can’t pay attention to the mother.
She does not want a contact because the suffering of the mother is affecting her too
much, actually. It is the opposite of what she says. She says, I don’t want to help her.
It is because she feels the pain of the mother and makes her too sensitive.
Have I understood a little bit of the case, what do you think?
-A little bit.
-I was thinking about Staphysagria. More than Causticum in her case.
-Why it’s not Staphysagria? There is one point which she mentions and does not go
with Staphysagria. Which is this point? And goes for Causticum. Very strong point.
-When she was talking, she kept emphasizing how terrible she finds injustice.
She kept emphasing the fact of injustice.
-That we said. That is one point. One more point which you heard?
-Desire for salt.
-Desire for salt, such strong desire we don’t see in Staphysagria, we see in Causticum.
So the unfairness with the desire for salt it makes a case of Causticum, especially
because in the past Causticum seem to have an effect.
Now the main thing is injustice, desire for salt and then this intensity. It is a deep
Causticum case. I said OK if we give Causticum and acts, then we are lucky.
Also the fact that she behaves in this way with the mother, according to my
understanding, is because she is too much affected by her suffering.
She sees the suffering of her mother, I have this, I have that, help me.
That makes her feel very … You don’t believe it? It doesn’t matter.
-It’s also a physical area where her pathology is manifesting and I’m talking about
the joints. This slow weakening of memory, of eye sight, these are points which speak
for Causticum.
-Causticum is in pathology affecting the small joints especially. And also the slowing of
the memory.
-This feeling as if the bones were broken in the joints is a Causticum symptom
-Did you find it?
-Yes, it’s there. 10 remedies, one of them is Causticum.
-If I did not shout, you would never get anything.
You will see me sometimes doing that in despair.
Let’s see now the potency. Who suggests a low potency, under 30? One.
Who gives 200? 1M? 10M? 50M? CM?
In such a case you have to go high and wait and wait, don’t repeat in this case.
10M is high enough, you can try one time 10M.
-Just ask you which level would you give her in this?
-Third group in the middle towards the bottom.
Now in this condition she is in her mind, it is because of wrong treatment.
For me she could have been perfectly now with that original Causticum, if it was left
to act, I think.
-I would like to know why you don’t want to repeat?
-She is in a confused state. The organism is in a confused state.
So you give one remedy to see if the reaction will come.
If you repeat, this confused organism which receives this information as something
similar, not similimum, then the repetition will just modify some symptoms with no
real effect.
So you have to see if your choice of one remedy the organism is responding.
Because she is in a precarious situation. Her mind is quite broken down.
I would not say she is group 4 but she is middle 3. And you will see also how long
you have to let these remedies act before the patient will tell you, I’m better.
In such cases, you get a feedback in 1 month and they say mmm…
In 2 months mmm…, in 3 months mmm… and then if you have the courage to wait
after a year, you will see the organism coming back to order.
Who will do that?
-I want to understand why in this case we have to wait so long?
I remember last time in the case of Lilium tigrinum you waited, I think 3-4 days and you
said, forget it and we gave another remedy.
-Yes.
-It is because she is in the group 3 or because the mental state is so ill?
-The mental state is very disturbed deeply. Deep disturbance in mental level
you have to wait. Deep depression also, you wait.
reaction and the patients are very suffering and they urge you to do something.
Could it be a possibility to maybe give them Causticum in a D12 for example?
-If you find the correct remedy, you give it. But if you don’t see the correct remedy
you better leave it. This is the idea.
I don’t say don’t give the remedy. Give the correct remedy. It will help but be sure that
this is the correct remedy. You can. You may repeat, as long as it is the correct remedy.