-So you gave me the Mercury.
-It was Mercury solubilis 10M.
-You gave me the Mercury and I was dizzy for two hours and then after a few hours
the constipation was gone totally, no constipation at all.
Generally I felt very good, the energy was staying up and this state maintained
for 21 days exactly.
22nd day collapsed to the old condlition at one day, constipation, bad mood, angry, frustrated.
-According to you was any reason for this?
-No.
-You did not drink coffee? You did not have a shock?
-No. Anyhow I went for a few weeks and in these few weeks it was aggravation more and more.
Something which I didn’t tell you last time, is that I have skin rashes which come every few years.
The first time when I had it was when I was 8 years old, then it begun again.
The expression of these skin rashes are in the beginning on the forehead and in the nose,
then behind the ear and then all over the head. Then the skin begins rough, peeling,
very dry and hot. I feel as if I have to take a cube of ice and put it on the forehead,
so it will take the itchiness.
Then already in a few weeks everything was aggravating, the constipation, the mood.
So I took by myself another dose of Mercury 10M and then exactly the same pattern happened.
21 days everything is going. Energy is good, constipation has gone totally,
the mood is very good, 22nd days collapsed in one day like this to the old condition and
again aggravating, aggravating, aggravating.
I went a few more weeks, I see I’m feeling very bad, so I took another dose of Mercury 10M
and then the 3rd time not so much.
So I thought I wait until I see and see what to do. Then in these few months,
there was a peculiar physical symptom which happens.
First of all I noticed, when I was young I used to be athletic, all the time sport, to exercise
the energy out.
I used to sweat a lot, after running I was taking the shirt like this and water would come out.
This time I’m running for two hours and I sweat a little bit, no sweat.
And the perspiration is very oily. I take the shirt like this and is like oil.
As well I noticed when I feel cold, I feel as if the body does not produce heat.
I feel generally cold, shivering a little bit or I need to move but in this winter I felt
as if the body is a cube of ice and the body can not produce heat.
The discharge is still there and the pain around the scar area sometimes is still there.
It’s always aggravated when I feel stress. When I’m stressed…
-The pain was affected by Mercury these 21 days?
-Well I can’t really say if there was any change.
-So where is the pain? Around the prostate?
-I felt something peculiar. I felt a few times as if the prostate is becoming hard.
-What about urination? You had any problems with urination?
-Sometimes I feel pitching pain in the urethra, if the bladder is too full and after. Not always.
Every once in a while.
-So what is the situation at this moment? You said the 3rd dose you took is so and so.
-I still feel this kind of pain and the discharge reflects that there is still an inflammation.
-What type of discharge it is? The same as it used to be or the discharge has changed?
-I can’t really say. It comes only when there is the effort to give stool.
If there is no constipation, the effort is stronger, so there will be more discharge.
But let’s say when I’m travelling to India and over there the toilets are on the floor,
so because of the pressure there is more discharge.
-How is your sexual energy?
-After the remedy it was increasing and after some time it’s normal.
-Now at this moment that you are talking what is the situation? General situation.
-Generally I feel more energetic, definitely the level of the energy is rising up.
The constipation is less severe. Every day but still very dry and very difficult.
Something which happened after I received the first dose of Mercury is that the voice
changed totally. This thing I wanted to tell you about.
It’s bothering me from when I was 12 or 13,14.
Whenever I’m excited or feeling stress, the throat is talking but I cannot speak.
I swallow my words, I speak too fast and as if the voice can not come out.
And when I received the first dose I was amazed, speaking freely and fluently
and no disturbance at all.
This kind of difficulty to speak in a clear way, to swallow the words and to speak fast,
many times has put me in a seat of lack of confidence. So if you can consider this.
-What I don’t understand is, you said about this skin eruption that came since 8 years old.
Now after the remedy it came back?
-No, there was as well some sign of it before the remedy but after the remedy it accelerated
in the extend that I’m doing like this on the head and you see snow of skin falling down.
-So it accelerated very much for a period of time, of how long?
-For a few months and then I feel so much bad with it, so I used chemical shampoo.
-With Sulphur inside?
-Yes, Sulphur and Selenium. I used it twice and then it’s all gone immediately.
-So it’s immediately gone. When did you use it? On 21st day?
-No, something like 2 months ago. All the face, the skin was peeling and all the head.
Huge amount of skin, I do it like this and like snow is falling down.
-How many times you used this shampoo?
-About 4 times all together.
-On consecutive days?
-No, whenever it’s becoming more severe I use it. Then immediately after it’s going away.
As well on the face, I use it on the head and even on the face it will go away,
although the areas which are on the face are not…
-… are not affected by this shampoo.
-Yes.
-It came in the beginning all right and you left it for how long? One month,
two months before you use this shampoo? You left this eruption for how long?
-I tried not to use it at all because I didn’t want to disturb the remedy.
-Yes, in the beginning for how long? One month, two months?
-More about 4 months until I couldn’t bear it anymore.
About February I began to use it because it was too much.
-Any other changes that you have noticed? Are you more organized?
-When you gave me the first dose, the most dramatic change that happened, the things
which I felt the most emotional are…
The usual pattern that used to be before is that if I go into any kind of social circumstance,
immediately I feel threatened. I feel that people want to attack me. So I close in and I can
not communicate. Then because of this entering inside and isolation of myself,
what happens is that I begin to produce energy that makes me irritable inside.
This kind of irritability makes me extreme. Let’s say I will go to another country.
Now after the remedy I feel the trigger of being threatened but I can not feel irritable.
I feel hopeless of not being able to do nothing, some kind of helplessness,
I can do nothing at all, I’m trying to push myself into this kind of acceleration to do something,
to go and do, to become extreme again but I can not. The organism does not produce energy
which makes me irritable.
So I experience in myself a lot of helplessness. I can not do nothing, I am exposed.
-So it is good or bad?
-I feel it’s good because after a while when it happened I began to be more observing,
more settling down, more quiet.
Another thing which happened…
-Before you used to be sloppy with your things or you used to be organized, very fastidious?
How it was this aspect? You understand? Your things in your room were disorganized
or were organized very much?
-I would say there is a disorganized organization. Everything is unorganized but I know
where it is before it’s disorganized.
-There is any change after the remedy on that level?
-No.
-What about your sleep?
-Sleep is good. Still a lot of saliva.
If anyone comes and see, the pillow is wet and still a lot of aphae.
-You are a pure case of Mercury. Very lucky.
-There is something that I wanted to tell you but I forgot.
-How is your self-confidence?
-Still there is a big difference between how I am and how you perceive and how I feel inside.
Inside I don’t feel confident.
I feel very fragile, very weak and because of this I build expression of looking strong.
You asked me I saw a video a few days ago, from myself in the last interview and
you asked me then why I became weak? What was the reason I became weak?
Now I saw it and then I realized what made me so weak? What began this degeneration
of the physical energy.
And I remembered that somewhere at the age of 24-25, there was something in me which
was totally into a state of desperation because of not being able to succeed in
these spiritual activities which I was involved.
Let’s say 3 years in this spiritual practice and then 2 years in this one and then 1 year…
And then I thought that I’m putting all my life energy into this philosophy or dogmatic ideas
and then in the existence in myself nothing has changed. So I began to enter into a state
of total desperation, of feeling helpless and that was a point where I felt that the whole energy
is going down.
And this kind of helplessness, of putting all my life into certain life style which does not
really show, how I’m helped by that or how I’m saved by that…
-There is a big disappointment for yourself?
-Not for myself. All my energy is leading towards, let’s say, meditation.
Doing meditation for 2 years but after 2 years of knowing all kind of meditations
and all practices and all mantras and all everything, still I find myself in the same troubles.
And this kind of realization that I’m getting nowhere and already feeling weak and arresting
all my life in something that does not give food, brought me to a very weak condition.
And this is a situation where I can not feel confident in myself to, let’s say, the life demands
from me to do a contract. To build up my own clinic, I don’t have the guts to go and do it
because I don’t trust in me, because of all this exhaustion.
It’s a whole cycle of not being able to do.
-To accomplish. During this time did you ever have any metallic taste in your mouth?
-Sometimes yes and as well there is a very heavy smell from the mouth.
-This heavy smell is mostly in the morning on wakening?
-Mostly in the morning. If I eat something, it goes away.
-Tell me something, as a child did you suffer with ear infections?
-I don’t recall that.
-Neither now you have any problem with the ears?
-There is some, yes.
When I was 24, there was one winter in Jerusalem, where I lived where about 8 months
I bloated my nose. And so much I bloated my nose that something in the ears I felt is changed.
And since then when I bloat my nose, I feel pain in the ears and I feel that the mucus
is somewhere in the ears.
Generally I feel that the mucus is very sticky and it’s stuck on the throat,
I can not swallow, I can not spit out.
-Very good.
-What good?
-We’ll talk to the class. I will tell you.
In his case he related some strange phenomena. 21 days, boom, a relapse.
I’m not sure that there is a magical number there. 21 is the magical number but
what is interesting in his case and I said, you are lucky, is the fact that when there is
a relapse and the remedy you give, it works again and then a third time and it works again,
it shows that the organism is strong and this remedy is the main remedy for the organism.
That means the organism will make its best by this remedy.
So in this case you don’t leave the remedy.
You have heard don’t leave the remedy if it’s acting etc. but you have to know when the remedy
is really acting deeply and acting curatively and correctly and deeply and it’s going really
to make a big change.
In these cases in spite of the fact you may have a relapse, the relapse goes back
to the same remedy.
You will see in contrary to the other case we saw, this case is going to start with this,
is going to go there and most probably a remedy which will be needed is Thuja in her case.
Thuja will be needed eventually but we will see how she will develop.
In this case you give Picric acid, it’s not going to have the same effect as he has.
It will affect a little bit better, a little bit better and then starts I have this symptom,
that symptom, then you struggle, then you go and find out the next remedy…
When you have mental problems, you see he has also mental problems but his mental problems
are of more superficial kind, so the remedy can clean  this.
Also being Mercury he withdraws and can not speak.
He described very beautifully the stammering of Mercury.
Stammering does not have to be there. Stammering starts from the difficulty to express,
perhaps you don’t even understand that there is a difficulty and then it goes to real stammering.
This is the kind of stammering that Mercury can develop.
So you saw how he described it. There is something which holds me and my enemies,
mental, everybody is enemy, I have to protect myself.
This is characteristic and the aphthae is characteristic, salivation is characteristic,
everything is characteristic. It doesn’t matter now.
He can counteract the remedy by drinking coffee, whatever.
His remedy constantly will be Mercury.
These are of the lucky cases we said, they are going to live long. Very good.
-I think it’s rather strange that the remedy which acts so well, only acts for such a short time,
for only 21 days, if you give a 10M.
Is it either possible that the remedy was not potentized correctly or is one of the cases
who actually would need one dose every day.
-There are cases that they will need more frequent repetition. The remedy is clear and
yet it doesn’t hold. Then after 5 days, you need again another dose, after 10 days, after 21 days.
He made it sound as if 21 is a magical number, which is not.
It’s more or less an intellectualization because the 3rd time he is taking the remedy…
I mean, it doesn’t divide from 3 the 21, from 8 months in between.
So you took 3 times the remedy, it’s not actually every 21 days.
Because from September to May is 8 months.
He took it 3 times, he repeated. So it’s not every 21 days that there is a relapse.
In the beginning it seems to. Yet it’s the same potency, which it was repeated 3rd time.
Also it’s very probable… You see all the remedies I have here are all the remedies from
America. I have them here, there, in my house.
You can not have unlimited number of remedies and potencies.
Here I have kept the remedies which are brought from America by an old homeopath,
who had a nice pocket and said, somebody gave it to me.
This might be the case. The potency is not strong enough.
We will see, maybe MM will be the potency for him, which will clear up the case. Maybe CM.
The 3rd time he took it, it seems to be a better potentized 10M. From where you got this?
-From Israel.
-We will see.
At this moment of course, he has to stop putting the Sulphur.
I have seen this happening with Sulphur soaps, they can eliminate an eruption,
especially in the head very fast and of course we don’t know really whether this is a suppression.
How much of a suppression that can be.
Actually you have to leave it and see what happens, much longer. Because if it naturally
goes away, then naturally your body will stay free from the disturbance, as well.