-A young man, what is your problem?
-First of all the main complain right now is constipation, which begun one year ago.
The nature of the constipation has changed. Sometimes is 2-3 days, 4 days, dry,
very painful. The second main complain is some kind of inflammation, which begun
maybe 8-9 years ago; at that time I was in the army.
There was a hernia operation on the left side, which was operated in the army.
One year after the operation there was the beginning of a discharge.
While there is the effort to give stool there is discharge, very sticky and look like
sperm from the sexual organ. Only when there is the effort to give stool.
Since then there is a lot of pain in the scar area from the operation.
There is cicatrices.
On the left side there is a scar from the hernia operation. Since the operation there is all
the time a lot of pain in the scar area, very sharp like knife, as if the cutting is still there.
The pain of the scar remains since the operation and since the operation the doctors
told me there is a local inflammation, which probably begun at the local area of the scar
and developed to the prostate gland.
The sign of the inflammation in the prostate gland basically is discharge, only when there
is the effort to give stool.
They examined this discharge and they said there is a sign of inflammation from streptococcus
and staphylococcus aureus.
As well there was hernia when I was just born.
The history of the hernia operation is going like that. I was born with hernia which was
operated when I was 3-4 years old, it was on the right side.
And then the second one was on the left side when I was 20 years old, 9 years ago.
You told me to take Selenium in June. I took it but no help, no change.
-What is the next? What other problem you have?
-Physically right now this is the main problem, the problem which is worrying me at the
moment is the problem with the discharge, the inflammation in the scar area.
I spoke with a few doctors in Israel and they say, one of them said that it might put
the sperm into danger. So this seems to me right now the main problem to treat.
-Another problem?
-Basically I would say the last 3 years there is general weakness, something which
is chronic fatigue.
-So strong that it looks like chronic fatigue?
-This is the way I experience it because I remember myself with huge amount of energy.
I remember myself with so much energy, when I was from 11-25…
23,24 I had huge amount of energy, like a bomb of energy.
-And why you lost this energy? What happened?
-I don’t know, I can’t really say something specific, a general exhaustion, becoming
more and more exhausted.
-Yes but it must be a reason. Why?
-I can’t really say.
There is many incidents which contribute to this situation of being
exhausted, there is many of them actually.
-Like what?
-First of all I must say about the hernia operation in the army that at that time I was
under tremendous amount of pressure, really tremendous.
It’s really hard for me to describe how much stressful was at that time.
-Why it was stressful for you? You had somebody after you or you were afraid or you
didn’t want to shoot, to fight, why?
-First of all the army is stressful by itself, the army life is a stressful thing but
what happened to me one year before the army, I was born in a kibbutz.
-So you are a kibbutz boy.
-Unfortunately. Anyway the kibbutz is unreligious life style.
When I was 16 years old I changed all the structure life for myself.
I just left school I left my home, I left everything and I went to Jerusalem to some kind
of commune place where after that you become religious person.
-Very religious?
-Not very, extremely religious.
So when I went to the army there was a few vectors
of pressure, from many angles, the family, the religion aspect, the army aspect,
the personal aspect. From many angles there was a…
-Conflict?
-Conflict yes, I would say that but not only that, as well the objective like the family
and all the rest.
-Why the family?
-The family want me to become again non-religious and the people in the army they
couldn’t understand what is going on, so them as well gave me a lot of hard time.
And the religious people where I was then, them as well put on me a lot of stress
to do all sorts of things.
-Being religious you are not supposed to go to the army?
-Yes. They wanted me to leave the army and it’s a long story here.
-And escape.
-So I was in the middle of all that and as well, as you said, there was much conflict
in me about all those things of god, religion, different ceremonies and different issues
about life and all that.
-Life beyond death.
-A lot, I was busy with this. When I say that I went extremely into it, 24 hours the day
for a few years only with that, nothing else.
-And during this time you are not allowed of course to have sex or you are allowed?
-No of course, only when you are married.
-And was that a stress for you, that aspect?
-Yes very much.
-Because you had a lot of energy and then you had to spend this energy.
-Yes, concerning this thing I had a few girlfriend because I became religious, so at
that time when I became extremely religious this subject for me was very hard
to become celibate, it’s very hard for me.
As well people which I engaged then, they put on me all sorts of ideas as you go to hell
all this rubbish, you produce demon in the world.
So with that came a lot of guilt because of sexual feelings or attraction; with that there
was a lot of guilt coming.
But the hernia itself at the time when it happened I remember it’s very clear the way it
happened. It was very funny thing. I just walked in the army, physical walk and then
I sneezed and with this I felt it out of the intestines coming out.
-And it was operated you say at the age of?
-20.
-But you lost your energy at 24.
How long you stayed in the army?
-3 years. From 18-21.
-And then you worked or you went back to the religious group?
-I continued to be with them for 3 years.
-For another 3 years?
-I’ve been with this kind of thing for 3 years until I dropped it.
I’ve been with that for 3 years, with this kind of life style, of very religious.
-Which years?
-I begun 17,18,19 and 20 I left.
-So while you were in the army, you left the group. Correct?
-Then when I was 20 at the time when I left that religious extreme group, I went to
another group of spiritual search, which I met in Israel, I’ve been with them for 3 years
as well, another 3 years of very intense spiritual quest.
-Spiritual practices.
-Yes, all sorts of meditations and researches about religion, about colors, numbers
all esoteric subjects that you can imagine. I’ve been with them 3 years and then as well
I left them.
At that time I went to the States to be a counselor in American summer camps.
After that I went to Indian tribe, I became to be an Indian member.
-You lived like an Indian.
-Yes, I went to an Indian reservation and I lived with them for a few months,
for about 4 month and they accept me immediately, for them there was no question.
They did some kind of ceremony and god tell them whether I belong to the tribe or not.
So the chief told me that two months before I came to the tribe, he knew already that some
Israeli boy is supposed to come because god told him that this person belongs to the tribe.
-So you stayed with them for how long?
-For 4 months.
-But you could not stay anymore?
-The visa finished, I had to go back.
-You liked this place there?
-Yes, that place changed my life.
-You felt good?
-Living in nature, living in a totally natural tribe, living with the trees, living with
the rivers, with the birds, with the bees…
-Did you have to work while you were with them?
-Yes.
-What work you did?
-Everything but it’s not actually a work, it’s part of joining the tribal life style which is
you won’t do nothing which you are not qualified or don’t want to do. Whatever you will
do is coming out of yourself.
For long time we did many spiritual practices of the Indian culture and after 3 months
they want me to qualify me to become an Indian philosophy teacher because I read
all the library which they had, a huge room.
-You had specific interest on their life and philosophy? You felt at home with them?
-Yes, definitely. Very good connection, very immediate connection.
Immediately straight to the core and the essence and the meaning…
-And when you went back to Israel what you did there?
-Before I went to the States, I begun to learn Chinese Medicine.
When I went back to Israel I continued to study Chinese Medicine and I finished that,
I became to be a Chinese practitioner, as well I became to be teacher in Chinese Medicine.
-Something has happened in your health, I try to find out what was happening in your
health that brought down all this.
-When I went back from the States in Israel at that time I was still belong to the kibbutz.
Then there was something about argument about if the kibbutz would help me to study
Chinese Medicine or not, they say they won’t help me with this.
I say OK I leave. So I left the kibbutz and when I left the kibbutz I left without even 1 cent
to begin life. But then I had to pay rent of living in the city and as well rent of the school
and at that time I learned at the University first degree of human behavior.
So I learned with one University, with second University and I had two Universities to pay
rent, huge amount of money to pay.
-They were not supposed to give you some money?
-They were supposed but they didn’t and it was really small amount.
They gave me amount which is for 2 weeks living in the city, without doing nothing.
They gave me 150 $ to be precise. Anytime at that time I lived for 6 months with only
eating bread and I really lived for 6 months a poor life and I remember that after this
winter of living for half a year only with bread, the whole health condition really went down.
As well I lived at that time in a very old place in Jerusalem, in which the room was very
cold and humid and after this period of 6 months, I remember that was the main year
in which the whole health condition …
But what I tell you now is really a short cut of the story. It was many other things which
happened at that time, many other things, also spiritual stuff and groups and people
which I was involved of many kinds.
-During all these years how did you feel emotionally? You felt angry, you felt let down
you felt betrayed, you felt depressed, you felt anxious, you felt fears,
how you were feeling all these years?
-What do you mean all these years?
-From the time that you went to the religious group, 17, 18 ,19, then you went to the army…
You can say I felt this or that, can you give me an idea how you felt?
-I can’t really describe in one word but when it begun I was at 16,17 at that time the whole
life changed upside down and the main thing which happened at that time was an
avalanche or crisis or earthquake of everything which was in me, physically and emotionally.
I actually experienced in myself actual earthquake in which everything completed
destroyed becoming dust like and then it felt a need to rebuild everything.
At that time I was under very severe condition of depression and loneliness.
I would sit all along in my room alone.
-You talk just before entering that religious group?
-Yes, when I was 16,17.
-You shaken down was because of the kibbutz situation or because of your parents?
-I can’t really say, I can’t really see what is the reason for this thing.
Of course I can give you some explanation but I don’t feel it will be the actual one.
I can’t really put my finger, what was the thing which really caused it.
-While you were in this deep depression, you found that group.
-As well that kind of crisis I used to …
It’s slight difficult to explain because just before this kind of thing, of change,
I was the best in school, the best in sport activities, the best in learning and when
that thing happened everything changed upside down and I became from extrovert to introvert.
And all the energy which I had, and I had a bomb of energy, went from outside to the inside.
And I begun to write poetry, to paint paintings, to read many books but I mean huge
amount of books. If you know Jewish religion …
-It’s huge.
-It’s more than huge, it’s unnumbered books about god and whatever.
So I used to read, take for example the Bible and read it 50, 60 times.
-And then you enter that group and you felt better psychologically?
-No, I can’t really say, I don’t think that this group really changed something in the
emotional suffering, I don’t think so.
-So you felt lonely also?
-I felt very deep urge to search about god, about religion, meaning of life but I don’t
think that the suffering or the crisis led to it, I feel more that there was deep need to
go and really find a true answer about these questions.
Actually I still feel that.
And as well I must say that before entering in this group there was a lot of
self-destruction, a lot of alcohol…
-During which period?
-Before entering this group.
-At the age of 17?
-Yes, a lot of self-destruction with huge amount of alcohol until fainting even.
-Which you entered the religious group and you stopped all together.
And now you went to the army.
In the army how you felt psychologically?
-I felt very bad, more than terrible.
-Suppressed?
-I felt fear as if I’m going to die, that people want to attack me and in army basically
this is what you face. When this commando coming to you doing all sorts of things
as if he wants to kill you, he puts a bomb near your ear after you are running for 16 hours,
putting this gun in your ear…
-You have problems.
- And I entered into the army with a lot of conflict and psychological unbalanced condition
because of this religion and change and internally many things happening all the time.
-It must have been a lot of anger inside you.
How you express this anger?
-I think it was more fear than anger.
-Fear of dying, fear of destroyed.
-Fear of many things, I felt all the time under attack and under something bad is
going to happen, I felt a lot of insecurity.
-You felt that everybody is enemy to you, you didn’t feel friendly.
-I can’t remember actually but you can say that, it doesn’t feel foreign to me what you are saying.
-Do you have a salivation during sleep? When you sleep there is saliva coming out?
-It used to be much more, right now it’s less.
-Have you ever taken Mercury?
-No. Maybe.
In Israel what happened is somebody gave me a few remedies, he gave
me two remedies, I don’t know which they were. The idea was that I’m an Aurum person
and I felt after taking this remedy that I became more weak, much weaker and then
I came in June to the seminar and everything collapsed.
-Yes, you came in a terrible state. Have you ever taken Staphysagria?
-I don’t think so. I didn’t take much remedies. I took only what you gave me and only
what that person gave me, which seems I was pretty much confused, I didn’t know what to do.
Concerning the inflammation in the scar area sometimes there is pinching pain after urination.
-Where is the pinching pain?
-In the sexual organs.
-In the testes or in the urethra?
-In the urethra. And as well sometimes after sexual intercourse there is this kind of
pinching pain.
-Do you have any fears now? What are your fears?
-Right now I can’t really see a specific fear because what I feel generally is that lots
of things, I motivated to do things which counteracted fears.
Let’s take this example at the moment I really wanted to receive interview from you
and you are so busy, so it’s impossible.
So somehow this thing of coming right now in front of all the class for me it’s a fearful
thing to expose myself like this but I will do it to counteract the fear.
And as well like this, I found many situations in my life, which I did it because there was
a fear behind and I did it to counteract the fear.
Many situations which I did in my life behind there was a fear which I needed to overcome,
to do the opposite.
-Fear of dark you have?
-Not much.
But maybe yes I can’t really say because whenever I’m having fear there is immediate tendency
to go and to counteract it.
I remember myself at the age of 20-21 to go into a total dark room to see how I feel with this.
I stayed to a totally dark room for half an hour, to see if the devil will come to
eat me but he didn’t.
-You had fear of devil by that time?
-No.
Basically more specific fear is fear for the future, what will be, what will happen
with me, how shall I manage, no money, more about the future.
-You feel more weak in the morning or the noon or afternoon?
-I can’t really say. Sometimes after stool there is some dizziness and weakness.
That thing is before of the effort, the constipation is very dry.
As well there is this symptom of bloating stomach, especially in the evening.
-What time?
-I can’t say, if there is constipation, there is aggravation, if the stomach is empty
there is not and as well pain in the large intestine.
I actually feel the large intestine as if there is separation from the body.
I feel the large intestine very painful, as well sometimes I feel the stomach very painful
as if there is a knife inside.
-Do you have problems with you gums, bleeding gums?
-Sometimes.
-What about your smell?
-Not too much but my girlfriend is saying that basically when there is constipation
there is more bad smell, otherwise it’s OK.
-Do you perspire?
-When I was younger I used to be so hot in the body, so I used to sweat all the time
but not it’s basically normal.
-You prefer cold or warm weather?
-When I was younger, I used to be very hot person. I used to go in the rain with a bathing suit
to wash myself in the rain, in the winter because I was very hot.
But right now it seems that it’s gone upside down and I have a small shivering of cold wind,
every climate change.Especially when it’s from warm to cold, sneezing, coughing, running nose…
-Affected in the change of weather.
-The last few years I’m travelling a lot and I see that every climate change, especially
to cold, immediately I’m becoming sick.
-Do you grind your teeth in night?
–No.
-What is your age now?
-29.
-Do you have any special desire for food?
-Yes, a lot of sweets, many chocolates. Sweets but many chocolates and the main pattern which
I can tell you about food habits and that’s as well in the emotional processes,
basically this pattern I see coming across all my life, is a tendency for being extreme,
being tremendously extreme.
-One way or another.
-One week only cheese, one week only chocolate, one week only meat, milk product
it’ s coming as waves.
-Your life also is like that, going from alcoholism to religious and back and forward.
-Yes, yes. The pattern to be extreme is pretty much. The last two years I’m becoming
more moderate actually but the tendency is to be extreme.
-Do you wake up refreshed or unrefreshed in the morning?
-For long time I felt this unrefreshed in the morning and something else which I need to say,
I think it’s important is this.
When I was born and I was one year old my father died.
When my mother was 5 month pregnant with me, her father died and then when I was 1 year old,
my mother’s husband died, my father died.
So basically this time of pregnancy something with death all over, the atmosphere of insecurity
and death and being abandoned and all that.
And my mother faced tremendous emotional crisis when her husband died.
-From what died your father, do you know?
-At that time the border was near the kibbutz where I lived and every man received
a gun and nobody really know, it might be a suicide, it might be an accident.
There was two bullets entered into the heart while he was cleaning the gun.
But nobody knows, a few people investigated that and they can’t come to conclusion
if he committed suicide or if he died from accident.
I became really curious about it and at the age of 14-17 I investigated almost everybody who knew him
and some people say it’s impossible to be a suicide because at that time he reached
the peak of his life.
But I can’t really be sure about this, maybe it was a suicide.
-What was his profession?
-He had no profession.
He was kibbutz member. He used to be very strong man.
He used to be tremendously strong man which survived a terrible thing in the Holocaust.
He was a person which his mother in the train to the concentration camp knew that he will die.
At that time he was two years old and she knew that he will die in the concentration camp,
so while going in the train to the camp, she threw him out of the train.
Nobody knows how but he managed to survive from 2-6 years old in the forest in Poland by himself,
like a wolf boy and later on when she came out of Auschwitz she went back to the same area where
she threw him out and she found him in the woods.
She knew him by a scar on the head which he had and as well by some schema in the knee,
like a birth mark.
-And he grew to be very strong man.
-He survived this forest and later on when she found him, my grandmother, his mother
she was completely mad because of this concentration camp and he was
as well completely wild.
She used to beat him with a stick for hours and somehow, I don’t know how, he managed
to survive that as well, her madness and learn to speak, learn to communicate.
But he had this kind of psychological pattern who is very quite, very good to people
very loving to people but suddenly without any visual cause he was becoming volcano
of violence. This is what people told me.
-Do you have any impulses inside you that you want to do something violent some time?
-Yes, I never expressed it. Only with very rare situations which were life-threatening
I become violent. It was a few times in my life where my life was under real threat
that time I become, surprising myself, I become very violent.
But without this coincidence I never express violent although some time there is
inside a wave…
-But you have to control it.
-A wave like a storm to destroy everything which is around me, taking the table…
Not to kill somebody, just a storm of violence to destroy the world.
-This comes suddenly.
OK good case, now I have more idea.
-We have to analyze this very interesting case of these dramatic changes.
From a point of view is interesting because we have been talking about this new spirit
which is developing in the planet, which is exemplified exactly in that case and how the
conflict in this level takes away the energy.
It is very interesting also and I have to point out to this fact that whenever you have a
big conflict inside you, you have loss of energy.
The energy is taking so much by the conflict that really you may see flat energy in the individual.
So it is very important to have clear targets, what we want to do.
If we doubt and our society is a doubting society, we doubt everything, we doubt
everybody, we doubt whether this or not, we accept that this maybe so or maybe the
opposite and this brings us in a state of lack of energy.
Who wants to speak about the case?
Did you see at all the repertorization? Please.
There is something from the case, lots of gas in the abdomen, bloated very much a pain like knife
in stomach, desire sweets, chocolate, aversion to green pepper very good appetite.
I have to give you a little bit feedback because he said that I treated him before
he was here in June, in the course and the moment that he arrived he called me
and I went to see him because he was in a very bad state.
He had very high fever around 40, tremendous headache, tremendous exhaustion.
He said, I can’t pick up the water. He had constant diarrhea and vomiting.
I said, what is this? What happened? He said, two weeks ago, test my memory
because I say all this by heart, it was a few months ago.
He said, two weeks ago I started with some influenza and then it became a pneumonia
I tried to treat it homeopathically, somebody prescribed for him, it didn’t succeed
eventually he had to take antibiotics.
He took antibiotics, the original bronchopneumonia subsided and then for a while
he was in between with some diarrhea. Then the diarrhea started with vomiting and
high fever and there he was lying for the third week in that exhausting condition.
So the pain in the head was absolutely unbearable, the exhaustion was tremendous the head was
very hot, the feet were rather cold and the remedy I prescribed was Belladonna 10M.
He took the Belladonna 10M and the next day the fever was practically gone,
the headache was much less, the exhaustion continued.
I don’t remember the thirst, do you remember the thirst?
I don’t think he remembers himself the symptoms. Do you remember if you had thirst?
No thirst but it looked really precarious condition because it looked to me very much
like a typhoid fever.
With the diarrhea, the vomiting, the headache, the exhaustion looked like typhoid fever
and Belladonna picked up the whole situation.
If I remember well the next day or the day after the next, I completed the action with
Calc. carb. 1M and in 2 ½ days the whole thing was subsided, he was in the class
sitting there, attending the class.
Then he said to me while he was leaving, I have this loss of semen while having a stool
I still have exhaustion.
I said to him try a dose of Selenium with these two symptoms because Selenium has this symptom.
I do not know why we were not able to find it.
Has anybody found this symptom in Kent’s Repertory?
-Prostate fluid.
-In the Repertory is under pollutions after stool, that’s where it is.
-Are you sure?
-Yes of course, pollutions after stool. Can I speak about the case?
He mentioned about traveling so maybe it is interesting to know where he traveled
because of infections agents and all that. First hearing the case we hear about the
operation and the scar and the pain and it sounds like Staphysagria to begin with.
Then you hear the underline maybe there is some anger, violence and then we have
to think about other remedy and Staphysagria comes up under pollutions after
difficult stool which he said.
It’s really when he is actually straining …
-Yes it is correct what he is saying. When you have a scar and the scar keeps on
paining years after the operation and especially the way that he described it.
As if I’m operated all the time there, that is a symptom of Staphysagria.
With his suppression of feelings, you may have a case of Staphysagria.
Carbo Vegetabilis comes first, then Alumina, you remember the strong constipation
with hard stool, then Mercury, then Silica and Nitric acid, Lachesis, Staphysagria…
If you put pain after stool, underline it more, 3 times to see if it changes.
You see Selenium comes very strongly in pollution during stool.
Selenium is very strong whether it is prostatic fluid or it is seminal.
-I think we have to differentiate between pollutions or ejaculations, which is usually
connected with orgasm or seminal discharge and between emission of prostatic
fluid because I think this has to do more with the prostatic gland.
So for me the right rubric should be prostate, emissions, stool during.
-Wait a moment. He says that it looks like sperm. It is not very clear whether it is
purely prostatic fluid or it is seminal or a mixture of both.
Whatever you take more or less the same remedies are there.
Alumina comes first, Carbo vegetabilis, Silica, Mercury, Sulphur, Lachesis.
Does anybody wants to talk? I will give you some more information about him.
Another symptom which he forgot to say is that he is covered totally by the blanket,
he covers all his head and only his mouth…
Salivation he said he had in the past quite a lot but now it’s less.
Now suppressed, he said, I’m not sure I have suppressed myself but we can argue about that.
Make clear to us whether you feel now cold more or heat more or both extremes you
don’t like or what exactly?
-Generally I’m more a hot person, quick to sweat a lot but if there is a quick change from
hot to cold I receive running nose, coughing, sneezing but the nature of the body is to
be very hot.
-George about the operations is under generalities injuries operation ailments from
and Staphysagria is the only bold remedy.
-I also thought about it and I had the feeling that in him a strong change had taken place.
A kind of suppression where I had the feeling that he used to be hot, now he has
problems with warm and cold, he used to perspire a lot, now he does not perspire a lot anymore,
then there is the issue of covering completely during night, weakness after stool,
more salivation was there before and now it’s kind of suppressed. So I really like
the idea of Mercury very much.
He also has a kind of violence and he is very sensitive to outer impressions and with Mercury
you always have to look for suppressions in the past.
Also during the time when everything changed for him, he constantly had this idea of
being attacked and that is Mercury, even though Stramonium has this too.
-That’s very good, I can not translate of course, it’s too much.
He says, for me the idea of Mercury is strong because of several things.
One is salivation, the second thing is that he is worse in changes of weather, he is
suppressed in his emotions, there is some violence inside and there is some violent
impulses, which he described.
But he said something which is very interesting and you did not pay attention.
That, he said, he felt everybody was attacking him. That is also a sign of Mercury.
So he has the signs of Mercury. Before the salivation was even more.
The changes of weather, they are sensitive to changes of weather, Mercury.
They do not show the violence. Mercury have impulses inside them and impulses to do
some violent things, to throw things, to kill, to do some violent things. Though he did not
admit he wants really to kill but there are impulses sometimes they just want to destroy
everything in the room. This, combined with the idea of enemies, feels everybody is his
enemy or is attacked by everyone; that gives us the idea of Mercury at least at the age
around 17,18 when he started having this, when the salivation was more.
What age the salivation was more?
-George first of all I must say something about another thing.
Because in my life history there is some background of the Holocaust, I must say
because of our own group that from my side there is no any point of accusation or
something of this nature against German people. It’s totally clean. So I wanted to be
clear about that. Concerning your question maybe salivation used to be a lot at the age
of 6,7,8 and as well 17,18 but it comes in waves. Sometimes there is a lot, sometimes
there is not too much.
-Also the moment he said he became introvert, he couldn’t communicate very much and
he had to express himself by different arts he was doing, that is another point.
Why don’t we go to Alumina? Because he does not show the mentality of Alumina, the slowness,
he answers very precisely. He did not do this. That’s why we do not go to Alumina.
Why do we not go to Silica?
Because in Silica we need to see the worse from cold very much but I would like to see now
because we added this element, which is strong for Staphysagria, we added in the repertorization
and I would like to show the analysis.
Ailments from operations, injuries from operations.
The analysis shows Nitric acid, Mercury, Alumina…
So Mercury remained in 4th place with Nitric acid on the first place.
We do some Materia Medica, one more remedy. What is the next?
That’s Mercury. It’s good that we have to talk about Mercury.
Excessive salivation, metallic taste and offensive breath are 3 symptoms that if you find
is Mercury. In his case we do not have the metallic taste.
Do you have metallic taste ever?
-Yes, there is.
-It may be.
So we have aphthae, gums are bleeding, profused perspiration with every complain
but not only does not relieve, it also aggravates the patient.
Now this is another point in which you have to ask to confirm Mercury.
Perspiration? Can you tell?
So he confirms that point also. Great weakness of course. Pains are worse at night,
worse both extremes of temperature, rapidly spread in ulcers but I do not put here
anything about the mental-emotional state of Mercury.
So we shall be talking a little bit about the mental-emotional state of Mercury.
Mercury is unpredictable. He can go this way or that way, he can go very fast up,
very fast down. You see how unpredictable is when you try to hold the Mercury?
It will go, so it can go both extremes. It’s really a remedy which has a lot of anger
inside and becomes introverted once they are hurt.
Once they are hurt they close inside and they live only with their inner feelings and
thoughts. They do not want to share things and that’s why they feel threatened by the
environment because the support group, everybody has a support team, the support
team around is broken down. So they come to the point where they feel that they are
threatened very much by outside people. They are so much threatened that they can
reach even a delusion that everybody wants to do harm to them.
This is a reason why also they cannot express their emotions and because they can not
express their emotions, they start stammering.
And I said stammering with Mercury is a sweet stammering, it’s not an aggressive stammering.
But the most interesting thing for the mental picture of Mercury is that this aggression that
has been kept inside it comes in waves as impulses to do violent things.
Suddenly it comes a wave that … and he described exactly that there comes a wave
and I just want to destroy everything.
And I want to do some violence and so much strong is this that sometimes they say I
need to go out almost and shout. They try to keep themselves not to shout, not to do
violence and there is a constant struggle, violence comes from inside and then the struggle
not to show it.
In this case, apart from the symptoms which Mercury has, he has these core feelings
of Mercury, the impulses to do violence but he has to resist.
And maybe one time or another when he feels secure, then if you put here, one more
symptom like feels everybody is his enemy, Mercury will shoot up.
Do you want me to show you how in this Repertory, if you put the right symptom, you will
get immediately Mercury first. I will tell her to do that to show you that of course
repertorisation depends on what you are taking for repertorisation.
And then if you take impulses, then again Mercury will be.
-How about the scars, the operation that he had and the pain.
It doesn’t mention anything in Mercury about this.
-No, Mercury does not have that symptom.
-So would you ignore it when you prescribe?
-I would ignore it for the time being and maybe later on if that symptom remains,
maybe a Staphysagria can come as second. You could actually give first Staphysagria and
then Mercury but I see now that the Mercury symptoms are much more strong and over whelm
the idea of Staphysagria.
And it has really the history of Mercury symptoms. In the past also he has the Mercury
symptoms. So Mercury is running through from a period onwards. So maybe Mercury will
bring back all his lost energy and will cure all his physical problems.
Mercury you see he has the constipation, the cicatrices, salivation in the night, weakness
after stool, cutting pain, change of weather aggravates, desire for sweets, unrefreshing
sleep, pain stool, injuries operation.
-We didn’t put any mind symptoms.
-OK, just put one mind symptom. I will tell you.
They have programmed my thinking. It’s very obvious, if you take the right symptom.
Even if not taking the right symptoms, Mercury would come fourth, third, so you could
get the idea that somewhere there is Mercury. And then you go back…
Then the suppression, the impulses, Mercury feels unprotected, the defense mechanism
is weak. That’s why the ulcers are spreading. There is an ulcer and the mechanism
instead of making the ulcer smaller and smaller, it allows the ulcer to be bigger and
bigger. There is no power behind the defense mechanism.
You see the weakness and the trembling because of the weakness.
The trembling and Mercury is one of the main remedies for Parkinson.
Hands are trembling, legs are trembling.
Now he gave me his case the other day, just superficially like that and I was thinking
some remedies but never Mercury. I was thinking some remedies but I was not happy.
I said I cannot give the remedy, I will give him the wrong remedy.
And really you have to put together the symptoms because there is also the possibility
of Alumina, of Silica, of Bryonia, Stramonium, Staphysagria, all these possibilities are
there but what is the right remedy that will make the trick. That will free, will take him out
of the jail. He is in a jail now.
-The search of religion and god… in his life?
-Yes. You don’t take now this religious. You can but it is not really religious, he is not
religious at this moment, with the meaning of religious.
He has been but with the despair through which he was going at the time he met the
religious group. Bring yourself to that situation where you don’t have a house, the kibbutz
is finished, they sent you away, he said they told him you just go away, you have no
money and then you meet these people who like to support you, to give you some love,
some affection and all that. You believe and you follow because it’s a matter of survival.
Is this a matter of religious? Yes but his character being this character what he is, he
goes full speed but then he goes away, he swings on the other side, like a pendulum.
Too much heat and goes to the other way, I don’t like it, I go away from it, too much cold
I run away, this is the idea of Mercury.
Put a lot of heat and it goes away, put a lot of cold and it goes away.
-Where would you put this much travelling that he mentioned that he likes it very much.
-I’m not sure really that it is a pathological desire for travelling, I’m not sure but we can
investigate and see whether it is really desire to travel.
He goes to one place and then he has to go to another. Can you tell us?
-Basically I love travelling but I don’t see travelling as a solution to solve the problems.
If I could, I would have it for few more years but I don’t see it as something which is
solving any problem which I need to run away.
-I will tell you something. In 1970 in Athens we met a woman who looked at our hands to
me and my wife. So the woman said to me, my god you are going to travel so much and
my wife said, fantastic I like it so much. I said to her, the day will come where you will
say, I had enough, I don’t want to travel. I mean you ask her now if she likes to travel.
Not anymore. Actually travelling is liked by everybody because you see new experiences
but to be pathology, that means I travel and I can not resist. I have to pick up my
luggages and go, I’m happy. Calcarea phos. for another reason as we said,
Tuberculinum for another reason etc. Is this his situation? Maybe he can tell.
-What I feel more to travel is because I like the dynamic. If I stay in my place for a long
time the boredom just makes me mad. I need a very dramatic activity. I can’t stay for long
to one place.
-What he says now is a tinge of tuberculosis. We have an idea of Tuberculinum but not
other symptoms of Tuberculinum at the moment.
We give a lecture on Mercury.
-I would like to ask some questions about another remedy which came to my mind and
this is Sulphur because he has many 3rd degree symptoms and 2d degree symptoms of
Sulphur. For me I have chosen several rubrics…
-No, no, it’s not correct what you are saying.
-I have chosen several rubrics, I want to tell them to you so that you say whether they
are correct or not.
-All right.
-We know that he has hernia since childhood.
-Nux vomica, Lycopodium, not Sulphur.
-Hernia since childhood in Repertory is Sulphur. Then we have prostate discharge
during stool, which is again Sulphur. We have constipation with dry stool, which is
again Sulphur. We have weakness stool after, which is again Sulphur.
We have this philosophical and theorizing theme in him because its mental symptom
he says yes, but I know it’s very good for myself and then we have this tendency to
alcohol, which again is connected to Sulphur and we have abdomen distention
evening, which he confirmed and is again Sulphur 2d degree and we have the heat
he is rather hot. I don’t have the impression that he is very much sensitive to
extremes of hot and cold and I’m not sure whether the symptoms of delusion
everybody is an enemy is still existing and whether the desire for sweet is not pointing
more towards Sulphur. So I would say that we have reasons to investigate in this
direction, Sulphur and with hints of Tuberculinum.
And there is something else that I would like to say, if I can.
In this case I see that we have a lot of work to do, not only through Homeopathy but
through other source of healing, as well. I think this guy has ruined his health because
he has not paid enough attention to his way of living.
-I’ll tell you Peter, you may need Sulphur!
This is theorizing. Not him, what he did is not theorizing. He is stuck on facts actually
hard facts. We agree in the other things except of theorizing and I also agree that you
might entering a state of Sulphur, which maybe a good idea actually.
Have you taken Sulphur before? Now? Oh, you are a proving!
-Not yet. I took Sulphur 2-3 years before, the last time.
-Not lately?
-No.
-Wait, we may have a very good idea of Sulphur.
The prescription for this case is Mercury and the possibility of Staphysagria, later on.
-I would like to ask if we take this pressure in the time of army, as a trigger point?
Because now it is not anymore there.
Is it?
-No.
-I mean have we taken this as a trigger, as an exciting cause?
-So why did you take this as a symptom? I mean the feeling of enemies was only in the army.
-If the feeling of enemies is still there? I don’t know, we can ask him.
-How he said it? Not everybody is an enemy but everybody can be not my side but
against me. This is the idea. When we speak about a symptom, I said a symptom has
stages. It starts from this and then goes to there, goes to there and then you may even
reach the point where he feels everybody is the enemy but we don’t have the other
stages. That’s why I took this to show you. Because this tends towards that direction.
-Can we get problems with a special potency of Mercury?
Can we give low potencies or highs, maybe because of problems with that?
-In this case, because he is a young man, his basic constitution is strong, I will give
a high potency, one time a high potency like 10M or 50M Mercury.
With most probably a reaction. Some pains will be there developing for a week or so
and then the amelioration will start, will ease off.
So it was synchronized with the Mercury. It was very strange that we arrived at that point
and we had the opportunity to analyze, in a live subject, the case of Mercury.
-What about the aphthae?
-Aphthea in the mouth? He does not have.
-I can’t understand.
-He can’t understand. That’s why you are here.
-George I would like to confirm these wounds in the mouth, these aphthea which appear sa lot.
-This will teach you something. We made a good lesson with him.
It’s very interesting because he said to me, where are the aphthae?
I said, he doesn’t have it, it doesn’t matter. So he said, this is what I say
I don’t understand and then he comes and say, I forgot something, I have a lot of aphthea.
What it means is, it does not matter. Once you have the essential things, the others
are details, he may not have it.
-As well there is a teeth mark on the tongue, because I’m dealing with Chinese Medicine.
In Chinese Medicine they make diagnosis, so my tongue is full of tooth marks.
-That’s terrible.
-Because it’s a clear remedy can you come to conclusion that (?)
I’m on a high place or low place?
-Well, not bad. You may feel rotten with all these, you may feel totally degenerated but
you will see after Mercury your health will start developing back.
-I have an elderly patient with Parkinson disease but who has all symptoms of Mercury.
How high may I go with potency?
-Not high. It’s better with Parkinson you start with low potency, like 12X or 12D.
In German you call it Decimal. It’s also the mark for 10, in Latin this is 10.
Decimal is 1 in 10, 1/10 in the 12th, instead of 1/100 to 12th which equals to C.
In Germany you call it D30, D12.
That indicates the dilution that is 1 in 10 where centesimal means 1 in 100.
CH Hahnemannian it means that the remedy is diluted 1 to a 100, but out of this
dilution one drop is taken in another bottle and again another into 99 drops.
So you have in CH dilutions, you have change of bottles. That means one bottle
another bottle, another bottle, 10.000 bottles.
Where Korsakov you empty the bottle and you refill it and then you go on
emptying, refilling, emptying, refilling…
We always leave unfinished some lesson.