-You tell us what remedies he had.
-In the beginning he had Phos 200 and then he got very high in the blood sugar and
after 4 days he got another remedy because it was very bad for him. It was Carcin 200.
-When?
-Here in Alonissos 19th of May.
-One year ago.
-With the Carc the blood sugar went down to the normal again but he became very tired
and he got problems with his knees and his heels. He had this before and he got it again.
So he could not play football or do sports and he felt very tired.
-He got some weight, since I saw him last year he is 15 cm higher at least.
What is your height now?
-I don’t know. 1,75.
-We have to measure him, before you leave not now. We have to record it, perhaps even
20 cm higher.
-And because of these problems with his heels he got Pulsatilla.
-Through the fax?
-Yes and with Carc he was very tired and he was standing at home only, he didn’t want to
go out but now he is in a much better energy.
-After Pulsatilla?
-Yes.
-When did he get Pulsatilla, can you give me the date?
-In the end of July. Pulsatilla 200.
-One dose?
-One dose.
We had a follow up here in October, he was not here but you asked me and he began to
sigh, he was sighing a lot and he got Ignatia from you in October.
-Ignatia 200?
-No from 15 up to 30, 3 times the day. With this he wanted salt very much.
-He started craving for salt?
-Yes, more than usual. And so in February he got Nat mur 200C and with this he took
this in 27th of January and 2 weeks after he had taken the remedy he got a flu and the
influenza lasted about 2 weeks and he got fever and he had never had this before.
It was up to 39 degrees.
-I have problems with all Norwegians, with you it’s double.
-We all have problems with her.
-I come from the South. And he was very red on his cheeks and he felt very warm with
this fever.
-No.
-It went for how many days the fever?
-About 4-5 days and he had a very dry coughing and down here on the chest. When we
were going to bed he was starting to cough more in the evening. He was not awaken by it
-In the meantime you didn’t tell me how many units of insulin he was taking all along this
time.
-He did not change, about the same units.
-You did not change why? Did you measure the sugar?
-Yes.
-It was about 35 units the day.
-But what was the level of sugar in the blood?
-With Nat mur it can change…
-It can change from day to day. In average it was approximately 7,5.
-What kind of measurement is this? What is the normal?
-It is between 3,5-6.
-No it’s 8.
-She should agree with me, it is between 3,5 and 7,5  that’s the normal.
-And his average all this time was 7,5 that means the uppermost to normal rage.
-Yes that’s correct. He got to the doctor and he measured it for 2 months.
-Each time Alexander goes to the doctor, he measures the average for last month period.
approximately that.
-Was any time that it was 5?
-Not in the average but from day to day it can be from 4 to 15 at the most.
-Have you noticed any condition in which the sugar will rise? If he gets upset or he eats
sweets or what?
-If he eats sweets.
-Does he eat a lot of sweets? I’m afraid he is eating much more sweets than usual.
-No.
-Tell me because we have to make the right conclusions, if we have wrong information
we draw wrong conclusions.
down and every day he was under 4.
-In spite of the fact that he was eating sugar?
-No, then he took sugar.
-It was low, he started eating sugar or chocolate?
-Chocolate.
-How much? We want to know how much? What was the biggest piece that you ate in
one day? From a block of chocolate of that size you will eat half?
-Almost all.
-That’s big. The chocolate 20 cm by 10 cm is quite a lot, I don’t eat it myself but anyhow
what I want to know is, he grew so much, he increased his eating habits in general?
He ate more than usual?
-Yes he eats a lot.
-So he has very good appetite.
-Yes, a lot of fruits, a lot of…
-He eats all kinds of fruits?
-Yes he likes fruits very much, oranges, juices and apples, grapes, bananas.
-All sweets, so you forgot that you have a problem with the sugar and just enjoy your life
as I understand.
-That’s not correct because what happens if he eats a lot more one day than another day
also more fruits than normally, then also he will inject more units of insulin because this is
the balance between sugar and that.
-So there is some days where you inject let us say 15 units or not? What is the lowest?
-I believe the lowest is 30 a day and the most might be 40.
-What is the highest amount of insulin he needed in the past? 50,100,200?
Was ever more than 100 units, he had to take more than 100 units?
-No he hasn’t taken that much.
-What do you remember? In the past what was the highest units that you had to inject?
One day you remember I had that day to inject maybe 50 or 60 units.
-50.
-The highest I think it was here in Alonissos when he got Phos.
-How much?
OK you find out and then you tell me, we can proceed now.
Does he have any epistaxis from the nose?
-Yes he got after Phos acid. He had one and a half day which comes and goes. Not
constantly but a lot of the day.
-No more now.
-The epistaxis comes from one side or both sides?
-It’s often both.
-The desire for chicken is still there or not so much?
-Yes.
-The coldness of your hands is still there?
-Not there.
-Perspiration in the night?
-He is much warmer in the night and the day and he is not so cold. And in the night he
takes his feet out of the cover.
-Because it’s burning?
-Warm.
-Generally he is warmer now.
-In general how do you see his psychological state, how he is?
-I think maybe you will talk now.
-His psychology is superb. I think he is very good, a lot of energy, he is positive.
-Happy? He studies?
-Yes.
-In the school he is good in the class?
-Yes he is good.
-Very good?
-Very good.
-Now how old is he now?
-He is 16 in August this year.
-In the beginning, one year ago he was biting his nails.
-Yes he uses the scissors very much now.
-Ah, I thought he was biting his sister’s nails which would be more interesting!
-He has reason to do it.
-All the time he uses this scissors so much.
-You still don’t like the tomatoes?
-No.
-You are still afraid of dogs?
-If they are barking yes.
-This little dog which is outside?
-No.
-How is your thirst?
-I’m very thirsty. I drink very much.
-For cold or for normal temperature.
-He prefers cold drinks.
-You remember that you said to us in the beginning if you eat ice cream you will have a
headache, now do you still have this?
-I still have it.
-In the same intensity that was before or it’s not so much?
-The same.
-You are not very sure.
-I’m sure.
-Also you have said if you over sleep, then you get up not well.
-Then I’m tired.
-How is that? You don’t sleep so much anymore?
-No, he wants to sleep more, he doesn’t want to go out, he sleeps very long. He is so
tired, he wants to sleep even more.
-He does or he doesn’t?
-What he likes to do mostly? To do athletics or to study your lessons?
-Athletics.
-And you play basket ball?
-Football and handball.
-What position you play in football?
-Defender and attacker.
-And you like to be a professional football player?
-Maybe, I don’t know.
-Very good.
-His reflexes are extremely good.
-But here you have written that his mind is awkward, what was that?
-I think it has more to do with distraction. He can not concentrate when he is walking and
perhaps there is something on the way and he doesn’t see it.
-He can fall?
-Yes.
-Do you have preferences in one of the subjects at school, like mathematics or history or
languages or for you it’s the same? What is more easy for you?
-Just the same.
-Everything is the same more or less. Mathematics also?
-I think mathematics is one of my best.
-So that means if he is good in mathematics, he can concentrate. You eat fried eggs?
-Yes sometimes.
-We bake them, not boiled eggs.
-But does he have a desire for fried eggs?
-No he has very strong desire for bacon, that’s the only time he is eating eggs.
-Chicken is really your best food?
-No.
-Not so much now as before.
-But the tomatoes still he doesn’t like them. You are sure?
-Yes I hate them.
-Was he ever anemic?
-No. He had problem with the stomach when he was little, because of diarrhea of milk.
Some milk is not good for him but with the Nat mur he liked to drink a lot of milk.
-And then he had diarrhea?
-Yes.
-That means if now he drinks milk, he will have diarrhea.
-Yes. After Nat mur he had a lot of pain in the stomach.
-Because of gas in the stomach? You were bloated?
-No, just pain.
-Do you have eructations?
-Sometimes?
-A lot?
-Some of these days was a lot.
-Tell me Phos acid how many doses he took?
-For 15 days.
-200?
-No, 30. One month ago.
-If you eat ice cream, where you will have the headache?
-In the front.
-Only after ice cream?
-With Nat mur he had headaches 2 times and this was not good because first he felt
very numbed and paralyzed in the mouth and his right hand.
-During the headache?
-No, first he got this and then he slept and then the headache comes and he was afraid
of this, he felt paralyzed in his right side.
-You could not move or you could move but it was like heavy?
-Yes.
-This comes 2 times after Nat mur.
-What do you like to do when you grow? You want to become a lawyer, an architect, a
doctor, what would you like to do or you have not thought about it?
-I haven’t.
-Difficult matters.
You eat red meat also in your house?
-Yes we do. Lamb.
-If the meat has fat on it, you like to eat the fat?
-Yes.
-Always you liked the fat or lately you seem to take the fat even more than the meat?
-He prefers the meat.
-He is not sure what he prefers but anyhow if we allow you to eat sweets, as much as you
like at this moment, how much you would like to have? Give me an idea.
-It depends of what it is.
-Chocolate, sugar, what would you like kataifi?
-Chocolate would be approximately 50 grams.
-But he likes better other sweets than chocolate.
-Don’t be shy, just tell me I like this.
-Some small pieces of chocolate, gums milky, very sweet.
-How much of these you can eat? All day.
I want to ask you something else. You prefer to have instead of food, just sweets?
-No.
-How is your sleep? You sleep right through the night? You don’t wake up inbetween?
-In the beginning on the stomach and then on the back or in the side, he turns around.
-But he used to sleep on his side mostly on left. Now he turns around.
Do you see dreams? Do you remember?
-No.
-Does he ever see a nightmare where he will wake up in a fright?
-You don’t remember any of your dreams?
-No.
-He tries to remember but it has to do with his sugar. He has a fistula in the rectum.
-Yes he had 4 times but it’s taken away. It comes back for 4 times but not now.
-It was operated 3 times, not by itself went away?
-Yes and then with antibiotics the last time.
-But do you know that if it comes, you have to leave it ,you can not operate.
-I know. And he got one here in his mouth.
-Now lately?
-Yes a week ago.
-If he perspires, his perspiration smells, is it offensive?
-On the feet yes.
-Quite a lot?
-Yes.
-What do you say?
-Also one thing I forgot when you asked about this psychological state. For quite long
periods this year, he has isolated himself from us, he comes from school, he like to be in
his room, he watches TV and do his homework and he has a lot of friends that are calling
him and he never calls back, he likes to be with them but he takes no initiative to call
them.
-But he studies his lessons.
-Yes and he reads some books and see some TV and he is quite social in the family
and he is very social when he is together with the boys but he likes his own company.
-He is self sufficient man.
-In a way, like his father.
-But will you say for yourself that you are hard working, medium working or lazy?
-Between lazy and medium.
-But would you like to be lazy?
-No.
-You still like to do some work and you like to be first in your class? You like it? It is
important?
-No, it’s not so important.
-It just happens.
-Inbetween he can be very angry.
-Then what he does?
-Probably he has reasons for being and mostly it is when he is arguing with his sister
and brothers and when he is angry he may throw things and closes in his room and none
is able to get in contact with him for hours.
-When he throws things he throws against the person or in the floor or he throws it in
such a way that it can not hurt.
-It depends how angry he is. When he is very angry, he is throwing at the person, that
happened twice.
-When this happened? Can you remember this incident when he threw?
-It wasn’t a knife.
-I hope. When in time?
-In the car.
-About? It was one month ago, one year ago, 5 years ago?
-It was once I believe in February and October, November last year.
-Today he was very angry.
-And then he shouts or he just throws?
-Yes and then he shuts the door and go into his room, this is the most.
-Are you sure?
-I have never seen him throw anything.
-But he is a very caring boy.
-For others?
-Yes and I think he is very occupied with just this.
-About others also or about injustice towards himself?
-Both.
Is in your family the other children quite tall?
-He is the tallest.
-Is he the oldest?
-No.
-You remember what I told you, wait you will see.
-I meant by age, his brother when he was 16, he was 1,30.
-I see what you mean. I wanted the absolute values because it could have been like
this. People who are doing Homeopathy, we say the children they grow taller than their
brothers or sisters and because of his disease also there is possibility of not full growth.
This shows that assimilation is quite good and the situation is…
What’s your evaluation? Your evaluation is that he is eating properly for what he has?
-No.
-So he is not careful with the diet and the idea is that he has been fed up with all the diets
and now he sees his values are towards the lower side and he uses more the sweets.
-George I don’t think he is very extraordinary in this, virtually all diabetic teenagers rebel
against the diabetes and their diet is, they eat what they like.
-The idea is now, do we have the picture of a remedy at this moment?
-There is something I would like to clear up. Last time I wrote down that he was suffering
from fissures, now we heard about fistula, could somebody please tell me which was the
correct?
-Does he have questions about several things? Why is this? Why is that? Why the sun
surrounds the earth?
-No.
-He is not an enquiry guy.
-It’s fissures.
-Because we had written fistula. Fissures were operated? Because it was very painful.
-Yes it was very painful.We tried with homeopathy once but we were afraid because he
was so bad, so we went to the doctor to take it away.
-Who wants to speak? Nobody wants to speak.
I think that at this moment he is having a picture of a remedy and give me the symptoms
that she has used, I just want to check the symptoms.
Desire for sweets underlined twice and combined with chocolate, desire for fruits, feet
warm in the night, fear of dogs, underlined only once, long sleep aggravates, desires for
bacon, aversion tomatoes, diarrhea from milk, perspiration of feet offensive and anger
general, fissure. That’s good enough and the Expert System says what?
Sulphur. Put the columns. Sulphur close with Arsenicum, Phos third.
Show me Sulphur, explain why?
Feet our of covers, perspiration offensive gives the idea of Sulphur. The fact that he has
become warmer also takes us towards the Sulphur. It was very interesting what he said
I’m between lazy and medium in putting the effort, which is quite accurate I would say.
This is an easy case.
So far so good, I think he has been helped quite a lot but still we don’t see the action of
the pancreas, we don’t see the production of insulin to such an extent as to give us more
optimism but the way I see him, he is growing and apart of his timidity which is there and
is going to be for another 2-3 years I believe, he is growing quite well and in a quite
balanced way. I believe with Sulphur we can have a step forward but apply better diet
so we can reduce the amount of insulin, it’s very important to give the possibility of the
organism to be resurrected, to be functioning again. If you give ready made insulin the
organism becomes lazy, I don’t need more. So we have to reduce and keep the sugar
with a better diet, with Sulphur I believe he will manage with 20 units, even less.
-My wife should have said that I should be careful and so I will.
-This is a very open class, you can be as open as you like.
-You said that if he eats a little bit sugar or chocolate he needs more insulin and he is
well balanced in the way that he takes blood sugar 4-5 times each day, so he knows
where he it is and the average level of blood sugar, as I told you, is approximately 7,5
which the doctor in Norway at least is one of the best he ever had. Then my question is…
They love it to be underneath 7 of course but mostly when you are at his age is 8 or 9 or
even worse of that, my question is how the body is getting lazy because let’s say you eat
10 grams of chocolate and drop 2 units of insulin, in what way it is getting lazy?
-It’s getting lazy because you keep the sugar low with these 35 units. All together he
takes 35 units, what I say is that with the remedy that you give and with the better diet
we may be able to come down from 35 and in a few months we may reach, perhaps 20
units, which we may have the same results as we have here, keeping the average in 7,5
which will be a great improvement.
With these cases we don’t have an improvement, we have a degradation. So if by any
kind of therapy you are able to reduce the amount of insulin, that means the rest which
the body needs, is produced by the body. Clear?
-How do you understand his acute disease he had in this case?
-That’s a sign of improvement as well. This is the first time he has an acute and we know
that the organism that can have an acute has gone up one step.
He never had before high fever. Is it correct?
-She told me he had a virus before he even started with diabetes.
-This is what we have been saying that in lower group 3 or 4, if you have an acute, the
organism does not have enough force to bring out a defense which will bring out fever.
This is something that you have to keep it in your mind.
-Which children diseases Alexander had?
-The idea is that if they can have a better diet with Sulphur, how should we give Sulphur?
-Low.
-Every day.
-How shall we give Sulphur? Daily? Starting from high, from low, from medium?
-Low. Who says low? 100. Who says medium 200? Who says high?
This time we have to go to 12C, start with 12C three times daily and every week you go
one step higher, 13,14,16 etc. And keep this for at least one month but if you see that you
observe that the insulin needed is not so much, that means you can use less and less
you keep on second month, third month, fifth month.
-As to the children’s diseases there was a publication, it might be in a medical journal
about a vaccination against parotitis and you know parotitis can make diabetes and that’s
one of the reasons that people say vaccinate against. In Finland everybody has been
vaccinated against parotitis and the incidents of juvenile diabetes with certainty went up.
It was a good journal and it was 5 years ago.
-It was a pediatric journal?
-I don’t remember which one, I’m sorry but anyway
what I wanted to suggest is he hasn't had parotitis
so probably he has been vaccinated.
-About 2-3 years I think.
-When you started noticing the problem? What age?
-When he was 9 years old but before this he had a very big problem with urinating in his
bed in the night.
-But did he have a problem with much urination?
-Yes I think so but he always drunk a lot from when he was very little and the father
drinks a lot.
-We don’t know exactly in what age and what caused it but it is one of the possibilities
that his organism might have been stimulated towards this direction by some vaccination.
We do not know but it is interesting that he got 3 remedies which are grief remedies
which have acted and I see, as far as I’m concerned, he is more open at this moment
more expressive and the fact that his father says, he actually expresses his anger, it’s
one more confirmation. Most probably he is more reactive and now it is interesting that
after the flu and the fever, for the first time we may have a picture which is really more
clear than any other time. So for me it’s very interesting because we know the first
analysis we had and now having a picture of a remedy which is I would say 70% clear.
It’s very interesting, let’s see. His doctor who attends is a very good specialist?
-Yes, he is considered to be one of the two very best in Norway, he is a Professor.
-Very good. What is his opinion so far? The boy is doing well, is doing very well, is doing
medium, what is his last opinion if he said so.
-First to say in his opinion is not possible to cure that.
-Sure that’s one fact for us also, we are not claiming that we are going to cure but if we
cure what he will do?
-He will have a problem.
-Because from Norway we had another case where his kidneys were destroyed and two
Professors who attended actually said that if anybody cures you, he needs to take a
Nobel Prize. So I wonder whether… And one of these two Professors was one who
nominates the candidates but anyhow.
This time I will be interested to know. does he know he takes Homeopathy also?
-No. To answer your question Alexander has the disease 6 years now. Every year he
can’t understand why the increase in the need of insulin it’s not high as it should be, it’s
low compared to what is normal.
-That’s all he remarks, he doesn’t say that the boy is growing very good, that I’m
impressed that his growth is quite good for what he has.
-Not the growth but the need for insulin.
-Yes I understand.
-He is very satisfied with him and compared with others at his age he has lower average
blood sugar levels than others, so he is very satisfied with Alexander and he doesn’t think
he is lazy, he thinks he is very good in handling this disease.
By his injections, the number of units he is injecting.
-He is good, he is low.
-Yes, it’s correct from the view, normally it’s a balance between what the body needs and
what the number of units he inject into the body.
-Very good.
Here we have the report of the juvenile diabetes case, the child from Norway, to whom
we have ordered to take Sulphur 12, 3 times the day, go up every week. It delayed very
much to start taking the Sulphur, so since 1 month he is taking Sulphur and the report
is like this. In general Alexander has more energy and is stronger. He can discuss and
disagree with me, he has a very good appetite. In June before he takes Sulphur, he lost
2 of his nails, 1 of big toe and 1 of finger. Just fell off?
-The nail on the finger got a little bit inflamed on the root and it’s loosened and (?)
it fell off, both on the finger and on the big toe.
-In the middle of August he took Sulphur, he was supposed to take it 3 times the day for
a week and then go up and so on. After 2 days with Sulphur 12, he got a very strong
epistaxis, it started sudden when he was looking on a football match. The next day he
also had a hard epistaxis, the third day I saw him a lot of blood coming out. It was really much
and in the end the blood was dark, clotted and coagulated. All his life has this problem
with nose bleeding but never so strong as these 3 days. One week later I was awakened
in the middle of the night with someone crying. I ran to Alexander room, he was standing
on the floor, bent forward, trying to stretch the back of his thigh.
He was half awakened, first I thought he had a nightmare, then I understood he had
cramps on the thigh. He is a very tough guy with all his sports but I never have seen
him crying since he was a little boy. That is true, I remember because we thought of
Nat mur and all that.
In the age of 3 he had this problem when he slept in the car, he woke up crying with
cramps in the thigh.
This episode he had 2 times that week with 13. With Sulphur 15 one morning he had
strong pain in the stomach. The pains were so strong that he wanted to sit together with
me, he was pale and afraid. He had no constipation, flatulence or diarrhea. After about
3 hours he took some food, after I have managed to persuade him because he had no
desire for this. Then he was a little better and wanted more bread, in the end he ate 6
slices of bread and then the pains had gone. That is very good diet. Then measure his
level of sugar.
As a younger boy he had a lot of pain in the stomach with diarrhea after milk etc. but this
pain he may had 4-5 times so strong. After this episode Alexander did not want to take
more of the remedy. I called him from Alonissos and asked him if he would try to take the
remedy, he was very well and of course he could start to take the remedy again. Now he
could not remember that he stopped taking it because of pain. He said he only forgot to
take it. I asked him to try to avoid sweets to see how the remedy acts. This is not so
happy with, he said I will try because he still has a very strong desire for sweets. But still
with Sulphur the blood sugar has been very stable. He measures the blood sugar by
himself 2 times each day. When you say stable you mean low? The blood sugar can be
stable and have 4 milligrams.
-No, I mean that he used the same amount as he did before and he is not having this
jump up and down.
-In general he has been more awkward, he drops things easily and as little boy he was
stumbling a lot. He is sensitive to noise and if it rains he has problems to sleep because
of the noise from it. He needs good sleep, he has isolated himself even more, his friends
call him to see him, he says maybe but he never goes out. If I ask him why he would not
go out with them, he gets angry at me and do not want to talk about it. It is impossible to
push him, in this he is strong, he does what he wants. Cold, wet weather aggravates.
Takes a deep breath.
-I thought he got Ignatia and he was sighing a lot and I thought this maybe was coming
up again but now when I heard about Nat sulp I feel it’s more like this, that he takes a
deep breath.
-This is correct what you are saying. The idea of Nat sulph maybe is a good idea. I would
still wait and see the effect of Sulphur and especially if there is an amelioration after stool
this is a keynote, then we have to change to Nat sulph in the same manner as he does.
But what I would like more to hear in the report would be the actual measurements.
You will have to send me some times the actual measurements.
-So tell me what was the last remedy we prescribed.
-Alexander got Sulphur and he was going to take it from 15 and up, 3 times the day.
-For how long? Did he take it?
-He took it up to 30.
-And what happened?
-He was so well and I felt that this was not maybe the right for him anymore, so I stopped
it and in the blood sugar, he has been become very tall almost 1,85.
-Oh my god. I was just that all the children that Homeopathy become tall.
-Yes and he needs more insulin now.
-He needs more? Why?
-I think it’s because of his age, he is 17 years old and he is growing so fast and with the
Sulphur he eats a lot, all the day and he has problems of not taking sweets.
-He likes sweets?
-Yes, he didn’t so much before Sulphur but he is more strong mental and emotional.
He seems so ... in good harmony and at school he is studying more efficiently, he does so well and
he had problems with epistaxis all his life.
-And now?
-With Sulphur he had epistaxis for 1 week, very much and now for the last year he
doesn’t have it anymore.
With this fast growing he has pain in his back. When he walks on hard ground, he got
pain.
-Pain is mostly on dorsal region?
-Yes and he is (?) and in the morning he often has pain in the neck because he wants
to lie with the head high on the pillow and then he gets pain in the neck. And he also
has pain under his right toe.
-He still has aversion to tomatoes.
-Yes he has but now he desires fish and ice cream and when we have been on vacation
he only ordered this every day. Fish and ice cream.
-He has to take more insulin.
-Yes and he has inflammation under the finger nails but this appeared again now. He had
this for 2 weeks ago and  then it was gone and he is not as warm he was, he is more cold
especially on his foot and fingers tips and he can be very cold in the finger tips, in the
afternoon he is icy cold and have sometimes numbness in these finger tips.
He sleeps on his sides, sometimes on the left, and then on the right. When he goes to
sleep he sleeps on the left and then when I come in the morning he sleeps on the right
side and he is very refreshed in the morning. I tried to give him Sulphur because I thought
maybe I should try once more.
-Now is the time for Phosphorus. You have given Phos before, you see now what
happened? Now the picture is coming more and more, refreshed sleep and numbness
and coldness, desire for fish and ice cream, is for Phos.
-Yes because he is a very strong person and I told him, he is timid, he wants to stay at
home, he doesn’t want to go out with his friends but he is more open and he doesn’t like
to go on boat. So I asked are you afraid of the sea or what is it?
I got sea sick, but today it is so nice weather, Oh, I don't want even then
And I remember now when he was very little he didn’t want to go with me into the
basement, I was washing and I asked him do you want to go and he said no.
-Why?
-I don’t know, I think he was afraid with this because when I came up, he was crying, he
couldn’t remember I had gone. Still he didn’t want to go with me down there.
-Does he express any anxiety about you, his father, sister?
-Yes, he expresses that he doesn’t like contradiction. He doesn’t want us not to disagree.
He is very sensitive for everything. It’s difficult to stay aside, he has grown up, he is so
sensitive, sympathetic I think.
-Still there is desire for bacon?
-Yes but not so much for the eggs. But he likes spicy food still and he is not so afraid for
the heights anymore. He sits and I’m afraid when he sits, to look at him.
He uses his scissors very much to the nails, very much.
-Why?
-I don’t know. I ask him.
-He doesn’t like his nails to grow?
-Or they grow very fast, I don’t know.
-He has said that he had pain in the stomach from milk especially. Have you noticed that
he still has it?
-Not so much.
-Also he had said that he desires fruits, still is there?
-Yes he likes fruits, especially grapes.
-And fear of dogs, do you know?
-Yes he has fear of black dogs if they come suddenly and now we have a hamster
because I think he likes all animals and it go away and I couldn’t take it and I said
when there is flour on the bread, he can not hold it.
-If the bread has flour he doesn’t like it?
-Yes, it’s so bad.
-Do you know if the perspiration in his feet is still offensive?
-No and he is colder.
-Because he used to have hot feet.
-He is cold in the afternoon.
-So Sulphur did very good.
-In this winter he notices I don’t like being (?) anymore, I want to stay in the sun more.
One special thing when he has high blood sugar in the morning, then he has mucus, very
thick, thick and white.
-How many units he takes now?
-He takes 60.
-But as I understand he eats freely ice cream, he eats a lot of food, he eats bread.
-Yes.
-No restriction at all?
-Yes I try, no but…
-Yes or no?
-Yes but you use the insulin together with what you eat.
-Yes but every day he needs 60 units, sometimes he needs 40 or 50, it’s like this?
Between what? 40 and 60?
-Yes.
-So I know better than you how much insulin he needs.
-His height now is 1,85?
-Yes 1,83.
-His father how high he is?
-1,80.
-He is now 17?
-Yes, in August.
-Most probably he will reach 1,88. He is quite big. How is such a big one?
-All my children are big.
-OK now what you can do, you can start with Phos 12C once a day and then you
monitor the units because I believe now with Phos, after a month of Phos you will be
able to reduce the insulin now.
-That will be nice.
-And if you can of course it’s better to make it 13 and every 10 days if you see changes
especially if it reduces the desire for ice cream, that will be good and the chocolate and
if he reduces or if it changes the coldness and the numbness in the fingers. That will be
guiding symptoms for not wanting anymore Phos and then you give me information and
then I will tell you. All right?