I would like to read, it’s a woman 35 years old, first case, came with panic attacks,
fear of death, one sided numbness, perspiration, trembling, vertigo and dyspnea.
She also suffered from stomach ailments, gas, bloatedness from the abdomen after eating,
which was from 4 to 6 p.m. and pain in the right hypochondrium.
Lately she couldn’t travel in a crowded bus because of these panic attacks.
When I asked her how this began, she told that about six months ago she had been
in a car accident and although she had not been hurt physically,
these symptoms of panic attacks had started and have been occurring 3-4 times weekly.
As she was telling me all these things, she started weeping uncontrollably.
She told me that she was dissatisfied with her marriage and that her husband
had an extramarital affair.
She needed very much the support of the husband but he has been hard on her.
Generally worse from heat, desires open air, aversion fat.
Here there are three remedies, as I can see. You should be able to see three remedies.
One is a woman 35, panic attacks, with fear of death, one sided numbness, perspiration,
trembling, vertigo and dyspnea.
These symptoms point out to Aconite. Correct? We agree.
But we see also suffering from stomach ailments, gas, bloatedness, distention of abdomen
after eating, worse 4 to 6 p.m. and pain in the right hypochondrium.
These symptoms point to Lycopodium.
You did not know Lycopodium. Very good, it doesn’t matter.
Lately she couldn’t travel in a crowded bus because of these panic attacks.
For those who know both Aconite and Lycopodium, this symptom is common to both,
Aconite and Lycopodium.
But she had a car accident and after the car accident started the panic attacks.
That means that after the car accident she started a symptomatology, which is
the recent symptomatology, which we have to take into consideration.
But further down in the report it writes that she started weeping all the time.
A remedy which is weeping all the time during consultation is Pulsatilla.
It’s another remedy, you don’t know, you’ve never heard.
So she cries, cries and she needed the support of the husband, but he is hard on her.
Pulsatilla is worse from heat, desires open air and has aversion to fat.
So since you did not know neither Lycopodium, nor Pulsatilla, the answer is Aconitum
and the answer is correct. Aconitum is the correct answer in this case.
So the majority of you, you got it but if you wrote Pulsatilla or Lycopodium,
you will get some marks.
Some of you may have thought of Pulsatilla or Lycopodium but Aconitum has to be
the first remedy because there is this fright and then the panic attacks which is typical
of Aconitum and you can not ignore this and go to a deeper remedy,
what we call a deeper remedy, which is Lycopodium or maybe Pulsatilla
because of this complaining with her husband and things like that.
With the information that you had so far, I give you this case.
Let us say you don’t know anything, you don’t know anything about Pulsatilla or Lycopodium
but Aconitum you know, so if you write Aconitum you get 10 marks,
you don’t need to write also Pulsatilla.
But if somebody knows already Pulsatilla, write Pulsatilla, we’ll give some marks.
-German marks?
-German marks yes, very valuable marks.
Before I go ahead, I wanted to read from the Medical Dictionary, Dorland’s Medical Dictionary.
What he says, because I see you did not know, apparent death.
Apparent death - he says: a state of complete interruption of bodily processes from which
the patient can be resuscitated, resurrected. This is Dorland’s Medical Dictionary.
Apparent death is the right expression for “necrophania” which the Greek word is.
It appears to be dead, is the exact translation of “necrophania”.
Complete interruption, that means there is no breathing, there is no heart beating
and they can stay in that state for two or three days and can be resurrected
after three days.
This is a phenomenon which happens from time to time.
Yes.
-I have one question to the last case to Pulsatilla, when we give Pulsatilla now,
as the first remedy can it help her for tachycardia?
-You will not do anything. Pulsatilla in this case will do nothing.
-Only as a second remedy perhaps?
-Maybe as a second remedy and then maybe Lycopodium as a second remedy
and then third Pulsatilla or vice versa but you are not concerned with that.
What I am interested is whether by reading this case you are able to bring back
what you learned and connect with the case.
Does it sound like…
She is asking in out of the body experiences. The patient is out of his body
but still the body is functioning, whether this is an interruption
and where is the interruption?
Is that correct now? Yes.
As I pointed out with the slides, the disconnection can be a little bit, more, more, more
and it is in its highest in apparent death.
Now what happens is that the people who have seen that phenomenon they say that
there is a thread which connects the etheric body.
They describe, I’ve not seen it, which connects the etheric body, what we call the vital body,
with the physical body. So there is a kind of silver thread through which life passes through
and connects the vital body – that means the energy body which is there
and gives energy to the physical body. In death this is severed.
This is cut and this lives.
So in all cases where we have disconnection always there is a connection through a thread.
This is the explanation which is given by people who claim they have seen this connection.
What we are interested is not so much the mechanics, as the facts.
The fact is that I’m outside of my body, the body is lying there motionless and I can observe it.
This is a fact which nobody can deny.
Also it’s a fact that when you sleep, somebody can even come and move you
and you will not wake up.
Some people sleep deep, they can have thunderstorms,
even canons and they are not aware. They are like dead.
And there is a state which is called “catalepsy” in which you try to enter back into your body
and you can not and you feel conscious and want to move your hands or feet and it’s not possible.
This is called cataleptic state. You have not been able to come back totally to your body.
So there is always a connection until the time of death.
Until the time of death the connection is severed and you are totally free
and it is very interesting that during these states usually the individual describes
very nice feelings.
The pain in the body is totally unaware and the feelings and the visions are very spiritual,
very uplifting. I had a case of an architect who opened the gas by mistake and he was gone.
They had gas in their house and he opened to make a bath and his mother saw that
he is not coming out, she knocked, broke the door, brought the ambulance
and he was able to observe everything that was happening.
How they took him out of the bath, how they put him in the ambulance,
how they put him in the hospital and then they pressurized his lungs to make his heart start.
He was so happy, he said why they are doing all that to me? I’m so well.
And this is not one time, it is again and again and again, so we cannot anymore
in Medicine ignore these facts.
If we are saying we are treating the human being, we have to take into consideration these facts,
though we do not understand the mechanics, how they work exactly.
How this disconnection is a thread which can be so long as coming from London to Athens,
it is unbelievable. What happens?
Or in that dimension we have other laws, in which time and space do not exist?
Time and space do not exist because you think of going to America and you are in America.
There is no space actually, space is cancelled in this new dimension, in this dream state
where we know the dream.
You know how in your dream you change states, from one to the other.
But people who have experiences…
That means I have been related people who are here, they go to America, saw the problem
saw the child because the child is in America, had a problem and the mother went to America
and saw the whole situation, what happened to the child and she came back and
received a telephone call later on to say exactly what she has seen in her dream.
How things are we don’t know. What we are interested now here is that we are dealing on
this level. We are dealing on an energy level all the time by using homeopathic remedies.
So we have to be aware of what we are doing. Otherwise it will be totally blind,
take a remedy, throw it here, there, whatever.
We have to be absolutely clear, as much as possible, of what we are doing.
Then I believe later on Medicine will start changing and will take into consideration these facts.
Case 19. A woman age 50 complained that she had a pain located in her right shoulder.
Now for two months, her arm was almost ankylosed. She has been suffering with arthritis
for years and different other joints have been involved previously.
She was sighing all the time, during the interview and crying from time to time.
She also confided that a neighbor of hers passed away and she attended her funeral
and since this time, she feels strange, as if surrounded by her presence.
She was very anxious about her condition.
As she had great anxiety about her health, kept on asking a lot of questions
concerning her condition and whether she will improve.
Desires salt, fat, worse cold, worse on waking in the morning.
And your answer was Calcarea carbonica, many of you.
Here actually I have kept a little bit of information back,
so I do not make it very easy for you, to see if you are perceptive.
Because if I had put all the information, everybody would write the remedy and it’s no good.
So you have to be perceptive. Is this a case of Calcarea carbonica?
Is this a case of Ignatia? Is this a case of Nitric acid, anxiety about health?
Is this a case of Calc. carbonica?
In order to have Calcarea carbonica you need some certain signposts.
If in this case it had been written that she is perspiring on her cervical region,
you are entitled to prescribe, with the addition of that symptom, Calcarea carbonica
because anxiety about health is there.
If she said, no perspiration but the desire instead of salt and fat was for sweets and eggs,
you are entitled to write Calc. carbonica. But here you do not have enough symptoms to
prescribe Calc. carbonica.
You are not justified, I’m sorry but I feel that some they saw some others
writing Calcarea carbonica and they wrote Calcarea carbonica, no? In this particular case.
Because you did not know what to do, so you asked what do you write? Calcarea carbonica,
Calc. carbonica…
She is sighing all the time and it is underlined. Sighing all the time
and you think why not? Because a neighbor died, Ignatia.
Ignatia might be the remedy and you can write Ignatia
and you can get some marks but you will not get marks for Calcarea carbonica.
Wait a moment. The idea is…
It is your first touch with the whole idea.
I could make these cases very easy for you and everybody would be happy. No need.
The idea is that you have to think and you have to struggle
and have this in the background, the information that you have
and this case in front of you, you will see what you could best do. This is the idea.
I could give you one more symptom because it says she has been suffering
with arthritis for years and different other joints have been involved.
Here the joint it was mentioned, which joint?
But if I put the joint, forget it, you don’t have to think.
So I took away which other joint was affected because if I put the joint that was affected,
most probably, most of you would write immediately the right remedy.
So here we have the anxious about her condition.
What am I having? Also I did not put here fear of cancer
because you will not get it always in this way.
She says, what do I have? What? And it says, she kept on asking a lot of questions
concerning her condition. What is it? What do you think?
That is thinking and entering into the state of the patient who has that mentality
and kept on asking a lot of questions? Shall I be well?
Who is the person who does this? It is a person who has a weak will.
It is not a strong person. They don’t even mention the word.
The word cancer for them is a taboo.
To mention the word, to say I have cancer or I think I have cancer…
You say, you put the question, are you afraid of having cancer?
They will go like this.
So what you have to read here and the solution in this case is the death of the neighbor.
There is a neighbor, it’s not a relative to justify grief and sighing
because if I said after the death of her daughter, sighing, yes Ignatia.
But after the death of a neighbor, she went to the funeral and after that
she felt dead people around.
Of course if I give you the exact words which I use here for a case,
you will not be able to think. You will just write the remedy and it’s no good.
Don’t worry, you will get it. Eventually you will get the system, you will get the feeling.
Once you learn these remedies, you have to study these remedies
and you enter to the psychology of the remedy and then you will get it but don’t be upset.
The idea is not to be mechanical but to be flexible and to see through the information
what you can do with this information because I give you limited information.
I don’t give you symptoms and symptoms and symptoms, you put the Repertory and
whatever comes. I give you limited information, what can you do with this information?
Then you have to think, you use your imagination.
-I did not write Calcarea carbonica, I wrote Arsenicum album
but I didn’t feel comfortable with it, I was looking for some…
-Where is the restlessness?
-Where is the compulsiveness, I couldn’t find any.
-Where is the fastidiousness? You could not get it through the information.
Through the information you could get this, “what do I have?
Doctor, are you sure?” This you get it from
the information but it is not direct. She is asking all the time, do I have cancer?
Everybody would say Agaricus. Very good but now things are a little bit more subtle.
We did Calcarea carbonica?
-Yes.
-There is a symptom which I have not mentioned in Calcarea carbonica.
There is a symptom in Calc. carbonica children. They enquire about the beyond.
They enquire what is an angel? What is god? What is after death? Where are you going?
Things like that.
I did not say because I do not give the whole information here in that step.
So the information I have given you was with the Agaricus.
I said the connection with cancer, dying, graves, dead people, ghosts all around, spooks
and I said weak willed individual that will ask a lot of questions.
I did not say will ask a lot of questions but you have to perceive it through the information.
So this could make a case of Agaricus but maybe it was too much work for you, for the afternoon.
-No, it wasn’t too much.
-Agaricus is the remedy for Nr 19 case.