-In regards to the teeth grinding, have you any idea whether there is a particular part of
the night that you grind your teeth more?
-No I don't know but I know when I''m stressed, I grind them more.
-In relation to food desires, is there any particular relation between chocolate and you?
-Yes, yes very strong.
-And that desire is it affected by your menstrual cycle?
-I wouldn't say so, although I've noticed that if I carbohydrate before my cycle,
like a week before, that it helps.
-You mentioned a couple of times that your sexual desire at different times in your life
was not that strong, has it ever got to the point that you actually had been averse,
that you pushed someone away.
-Not averse because it is averse to a person maybe.
-Or aversion from fatigue?
-Yes but I wouldn't use the word aversion.
-I can't be bothered, I'm too tired?
-I'm too tired.
-Thank you.
-How you would completing the things you start?
-I'm getting better, I used to often not being able to complete what I started but because
I'm aware of it now, I make a point of doing it and unless it's ridiculous to continue.
-Do you often start many things?
-Yes, I use to work on many things at once like when I'm cleaning the house,
I try very much to focus on one room at the time but if I'm passing through somewhere else,
I'll do something. I have to learn to focus.
She has been harassed and the defenses have been gone down and could not keep
anymore the acne, the trouble in the skin.
This might not have happened during the time she was taking the antibiotics.
I feel that during that time, 50% of the problem was gone already
but the organism itself went down and then because of the harassment from the antibiotics,
the whole thing disappeared.
But it is the effect of the antibiotics which brings the organism to that state
where it cannot anymore bring out the eruption. If we now give the correct remedy,
she will start slowly having more and more pimples and more and more eruption,
which will show what? The defense is better because of the right remedy and then
the organism will remember what has to do when it is in a good state, to bring out an eruption.
-Didn't the eruption come out again stronger after she stopped the antibiotics?
-Yes, which again for me it is the same thing.
The defenses are down and then the eruption is a lot but the organism has been
weakened and eventually it withdraws.
-Have you purposefully ignored the herpes and the desire for chocolate?
-Not purposefully but the desire for chocolate in this case, I do not give much weight.
I take it as the desire for sweets it is good enough.
The Repertory gives only two remedies for desire for chocolate
Hydrophobinum and Phosphorus.
-And Carcinosin and Sepia and Argentum nitricum.
-Yes but I'll tell you why I ignore it. Who likes chocolate really? Look.
And there are two remedies in the Repertory. Most of the people like chocolate.
Therefore in a case like that I will not base my prescription on the desire for chocolate.
That is one reason why I ignore it. The second you ask is why herpes?
Herpes is a periodic manifestation and you say I ignore it but I don't.
Herpes is a condition which can be produced by half of the Materia Medica.
Not there but if you look all the chapters where herpes are mentioned and you count the remedies,
it will be half of the Materia Medica.
So if there are so many remedies that can produce herpes, how herpes differentiate
for me this or that remedy? It is very difficult on the strength of the herpes to differentiate.
Vaginal herpes. You want to differentiate on that.
She said that they told her it is herpes but she could not see anything.
-Is that what you said?
-I'm sorry, I missed the question.
-You said that they told you, you had herpes but you could not see anything.
-I did but there was never confirmed, there was never actual test that showed that it was positive.
It was a doctor who said it looks like it could be and since that time I never had any problems with it.
-So you have something which is not really defined.
-Most patient similar to her could have come for menstrual difficulties rather than fatigue.
She said that she has terrible cramps that started since the age of 13, at the same time of acne.
So probably the same remedy interesting for her initial, would be interesting
also for her menstrual cramps and other disorders.
Like that we don't have anything in our rubrics concerning her menstruation and
concerning short periods or any other characteristics.
-We can take into consideration. What you would like to look in the Repertory concerning her menses?
What symptom you would like to look?
-I don't have many information about her menstruation. I don't know whether she gets
hot flashes, whether her sex drive tends to be better or not, whether she gets craving or not,
whether her perspiration is different
or not?
-She said that before menses she gets upset and she gets all kinds of psychological
but you can tell.
-Two, three days before I start I get very, very tired and at first day I feel terrible, when
it starts and I wish I could stay at home. It's cramping and irritability and bloating and all
the usual things.
-What you want to put into the Repertory out of what she said?
-Not very much so far but I wonder if it is important to investigate more on that.
-To investigate more? We investigated. Don't push something which is not there?
By putting questions and questions and pushing it's not going to take you very far
because she said exactly, three days tired before menses. You can use that.
Do we have this? Weakness before menses? Let me see the rubric.
-Weakness yes.
-She said weakness three days before menses and the day during menses
she becomes very irritated and crampy. Show me irritability during menses.
-Actually I take a prescription for it.
-What do you take?
-Anoprox.
-What is this?
-Anoprox is anti-inflammatory for the cramps. They are quite severe.
-Cramps where, in the lower abdomen?
-Yes.
-Cramps on the lower abdomen during menses.
The irritability is only one day, the first day or it is during the whole menses?
-It's maybe the day before and the first day.
-Here we have bone aching, dull pain, cramping pain during menses. Cocculus, Sulphur.
-She also said that she gets radiation.
-When she is menstruating does she have a feeling of a symptom with pressure down?
-No, she said no.
-During menstruation do you have the feeling that everything will come out?
The intestines will come out?
-No but I feel like point downwards, it's not like the intestines are coming out.
I feel like there is a pressure pulling down, like gravity.
-She has a gravity.
-When she coughs, sneezes or laughs does she lose any water?
-No I don't.
-Going back to her constipation would she be able to describe the feeling in the rectum?
I'm looking for a keynote.
-You are looking for what?
-No, no.
-That's the French part of me coming out.
-If you are constipated, do you have any particular feeling in the rectum?
-C'est tres lourd. It just feels like I have cement in my gut and my stomach feels hard.
-Like concrete.
-Yes.
-Do you have this feeling in the abdomen pulling down?
Not during menses.
Dragging, bearing down in abdomen.
During menses she says.
Secale, Platina, Pulsatilla, Lilium tigrinum.
Now what you will do? Here is dragging, bearing down during menses.
Do you have any palpitations?
-Not that stands on my mind.
-I just like to ask because in my mind it keeps coming back Sepia in this case.
You tend to dismiss Sepia here because she did not seem to have the emotional state of Sepia
but it's been my experience that in this modern world for some reason,
the Sepia type being more the workaholic female.
That you don't tend to take the kind of emotional symptoms, as clearly as you might,
when you read  in the Materia Medica. So if I set that aside and I certainly had
a couple of patients who fit that kind of picture and that may be a prejudice in my mind to some degree
but the rest of the symptomatology seems to me that suggests very strongly Sepia,
although I agree there is a strong element of Silica there as well.
-As we have seen from the repertorization, Sepia was coming as one of the first remedies,
first or second remedy all the time, which means a lot of her symptomatology,
there is no question, it is covered by Sepia.
Here it's very interesting - I'll make the comments in the end - how we make the
differentiation in the case where we have two or three remedies that come with quiet a lot
of symptomatology, all of them. How do we differentiate one from the other?
-I keep wondering if the dragging or bearing down sensation is in the uterus
or rather in the abdomen?
-I don''t know if she knows so much anatomy but we'll see.
-I think it's the uterus.
-You feel it's bearing down.
-When you say you have a sensation of bearing down, pulling down, is this in the whole
of lower abdomen or it is the uterus? Can you differentiate that?
-No, I can't.
-What is the bearing down? Sepia, Pulsatilla, Lilium tigrinum, Belladonna.
-I think what we need to do here is to go back to over all the symptoms that we gathered
and to read them according to their characteristics, their spontaneity, their essence
and pick up the top 6 to 8 symptoms that we think are key,
so that we are not getting lost in the details and go from there.
-Very good.
This is a very good observation.
You see what happened in the class, I let it run like this.
So you asked questions, more questions, more questions. You reached her to the point
where she has bearing down feelings.
If that was prominent in her case, she would have mentioned it on the very beginning.
When she mentioned about her menses, she would have said not that I'm irritable and I have cramps.
She would say I have a bearing down sensation.
That would be the first thing to have said and then first things first.
Now by asking and asking and asking, you reach a point where she will say
yes I also have a bearing.
It's exactly an example which I gave you a few minutes ago.
Don't you have a bearing down sensation? Don't you feel something is pulling you down?
Well yes I also have that but what she has said in the beginning? We have the video and
we can go back and look.
When she talks about the menses, she says three days before the menses I'm exhausted,
I'm very tired and during the first day of the menses I'm cramping and I feel miserable,
I don't want to go to work.
She did not say for her to be or to rely upon that symptom and go and say this is a case of Sepia,
since you don't have the aversion to sex or the lack of orgasm and you want to rely
on the bearing down sensation, it has to be strong.
This is what I spoke in the beginning. A symptom has to have intensity,
has to have continuity, has to have depth and has to have also uniqueness.
This symptom lacks the intensity.
If you keep on asking questions, you will bring out 1000 more symptoms and you will say
what about this and what about that and there is another one.
I can make it as a test in another case if you want and you will see how many more
symptoms we can gather and gather and pages and pages of symptoms.
Then what you do with them. Then you have to focus to what?
She said something which is very strong and important and when did she say that?
In the beginning. Not that this case is not Sepia because it looks like Sepia,
it looks like Silica, it looks like Psorinum but we have to differentiate between the three
and come down to one conclusion.
There is definitely from the repertorization we see Sepia appearing,
we see Silica appearing, we see Psorinum appearing.
This is our job now to differentiate, to go back and say what does she look like?
-What about Psorinum? We considered a number of differential, we haven't really talked
about that, she certainly seems to have a lot of Psorinum symptomatology and
some of them are keynotes. You were saying before what is the essence?
Coldness, she is freezing, she wears six sweaters in the winter, she can't go out without her hat on.
Is it not a strong Psorinum keynote?
-Right exactly, this is very good observation. You remember I asked her a keynote
of Psorinum because Psorinum they feel so cold and they feel aggravated by cold,
especially in the head, to the extent that they cannot go out in winter without a hat.
-But she is not wearing much today. She is wearing about the same as you.
-My nose is cold, my hands are cold. I don't know about my feet.
-I'm perspiring.
-All women are cold.
-No, I have a problem with being cold leg.
-You wear only one shirt and she wears two, a jacket and a shirt.
-But most women, a lot of them are cold. It's not uncommon to hear that women
are cold and chilly.
-Sometimes in the summer time when it's completely hot, I feel cold.
-She even said that she cannot sleep at night if the room is cold.
-She has a headache if the room is cold, she wakes in the night.
There is an aggravation definitely, which you cannot ignore.
-Is there a rubric for head pain cold, head getting cold at night?
You see her head becoming cold?
-I have to disagree. There are lots of women who are warm and who feel really, really hot.
So I don't think that all women are cold. I think that's a wrong observation.
By the way I just remember that I'm perspiring all the time, so why should I perspire?
Pain and getting cold, Belladonna, Sepia and Silica. Sepia again is coming quite strongly and Silica.
Here Psorinum has to be added by the way.
-In what degree?
-Psorinum at least italics, Psorinum is one of the main remedies.
Psorinum will sleep in the night with a hat because they get very cold in the head.
Also Silica, not so much Sepia. I have not seen it in Sepia.
I don't know it is in the original Kent? Sepia is capital.
-Are you aware of any aversion for hat with Silica because a homeopath told us that
Silica people generally have great aversion for hats.
-No, I do not know it.
We all agree that the choice is between Psorinum, Sepia and Silica. Which one?
-She is clairvoyant.
-Are you clairvoyant?
-Sometimes.
-In Boericke in the Psorinum it says phagocyte's defective which is interesting because
antibiotics cause granular cytosis, which means that your faculties don't work.
-I would like to know how you were before your menses started?
As a child, how was your energy level?
-Great.
-Also as you were been brought up, nutrition wise what was your environment?
You were brought up in a good environment or poor environment?
-I think that we ate quite well. There was some junk food in there but pretty typical of what teenagers eat.
-I just want to find out if she's had Raynaud's, if she's had any thyroid panels done
because she is showing a lot of thyroid symptoms.
-Which disease? Raynaud's.
-Did you have any thyroid tests?
-I think so.
-Was anything wrong with your thyroid?
-No.
-In the Raynaud's disease there is freezing of the fingers and the toes and they go white.
-I''d like to know if she is perfectionist. She told us she would like to do more
but when she works, is she working extremely precisely?
-If she does, what you will do?
-I think it goes better with Silica. Silica people they are supposed to be excellent workers,
doing the best all the time, giving good results at work and the rest.
-Show me fear of death.
-In regard to that Sepias are also very artistic. That could be also in favor of Sepia.
Also I would like to know where  your eruptions were when you had the antibiotics
and before the antibiotics?
-On the face, the back and the buttocks.
-Anywhere specifically on your face?
-Forehead and chin.
-OK thank you.
-There was a time when you had fear of death. What age?
-Around 20 to 21.
-I'll tell you the solution, so everybody will be happy.
We'll give in the morning Sepia, in the noon Silica, in the afternoon Psorinum.
Even for those who use polypharmacy, analyzing a case is so useful.
Once you do that, you have a possibility.
Well it's a difficult case, the decision is very difficult.
Especially the decision between Psorinum and Silica.
Sepia for her is a little bit more on the side.
I do not like the fact for instance that she does not have a perspiration which is offensive.
For Psorinum I would like to see that the perspiration was much more offensive
than she has accepted.
-Offensive perspiration on her feet?
-Only if I'm not wearing cotton, if I'm wearing nylons.
-Both Psorinum and Silica they have offensive perspiration and the perspiration of Silica is
many times acid and it spoils the shoes. Do you have that?
-No.
-Do you have any perspiration in the night in the head?
-Sometimes I sweat a lot at night but it's not often, it's every once in a while.
I wake up and my clothes are wet.
-You wake up sweat in the night?
-In the night.
-What time? First part of the night or you don't know?
-Right in the middle of the night.
-Perspiration in the night.
You see Sepia is quite strong in that.
Silica and Sepia, Sepia also.
Does she perspire so much as it appears here? No. Still the third degree?
-Although Calcarea was not there. I didn't see Calcarea before.
-So her perspiration is rather of that order, not of this order. Not three underlines.
You would put 3-4 underlines in her perspiration? No, she said sometimes I perspire in the night.
Once in a while.
With this case to finish because I get the feedback that
we have analyzed for too long the case.
Why we have analyzed it too long? Because it is not clear and because
I, myself have not really decided on one or the other remedy and I keep on thinking all the time
that we have been analyzing the case. Where we should start?
My decision for starting the case will be Psorinum, with second possibility Silica.
In case Psorinum does not give an effect, then I have Silica as a second possibility
and then we can go ahead and give it.
The reason for giving Psorinum first is because the trouble that
starts the whole thing is an eruption.
Another reason is that Psorinum also like Sulphur is indicated with unclear cases where
we have not a clear cut picture.
So Psorinum is one of those remedies that go quite deeply and they change the constitution.
Show me Psorinum.
Also Psorinum has grinding of the teeth during sleep, which is interesting because though
it is not strong...
Psorinum has most of the symptomatology actually.
-What potency?
-200.
-OK, 200. Give her 200, 1M and 10M, morning, evening and night.
One dose, one day, yes.