-She is 47 and she has psoriasis and I think psoriatic arthritis of the hand and feet,
she has sleeplessness, she is exhausted and she has very bad migraines.
She has since five years thrombophlebitis.
This has this psoriasis since the 9th year generalized.
As a child she had measles, chicken pox, rubella.
She had vaccination poliomyelitis, diphtheria, small pox...
She has arthritis since the 17th year of the hand and the ankles, small finger
and since the 16th she got cortisone therapy inside and outside.
-She is still taking cortisone?
-No.
She got Sepia from a homeopath which had no effect, she changed it to another Homeopath
and she got Rhododendron which was a success because she did not need her voltaren.
She did not need to take any anti-rheumatics.
-So she has psoriatic arthritis.
-Now at the time she had appendectomy in 1959 and a duodenal ulcer in 1987.
In 1967 she married and in 1971 her son was born.
That was after she had slept the first time with her husband.
-For three years she did not sleep with her husband?
-No, she married him because he accepted her disease.
The skin disease and he was something like a father for her.
Then later after the son she started to have some interest in sexuality and she had
a love affair that was early disappointed and later she had some other love affairs.
Now she has come here with her friend.
-With her boyfriend but she is not married anymore?
-They are now separated.
-They live separated.
-Yes now she lives with her son alone.
In night she gets palpitations and fear and then she runs about it doesn't get better, it gets better by that.
Sometimes she has something that she feels that she is unreal,
that she doesn't have contact to the floor.
With her new friend she says that she doesn't love him very much
because he is too closed, she would like to have deep feelings.
When she was 1 1/2 year old when she went in the street she was stroke
by her mother and she did not dare to go out of the house for one and a half year.
-What remedy she has received?
-She has received more remedies and when she came she got Pulsatilla.
-What other remedies she had in the mean time?
-I don't know.
-She does not know?
-Maybe she knows, she told us about Sepia and Rhododendron and then she got Pulsatilla.
She could sleep for 14 days and she felt quite well and the skin became very bad;
then the sleeplessness came back, the exhaustion and all that.
-You repeated Pulsatilla?
-No. It was too short, I didn't do the initial treatment.
-What potency?
-1M.
Her father had psoriasis and died at 66 from heart, asthma.
Her mother had gallbladder and digestive tract disease and she is living,
the grandfather of the father had cancer of the stomach
and the grand grandmother was very arteriosclerotic.
-Anything else?
-I can tell you more but this was why we prescribed Pulsatilla.
One thing that came out for some time that the skin was better when she had shower.
-The skin better when she had hot shower always?
-No, for some time after she had Pulsatilla. I don't know the actual state.
-She speaks English well?
-She speaks English but she is not used in speaking.
I can give you some more symptomatology.
-I would like her to come in.
If she forgets, according to your symptoms, she does not mention anything then we can add it,
I would like to hear the story from herself.
By this introduction that we had in the case, we more or less know the character of the person.
We have enough information. When she was one and a half year old, the mother smacked her
because she went out of the house and for one and a half year she didn't go out of the house again.
It is important.
She married with a man and only slept with him once when her skin was better.
-No.
-What did you understand?
Oh she didn't say that. Anyhow she slept with him once after three years.
So you perceive the kind of person, this fact indicates very much the type of the person we have.
What type of person we have?
-Very sensitive.
-Very sensitive, who can be hurt very easily. Let's see.
Are you ready? Do you know what other remedies did you have except of Rhododendron,
Sepia and Pulsatilla?
-Sepia and Rhus tox.
-You had more remedies?
-Yes.
-But you don't remember the names? Have you written them down?
-Yes I wrote in the paper.
-The paper is not there.
What is the impression she is giving you?
-Shy.
-Very nervous.
-...
-Sad.
-What is the main thing is, it seems as if?
-Restlessness.
-Desperate.
-No energy.
-Embarrassed.
-She is not clear in her mind.
-She is not clear in her mind, hazy, I ask questions like what remedies did you take...
There is no clearness in her mind. Why the mind is not clear? She is too shy,
she can not remember... What is the remedy that you think first?
-Alumina.
-But timidity is strong, Staphysagria, Silicea, Baryta carbonica.
You can think of Bar-c. as a first impression because you can
say that she is too shy to show to her husband her disease, to undress and too afraid
because the mother smacked her and stayed in the house for one year without daring to go out.
-very short experiences and I forgot.
-Can you tell me how it developed? You have psoriasis? When you were nine years old
or since nine years?
-When I was nine years old.
-And you remember anything happened at that time? Your mother separated?
-My grandmother died three months before.
-And you were connected very much?
-Yes I suffered very much. I was connected with her.
-Much more than your actual parents?
-Yes in a way.
-You were connected more with your mother, father?
-With my father but the grandmother was the mother of my mother.
-And your father was very good to you?
-Yes.
-Your mother?
You see the difference? I say your father was good to you? Yes and your mother?...
There is a difference, perhaps there is a big difference, the mother smacked her severely
that's why the child stayed there.
In these cases we have the syndrome the mother being jealous of the daughter
and the father replacing the mother by the daughter.
Taking out the daughter to go to the cinema and the mother stays in the house.
Then there is a complex there which develops a lot of ill feelings for woman,
a lot of resentment and lack of self confidence in herself.
They can stay without much self confidence in the rest of their lives.
We have been thinking of Baryta carbonica so far, have we confirmed the Bar. carb.?
-No.
-No, because she gives answers quite correct and she is right there,
she is not really hazy in her mind or what appeared to be hazy in the beginning.
-Your mother?
-It is complicated.
-Why?
-She was not very happy in her life and connected to my father.
You see they won't give the problem immediately. Her problem is not that the mother
was not in a good relationship with the father.
Her problem, if there is any problem because of that, is that the mother
did not have a good relationship with her.
-It's a long story.
-Can you make it short?
-Yes, her first fiancé died and after she married my father...
-Not because of love?
-Yes I think so.
-And that's why they had problems all the time?
-Yes.
So now it is absolutely sure that the father did not get response from the mother,
did not get enough affection from her, therefore she is going to get affection from the daughter.
Therefore the mother will start being jealous of the daughter.
-And there was a kind of jealousness from her side.
-About you? Because your father liked you?
-Liked me and took me out more than her.
-And so she was vicious to you?
-Not obviously.
-Underlined.
-Yes.
What you observe now through this questioning? How is the character coming up?
I want to know what it came out eventually and I asked but she does not bring that.
She said other things instead.
What kind of character will do that?
-Closed.
-Closed and a character...
-Ignatia and Natrum mur.
-Not only these remedies. It is something that concerns her.
I said what is your relationship with your mother? And she does not tell me.
She knows exactly what is the relationship but she does not tell me.
Therefore she wants to cover up the mother. She says never mind, forget it, it is a long story.
What is the long story? Well my mother was in love and then she married...
-What is further on that? Then I almost tell the story instead of her
but she wants to cover up the situation.
It is not a vicious character. It is a character that wants to cover up.
This happened, I understand. I don't want to offend somebody.
It's a very sensitive person, tremendously sensitive and the fact that she had suffered so much
made her over sensitive.
To have a problem that is so deep, also esthetic problem for a woman is terrible
to have it from nine years old.
-She suffered about this skin disease. She often said that her fault to have a child
with such skin problem.
-Do you have brothers or sisters?
-One brother.
-Did he have any problem?
-No problem. He is two years younger than me.
-Why your mother said that it is her fault that you have the skin problem?
-It was her idea, no reason.
-Your father had psoriasis, the same thing?
-Yes but very little. Only there, only sometimes.
-Why your mother said it was her fault? Because she married your father who had psoriasis
and then she had a child with psoriasis? Is that the reason?
-No, it was not conscious to her. After I had the disease the possibility was there
that it was my father's fault but he had never treatment, it was so little.
-After psoriasis you developed sleeplessness or migraines?
Can you give me the history how it developed? Just give me an idea.
Nine years you had psoriasis.
Then they took you to doctors, they put creams, you took cortisone?
-Yes.
-Then what happened next?
-Next point was at 17 years and my bones ache.
-Your bones, your joints?
-The tooth.
-They started deformities on the toes?
-Yes.
-This pain started at the age of 17 and while the psoriasis was better or while the psoriasis
was still very bad?
-Still very bad.
-And the pain started?
-Yes. Also pain in the wrist and in that bone and the neck is also damaged.
-Osteoarthritis?
-Yes.
-It's not an accident?
-At 17 years first the feet and then the neck and then the wrist.
-And then you took other medicines for this? Pain killers?
-Yes and other cortisone things. Later on Voltaren.
-Then what happened? How it developed?
-At the age of 24 I started a treatment in a skin clinic up to the North Sea,
a climate treatment and from that time I did it every year and the skin was really for 3-4 months
it was good.
-What treatment it was? With lights?
-With light and with Cignolin.
-The basis is petroleum?
So for 3-4 months while you were there psoriasis was better?
-Yes.
-Then what happened?
-Then a new soup followed.
-In 3-4 months she fell back.
-Yes but not so heavy.
I went on for years that way until two years ago from now it was bearable.
-The pains and the psoriasis?
-Yes but in the meantime I had the treatment with homeopathic things because of the
bones, only of the bones, he never treated the skin. He concentrated on the bone pain.
-And you had Sepia and other remedies.
-Yes and two years ago I started with migraines.
-What kind of migraines?
-It starts with a bad feeling all over the body and in the stomach I feel nausea
and I feel cold all over the body and there is a pressure in the head and vertigo.
Vertigo that I don't feel sure on my feet, sometimes that's all and sometimes
it's followed by a terrible headache, sometimes right, sometimes left.
-Where is most of the times right or left?
-Right mostly.
-Or is it one time left, next right, left, right?
-I can't say it.
So far with all this symptomatology she is talking about the only thing we understand
is the sequence of events, what took place in her organism which shows the progress
of the disease on deeper and deeper levels.
We do not get an information about the remedy. What she says does not give us the least
conclusion of what the remedy might be, in spite of the fact that we have a lot of pathology.
Is anybody who knows the remedy?
-Then the severe pains come? How is the pain?
-The pain is stitching, more often this pressure feeling.
-It stays on one side or it goes from one side to other side?
-It starts here in the neck and goes there.
-To the occipital protuberance. Either left or right?
-Always left, it goes all over the head and then for one hour it is painful all over the head
and then it decides to go either to the left or to the right.
-But it always starts on the left occipital protuberance.
-Yes.
-How long it lasts all together?
-It is different, sometimes one day, one night, sometimes two, three days.
In the beginning two years ago it was only once in a month connected with my menses.
-Before menses?
-Before menses and during menses. Now it is more often.
-During the headache you have to lie down?
-Sometimes yes because of the nausea...
Weakness.
-When the weakness started, the weakness comes only during headache or you have weakness...
-Before the headaches starts.
-Three years ago you had weakness?
-I always had problems with my blood circulation and weakness
-Did you ever had vertigo with headache?
-Before the pains begun I had often weakness attacks.
-When the weakness started?
-I think all over my life it was, 10 years old.
-You still remember you were very exhausted?
-Yes but not as much as now.
-Now you are very exhausted?
-Yes.
-Your father is still alive?
-No.
-When he died?
-He died six years ago.
-Did you have a big grief when he died?
-Yes in one way but for him it was good I think.
-Why?
-He was ill, suffering.
-On what?
-On heart asthma and he died very suddenly.
-Did you cry when he died?
-Yes.
-A lot or very little?
-I was very sad a long time.
-Yes sad but did you cry?
-A little.
-Or not at all?
-Not at all.
-You were sad and not crying?
-Yes.
-You wanted to cry? You couldn't cry?
-I cried a little, not too much.
-Generally you cry a lot?
-I cry more the older I get. When I was young I cried little or not at all and now I cry more.
-Can you describe your character?
Is she going to describe her character?
-No.
-Never mind how hard you try. She always go around, not because she does not want.
It is almost impossible to say deep things which are happening, why?
Because this kind of people are so sensitive,
they are afraid to come up and expose themselves.
It is like taking the skin and it is very painful. Let us see what she says.
-That's difficult. I try.
I think as a child I was very calm and introverted and now I am more open.
She thinks she is more open now. What is interested for us to observe is how a child
becomes calm and introverted.
How the environment will shape a lot of the child. What is the environment?
A father who married a woman who does not love him but she married him to have a husband
and to have a child.
The mother had in her mind the boyfriend that she lost, the love affair who died.
Most probably she never gave any real affection to the husband.
This coldness in between the couple is going to be transmitted into the understanding
of the child and the child lives in an environment where there is no real love, real affection.
No love and affection is expressed.
Further than this complex we have the mother not liking the husband,
she does not bring out her nature.
The nature of woman is love, the nature of man is wisdom!
Symbolically men supposed to be more wise, women supposed to be more loving.
Every one of us have both love and wisdom, don't worry.
Especially you, you are full of love and wisdom.
About love I don't have any objection. Wisdom...?
Symbolically this is the nature of woman, accepted or not.
When the woman gives love it feels at best, it feels she is fulfilling her function.
Now she cannot fulfill her function because she does not give love
and the child remains closed, remote ,calm, closed.
What is happening is the grandmother who comes into the picture and replaces the love
that the mother does not give into the daughter.
That is why the shock is so great for the daughter when the grandmother dies.
The shock is tremendous when the grandmother dies because the affection is not there
and the child finds the affection only in the grandmother and she is attached to her
but without speaking. It is an inward affection that she keeps to the grandmother. Why?
The child has not learned to speak emotions. Because emotions are not positive,
when emotions are not positive, you say I'm so angry, it's better not to talk.
It is like that, when you have a negative emotion it is better not to talk.
When the emotions are positive they are expressed and this is the nature
of positive emotions, they will be expressed, the others will perceive them.
The others will also perceive the negative emotions.
So that's why when the grandmother dies is a big shock.
This we can explain, we can understand now what took place in the heart of the child
by saying the whole story. She does not tell the whole story, she does not tell details
but we can imagine the details with the family, the structure.
Why do we have to understand all that? We have to understand for different reasons.
Because you are dealing with her disease and how... in an environment like this,
you can predict that the child will go this or that way.
And then you need this for the analysis to understand the remedy for that child.
What is the remedy? It must be a sensitive child who understands what is going on,
who gets attached to the grandmother, who doesn't talk, who understands the jealousy
of the mother, who smacked by the mother and never goes out,
then you have the construction of the character.
Otherwise you are going to find it difficult to prescribe for this case.
You have enough information? No.
-You consider yourself now an open person?
-Yes, I think.
-You can't talk about your problems with others?
-Yes, I can, I've learned.
-How you learned? By psychotherapy?
-Yes.
You see how much she is in a hurry? How you learned? The idea is shall I tell now?
You see? I did psychotherapy and shall I tell? She tries to find the way to tell without telling.
-And there they taught you to talk?
How long you did psychotherapy?
-Four years.
-What kind of psychotherapy?
-It was analysis of Jungian dream work through painting.
-And so you consider now yourself much more open?
-Yes I got more self-confidence.
-You had very great lack of self-confidence before?
-Yes I think.
-What would you do? Can you give an example?
-I'd stay at home, too frightened to leave home to do the shopping.
What are the symptoms, they are coming back again to which remedy?
Baryta carbonica. Too timid, she does not want to go out of the house.
-The husband had to do the shopping.
-All these things my husband did for me because he saw my trouble and my diseases
and he always said I do all the things for you. You lie down and rest.
-So you were lying down and resting and he did everything for you.
-I had no job and I did very few things in the house.
-Why? You were lazy?
-No because I felt ill, exhausted and frightened that I would not succeed.
-Even cooking?
-Cooking I did sometimes but not very much. Later on I left my husband
and I did that psychotherapy and a lot changed in my life.
-What changed?
-One little thing I took driving license.
I never dared before. That was the first feasible thing I did.
-You did something. And then?
-Then I drove a car myself.
-Then you felt more confident?
-Yes.
-And what else you did? You got another husband?
-No but another friend.
-Boyfriend?
-Yes he was an elder man, not a boy.
I live together with him for six years and I work in his praxis.
He is a doctor and I was his patient.
-Then what else you did? Then you left him also?
-He left me and I was very down, very depressed.
-That time you felt that you wanted to kill yourself?
-Yes but I have a son together with my husband.
That is the time we may think of a remedy. Which remedy?
-Natrum sulphuricum.
-In which case you may thing of Natrum sulphuricum?
If she says that there was a constant battle inside me between killing myself and living.
In that case alone with constant battle. Immediately we have to clarify that issue.
-I think if I hadn't him...
-You would have killed you.
-I think, I don't know.
One who wants to prescribe Natrum sulphuricum here we see what she said.
She said it but it's not the whole truth.
What I'm teaching you to hear, a person says I'm afraid, another person says I'm afraid
and a third person says I'm afraid or the same person says I'm afraid three times
and it might be totally different in intensity and in what he means.
The first time I'm afraid and there is real fright, the second time he says I'm afraid
and the third time he says I'm afraid, it's different.
But he says the word, he's afraid, it doesn't matter.
With intensity you don't expect to hear...
She said I would kill myself if I didn't have the boy, therefore I give her Nat-s.
I don't think this is the case. You say but she said it.
I don't think this is the case. Let us see.
-I think, I don't know but...
After the child...  that's the same time when my migraines started.
-Two years ago?
-Yes.
Not at once but in a few months. I had to change work, to change house and all my life changed,
to look for a new doctor.
-So by the time that he left you and you wanted to kill yourself,
the only thing that kept you was your son?
-Yes I think so.
-Did you have a big battle inside you to kill yourself and then you say no,
let's not do it and then again.
There was a big battle inside?
-No.
-Just some thoughts?
-Yes.
-Very short time?
-Very short time.
Do you see the difference? Do you see the real facts? These are the real facts.
We have to be aware of what is going on, don't stick on words, stick on the truth
of what is really happening.
-Don't we have enough symptoms for Nat. mur.? Every time she has a grief...
-Yes and the real grieves are two. The one time with the grandmother
and the other time with her lover.
These are the two times when she has real grief and the disease is pushed inside.
It goes to another level, it becomes much worse.
-Ignatia?
-Ignatia is a possibility.
We are considering Ignatia as well, we are considering Nat. mur.,
we are considering Staphysagria.
What it depicts this mouth in comparison with the mouth that we spoke about the boy?
What is the difference?
She has artificial teeth?
-Yes.
-The upper part of the teeth.
-I don't know, we can ask her.
What I want to give you my impression if we compare the two mouths.
This mouth shows determination, shows power, the other shows weakness, degeneration.
That face the degeneration is quite on a deep level, here the degeneration
is on a physical level only, it is not so much on mental-emotional.
She is very closed but still she is coping emotionally.