Her main complaint is bronchiectasis  and she is having it since childhood.
Her chest was worse in winter, worse in the evening, she has yellow-green catarrh,
she has a...  on the left side, very low energy which is much worse
when she is emotionally upset, she passed pneumonia at 18 months,
she had a mastoid in the right ear at age three which was treated with bandages
for six months, and she is deaf in the right ear now, she had chicken pox at four years
and then her left ear drum burst and so her hearing is now quite poor.
She's had catarrh and chest infections continuously with discharging ears.
She had deafness in her teens and they thought she was stupid
because it affected her work so much but she worked very hard to prove
that she was not stupid. She was not that good.
At 20 she had pneumonia and after this time she had several operations to drain her sinuses
and then they put local anesthetics to do this and many antibiotics
and finally they diagnosed the bronchiectasis in her early 20's.
In 1971 she had a duodenal ulcer which was complicated by...
She had tuberculosis and she caught this from another patient.
She was working in the hospital at the time and this was treated with streptomycin,
rifampicin and ethambutol for two months and she decided at the end of the two months
to stop the treatment and started taking tissue salts
because they wanted to continue the treatment but she decided to stop.
She had too many car accidents and in spite of being so ill she managed to keep her job
for 15 years and in spite of being told that she was invalid
and recently she had a D&C with fibroids.
-What is the D&C?
-Dilation and Curettage
Her relationship to men suffered tremendously due to her health
which she was always trying to hide from people, she never wanted anyone to say
that she is not well.
People don't know that she is not well.
She is very open about her feelings but resenting this for many years of being ill.
She is quite shy in company although she is not shy with me.
I think she is shy when she meets new people but not when she has a good contact with someone.
She lacks confidence and when she is emotionally upset she feels very ill.
-This is the case you took in the beginning or the now the present situation?
-The case I took in the beginning is very close and some symptoms were worse.
She had more pain in her ribs and more perspiration she had some symptoms a bit worse.
She takes everything to heart and very sensitive to external impressions.
She always thought time is very short.
When she is well, she is all right but she has tremendous anxiety about disease when she
is not feeling well. She has a fear of mice.
She has a fear of failure, she is quite loquacious, she is romantic,
she keeps her problems to herself.
...for relationship with someone but she is not promiscuous.
Her sexual energy she says is normal to strong but inside she feels very deep wariness.
She feels icy cold generally, cold extremities and at the moment
she has numbness in her fingers sometimes are so cold.
She hates the winter and she is generally better from heat.
Perspiration, night sweats twice the week now, she is doing treatment, now she is relapsed again.
They can be offensive.
The menses heavy bleeding, dark clots, considerate pain of the right ovary,
the bleeding sometimes stops during the day and it's profused at night.
This improved about a month, now again she is relapsed.
Food; she desires vegetables twice, fish twice, sour fruit twice, lemons twice,
onions, garlic, butter, she can eat the crispy fat of meat, sweets not very strong.
Very thirsty for water only at night and sometimes she gets up in the night
and she is hungry.
Her sleep is 8-10 hours per night, sometimes troubled and she wakes up unrefreshed.
The ears are still discharging a yellow, white offensive and sometimes brownish discharge
and it's ringing and humming  noises in the ears.
Very sensitive and she began salivating in the beginning of the treatment
and that comes and goes.
The first remedy she had was on October the 19th Mercury solubilis 1M and on December the 7th
that was repeated and then I went to discuss the case with another homeopath
and he thought Silica.
So I was confused how to get to Silica through...  whether I should go straight to Silica
or whether I should get through Hepar Sulphur and now what happened is she said
she wasn't well after the first remedy and that wasn't clear when I retook the case in December,
she was saying she wasn't well...
So now I'm going confused, there are many remedies I consider for her.
-Hepar Sulphur what has done?
-She was better for a while, she gets better all the time and then she relapses.
She is not as bad as she used to be.
-What are her main symptoms now?
-She has lots of little symptoms, they change all the time George.
-There is no difficulty in respiration?
-She is coughing a lot of sputum.
-What is the main complaint for her?
-Now she said her hands are numbed.
The numbness in her hands, the ringing in her ears.
-They have diagnosed Raynaud's syndrome?
-In the beginning because the pain in the chest and the weakness and the tiredness,
always in the telephone is the weakness and the tiredness and when am I going to be well
and I feel terrible and a lot of physical complaints to go with it.
I never have enough energy to cope.
-What is her main complaint? You never tried Tuberculinum?
-They are confused to look for which one it is, I can say that. Tuberculinum, Phosphorus, Calcarea ...
This is a case of bronchiectasis primarily with the main symptomatology
a very deep seated tiredness.
There is a very deep feeling of being tired, this is the main thing with the bronchiectasis.
She is a woman that has been through tuberculosis, through different hospitals
and she has been treated quite a lot, brought eventually to that state with is great tiredness
and the production of the lungs, almost constant bringing up sputum with bronchiectasis,
which is X-rayed and which is radiological confirmed.
What you hear here in this case?
This case has been treated for a year before with different remedies which were Mercury,
Hepar sulphur, Silica... did you write all the remedies?
The impression of the practitioner is that all the time she is getting better but relapses,
getting better, relapses etc.
When you hear that story is not a good story.
It may indicate two things.
One is that the prescribing was wrongly all the time, so it gave the impression
of an amelioration and then the person comes back without a real progress of the case.
The second possibility is that one of these remedies is correct,
brings about an amelioration for a short period of time, then it relapses.
An immediate amelioration would mean in such severe case which means
that the case mostly rather is incurable. You don't like in severe pathology case
an immediate amelioration, you don't like that.
And if you hear it, expect that in a short period of time the person will come back
and say I'm back again.
You give the same remedy, it does not work, you change the remedy,
it works a little bit and back again. Another remedy, works a little bit and back again.
That is a bad observation, it means that the pathology is too deep
and most probably it is incurable.
Invariably in all the cases I have seen when the practitioner brings the case
and says the person reacted well to that remedy and he remained well for a month,
he remained well for 20 days, he remained well for this and this period of time...
And he says now I'm confused. You should not be confused,
a homeopath should know what is going on and why he should wait one time
and why he should not wait another time.
When you are going to prescribe, immediately almost the second day or the third day
after your prescription, you have to prescribe another remedy,
like another case of pneumonia that they brought me, neglected pneumonia
and they brought to me at 12 o'clock the case and I prescribed the remedy in America
and I said if by tomorrow morning she is not better, we will try another remedy
and then give antibiotics.
I mean there is no need to wait there. How long you are going to wait?
You cannot because the case is too severe, it has to react immediately.
In such severe case the reaction will be immediate.
You cannot say I think the remedy something has done and you wait very nicely
and if you go to sleep in the night you may wake up with a shock in the morning.
So don't come and tell me, George said you wait and wait, no.
George did not say you wait and wait. George said you can prescribe after two hours
if the person is dying, you are not going to wait next day because she will die tonight.
So your remedy has to act within two hours, it has to act within five hours,
it has to act within 20 hours, it has to act because of the severity of the case.
In this case we have the practitioner saying we have a little bit amelioration
and again back, amelioration and again back. The case is deep pathology
and the assessment is most probably the remedies were wrong but we will see now the case
and we will assess if this might be an incurable case.
-What are your main symptoms? What you would complain?
-My main symptom is my hearing problem. I can't interpret the word,
I can't make sense of a sentence. The other is my chest, it's wheezy.
-When?
-When I breathe.
-Have you noticed that?
I'd like to draw your attention to the question. I said what is your main problem?
When you have a case presented to you, the practitioner usually present it
with her own experience...
She has so many symptoms, does not know what symptom to give you first...
she gives you a heap of symptoms.
Now out of this heap of symptoms what is the most important? Why?
Because the remedy has to revolve around this main symptomatology.
Therefore as you go along with your study of Materia Medica and the study of our medicines,
you will realize that each of our medicines have the capacity and the ability to affect
certain areas of the body. Mostly the eyes.
If you see a case where most of the symptomatology is around his eyes,
eye problems...
your mind will go necessarily to Phystostigma or Ruta or remedies that have an ability
to affect the eye.
When you see the chest your mind will go to remedies that affect the chest or the liver.
I do not say give a remedy that affects the organ, don't misinterpret me
but the remedy has the capacity to affect what?
If somebody says my liver and my guts, my colon is affected that is a case
where you will think of Lycopodium?
Not necessarily because it affects both the liver and the colon, Lycopodium.
When a person says my main problem is urinary infections, which is the main remedy
which is indicated in cystitis? Sarsaparilla.
You get an idea of the remedy in this way, not that Sarsaparilla is going to be the remedy
or Lycopodium is going to be the remedy but the idea is there.
Unless you think in this way I'm explaining to you, you will not find the remedy in this case.
This person comes and you say what is your main problem?
The practitioner presented the case, you had the case.
Now she comes and says my main problems are hearing problems and chest problems.
Did you hear that from the practitioner? Did you understand it from the practitioner? No.
He said, it's coughing, sputum, numbness, blah, blah, blah.
Now she comes and says hearing and chest problems.
Now you concentrate, you limit your possibilities a little bit more now on the remedies.
-Wheezing and difficulty in respiration?
-No.
-When the wheezing is more? In bed?
-If I'm flat and when I have tremendous tiredness.
-When the tiredness is mostly?
-If I'm strained with living, with general conditions?
-When you exert yourself physically?
-Not necessarily. When I'm in unhappy atmosphere.
The tiredness is worse when she is stressed, she is under stress, especially
when she is under mental stress, she feels very tired. It is a deep sense of tiredness
which you will not see it very frequently described in this way
because she will describe it again and again.
Can you find anything in the Repertory?
From mental exertion, weakness in generalities, worse from mental exertion?
It is Calcarea, Cuprum, Ferrum picricum, Lachesis  etc.
-You sleep 10 hours?
-8 to 10, 8 hours regularly.
But then I need to catch up. But again if I'm very happy...
-In bed do you keep a position, left, right?
-No...
-When you wake up, you are very unrefreshed?
-No very refreshed.
-Sometimes unrefreshed?
-...I wake up very thirsty, I have to stop myself from a drink.
-You have great thirst?
-Yes at night.
-Does it have to be cold?
-Yes cold.
-Do you put ice?
-No ice, never, just cold.
-Did you ever have any bleeding on the lungs?
-Just before 3 years I think I might have been having in the sputum...
But I get a tremendous cold hands and feet and numbed. I have to shake them.
-Both?
-Yes, particularly my right.
-I did not understand, did she say the hands become numbed because of the coldness or not?
-What did she say?
-She said that she had cold hands that become quite numbed.
-From cold?
-She didn't say directly... She has to shake them to become unnumbed.
-There is connection between the numbness and the coldness?
-Most probably she is a cold person and she is aggravated by cold and we have to understand
that this numbness and coldness comes from exposure to cold.
-...My eyes are very tired with the contact lenses, I have to take my contact lenses out...
-How many years do you wear contact lenses?
-Three years...
-Do you still have your menses?
-Yes, on and off.
-Menses are irregular?
-They were regular but then I had a lot of bleeding...
-When you had your menses before there was a lot of blood?
-Yes and clotted...
-You told me it was very profuse.
-That was at...  and I had pain in my right ovary.
Has anybody thought about the remedy so far?
You have any idea about the remedy that maybe indicated?
Calcarea, Silica, Lycopodium, Phosphorus, Calcarea carbonica.
You have different opinions about the remedy because as we said the case is not clear.
So far the case is not clear and therefore if you take certain symptomatology
out of that you say Phosphorus, if you take another symptomatology you say Calcarea, Silica etc.
But you cannot put together things and say this is the remedy.
You can argue for any remedy, it is not clear.
It indicates for progressed pathology and difficult cases the remedy is not apparent
and you have to be very careful in your first prescribing because we can spoil these cases
by repeating too many remedies, giving too many remedies.
And then you can lose the picture all together and you cannot find it
and even if a master comes he cannot find it because they are masked,
symptoms have changed.
This is the most unfortunate situation and this is why we don't like the complex remedies
that they suppress symptoms, they cloud the symptoms.
That's why we say you have to be careful. If you give 10 remedies here, what is going to happen?
Some of these remedies will affect the symptomatology in one way or another
and you will lose the real picture of the case.
-Many things but I can't get the right word...
-It was full moon, that has an effect to me. I don't know.
-That was one time?
-No, every time after few weeks...
I begin to wonder if it is tight up with the full moon.
I get a pain in the right breast just quite a shock, a hot pain, I feel a hot feeling.
-How do you feel emotionally?
-The other day I was... and I got emotional...I'm helpless.
-You mean you cried?
-Yes in a way...
-Can you describe your character?
-Up and down in a way. How to describe my character?
...I can be hard but I can be very sympathetic...
I like to be with people and I like uplifting situations and if someone has got a problem...
-Do you have a lot of enjoyment? Do you enjoy life?
-I like to... where my limitations are, I can't do much, I wouldn't dare...
The same with sports.
-The biggest fear that you have what is?
-Fear of mice.
-The biggest fear she has is fear of mice, what is the remedy?
Calcarea carbonica has fear of mice.
Can you tell me so far, what symptoms you have noted down
and how you will look so far in the Repertory?
-Worse from mental exertion, great thirst.
-Thirst underlined perhaps 2-3 times.
-Cold.
-Cold underlined two times.
-She is very loquacious. She is trying to please you.
-Yes.
-Sympathetic maybe.
-What about other symptoms?
-She does not want people to know that she is not well.
-Wheezing.
-Bad hearing.
-Both ears are affected.
-Desires company.
-Pain in the right ovary during menses and pain on right breast.
-She works, she is high spirited or something like that.
-Hopeful.
-Cheerful.
-Tired in full moon.
-Memory weak.
-Refined.
-Why you say refined?
-I have that impression.
-Icy cold hands and feet and numbness.
Can you look in your Repertory now if you have enough symptoms?
Can you tell me the remedy now?
Why you cannot tell the remedy?
You have enough symptoms already, perhaps quite a lot but you cannot tell the remedy.
Why?
-No peculiar symptoms.
-You see here we have symptoms that are not peculiar, we do not have keynotes
to be guided and also some of these symptoms are our own subjective observations.
Maybe they are not true, maybe some other symptoms we did not hear well
and we did not pay attention to what might have been peculiar in that symptom.
All these reasons make up for a confusion, that's why the case now is confused.
Nobody can tell me the remedy. Does anybody think that because of this,
this and that symptom the remedy is that?
If you go to the Repertory and you look, you will see several symptoms, polychrests
but not the remedy.
During the interval think about the remedy and when we come back I'm sure you will know it.
Do you see the confusion?
She will get one remedy and she is going to have a reaction.
It is a big reaction, it is a reaction that you may think it's a wrong reaction,
she is getting mentally... bizarre symptoms but you will see the whole class will say now
this is the remedy.
You will see how much clear the second remedy is going to be that almost the whole class,
I don't know your level of excellence but seeing the attention that you pay to all
these nonsense I'm talking about that means your level is quite high!
Let's see a little bit more because there are some hints.
Of course how I prescribed the remedy, it's not intuition, I've put things together.
I didn't pay attention to some, I paid attention to some others, I evaluated the case.
Also for those people that come for the first time I have to say that I have been accused
for being a 'Kentian', they say Vithoulkas is a Kentian, that I follow Kent too much.
He is a Kentian, forget him, don't pay attention to him.
And it is true the one who really taught me is Kent. I've learned most I know from Kent.
Yet I realized very early that whatever is written here in this book
which we call Kent's Repertory is not absolute.
That means if I have a remedy, if I have a case and present a symptom like fear of mice
but here I see only Calcarea carbonica, this is not absolute.
It doesn't mean that I cannot go away from Calcarea carbonica because in fear of mice
Calc carbo is the only one which is mentioned here.
That means there are some omissions in the Repertory, there are some remedies
that have symptoms that have not been recorded here in this Repertory.
And also there are other symptoms which are recorded in a false way,
paying too much attention or paying too little attention.
So we have to add and to refine the Repertory and if you come
and say this is not in the Repertory...Every time I face the same situation.
This is not in the Repertory, I say OK that does not mean anything.
It means that this remedy that I'm going to give perhaps has also fear of mice
and it is not recorded in the Repertory.
That's all it means, if that is going away by the remedy I gave.
Or it might mean another thing that underneath the remedy I'm going to prescribe,
there is another remedy, maybe Calcarea carbonica, which is coming later on.
So there are some symptoms always that come from...
-Other layer.
-What you are interested always is the first layer.
The first layer is Ignatia, you have to give Ignatia but in this layer of Ignatia,
which underneath has, let us say a symptom here, which is desires salt...
Desires salt is the symptom but appears together with the symptoms of Ignatia,
it appears desires salt but actually it is the second remedy that we should have been given.
But it pops out one or two symptoms of Natrum muriaticum but most are symptoms of Ignatia,
give Ignatia first and then Nat mur. If you go the other way around, it's not going to work.
-You don't like the cats?
-I don't want to have a cat...
-Are you afraid?
Do you hear that? What is this? A kind of aversion to cats.
What is the remedy?
-Tuberculinum.
-The lungs are affected, Tuberculinum.
You see, you have not been thinking of Tuberculinum before.
Now with this information in your mind comes Tuberculinum.
You retake the case and you look through the case, does it fit to Tuberculinum?
It fits?
-I'm not disgusted, I don't like cats. Anything that smells. Membrane...
-You are afraid of disease? You are concerned?
-No.
-Do you have any fear during thunderstorms?
-No I enjoy them.
Enjoying thunderstorm, what is the remedy?
-Sepia.
-Very good, you know your Repertory quite good. Is this Sepia? Can be Sepia?
The physic is like Sepia very much because she is thin. Her physique is like Sepia.
Sepia can be affected in the lungs? Yes it can be affected in the lungs.
Tuberculinum can be affected in the ear? Not so much, a little bit.
Again the same question.
What she tells now, she gives some keynotes the last few times.
Tuberculinum, enjoying thunderstorms, I asked for Phosphorus and she comes out
with an answer which indicates Sepia.
Is this Sepia? Is this Tuberculinum? Is this Calc carbo? This comes to my mind.
-You speak very fast, can you speak a little bit more slow because I'm not English.
-Sorry.
-When you talk, after talking you get tired?
-No.
Why did I ask this question?
-Stannum.
-If she complains about a deep tiredness and she is a person she had tuberculosis,
with the deep tiredness the remedy that has this pathology very much is Stannum.
Stannum is a tubercular remedy with a deep sense of tiredness, with sputum coming out.
For years she brings out sputum.
In Stannum when the person coughs immediately comes big lumps
of mucus comes out and tiredness.
But Stannum has tiredness especially when talking, then it gets tired.
If this person would say I just talk in the telephone half a minute and I'm exhausted,
that becomes a keynote of Stannum and might be a case of Stannum.
The answer is no, I don't get tired when I talk.
Also knowing what I know about Stannum, this cannot be a case of Stannum.
Stannum is too tired to laugh, too tired to communicate in this.
What is this tiredness, what is the peculiar characteristic of this tiredness
is that it's a deep seated tiredness.
It's not on the physical level almost, it's a tiredness on the mental level almost.
It's a very deep background tiredness that holds her back and she cannot continue to do things.
Stannum is not like that, it's more physical.
What is the most tired remedy, more than Stannum?
-Muriatic acid.
-Picric acid.
-Picric acid on a mental level very tired. Phosphoric acid on an emotional level very tired.
When we say emotional, no emotions, inside flatness but physically it will keep on doing things.
Picric acid the mind stops, cannot produce thoughts. Picric acid will make a big effort
to understand a simple sentence, tremendous tiredness on a mental level.
Muriatic acid- I'm talking about the three acids- is a physical tiredness, exhaustion.
The emotions may be there acting, the mind in Muriatic acid will work
but the physical part of the human being is so tired.
Stannum also is physically tired. There is another remedy which is physically tired,
which is Gelsemium.
There is a very seldom indicated remedy, which is very tired and especially
when they try to move they are producing flushes.
-Helonias
-Who said Helonias very good. Have you heard it from me?
-Yes.
-Very good, he remembers it. Many heard it but they don't remember it.
Now here is again a case of tiredness. This is a new kind of tiredness, see this tiredness,
put it in your mind. Now if you meet it again, you will recognize it
in the remedy I'm going to prescribe.
-Do you like talking?
-Yes sometimes. I realize I repeat myself.
I investigated the possibility of Lachesis.
-Do you like fish quite a lot?
You see the practitioner, if you remember, says desire for fish and that misguided me
because if the practitioner says this is this, your mind is not guided properly.
But you see I never trust anybody ever.
You say yes and I sit back and I think to myself, is this yes? Why it's yes, why it's not?
I've learned because of human experience that there are many reasons why we could not trust.
Because people do not themselves know what they are talking about,
because they want to mislead you, because they think it's better if I tell this and not this,
because of many reasons we twist facts.
We present facts in a not straightforward manner and what we need here is the language
of the defense mechanism which is not the mind.
The defense mechanism says give me salt, give me salt and the mind says no salt,
no salt. Give me salt, no salt and then the mind put the stamp, it says no salt.
Then he comes to your examining room and you say do you desire salt? No.
Do you have an aversion to salt? Yes aversion to salt and then in his yes
I see in his memory something is not clear, something bothers him,
he does not even understand it.
I say did you decide not to have salt? Yes. Did you use to desire salt? Yes.
How much? I take salt and I eat it like that.
And you come to tell me that you have aversion to salt and I write aversion to salt,
that's not right.
You misguided me completely because your mind decided not to have salt
and you managed to do it...
Then what shall I take into consideration? The language of the mind
or the language of the defense mechanism?
I'm interested in the language of the defense mechanism, what is coming forward
from an instinctive level, that's what I'm interested. Otherwise I have no way.
We can disguise all our symptoms. The stories I have heard about the symptoms...
Why this pain is there and not there.
That is why you will find it more easy to treat people that come from villages, uneducated.
They have strong constitution, fish? Yes I take fish and I eat it, this is the language.
Give me sweet or salt yes I take this or I have this pain, it's clear.
You get a sophisticated man from town and you are lost. You don't know
what he has decided himself and what his organism has decided, it's a mixture of the two
and that's why I say I don't trust.
-You like fruits?
-Yes all fruits, particularly not so much the very sweet.
-You prefer the sour?
-Yes.
-Do you prefer unripe fruits?
-Slightly unripen.
She prefers unripe fruits, is this a case of Calcarea sulphuricum,
is this a case of Medorrhinum, of Veratrum? Sour fruits.
-When you drink water you will drink a whole glass or you drink a little bit?
-No, a whole glass. I take a jar to bed.
-You drink the whole lot until the morning?
-Sometimes yes.
-Do you like salty things?
-Yes. I don't take salt.
-Why because it's no good?
-No, no because it takes the flavor of food, I put half of it in herbs.
-If it is salty you don't like it?
-I don't enjoy it.
If it was Phosphorus this case would she give this answer for salt?
-No.
-The most probable would be that desire for salt is there for Phosphorus.
If she was Calcarea carbonica, most probably desire for salt would be there.
Both desire for salt and desire for sweets.
What I'm struggling here is it Calcarea, Tuberculinum, Phosphorus, Sepia, Stannum
what it is? Now I have come to the conclusion what it is. I've shorted it out.
It is none of these remedies. You will hear and I believe you will understand what I'm thinking.