-This is somebody whom I saw in October 1990 and I haven't given her any remedies for
at least one year but in the beginning I gave her Lycopodium 30C and then I gave her
Kali silica 6C, Phosphorus 200C one dose, Calcarea carbonica 30C
-That made me sick.
-That made her worse, Tuberculinum 30C. That was March 11th 1991, when she had the
Tuberculinum and that was her last remedy.
-Is there a diagnosis?
-She has many symptoms, maybe just wait to see the interview and then we can decide
the diagnosis.
-You are photogenic I see.
-Thank you.
-What is your problem?
-I have a lot of different symptoms. My main complaint is fatigue, I'm tired most of the time
and dizzy almost all of the time, poor concentration, loss of balance, feeling spaced
out, nausea, when I'm very tired I feel very nauseous. I think I have to look in my book.
-These are the main things that you remembered immediately.
-Yes, those are the main things. Feeling tired most of the time, I get energy I feel very
energetic and then all of a sudden my energy drops down.
I wake up feeling tired most of the time, sometimes I wake up feeling depressed.
I have mood swings where I feel great and then I get depressed and I can be that way for
a couple of hours and then I come up again and I feel OK.
Everything that I do every day I'm always judging whether I can handle it.
It's always like a fine balancing between what I can do and what I can't do.
Where I should hold back and take it easy and rest  and where I can push myself and see
how far I can go.
-Since when you are having these problems?
-Ten years.
-From age of 19 you are fatigue.
-Yes.
-Why? Do you know why?
-I have ideas. When I was 16 I started antibiotic treatments for three years.
-Three years?
-For three solid years.
-For what?
-For my face, acne. I didn't know anything about it then, now I know a lot about antibiotics.
And I react now when I take antibiotics, like flu symptoms, I get very sick for a couple of
weeks and stay in bed.
I was worse about five years ago. There were times when I couldn't get out of bed,
I would go to bed sometimes 8-9 o'clock in the evening and I would have so little energy,
I couldn't even talk to anybody, I was just lying in bed and watch TV.
From that time I got a little better, so I'm definitely better than I used to be.
There were times when I couldn't get out of bed.
-Who gave you this treatment? It was a doctor or yourself?
-I started with a chiropractor. He would do body work on me and he gave me Airborne
remedies and tinctures and things like that.
-But what about the antibiotics? Who gave you?
-That was the dermatologist.
-He, himself said for three years you have to take it?
-Yes, I was going back and say I need a refill and he just
-He wrote another prescription.
-He would do a drawing of my face every time I went to see him, how many pimples I still
have on my face.
-Now you have very nice skin but behind the skin things are not...so great
-What will happen if we give you a remedy and your acne comes back?
-That's OK. If I feel better and I have acne that's OK.
-That's OK. Are you sure?
-Yes, I'm sure.
-I understand how much you suffer from that.
Other symptoms that you have?
-Do you have anemia?
-She is ready to cry.
-It's been difficult.
-What you thought now and brought you tears? What was in your mind?
-Thinking about the symptoms.
-You thought some symptoms that you wanted to relate and that brought you tears?
-I think just talking about it. I think most of the time that I'm OK, that I'm not sick.
-You try to persuade yourself, you say you are not sick?
-Yes, I think I'm OK and I get up and just keep pushing on. Every day I just keep going.
I have good days also and I have some days where I feel really good but those days are
far and few.
-Are you married?
-No.
-Do you have children?
-You live with your family or by yourself?
-With a roommate.
-How do you feel emotionally?
-I feel stronger than I used to. I used to feel depressed most of the time.
I used to cry a lot, I used to feel not very strong, I feel much stronger now.
I've worked out some of the emotional things.
In the beginning it was more difficult because I would see medical doctors and
they couldn't help and they would say there is nothing wrong with you.
You just need a psychiatrist. That was difficult.
When doctors kept telling me there is nothing wrong with you and they still say that.
From time to time I go back and tell them that I don't feel great.
They do blood tests and they say everything is normal, you are fine.
-Very good.
So far the case looks like Pulsatilla.
-I have more symptoms, a lot more.
-We will talk about it, don't worry but we make an analysis until this time and we say
that she looks like Pulsatilla; she used to cry a lot and she has changing moods.
-Lot of headaches, very often.
-When are  the headaches?
-I wake up in the morning with a headache sometimes, at the end of the day, it doesn't matter.
-There is no special time when you usually have a headache?
-No.
It's more often towards the end of the day rather than waking up with a headache.
-The fatigue, the dizziness, the poor concentration and loss of balance, all these
symptoms that she related in the beginning fit to a remedy, which is called Gelsemium.
And then eventually we have the changing moods and the weeping which went into Pulsatilla.
Now headaches without real modalities. What else do we have?
-It's hard to describe but I think you know how horses have the blinders on the sides?
Sometimes I feel that I could do this because I have a hard time focusing,
not so much the concentration but if I'm walking down the street, I feel that it is easier for me
to look and to focus more in a smaller space rather than in a big space.
It is almost as if it is too much for me to take in. I can't focus. It's almost like a visual thing.
I get spaced out in Malls, so I avoid Malls, shopping Malls.
I get very late headed when I'm in a room that's really huge, where the ceiling is really high.
And the lighting affects me sometimes too.
I don't like neon lights, I just become aware of the fact that I'm in neon lights and I don't
know somehow it seems to do something to my focus.
-She has 16 pages of symptoms.
-No 25.
-25 pages of symptoms, can you imagine? Again the same problem.
The immune system that has been harassed by three years of antibiotic treatment and all
kinds of chemicals that you inserted in your body.
-I started taking Gaviscon which is an anti-acid.
I took that every single day for a couple of years because of heartburn.
That was the beginning. When I was 16, I started to have this problem but I was taking
antibiotics at the same time.
-You were taking already antibiotics and then your stomach started having heartburns and
then you took anti-acids.
-Yes.
-Do you still take anti-acids now?
-Very rarely. Every once in a while I do.
-Also in this case we see the different steps that the disturbance followed.
First it is on the skin, then it goes to the stomach, to the mucus membranes of the
stomach and now it is deeper causing generalized problems, a fatigue syndrome almost.
It is not a fatigue syndrome, it is an indescribable
Thats why they cannot find through the laboratory tests and pin down the disturbance.
Can you give us what is bothering you? Give us more information.
-I have bowel problems.
-Constipation or diarrhea?
-More severe than that. Sometimes cramping, a lot of mucus in the stool.
I was in a hospital about two years ago, my stomach was really bloated out and I had a lot
of cramping.
And I had a fever, so I went into emergency and they kept me for a week.
They thought at first I had an appendicitis but after three days they ruled that out and
they did some endoscopy tests, they do a lot of tests, ultra sound, blood tests,  lots of different things.
They couldn't find anything except to say that they felt that I had irritable bowel syndrome.
So everyone my bowels act up and then I just rest a bit more and I'm careful
of what I eat, I don't eat any meat, I don't eat breads and things like that.
I just eat soups and cooked vegetables until it clears up, then I go back to my normal diet.
I had it last week for about five or six days and sometimes it gets to the point where I'm
lying in bed for a couple of hours and that seems to just make me feel a bit better.
-At this moment we can go to the Repertory and see if we use fatigue, dizziness, we look
through this poor concentration, nausea, unrefreshed sleep.
-You still have this bloatedness?
-Not all the time, sometimes.
-Mucus in stool frequently?
-No, when I start to feel the cramping.
-How frequently?
-It's very mild for a couple of days. It's mild when it's bothering and then I know that I have to be careful.
-Once the month, sometimes twice the month.
-The headache how frequently?
-3-4 times the week.
-The headache, the most frequent time that comes is morning, evening?
-Middle day to evening.
-Specify the time, if you can.
-Early afternoon, two o'clock.
-Until?
-It depends. Sometimes it lasts for two days, sometimes I go to bed still with a headache.
-Because her symptoms are not peculiar and are not defined and are not with modalities,
we can only get an idea by looking what is most prominent in these general symptoms.
How many symptoms you put already in, 5-6?
Can you give me the symptoms? Let me see the symptoms.
Suppressed eruptions, weakness, weeping in telling her symptoms, changeable mood,
mucus in stool, unrefreshing sleep and stomach nausea.
It's very difficult to make a decision with these symptoms and
if we go to the flat repertorization, it will show?
Flat repertorization gives Pulsatilla as a first possibility and Sepia as a second
and Kali carbonicum as a third.
So the Expert System most probably will give Pulsatilla as well.
No. Psorinum, Petroleum, Sepia, Sulphur, Baryta carbonica, Staphysagria, Alumina,
Ammonium carbonicum.
Do you feel in general better in cold weather?
-No, worse.
-Very much worse? Cold really affects you?
-Yes, very cold weather does.
As you saw in the Expert System, it cannot make a decision.
So it gave underneath, interrogate about these remedies.
So the first thing in order to discriminate between the Pulsatilla that has most of the symptoms
and the Psorinum is the feeling of cold or warm. She is a chilly person aggravated by cold.
Can you give me what symptoms has the Psorinum?
The suppressed eruption, strong weakness, the changeable mood, mucus,
the unrefreshed sleep and the nausea.
-I should add also one more thing that I have sore throat a lot, chronic.
-So she had an aggravation after Calcarea carbonica, she became worse?
-Yes it made me quite sick.
-Without improving the situation?
-No. The only thing that helped was Phosphorus but it didn't help for very long.
-It doesn't matter. Would you give some of the symptoms that you have underlined
or do you want to continue with your symptoms or you finished?
-I have others but the ones that I gave you are the important ones.
-Do you have fears?
-Yes.
-What kind?
-Fear of running out of time.
-Which means you do not have enough time to do the work?
There is a feeling of hurried inside?
-Yes.
-Another?
-Fear of losing control.
-Losing control of your mental faculties?
-Yes.
-That's a strong fear, very strong? It bothers you really or it's just in the background and
sometimes it comes as an idea?
-In the background, sometimes.
-Another one?
-I think not reaching my potential.
-You are afraid you will just drift through life without really doing something creative?
-Yes.
-What are you doing at this moment as a profession?
-I paint, I make jewelry also.
-Do you have a relationship? A boyfriend?
-Yes.
-How you are with him?
-Good.
-You have no problems with your sexual behavior with him?
-Sometimes.
-Can you describe?
-I guess a lack of drive from my part sometimes.
-But when you have drive, you have desire, then you can reach orgasm?
-Yes, no problem.
-You see this is the possibility of Sepia that was coming up as a second possibility,
which seemed to be for a moment a possibility.
It might be because Sepia has all that fatigue and difficult concentration and the nausea.
Can you show me Sepia how many of the symptoms covers?
Sepia is a second possibility and it covers suppressed eruption, weakness, weeping,
telling of her sickness, changeable mood, slimy mucus, unrefreshing sleep, nausea,
inflammation of tonsils.
Did you put worse cold? Did you enter it?
-I feel better in the summer, much better. In the dryness and the sun.
-Better warm. Baryta carbonica, Tuberculinum, Sepia, Carbo animalis, Petroleum,
Digitalis, Aconitum, Sulphuric acid and Alumina.
Baryta carbonica, that gives us another idea and Sepia possibilities, with Carbo animalis,
with the sluggish circulation.
-Do you perspire at all?
-Yes.
-Is your perspiration offensive?
-No.
-You do not use this deodorant?
-Yes I do.
-That's why it is not. You don't know.
-I do most of the time, not all the time.
-Why you do it? Just in case?
-Just in case.
-When you are in bed your feet are cold?
-Yes.
-You have to wear socks?
-Not in the summertime.
-In winter?
-Yes. My nose and my hands are usually cold.
-In winter do you have to cover your head?
-A lot.
-Do you have to wear something warm?
-Yes I'm covered up to here, I wear lots of layers, 4,5,6 layers.
-My god.
-Sometimes two pairs of socks and boots that are lined.
-If your head is exposed to cold, will you get a headache?
-Yes. If my room is too cold, then I wake up with a headache.
-So do you have in sleep to wear something on your head as well?
-No.
-But you have to warm your room quite a lot?
-Yes.
You will see that Psorinum, I was not thinking at all about Psorinum but I got the hint from
the repertorization and the hint seems to be maybe a good one to start with this case.
-Tell me did you have a lot of boyfriends? You were hurt during these relationships?
-Sure.
-A lot?
-Sometimes, not always.
-Tell me when it was the time when your skin finally became clean, as it is now?
At what age? 19 or 20?
-It got better in early twenties but it still breaks out.
-But a little?
-Less.
-But it got much better already by the age of 19?
-No, when I stopped the antibiotics it got really bad.
-Then what you did? You took some more?
-No, at 19 I stopped.
-Then how the acne disappeared?
-Just slowly over the years.
-When did you start having sexual relationship?
-16.
-16 already?
-Yes, don't tell my mother.
-We don't tell anybody. Actually everybody here who is in the class is under oath that will
not discuss anything outside of the class. Otherwise it would be very difficult.
Here we can discuss everything but outside of the class there is a code of secrecy.
Sexually you were awaken strongly?
-No.
-The acne broke out at the age of 15 or 16?
-No, it started at 13.
-You started having sexual intercourse at the age of 16 regularly?
-No.
-It was accidental?
-Yes a couple of times.
-When did you start having normal sexual intercourse, at what age?
-I would say about 20, 21.
-Do you think that there is a kind of relation between having sexual normal intercourse
and the diminishing of the acne?
-No.
-Are you the only person in the family? Do you have a sister?
-I have two sisters and two brothers.
-Did they have the same problem with the acne?
-My sister does but it came out much later, in her twenties.
-Do you have strong finger nails or they are weak? They break easily?
-When they are long, they break after a couple of weeks, they split.
They are a bit stronger than they used to be. They used to be very weak.
-Usually they split or they crack?
-They split and crack, both.
-This one is strong.
-Only one finger is strong. So you keep it longer a bit. I see it's the only finger nail that is a bit longer.
We have that symptom? No.
-Only one never breaks.
Here we have brittle finger nails, we have Graphites and Psorinum which are capitals.
-They are always drying around the nails, always.
Dryness of fingers around nails, do we have? No.
-Are you jealous?
-No although I can be.
-Can you wear something which is tight here?
-Never. I never wear anything really tight.
-Why?
-I just like my neck open.
-Why? Because you have a nice neck and you want to show it?
-No because I just feel uncomfortable when there is something around my neck.
-Around your waist you can put a belt?
-Yes.
-Around your breast you can wear a bras?
-You can wear, you don't feel restricted by that?
-No, just around my neck.
Can you show me that symptom?
Silica is another possibility for her. She is cold, she looks mild. We don't know whether she is mild.
We have to ask her boyfriend to tell us how mild she is.
-He won't say this.
Clothing aggravates. Crotalus horridus, Sancris, Lachesis, Crotalus cascavella.
Put that also, put it three times, she is definite about that. You don't want...
-I hate it.
Let me see the analysis.
Still Psorinum and you see the Lachesis it was a thought.
It has come up with Sepia and Silica. Silica also is there.
Now we have different possibilities to think about. Give me the columns.
Here you see the Psorinum, Sepia, Lachesis, Silica, Kali carbonicum, Tuberculinum, Arsenicum,
Carbo animalis, Nitric acid, Kali bichromicum etc.
The most interesting possibilities for her are Psorinum and then Silica
and then I would say Lachesis. There is a possibility for Lachesis but as a second prescription perhaps.
When the body is more warm. There are any flashes of heat?
-Sometimes yes.
-You were never jealous?
-I can be but I don't consider myself a jealous person in general but I can be of course.
-Yes of course, sure.
-Is there severe anemia her whole life?
-Can you give us some more information from what you have underlined?
-Not severe so much anymore.
-Since 17 years old she had anemia.
-You often wake up with cramps in your abdomen?
-In the mornings, almost every morning.
-Waking up with cramps every morning, can you give me cramps in abdomen?
Just show me that symptom. Cramps in the abdomen on waking in the morning,
morning in bed on waking.
Agaricus, Cobaltum, Colchicum, Lycopodium, Manganum, Menyanthes, Nat. muriaticum,
Rheum and Xanthoxylum.
-Lots of back pain.
-With the bowel problems comes the back ache.
-Higher in the back or low back?
-Low. When my bowels are acting, cramping and bloating and all that, then I get back ache with it.
-Her memory is very bad.
-The short term.
-You remember past things?
-Yes.
-What you will forget? You want to get something from the other room and you will forget?
-Yes sometimes.
-Or you want to say something and you forget or you forget the name of your friends?
-Yes.
-All that?
-Yes. It's up and down.
-Her muscles can burn with fatigue when she climbs upstairs, her muscles are burning
and she can't sustain regular exercise. She feels better if she eats every few hours.
-Better eating?
-Better eating every few hours but not too much.
-But you may feel bad in general and then you eat and you feel better or especially the
stomach feels better after eating?
-After I eat I feel better, if I haven't eaten too much but sometimes I feel nauseous after I eat.
-Again we have a symptom of Sepia here. This is a strong symptom for Sepia.
-She is describing herself as having an open nature and sympathetic.
-I feel that I'm shy but I'm bold also. It depends. I can be very shy and I can be very bold.
-Are you sympathetic?
-Yes definitely.
-What example would you give for sympathetic?
-I feel open and warm towards people and I feel sympathetic to people.
-But do you feel it to a pathological degree?
-No.
-She likes salt and sweets. One after the other, she said.
-But would you take and put extra salt in your food before tasting it?
-Sometimes, I try not to.
-Do you have to have sweets every day?
-Almost. If I don't,
it's a conscious decision not to.
-Thirsty all the time for warm and cold drinks. She is quite thirsty.
-How much you drink in total?
-A day?
-Yes.
-Eight glasses the day or more.
-A little by little or you drink half a glass?
-A little by little, usually it's slowly but sometimes I drink the whole glass in one shot.
-What else do you have underlined?
-Fear of closed in spaces.
-Like the elevator?
-No.
-Can you give us an example?
-A really long narrow room, if I have to stay in a long, narrow room.
-Not that you go to the cinema for instance and you feel claustrophobic?
-Not anymore. I used to have panic attacks for one year.
-Which year?
-At 20 to 21.
-She had a fear of death at that time.
-Yes very strong fear of death.
-Not now?
-No.
-It's gone totally?
-Would you say it's better if I die? No.
Do you say to yourself what a life and I'm struggling and it's better if I die?
-Sometimes but not most of the time.
-Neither you contemplate ever suicide?
-Maybe for a fleeting moment I have the thought but there is always enough hope in me to continue.
-Fear of spiders.
-Not so strong.
-Stomach bloating of Ovarian cysts on the right side.
-Show me the right side. How did they find?
-Ultra sound.
-Because you had pains or accidentally?
-Accidentally, just a routine examination but now sometimes it bothers me.
-How big is that cyst, did they tell you?
-It's in my file but I don't know.
-Cysts on right side. Apis, Floric acid, Iodine.
What is the capital? Lycopodium. Palladium, Podophyllum, Rhododendron.
-There was one here that we wrote down before, that when I'm really tired, when I'm
reading something the words just fly off. They fly off my page and I lose my balance for a second.
-Anything else?
Words jump when reading, give me that. Only Senega?
Words jump when reading, Senega, Belladonna and Lyssinum.
-I feel guilty about being sick.
-Why do you think you feel guilty? You feel you have done something that you are
responsible for what you have done? Because you took antibiotics or it just comes out?
-Sometimes.
-She wants to give up sometimes.
-But when we talked about fear of going crazy, the fear that all finally will break down.
-You are free now to torment her by your questions?
-OK I grind my teeth.
-When? During sleep?
-Yes.
-Give me that symptom so they can see in the Repertory, grinding teeth during sleep.
Arsenicum, Tuberculinum of course. Enter it to the repertorization twice.
-I think it was December '90, I was told that I had herpes but I've never had problems since then with it.
So I don't know if I actually have problems or not.
-Tell me something, your foot nails, your big toe they are in growing? You have a problem like that?
-A little bit. Not serious problem.
-First of all can you tell us a bit more about your headache? When you get a headache
what it is like? You have any symptoms that come with headaches?
-If I don't take Tylenol for the headache, it just gets progressively worse, so that eventually
I get very nauseous with the headache.
-Where does it hurt? Usually it's the one part of your head?
-On top. I have a headache now, it's very slight and it's on top.
-It's that where usually is?
-Yes on top and sometimes in the back of my neck.
-How about your cramping with fruits and sugary things, does this disturb your abdomen and give you gas?
-It tends to be heavy things like a bagel. I can eat one bagel, they are very dense,
I can eat meat a couple of times the week. I make sure that every day I eat fruits and vegetables,
like with the more concentrated foods I make sure that it's balanced.
-How do you do with onions? Do you like onions?
-Yes I love onions.
-One last question. When you have problems with cramping do you ever get a sensation
as if there is a heavy pressure on your abdomen?
-Yes if I press my stomach, it feels very hard and it feels as if my intestines are like filled
and it's very compact and hard to touch.
-Do you ever get the feeling as if the uterus is pushed down through the vagina,
that kind of sensation?
-Not really.
-I want to ask you something. I was wondering during this whole interview you had your legs crossed.
If you uncross them what kind of sensation do you experience?
I don't mean now, generally? The whole interview you haven't move your legs,
what will happen, why you always have them crossed?
-Nothing will happen except from nervous.
-So there is no sensation or anything else?
-It was time to uncross them.
-Do you have any white spots on your finger nails?
-Yes I do.
-Let me see.
-Not right now.
-How are you with shots? Getting injections?
-If they take a lot of blood sometimes I feel not too great after, I lie down for 10 minutes.
-Any history of recreational drugs?
-Not really.
-Tobacco.
-How about foot sweats? Does your feet sweat?
-Yes.
-Smelly?
-Only if I wear nylons.
-How about sharp objects?
-What about them?
-He mentioned injections, how do you feel about pointed, sharp objects?
-I use them every day.
-Can you tell us about your menstruation please?
-They are terrible. I suffer a lot.
-Could you tell us what is most important for you? Personal relationships, job, ambition,
what is that you really want in life?
-Work is very important. I think it's number one. What I do with my life, my path.
-What do you do?
-I make jewelry and I paint.
I feel very tired to the three days before my cycle starts.
-And you have pains?
-Yes, the first day I wish I didn't have to work, I wish I could just stay home.
-Is it since the beginning of your menstruation,
since the very first time that you're having this?
-Yes, it's always being like that.
-How do you express affection for your loved ones?
-Doing things for them, baking something that they like, running if they need to do
something and they don't have time, telling them
-What about hugs?
-Sure, hugs and kisses.
-You said you like sunny weather. Can you afford to take sun baths?
-I love sun and I feel better in the sun.
-It means you may stay one hour, taking a sunbath and feeling well?
-Yes.
-Now about your menstruation are they in time, very regular or late?
-They are a little bit off but they are very short.
-Off you mean sometimes late?
-My cycle is18 to 24-25 days.
-Thank you.