The next case is a case of myalgic encephalomyelitis.
We have here the analysis of the first follow up, in which case I will mention what took place.
-You didn't have any reactions from these remedies?
-I think I had reactions from Lycopodium. When I went to my first homeopath,
after three remedies she did not know what to give me and I read a book
and I saw my life there, in Lycopodium, so I passed it to her and she gave me Lycopodium.
I think I had many reactions from Lycopodium and I still think I'm in Lycopodium
from the beginning in 84.
-He gave you the clue.
So you got reaction from Lycopodium. All the other remedies?
-All the other remedies, I don't think I had any reaction.
Maybe a little bit from first remedy.
-Staphysagria?
-Not Staphysagria, Phosphoric acid.
Then after a few days I felt so bad I took some Valium and then it stopped.
-What is the main complain?
-The main complain is that the brain does not work anymore.
Over the years the brain has skipped all the problems and became at very little things.
At my first homeopath I went there because I had psoriasis and nothing else
and then after a few months I took various colds in head in 84 and also in 82
and then the brain... I began to see my nose.
I could see the nose all day and all things would do automatically like opening the door,
putting a key. I was always using the wrong key and then the memory began to weaken,
I began to forget names, things I was to do.
-In the meantime the psoriasis was improving?
-When I took first Lycopodium it got worse for three weeks, it was very much white
and very thick and it began to break and then after three weeks, the psoriasis went away.
I began to feel full of energy and to feel strong.
I've been school teacher until 78 and after that I couldn't do my job anymore, so I stopped.
I felt I was beginning a new life.
Then I began to study Homeopathy and studying Spanish.
But after a few months the brain didn't want to work.
The information wouldn't get in, it wouldn't get out anymore but I know
that everything I ever read is there in the brain but it doesn't want to come out.
It was in July this year that I first thought that it was a problem of weakness
because then I had days and weeks that the brain felt exhausted.
It was so tired, just opening my eyes I was so tired, so exhausted feeling my head.
From that moment on also the muscular power began to weaken, the strength in my body.
I think that it began last year in September when it was always a slippy feeling here
in my arms and my head and my calves and my feet.
I needed to get a little obstruction to get that sleepy feeling
and at last it was not obstruction at all, my feet begin to prickle
and it was a crawling feeling in the calves and later on it was a nod in the muscle.
But I think it wasn't a nod because it always changed place
and the calves began to feel very flabby and I couldn't get to the stairs anymore.
I had pain in legs from tiredness, not from stiffness but from tiredness.
I had to sit down and wait.
-Before all this started did you have any virus infection?
-It was in 82 that I had a terrible cold in the head.
I was skiing in Austria and I was sweating and sweating, it was very hot there
and then we did snowboard on the North side of the hill, it was very cold
and I was waiting for the others and I felt the sweat in my body.
The wind was blowing through my clothes.
Then it was like needles straight right through the head and it hurt
and through the eye it was like needle and I don't remember if I took... I had very much coryza...
but after two months I was still hawking up and I went to the doctor and she gave me penicillin
but I took only 15 out of 20 tablets.
I thought I go to Greece, well everything will stop there.
-Before you go to Greece?
-In 82 I came to Greece for holidays and I thought the weather is beautiful to Greece,
it will go away and then it was terrible, I could blow five handkerchiefs a day,
both ears were full with mucus.
-What did you do here?
-I was sailing in Corfu.
-Did you take anything?
-I took penicillin again from a Greek doctor.
-For how long?
-All the 20 days and then the coryza went away and the heavy feeling went away.
Then I went to a make a massage by the end of the year because I had a problem with a leg.
I couldn't walk for 200 mt and I still can't and it worked so perfectly that in 83 I felt wonderful.
I felt stronger, I felt better than I had felt since I had left my school.
In 84 again in February I took a new cold in the head and the same happened in 85 and in 86.
Every time in February...
-When the weakness started?
-I think the sleepy feeling started in September 85.
I was skating at the end of 85 and I could let my body do any kind of sport I like
because I'm technically very good and I technically skate very good
but I couldn't get with the others and then I wondered if I was getting weak.
But I first knew it in June or July this year when I felt so exhausted from the legs,
just by riding on a bike.
I could go to a certain speed and just a little bit of that speed, two steps
and then exhausted in the legs.
-Do you feel your muscles are becoming wasting?
-They are very soft as if there were no muscles there anymore in the calves
but it improved last month again.
I just wanted to ask a question.
Let us say you are in a regular School for Homeopathy and you are given a case like that.
How much time you will require to have to study the case?
If you are left yourself to study this case and tell me the remedies you have come,
can anybody tell me how much time you will need?
This is a difficult case, it is not a usual remedy, as you understand.
How much time it will be sufficient for you to study.
-Initially it will take two hours and sometimes you may need more time.
-Between 2-3 hours including the case
-No after.
-After the case to come to a conclusion.
I should have let you to work more.
-How long after the psoriasis went away this muscular illness began?
-The muscular illness started after a cold and then it was relieved and by the second cold,
a strong cold then he remained in that state. His organism seemed to react in the first cold
and come up and then in the second cold he stayed in that state.
Now during that time while he was having this condition, he took Lycopodium.
-And the psoriasis went away?
-The psoriasis went away and he felt very good, that was 2-3 months and then he relapsed.
And after that did you hear the remedies so far he had taken?
-No.
-He has taken quite a lot of remedies.
-Do you understand the suppression of the eruption has anything to do with this illness
at this point? Are you thinking that?
-No, I'm thinking that the immune system is dropped considerably.
This for me is what we call a myalgic benign encephalomyelitis.
It is this new kind of disease which circulates the last 10-15 years.
Its' a syndrome which imitates a lot of different diseases, it comes usually
after a viral infection and it is very stubborn disease that you must not be impatient with.
Don't be impatient with that disease.
Also these people are very sensitive because their immune system is very weak.
What he describes it's very interesting as a description of the remedy
because we don't have it in our Materia Medica.
Nothing will come into the brain, nothing will go out of the brain.
This is a subjective feeling but it's very clear. It is as if there is a blockage,
as if the brain does not perceive and does not send out signals.
Is this for instance a case of Helleborus?
-No.
-I never say the remedy from the beginning.
Sometimes I will do it and you will have a surprise.
Yet you cannot have a clue about the remedy, that's why I let the case develop
because it is not possible you can have a clue of the remedy so far.
What is it? It is new, the Materia Medica does not describe it anywhere.
It is a new situation, we do not know it.
-There is something I didn't understand. What did he say about the nose?
-He could see his nose. Usually we don't see our nose, especially if one has a small nose
but even if you have a big one, you don't see it.
Now he does not have a big one and still he sees his nose.
-But it improved last month again, I took Baryta carbonica and then the sleepy feeling went away,
the crawling is still there but then they are a bit stronger after Baryta carbo.
You see when the remedy is close, it's going to act, its' going to produce something
but still leaves the patient sick, it does not bring about a cure.
It's a Baryta carbonica yes. It's one of the possibilities.
-Can you walk upstairs now?
-Yes I can walk upstairs now.
-You can run?
-I didn't do very much running or many physical things lately.
-Did you take Gelsemium?
-No, never.
Gelsemium is also another possibility that one may think in this case
because you have the heaviness, the exhaustion, the legs are very weak, he can't climb upstairs,
he can not run.
It's a remedy that must be indicated very much, in the books they say after flu symptoms.
Most probably they have seen the syndrome before and Gelsemium
was one of the remedies that has counteracted this syndrome.
-I'm a little bit thinking of Lycopodium because when I first went to homeopath,
I just had a little bit of psoriasis and the thing that I liked or didn't like with Lycopodium
but I recognized in Lycopodium is how you feel about women.
You see women how to go to bed with and I think there is one fear in me
that you described there because I never went to bed with any woman.
-Never?
-No, never.
-You didn't have sex intercourse?
-Just a few times when I was 20-24, one time when I was 27
and then for 10 years no intercourse at all.
I was just afraid that a woman might I like you, let's go to bed.
I was afraid that it wouldn't be any erection, I would fail in that.
That's what I recognized in Lycopodium, wanting but erection failing.
It is now for a few months that I go steady with a girl and I can sleep with her
and sometimes I have an erection and sometimes I haven't but I always have the feeling that
there isn't enough erection power there and also what you described the wanting for company
and not wanting company and company in the other room.
I stayed with my parents till I was 38 years old, I lived with my own parents;
I didn't dare to live on my own.
-Which symptom you consider to be the most serious?
-I'm thinking that my brain will let me down and I won't have any brain power left.
-Can you describe how you feel exactly?
Did you hear that?
-No.
-It says on the notes, when I get overheated my forehead goes cold.
And he says I'm afraid that I will be left without brain, not physical that it will evaporate
but that he will become senile.
-Conium has suppressed sexual feelings.
-No to my understanding, it cannot be.
What he explains about Lycopodium, he explains it the wrong way.
What I have said about Lycopodium is that he has a lot of different women,
he gets the excitement of one night stand with a woman and then when he is married
to have a steady relationship, he cannot have a normal erection and desire.
He loses the desire and the erection and then he has to go for excitement
and then he tries to find excitement out of his marriage. It is not his case.
He has interpreted what I said.
The world becomes strange because the brain is not able to receive the information,
when this coldness comes.
I understand this is a constant state which is aggravated when he is getting heated.
-This feeling is also present when there is much wind or when it's very calm.
It's worse outside and when I get in the car to go home, it's better.
Sometimes the world gets strange.
-I think since I wrote that, maybe in June, first it was the brain knowing
that it couldn't take all this information, it shut me from the information off
so that I didn't recognize the world.
I lost my way in the car when I wanted to go home and I couldn't find my home
and now that hindering has gone all the information is coming in
and the brain is getting exhausted.
Now the world does not look strange anymore...
-The last remedy has improved?
-I took Baryta carbonica after the exhausted feeling, about one month ago.
-And you feel better after that?
-The muscular power a little bit is coming back but the brain is no good.
Three days ago there was no contact with the world, I was just living inside my brain.
Going over and over the problems that are in my brain, the fear, the worried...
-What other things you feel or this is all? You have said everything?
-No I don't think I have said everything.
I think for all my life there has been a lack of feeling, I never fall in love,
I don't feel friendship but that is one of the things I felt when I took Lycopodium
for the second time.
One night I was caressing my cat and I suddenly realized that I didn't want to lose again.
It only remained there for half an hour and when I saw a girlfriend I felt the warmth,
I was happy to see her and normally those things don't mean anything to me.
-You don't...
-It is as if I don't love very much and I don't hate very much.
I like a little and I dislike a little but there is never any strong feeling in me.
-Maybe it's good to tell about the girl.
-I was in love I was 16 years old and I think it's the only time
I fell very much in love with a girl.
She liked me especially in the beginning but we didn't have any intercourse.
We were very young, I didn't want it then.
She was going to bed with elderly men.
-She was going to bed with elderly men and you knew that?
-I knew that but I didn't want to lose her but after three years when I was 18,
she went to bed with my uncle and then I said this can't go on anymore
and it took me another 3 years to fell out of love.
And I always thought that, that might have killed all other feelings.
Before that time I don't remember very strong feelings.
You see how the case is prepared for what is coming eventually.
Can you imagine his psychology? He is too idealistic, too romantic, too pure
and he finds out eventually that the girl he is in love with, she goes with elder men
and he has the shock of seeing her in bed with his uncle.
That prepares the ground for what is coming and when he gets the flu,
the organism is already depressed and he goes into that permanent state now.
Already his feelings are reduced.
His feelings were I believe 10% of the original feelings that he had after this affair.
-I had very strong feelings for my father or for my mother or brother, sister or relatives.
-Did you take Staphysagria, Nux moschata, Platina, Pulsatilla, Lycopodium, Nux vomica,
Sulphur and Baryta carbonica?
-Yes.
-Phosphoric acid?
-The first was Phosphoric acid and Rhus tox.
-Phosphoric acid did not act?
-It was too short after leaving school, so I had periods when I felt bad and I had to take Valium.
-When you say leave school?
-I was school teacher and after 15 years I felt so tired, I couldn't go to my job again.
-He doesn't have to work anymore.
-I can't work anymore, I'm paid by the government.
Not now but when I took Lycopodium I thought I could start a new life and fight again.
-Lycopodium was not repeated?
-Phosphoric acid was once repeated on my request after Pulsatilla.
She gave me Pulsatilla and after that I asked her to try Lycopodium again and it didn't work.
It went badly.
I took Lycopodium 1.000, I had to shake it 40 times, then I had mint and I was afraid
that the mint might have broken the action, so I shook it another 40 times and I took it again.
-So you had a big reaction?
-No, I just felt very bad.
I was riding on a bike and the whole world was strange.
I knew where I was but it was strange. Like you build your own house from paper.
-You thought the world was made out of paper?
-It just wasn't real. I saw it but it wasn't real.
-Do you have any constipation?
-No, more diarrhea.
I'm thinking of what remedy now?
-Alumina.
-I'm thinking of Alumina and that's why I said do you have any constipation.
Because that state you can see in Alumina, it is an extreme state that you see in Alumina.
Perhaps not so strong as he describes but very close.
-More diarrhoea. It changes through the last 2-3 years.
At the moment after I'm eating I must go to the toilet and in the morning it's normal
but in the evening often it's diarrhoea.
-Are you afraid of snakes?
-No, I'm not afraid of snakes.
-Do you feel that you don't have any contact with a woman because you feel intimidated by that
or you feel cowardice?
-I think that all my life people liked me very much, I'm gentle and I'm afraid that
when I talk to a woman she would say, let's go to a cinema and it will develop to go to bed
with each other and I'm afraid to go to bed.
-In case you fail?
-In case I fail.
-Not because you don't like her?
-Not because I don't like her. I'm always very fond to look at girls.
-What are you doing to let this desire out?
-I've masturbated from the age of 10-11 until now twice, three times a night.
The last 2-3 months my homeopath said try to let that off and it is very much less than before.
-In your imagination when you masturbate, do you imagine an intercourse with a woman?
-With a woman, mostly young women that don't have any experience, I feel more comfortable.
It's only with women.
-You are brought up in a family of how many children?
-Three children.
-Did you have a good life in your family?
-I think I had a good life. My father left us very much but he was very dominating,
not that he hit us. I was only hit once in my whole life but he saw the world...
He thought that life must be led and he made us live like that.
Like eating at six o'clock is good, so we always ate at six o'clock, never one minute later.
Going to bed early is very good, so at ten o'clock going to bed, maybe birthday,
maybe New Year's Eve but always discipline at ten o'clock.
I had friends, we stayed at the sea side and we were 16,17,18 years old
and we were lying and talking to each other, I was always the first, holidays or no holidays,
half past nine, I had to go to bed.
I think that was his insecurity that made him live like this.
-And all the other brothers and sisters did the same?
-I was the oldest. My brother was three and half years younger and he could go to bed
at ten o'clock.
I had to go to bed at ten o'clock when I was 17, he had to go when he was 14, 15 years old.
And he is very different character from me, he didn't mind very much.
He was big and strong and he didn't do what he didn't do.
-When you masturbate do you have proper erection?
-Yes but not always. There are months that I don't have proper erection
and then for a few months suddenly the erection comes back,
so I can masturbate two times per night.
-Do you have orgasm?
-Yes.
-Which comes every time?
-Every time I have orgasm, that's orgasm I didn't go to bed with a girl.
I'm staying with this girl now and I go to bed with her, there is orgasm.
There is orgasm but it's much less than when I masturbate.
When I masturbate it is very much better.
-You have a sexual intercourse?
-Yes.
-And you have an erection?
-How often?
-Once every two days I think.
-But you still need to masturbate in between?
-I have masturbated in between, yes.
-And the erection is better when you masturbate?
-Yes.
I have always to be aroused by her, it's never coming from myself to make love to her.
When we have our clothes on and we are kissing, there is no erection.
Only when we are lying in bed and she is naked...
We have some information now. What remedies are we thinking?
-Picric acid.
-Staphysagria.
-Agnus castus, China, Lilium tigrinum, Phosphoric acid, Gelsemium.
All these remedies can be the remedy.
I will read a remedy.
-Cocculus.
-I will read the remedy and you will find the remedy.
Great exhaustion and drowsiness,
affection of the muscular fibres of stomach, very sensitive,
head confused, pain in the head as from a band tightly crossed forehead,
conscious of nose, feels as if he has two noses.
I played a trick because I read on a piece of paper...
I always play tricks because you have to work hard.
Is this the remedy?
Let me read you from another remedy.
There are remedies we can be thinking about.
Want of power of concentration and coordination,
numbness in the head and muscular prostration,
association of head and eye symptoms with muscular tiredness and worriness.
It produces diminution of sexual desire in both sexes,
sexual neurasthenia, depressed or lost sexual life, loss of memory,
nose feels dry...
confused, dull, heavy, dizzy, pressing upwards in occiput,
tired and numbed feeling in legs, staggering, worse from motion, tight clothing,
better when lying down on back, from cold drinks and eating.
That is another remedy.
They are not usual remedies what I read you. They are unusual remedies.
Let me read another remedy.
What was this remedy I just read? It was Onosmodium.
The previous remedy I was reading, who found it? Nobody?
Mercurialis Perennis, the first remedy.
I read another remedy.
Marked effects on the genito-urinary organs and especially indicated for sexual atony.
Great debility, worse with heat,
easy exhaustion mental and physical, especially in old age,
debility after exhausting disease.
You are going to have a problem in differential diagnosis.
Mind, lascivious thoughts with impotency.
He has the desire, he sees the girl, he says it's nice... with impotency.
You are going to have a problem.
Mental labor fatigues, extreme sadness, despair, uncompromised melancholy,
this is Selenium, hair falls out. You see his hair is out already.
Male, dribbling of semen during sleep, loss of sexual power with lascivious thoughts,
increases desire and decreases ability for sex,
sexual neurasthenia, on attempting coition penis relaxes, Selenium.
You will have a problem, I told you.
All these remedies are unusual remedies but in its own way each one describes
some of his state.
Which is the remedy?
-Lycopodium?
-Lycopodium was tried again with no effect. No point in trying it again.
It gave a bad aggravation, he lost the contact with the world, he became unreal etc.
-Can we find it through the Repertory?
-Yes you can try. There are some people who have seen the case and I believe
they remember the remedy.
Who has seen the case? Do you all remember the remedy?
Who does not remember the remedy?
All the others remember the remedy? You understand the tricks...
But what I read you was close enough? Very close.
-You said once that after Baryta carbonica... the extremities was strong, then we look at...
the mental level is better and the physical level is aggravated.
So you don't have to consider to wait if Baryta carbo is the right remedy?
-I think there is enough time between Baryta carbo and the time I've seen him.
What actually happened when I prescribed the remedy, his practitioner played him a trick.
He gave him another remedy and he said this is the remedy that George prescribed.
-Why?
-I don't know why. You don't understand why?
So he did not take the remedy I prescribed until how many months later he took it?
-Between 4-6 months.
-4-6 months after this consultation, he took the remedy I prescribed.
-Did you advice then?
-No, I did not advice then. I advised to take the remedy, I'll tell you which remedy.
But I did not give him the remedy, so he went back to his country and the practitioner gave him
another remedy and told him this is the remedy that George has prescribed.
-Why?
-You don't understand why. I don't understand either.
I have some suspicions but it's better not to voice them.
On the second interview the situation...
Which remedy you prefer out of the 3-4 remedies I read you?
-Mercurialis.
-Let's see a bit more.
-When we have our clothes on and we are kissing then there is no erection,
just only when we are lying in bed and she is naked there is erection
and she has always to caress me or do something.
When I had Lycopodium, when I had the second time Lycopodium, I was walking in the streets,
it wasn't even spring and I had erections all the time. I had to put my mind to things.
I was always walking in the street with an erection all day.
That was so strange with Lycopodium.
-Do you usually have any reaction from the weather?
-When it's too warm is worse, when it's windy it's worse,
when it's very crowded and warm it's worse.
That's why I was afraid to come to Greece because it's always warm here
but too much dry when I was in Athens. Everything was good in my head, no problem.
-Actually you are afraid of the heat but now you found out that you can tolerate it?
-I can tolerate it now but 2-3 months ago I couldn't.
I was going to the beach in Holland where it's not warm like in Greece
and they were very many people there and everything went strange.
-Because of the heat?
-Because of the heat and the many people and the colors and the wind.
If I would write it down now it would be another story. Every time I go to the homeopath
the symptoms have changed a little and I would tell another story.
-Do you cry easily?
-No I don't think so. Do I cry easily?
-Just a bit of tears.
-It's like in a situation I cry and when that situation occurs again I don't cry anymore.
I've cried the last few weeks when I'm with this girl which is quite a new situation for me.
Three days ago she told me she loves me and she wants to live together
and have children maybe but I don't' love her. I like her, she is good for me I think.
-But you don't have the feelings?
-I don't have the feelings of love, so I'm not going to live with her or anything
and I was so afraid that she would leave me when I told her, that I had to cry.
I cried because I was so afraid she would go away and that is very strange
because I  think maybe I will leave her.
Because it is lasting too long.
-How long is lasting?
-20 years is very long, we may be together 20 years with this girl.
-Wait a minute, 20 years with this girl?
-No, I'm just a few months with this girl. I know her for about 3 years
but if I don't put an end to it now or in a few months, I may stay 20 years
and I can't see a period of time to stay with one person.
-Why? If you like her?
-If I look at another girl, I think what a beautiful girl that one is...
When I see this girl, I can't go to bed with the other.
-But you can't go to bed anyhow. You had difficulty for so many years.
Why don't you stick with her? Why don't you stay with her?
Because you had so many problems?
-But I don't love her. You need to feel a little bit of love. You have to feel warm feeling,
when you see her, you have to be glad that she is there and I really don't care if she is there.
She might have been some other girl.
-I see.
This numbness that you have in the legs it's only in the legs or also in hands?
-It's in the arm and the hands and not to legs, just the calves and the feet
and especially the soles of the feet.
The legs and calves are always prickling and in the arms is just a part of it.
Sometimes these two fingers, sometimes just a little piece of the finger,
it's not the whole arm that feels... Just a little part of it.
In the arms I never have the contractions. The contractions are only in the calves.
Sometimes it feels like a little burning is here and when I look at the calf
I see very little contraction and sometimes it's inside the calf, I think.
When I came to Athens there was still the tendon that fits the calf to the knee
was very painful but now it's gone.
It was very painful when I came to Athens but it lasted only two days, now it's gone.
-How do you feel psychologically? You feel optimistic or pessimistic?
-I feel pessimistic when things are going bad.
I was even afraid that by the time I got here, I couldn't talk to you anymore
because the brain would let me down. I'm afraid that I lose contact with the world.
I don't recognize the world, I don't recognize people, the brain gets so tired
that it does not want to have anything to do with the rest of the world.
Then all of the sudden the brain clears a little bit and I feel a little bit more optimistic.
They will find for me something in time and when it's bad I'm afraid
nothing will be found in correct time.
If somebody would find a good remedy, I would be restoring less half a year.
There is a feeling that something is just around the corner, that just the remedy is there.
I think that is optimistic.
But I haven't felt much joy in my life.
Going abroad to Greece or Spain or skiing in Austria it doesn't mean much to me.
It's something that people do. It's the same with love.
There is no joy in it now.
You have to ask me are you coming to ski with us, I say that's OK but just the eagerness
to go is not coming out of myself.
I just told you one time with Lycopodium that I'm feeling so stupid...
I'm coloring the story so much.
-How is the stool? Anything peculiar in the stool?
-The stool is light color brown.
The urine was always with much foam, white foam.
At first I thought it was my toilet because I used a kind of soap to my toilet.
So I told no one in the beginning.
But no special color or special odor.
-How is your sleep?
-That changes too. I had periods when I couldn't fall asleep
but then now I fall asleep rather easily and then I wake up sometimes after three hours already
and sometimes at 5 o'clock.
The last few months I fall asleep very easily and then I wake up at 5 o'clock.
I want to sleep because there is so much trouble in my head.
-Do you fall asleep again?
-I fall asleep again.
-Do you have any trembling?
-No.
-Do you eat sweets a lot?
-I like sweets a lot.
It's the only thing I can say for liking or disliking things, it's that I like sweets things a lot.
I had distention, that was in March 85, not at the moment.
I had very much flatulence, very much wind.
-Any time?
-All the time from March 85 until now there is very much wind in me.
In March when it started I had distended stomach from eating just one sandwich
or half a sandwich and I couldn't eat until 5 o'clock in the afternoon because I was...
-Not now?
-Not now.
-Do you have a time period when you sleep very little?
-I sleep very lightly. I'm not sure.
I think just in the middle of the night I sleep very good because people are waking by bad weather
or thunderstorms and I don't wake up.
I sleep very lightly till 8 o'clock and then I can sleep for a couple of hours deeply.
-During sleep there is salivation?
-No.
-Can you have pressure in your body?
-I don't know. I have the neck open. Sometimes when I go to a concert I leave it loose.
Better when I had the distention I couldn't feel balance, I can tolerate it now
but then I couldn't.
-Do you sleep on one position?
-I sleep mostly on my right side.
-Do you feel jealousy?
-Not anymore. I did.
-Do you feel great jealousy by the time you had this love affair?
-I think yes. I had that nobody else could take her if I couldn't. I was very jealous then.
-Would you imagine her going out with men?
-I was not imagine her, she told me.
She had to go to bed with him because...
-Because he would beat her?
-Not beat her.
Let's say she would take a lift from Amsterdam to the sea side and then he said
I want to go to bed with you, otherwise I put you out of the car. So then she did.
That is the story she told me, I don't know if they are correct.
But of course she went to bed with boys about my age and maybe 2-3 older than me
and they will be boasting about it.
I think I'm easily jealous.
Now when she tells about her other boyfriends especially when she was on holidays
with a married man who had two children, I don't feel well about it.
In my head I know I shouldn't, past is past but I don't feel happy with it.
-When you sleep do you ever have choking during sleep?
-No never.
-Your feet are warm in bed? You have to stick them out?
-Yes I have to stick them out.
-Do you need a fan on top of you?
-No I don't need a fan.
I feel better when the head is cool but I don't need a fan.
As soon as the feet sweat and when the sweat is drying, my feet get cold
and it comes pain in the joints, then I put new socks on and then I go walking
and then the pain disappears.
After I had that coryza in 84, I had also trouble with the joints, pain in the knees,
neuralgic, always painful and it was dislocated my right shoulder when I was in a kayak.
The right shoulder it was rambling, not only cracking.
-How is your thirst?
-I don't have very much thirst. I'm not easily thirsty.
-Do you eat oysters?
-No I never eat oysters.
-Why?
-I think I don't like them. I like fish but oysters I don't like.
-Do you like salty things?
-No I don't think so.
-Salty in general?
-I don't take very much salt.
-Do you feel aversion to salt?
-No, just normal.