-Could you give me a report of what happened after the medicine?
-I was aware that if it was working, as it should, I would have some symptoms,
I was looking for them.
After I took the medicine I went up north in Norway in different situation,
different place working too much, working hard, so the situation was tense.
In this period, the first days of June I had this neck pain.
-Stiffness?
-Stiffness and pain. This is the only physical change I could register.
-How long it lasted?
-Three days.
-And you took no medicine?
-No.
-You let it go.
-I was a bit unsure whether I should register this as a symptom
because this appeared also during the trip from Oslo up north in the car,
so it could have been from the car.
-Yes sure. You just report everything and then we will assess.
Just give all the information. What other things you have noticed?
-Physically nothing.
-You went to work up north and you worked hard in what situation?
-In a restaurant.
-Did you have the physical strength to work?
-Oh yes, a lot.
-This was normal for you or you felt that you had more energy than usual?
-I'm not sure. I was very active but it was a situation where there was nothing else
to do than work, I was working all the time, I had to.
I had a lot of energy and I didn't have time to sit apathetically, I didn't have time for that.
It didn't bother me.
-Where do you attribute this energy? To the situation?
-Maybe.
-You didn't feel that the medicine made you feel better in general so it gave you energy?
-It's hard to tell.
-What changes you were expecting from the medicine?
-I was expecting some of my previous infections would come out again like pain in head
or the gonorrhea, the venereal diseases.
-Do you want to take out your jacket because I'm afraid it's too hot here.
-Yes. It's not as hot as it looked.
What do we expect to hear in this case to assess that the remedy is working?
What has to change?
-The anxiety and fear.
-The anxiety and fear of the disease in general.
The fear of the disease that we consider it maybe normal, it is not normal.
It is too much and therefore if the remedy is acting, this fear of the disease
will be taken away to a great extend.
Apart from the fact that the energy level has to climb and apart from the fact
that the sub-maxillary glands, which are swollen, have to go away.
And also if this person with the syndrome of loneliness forgets about this,
there is no mentioning it anymore of the loneliness.
He will see the world with other eyes, with different eyes.
This is in October 87.
-Did you have any sexual contact during that time?
-No.
With nobody. How were your glands in general? Are they swelling?
-This, no symptom. All the things, they disappeared.
-Can you tell me if there is any change in your character, your personality,
your way of dealing with the situation?
-I feel very full of many things, positive and negative and maybe the negative
is taking more and more over. I'm getting full of fear.
-Fear of?
-Fear of doing things.
-Sexual things?
-That too of course but I don't take challenges at work, the day challenges,
which is easy and I think more cowardly.
I feel more and more fear, every day fear situations. I don't have the guts.
-You don't have the guts to do what?
He feels he doesn't have the guts. You see how he perceives?
He doesn't have the guts to do, the courage. I'm more cowardly now.
- You don't have the guts to do what? Can you be more precise?
-I wanted to have a career, I wanted to do the best of what my talents are
and when I learned about my infection I thought this was really...
I must hurry because now there is not much time left, that's the time of thought you get.
Now this has changed and I don't want to do things, be more like this.
I don't think I can do, I don't have the self-confidence anymore.
You see he goes through a phase, where before he says I'm going to die,
I have to do things quickly, so I can live the space of time that has left for me.
And then he says now I seem to sit back and I don't take initiative,
I don't want to do anything.
So it's a phase for which he is going through, thinking, changing, why?
What has changed is the metabolism inside, if we put it on a physical level.
-We talked about it last time I was here too, about the fear of being lonely
and this is getting stronger.
-Tell me more about yourself, how you feel now? Just describe.
-Confused, I have to pick thoughts or I should try and go around
or I should try to do my career, even though I don't have the self-confidence,
as a radio reporter.
-The radio reporter that is what you like?
-Yes this is what I'm doing.
-As a journalist.
What element is missing from the previous interview in his character?
-The intensity.
-He is not intense.
-The joking.
-The joking, the performing, he is not performing anymore.
He is more looking upon things, he is serious.
-Smugness.
-What is this? Australian expression?
-Self-satisfying.
-I think he never had the guts but now he realizes it.
-It doesn't matter.
-You don't have the courage to do that?
-No, I don't have the courage to do that and I don't have the initiative to go around.
I do nothing instead.
-Did you stop working on the North?
-I work as little as possible.
-But you said in the beginning that you worked quite a lot.
-That was in the restaurant business this summer. That was for the last two months.
I had no choice.
-But you had all the energy to do it.
-Yes.
-How is your energy now?
-If there was something I had to do, I would do it.
I have a lot of energy inside but I don't feel like I have been able to get it out
because I'm so confused.
-Do you lose any weight?
-On the contrary.
One thing we have to remember once a person is getting better,
it is always that better it is connected with some activity, creativity which is taking place.
You have somebody who has never worked in his life and you give a remedy,
don't expect that the next day he will go and work. He is going to go through different phases,
thinking, stimulating from the environment and then eventually...
If you see a schizophrenic is getting better, the first thing he will get, he will get a job,
when he is really better. He will say now I want to work.
It is a great thing for a schizophrenic to see this happening,
I want to go to work or a mentally deranged person.
Once we see this creativity coming up, then we know the person is really getting better.
And what is better after all? Health. What is health?
It is the measure to which we can be creative. To that measure we are healthy.
If we can be creative all the time, we are absolutely healthy.
When we sit back, I can't think, I can't do anything, to that extend we are diseased.
-Do you lose any weight?
-On the contrary.
-How much weight did you put?
-Maybe 3-4 kilos.
But that is much in my part because I never was so much in my life.
Everybody tells me that I'm going to lose weight.
The normal for AIDS positives is to lose weight, when you are getting sick,
so I don't want to have the symptom of losing weight because then I feel sick.
Maybe that's why I eat.
-Whether you eat or drink it doesn't matter, when the disease is taking over
but most probably the treatment is helping you.
-Maybe.
-You have quite good energy, the glands are not anymore painful
that they used to be and your appetite is good, you are putting on weight
and you have some more moral problems.
You must be having a lot of turmoil inside you concerning the possibility of having
an affair infecting somebody.
These are the problems which are very strong problems for everybody and in spite of this fact
I don't see that you are doing bad at all.
-I must say when I compare myself with others...
Another point which was in favor of Causticum was the fact that he did not go
and have relationships. Do you understand that?
Because he does not want to infect others and he holds back.
Not all AIDS people will do that.
-... and the others have more specific problems like the one is thinking about death all the time,
another one is just very apathetic, not able to go to work or anything.
They have more specific problems, I feel a little more cheered and positive.
-You have a little bit blisters here. When did they come up?
-One week ago.
-Were you specifically stressed that week? Any particular stress?
-I'm particularly stressed always, that's my character but these I believe is normal herpes,
which I first had many years ago when I was in India. It was very big
because of the humidity it was spreading it.
I tend to get this once or twice the year in winter combined with the cold.
But this is very small, it's going away already. Sometimes it gets big.
-I see.
-You remember the last time we spoke about your character?
You described yourself as a moralist and you explained different things that you were feeling,
especially concerning people who are put down.
Whenever you saw injustice, somebody to be put down, you were very exploding and reacting.
How is that aspect of your character after the treatment?
-The same.
-I don't hear your voice saying strongly.
-I must admit that I knew this question would come because I know that it should have changed,
I've been told.
-You have been told that it should have changed? Who told you?
You see how bad it is to tell a person this we expect to change?
Because you do not get a real feedback after that. It's useless.
-So what do you say?
-I can't say I see a change.
-Were you in a situation where you felt that something wrong was done to somebody and
then you reacted or you had no chance to check it actually?
-Yes I had a situation where I reacted just as before.
-Can you tell me what it was?
-One month ago outside a discotheque in Oslo a black guy went by
and the white guy calling him you bastard and I run after the white guy and kicked him.
I wanted to get the hell out of him. That's a normal reaction for me.
I didn't fight with him, I don't like to fight with people but I like to scare them.
He applauds.
Now he is a Causticum.
-Any other reaction?
-In my radio work I'm more an idealist and being a professional carrier for my own set.
I mean I do it because I want to change the world, when I make programs it's
because I think it's worthy to make that program.
Whatever I do, I do it in this aspect of trying to improve, to show...
-Is anything of your character that you didn't' t say last time and you wanted
to complete the picture this time?
Is anything that you felt either you misguided me or you didn't tell me at all
that you wanted to speak now?
-The only thing I've listened to at myself after the meeting and the only thing I felt maybe
it could be misunderstood is when you asked me about the sexual desires.
I interpreted the question as if are you a sexist or are you not?
And I said I'm not a sexist but I'm none either. I have a very active sexual desire life.
It's important part of my life and you were asking about how many partners?
I don't remember the number I said but if it was up to me, I would have a lot more partners.
That is my desire rather than the actual number.
So I wanted to correct that.
-Still I'm not clear, when you say sexist what do you mean?
-To me sexist is a person who is thinking sex all the time.
-And you are not that type?
-No.
-But sometimes you are, you are saying.
Sometimes you are preoccupied with sex a lot and many other times you are not.
Is that what you are stating now?
-Yes.
-If it was up to you, you would have much more partners.
Is that what you said now?
-Yes.
-What I was enquiring is whether you might have had infections because of multiple partners?
Whether you might have had multiple infections because of this situation?
-Then my answer is the same with the last time. The frequency wasn't any higher
than I said, I was not lying.
-Is anything else that you wanted to correct from what you said last time?
-It's a bit hard for me to remember all the talks that we went through, so if you give me some clues,
maybe I could remember.
-You said to the practitioner, you told her that you were not satisfied with the interview
because they were things that you wanted to say, that you did not say.
Do you remember what you wanted to say and you did not have the chance to say,
so you can say it now?
-That is difficult because what I was dissatisfied about was the setting as I found,
very distant and a bit cold, as an object, not a person.
I didn't have the chance to go to the depth of my explanations.
I felt like I was defending myself in that situation.
So I feel that everything we were talking about, I could say more about if I felt more safe.
This is not actual the setting for being open. I think that is a normal reaction.
What he is complaining about is that he did not feel the contact,
that he still had this feeling of alienation, of being alone, of loneliness.
Even if when he talked to me, the feeling remained, didn't go away.
What he felt very strongly is what others say about my interviews
that you can't not tell a lie to George.
Because I don't know, the way I look, I'm not involved, I don't want
to get involved emotionally into a consultation.
I like Anne or Helen and then I get very excited.
You have this fear, tell me about this fear. You suffer, poor you...
In the end I will finish the interview and I will not know head or tails, unless I sit back
and I really objectively evaluate what he said to me. I'm not there to have an exchange,
I'm not a psychotherapist to have an exchange of energies and vibrations and all this... you cure.
You don't cure by that, you cure by sheer logic. I need to see what I have in front of me.
It's not an object, I'm much more concerned that anybody can ever think,
if he remembers me 20 years later, if I'm alive about his case,
I will say yes I gave you Causticum and say all the details.
How is that possible that I did not take into account,
if I remember so many years later after so many cases, unless I was very attentive.
But what he saw he could not bluff me, he could see that there is no way that
he could present himself the way he wanted to present himself to me.
This is what he is saying.
It will be so nice, oh you are such a nice person, save the world,
I also want to save the world.
We are friends and then he goes out and he says this doctor is so good.
He is full of love. Prescription? Forget it.
Confused prescription.
I've told you one of my doctors, a lady doctor, she was sitting there sending me the information.
It's so nice person and where are the symptoms? No symptomatology.
I was supervising in prescribing for the case and I said you didn't write the symptoms,
you got involved with the conversation. Would you please call him back to complete the picture?
She called him back, she said he is a schizophrenic.
When she looked upon the case, she saw that it was a very progressed mental case.
It's a manic depressive case where the mania in the period of mania they are so vivid
and so engaged into discussion and she got involved.
And what she saw it was a nice person, that is what I was reading all the time because
she was influenced by his vitality etc. But she did not see at all objectively the situation.
I got into another consultation room, there was another lady doctor, writing a case of colitis.
I looked at the patient, I read and it's only colitis symptoms.
I looked again the patient, I tried to find any mental symptoms nothing, no mental symptoms.
I said it's impossible, this man is completely crazy and I can't see any mental symptoms,
not reporting anything. What shall I ask?
So I said to him do you take any medicine? He said no. He meant for the colitis.
I said he must be under strong medication and what I see is a picture of a mentally ill person
who takes a lot of drugs. I said are you sure? He said yes.
I said I don't mean medication for the colitis. Do you take medication for something else?
He says yes. What? He pulls out from his pockets a heap of medication.
I said to her what is this? He came to be treated for the colitis and he is crazy.
The colitis was the problem? I said you are not looking objectively.
He said the colitis, I have the pain.
No, sit back, observe, do not get involved, homeopath should not get involved.
He should not have a love affair from the consultation, he can have outside but not inside.
Because if you doubt, forget the patient. I'm saying it very openly, I make you aware.
What I hope to show you in this seminar is how a cure can take place in time.
Unless you perceive this idea, you will never have a cured case.
You will have successes in the beginning and failures in the end always.
Unless you perceive the person is doing well for these and these reasons not with judgment,
I don't want to judge a case and say he is doing well while he is doing worse,
but unless you do that and you perceive he is doing well, leave them alone, when you
see cure. In the end you will have happy people that have no problems.
If you don't perceive that, you will see unhappy people with a lot of problems
and you will be unhappy.
Please understand this point in Homeopathy because it is a point that has never...
according to my understanding when I see how people are prescribing
and I have made the mistakes myself and I'm talking about the mistakes I've made
and I've seen the effects...
Let us see now how this man who got Causticum is feeling one year later.
This interview is one year later.
-He didn't take any more dose?
-No more dose, as far as I remember.
Unless there is a relapse, a real relapse do not repeat the remedy.
Which is the date of this? July '88. It is close to one year. 14 months.
Before you start I wanted to say also a few things.
As we said with the Cicuta child, when he is going to be better?
When he will start having contact, not when the epileptic fits will be bigger or lesser,
the deeper level when he will start being better.
Cicuta, it has given different remedies and the parents are happy,
they see the child is doing better. But what is better?
One time the fits were this way and the other time the fits were another kind of convulsions
or a little bit less convulsions.
After one and a half year of treatment that the child had before,
the result is not only the same, it is worse.
He started with mild convulsions and ended with grand mal
He is a completely autistic child.
The child seemed not to be autistic from the very beginning.
At the age of 6 months he had some rapport.
Then he becomes completely autistic.
You can't say better the convulsions, a little bit better of this and of that,
the coughing is better and then the child is better. That is how we go wrong.
We don't perceive what is deep.
When the Stramonium child came in, we don't perceive that it is much better.
I didn't know what happened afterwards. What I know is that the child is better?
Why? More calm.
I can see it immediately and then some supporting elements are there,
some real hard facts are there.
Then wait.
I believe that the eye of the child it will be almost completely well and I hope
that Matias may have a checkup and you give us a report of the ophthalmologist.
Now this man he went through a phase, what he described.
Let us see what has happened now?
-You saw George in November last year, could you tell me how it is since then?
-He gave me another dose of Causticum, which I was to take...
That was placebo.
-I took it every week on Tuesday, I think it was for 10 weeks.
So I finished that in January. What I remember from this is that every Saturday
after I had taken it on Tuesdays, I had neck pains, each week.
I thought this is nothing, this has got nothing to do with this remedy
but in fact I must admit after I had taken the last pill...
It's very interesting for those who do not know Causticum, the Causticum has a stiffness
on one side of his neck and a pain it may appear on occipital protuberance.
And mostly they have stiffness on the neck. It is very interesting
because he takes placebo but the first observation that he had that is definitely a sign
that the remedy was correct.
Once we have a general amelioration and a keynote of the remedy appearing,
that is a confirmation that we have given the prescribed remedy.
When we have a general aggravation plus new symptoms of the remedy,
we have a proving of the remedy. You understand?
-In January I didn't take any more neck pain.
-You originally got neck pain the first time you took the Causticum?
What was the pain in relation to the glands?
-The back of the neck. I'm not sure whether it was the muscles or the bones
but I think it is the muscles.
-It was an ache or stiffness?
-Ache. The first time I took it it was so bad, it lasted three days, I could hardly move.
Autosuggestion almost. And we see it with sensitive people who have a kind of hysterical
streak that they can reproduce.
You give a remedy and they have a big reaction and then  they do well
and then at a certain moment they go towards a relapse.
You judge it is not a relapse and you give placebo and they bring out a kind of reaction
that they had in the beginning.
They say I had the same reaction as in the beginning. It means it is not a real relapse,
it is just the organism coming down, it is going to come up again.
You don't need to prescribe a remedy.
-It was so bad, it lasted for three days, I could hardly move but this time it was not that bad.
It was the same kind of ache and it lasted only for one day and it was gone again.
Do you see a change in his face? What is the change that you see?
How do you define that change?
-He became more mature.
-Not so frightened.
-It's not that frighten look that he used to have and he is more mature.
You will say is it possible that you give a remedy and the person matures?
It is possible yes, within a year different changes will take place inside
on a healthy organism now and you will see healthy reactions.
Who has seen the Baryta carbonica case in Bern? How many have seen the Bar.carb.?
I just got a report because her doctor is here.
She will give you the report, how well she is doing, going back to college, finishing the college,
lots of changes, real changes in real life, where she was hiding, she could not do anything.
-After that when I finished this cure my homeopath in Oslo,
she tested a remedy with using my hands, it is called organum triplex.
-I know yes. You have it with you because it is a combination of remedies, I think.
-No, I don't have them with me, it was liquid in bottles.
It was just this test and then different remedies in my hand.
-Did you have any symptoms at the time?
-No, she said she wanted to give it to me to give me extra strength after the cure.
It was most probably placebo, I don't believe she gave anything.
-When did you have that?
-I started in the beginning of March and I finished in the end of February.
-For 10 weeks you did that?
-Yes.
-So it was a week you took it or daily?
-Every 3-4 days. So far I haven't taken any more remedies.
-So how have you been this time?
-Very well generally. I've been very active.
-Do you have a work? What are you doing?
-I've taken part in starting the Norwegian HIV positive organization
so I've been using my whole self into work.
-Because last time you had been working very little.
So you feel this is the area you want to be? What else has been happening?
-I have been busy, not like I have been told before, I have been very lazy
and having trouble getting up in the morning. Now I've been really getting up early
and working hard, maybe it's been too much. I haven't have private life,
I have been very much concerned about this. I can not say I've done much rather than working.
-How is the work doing a lot of opposition because of the area of the work that you are doing?
-No, it has been easy. I had reduced the opposition in myself because it needs strength
to create something which is not there because there are always skeptical people around you.
So I had to use a lot of strength.
-Have you had the energy to do it?
-Yes.
-Good. You mentioned last time that you had a fear of loneliness, that was a problem for you.
What is happening there?
He had forgotten it. Did I say that? That is more or less what you expect.
This is what happens with the cases.
After a certain period of time once they get better, they completely forget how they were before.
So when you ask them to compare, they are not in a position to compare really.
What was happening and what they are now it is so totally different that they have disassociated
and they will say things that are not relevant really.
I remember a case of stammering and we have him on video and the year after in the follow up
I said how is the stammering? He said it's the same.
Then the whole class will say... and the other time... talking fluently
and he was saying the stammering is the same.
He had still a little bit of stammering but comparing the two videos you could see
the tremendous difference.
-What's happened then?
-I have been compensating in my work.
-When you are not working and you are on your own how do you feel, what you are doing?
-I always have a lot of people around me.
-You make sure that you have...
-Yes.
You see, is it possible that you always have people around?
What he explains now, I don't have time, the situation has gone out of his mind.
Loneliness is not something which is real, it is something that you feel inside.
It is a subjective feeling. So whenever you are alone in the house,
it comes this feeling of loneliness.
-I'm never alone but I have trouble getting this...
What the practitioner makes it's a mistake here.
She says you make sure that you have people around and he says yes, yes.
The patient did not say that. It's a different thing.
If the patient said I make sure that somebody is next to me all the time, it's different
when the practitioner says you make sure that you have somebody next to you, he says yes.
You see I can not go to London anymore and she is a very good practitioner who takes the case,
she is sensitive but from time to time she makes a mistake like everybody, like I'm doing.
I'm doing big mistake when I take a case where I put straightforward questions.
-So the loneliness is still there but I have been compensating
and I have trying to arrange my life so that I can't have that OK, I do it this way
and I'm satisfied.
-You don't have a close physical relationship?
-No, just partly but I have problems involving myself 100%. I get back.
-Is it difficult to commit yourself? Why is that?
-Maybe this fear.
-Of what?
-Fear of not succeeding, fear of trying so hard. I think it's ordinary human fear of failing.
-What about confidence? Do you have confidence in yourself?
-I do, sometimes I have too much. When it comes to a certain point, I lose it
because on one hand I feel very clever, doing my job I'm very clever and I have big confidence
in my job, what I do. When it comes to my own feelings, it is who am I?
I don't know if that answered your questions.
-We will come back to that. How things have been physically? What about the glands?
Do you still have the swelling on your neck?
-No.
-They have gone completely.
-Yes.
-Since when they have gone?
-They haven't been here since I was here last in October. There is nothing to say about it.
What I could say about the physical state is that I had some strange things,
I think it was a pain in my left knee, which I couldn't explain.
I'm not sure it was the left, it was one of the knees.
-Was that long ago?
-About one and a half month. It suddenly appeared, it suddenly disappeared.
On top of it I had some warts in my mouth. I didn't know what it was
and I asked my homeopath and she said it might have been this flash.
-What it did it look like?
-Little white marks which I think it is typical for HIV positives but it was very small
and in two days it disappeared.
-Anything else?
-Like my HIV friends, I have my herpes on my lip but very small.
-Is that coming more or less often because I had that it comes twice the year.
-No.
-It's always on your lip. What else?
-Nothing. I have been quite well because these are just...
The question is, is he well?
We don't know how much well he is with this disease.
What we know is that we did the best we could for his organism
and after that we can do nothing at all.
If you try to boost up, forget it, you destroy the whole case very quickly, very fast.
What can you do is wait until he develops some symptomatology and going according
to that symptomatology, nothing else.
If you try in this case to do anything else, you just spoil the case.
-In the first follow up it was very difficult to see that he really improved
because what he said is I'm getting full of fear and then more and more fear, no courage
and then no more self-confidence, fear of loneliness is getting stronger.
There were several points at the previous interview where you had to evaluate these points,
you had to understand the process.
He is somebody and then he loses that attitude of quarrelling.
Maybe he will feel more coward but now he will not jump in situations and kick the other person
because he is a racist, he loses this element.
He is not going to lose it completely but that element is going to be transformed
into really creative situations.
Healthy people understand immediately what is destructive and they should avoid and
what is constructive and they should do it.
That's why a healthy person is going with the car and comes in front of you
and you are in the wrong side. If you are healthy person...
Stramonium comes out, opens the other door, pulls the man out of it and kills him on the spot.
This is a reaction, you will say it's his character, no it's not his character, it's his remedy.
Staphysagria what will do? He wants to kill, he wants to do the same thing but will not
dare to come out of the door. When he will go home, he will knock the wall and say,
I'm stupid why don't I get out and kill? That's a different reaction.
A Nux vomica will jump out and he will fight but most probably he will swear and say,
you stupid bastard.
A Tarentula will hit him, never mind what, he will hit the car. It is a different reaction.
A healthy man, when this happens, will understand that this man is under some sort of condition
that maybe he is drunk and says why you did that?
Especially if not a crash has taken place?
What we do is influenced so much by the pathology and that is why we appear
in the world in the way we appear. One appears this way, another appears that way.
He does something which inwardly feels is something helping the others and he is happy.
The other thing injustice, when he was jumping up and talking about injustice,
he was not feeling? No, he was not feeling.
Because the organism knows when you do something constructive
and when you do something destructive.
-The first time he was in this period where he couldn't do anything, he was at home.
-Yes there is a phase for these cases that you have to wait, you have to understand
is the remedy active? Yes, wait and you will see.
Then you will see miracles but if you expect that you raise the dead, you go inside
and you say what happens and he is in coma.
Take a remedy, he comes back and everything is finished.
This is magic, forget Homeopathy.
Sometimes you will do that but if you believe that what you did it was really rising the dead,
it is finished.
Because it was a hysterical fainting and you gave some Lilium tigrinum and came back.
Just a fainting, you pull out your Carbo vegetabilis, you give it and comes up
and people who see it around say, my god how you did that? You are a magician.
You know the story how I raised the dead cock? A dead cock.
While he changes the tape, I'll tell you the story.
I had some hens and the neighbor gave me his cock to be with my hens,
so the eggs will be fertile. Somebody else offered me another cock.
He says don't take a lented cock, I'll give you your own. I said great, bring it.
He brought the other cock and the two cocks started fighting.
I see fighting, I take the one cock of the neighbor's and put it inside a green house.
The cock who was inside the glass would see the other cock outside
and would jump against the glass.
At a certain point I go to take the cock and to give it back and I thought the cock is dead,
lying down. I don't understand what happened, most probably it was too hot.
What shall I do with the cock? I take the cock, the cock is dead and I go to the neighbor.
Well I said this is your cock. I don't know what happened to the cock
but are you going to eat it because it must have died, it was alive two hours ago.
I can promise you.
Are you going to eat it or shall I raise him back?
She says, you are joking?
In the meantime as I was walking from my house to the neighbor's house ,my mind was working.
What happened? What happened?
So I saw the whole scenery in my mind, what it must have happened it was that
so therefore he had a brain hemorrhage.
The cock was charging with his head against the glass.
One, two, three, four, five times then a brain hemorrhage, then he was out.
So I said are you going to eat it or shall I raise him?
She says, come on George it doesn't matter, we are not going to eat it, forget it, dead cock never.
I said OK, I left him downstairs I went home, I take some Arnica 10M, 50M I can't remember
and I went to the cock, opened his mouth and put the 10M.
As soon as Arnica 10M touched his tongue, the cock did this, a movement.
I said to her, every hour you do that until the night when I come back.
In the night I come back. She says, you know what?
Every time I opened his mouth he did this, by the night he did it a few times.
I said by tomorrow he will be all right.
By tomorrow the cock was standing on his feet, by the night next day the cock was walking.
So I raised the dead! She said do you know some of the stuff?
It is absolutely a true story, a 100%, there is no...
I raised the dead and now what happened is in this family, the old mother of this couple
one day she comes out in the balcony and she says...
It is Sunday or Saturday, they can not find the doctor, she is not under my care the old woman
because she was taking a lot of other remedies and she says, George can you call the doctor
because my mother is out, is dying in coma.
It was Sunday, I could not find. I said can I come and see her?
What happened? She said what happened, they forced her to eat,
she was not in a good state in the mind and the daughter did something that upset her,
something nasty and from that time they forced her to eat and she went out like that.
I said do you want me to raise her? She said, what do you mean, she is my mother
but I knew this woman gave hell to that couple, maybe they did not want to.
I go and get a dose of Ignatia 10M, I give it to her, within a minute she was back.
You understand how the fame goes about and what the other people think but what you know
is a different story. You know that this man is not cured.
So you have to wait and see. How long you wait? I don't know.
Before we can pronounce him cured, his HIV has to be negative and his whole organism...
At this moment we are not in a position to do anything more for this man.
You can give HIV antigen potentised, you can give proteins, antibiotics potentised,
all this is stupid.
Don't do anything of that type.
-He is having another test?
-He is not having another test yet, he is going to have but I don't believe that the test
will be negative yet, no. I believe it is too short, within three years I believe that maybe
his test will go negative.
-You have seen the case?
-No, I have not seen the case. I have seen cases that are improving yet
before we have an observation for at least 3-4 years we can not say anything.
Do not get the impression I'm saying that we can cure AIDS.
I'm showing you what is happening and if all the symptomatology goes away
and still we do not feel that the disease is really gone.
-Why...[ ]
-Because he has become coward.
Correct.
According to me he was doing too well to spoil this by the action of another remedy.
-If the first remedy made him have a clear picture?
-It was not a clear picture. The way he said, I'm coward now, I'll tell you how I explain that.
You don't listen to me, you are thinking your own thoughts.
-Fear of solitude. Now the second follow up there is no real big changes.
He doesn't commit himself to personal relationship...Weakness of memory.
-Weakness of memory is not Lycopodium. You have to give Anacardium, Argentum nitricum etc.
but let us state a very good remark. What he does is a very good remark,
there is no question and everybody could have done it.
But let me explain what I hear. I will explain it to you.
When this person says, I have become cowardice, he most probably does not mean that.
What he means is that he lost this element of jumping up into a situation and fight.
He observes the change in himself and he says to himself, have I become a coward?
Why? He lost this impulse and that is the action of the remedy.
What I explain therefore is that a remedy brought a balance on that level
which he calls coward. I become a coward.
-It's theorizing.
-Well, it's a good theory perhaps, perhaps correct.
I wish we had the possibility in such cases to show you what happened if we gave Lycopodium
and what happened if we did not.
Since I do not have that possibility, you can always criticize me and rightly
because I accept it. The right criticism is something beautiful.
What he says is something very valid. And if he had done it and he was in my class
and they are ready to get the diploma and he would say this explanation,
I would say wrong explanation, take the diploma.
You see?
Because according to my understanding it is wrong but he might be right,
I accept that he might be right.
But what I know from my experience is that if you touch such cases,
you usually spoil them and if you touch them with a close remedy, you spoil them.
What he is doing now, not to have a relationship, don't forget that these people,
immediately after they tell them you have AIDS, they attain a specific psychology.
Because they are confronted with thousands of questions.
Now shall I have a relationship at all? The first thing is that I can not
and there is a realization, that they should not have a relationship,
unless they give the disease to somebody else.
Then they are confronted with the possibility that they may have a relationship
which makes them worse, whatever they may think.
We have to take into consideration all that before we say why he didn't go yet
into a relationship? According to me what he is doing it is very healthy.
He says wait a moment, don't make a relationship.
If he would jump into a relationship, I would say not yet, not reach yet the state.
You remember the Nux vomica case with AIDS?
He was having a relationship with a woman who had AIDS as well.
When he became strong, I told him you better stop this relationship and he did.
You remember another case, Thuja? I said this Thuja case he will have back his gonorrhea
most probably and he will go and get antibiotics.
It was exactly that, he had back his gonorrhea and took antibiotics.
And from Thuja he went to Medorrhinum, Medorrhinum stopped having relationships?
No, he kept on having relationships.
So this reaction I consider the most healthy, I would say.
He is happy, he is satisfied, he is working, he has a lot of energy, glands are gone,
his health is quite good, wakes up refreshed in the morning, he sleeps good.
Why we should give a remedy?
That temptation I know it is very great but I have seen so many cases spoiled
that I would think very much before I give a remedy.
-George do you think is it possible at all that the HIV is negative ?
-I do not know. I can not pass a comment.
I have seen the Australian antigen going negative under homeopathic treatment.
I have seen the thalassemia traits disappearing. I don't know here.
We have to see it a few times and then we may say yes it is really possible.
At this moment I cannot really say.
Seven months is too short or too long?
Absolutely, if you wait long enough, you will see year after year,
the patient is getting better and better.
Don't give any remedy and you will see. I've told you many times when Bill Gray was
here, when he came to study for two years.
He left his patients there without a remedy and he tells the story himself.
Some people he would prescribe by correspondence and never see them again.
Two years later he goes back, he says everybody was cured.
I never had such results when I was prescribing every month.
But make sure when to repeat the remedy, don't let a person die
when he needs a remedy at the same time.
The man with the bleeding he is dying, you can't leave him, you put him in the hospital,
do something. You can't say he took a remedy, let's wait. He needed a blood transfusion,
otherwise he will die, what do you do? You give a blood transfusion.
Don't get me wrong.
-George is it wrong to prescribe on 2-3 keynotes of the remedy?
-But you did not prescribe only on a few symptoms.
He takes in consideration the mental symptoms, amelioration after midnight,
he takes into consideration coward, he takes into consideration general symptoms and he prescribed.
-The first follow up he said he was angry...
-But where is his anxiety now? The fear of death, the anxiety, all has gone.
-At the first follow up he said he wanted to eat a lot because he didn't want to lose weight.
-I don't think he ate more than usual. I think his appetite became bigger
and maybe he ate normally, as much as he wanted. I didn't get the idea that he forced himself to eat.
The fact that he picked up weight it most probably says that his appetite was better
and he Eating perhaps a little bit more.
One thing that we see in Causticum is that they have a strong metabolism,
they are burning a lot, rather hyper active metabolism and that's why we see this intensity,
the fire which they have inside them and they are usually thin.
That element is taking away by Causticum and maybe he is eating the same amount of food
and we can check and maybe he still picks up weight.
The fact that he picks up weight also tells in favor of the Causticum action.
There are several points which I had to consider and I said no remedy.
I brought these cases to demonstrate, never mind how much verbally I may say wait.
I bring these cases on long follow ups, I hope to show you some more, to see the effect.
You will never believe and say but he is not doing well but he is doing well,
you have to perceive.
The other day I said unless you perceive when a person is doing well, forget Homeopathy.
You can't carry on with Homeopathy.
He is doing well. You have to perceive it. You have to understand it immediately.
He is doing well, don't touch it.
It is like a beautiful painting.
It is coming up so beautifully and then suddenly you take the brush and go like that,
not in harmony. The picture is gone.
This is so sensitive, so apparent so vivid for me, that's how I perceive it.
Sometimes I have to do it.
With the Cicuta child they telephone, I see it is a serious situation,
I don't have enough symptomatology and I'm not sure is this Sanicula, is this Bryonia
or is it another remedy?
What shall I do now? I keep them on the telephone and I know he is calling me
from Australia and it's going to cost him a lot of money and I try my best
and I give Sanicula and it doesn't work.
That can spoil the case and I give Bryonia and I said if it doesn't work, he said it doesn't work.
He calls me back and says the child is completely exhausted with fever over 40.
He gives me symptomatology and I said Belladonna, more clear now the picture.
Next day he calls me, he is better, thank god but thank god it's not enough here
because after a week he may say the child cannot walk again
and you see how nice you feel after that.
Unfortunately you will say, if Homeopathy is so difficult, what shall we do? We try.
It is difficult, I never said it is easy.
But if we try, then we see beautiful things happening in the end.
We will see the beauty.
If we did it the wrong way, we will be so disappointed.
I've seen even students of mine going astray. It's too long, I can't wait and they will get disappointed.
Then they will come back and say, you are right.
-George in a normal case, would you take homosexuality...
-In a normal case if I would take into consideration the pathology? Absolutely.
Ah, the pathology homosexuality?
You see with homosexuality we don't know the remedies that produce that turn,
neither the homosexuals accept that this is pathology.
Whether they accept or not it doesn't matter, still the remedy may change that
because I've seen several cases changing.
So it is pathology for some cases. I've given my ideas about homosexuality.
I don't want to go into that now.
There are different groups of people, those that can change or they may never change.