I'd like to show you another case and to show you another aspect of wrong prescribing,
how wrong prescribing pushed the disease into the inside.
You will see how she will describe it and also you will see again the picture of the remedy.
Before, I'll tell you a little story concerning Arsenicum.
In 1966 I visited London and I visited Sir John Weir.
Do you remember Sir John Weir? A big homeopath from England,
a big teacher who was teaching at the Faculty.
By the time I visited him he must have been about 75 or 78 years old.
That was 66-67 in London. I visited him and he had a butler.
He took me to see him. He didn't greet me.
He sat in his table, he pulled a case and he said you are the homeopath from Athens?
Yes, yes.
He reads his case and said what did I give him? I said Arsenicum.
He said I did not give Arsenicum, I gave Nux vomica and he came after a month
and he said that there was no action at all and then I gave him Arsenicum
Then he came after a month and he read me the report.
He was better in this, better in this, worse in this. What did I give him then?
I said sac lac.  What is your name? I'm very glad to meet you and we became friends.
He dedicated all his books to me etc.
To show you that he was a great homeopath.
What I want to show you in this is the fastidious element,
the fastidious element is in Nux vomica as well and the irritability sometimes it's there.
The worse cold and there is a possibility that you may confuse this.
Also the fastidiousness is with Thuja. Thuja is very fastidious.
I don't know if I have given you the additions, is in the additions Thuja?
Carcinosin and Thuja, especially Thuja, can be as fastidious as Arsenicum.
Let us see another case.
-This is AC, she is almost 30.
At first I saw her in July last year and she is actually referred to me
by another acupuncturist who had tried to treat her with not very much success.
She was complaining of genital herpes that occurred twice monthly,
itching all over her body which she gets any time and anywhere on her body
but it's actually worse in the genital region.
She has itching in the vagina, which the hospital have diagnosed as microscopic warts,
she also get an inflammation of the eye that can be either eyes,
her eyes get very inflamed and red.
She has a great fear of dirt, of contagion, she is ever washing her hands
and she has a disgust about touching, particularly in her own body.
She is also prone about some diarrhea and hemorrhoids.
Generally she is also very tired but she said that she doesn't get often colds.
Her sleep is disturbed by the itching and also by pains which she gets on the rectum.
-The itching is all over her body?
-She gets to different parts all over her body; it can be the arms, the legs,
the face, her trunk but it's more constant in the genital region as well.
She has a history of stomach ulcer which was treated by [drug name]
I'm not sure how long ago, maybe some years ago.
Besides, the diarrhea... in the hospital they mentioned colitis but she never
had a definite diagnosis.
The hemorrhoids have pain and they bleed.
She took the pill 4-5 years ago because she had heavy periods, heavy menses.
She stopped the pill and her menses had been quite irregular and she said she had headaches
and extra growth in the pubic hair since she stopped the pill.
She desires sweet fruits, very strongly, three underlined and vinegar.
She also likes liver and mayonnaise.
She is aversed to things like snails and tapioca..
She has little thirst and she drinks many fizzy drinks, alcohol, vodka and wine.
She said she is a chilly person but her hands are warm,
she doesn't suffer with cold extremities particularly.
She worries a lot and she said she's closed, she doesn't have many friends.
She gets very depressed about her symptoms and she would cry about her symptoms.
She has a great fear for the future and because of her phobia she can't work.
She does very open a relationship with a man who was a professional gambler
and she says that the relationship is not longer a sexual relationship
but she needs to have someone there.
She has a great sense of worthlessness about herself and she also worries a great deal
about her mother. She mentioned her mother.
She wants to be clean all the time, she baths a lot,
she won't have carpets in her flat because she likes to wash the floor and disinfect it.
She said the first time it started she was at school, she was about 12,
it had started with a fear of becoming pregnant, which she still has.
-She doesn't want to be pregnant?
-I asked her, it's not that she doesn't want, she just has the fear of it.
-Many times they've asked me how did I produce Materia Medica?
How did I have this information? Just by observing these cases.
Take the common factors that run through these cases
and you will see the picture of the remedy.
There is an element of limitation in general in Arsenicum.
This element comes from insecurity. The insecurity appearing in different ways.
Also you will see in Arsenicum there is no much sexual energy.
Yet they want somebody to have as company, that's desire for company,
you will find it in books desire for company.
They desire for cleanliness and order in one way or another,
they will go through.
Almost in all cases it will be underlined a state of anxiety.
Mostly anxiety about health matters, fear of different kind of diseases
and finally fear of death.
What is most important with Arsenicum is to have this urge for order,
this fastidiousness and at the same time a limited individual,
an individual who is not broad minded.
They are concerned around themselves, they are revoving around themselves
and around their own symptomatology and pathology.
I have this and I have that, they complain and they revolve around themselves,
around their own elements.
The selfish element is in a particular way.
Because you saw this woman, a selfishness on another level,
I do everything correct. I'm super.
And when it breaks down, it comes to the other state of despair.
I'm nothing, I'm worthless.
You will see for instance Arsenicum indicated in women,
where they have performed their duties, they raised their children,
they have gone through menopause things and now they are 55-60
and the children they get married.
Nobody from the family wants anymore the help from the mother
and suddenly the mother feels worthless, without mission, without anything to go ahead
and to go on with it.
And she feels completely in the air and you will get a tremendous anxiety during that time.
When a woman comes, she says this is an anxiety which comes from insecurity,
she has nothing to cling on anymore. She says everybody has gone
from the house. All the children are gone and now what?
Then it comes the fear, the anxiety, as if life has finished, the end is coming.
The Arsenicum individuals have been enjoying life, put things in order, they enjoy that
and as soon as the problem comes, then life becomes difficult.
Otherwise they enjoy.
Can you imagine somebody dressing, he is very happy with his appearance?
The appearance is of great important for Arsenicum and it has to be meticulous.
The more meticulous...
If you observe a woman, you'll observe the way she paints her eyelids.
She gives you impression of perfection, that is a case of Arsenicum.
The way she dresses, perfection, case of Arsenicum.
The way she paints her face, perfect.
Then they will not cry, why? Because crying will bring up...
They are going to be in pain... some spots.
She can't tolerate these spots, so she will not cry. Then limits, limits.
Then we have the other situation that we saw first, tremendous limitation.
Nothing moves.
-She's fearful of people... she doesn't like to be touched.
The itching on her skin generally started soon after she met her boyfriend
about six years ago.
She said she didn't have the itching until she met him.
She also said that she contracted... her initial outbreak of herpes
after she met her boyfriend.
The itching is worse at night and worse when she thinks about it.
It's better with warm bathing, she takes bath during the day.
The initial herpes started after she met her boyfriend,
she didn't have any herpes for two years and then when her father died...
-I'd like you to see the patient and to see how she describes this thing
and I would like you also to see something very interesting that happened.
As she described different remedies, what happened is
that the woman did not want others to touch her because she felt she was getting dirty
if she was touched by somebody. She had to wash if she touched anything outside.
The outside world was very dirty for her.
She took different remedies and you will see now what happened.
It doesn't matter whether the itching now is gone or is not gone.
Unless we see the whole picture of the case, what we are doing,
we are improving the case or we are degenerating the case?
Then that is the idea with Homeopathy.
You give a remedy for the itching Rhus venenata and the itching is better for a week,
it doesn't matter, you give another remedy for the itching, it doesn't matter.
-What is your main complaint?
-I feel rejected, rejecting myself.
-This is much more than pain?
-I'm not able to relax in my own body.
-You had a boyfriend who left? He came back and left?
-It's like 7 years, it's been like that.
Then last week he writes me a letter saying that he must go
because he is no good for me because he's a gambler.
He does bad things, he upsets me and I'm always trying to get him out of it...
-You have been upset by this incident very much?
-No, I've been upset with what he's giving me...
-But you are not upset because he left?
-Yes because I feel insecure.
-This state that you feel rejected this is lately strong?
-Yes if he comes back, I won't feel so rejected but I still reject my own body
because of contamination.
-You feel that your body has contaminated you and you reject it?
-Yes.
-Your mother is not alive?
-She is, she is in the States.
-You don't have a good relationship with her?
-We love one another very much but we've both gone through so much with my father
and when I went to live with her, I've been going through... found out
about everything... and on the top of that I had to find a job and everything...
But it didn't turn out like that because I was going through so much stress.
And then she lost all her money...
-You had to leave and come back.
-Due to my health. I feel within this year I've come forward from where I was.
-To what respect?
-I don't know. When I first arrived here I was terrible with feeling very contaminated.
-You have an almost obsession for cleanliness?
You have to wash to take away the contamination?
-Oh yes, before all that happened, I was...
with all those clothes, they had to be clean.
If I go pass a tram,  I go  in a panic, I have to wash my clothes and wash my hands
after doing a job and everything was in little piles, things like that.
If I touched a door handle and I didn't feel was clean, I didn't let my fingers.
My parents I didn't touch them for a period of time,
even the door handles I had my own tissues. That was prior to this...
Then I got a lot better but then this happened with Christopher
and now it's turned the other way. It's my own body I'm scared off. The phobia is still there.
I still hate hotels and beds where people slept in.
I still find a fear with beds in hotels and things which I don't feel they are clean.
I've got a lot better about things, like carpets, I wasn't able to do that.
To walk out of my back and on the floor.
-You reject yourself?
-...I reject them before they reject me.
I don't feel I have a proper, loving relationship because of that.
Also with Christopher we never had a proper relationship.
With his gambling he's never been interested in a loving relationship.
It's been a companionship. That has been difficult because we never go out together,
to enjoy an evening out.
-He gambles every night?
-Every day. He is obsessed with it.
-Did you know about your father whether he had any venereal disease?
-No.
-Do you have any other fear?
-I also got fear of death but it's not obsession, I'm not thinking of that all the time.
I have a fear of future, of not meeting anybody and being lonely.
That is very important to me. Loneliness, I get very depressed.
-You have a desire, you feel better with somebody?
-Yes.
When I take rubrics and I do differential diagnosis, desires company.
I say how and why each remedy desires company?
It's not desires company it's there or it's not there.
The idea is with the person understanding Arsenicum, understanding their needs,
their insecurities, what do they need? Why they need company?
Do they need company to converse? Do they need company to give some pleasure to the others?
Do they need company for themselves?
What is this insecure element which makes them desire for company?
This is the desire for company, this is the way that she expresses.
So you will have to understand the 3-dimensional picture of our remedies.
This is what I try to show you in this seminar.
It's not a flat desire for company. They are not going to say I desire for company.
This is how she is going to say it and then you have to perceive the need.
This is a need, desire for company. She is not feeling well when she is alone.
You can be looking in your Repertory, when she is alone
but you will perceive it in this way.
She is not going to give you the words of the Repertory.
She is going to give you the essence of the remedy.
What you will need more to confirm the diagnosis of Arsenicum?
Chilliness, worse cold, what else?
For instance, if you ask her how you drink and she will say in sips?
Also you will see in these cases the lack of responsibility, real responsibilities
they don't like. She doesn't want a child the Arsenicum.
Why she does not want a child? The responsibility is very great for her,
it is too much of a burden.
When somebody expects something from him in the Repertory, it gets very anxious.
Arsenicum gets very anxious.
-I don't want dust. It's not furnished at all, or got carpets, I don't stand on the floor.
If I change the sheets because the bed is old and the blankets I don't feel is that clean.
I won't put the blanket because I feel the blanket is dirty.
-Are you very fastidious with your clothes? Which one to wear?
-Not really, I have to see that they are clean.
If they got a mark and I know it's me that made the mark and I know what it is, it's fine.
If it's got a mark and I don't know what it is, then...
You see when the pathology goes on a deeper level, how the context changes?
Her pathology is fear she is contaminated, she is full of germs,
she rejects her body all the time, she is disgust. She has rejected her own body.
Where she was rejecting outside, now she has rejected her own body.
Now once this fear comes upon, the other element of cleanliness is subdued.
What is this? I don't know where this came from. It may be full of germs.
That is important.
If she has something where she knows she spoiled, she put her milk in here
and she knows this is milk, she doesn't care.
With the pathology of Arsenicum on another level, which is not so deep,
she will care very much. Everything has to be absolutely meticulous.
Here the organism says, it doesn't matter.
What is important is germs, I don't want germs.
The pathology goes deeper. Then it changes the symptomatology, the way it appears.
Do you understand that?
Many times I've said in different remedies that once the pathology goes on a deeper level,
keynote symptoms disappear.
Calcarea carbonica has desire for sweets, desire for eggs, worse cold.
These are keynotes symptoms for Calcarea carbonica.
Let Calcarea carbonica become complete mental picture and develop tremendous fear of insanity,
fear of death, fear of disease and all these keynote symptoms will disappear.
No desire for sweets, no desire for eggs, not feeling so cold.
In another level of pathology and then the other portion of the organism is left normal.
Yes eggs I take, sweets I take. It's not a big deal.
Bring the pathology down to physical level and you will see the desire for sweets increases,
coldness increases.
-You eat a lot of sweets?
-Not that many.
-But you like sweets?
-I like sweets.
-Very much?
-Yes.
-What about eggs, do you like them?
-Not really. I don't really like eggs so great.
-What about water? How much water do you drink?
-I wouldn't say I drink water every day.
-You would say medium or less than medium?
-I don't really drink that much water.
-If you drink water, how do you drink it? The whole thing or sip it?
-A cup I suppose. I like water.
If I drink a glass, I get breathless and I go dizzy.
-So how you drink it? You take it in cups or sips?
-Not in sips. If I have a drink in front of me, I'll drink it.
If I go out and I have a glass of water, I'll drink it.
If they bring it in front of me, I'll drink it fast. I'm a fast person.
-Your appetite is good?
-Yes, some days I can go like eating, other days I don't think about it.
-The examinations that you had in the clinics, did they examine your liver?
Do you know if they gave you liver tests?
-I don't know. I don't think so.
-Did you ever had any problems with your liver?
-I don't know.
-But you have an itching all over your body you said.
Now you still have the itching?
-Not so much.
-In the vagina?
-Yes but the last 3 weeks it has been good.
The general itching is gone, the itching of the vagina is almost gone
but she is going into pieces, the real disorder goes deeper and deeper.
Now she has rejected herself.
She doesn't appear to be suffering very much but now she is suffering much better.
This is the idea.
How long she is going to stand this feeling of being contaminated,
not being able to have a relationship because she is contaminated, rejected herself?
That is how she will be led into having suicidal disposition and suicidal tendencies.
As I said before, when you have this kind of pathology on this level,
the other pathology, which appears to be keynotes symptomatology on another level, disappears.
I hope I've been able to give you some idea about Arsenicum.
You had enough of this poison today.
-What about the pills?
-She has to stop the pills if she takes homeopathic treatment, she has to stop the pill.
I want to thank very much the organizers of this Congress, very good energy!
Also to wish you a very great success in your practice. Thank you.