-Do you have any clues so far?
-There is some thoughts.
-Do you have any ideas of the remedy?
-Arsenicum album.
-Staphysagria.
-Nat. muriaticum.
-Ignatia.
-Silica.
-Petroleum.
-Nat. carbonicum.
Let us see a little bit more of information.
-Just some thoughts.
-For very short time.
-The depression was what? You cried?
-Yes, this time I cried and I wrote all the story what has happened.
-You wrote it and you published the book?
-Yes, no!
You see the sensitivity? You see how automatic is the sensitivity?
Did you publish the book? She said yes. Why did I ask again?
Because I perceive she is answering without hearing.
I perceived immediately she did not hear what I asked.
That is how automatic should be your sensitivity, understanding the other person.
Almost reading their minds.
Sometimes some of you have seen some of this kind and you say, George is reading the mind.
It is not reading the mind, it is pure sensitivity and logic put together.
I'm not intuitive and illogical. I put logic and sensitivity together with perception.
I put these elements together and each one of us has to develop these elements.
How? By observing, by listening to others and not to your mind, listening to the person
and not to your own ideas inside. It is Calcarea carbonica, it is Causticum, it is this...
Forget it. The idea came, it is maybe Causticum. Wait and we confirm it.
-No, only for me.
-For yourself only.
-Yes.
-Do you eat a lot of salt?
-No, little.
-You don't like salt?
-I do yes.
-You eat fruits?
-Yes.
-You like fruits?
You see these questions go to the mind where some of you went, Nat. mur., Ignatia.
I see the grief, there is around Nat mur, is this? And the answer unfortunately is not.
Do you eat fruits because Ignatia aversion to fruits many, many times and not only that.
It has other keynotes like perspiration in the face only.
I will try to get this information to confirm is this or that and then to proceed further
to see what is happening.
It's not a great desire for fruits but she eats fruits.
It's not a great desire but from time to time she eats fruits, there is no aversion.
-Maybe salt is bad for her.
-Do you think it's the type that will take into consideration the diet?
That's another thing immediately you see in this woman.
She will not take care of herself.
You remember she said she did not have sex but once.
Did she say that?
-Yes.
-With the first husband.
-Once only after three years when her skin was better.
Did she say that?
-No, it was reported.
-I don't like milk. Not at all from two years.
That information is important now, aversion milk, why? Because she volunteers that information
and then she confirms it by saying since childhood I do not like milk.
That's definite, there is no question about that.
We have a symptom on which we may rely.
-And if you take something which has milk inside?
-Yogurt, that's OK.
-Is anything else that you don't like?
-Yes, fat meat, pork.
You see how I make long pauses and she will not volunteer any information.
Every time I pause, she will keep quite. She will not volunteer any information.
Aversion pork and aversion fat, it points out to Pulsatilla and aversion milk
it might also be there but this is not a Pulsatilla case.
Why? Because she is not forwarding anything, she is not open at all.
You know the Pulsatilla she will forward information, she will tell things,
it's not holding back so much as the Natrums or as the Ignatias.
-Do you like the sun? Do you sit under the sun?
-I like the sun very much but since two years I cannot bear it.
Here it is terrible for me because of the sun. I always have hat and I have headache at once.
After a short time of sunshine I get headache and weakness.
In former times I liked the sun and it's the best for my health, for my skin.
-When it started this aversion to the sun?
-Two years ago all the things together.
Since two years she has become a medicine which is worse by the sun, aversion to milk
and she says aversion pork and fat, not since two years but it seems there is a point
where the remedy picture has changed due to the fact that she is so sensitive to the sun.
You see how sensitive she is? It is terrible here.
For how many of you it is terrible? You have to wear really a hat?
You can't go anytime in the sun? If you go in the sun, you feel exhausted?
You feel headaches?
So there is definitely an aggravation from the sun.
-Did they give you Nat. mur.?
-Yes, I had it in very small doses in 6X.
-Ignatia you got?
-Yes, I got.
-Low potency or high potency?
-Low.
This case cannot be touched by low potencies.
Even the right potency will not produce the deep changes that we want to produce in her.
And you see grief Ignatia, grief Nat mur but it doesn't work always.
It works sometimes, not always. Here she needs another remedy.
Now you will tell me you are going to give Nat carbo and the picture has changed in two years
and you base your prescription on aversion milk, which is since she was two years old.
How do you tell us or how do we believe that the remedy changed two years ago
and she went into Nat carbo since the aversion for milk is from young age?
She could tolerate the sun by that time, now she cannot tolerate the sun.
Is in that a contradiction, yes or no? Why didn't you ask me?
-As she is proceeding there are more and more symptoms.
-Yes but it's a logical question to ask and I like to hear these questions.
To say wait a moment and I let enough time to pass so somebody could ask me.
Do you understand the question?
Why are you saying this is a case of Nat carbo and she, because she is having aversion to milk
but she says the sensitivity to the sun, which is Nat carbo, came only two years ago.
What might have happened? What is the answer?
-She got the wrong remedy.
-If she got the wrong remedy, it will do two things.
Either it will bring a few symptoms for a time of her own and then it disappears
or it pushes the disease deeper but makes a clearer picture.
You have a case of Ferrum and you give Pulsatilla
and you see more strong symptoms of Ferrum eventually.
Then a headache starts with the Ferrum.
The answer here can be, and you have to remember that very well as a general remark,
that a symptom could continue under 2 or even 3 remedies.
That means aversion to milk might have been with another remedy, Lac defloratum
which is feeling the cold very much, likes the sun very much and has aversion to milk.
When from Lac defloratum changes into Natrum carbonicum, then certain symptoms
of her change towards Natrum carbonicum but one symptom remain, which is common to both.
So you may still need a second remedy for her, which will have aversion to milk
but perhaps of another intensity.
She may needs some Sepia later on which it has aversion to milk,
she may need some Calcarea carbonica, which has aversion to milk also, she may have been
Calcarea carbonica as a child, aversion to milk, coughing, worse cold, perspiration.
Or now from Calc carbo to Nat carbo, still aversion to milk but stronger now.
If we had a way to measure these symptoms we would see that now the symptom
because it is stronger in that remedy, it is stronger in her as well, very strong aversion to milk.
This is the same thing when a person says...
How are you? You call him after the first interview, he has come for headaches
and you say how are you? I still have my headaches he says.
When I hear that I don't write he still has his headaches, what else?
No, what I want to know is how strongly is. The same, as strong as before.
Still I want to know how frequently he has them.
And there it comes the answer, which you usually will hear, if you have given the right remedy,
you will hear I used to have headaches every second day.
Now? Now the last two weeks I didn't get. I just got two headaches.
Strong? Strong as before but one headache in a week from every second day.
The amelioration is therefore 70%.
If you wait, it will go up to 100%.
What she says, what she relates to you is that yesterday I still had one headache.
Yes one headache but what kind of headache?
Unless you perceive this, you can't proceed with Homeopathy.
This is so important, I cannot stress it enough.
It comes the Stramonium child and it says, the aggression is better thank you very much.
Ok, placebo, placebo, placebo. Everything will go away but just give placebo,
don't give other remedies.
The Causticum comes and says, I have more appetite,
I picked up weight and my energy is good, still I have the pains. Placebo, you wait.
I will give you some examples in this seminar, I have to give you some examples of waiting.
Already I have given you enough but I will give you more to see what I mean when I say
waiting and you will see in the end you will have a cured person.
In the end you will have somebody who is cured.
If you don't do that, in the end you will have somebody who always suffers.
Let's see for her what shall we do.
-You get a cold easily?
-Very easily yes, little fever.
One could make also seeing sighing, why don't you take into consideration sighing in this case?
Sighing but not enough to over throw the worse sun, exhaustion from the sun,
headache from the sun, aversion milk. The sighing is not tremendous.
If you would see that on the video...
I would say wait a moment, it is too strong the symptom. Forget about the sun.
Now I say forget about the sighing, the sighing is not going to be the decisive factor.
-2-3 times the month.
-Are you afraid by thunderstorm at all?
-Not very much.
-Do you have any fears?
-Yes a lot.
-What fears?
-Fear of falling from the staircases, rolling stairs.
-It's a fear to step on them because you don't feel secure if you have vertigo?
-Yes and anytime.
-Another fear?
Did you understand? She has vertigo when she goes into the circus where the children play
and they go into something that they go around like that or up and down.
-The escalator?
-Not the escalator, it is on the circus when they play "Mary goes round".
-Also a kind of claustrophobia in the rooms and crowded, more in small rooms if the door are shut.
-So you didn't describe to me yourself. What kind of person you are?
You said you are a person without self-confidence.
-Small self-confidence but more than in earlier years.
-Now you do not have so much fear of self-confidence?
You have more self-confidence now?
-Yes.
-Do you feel happy inside?
-No because of my physical problems, they are too much.
-What is mostly bothering now?
-The headaches, the infections and a sensitivity of my stomach.
What do we have here? We have a picture of Nat carbo more confined, why?
Because Nat carbo almost always has some problems with the stomach.
The stomach in Nat carbo is the weak spot.
Whatever it happens it affects the stomach.
-Fear of driving.
-I don't see in Nat carbo this, I don't know whether they have fear in escalators.
We just hear it now. If it goes away, then we wait to see if that fear goes away,
then we noted it down and then we may see, like fear in the" Mary goes around".
That is very much Cocculus, Argentum nitricum, Petroleum, Tabacum, remedies of that type
but not Natrum carbonicum so much.
So we wait to see what happens and how many symptoms of this patient will go away.
But what do you observe? You observe the closeness.
She searches what to say, she does not know what to say.
The self- importance is minimized.
If you ask me what do I think about myself... I'm the greatest homeopath!
Do you believe that? You don't believe it but it doesn't matter.
What it matters is how I feel. I feel very self-important, so I will tell you everything,
all my good points.
How sensitive, how nice, how loving etc.
Come on George.
A Natrum muriaticum that may have all these qualities after all and will say, what am I?
It is a difference, it is not accidental what you see.
We will see that later on when she will say for three years I did not dare to have sex
with my husband because my skin condition was so bad.
Once the skin condition for some time went better, she dared, she allowed herself
to have sexual intercourse with her husband.
How much concern about the other person that he will not get repulsed.
It is interesting to hear the whole story.
-What do you have there? Pains or discomfort?
-A discomfort and a little pain.
-It's all the time or after three hours after eating it starts?
-It's only if I eat the wrong things, too sharp or too fat.
I think my pancreas is not working right, I have feeling of low sugar.
-Do you desire sugar?
-I start trembling.
-If you eat sugar, it calms down?
-It is a little better if I eat sugar but not completely.
-Hypoglycemia.
-A little bit.
-So you have to eat something. Do you want to eat something during the interview?
-No, no.
-What kind of weather do you like? Do you like cold or warm weather?
-At the moment I like cold weather better.
Skin has gone very bad these days of my travel to Greece.
-Because it's hot? It's too much sun?
-I couldn't bear the sun because of the headache and I missed the light therapy at home.
-Ultra violet?
-Yes.
-So what type of person you are? Discribe.
- i did.
-Not enough.
-I don't know where to start.
-Tell everything, everything that comes first in your mind.
-I think I don't live my natural character because I'm always handicap by my physic.
-I know but how do you feel?
Did you see the answer? How do you feel, what is your character?
Instead of describing the character, she automatically avoids...
Never mind how much you try. You see the resistance, it is very difficult to open up,
especially under the circumstances.
-How do you feel inside? Just describe to me.
-I feel good inside.
She still avoids the answer. If she says I feel good, there is no more questions.
The interrogation is going to finish.
She asks for help now.
-I'm content with my life at the moment. If I were healthy, I would say I'm happy now.
But what do you feel?
-Describe me this feeling, you said when you walk is like not stepping on the floor,
it is like flying, when you have the vertigo?
-It is like on a star.
-But you said as if you are not stepping on the floor.
-Yes.
-Do you get angry easily? Irritated?
-What do you do then? Do you come out with the anger or you withhold?
-I think I come out with the anger.
-You think. Are you sure?
-Yes.
-What do you do? Can you describe a case when last time you were angry?
-I'm impatient with the other person. I'm angry with my friend when he is very slow
and he doesn't understand me at once, I can be angry and impatient.
-Then what do you do?
-I tell him I'm angry.
-How?
-I try...
-She shouts.
Now this relationship that you have, you take some initiative or you follow what he wants?
-No, I have to take initiative.
-Is he the same age as you?
-Yes exactly.
-Do you feel that you protect him?
-No but it's unusual for me to take initiative at all when I look at my before life.
It's new and it's not very easy sometimes for me.
-What it bothers you most at the moment is first the headaches and then the stomach
or the pains in the joints?
-The pains in the joints are good. No pain.
-Then the pain in the stomach is second and then the skin or the skin is second
or the skin is first?
-The skin is second.
-And the pain in the stomach is third or the exhaustion is?
-I think the infections, the frequent infections are.
-Where are the infections mostly?
-Colds, but also to the stomach.
-The stomach seems to have become very sensitive?
-It is like infection. It has diarrhea.
-When you get a cold usually it is with vomiting and diarrhea?
-Not usually but many times.
-Are you constipated?
-No.
-Your nails are strong?
-Yes, very strong.
-So you consider yourself open?
-Yes.
-Why you laugh?
-I think so.
-It's easy for you to talk to me?
-Yes.
-Do you think you have given me enough information?
-I hope so. In german it would be easier.
-Do you drink alcohol at all?
-Few and only beer.
-Does it aggravate your skin?
-Wine yes, beer not.
-Not at all. How much beer you can drink? One bottle?
-Yes.
-And you like to drink one whole bottle?
-Sometimes when it's hot here I drink it in the evening.
-Do you feel more happy when you drink the beer?
-No effect.
-With your boyfriend are you talkative?
-Yes I would like but he is very silent.
-He is very close. No friends.
-Few.
-Do you have other friends?
-Yes but few. Some close friends.
-You don't talk much.
-Yes.
-Yes or you do?
-I have no idea.
-The menses are scanty, a small period, a bigger period, with a lot of blood?
-A lot of blood and myomas.
-For how many days a lot of blood?
-5-6 days.
-Was any time when you had a bigger hemorrhage, like 10 days?
-Yes.
-Did they examine you? They found fibroma?
-A big one?
-Not so big, it's controlled and it hasn't grown and blood is still 5-6 days again.
-A bit of blood during ovulation sometimes.
-And the headache starts in two ways, before the menses and goes on the first part
of the cycle to the ovulation that time. The second  part of the cycle was without headache,
this month and the month before.
-Do you have any leucorrhea?
-No.
-Do you perspire at all?
-Not very much.
-She has now flashes?
-Yes since two months.
-Flashes of heat?
-Yes.
-When did you take Pulsatilla?
-I don't know.
-She has some varicose veins now.
-Yes.
-The soles of the feet are sensitive?
-Not very much. Yes sensitive.
-What do you like to do? Do you work?
-Yes.
-What kind of work?
-In an office as a secretary. Arranging...
But only four hours the day, after that I'm very exhausted.
And I have much problems with my neck, I sit in the table and the neck
becomes stiff and painful.
-How is the sleep?
-At the moment it is good but sometimes ago I had much problems with my heart.
I slept and after an hour of sleeping I wake with very strong heart beating.
Exactly an hour after sleep. All night.
-You mean you wake up after an hour and you stay awake the whole night or you sleep again?
-I sleep again and sometimes it comes back the heart beating and sometimes I sleep.
-Do you have a fright when you wake up?
-Yes terrible fright. Fright to death.
-That you will die?
-Yes.
-Every night?
-Yes a long time it was every night. At the moment it is not. Here it is not.
-You will go to bed and after an hour you will wake up with palpitation and fear of death?
-Yes.
Can you find this symptom?
It's a very important symptom what she has said. Can you find it in the Repertory.
Palpitation on waking, waking from palpitations is close but this is much more strong.
She wakes up in a fright and she will scream.
She will say it later on.
Fear of death on waking in the night, do we have that symptom?
How do you know Aconite? Because it is in my lectures.
Fear of death on waking, Alumina.
-Excitement at night.
-Yes find me this. Where is Nat carb bold? Not bold.
It's interesting on this Repertory which has additions from different,
it has a note that comes from Hahnemann and it says chest, palpitation, night, waking,
only Natrum carbonicum it gives for that and it comes from Hahnemann.
It's interesting just to find some confirmation on what you are thinking.
What she says lately also confirms the initial diagnosis.
I was especially pleased when I saw this addition in this Repertory from a note from Hahnemann.