-Number 6 case is a case of...who knows the remedy?
The others you don't know the remedy?
Who would prescribe Aconitum in that case?
That majority. So we have to comply with that.
Here she has some symptoms.
Fear that somebody was behind her. Do we have that under Aconite?
-No.
-Fear that somebody will break into her house. How you will look on that?
Fear of robbers.
-Do you have Aconite there?
-No.
-Anxiety about others? Do you have Aconite?
-Yes.
-Worse with heat, she likes to walk in the rain.
She came to consult until September after labor where she started having phobias,
fear of something bad was going to happen.
The way things are underlined is not very clear that it's Aconite
but once you put things together in that case and especially after the lecture,
you can see the Aconite picture.
Yet there are things in her case that would one think it's not a typical Aconite.
From that case, I don't know if you are able to see, that it is not a very typical Aconite.
If you see the phobias before, so we see an Aconite constitution, as we call it.
But we see a phobia imprinted after labor that maybe she will be dying during labor
and the phobias appeared.
Also the case shows underneath that there is perhaps another remedy before Aconite.
And though we expect perhaps that Aconite will not finish this case
and maybe another remedy will be needed eventually.
What would be the underlined remedy?
I will read you the follow up.
50M.
She came after almost a month and the doctor has written better, underlined 3 times.
This is not a good thing to write.
The best thing to write is to have the exact impact and the impression in the paper case,
if you want the case to be studied by somebody else,
the best thing is to write exactly the words of the patient. Oh, I'm the same, oh, I'm the same.
Oh, I think I've been better. It makes a big difference. Fantastic!
If we have that indicated, we know actually by this explanation, how this case has acted.
And this is very important for us, we have to know it.
So better, underlined 3 times, it doesn't mean anything.
And I have told you many times, don't write that. Write the exact words of the patient.
From the first day what she says almost I felt better. The dullness in the head went away.
The last few days the flushes turned 2-3 times but without the dullness.
Psychologically I'm better, I'm not bothered by relatives coming to the house.
In that case relatives were coming to the house and she was feeling claustrophobic
and she would go away. She is not bothered now. The fear of death is better.
I do not cry but neither I have the constriction in the throat.
Irritability is better, I have more patience, I'm not so angry with the children.
Perhaps I don't sympathize so much anymore, she says, with things which happen to the others.
She is not in a hurry. Sleep is good, no position, no nightmares.
Fear for her kids underlined 3 times, she likes the rain, good appetite, nausea is better,
desire fish once, desire fat once, desire oranges twice, thirst twice.
The menses came 7 days earlier, she was irritable and she had a headache before menses.
Lately I feel a bad taste in my mouth and my husband complains
that my mouth is smelling badly.
So she comes about 10-11 months late after that interview and she says
I have started having flushes of heat in the face again,
the dullness in the head is not as before.
I have much mucus coming from the throat.
She says I'm not afraid anymore staying alone, actually I want to stay alone.
When I'm in grief, I have a constriction in the throat but I do not cry.
She is now quite irritable underlined 3 times and she shows that irritability.
Sighing underlined once and she is worse consolation underlined twice.
There is some anxiety about health and anxiety about others
but not as much as before the anxiety.
Very little anxiety when others come to my house, not in a hurry.
Sleeps in no position.
Desires milk, thirsty underlined once and she says that the last month she had twice menses.
The last 2-3 month she had twice menses and the menses lasted 3-4 days.
Great irritability before menses she says again.
Perspiration mostly on palm she says, offensive odor from the mouth,
and the last 4 months she has come up with some acne.
The doctor does not say why but a month ago she took some antibiotics for a week
but she does not say why.
Now what are you going to do?
Hormonal levels in her body must have been disturbed because of the acne
and the hormonal changes. So something is going on with the hormones.
Is this suffering the same as the first? She is on another level all together.
The problem is, can we help her further?
Other idea?
Who would see Nat mur in that case? Who would see Ignatia?
Who would see Sepia? Who would see Aconite again?
It was given, not by me, by another doctor in the Center, Natrum muriaticum 200.
And she comes 7 months later to say that she was doing very well
but she has family problems.
She has problems with her brothers and sisters that they want to take away
from her property or something like that.
She has a lot of irritability, sighing she says, she has developed fear of accident,
she is afraid to travel that maybe she will have an accident
and she cannot tolerate closed places, fear of accidents underlined 3 times.
I feel bitterness and ranged from the behavior of my brother, I have flushes of heat,
dullness in the head and confusion.
I have constriction in the throat and sighing, she does not want consolation, not in a hurry.
She has changed her house to another location where she does not have any more these relatives
coming so much in her house. So she cannot tell about that.
2-3 times the last 6 months she had severe headaches in the whole head.
When she has the headache, she has to remain immovable,
otherwise the least movement makes her worse.
She is worse jarring 3 times, the headache is better with vomiting, desire sweets twice.
The doctor has not counteracted the therapy by drugs.
Here what are you going to do?
She is very much irritable underlined 3 times, shouts, she has again the dullness in the head
with the flushes of heat, she has great fear of accidents,
she is afraid to travel and she cannot tolerate closed places.
She had 3 big crisis of headache, this is the symptomatology for which she is coming.
The flushes, the heat, the headache, the dullness in the head,
she has developed the fear of accidents and closed places.
You have to evaluate our previous prescription and what is happening.
What is happening at the moment with the patient?
She was under stress quite a lot because of her brothers who wanted to take her property
by some hereditary trick...Things like that are very stressful.
You cannot say in a case like that, when they say I have been well
and later on I have relapsed, you cannot say that.
Because what the patient says I'm very well and is under stress, it is a kind of relapse.
Not total perhaps but a kind of relapse.
She says I was doing very well .
What is interesting here?
Fear of accident is a symptom of Aconite.
Because causative factor is different, what we are mostly concerned is about the picture,
of the new picture that we have now.
What remedy covers that new picture most complete?
We have certain symptomatology of the past coming back, the dullness, the flushings,
the dullness of the head and also we have the claustrophobia.
The claustrophobia was there and the dullness in the head was there
and the flushing was there.
Now we have the appearance of a new symptom. The fear of action.
Did we have it in the beginning?
-No.
-So we have the appearance of a new symptom, which is one of characteristics of Aconite.
So we have a kind of relapse with a new symptom, which again points to Aconite,
in spite of the fact that the causative factor is now different.
The picture that is developing is again Aconite definitely because of this new symptom
which is confirmed.
For me what we're thinking is right, yes Aconite because we have that new symptom
which confirmed. What I'm interested is why this is happening?
We have given Aconite and she did very well.
Then we gave Nat mur, she did well and then she relapsed into a state of Aconite,
not into a state of Nat mur. This is my question.
I would ask myself in case I had left this case without Nat mur,
would have been perhaps the same?
Because Nat mur is a deeper remedy. That means we gave Aconite, it acted.
It took away one layer. Then we gave Nat mur it has acted. It took away one layer.
Then the most natural thing, when we have a relapse, is to come back to the Nat mur state.
If Nat mur was the underlined remedy really, it should have come back as Nat mur state,
not as Aconite state. If it had acted.
That is one of the reason why I say Nat mur,
either was indicated very superficial or not at all in that time in history for that person.
Could we have said that because of some grief it was an imprinted picture of Nat mur?
We could have said. So Nat mur is a deeper remedy
and we have to be careful how we prescribe it.
Here I don't believe that this is the case. Maybe it was some grief? No.
Most probably I reason out that Nat mur did nothing, the case would have continue to go
well and then under stress, relapsed into a state of Aconite.
My reason is that Nat mur at that moment that it was given did nothing, did not disrupt the case
and when she was under stress, we had back the Aconite state.
Aconite 50M was given again and she remained well for a year almost.
Eventually Ignatia was given to that person on '82.
It was good result and it was repeated again Ignatia in 1983 and in the beginning of 1983
it was repeated Ignatia and she has not come back since that time.
That means it was an Aconite, relapsed to Aconite state, then grief, Ignatia,
imprinted state of Ignatia, Ignatia was given, again more grief, again Ignatia it was imprinted,
then we give Ignatia and she continues in a good state.
Still we do not have the under Aconite. I believe that under Aconite,
it might have been Sulphur.
But still we have to see when she comes back perhaps after 2-3 years that we may be able
to assess Sulphur and we give it and then we make that person progress more.