-Yes.
-A long trip.
-Which country?
-All over India...
-Did you have sexual partners there?
-Not in what the school medicine tends to say is the risk of getting infected,
not that kind of sex.
So I think I must have been infected in Paris or in Barcelona,
I was in a weekend trip in Barcelona or in Copenhagen.
Because now we know the high numbers of infected in these places compared to Oslo.
-Oslo has a low rate still?
-Still yes.
-You had warts in the genitalia or in the rectum area?
-Yes I had once. I think I had once before 73, I mean 76. I'm very bad at years, sorry.
-About 75-76?
-It must be 78.
-You contracted warts?
-Yes.
-And what you did about it? You went to the doctor?
-I went to the doctor, it's not in the record. This time it was also in the anus
and it was penicillin or something on.
-And then it disappeared?
-Yes.
It was some acid thing, so it just went away very efficient.
It had to be efficient because I was going to Asia the week after, so I remember it very well.
So he is HIV positive since many years perhaps.
When he had smear 4-5 years ago because already it's 2 years
and they say we took smear 4 years ago, that means 6 years from today,
they found antibodies in the blood.
Therefore it is quite a long time which is going on.
-My homeopath in Oslo she asked me the same question.
I said I had warts maybe 10-15 years ago, I had one here and now I noticed it has returned.
-After the homeopathic treatment she gave you, you feel better?
-In fact I don't feel so bad, I didn't feel bad before. Physically I'm quite well,
maybe I'm becoming what you call when you think you have many diseases
because mentally I was stuck.
So now I look for symptoms all over and maybe they are false many times.
-The swelling on the glands went away after the medicine?
-They come and go.
-For yourself you feel strong, you have enough energy? You don't feel tired?
-Sometimes I feel tired when I feel down.
After I've taken the pills she gave me I had 20 hours sleep, so I was wondering that maybe
it was the medicine but after that I had not felt much change,
I had felt a sudden itching in the back of my foot.
So which is the symptom that he had described?
Anxiety about health.
He says I have become one of those who think all the time about diseases
and says my psyche is affected and when I feel down, I feel exhausted.
-So it was two times that you took antibiotics and one time that you took for the proctitis.
What other time you remember you took antibiotics?
-Penicillin it was.
-When?
-This time we are talking about.
I don't remember but I can not say no.
First of all I have a bad memory, second my parents are dead, I can't ask them
but at least it must be long ago.
-Do you have brothers, sisters?
-I have one sister, one brother.
-They are also gay?
-No. Not that I know.
-Is it possible that you don't know? They know about you.
You don't keep it secret.
-No.
-Can you describe yourself a little bit, can you describe your character?
-It's difficult. I was thinking very hard when I was sitting outside waiting.
I know this is important to be very honest about myself.
Today there were three things very abnormal about me. First I woke up early, I never do.
Second I had a big breakfast with eggs and third, I never eat breakfast
and third I was in time here, I'm out of time.
So first that. That describes me a little. I'm never that late, I'm 10 min late always,
I'm always very active, in a hurry when I need to do things and when I don't do things
I just sit back and am very apathetic, I can sit for hours like that.
-You like to sit for hours?
-I don'n like it but I'm not able to do anything else. I feel very bad if I sit too long,
all the things I should have done?
-What do you do? What is your profession? Your studies?
-I don't have a steady job for more than two years in my life.
I suppose it's right to say that I'm a very changeable person, I'm an adventurer,
I want to try many things. Last years have been the more steady in my life.
Right now I work in a restaurant and in the local radio station.
I have been working as a sonalist a part of my life but not very serious,
I don't have the education.
All kinds of job I can get to get money to travel, that's what I have done.
-Why you turned to homosexuality? What is your justification for that? What happened?
It was a traumatic experience before or?
-No, I was to get married. I had a very good relationship with a girl before but I think homosexuality
or bisexuality is something which has been in my body since my birth.
-When did you realize first that you were homosexual?
-As soon as I had sexual experiences but of course one tends to think
that the normal thing is to have girls and that's what you do and then suddenly I find out that
they want me to do what you really desire for.
That's reality when I was 24, it's very un normally late, I know.
-But before you were able to have a bi-sexual relationship
and enjoy a relationship with a woman?
-Oh yes, no problem.
-But it was more enjoyable for you to go with homosexual. You are bi-sexual now?
-No. I haven't tried that heterosexual for 6-7 years and that was just for fun.
-It was for fun to have heterosexual?
-I have no desire for that.
-You lost your parents?
-I was 15 when I lost my mother and my father he died four years ago.
-Do you have any peculiarities about yourself? Something that you have about your health
that seems peculiar? Any fears, any kind of symptoms?
-Phobias. I was afraid of water for years and this was due to the fact that I didn't know how to swim.
I was scared to go into the water because I didn't know to swim.
I learned to swim three years ago. So I went to courses. Now I feel more safe about the water,
I don't know if I can call it a phobia any longer but of course if I jump into deep waters,
I couldn't do that from a boat. Not still.
-Any other fear? Fear of the dark, fear of being alone, fear of being rejected, fear of thunderstorms,
fear of animals, any kind of fear or anxiety?
-I have fear of loneliness.
-By old age, you are becoming older?
-No, being lonely now.
-So you like company?
-Yes.
-Do you like company all the time or sometimes?
-I think it's OK with loneliness in a room, when I'm alone but to be in a crowd and feel lonely there,
it is terrible. To be lonely among many people it is awful.
Like last night I went to the discotheque, I didn't know anyone because I was alone
and first of all the noise was very strong and I couldn't talk to anyone if I wanted
but not to be able to speak to anyone and the only way of approaching people
was of having sex with somebody and I wouldn't mind of course
but it made me feel very bad in the crowd. I felt very lonely. This is the fear.
I was very fearful before I left.
By describing this way of sexual contact what it portrays? What it shows?
Homosexual people, as he said himself, in America for instance they've told me that
there are people who had 1.000 sexual partners the year.
It seems that activity in homosexuality is different than activity in heterosexuality.
It's much more intense. When he says I had only 10 partners, he really means
he is not sexual active at all.
What do you believe? If this was a case of Platina for instance, a case of Lachesis,
a case of Hyoscyamus, a case of Medorrhinum, a case of Origanum would he say that story?
He went to a pub and he felt lonely there, alone within the crowd, he could not establish
contact and therefore he did not want to have sex.
Therefore he is somebody who has to establish contact on a deeper level
than just the physical contact and in homosexuality we do have that phenomenon.
I've talking with an epidemiologist in Berkley and he said he was on the AIDS hospital
and they were trying to trace somebody who was AIDS positive and very progressed,
they were asking him to try and trace all the people he came in contact with
because they wanted to examine all those people and find out what took place.
So the answer he had received, the doctor, was what do you mean? How can I know the partners?
I know them from the waist downwards, I never saw the face. You see the idea?
In homosexuality there is that kind of strong urge for physical sexual contact.
So when he says I went to the pub and I could not establish contact,
I had either to establish contact or no sex, that means a person who has to establish contact,
he has to keep the proportions.
-He said he got himself ready to go to Asia...
Yes but he said also that he did not have sex in the medical way,
that is to transmit the disease which shows also that there was a kind of blockage
towards complete sexual contact.
Also he said that he did not have a lot of partners.
If you remember the answer, sex there was something going on. That's the idea.
But not this wild sexual activity which we see usually with the male homosexual.
Therefore we have to consider that his remedy is not a wild sexual remedy
but rather a remedy with some sensitivity that needs contact and romantic element.
Romantic element should be there.
-I was very fearful before I left because I knew this would happen.
It is the price I have to pay for travelling alone because I travel alone.
-That is something that you know about yourself that you always like to be with somebody
or you don't want the same partner all the time, you want to change?
-I like to be alone too, as I said, I sit alone and I get apathetic and I don't want anyone
to disturb my apathy. I can be there for hours but being with others is terrible to be alone.
I don't know if you are interested in astrology but I'm a fish.
Everybody tells me that I'm a typical fish, I want to be alone and I don't want to be alone.
It doesn't help you much.
I think it's very hard to answer some of these questions.
-Do you have any fear of heights? Looking from high places?
-No. Very high up like on a bridge and looking down, I tend to feel like wanting to jump.
-Always?
-Yes, it's very strange the feeling like something is pulling me, wanting to jump.
-Do you get depression sometimes?
-Yes.
-What happens then when you are depressed? What are your thoughts?
-When I get depressed I feel that nobody likes me because I'm peculiar, I'm not easy.
-In a relationship you have lived with a man together for a period of time and it was difficult?
You found that you were difficult for the other person?
-Yes on the one hand but I always tend to find persons who are difficult themselves,
so it's just been very difficult.
-But why you found yourself being difficult, what was the point that you found it is difficult?
I'm irritable of I'm very little tolerant? What are the points about yourself?
-I'm a moralist in a sense that I want things to be...it's difficult.
-You say whatever you feel. You are a moralist which means?
-If people say something to me and if they change their mind after an hour, I get furious.
-And if you get furious what you do? You show this anger or you keep it inside?
-No I argue. Why you are like this, why you are like that?
-You think you are very impulsive?
-Yes I do speak when I have something on my mind.
-Very soon before you even think about it, it comes out?
-Yes I suppose so. Especially when I'm annoyed.
I have been moralist in my way. If people are not acting or talking what appears
to my political view, then I get furious, I'm not easy to be with.
-Do you consider yourself of being fanatical by your political views?
-I don't but I'm sure that others do.
Again the same element.
I put certain questions to him, thinking of certain remedies and he comes out with answers
which indicate another remedy.
I say do you have any fear of high places, he says not exactly.
I have sometimes when I go to high places, I want to jump. Then I put a question to confirm Aurum,
is he an Aurum case?
And what he says is yes he is depressed but he brings on the morals again,
the morality and what he means by his morality. Most probably his morality is quite different
than the morality of other people.
But he says eventually if somebody is not according to what I believe then I get furious,
which shows an extremist again. Either you believe what I say or I get furious.
-An extremist?
-Yes.
-Anarchist, what they call?
-I don't call anything but I'm of course what others would say anarchist or socialist.
-And you get furious if somebody contradicts you and says you are wrong, it's not like that,
it's like that, then you get furious.
-No, it's the other way around. If somebody is saying I think it should be like this
and I think that is injustice, I think that's wrong, that' s terrible, then I get furious and I tend to...
Even in a little chat in a cafe I get very engaged, instead of talking about the coffee,
if somebody says that the coffee it should be very cheap, it is too expensive,
then I start to think who is picking this coffee.
And then the whole political thing tends to come up.
You see again the same pattern? Who is picking this coffee?
The people who are picking this coffee are very poor people and there injustice to them
because who makes the money?
Those people who transport the coffee and blah, blah, and then he becomes very engaged to that,
he is very intense. It is an injustice, I'm telling you.
This is the idea with that remedy and you will see it again and again and again.
What other common symptoms we have seen with the other case?
He also is a moralist, he wants to work for...
It doesn't matter what he is trying to do, the remedy will be lead to do something for humanity.
He may join a political party, he says the others may call me an anarchist or a socialist.
I don't call myself an anarchist, I'm right. This is the idea.
What I see is right, I see injustice, there is injustice. Of course there is injustice
but he ever asked himself whether he is a perfect human being himself?
So why he expects perfection from others?
But this is the point where Causticum can not stand.
You made this wrong. This is wrong.
If you tell him this is wrong, he gets very furious.
What he sees is injustice and that is the peculiarity of the remedy and that is what
we are interested to see and to find out.
It comes out the story, it comes out by itself. You don't even have to question.
I see some people are very tired, you need an interval, a coffee break.
I want to ask do you see similarities between the first case of Causticum and this case?
I see some puzzling faces. Where is the similarity?
-Emphasis on injustice.
-They are open minded.
-Intensity.
-Within their own sexual sphere they are more conservative than other medicines.
-The desire for company but yet fear of being alone.
Causticum is one of the main remedies fear of being alone, especially in the night.
They want company but at the same time they want to keep on their own.
Where Phosphorus definitely wants company all the time.
Causticum want their own time, to be alone as well. Not all the time with company,
not all the time with people. Causticum do not need to hold the hand of somebody all the time.
Phosphorus needs to hold somebody, to have company all the time.
They are a kind of extremists, not only anarchists, it can not be only but extremists,
living in the extremes, going towards the extremes.
I dedicated myself completely into this group, this is the idea.
They dedicated themselves to the socialist group, this is right
and I followed it with all my intensity. I'm telling you this is right. This is the idea.
If you recognize these elements, you will be able to recognize the remedies. That's it.
It's so difficult, now what he says. He has the sub maxillary gland swollen.
And he has anxiety about his health and some fear of death of course.
But with these three points you can find the correct remedy?
Never, no matter how much you try. You will never find the remedy
but here is a man who is candidate. Maybe we can save him, I don't know yet.
We'll see what happens and it will depend on him also.
Whether he will go again and again and get contraction again and get infected again etc.
But how can you find his remedy, unless you know the picture. This is my argument.
Sometimes you base your prescription only on pathology.
Base your prescription on pathology and you have no solution.
Give us a little bit more of this information.
-Difficult person to have a relaxed moment with because...
-Your political views are concerning injustice.
What affects you mostly is the element of injustice?
-Yes because there is so much, it is enough to pick up and it's going on for years.
-If you see somebody in the street who is suffering with head disease
and he is in pain which is not injustice but that will affect you?
His pain will affect you or it's only injustice that will affect you?
-I've been to India and I've seen thousands laying on the streets down but what can I do?
It makes me sad but...
I went to India with a camera to take pictures but I couldn't' take the pictures.
-Why?
-Because I felt like watching.
Why?
He saw himself looking upon something with a camera while at the same time
the suffering was so obvious, so intense and most probably he must have said, what am I doing?
To show pictures about this but now what is happening here is terrible.
People are dying from hunger etc. These must have been the thoughts of a Causticum.
-It was still even more. Instead, I took pictures of the flowers.
I think it's quite hopeless sometimes.
Of course it is injustice, I can walk out here and I can point some injustice on the street
but what can I do?
Of course I can be criticized for not being politically active, not going into a political party
or into organizing demonstrations and things.
-You can be criticized by whom?
-By others who do that.
But then I tend to think that my task is like a Christian to go around in my small environment
to speak about injustice and to try to change things at my job and
the situation there and to do the best kind of work as a sonalist pointing out what is good
and what is bad. I try to work in my way.
I'm not saying that I'm a just person, of course not. Personally I can be very unjust but I'm
talking about the political view.
-Do you like sweets very much?
-Yes I do.
-Very much?
-Maybe.
-More salt or sweets?
-It doesn't show but I tend to eat a lot, small eating whether it's potato chips or chocolates,
whatever I have I will eat it. I'm not sure but if I go into a shop I buy sweets.
If I'm going to have a dinner I like salt and I put too much salt on the meat.
-To all the food you put extra salt?
-Yes I work in the kitchen in the restaurant and the others are saying I put too much salt always.
So I suppose so.
-What is the main problem now with your health? How you feel it?
-It's my social status.
-You mean because you have been diagnosed that you can not have the contacts
that you would like to have?
-No, this is part of the fear of loneliness because now when I'm infected I have to be,
my first thought is I can not have sexual life. If you have no sexual life, you have no relationship.
Of course I have friends but it's not the same.
Now the fear is what the dream of life is to have a sweet heart, someone to love
and my first thought was that it was not longer possible.
The rest of my life will just be waiting for the decease 1 year, 2 years, 7 years.
And I was very afraid to end up in deep depression because I have the talent for depression.
So my reaction was to be over active in what I do and what I did to do more work in the radio,
to live as actively as possible, meet my friends, go out, have dinners,
talk not to be lonely, not to feel this. My fear of loneliness is my biggest problem.
When you are depressed I suppose you get less strong, defending myself from other diseases.
This kind of thinking.
So I want to stay and try to find this knowledge but I will get sick sooner or later,
at least the school medicine tells me.
-Yes.
-This is mental.
-You seem to be sighing frequently. You do this.
-Maybe.
-You don't realize it?
-Now? Much?
-Now as you talk. Do you like fruits?
-Yes.
-You eat a lot? Mostly what you eat?
-Mostly oranges or bananas.
-Other fruits?
-Any fruit.
-What about perspiration? You perspire a lot?
-Yes.
-Where mostly?
-In fact it's been a problem for me through my life.
-Because it smells?
-Not that but as soon as I go into do something which is a bit difficult
or asked something for me, I get nervous, this is the way of expressing my nervousness
and often I do things that are not part of me, things that I'm not sure that I will manage
but I want to do them anyway.
-How is your sleep now? Do you sleep bad?
-Ups and downs too because one of the symptoms as the school medicine says is
that you get night sweats  and I did in the beginning but it's like putting all of myself
and in the middle of the night I wake up and I'm sweating.
Sometimes I sleep very well.
-After the remedy you had been sleeping better than before?
-The weekend after I was a kind of exhausted also because I've been over active before that.
So I slept for hours and hours and I slept like dead for 2 days.
-Yes but after that your sleep became better in general
or it remained the same pattern as before?
-I think it was the same as before.
-You don't want to get up in the morning?
-No, I have this morning fear.
-Do you mean that you fear to get up or you fear life because a new day starts?
-It's facing the new day and I'm a person who tends to have many tasks for the day
which should have been done the day before or the day before. It's the first thought in my mind.
I should have done this.
-And that makes you irritable? It makes you what?
-Instead of getting up and do it, it makes me turn and sleep again
even though I have no sleep left in my body.
I'm able to sleep a little more, I sleep until my headaches is catching me.
-Do you physically fight ever when you come into conflict?
-Maybe 2-3 times in my life.
-Do you feel there is a lot of anger inside you?
-Not anger, I never feel like physically fighting with someone but I have this kind of anger,
which we talked about. About life in general, situations...
-Have you ever been near the sea or swimming in the sea or you swim in the lakes?
-I swim in the sea yes.
-Where?
-In Oslo but I only swim where I know the bottom is under me.
I'm still working on this fear, so my aim is to be able to swim everywhere.
-Have you noticed when you swim in the sea whether it affects your health?
That means you feel better or worse to swim in the sea?
-I can't answer because it is so few times, when I train swimming I do it in the pool.
I went to the courses to learn swimming, it was in the pool.
So the swimming in the sea or the lakes has been so few times that I can't answer.
But I like the salt in the water, I mean I like to taste or the skin after being...
-Yes but you like salt in general, in the food also.
-And somehow of course it feels fresher, when I think about it.
It's more fresh the water in the sea because there is waves and in small lakes the water is still...
Especially in pools it's a lot of chemicals, so I suppose maybe I like the salt water better.
-Is any time in the day or night when you feel better or worse?
-I feel very well at night, the evening. If I'm going to do something very efficient,
writing or preparing something mental I work best at midnight, after midnight.
Particularly I'm not disturbed, nothing disturbs me.
At night there is nothing I could have done. I could have called this person,
I could have gone to this office, at night there is no shops to visit, at night there is only me.
-But this feeling better starts really after midnight or even before midnight,
after the sunset? While the darkness comes you start feeling better?
-Maybe it's more correct to say that I feel better once I have over runned today
and this is after I stopped doing things.
From then I feel OK because then I'm active and pushing back these other things.
I'm more relaxed after midnight, I'm more able to think clearly, to concentrate.
-You never had any urithritis?
-What is this?
-It is discharge from the urethra. You know what is the urethra?
-No.
-Urinate?
-Yes.
-You had any problems from the urethra?
-Never.
-Do you have another case?
Why do I put all these questions? For what remedy?
-Medorrhinum.
-Medorrhinum very good. Who wants to give Medorrhinum?
-Many fears and he spent a long time with Phosphorus but now he has this with injustice
and I'm confused, how...[]  It's very strong this injustice.
-Did it work Phosphorus? Phosphorus can help? Yes it can.
-How strong is the Causticum and Phosphoric?
-Here we see another element of Causticum in which he is revolving
and it's the element of being left alone.
We know that this element is in Causticum and also it is in Phosphorus.
The way he is presenting that element it is not the desire to have company.
This is to have company because he is afraid he is going to die
and therefore he wants to have some company.
Causticum is afraid to die but the company is not to prevent the fear.
It is rather for the sake of not feeling in contact. Causticum needs to be in contact at that stage.
There is Causticum that progresses very much and paralyses the emotions
and he goes into apathy states but at that phase he needs the contact.
The idea that he may remain alone is unbearable.
Now here we get symptoms of Medorrhinum. For those who know Medorrhinum.
And the question is whether you will give Medorrhinum or you will give Causticum
and if you have to decide what is the decisive factor in favor of one and not the other?
Because we have amelioration in the night which is more prominent for Medorrhinum than
Causticum, we have a desire for sweets which is more prominent for Medorrhinum
than Causticum, we have desire for salt which is prominent for both,
desire for oranges which is in favor of Medorrhinum.
Maybe we discover that Causticum has also desire for oranges.
We don't know. Don't take these things for absolute.
There is only 3 remedies which have desire for oranges, maybe there are 13 remedies
and we don't know them yet.
But with what we know we have certain things which are in favor of Medorrhinum
and not of Causticum. What is going to be the decisive factor?
-His main complain.
-His mental state which is his main complain.
-What is the mental state?
You see more injustice, more what we call can not tolerate injustice,
which is in favor of Causticum than Medorrhinum?
Medorrhinum is not concerned for injustice but what is the decisive factor?
-Sexual wildness of Medorrhinum.
-This is what will hold you back from giving a Medorrhinum in a homosexual case.
You will have to have much more physical activity with Medorrhinum; they can not control,
the hormonal system is too strong, they can not control it so much as they can Causticums
which they need romantic involvement as well.
Because if you vacillate between the two remedies, it's going to be a decisive factor.
He says that because I will judge him he does not dare to say he has more partners.
No, he said himself that he was sitting outside thinking that he should tell me all the truth
in order to help him.
This is a desperate case, the man thinks, believes that he is going to die
and he will say it eventually, I'm going to die.
He will be ashamed to say I had 50 partners or 200? I asked this same question in
America and he said I'm going steady with my relationship.
I said can you tell me how many?
He said I can't tell you how many partners in a year. I said more or less, it's 5, 50 or 200?
He says more or less 300 partners a year and this is going steady.
He got Medorrhinum, he is going steady that means he was not as promiscuous
as he might have been.
You see here they don't have problems to speak out.
I don't think we should stick there.
When he tries to say a lie which he was not sure, you could see it very clearly.
Then I asked him did you take the antibiotics because you were going...
All this laughing, you could see he was going to tell a lie, not exactly a lie
but he knew in a deeper level why he was taking the antibiotics.
When somebody tells a lie it's obvious.
-Doubt of fear?
It's not, he is intense. He said all my talking concerns injustice and I see injustice in everything.
When I go out I will see an injustice taking place immediately. He calls that morality.
This is his morality. It is a kind of perception of the world under a remedy.
That's how they perceive the world.
It's another kind of Medorrhinum all together. When we spoke about Medorrhinum
yes you are right, we spoke about two types of Medorrhinum.
The one who is a monk and the other who is promiscuous; either they will go to be a monk
or a promiscuous. Here we don't have the idea of a monk to have the withheld sexual activity
which goes onto emotionality and to great intensity in emotionality.
Very common?
I had 10 people in the video, 10 Norwegians and he is the only one who spoke about injustice.
Why the others didn't bring up the subject?
And this subject has been brought up also during the first consultation he has.
He calls his own morality, he has a specific way for morality, a specific idea of
what is moral and what is immoral.
He is an extremist and he says the others call him an anarchist or a socialist.
I didn't hear these things from the other Norwegians and I had at least 10 cases on video.
Why didn't I hear that from the others?
-What about Agnus castus?
-Not at all.
-As a secondary remedy would you consider Calcarea phosphorica?
-No, I would consider Medorrhinum as a second possibility.
What is the main symptomatology? He has very little physical symptomatology.
Except of the glands which are swollen, there is nothing more and perhaps he feels tired
from time to time, there is not much physical. What is the mental symptomatology?
It's the anxiety. All the time my mind is there I'm going to die. There is an anxiety.
There is fear of dying, fear of death and a feeling of loneliness.
Why we say the person has a fear of loneliness?
If you are able on that respect to establish contacts etc. the fear normally goes away.
When you are sick it doesn't matter whether objectively you are going to die or not.
You still may think I'm going to die.
Argentum nitricum will think I'm going to die, Aconite will think I'm going to die,
in 2-3 months I'm going to die. Never mind whether it is an objective or not situation.
Each one projects the way and don't try to classify everybody into the same pattern completely.
The ideas are there.
One person is born strong, the other is born weak, one person is born in an environment
where he was made strong, the other was born in a protective environment
where he was made weak, weak socially, weak professionally. These do not tell about their disease.
The disease comes and takes the environment and uses the environment.
It says what environment? Very protective. The symptomatology will take such turn.
Another one is an environment very aggressive. The disease will take an aggressive turn.
An aggressive Causticum, a very mild Causticum...
When it's very mild the Causticum, you will see talking about injustice only.
Where somebody else who has lived in a more aggressive environment,
the symptomatology will become much more aggressive.
Let us take an individual who is Natrum sulphuricum or who is Dulcamara
and this person is born in an environment which is in a nice climate, very good climate,
dry, not at all humid he will have some pains.
A Dulcamara who lives there, I have some pains here and I have some pains there.
Take the same Dulcamara and put him in an environment which is very wet, will say pains!
It is the environment which produces the intensity, the challenge in life which you receive,
the stimulations which you receive in life will show the intensity.
A Causticum who is born on an environment that was really very unjust,
he will become an anarchist, he will take a bomb and throw it, finished.
There is no limit, it's too much.
It doesn't mean that every Causticum takes a bomb; if I gave you that impression it is wrong.
It is stages, I talk about stages and stages.
A person who is born in an environment in Norway is a very just country.
Most of the population are living in a quite high standard, there are no people
who are very poor and very rich and there is real injustice like in India
and others undeveloped countries.
Living in such an environment you will not have the stimulation for this.
Even in the most just system a Causticum will find a way to complain about injustice.
That's it. Even the most just that you can imagine, the Causticum will say this is wrong.
That is the idea, he may say it in a polite way, I think this is wrong and still it is a  Causticum
because the environment is very polite.
Like here in Greece very polite, you don't fight, they don't show you real emotions
which come from the deepest part, it's very nice, polite.
It is the stimulation of the environment, what it does.
You don't think I criticize only the other countries, I'm not a chauvinist.
I think I see objectively quite a lot, not everything but...
That is why I say this is still a case of Causticum.
You will tell me in Norway you will not find somebody who is more aggressive than him?
Yes but search his environment. And you will find the stimulation which is much stronger.
How the symptoms appear? Through stimulation only.
You get a Stramonium child. The stimulation is important, how much, what kind etc.
I usually do not theorize. Of course if I see somebody is telling me lies,
I will say he is telling lies but I do not see this man telling lies apart from one point.
All the other things he said I accept. I do not see reasons why?
Can you tell me what he is doing now?
First of all if somebody is telling a lie, shall I tell you what he does?
He will not look at you. If he says a lie, he is going to say the most sophisticated lie,
it's going to be like that, no I don't think so. This you can trust.
But if he looks in your eyes and says no I don't think so...
Tricks like that and you understand. Otherwise you doubt anything, you theorize anything under the air.
Anything can be said and can be theorized and it is the opposite of what he said.
Where do you end with that?
-Yesterday you said people Causticum desire sweets.
-No, this I don't consider desire for sweets, it is normal.
It doesn't go over the normal to consider it as a desire.
What I consider desire for sweets is really what he talks about salt.
Then there is real desire for sweets.
There are some Causticum that will tell you desire for sweets and they mention it strongly,
even more than salt, then I consider it as a desire.
In this case I will write it down perhaps but not even one underline.
Yes of course. Of course there is a follow up. There are several follow ups of one year.
So you will see what happens in one year, he is still alive once we have the follow up.
Causticum 1M. In the next interview you will hear it.
Don't expect me to remember anything. This was a case one year ago.
-We discussed this case with your practitioner, I advised her
but I feel that you should be checking yourself more regularly if you take that treatment,
it should be a kind of check-up to see whether there is any changes.
-You mean to see the changes in the blood?
-Yes to see if there is any real change objectively.
It is the end of the tape.
Why do you think that she got up and said can you open the window?
And why did she go to open the window?
These things if you don't take into consideration, what are you going to take?
She was bothered the most and some others also did bother but they did not get up.
She was bothered the most and at the same time she did not have much timidity.
So you find a remedy which is sociable and is bothered by heat.
We have two symptoms already for her.
So when she comes to me and says I have that symptom, I say take that remedy
because I have observed that.
I have observed the other one who is also there with the blue, she is also suffering.
True?
-Very much.
-How much?
That is another type, do you see how difficult it was for her to say it to the class?
It's not the same yes. That means she is another type who is suffering from the heat
but she is closed up.
This is what I want you to develop, power of observation and don't make stories.
She is suffering, she doesn't talk whether the other one extrovert, got up and opened the window.
Another remedy.
-There was another story after the interview. He was very angry about the interview.
-Why?
-I wanted to show you the point where he feels that he has not completed the interview.
He was very angry, he didn't want to take the remedy, he was not happy with the interview
because most probably he was not allowed to say everything that he wanted to say
and he had a strong reaction. Maybe he will say that, now we will see.
-Not made a complete report yet because there is no reason for making any report on this level.
There is no result.
I have just given a short report about the general, what you asked about and that's it.
-OK great. I saw you last time in London, when it was? When did you take the medicine?
-I don't remember exactly, it was the first days in June.