-What is the problem?
-They told me that I've got multiple sclerosis.
-Who told you?
-At the hospital in Birmingham 14 days ago.
-Do you have a kind of written report?
-No.
-That was verbally?
-Yes it was verbally because it was one person, they told me that I could expect it.
They weren't quite sure.
-Because you are too old for multiple sclerosis almost.
-They expect that I had it for 10 years at least.
Now it started with a different feeling here.
I asked these questions because he said he is 47 and usually the multiple sclerosis
starts at the age of 14,15,16. Even in 15 it's very unusual.
-You had a numbed feeling in the inner side of the thighs?
-Yes. Then I had prostatitis.
-By the first time you had this numbness how long it lasted?
-That was 10 years ago and I believe it lasted for 2-3 months and I believe it was
something to do with the prostatitis. But they said it had nothing to do with that.
-When it was the prostatitis?
-In 1976. It lasted 400 days, more than one year.
-One year and two months.
Here I don't know if you can see that he is dressed very untidy. The way he is dressed reminds me of Sulphur.
When he said that he took Sulphur drugs, I'm thinking now the way he dresses...
That means Sulphur in mother tincture has helped him but he has taken too much Sulphur.
Most probably we have either to take away the effect of Sulphur drugs or maybe to help him
with the condition because the way he is looking...
His clothes are quite untidy.
I was thinking a perfect Sulphur picture in television is in a play called the 'odd couple' have you seen that play?
If you see this play there is a man there which is typical what we describe as Sulphur,
it is called the 'odd couple'.
Stoop shouldered like that, his friend came and tidy the place, he did not like it,
he was so irritated, he started throwing things,
he was enjoying life, very extroverted.
Eventually when he orders some food, he says give me that fat, I want fat!
I said my god he is a perfect case of Sulphur.
It's very interesting if you want to see Sulphur, to see this movie.
-During that 10 year period you had not others?
-All the time.
I had difficulty to sleep, during sleeping and I was sweating every night...
Now I'm almost sure that because he says I have difficulties all these years, I'm a hypochondriac
and then he says I'm sleepless. Sulphur is one of the main remedies that are sleepless.
Sweating all night, sleeplessness and sweating, I said myself OK Sulphur but let us see.
-So all these years you were feeling awful, pains, sleeplessness, perspiration,
psychologically wise?
-Ups and downs, I have been happiest as well. I've got a son, it hasn't been that bad
10 years but...
-Health wise were bad.
-Yes but I haven't been away from my job.
-What is that you teach?
-Mathematics.
-What other symptoms do you have in general? Now do you have sleeplessness?
-Yes, I get a feeling even in the finger tips that my heart is pumping and in the toes,
the whole body.
It started now 1-2 months ago this palpitation.
-Do you feel the pulse all over the body and it is mostly in the fingers.
-Yes but it changes, sometimes in the fingers, sometimes in the toes, sometimes in the stomach.
-Where do you feel numbness?
-Numbness in here, in the gums.
-Do you have any difficulty in walking?
-No.
-Running?
-Not particularly, I have some difficulties down here if I'm tired.
-What exactly?
-I feel my feet are not strong enough if I'm tired.
Walking in the street sometimes I feel it, not now but I was in Spain for three weeks
and walking in the street I was aching in my legs.
-Other numbness in the face?
-Yes.
-Where?
-It started on the right side but now I got it in the left side as well?
-Is there any disturbance in your vision?
-Not now but I had the glasses last year.
-But do you have diplopia?
-Not at all, I have been very carefully tested and it is normal.
-Except these antibiotics and these Sulphur drugs that you take for long,
have you ever taken other drugs for long time?
-Sleeping pills.
-How much? Do you take one pill every day?
-Oh yes and some years ago I took some anti-depressive but not very much.
-Why?  That time you were going through a difficult period?
I do these questions to explore what happened
They have diagnosed multiple sclerosis and why? There must be some stimulus
to have such a serious disease. So I want to know from the pathology point of view.
To understand why this has developed.  I still do not question at all homeopathically.
To understand the development of the disease what happened historically.
Eventually later on I shall go to the homeopathic questions.
Before I understand how deep the disease is, how the pathology has developed
I will not go into homeopathic questions but already what do you observe in him?
I said from the beginning that this may be a Sulphur case.
Already now I have doubt. Why, can anybody tell me?
There is something in the character that does not give out Sulphur.
What is that element? Can anybody describe it?
That can be Sulphur.
-He is more modern.
-That's a good description, not so much extrovert, he is not coming out.
The extroversion of Sulphur even in the Norwegians will be prominent.
What do you observe in him?
'Yes' is more.
With Sulphur it is not so much 'yes'.What he thinks is right.
-What difficulties do you have? With the work, with your relatives?
-I was a student first time and then I had this
I was afraid that I can protrude my exam, I have perhaps been thinking too much.
That period I was a student, I was a happy man, outside.
I was around the whole Europe, tourist...
-During that period you had a lot of sexual activity also?
-Yes.
-Have you contracted any time any gonorrhea?
-No.
-Before that?
-No. Once I was afraid that I could have and he treated me as I had.
-Why you were afraid, because somebody else had the same?
-No.
You see this information? By this time I was drinking a lot, then drinking Sulphur again.
Sulphur desires alcohol. Sulphur is one of the main remedies that you see in the Repertory
desires wine, desires beer, likes to drink, Sulphur again.
Then he tells me I was a tourist guide.
Then I perceive that he would have contact with tourist girls and too much activity,
perhaps the gonorrhea, perhaps Medorrhinum.
Then I asked him did you have a lot of activity? He says yes. Did you contract gonorrhea? No.
Then he said I thought I had gonorrhea but anyhow he asked the doctor to give him
the treatment anyhow because he was afraid.
Now all this gives the information Sulphur maybe, Medorrhinum no.
Again another remedy which is what?
It has come before but I did not pay attention.
He says do I have gonorrhea? The doctor says no.
Then he is not satisfied and says why don't you treat me anyhow?
The doctor because he insisted, gave a series of antibiotics. That indicates a kind of anxiety.
Before what indicated that anxiety? What shows this anxiety?
-It shows insecurity.
-No. This he does not know.
What he says is during the last 10 years I was not feeling well all the time and I was
going to the doctors and they could not find anything wrong with me and eventually
I thought that I was hypochondriac, which is again an anxiety about health during these years.
So we got some hints now, not Medorrhinum, possibly Sulphur, let us see.
-Do you still have desire for alcoholic drinks?
-Now I don't think I have desire about. I don't drink now unless it is Saturday and we have
good dinner and a glass of wine but not very much. It's more a life style than a need.
Of course I have lived in Kenya about two years and amongst the people I was working
there they used to drink more beer, they don't use much wine.
Of course it helped me to sleep, once in a while is good to sleep but only one glass it
makes me awake.
-You stay awake?
-Yes. Because I don't drink every day.
What he said is also interesting that one glass will make him awake, one bottle will take him to sleep.
Wine gives energy, one glass of wine helps people with energy.
One bottle...
Why it is important? (?)
Why do I think that it is important what he says?
He is honest, he wants to be as much as possible accurate.
He could have hide the information, he does not hide the information.
What is again behind this idea, that he does not hide information?
-His anxiety.
-His anxiety to tell the truth (?) Therefore in spite of telling things that will not make him to look good,
he is honest.
In a consultation there is nothing that is left aside. Then eventually you may help him.
Otherwise you have information there and there.
-What other serious diseases you have gone through?
-I don't think I had any serious disease, I had pneumonia when I was a baby,
my mother told me and it was probably that occurrence from the lungs that went down
to the prostatitis. That infection.
-At what age?
-28.
-Then again or just once?
-I had it for a whole summer. It was very difficult because I wanted to go to the toilet all the time.
-And it went away and never appeared?
-Then I had a cure with Sulphur again. It was the first time I had it.
I think during that summer I had difficult period with Sulphur.
-At the age of 28 you had bladder infection and at what age did you have the prostatitis?
10 years later?
-Yes. But all that time in between I felt that it was something wrong with this system.
-With the genito - urinary system?
-Yes. I forgot to tell that...
What I'm thinking now is the fact of cystitis was the after effect of having some contact with gonorrhea
and then repeated the bladder and then prostate, then Sulphur, Sulphur, Sulphur drugs?
Then antibiotics and then the symptoms of multiple sclerosis?
This is what I'm thinking. Also what he said that it was a style the drinking, it was not a need.
This is not Sulphur. Sulphur has a need for drinking. It's the body that needs the alcohol.
Then he stops eventually. I doubt again the Sulphur.
You see all the story goes Sulphur, back to Medorrhinum, back to Sulphur, back to
Medorrhinum, back to Sulphur. I'm not ready for the Sulphur.
-I forgot to tell you...
You see something important. He didn't say something important.
Most probably he did not forget, he knows what he is talking about but he was kind of evaluating me,
should I say or should I not and then he decided to tell it.
-I forgot to tell that the (?) it's away now.
-You don't have erections?
-No, very little.
-Desire you have?
-Yes.
-Very strong?
-Not very strong.
Now it's a new learning in the case, he says he is impotent.
Then I remembered that he was saying that these pains and the numbness from right to left
then immediately I say to myself is it Lycopodium? Because Lycopodium is impotent
and the symptoms start from the right side and go to the left.
And hypochondriasis or the anxiety about his health. It starts putting things together.
-It has nothing to do with my wife because I checked that.
-The desire you say it's not very much but it is there?
-Yes, there is attraction.
-Did you have a lot of sexual activity before?
-Not a lot, I don't think so.
-When this potency went down?
Do you see what I'm asking actually is do you have a lot of activity?
And then because of hyperactivity in sexual sphere you have impotence?This is to confirm Lycopodium.
I didn't want to put two questions. You had a lot of activity, you had impotence?
I'm just giving the possibility to think and to answer.
Lycopodium can have a lot of activity which is not involving the emotional side,
it is just to satisfy the physical need and because of that eventually he becomes impotent
because potency comes when the whole person is overtaken by the feeling of affection, to give love.
If somebody does it on the physical level all the time, he is detaching in sex,
then sure impotency will come. Unless he is a very strong, earthly type person,
like the primitive type of person that we see in Africa.
-I don't think it started gradually but this winter I started to notice that it was something wrong.
If I'm thinking backwards perhaps it started earlier but now I noticed.
And I talked about it as well with my wife.
-Since last winter you've been taking more sleeping pills?
-Yes last winter I had been drinking more sleeping pills but last summer I had
sleeping pills as well.
I asked that because if somebody takes sleeping pills or barbiturates that calm down the system,
he may have, as side effect, impotency.
So when he says gradually, I did not have much activity, I'm not happy with Lycopodium situation here
but it is really Lycopodium based that impotency that has come after this (?)
-Now do you have to take a pill every night to sleep?
-No, I promised myself, last night I didn't take any and I slept for three hours.
-At what time?
-I went to bed at 11 or 10.30.
-And you slept until 3?
-Yes, I had long way to go. I had leaved from home at six o'clock this morning and 100 km...
-If you don't take a sleeping pill, you will not be able to fall asleep? That's the pattern?
Late falling asleep.
-Yes and I get very warm.
-Then restless? Warm and restless?
-Yes.
-Do you uncover then?
-Yes, many times.
-You uncover all your body or mostly your feet?
-No, all my body.
-Was it in previous years that you wanted your feet uncovered?
-No, always I've been cold on my feet.
You see again the way of Lycopodium? I tried to confirm (?)
Sulphur keeps his feet out of cover, it's very warm and sticks his feet out of cover.
This is very characteristic of Sulphur. So not being able to confirm Lycopodium,
this is a case of Sulphur again, back to Sulphur.
And I put a direct question do you stick your feet out of cover?
He says no, not only I don't stick my feet but I want my feet covered.
This is very seldom for a Sulphur case. You will see what follows.
-My feet have to be covered if I can rest.
-In order to rest they have to be covered, they have to be warm?
-Yes.
-But if you are warm, they are uncovered?
-Not only my feet.
-You keep special position in order to go to sleep?
-Yes that has changed. I used to be on my side but now I'm sleeping like this,
I don't know why and crossing my legs.
Which is the remedy that sleeps in this position?
Rhododendron.
Again there is no confirmation for Sulphur which sleeps mostly on the side.
Most they say I sleep in the side because if I sleep on my back, I get a nightmare.
That's a good symptom for Sulphur, that's why I put all these questions and I get an answer
of Rhododendron.
-In your back?
-Yes and that's the way I lie if I want to take a rest on the sofa.
-You are a person that generally is aggravated by warm weather?
-I like warm weather but the best years of my life I was in Kenya and last year I have been
twice in Spain.
-And you like this warm weather?
-Yes.
-I want to stay here, to buy a house but I didn't do it because I have still pain.
The pain has gone but I've been in warm weather.
Sulphur is a warm person, as you know, aggravated by warm.
And he tells I was best in Kenya. Best in Kenya? He goes to Spain to buy a house
because it is warm and he feels best in Kenya.
-Then I felt very sorry. I went home again.
-When you are in bed, then you become very warm and then you don't like the warm?
-Yes.
And sometimes if I fall asleep, I wake up wet all over because of perspiration
and particularly, if I take one glass of water or wine.
-The wine gives you headache or any other problems?
-No.
-Only this perspiration?
-Yes.
You see this big pause? Now what? We start all over again.
Putting things together again, I look again the case, I look my notes.
Now where are we going from here?
It's Sulphur, no Medorrhinum, no Sulphur, Medorrhinum, Lycopodium.
Why Lycopodium, maybe Sulphur again...This is a problem.
If you see his eyes really, he is not happy, he is not satisfied.
There is a look there, you feel the doubt.
-If the weather is cold and wet or warm and wet, you are affected?
-Yes if it is wet and cold, I don't feel comfortable and I like when it's very warm inside the house.
If I'm aching, I fill a bathroom with hot water, as hot as I can, and even more hot water,
to get warm.
Now I go completely to different remedies; cold and wet aggravates him and very warm
bath ameliorates him. Is it Rhus tox, Calcarea carbonica or Dulcamara, Rhododendron?
What it is? A new line opinion.
So far I've lost all this and we will have a chance finally but this is how
I feel at the moment. I do not know, I doubt.