This case it was between small remedies, remedies that are unknown.
No known remedy we had to differentiate about.
They were rather small remedies all of them.
In such case the differentiating point is going to be only one point which may be quite strong.
We had an aggravation from heat which had to be in the remedy.
Amelioration by cool. That was a strong symptom that was not only said in the case.
This man was after me every day in Alonissos.
He would come and say yesterday when I gave you the case I was feeling very good after all
but today... and he would cry.
Because it's too hot... A Pulsatilla kind but not Pulsatilla.
This element of heat was not possible for me to fit it so strongly to one of these remedies.
There is also some information about Secale before.
Otherwise your mind can not go but this is how the Materia Medica has developed.
And this is what I try to do, to show you.
There was an element also in him, which is common in Secale...
Do you remember the expression I used about his anxiety about health?
-Intensity.
-Yes.
There is an intensity in complaining about their health
but they will never say I have anxiety about health.
But they complain in such concern about themselves
that then this becomes a  characteristic symptom of the remedy.
Secale has an anxiety about health, which is not said like that. I'm afraid I have cancer.
But there is an intensity in stating the symptoms, which behind this intensity
you perceive the anxiety, while at the same time you see stagnation.
There is a very easy swelling of the legs, the legs are painfully burning
and many times they have to put a fan all night to cool down the feet.
The masturbation?
We can ask him.
What I think it will happen even without asking is the power  of control for masturbation
will be much greater. He will not give in to masturbation so easily.
I have seen this again and again and you will see it also in your practices.
When the hormones are leveled, the driving is not so strong and we know that from the Platinas
especially because after all sex is enjoyable.
When a Platina has desire for sex 6 times a day and enjoys that and you give a remedy
and it's only becoming once the day or once every 3 days, then she is very disturbed.
Platinas will not like to change that particular portion of their activities
but when you give it they will change and then they complain.
Never mind how much they want, the organism does not anymore demands that.
So there is a balance.
In this way, in his case it's going to be a balance. That was a kind of release for him.
There is an element which I have seen in at least 2 Secales,
there is an element of out of the reality element with a kind of naivety, in this case.
It's a boy of 13-14 years old.
Actually Peter was telling me that one of the reports he has sent me about him,
he was writing he is crying like 14 years old girl.
There is a kind of immaturity in this man.
In another case we'll see that as an element of idealism.
It is presented as an element of idealism.
I have to have ideal situations in order to... Idealism is quite prominent.
I can't do this, it's not right. This is not a symptom.
When somebody says I cannot do this, it's not right but this is the only thing
that will save his life or somebody else's life, then it's kuku.
This you have to do it, it's not so big.
No, I can't do it. That is pathology.
Pathology is not when somebody proposes to you to do something really immoral
and you say I cannot do it. This is natural, this is healthy.
-Do you think Lycopodium could be underline here?
-It can be.
But if you touch him now...
You say let's see if Lycopodium can improve him much more, we will destroy him.
I do not have the follow up after Gelsemium to show you how he became
and how he was totally destroyed by a remedy which was close.
When I did the original analysis of the case, I mentioned Gelsemium like I mention it here.
I can't remember by that time what I have mentioned.
Peter told me you mentioned Gelsemium and the practitioner preferred to give Gelsemium
than Secale because they did not understand Secale and also I said in the class
that I can not explain to you with the information that you have in hand.
So they gave him Gelsemium and they told him this is what George has said
which was not exactly the truth
because George also mentioned other remedies, Selenium, Mercurialis...
If you had seen the whole case, we did not go through the whole case originally I think.
There are more questions but sometimes they tell me you don't want to see the whole case
and it is better if we stop at a certain point.
You may see even in the very end differentiating the possibility
and asking questions for a remedy.
He cannot be Lachesis, why? Can anybody tell me?
He is not full of energy, Lachesis has a vital...
I would say the opposite of what he has in circulation.
Lachesis has a strong circulation and that's why we see high blood pressure with Lachesis,
there is a very vital circulation, which gives a lot of energy.
Here we have a stagnation of circulation which gives no energy at all.
What is their blocking we do not have the possibility.
Is that the arteries are closed, the circulation is disturbed?
It is the cerebrospinal fluid that may have created such a situation obstruct
and we do not have a flow of the cerebrospinal fluid? That is another possibility.
What happens in the encephalomyelitis cases? We don't know yet all the pathology.
That is why we are left here with the desire to cure the person and not to explain everything
which is taking place, it's not possible.
-What about Staphysagria?
-Staphysagria will not say I have no feelings at all. It is difficult to destroy her feelings.
There are feelings there in Staphysagria but suppressed and in spite of being suppressed
they are nice feelings.
They don't become feelings with spikes, Staphysagria has round feelings
that do not hurt others, like Pulsatilla.
There is going to come out one way or another, in mucus membranes, the skin...
-In the rubric coldness of head...
-Coldness of head, which is the well-known symptom of Carbo vegetabilis
when it's ready to pass out, when most probably the circulation has stopped
and it becomes cool.
There is slight perspiration. It's a disturbance on the circulatory system of...
while he is heated, suddenly the blood stops going to the head and there is a fainting.
This is coldness of forehead, this is another thing.
It's a peculiarity, I've never seen it again. If we find it 2-3 times,
we can add it to Secale symptomatology.
What is interesting to see is that type of anxiety and the feeling
that something terrible is going to happen.
In the other two cases it was a feeling as if they will go crazy.
It was not the description of this blockage; nothing goes out, nothing goes in.
It was a feeling as if they will go crazy but they will not say it.
They will hardly admit it to themselves but the intensity for
which they presented the symptomatology indicated an underline anxiety,
which if you enquire they will admit, they will say a few things about it.
-After all his last remedy was Mercurialis...
-It interfered for some time, he was not feeling well.
I think it interfered but not decisively, to spoil the case.
What it's interesting in this case it is this curve.
I have told you many times, there is a curve going up and then suddenly it goes down.
Then if you wait, you will see it coming up again and then suddenly it will go down
and it will go up and will go down and will go up.
That is the time when you go down that we have to be strong enough not to be misled
to prescribe another remedy.
That is the time where you need most of your reasoning and understanding of the Theory.
-Which other remedies belong to this family?
-I don't know. What is the family of Secale?
-Ustilago.
-Ustilago also has definitely action on the uterus and on the women genitalia.
-Sexual excitement?
-No.
-But you said that.
-No, I said similar with idealistic situation.
What I meant is that they need a kind of idealistic situation to express their sexual energies
and maybe they go to masturbation.
I don't see promiscuity, in order to express sexuality, they need an environment
which is idealistic.
But this does not exclude the possibility that they may be excited.
What we have to understand mostly and what is interesting it to understand
that the circulation...
The circulation is stagnated like we speak in Sepia.
Fantasy? Yes, strong fantasy but the element I have seen is that
these people will not talk about their sexual things, as he talked.
Maybe the sexual desire is strong but they need a condition, a circumstance
which is idealistic kind.
Like true love, like we meet and there is a strong romantic element
and then they may get involved.
Fantasy you mean by masturbation? I do not know. I cannot say at this moment.
But if the assumption is correct that the circulation is lower, it is not strong,
the functions are lower. There is no strong vital force and there is no sexual urge.
But you will say he is having a strong sexual urge. He is not.
For me it is a release of the condition.
It's like something which is going on is suddenly stagnated and you try to push it
somewhat to keep on going. The excitement of masturbation.
This is how I feel in this case is the masturbation.
It's not a real pleasure, desire to masturbate.
It's a kind of an excitement that has to have to get out of that stagnant situation.
Can you imagine if you enter this man, nothing comes in, nothing comes out.
It's a dead man.
The only thing he can be sure about that he is alive, is when he masturbates.
That's how I perceive it. He is a dead person.
When you are in a healthy situation, you are not living that situation and you are outside
and you are looking but just imagine that nothing will come in.
He says I have here a wall inside, nothing comes in, nothing goes out.
So he lives in a dead situation, he just walks but somewhere he feels
that is absolutely bad and he has to have an outlet.
He has to have a release of that constant sense of death which is inside him
and he masturbates. This is how I feel the masturbation.
It's not a strong urge to masturbate.
I'll tell you something else which I found through the remedy.
If the remedy has really strong sexual desire, they will go and have sex.
They cannot avoid it.
He had a girlfriend, everybody else was going with her except of him.
What is that? We have to understand the situation.
You say strong sexual desire but it is not strong sexual desire.
It is a hypotonic desire.
A person who has strong sexual desire, never mind what.
Forget the morals, forget the upbringing, forget the family situations,
he will go and have sex. Can you stop a Platina, a Lachesis, an Origanum, it's difficult.
Here why you are not impressed by the fact that even his uncle goes with the girl
and he cannot. What is this?
It is a desire which is not strong.
This is how I perceive the situation.
-What about Staphysagria in that concept?
-Staphysagria is stronger than the situation. Staphysagria also wants idealistic situation.
You know what I mean?
I mean a situation where you don't meet a girl in a coffee shop and say, let's go
and have sex. This is not an idealistic situation, right? Or it is? Maybe it is.
Idealistic for the Platina but in general it is not.
You have to meet somebody, discuss, find out that you like him or like her,
then this can go on for a certain period of time,
for a few months before you know the person, before...
What is sex?
You like these topics?
-Let's go back to the original question.
-Very good.
-What are the core elements for prescribing Onosmodium?
-Onosmodium, I would prescribe to somebody who is irritable and nervous,
who will complain that he cannot have sex, that he was trying to have sex
and he was not able to have an erection.
He will try this way and that way, the sex is in his mind but it's much more... trying.
Much more realistic in his attitude towards sex.
He is somebody who is either too hysterical, too neurasthenic, somebody
who complains for little things, who tries to have sex and he cannot.
And then he is fixed in his mind, I must have sex. It is very important to have sex
and he tries again and has no erection. This is a whole situation all together.
-What about the question?
-What is sex?
When I teach I have to give some standards of what is natural, what is physiological.
Here sex is one of the instincts that produce disease and therefore it's important.
Frustration on sexual matters is one of the main causes of producing disease.
Frustration on the instinct of survival produces disease.
In order to survive, I need that space. If I don't have it, I'm stressed
and therefore I need some space, I need some basic food and some basic water to drink.
This is the instinct of survival. If this in conflict...
I lost my job, my boss told me you can not anymore have a job
and I have three children to feed. This is a frustration on instinct of survival.
Frustration on this instinct is going to produce disease.
Frustration on sex and emotional matters is going to produce disease.
And I have said now, in our days frustration on spiritual matters it's going to produce disease.
For past societies frustration on sexual matters and frustration on instinctual matters...
First on survival matters was very important.
Survival matters was on the older periods. Then we could see diseases
because of that frustration and diseases were coming mostly on the physical body.
Then as the sexual pleasure took over...
As we were satisfied with what we had to eat and we had a lot of sex
and any sex we like etc., then the question of spiritual survival came into being.
Spiritual survival is now for our society one of the main reasons
for bringing up symptomatology, for bringing up diseases.
The subtler we do, the subtler diseases are produced.
Subtle we say into mental-emotional pictures, so frustration on spiritual levels
produce very deep diseases.
But in all these matters we have to know what is normal.
What is normal, how much space you want?
I want one factory. All right have one factory.
I want two factories, I want a chain of factories, I want... It goes on.
This is disease, it's going towards disease.
How much sex you want?
Once the week, once every two days, once the day, twice the day, three times the day...
Where is the natural? There are some spaces of what is natural.
Within that context grossly speaking, we have to understand what is sex.
What is the normal condition of sex. The doctor has to understand these issues.
This is my question. Under these circumstances I ask what is sex.
Sex is the urge of the human being, because they represent one pole, to unite with another
and become a unity, become one.
It is the idea of becoming from something which is not whole, to become whole.
That is why the satisfaction comes. The satisfaction does not come
because you have an orgasm.
The satisfaction comes in sex when you feel really united with the other person.
How to feel that? If you are not feeling that, the pleasure is very little.
You feel that unification, the pleasure is great.
That's the urge, the urge to become one. Not to be separated, not to be alone.
Unless we create that situation, it's very difficult to have this feeling.
Never mind how beautiful a woman is, when she lies in bed she is the same like every other woman.
Men know that. It's exactly the same.
So what makes the difference? You say I want this woman?
But she is the same with another, she left you, it doesn't matter. Find another one and...
What is this? It is because he felt with this woman this kind of unification,
this kind of tremendous losing yourself into somebody else.
This circumstance is the natural state of things.
I state very crudely these issues, I understand. But I do not have time.
We could discuss this matter for five weeks but I want to give you my perspective in a nutshell.
When this is frustrated, then you go to sex and Platina goes to sex.
It's not Platina only, it's all the remedies. Nux vomica is worse, I'm telling you.
If you go to this kind, you frustrate this element.
By frustration you create a disease.
A man or a woman will say, especially a woman, even when they are 24-25,
they will say still I have not found the right man.
And you have to pass a judgment whether this is a frustration or whether this is a natural feeling.
A woman cannot just go to bed and open her legs and have sex.
This is not natural for a woman. The woman is more sensitive to perception
because she receives inside her, she receives the other person, so she is more sensitive than men.
And therefore she resists more, she says I don't want to have sex with you, forget it.
Once she is in good health, if she loses her health, then she can do anything
and then why do we find all these Sepias and...
...and the uterus of Sepia is in atony.
She goes to labor and the uterus makes the spasm but it does not bring out the child
and then she collapses.
Why? Because there is a frustration, maybe.
When I look upon a case, I look upon a case with a background.
I don't look at a case and I don't know anything.
I know certain things and according to these things I understand what is happening.
I do not criticize, I do not say, you are frustrated...
No, I try to help them. I understand first where is the problem and then I try to help.
I understand this man totally, what is the problem with him?
He is a human being who also tries in the scale of evolution
and he is going to evolve according to his...
and I'm called upon certain historical moment in his life to help.
Really to help, not to make upside downs and this is the idea with Homeopathy.
We have the possibility to help, help him correctly.
That is the whole idea behind it.
So in order the sex to be really enjoyable it has to have that element, mentally,
emotionally and spiritually and physically there is no resistance, one is merged in other.
If there is no resistance only physically but spiritually or mentally...
you can still have an orgasm and remember yesterday you were having an orgasm
with the other one and you compare, which is the better. She was better.
You are not there, you are not merging because you are able to think other things
while you are having sex. That means emotionally or mentally you are not in tune.
The pleasure is going to be much, much less.
The more in tune you are, the more you let yourself.
Therefore you are not afraid, you let yourself to merge with the other person,
the more you manifest the idea of one and the more pleasure you have.
And that is natural sex.
But what especially the American society is doing...
The child is 14 years old and it does not have a boyfriend or a girlfriend. What is wrong?
What is wrong in the head of the parents? Not in the child.
The wrong is in the parents head, not in the child.
The child is natural, it says I don't want that yet.
If children were educated to understand these meanings and to understand
that it's going to be a day that they will enjoy really, they would wait.
There are some children who say I can't wait. You say OK, come here, discuss the matter,
take Lachesis and then he waits, take Platina and then he waits.
And then it becomes a society, which is sane society.
Our societies are insane societies and that's why insanity
is coming into our beings more and more and more and more.
You will say I'm a weak man, a weak woman, I have problems.
It's OK, as long as you know that you are a weak man and you have this particular weakness
but don't present your weakness as your main point of reference.