-What is the problem?
-My problem is very much tiredness and often sleeplessness during the night.
In some periods I sleep quite well but never really well.
When I go to bed I need at least an hour awake or maybe half an hour before and so on.
Sometimes I sleep until I get up, sometimes I wake up at 4 in the morning
and for sure if I haven't slept during the night, I'm very tired during the day.
Especially when I'm at work, working as a homeopath, I get very easily tired,
I find it difficult to consult, especially new consultation.
I feel deeply exhausted, I would say more physically in that case, more tired.
And I don't find I have problems in thinking, reading but I just feel tired
and also I realize that if I eat, I get very tired afterwards.
Sometimes if I eat my lunch and I have a consultation afterwards,
especially if it is a difficult patient, where I don't see any remedy,
because if I see something, then I get excited and then it's OK because I'm more alert.
But if I find it difficult, sometimes I get so tired.
Especially at 3-4 o'clock in the afternoon I hate to have new patients
after let's say 2 o'clock because I feel so tired.
So I try to put my patients, the new ones, earlier in the day like at 10 o'clock
and not later than 2 o'clock.
When I go home I feel the need for at least half an hour sleep but very often
when I want to sleep during the day, it takes me some time until I fall asleep
and then I wake up after 15-20 minutes.
If I sleep well, I take a cup of coffee and then I'm OK usually
but sometimes I can get tired after that.
Especially those nights that I have problems to fall asleep like last spring,
my feet get very hot and sometimes I find it hard to spread my feet with cold
because it's so hot but that's not usual because right now it hasn't been like that at all
but for some periods of time my feet get very hot during night. I'm very restless.
I can't stand still, I have to move constantly all the time and I always have...
I can't stop doing it, except if I know about it, when I'm aware of it.
So I'm very restless in body.
-He needs Zinc.
-I thought about that.
I always had a lumbago which usually I don't have sciatica things but sometimes,
especially now because I got an acute lumbago and I don't want to go in the weekend
and I go to the chiropractic and I had three treatments, now it's getting better now.
But now I have this sciatic thing down my leg.
-Which side, left side?
-Now it is the left but I think that's because of the chiropractic treatment.
Also I find a pain up here, I get very tight up here but I think that doesn't bother me usually
and sometimes I wonder if that actually has been more often after I've been to the chiropractic.
I went to the chiropractic first time in 82.
I always had bad migrains that disappeared when I was aware until 82
because it was the autumn you were here the first time.
I've been driving a lot of taxi during my studies and I think my back is from the taxi driving.
I can't think of anything special except that I can get some background if you want.
I have a fear when I was doing quite a bit of drugs.
-What drugs?
-A little bit of amphetamine, cocaine a few times but not many times, maybe 5-6-7 times.
When I was at 20 I used to get a lot of barbiturates.
I think I wanted contact but I was very closed person and then I used these barbiturates
because they gave me a kind of self-confidence.
When I did that, I did quite a bit for a year, one and a half year but when I finished that
I took LSD once, some marihuana but not very much because also I had a lot of anxiety,
so I didn't want it.
-Marihuana is the cannabis indica?
-Yes.
-Except that LSD experience it was very good the first 5-6 hours, then I had 6 hours of nothing,
it was very bad and I think I had some kind of shock after it.
Since then I've been in very good care, I've been travelling a bit after that
and I've been feeling very good until I think it started in 1983.
Like I said I was very insecure and I didn't know what to do.
I went to University to study but I wasn't very sure what I wanted to do,
I have no motivation of going there.
I started travelling a bit and I got to a religious group, a Christian group in 1977
and when I came back, when I finished that I felt that it wasn't what I believed or hoped it could be.
I was looking to a religious experience or at least something to hold on
and I couldn't find anything.
When I came home I was really depressed and I was seriously thinking of committing suicide
and I think for about half a year I was very depressed.
At the end I came to a point where I had either to commit suicide or I had to do something
with my life and I decided I had to do something with my life.
I went to the University, I studied philosophy and I then I went into contact
with one of the people here, studying natural medicine, and I think from that point I decided
that I'm going to do something with my life...
I think I always have had had some mental energy, not that it bothered me
but when I got very weak especially if it was very warm in the summer but nothing very much
until when I studied Homeopathy.
Then I was driving a lot of bus which was very exhausting
and I had a lot of tension in my stomach.
I had anxiety about health because when I had all the stomach pains in the driving
I was wondering of this.
I can get it sometimes these years when I'm very depressed; also I can get it here
when I have pressure and I'm very tensed in the solar plexus.
If you want to know my desire, I desire sweets, especially in the evening
but during the day I don't have any desire for chocolate but very often in the evening
I got anything in there.
Also one thing I forgot to mention I have a tendency to low blood sugar.
I've been taking this 6 hours blood test and that was quite normal but I find that
if I drink coffee and I drink not much coffee but not more than a couple of cups the day,
that gives me energy at least for a little while.
But I found that if I drink coffee, especially if I have lunch, before 4 o'clock
I start to feel very weak and trembling, not very much and I feel very weak and low in energy.
My blood sugar when I feel that it's been very low around 2.5.
But like I told if I'm fasting, if I go a day and not getting breakfast,
I can go the whole day without eating.
This doesn't do me anything but if I drink coffee, then I think it's low blood sugar.
I was quite irritable but I don't think I'm that much irritable anymore.
But we had a discussion the other day, the things I don't like is when people contradict me
or they disagree with me, I can get quite tensed from that.
-You are not supposed to react in this way. You are observers, we are not criticizing
what we are seeing.
If you are taking a case and you are going to prescribe,
so you will have the responsibility with somebody else, so if you observe
and you don't know what is going on, you don't laugh so easily.
Also if you laugh, it means that you take a critical attitude towards what you hear.
Now of course you are doing it because you are not really responsible but never mind
how much something seems to you it's not right or it is different etc. still you observe
and you wait until you find really what is going on.
What he is saying is important information if you say, I used to be irritable, now I'm not.
For me it's very important information that tells me a lot of things, a lot of stories.
-Also I sigh a lot, my girlfriend tells me I do it all the time.
-What remedies have you taken?
-I have taken Lycopodium, Hydrophobinum that was two years ago, I took Medorrhinum...
-I was very Christian and I took Staphysagria, it didn't have an effect
and I took Ignatia 200, I took Tuberculinum and I feel quite confident that it did something.
Then another homeopath gave me Cannabis indica and Ambra grisea, then also Arsenicum
and then on thinking myself I took Natrum sulphuricum 1M.
Sometimes I thought about Aurum because I feel I'm too much Aurum the way you described Aurum
and I have some tendency to think about suicide.
-Why?
-Sometimes I feel not so much anymore but earlier I felt that life is heavy.
-Why life is heavy?
-You have to fight all the time, very many times I'm thinking that life is a fight.
-But you fight for what reason?
-How can I explain that?
-Life is a fight because... tell me what it is in you that makes life seems so heavy for you?
-Not anymore because I feel I have found...
If you ask me now if I'm thinking of committing suicide,
I would say no because was thinking very long to do it and I had that depression
but I don't think that way, like before.
-Which area is the most difficult for you? It's the area of your work, finances,
your relationship with your parents, your relationship with the girls, the relationship?
-It's vague I would say, work is difficult but I know it is and I have difficult finance
and it worries me a lot because we have problems and... we manage but it's like, it's difficult.
I think it's all in the back of my mind but I don't have that kind of attitude anymore.
I think it can be all this tiredness and I told you back in 82 I had some fears,
where I just felt...
If I had that, I would be 100% because I felt what I was doing was right, I was happy.
-What remedy you have taken then?
-Nothing.
-You had not started with Homeopathy?
-No, I started in 80.
-Are you sure it was not because of the remedy that you were feeling...?
Do you remember when did you take Sulphur?
-I took Sulphur afterwards, I took Sulphur that summer that I was working in a tourist shop.
I was very weak because of the heat and I couldn't believe it's so hot,
it was down to 40-44.
Also my blood pressure was down, I think it was tested the other day
and it was 6-9 or something quite low.
That was the summer in 83. Also that summer I hit a person on the road, it was killed.
That was before taking Sulphur. I was driving and then he went out to the red light
and she was hit by the car and she died the same night. That was a shock but in a way...
for three days I felt terrible but after that I was surprised how I recovered.
I thought it must be something wrong because I didn't reacted more.
It doesn't hurt me but then I know that it wasn't my fault either.
I was driving fast but the police didn't find any reason to condemn me.
But these problems started before this, so I don't think there was a connection.
-How old are you now?
-32.
-Have you been married before?
-No.
-Why you didn't marry yet?
-Probably next year. My girlfriend is sitting up there.
-She will owe me something, I will make you confess publically that you marry her.
Where is your girlfriend? She will give some information about you.
20 years you know him?
-Yes.
-Tell us about his character.
-Personally I think he is very tensed, he has developed some ticks,
especially when he is in a stress position, he is doing with his fingers like that.
Like he said he is also in some discussions, he can be very hard on the others,
sometimes, in some special discussions.
I think also his relationship with his father, he has always been hard in discussions,
he is always been the one who says I'm right.
Perhaps sometimes he can tolerate...
-Do you develop fever sometimes?
-Not very often.
-What is your normal temperature?
-36.6 but that was a long time since I measure it but I had an infection not this spring,
the spring before and I had 39 but then I didn't have any colds.
This summer when I worked as a tourist guide, I developed quite a severe cold with some sinusitis.
Last winter I had a cold and I started getting a sore throat and it seemed to me
that this will never finish and also if I talk a lot, I feel so tired in my voice
and also I feel a tension in my bronchi.
-So you have said everything?
-No, the desire, the sexual drive was very high before. That was two or three years ago.
-It was after the accident?
-No, before.
-You were happy before the accident.
-I felt in harmony. That's the way I felt.
-Yes but you were taking drugs, amphetamines...
-That was in 1977.
-After 77 you didn't take anything?
-No.
-But 82 you felt the best.
-Yes, very good.
-The first remedy that you took was Medorrhinum?
-Yes I think that was the first remedy I took. We had a clinic and we agreed to Lycopodium.
Then I took Lycopodium but I also thought about Lycopodium now.
I think I took Medorrhinum sometime afterwards but I cannot say exactly when.
But I don't think that changed my condition then. Then I was happy.
After I got in Homeopathy because I found something to live for and I was very motivated
and very interested and I felt that the more I spend in this, the more I can become.
I think that was the main motor why I felt so happy because for 10 years I didn't know
what I wanted to do.
-You said that your energy comes up in the evening again?
-No, only after sleep and a cup of coffee but if I don't sleep or I don't drink coffee
or even if I drink coffee but I don't sleep, the coffee doesn't seem to help me in anything.
-Are you fastidious?
-Yes I'm fastidious.
I can get very angry with my girlfriend when we work in the house.
It's an old house and we fix it up and I wanted to do it very properly
and so on and we got in some argument because she is sloppy when she works on the house
and I'm very fastidious on things like that.
-But she can fix the house very quickly because she is young.
-Sorry I'm so fastidious in this, I get so fed up sometimes because I want it to finish.
-So you took Arsenicum for that?
-Yes.
-Which remedy actually has helped you?
-As far as I can see, I hardly notice anything. I mean if someone else observes me...
I cannot say for sure.
-You never drank coffee before?
-I started drinking coffee only last year, I was drinking quite a bit of tea, a lot of tea before.
Now I don't drink that much of tea, then I didn't know anything about tea and Homeopathy.
-Do you feel the cold very much?
-To say it that way.
I don't freeze that easily, as much as my girlfriend does, but I think I feel the heat more.
I don't have tolerance in the heat anymore.
It seems to me that I have a tendency to get very weak, if it's hot but then
I can't swim in cold water, I don't go to swim anymore
and even in Greece the water is a bit cold.
If I stay more than five minutes in the water, I freeze very much.
If I sit in a room with more than 25 degrees, I don't like it, I feel awful.
-How is your pulse now?
-Now I'm drinking coffee.
-Yes because you are slightly trembling.
-Around 60-65.
Sometimes I get pains or I can get chronic pains.
-When you drive the bus? You still drive the bus?
-No, I won't do that again because I get very tensed when I drive the bus.
I think then it was when the tiredness got so much.
-You lost your voice when you talk much?
-Yes, it feels exhausting, if I can say it that way.
-You sweat?
-No, I don't sweat.
I get headaches but not that much anymore. When I was 20 I had some headaches. I'm not very thirsty.
-Any constipation/diarrhea?
-Yes I have the tendency to be constipated, especially last year.
When I'm away of home I got constipated.
-This is characteristic of Nux vomica, going away from being constipated.
-Also it seems that if I'm at home alone, then I relax and I can get desire for stool.
But if there is people around, than I don't.
I have tendency to be constipated.
-How do you sleep, on which position?
-Usually on my stomach but lately I started sleeping on my side too. I can't fall asleep on my back.
-Never?
-No, my girlfriend told me the other day that I was sleeping on my back but as far as I know, never.
At the time I had salivation during sleep. I had it once very rarely
and once in a while I grind my teeth.
-Do you have easily hemorrhages or open your nose?
-Yes, I often have nose bleeding especially if I have a cold.
-Have you taken Phosphorus?
-Yes.
-When?
-I think before the Nat mur, I took first 10M and then I tried 1M.
I'm always excited about a remedy, I take a remedy and I think that something is happening.
-I think he is an open person.
-If I talk with people I'm open but at the same time I can feel insecure.
-At years at school he would be the one who would stand up and talk
and he would be the one in the Committee and anything like that.
-Do you like cold drinks or warm drinks?
-Warm drinks.
-Cold drinks bother you?
-I would never drink a cold drink in the morning at least but if I'm in Greece...
But I don't have much desire for cold drinks.
One thing I didn't mention is during the periods of sleeplessness, a few times I noticed
that I have a kind of...
I can't explain, especially in my arms, a kind of aching but it's not pain.
I try to stretch. That's something I noticed when I lived in Cyprus for a year.
I was waking up with a kind of aching in my legs.
I always had this kind of restlessness in my body.
-When you had the pains in the back, how they were ameliorated?
-Mainly by lying down.
-Which position?
-It seems that... I don't think any specific.
If I lie down for a while, it gets better because
once I lie down that's when I have it acute. I find that if I lie on my back,
it's difficult to relax because I'm afraid of the pain when I start to relax.
-Mainly where is mostly the weakness? It is mostly on the mental level you would say or physical?
-It's not in my thoughts or anything, it's a kind of sleepiness maybe.
It's not so much physical. It's a difficult question to answer.
I don't find that my thoughts are confused or anything like that, especially if it's very late at
night. I want to say something and the other person talks, I suddenly forget what I was going to say.
-Was it anytime that you had anemia?
-Not as far as I know.
-The picture that he presents is not clear at all. What you feel is weakness, weakness.
This case is very difficult when they just feel weak generally without clear cut symptom.
We didn't get any symptom actually. What symptom did we get to say this is a symptom?
-Weakness especially after 2 o'clock.
-Weakness 2-3 o'clock you would say?
-I think at work.
-If you don't work, you would have weakness at that time?
-I don't think so, I can't say for sure.
-You see? The symptom is not clear, he cannot say for sure.
He appears to have some symptoms of Sulphur to my understanding, not confirmed.
2-3 is Sulphur and the afternoon is Sulphur but...he is too fastidious for Sulphur.
-And cold.
-Not extroverted, rather introverted but yet argumentative and intellectual.
We could have started with Sulphur, it is an easy solution but he doesn't like it.
There is a remedy which has depressed state Acetalinidum acid that lowers temperature,
it brings the whole organism very low, the pulse is low, the blood pressure is low, the energy is low.
We don't have much information but I have used this remedy once in a similar case,
where he described that the pulse is so low and the blood pressure is low
and everything has lowered down and with this kind of attitude which looks like Sepia.
Or you can think of Sepia mostly, the argumentative kind also
and also another possibility is Acetic acid.
With the debility and the hemorrhages that he has, the impossibility to sleep on his back.
-What about his indifference for the accident?
-It is not indifference. He thought he was not responsible.
I don't know. He says that he is not affected.
He says that his state started before that. If that is true..
-I don't think I had that kind of weakness or this tiredness that I had after the accident,
that is one thing but it's the firsts time I experienced such...
-After the accident?
-Yes.
-I'll tell you what is my problem. What I see here he is a person who has disciplined himself
to behave in this way.
Behind that I see a strong mental attitude, argumentative.
He sits in this way like Staphysagria but he does not have to do with Staphysagria.
He talks in a way which is weak but when there is an argument he might be very excited
in the argument and also when you talk in certain things, then he comes and says
it's not like that. He is not a person that will accept...
It's not what he appears to be finally, that is the problem.
There is a strength behind the weakness.
He presents a weakness and behind there is a strength.
Which remedy is that?
-What about Causticum?
-Why?
-To open half.
-Yes but you have to have reasons for giving a remedy. Causticum has what?
I don't understand because he has made himself in a way,
he is not with what was naturally growing there.
What has happened is that because of the conflict in very big level, he lost his energy.
There is some kind of conflict. Where is the conflict?
The conflict is because he feels very argumentative and very aggressive and he says to
himself this is not good, you have to be calm and very positive and you have to listen to people.
Is that the conflict? Maybe.
Then I'm thinking of what is the remedy. Also what I feel is completely trembling inside,
almost like an alcoholic. He is not an alcoholic but bzzz...
-I'm very nervous.
-You are very nervous, you get like that, trembling almost.
Maybe this case for instance it can be Tarentula, presenting himself in a completely different way.
Do you like arguments? Do you like discussion?
-Yes but sometimes I feel that maybe I speak in a complicated way so people
don't understand me and I get this tremendous pressure inside but I like an argument.
-You like the argument because you think that your ideas are very interesting?
-No, no.
-Why you like the argument?
-If in something I'm right and people contradict me, I feel that they don't...
I want an argument like that. I want...
-Do you get irritable sometimes? Out of control?
-Yes.
-What do you do then?
-If I get angry, I can feel like crying.
It's not really crying and at the same time I feel like a hypocrite.
I can't get easily angry but I'm very controlling at the same time.
When I throw something if I'm angry, I still have much control, I don't throw things out of the window.
I throw where I know it will not hurt.
-You get more answers. More real answers. He is intellectual with a conflict inside
but now where is the conflict?
The organism should be going towards a particular direction but he does not allow that.
Yes I would throw the plate but not exactly that, I will throw it to the left side, not to the right.
All this is mentalised reaction. Reactions which try to control it.
-He does not like the summer.
-I like the summer but I don't feel well because of the heat.
-It's a symptom. But why?
-I think the reason why he is doing like that is because he is he felt inferior
because he was never allowed to express I'm right and therefore often he gets into these arguments.
It has been a couple of times where he can be furious over a small thing
and I feel that he is never able to say I'm right in my arguments and I'm wrong.
-I think you picked him because you wanted a demonstration of intellectual dropping.
-No. Actually he came in to take the case and when he told me about a few things,
I said this is not a good case, let's see it individually.
So I said OK come because I understood immediately this is going to be a difficult case.
Also if you have somebody saying weakness, it's very difficult to hit the remedy.
What is the blockage here? Is it and aggressiveness that has been disguised,
is it some traumatic experience in early stage of his life, is it the suppression of his father
and the authority of his father that has produced this kind? I can't say.
What you were saying? Give us some help.
I was going to predict that you are not going to give any information.
Tell us your own observations, you don't need to agree with him.
Tell me something that comes to your mind. What is the first thing
that comes to your mind about him?
-He is always thinking.
-Intellectual.
-Very restless.
-A restless intellectual, which is tired as well, Picric acid.
-Much anger inside and anxiety about health.
-Do you think you have anxiety about health?
-Yes.
-What do you think that you are going to develop cancer or something like that?
What do you think will break down first?
-What worries me is my weakness, nothing more. I don't think about heart or cancer
or anything like that. I did that before.
When I had always pain in my stomach, sometimes I thought that maybe it is cancer
but now I don't do that anymore. Now I worry about this weakness.
-The pressure in your abdomen comes when you drive a taxi or you drive a long time?
-Not just walking... the traffic... people in the bus...
-When you see all this traffic or when you are in the traffic?
-When I'm in the traffic.
-And you are afraid that you may have an accident? You worry about that?
-Yes, I had several accidents.
-Why do you think you have accidents?
-I had an accident where I nearly killed myself.
-When you drive so fast...
-No, I enjoy it.
In the night when I was sleeping it was like I was still in the driving and I couldn't relax.
I had this tension all the time.
-Do you like eating fat?
-Yes.
-You enjoy?
-Much more than before. Before I had an aversion to it, now not.
Especially what we eat at Christmas, this pork.
I like butter very much, I like the sour cream.
-You said before when you are really angry, you may be bursting into weeping finally.
-Yes.
-That's the only thing he said yes. You don't want to change that? It is a fact?
Can we rely upon that?
-When I get to that point, at first I'm very angry, I explode and then I have some kind of weeping.
-It was a period of time that you liked drinking wine, brandy?
-Not so much. I like to drink very much but I get very tired from it, so I avoid it.
-The remedy at this moment is Nux vomica because there is actually an aggressiveness
behind all that which he is presenting, because of the sleeplessness,
because of the tendency to cry finally after a great fit of anger and irritability
and because he feels tired and wants stimulants.
Since one year he wants to drink coffee, he must stimulate himself
and because his energy goes down.
You see how nice he presented it and covered up?
-Coffee would harm him very much...
-Also the fact that he drinks coffee and brings up his system,
it means that coffee will definitely antidote his remedy. He has to take a Nux vomica,
just be absent for a week from his house during the aggravation period.
The only remedy that I feel most close at this moment is Nux vomica 1M or 10M even
and leave it to act. Stop drinking coffee.
If Nux vomica is drinking coffee, the remedy is finished.
They desire coffee, they drink and they get high and then they cannot sleep.
The symptom which we rely at the mostly is weeping after anger. See in your Repertories.
Read the remedies. We have Arnica, Belladonna, Nux vomica and Platina
are the main remedies for that.
There were other symptoms to imply but Nux vomica was better
where there was an aggression inside, and irritability that was held back,
there was a sleeplessness, as a main symptomatology.
So irritability held back and sleeplessness gives Nux vomica, with a keynote weeping after anger,
when they go very nervous and then they break in crying.
This is characteristic of Nux vomica.
Then the fastidiousness, the fat and the stimulants.
He said since last year if I can drink 10 coffees, I will drink.
I'm afraid that my health will go down but there is a desire for stimulants.
This is what we say in our Materia Medica desires stimulants.
Don't see the Materia Medica as something flat.
Imagine it in a person drinking, drinking coffee and whatever can stimulate his body.
He is from a health kind of line, therefore he does not allow himself to drink
so much coffee or to drink alcohol but he needs that.
You see a case who does not drink coffee and suddenly he need coffee, he needs stimulants.
This is a time where he has been into a state of Nux vomica.
Why? Because of that reason, that reason also. Not only because he needs stimulants.
If you say, I had been drinking coffee since I was a baby, instead of milk,
my mother gave me coffee, I would not take it into consideration.
But if he says since last year I need a coffee, what I hear is since one year he needs stimulants.
Since one year he is Nux vomica.
Nux vomica with a possibility of -later- as a complementary, of Sulphur.
Maybe after Nux vomica Sulphur will be indicated. Just have it in mind and if the symptoms arise...
If he will notice that the desire for sugar or for sweets will increase, he will notice
that his feet are warm and he must take them out of covers, perhaps that he is not
so fastidious anymore, he will notice that he would become lazy
and I don't want to study or to work...
These kind of things he will notice and the aggression will be less, maybe after a Nux vomica
he will have a quarrel one day.
OK, I think we went through.