-You can tell us what is the problem.
-The problem in my life is unprotected, vulnerability in my entire life, a weakness
which has been running through in my entire life.
An emptiness in the stomach and the feeling of an inner enemy, an internal enemy.
I would like to tell you the story of my life and I would like to differentiate between
my physical diseases and mental-emotional problems.
I was not nourished by my own mother but by a woman who feeds children.
I had strabismus, I was operated twice.
-In one eye? Right?
-I can not remember and the result was that on my right eye, I have weakness of the one side, myopia.
During one of these operations, during the anesthesia I made the experience of a
feeling as if I was captured in a tube, which had several holes through which rods
were coming in to hurt me.
What I remember from my earliest childhood was that I always had an aversion
to water because every time I came in contact with water, I had a strong itching.
And I could not bear wool at all.
When I was 6 years old an axe hit me on the head. I can not tell you anything more
about it because I was unconscious after that, I can't remember how it happened
and nobody afterwards ever told me what the issue was.
-Nobody ever told him?
-No.
-But it was an axe or it was a wood that felt down.
-It was an axe.
Between my 3 and 5 year of life I had very soft bones, so the legs bend outside
and this was treated by orthopedic exercises and other physical therapy.
When I was 14 I had a severe pneumonia in the midst of summer,
when I was 17 I had a severe purulent inflammation of the lymph nodes
with many  abscesses in the area of the neck which were opened surgically, without anesthesia.
In 23 years I had hepatitis, I was turned yellow, in 25 I had again large boils on the
buttocks which I opened myself with a razor blade.
Age 23-45 I had a recurrent lumbago which I cured myself by doing exercises and by
running, I don't suffer from it anymore.
In this time, meaning up to the age of 45 years I was never able to stand longer than
5 minutes at 1 time.
During my other times of working I never was ill otherwise.
My life disease occurred in February of this year. I had a severe bronchitis which
healed by itself, spontaneously, without medication but for 4 weeks I was not able
to work because I could not concentrate.
-He did not take antibiotics?
-No.
-Homeopathic?
- Yes, I will tell you later.
-I'd like to continue over with my emotional things. For 3 years my father during a
vacation we had, he threw me into very deep water because I did not want to go in
voluntarily and finally some time he pulled me out of it again.
But I remember up to today how I was screaming below the surface of the water.
My mother was very strict and all my sins were punished by beating on my neck
and buttocks. Maybe I may tell you an example.
One example when I went to school during winter, I always had to wear long woolen
socks going up to here which were attached to holders.
And as I could not tolerate the wool on my skin, every day when I went to school
I took them off. I did that for about one week and then my school called my mother
and complained that I arrived in school frozen, blue every morning.
And for this also I was punished in the way I had described.
Another example, one day it was raining and I was playing with a boyfriend of the
neighbor and we were sliding down the hill on our pants because it was so much fun
and of course the pants were damaged.
And for this I got punished in the way I described.
-By his mother?
-Yes from my mother. When I was 8 years old my father died from hemorrhage in the
brain; my father was a surgeon and during the entire war from 1939-1944 he had
always been present in the different front areas of the war.
I actually hardly know my father at all. I saw him once before his death and then he
gave me his hand and told me I should take care for my mother.
From 1942-1945 the time is described best with all the bombardments that were coming
all the time, the air attacks and the fear of being in a small tiny basement, a shelter with
the walls and the ceiling coming down upon me.
The years from 1943-1948 were characterized by hunger because we did not have
enough to eat. I was completely thin, I had lost my weight and since my father was not
alive anymore and we lived with my grandfather, we did not have enough money to buy extra food.
In 1947 my mother got pernicious anemia which in that time was incurable and
progressed in spite of the therapies which were possible on that time.
She came into severe depression and twice tried to commit suicide with gas.
From that time on I always had the fear inside me that whenever I may enter the
apartment, we might all explode together.
This is also the reason why I always turn off the gas and I always kept the key with me.
When I was 15, I travelled to relatives during my school holidays.
During this time my mother committed....
and she was never recovered. And she left me a letter. Word by word said, she
disappeared in one of the Bavarian (?) and her body was never found.
She left me a letter in which she wrote to me that her death was my fault because
I had not passed 7th grade at school.
The sister of my mother then took me into her house and I finished my final exams in
high school (?) Medicine.
Besides my studies in Medicine I also dealt a lot with philosophy because I was looking
for possibility to develop my own personality.
And the development of my own personality was much influenced by Herman Hesse
of whom I read every book.
He also illustrated to me that the development of personality can only come out of
oneself and he also illustrated to me the connection between heart and love.
I then finished my final exams in Medicine... filled with joy that I had passed the exams.
We turned home to my step family and to my grandfather. My grandfather was the one
that made it possible for me to study.
Of course I always had to work alongside during holidays but without my grandfather
I would not have been able to study.
During this visit where I came home filled of joy that I finished exams to tell me my grandfather
the only son of this step family killed himself by shooting himself. And he died in my arms.
In 1965 I married and I have 3 daughters.
From 1965 on I started specializing. I started with surgery and internal medicine and
then later specialized for anestheology and intensive care at the University of Munich.
It was a period of very hard work because during those times the assistant doctors
were in the clinic mostly day and night.
In 1970 I got a call from the hospital in Lansberg to become the chief surgeon there.
The head doctor. During those times intensive care medicine was only starting to
develop and it was very hard work to develop this kind of intensive care unit in this
clinic because up to then nothing had existed in this clinic.
During that time not only started the intensive care within the clinic but I also spread it
out of the clinic, in the surrounding area because I saw how many people were dying
because they have found no proper care.
Then I set up this emergency doctor system.
Professionally was a very good time for me and I also was a very known doctor at
that time and it was one of my main goals to teach my assistants in a protective way.
Protective teaching.
-I don't understand.
-His assistant doctors who were learning from him, it was one of his main goals to
teach them in a protective way; this means I protected them from the personal attacks
or arguments which always are found in this kind of hospitals, I protected them from
that so that they have really time to learn.
I had very good assistants and all the assistants that they have learned from me up
to today say that they really were able to learn a lot in a very good way in the clinic
when they studied under me.
I had developed a special sensitivity for threatening complications in patients who
were in the hospital and it was really strange that I usually, without having been
notified, appeared in the hospital when the situation was occurring.
Although the funding or the establishing of the family for me always was most valuable
or is the most valuable and I've been faithful to my wife all these years.
In spite of that our common understanding drifted apart more and more over the years.
It was very important to me to keep the children away and protect them from
witnessing personal arguments between my wife and myself.
In 1980 after 15 years of marriage we have had a very open house, also a
Lutheran priest came to our house and in my wife an unbelievable change took place.
All of a sudden she dressed beautifully and was completely changed.
Since the operations in the hospital usually took longer than noon, I often only came
home late for lunch [...] with my wife and my children on the family table on my chair.
I also met his wife, the wife of this pastor and immediately I felt an unbelievable
vibration between her and me but for another half a year I kept trying to get my wife back.
And so I fell in love and developed closer relationship with the wife of this pastor.
I tried to resolve these problems in discussions, the 4 of us had together and to try and
clear what were the real true feelings but for me was not possible anymore to go back
to my wife.
When this decision became clear for me, then my wife and also the pastor wanted to
go back to the situation that had been before.
-Which is the situation? Staying each with his wife?
-Exactly. But for me was not anymore possible and so I decided to take over the
responsibility and to die.
But since it is not possible today into our area to just go into the woods and die
I planned a suicide in which I was going to hit a tree driving the car.
And I planned it very precisely, as to ensure that nobody would ever feel any guilt
thinking that he might be the cause of my death.
It was supposed to be just an accident and I chose a day on which many people were
in my family and we were taken care of and protected and I then progressed in
committing the suicide by in advance injecting myself several anesthetic medications.
I wanted to be absolutely sure that I will die and I had exactly 12 seconds between the
injection and hitting the tree.
I chose a street where I could look very far away ahead to see if any other car was coming or not. Why I survived this death?
It is against any known toxicology but since I did survive this death, I assume I suppose
to continue living and since then I have never thought of committing suicide again.
-Let me understand. He went into the car and he drove against the tree or he never
did that?
-Yes, I was sitting in the car, the engine was running, I injected the medication and I had
planned exactly precisely, so I knew how much time had left and the time between
injection and falling unconscious, I used to crash against the tree.
-And he did it?
-Yes, the car was a complete wreck.
-And he got out being injured by this?
-Yes on my head but otherwise hardly at all. It was an absolute miracle.
-So he was in deep depression by this time.
-Yes and actually it was a good ending for me at that time because I had done good
work, I have been good to my family, they were well taken care of, I had done
everything in this life which I could do and it was a good time to end it.
Everything was taken care.
-And how many years ago it was this?
-1980. Then it was an intensive care in Munich, they put me together again and so on this
way I also experienced intensive care on myself and returned to work in my hospital
after 2 months.
I must say that all people around me protected me in an unbelievable way.
Beginning from the politicians all the way to the employees on the hospital.
I had told you that anestheology and intensive care had developed up to that time and
it was then a kind of medicine I would call human integrated medicine because we
respected life but we also respected death.
But within future development which begun in 1980-1981 these areas got more
self-independent and developed into human disintegrated medicine.
Of course I could bring many examples but I think it's sufficient if I just explain it
this way.
And so in 1986 I decided to resign from this hospital because this kind of medicine
became unbearable for me.
Then started in Homeopathy and I must say that before I started that I had also
already studied acupuncture which I also used within the hospital.
And so acupuncture and homeopathy became the two ways by which were
possibilities for me to treat patients in an energetic level.
In 1990 together with a colleague we opened up a practice in Lansberg
I might have to add that during these 6 years I did not have any regular work, so I
earned the money for my family with emergency doctor system, where I was working.
To make it clear [...] either with acupuncture or with homeopathy.
And I should also add that since 16 years now I live together with the wife of this pastor.
And she is the first person in my entire life who loves me the way I am and not for what
I should be.
I have taken Nat. mur. in C200 and 1M.That was about 5 years ago.
And Bar. Carbonicum C1000 because many homeopaths said that many medical
doctors are Baryta carbonica.
I proved Lachesis quite intensively. I proved it and I developed a proving and I have
very intense images of snakes.
About 2 years ago I once took Psorinum 1M.
In November 1996 I had a severe coxitis on my right side and I had many Bryonia
symptoms, I took Bryonia and I was cured within 2 days.
Since then I haven't taken any other homeopathic remedy because I wanted to be
very sure not to take anything else before I come to see you.
And that is also why when I had this severe bronchitis in February this year, I did not
take any remedy.
-You never took Ignatia? -No.
It is so that I have reached a point now where I feel that my clear mental calculation
is beginning to suffer.
-Did you have any otitis as a child?
-I think once.
-Do you perspire a lot?
-There were times where I perspired strongly also at night and what I might also add
is that I suffer a lot from insomnia but maybe it's because also of my profession which
often included many sleepless nights.
It's now so that I'm mostly awake between 4-5 a.m. and I must go to bed before
11-11.30 p.m. at night to be able to fall asleep.
If I go to bed later than midnight, I usually can't fall asleep anymore.
-If he perspires, does he feel uncomfortable with the perspiration or he feels good?
-It's not unpleasant.
-Where is the place you perspire first?
-Usually on my chest and partially also face.
-He never got again boils? At what age did they stop coming out?
-It was when I was 24 years old, it stopped then. I also wanted to add that these
severe purulent boils of the lymph nodes, I developed about half a year after the
death of my mother and the boiles I had on my buttocks, I developed 6-7 months
after my cousin had shot himself.
Probably was my luck that through this I was able to mentally develop my life.
-Is he clairvoyant? There are other things which are happening and he has a
premonition about them?
-Only in the hospital.
-Still he can not stand?
-It's got better but let me give you an example. When I was still studying, when we
went to the theater to a concert once for a while, all we could afford was the place
where it was standing, we had no chair and every time I did this I actually had no joy.
I could not enjoy the concert or the theater play because of the pains I was suffering
during that time.
-Temperature wise, he is very warm, very cold in his body?
-I like warm. This question is very difficult to answer for me but I can definitely tell you
that in a room which is overheated, I can not stand, I have to open the windows.
And I love the shade more. I lie in the sun for 1-2 hour but never longer.
-What about his feet? Cold, hot?
-Feet are always warm.
-Does he stick them out of covers?
-Seldom.
-I perceived that during telling his case, many times tears came and he wanted to
cry but he managed to control it. He never cries in other situations?
-I can cry yes.
-It's difficult.
-It was very difficult but maybe also due to Nat. mur. it's got easier.
-Also during all this case, he was sighing. Is this something he realized?
-I sigh every now and then again.
-Outside of this he is sighing also?
-Yes.
-He had to stop talking before he couldn't control himself. Did he feel any constriction in
the throat area?
-Constriction no. A certain kind of dryness.
The main reason why I interrupted talking was to find the correct words.
-Not because of too many emotions?
-Of course also but I had 10 days here now these 10 days were a bad time for me.
-Because he was preparing himself?
-Yes. Preparing for the talk with you and since I wanted to say my entire story without
skipping anything, I really had to dig again and I dug some feelings which I actually
had already set aside and to tell you the truth entirely, I had to go through many things.
-During sleep does he have any salivation?
-Never.
-Does he eat fruits?
-I do eat fruits not so much but for example here now I like to eat grapes and I do eat
fruit but I'm not a fruit eater.
-What he likes to eat mostly?
-Actually I eat everything because that's how I was brought up but I like very much fish
I also like meat.
-Fat of meat?
-I eat it yes. I usually don't cut it off. I have a special aversion and that's aversion to
butter milk. I couldn't really say sour milk. Butter milk is the remain after making butter.
The liquid that is left over, that's what the butter milk is.
-Does he think that the death of his mother left guilt feelings in him?
-Yes for many years of course. During all school time I had really hard problems of
passing my final exams because during the entire time, more or less, wasn't really
there, wasn't really present and it was a hard time and actually my life begun to
become easier after I had left school and when I started studying.
That was the first time I felt some kind of personal liberty.
-When he went to the University?
-Yes. It just gave me the possibility to orientate myself anew.
-He became a good student?
-Yes.
-The sensitivity to wool is still there?
-I still have this itching after water. It's not so severe in the ocean but I could never
enter a public bath because already the slightest additive to water brings intolerable
itching.
-Does he grind his teeth during sleep?
-I don't think so, my wife never told me anything like this.
-How is his desire for sweets?
-I like to eat sweets once in a while, chocolates and cake but it's not a pronounced
desire, it's not that I have to have sweets, except chocolate.
Chocolate, I eat one of these bars at one time.
-How much thirst?
-Basically I do not have much thirst but they are situations where I develop more thirst
but in every day life I'm more thirsty.
-Eggs?
-I like to eat.
-Does he have any fears?
-I'm afraid of deep water. It's difficult for me because I actually trained myself to drive out
my fears. I do up into mountains and I climb great heights but you could say there is
a kind of fear of heights which still remains.
For example the Bernina which goes down very steep, right and left, I couldn't walk that.
-There is any anxiety about children?
-When my children were not at home I had terrible anxiety. I could not fall asleep
before they returned at home.
-Does he have children with his second wife?
-No, we don't have children. She had two children and for me that of course was
very difficult time because I never, never intended to set myself between the children
and father and of course during those times they were problems arising and suffering
and so on it was not easy but in the end I think it was the right way to go.
I actually have a good relationship now to both of those children and the one son
said to me the other day that actually he feels very lucky and happy that was able to
grow up in the Community of his mother and me, preferable of growing up in the
Community of his father.
If I may add something concerning my own children.
going on with my wife and me, I'm more or less left them with her.
Because I never wanted to pull them into this situation between her and me and these
arguments and quarrels and I wanted them to have at least one stable home, a place
where they could be and I visited them but they live with my wife.
Now 2-3 years ago with all 3 of them I had very good and very deep talks and I was able
to explain everything from those times and they told me all their feelings and what had
happened and we really worked it out well.
I just want to say that I love them all 3 very much and they are just really wonderful
daughters.
-His ex-wife married to this priest?
-No. Already at that time my wife discovered that I would be the better man after all
I could have changed that anymore.
-His father died from brain stroke?
-Hemorrhage of the brain.
-At what age?
-37.
-How does he know it was hemorrhage of the brain?
-I know from my mother and I also heard it from other doctors and professors.
Even though my father was very young in age, he was very reknown doctor and
he had a leading position in one of the Munich hospitals and I just think that during
the war probably most of us today can not imagine what it means if hundreds of people
are brought at the same time and what the surgeons of those times really did for hours
and hours. They were working until they just fell over but of course they were many
not only my father and I just assume it was too much for him on those years.
-Was any of these remedies found that helped him?
-I think what probably helped most was Nat. mur. but I only took it once.
I was treating myself but actually I didn't want to treat myself.
What I definitely didn't want to do was to try 20 remedies and see which one does
something. So I told myself not more than 1 remedy per year and just whether it does
something or not.
I was clear that homeopathic treatment would have to do with my life and I never
It was difficult for me to bring myself to this point.
wanted to surrender these details of my life with anyone and as you can imagine
it was really difficult but also at the same time for me I am very happy now that I was
able to tell you Mr Vithoulkas and also in front of the class.
but as I told you at that time my decision already was made and there was no way
-Yes sure. Thank you.
-I would like to analyze this case and to discuss a little bit about it.
I want to first give you some of my thoughts and then you can decide what is the remedy.
I must say that this was one of the most painful cases because it was very sincere.
It came out of real feelings and it was very difficult for him primarily and of course for us as well
because either you want it or not you participate in the feelings.
And you feel all this energy which goes inside and Uta was telling me, I was collapsing
trying to translate.
I would say that very seldom we have the opportunity to hear the real truth.
We try to more or less understand what is going on but if somebody has been through
this kind of grief to come out and confess it, it's very difficult.
And it took a lot of courage and he must have taken a lot of thinking and days and days
of thinking before he could do that. I don't know, I believe.
This is very instructive and very good for the class because it was exemplify in my
understanding certain things which are going on in Homeopathy and how do we deal
with it and what is priority?
You were asking how do you recognize this layer and that layer?
This is a case where definitely one remedy is not going to do the whole treatment.
Yet it appears to be clear and yet it's not clear and I will give you my thoughts
concerning the case.
When he sat down and he said, I have 3 problems. You remember he said
vulnerability and then he said, the second is weakness and the third is the inner enemy,
an emptiness. I wrote down the remedy.
-Mercury?
-Mercury, very good.
This kind of vulnerability, we have spoken about Mercury, they are very vulnerable.
They can not face the world and finally they come to the conclusion that the whole
world is an enemy, they see an enemy all around etc.
And there is this weakness and there is the difficulty in speaking and expressing
themselves. I said well, that's it.
And then the case progresses and as the case progresses I wrote down another remedy.
-Ignatia?
-No, I did not write Ignatia. Somebody said it, Sulphur.
Worse standing. When he said it was very difficult for me to stand for 5 minutes.
Even for 5 minutes to stand, I wrote down, not only for that reason but because of
another reason standing combined with water bringing this itching and furuncles.
Sulphur is the main remedy for repeated furuncles, they come here, they come there.
And then as he was going deeper into this state and analysis, I said oh my god he must
have taken Ignatia because he was constantly sighing.
Then the idea of Ignatia came because of this grief and then he described exactly
the way that I have described Aurum to you.
I have described how the Aurum patients take the car and they just drive against
the tree, just out of despair and commit suicide or jumping from a high place.
Definitely at this moment we have in his life the layer which is uppermost, is Aurum.
So we have Mercury, Ignatia, Sulphur and Aurum.
And he took Nat. mur. very good. What shall we do now? Shall we start with the Aurum?
Shall we start with Ignatia, Mercury or Sulphur?
And this is the question we have to solve at this moment.
Aurum, is he still Aurum? There was a layer which was Aurum?
We have said many times that Aurum he really means suicide.
When he tries to commit suicide, he really means that, he really wants to finish his life.
He is not trying to get out. He planned it. The first time I heard so clearly.
I planned it, I just wanted it and also I didn't want to give bad feelings to others or responsibilities.
So if you have him as a patient, during that time, you plan it you say forget it my life is
finished and once they find themselves in a high place, they just jump.
I told you about the case in Las Vegas. He telephoned one night that man.
He said, I will commit suicide tonight. I said how? He said, I will jump from this high place.
In Las Vegas there are some very steep rocks, 50-100 meters. He said, I will jump from there,
tonight and then I said to him, can you change it for tomorrow morning?
He was serious, it was not like this, my heart was going like this.
He was just informing me because my student, a medical doctor had made and affair
with his wife.
And therefore it was my fault because we had been in his house together with this
student of mine who had an affair with his wife.
So I was also in his mind responsible. What kind of students do you have and all this blaming.
He said to me that he had planned all that.
Of course it was time lapsed. By the time we went to his house and the time he decided
to commit suicide, there was an affair going on with this doctor and his wife.
So he was telling me actually that this was his decision but I should know why and that
was the reason.
I said, would you do me a favor? Because I was very nice with him. I had treated him
and I've been to his house and met him and we discussed and I was supposed to treat
him if he needed something, I would provide. He was very nice, we were friendly.
And he said OK but you have to know that this is the reason and he has done all he had
to do with his lawyer, made his will, what will happen afterwards.
Of course in Berkley and he was in Las Vegas and he was telephoning me that in a few
hours I just commit suicide, you have to know why?
Then what could I do? I said, can you wait until morning, do me a favor, last favor.
Wait until tomorrow. He said OK tomorrow morning.
Then I said, will you please take this remedy and if you want to commit suicide by tomorrow, you do it.
There is no question but do me this favor, take this remedy.
I called his wife who was still with him and I said, give him a dose of Aurum CM.
You have Aurum CM? Yes. Give it to him now. He took it.
Next morning he telephoned, next afternoon. He said, I have decided not to commit suicide.
This man died 10 years ago by falling from his helicopter.
His helicopter broke down and he had an accident. He died from a fall.
But anyhow this suddenly will develop an Aurum situation. You have to give it.
Now the question we have with this man, with all this deep, unbelievable grief and
putting on him all this guilt, grief and guilt, because of his father, his mother and then
because of his wife of course.
You can imagine, she changed her mind, no, no I love you.
No, now it's too late and all this guilt. Is this still an Aurum case? This is what we have to solve.
Or the layer of Aurum has gone, through what?
-Through Nat. mur.?
-No, I don't think.
Actually this layer was counteracted by a very intense inner action.
It was a homeopathic nullification of this level like auto therapy, when they take blood
and they inject it again back. Most probably this level left.
So therefore we are left with 3 possibilities. The Mercury, Sulphur and Ignatia.
Does anybody has any other idea?
-Nat. sulp.
-Staphysagria.
-I think the layer is already gone because he says he has a very healthy relationship
with the woman 16 years already and that she is the only person that took him the
way he is and in this way she loves him. So I think no more Aurum.
-I think one time he would need, not now but later. He will need also Carcinosin. His mother had
pernicious anemia and his father died very early and if he had all the symptoms of Carcinosin...
-I don't know but you like Carcinosin and every time comes to your mind.
-What about Arsenicum? I know that you are telling me it feels hot but last September
was sitting here, he didn't let us open the windows
-Never mind last September. Now he says, he is feeling warm. He thought about it and
he said when I am in a warm room, I don't feel comfortable.
And Arsenicum will say, when I am in a warm room, I feel very comfortable.
What is your idea?
-How is it with the physical injuries he had, with the axe what he told and
with what he had when he was in anesthesia and he said he was in a big tube
and he was stuck with It. was his first thing he said.
-That was an experience.
-What about all shocks that he had, one after another?
-He had a series of grief and a series of very strong events in his life.
There comes and his father is dead and there comes and somebody shoots himself.
The moment he is happy, he has finished his study, he comes there and finds somebody
who dies in his lap and his mother commit suicide and leaves a letter.
That is really very deep because there is a connection, you are connected.
You can not forget. Try to forget this event, how? I don't see how you can forget.
So that state is a deep grief inside and guilt feelings and grief.
So there is any question that there is grief in him? No.
The relationship which he has with his wife now, whom he loves, he found somebody
with whom they have a very good rapport.
That relationship takes away a lot of problems, there is no question.
But can this relationship take away all the grief because if it can take all the grief away,
then we are justified to go to purely physical symptomatology and see which remedy fits.
All the grief is out because of a good relationship? What's your impression?
-No.
-So the grief is still there. Therefore we are going to deal first with the grief.
First we are going to deal with the grief? It's Aurum, Staphysagria, Ignatia, Nat. mur.?
-Ignatia.
-It's Ignatia, why? Because you see this deep sighing constantly.
That's what when we described the remedies, this is how we described Ignatia.
And not crying. He can cry but you see how he control the crying?
He needed a lot of power to control the crying because it is his remedy to control
the crying; otherwise why he should control?
Somebody else will cry but he didn't feel comfortable in crying, in spite of that
tremendous grief, in spite of the fact he was confessing this grief and digging
inside his soul. All this grief coming back, again relieving every point and you could
see he was not detached, a person who was relating about the grief.
He was living the grief, he was one with the grief. So the grief is there alive.
Then we have to deal first with this grief and then we go deeper.
The remedy which is indicated...
This is interesting. Ignatia, Mercury, Sulphur the 3 remedies we have been thinking are
prominent, 3 prominent remedies actually. Aurum, Pulsatilla, Natr. mur.
So therefore as the case unfolds and you are searching for the right remedy at this
moment, you can not say I'm going to give him Sulphur because you see the life grief.
The grief is there because in spite of the fact he has a good relationship, in spite of the
fact he talks with his children and they talk it out, this is not enough for the organism.
The organism has been wound deeply and needs the homeopathic remedy to bring
some kind of balance on that level.
The Ignatia will bring a kind of a balance to a certain level and then underneath
what will be the remedy underneath?
Who says Sulphur? Who says Mercury? Who says another remedy?
My idea is this. Many times Ignatia is complemented by Sulphur.
You have to remember this. Ignatia many times is followed well by Sulphur.
Now in this case we have too many symptoms of Sulphur to be able to ignore them.
Vertigo high places, worse heat, aggravation from water, itching from water, wool
aggravates, also aggravates the Mercury. All these are keynotes of Sulphur.
Emptiness in the stomach is also a keynote for Ignatia. All gone feeling in the stomach.
As the case unfolds from Mercury to Sulphur, to Aurum, to Ignatia, you say wait a moment,
what potency?
-Very high.
-Very high, 50M, CM. You give and you can repeat it also.
50M 2 times, CM 2 times 5 days. In 5 days he must take a deep breath and the
organism will forget most of the grief. This grief is never going to be forgotten totally.
Don't make a mistake.
-Why 5 times?
-Because the grief is 5 times, multiplied by 5. Put any grief, multiply by 5 and this is
the case. It's very deeply rooted, tremendously. It's unbelievable.
It's one of the most dramatic cases I have encountered, as far as relating the cases concerned.
To be able to give out this information in front of the class...
If there was a psychiatrist here would say, well this was a healing experience.
Forget it, not in his case. Because he has done it already with his wife, with his children.
The grief did not go away.
-George I think that he was able to do this in front of the class, shows how deep he suffers.
-Also the preparation he needed. The psychological preparation, he must be
torturing himself, he must have thought again and again how shall I say, what shall
I say? He wrote it down to be able to stick to the facts and you could see the
trembling when the whole organism was in a state of turmoil.
-I think that Aurum layer will come up again.
-I don't think, no. Taking the way his life is at the moment. God help if something else
happens, I don't know but in this way, no. The way I see the situation, no.
-Do you then say this was an acute? This Aurum was an acute?
-Exactly, it was a layer added which changed the layer of let us say, Sulphur or it might be Mercury.
Maybe this case is Ignatia and then Sulphur and then Mercury.
And there was a time where he needed Mercury and Sulphur.
Aurum I should put it here. This was counteracted by itself, by the fact and then
Ignatia stayed and then Sulphur and then Mercury.
I think this is the way is going to do but he will feel much better after Sulphur.
The big amelioration for him will come, will be another person.
-And when you do get to the Sulphur, will also be a high potency?
-Yes, not a very high like this. Ignatia is the level of grief and the level of grief is deep
and strong and embedded inside. He has permeated all his cells.
To unroot that it's a miracle because it might have been so deep that you can not
even see it. But now all this pointed out to us.
-Mr Vithoulkas I was almost in the way of these things except the one tone.
The tone to the Aurum, maybe from my mistakes some other people can learn also.
I thought about Nat. Sulphuricum because he planned this act so detailed and he
didn't want to bring the harm to the relatives and that was a key issue in all this
discussion and so together with the symptom of waking at 4-5 a.m., could you please
bring a little bit light to my mistake? Thank you.
-Have we talked about Aurum?
-We talked about Aurum the first lesson. I described the way they commit suicide.
One of the ways is taking the car and hit it against the tree.
This, the Nat. sulph. they don't commit suicide because they think of the others.
The grief they are going to inflict on others, prevents them from committing suicide
though they think all the time, I want to die, I want to die.
No, you must not die, you have a daughter. No, this is not life. All this time, this fight.
This fight we don't see and then they hang themselves. Usually Nat. sulp...
-I just remembered the story you told us about Nat. sulph. in one of your cases.
When you treat some patient who was in grief because his wife died and he doesn't
want to harm his daughter. Is it the same, the wife like died because they divorced
and he doesn't want to bring this grief to the family.
So he planned it very well but at the same time he was just on anticipation...
-Planning suicide means finished, I don't want to live. My life is finished. They jump.
They take the car under this condition and they hit the tree.