-Tell me how you are.
-After Staphysagria I was very angry. You gave me Staphysagria because
my emotional state was very heavy and with the Causticum I feel good in the
physical level but emotionally I was very angry and this anger was my sickness.
I was with fever, I was very sick in the winter and I told you that after the Causticum
I feel like I dropped out my heavy burden and after that I was very sick and you
asked me what is your problem and like a volcano all my emotions came out from the past.
I had also emotional pain about my mother that killed my child before it was born and
about my daughter that got married against my will and about my partner that lost
my medical center and a lot of other problems, my father was dead in certain period.
After Staphysagria I didn't feel something special but 3 weeks after somebody wanted
to meet me, a man and 7 years I was very close because I didn't want other problems.
For me men is a heavy problem and 20 years of marriage is trouble.
-So you met somebody.
-Suddenly I want to meet him and this I think was falling in love with the first sight.
-Very good.
-I was like in "Olympus" and all my emotional burden I think I transported from this plain
to another plain.
All my feeling that I thought it was dead, for a long time, 7 years I had
only homeopathic treatment and study and I was like monomaniac.
If I wanted to speak about something was only Homeopathy and only how to treat and
how to understand the patient and I was no interested in something else.
And this time this was 3 weeks after Staphysagria I feel that it's another thing
important for me.
-Another department of life.
-And my feeling was another level and I can cope with my reality, with my mother and
with my daughter.
-Everything becomes more easy.
-I was very lonely and I think that I get with me my daughter' s family because
I wanted them to demonstrate that I'm not alone but it was very difficult for me to study
and to be with my grandchildren and all this. It was not very good decision.
At the end of June I stopped to be alone.
-You live together now?
-Not all the time because I work very hard and I like my profession.
-Is he also a doctor?
-No he is a businessman.
We came together here, he was here for 1 week and it's
fine to feel that somebody can treat me and not I have to treat others.
But in August I get a kind of burning on my soles, not pain and this was more and more strong.
This was not enough to put ventilator but at the time I can't stand on my feet
because of this burning pain.
-It's so much.
-If you remember 1 year before I came with a burning pain on my chest and cramps
on the calves and all these things disappeared.
I did a check up to cardiologist and he found that my LDL cholesterol is very high and the HDL
is very low and he wants to put me on medical treatment, I didn't take it.
All this pain that was 1 year before focused in my epigastrium and this is the same kind of pain
and sometimes come up a constricting pain like a stone that came on the throat.
I speak with the gastrenterologue and he told me that this is stomach ulcer.
My father had stomach cancer and I did ulcer when I was a medical student but this
was gone and after Staphysagria came back in the same symptoms.
-As strong as it was?
-More strong and more painful and I was afraid about this pain.
-The last time here you had pain in the abdomen and you had to bend double. How is that pain?
-In the same way but only in one limited area, not on the chest as it was.
-It was in the abdomen.
-No, it was on the chest.
-6 months before, last June, you said you had pain in abdomen.
-No, somebody else translated for me but I said to chest.
I sent you a fax about this pain and the burning pain on my soles and you wrote me that
I can take Medorrhinum 1M.
I'm afraid to take Medorrhinum because of my work and I took it one day after that I came here,
2 weeks ago.
-You took Medorrhinum 1M or 200?
-Yes and I have some symptoms after the Medorrhinum. One of them is I'm tired and
I feel like floating, not dizziness, like I'm not here but in other place.
I don't concentrate and I have a sort of restlessness internal. I'm very impatient,
I can't stay a lot of time in the chair, I have to go out, to come in all the time.
I have problem with my sleep, all day I'm very tired but in the night I can't sleep.
I want to dance 3 hours.
-You go to disco.
-I can't sleep in the night.
-The sleep comes late or you fall asleep and you wake up?
-I sleep for a sort time and then I wake and after that I have to do something because
I can't only lie, I have to get up and to do something.
-Then you go back and you sleep again.
-For an hour.
-And then you wake up again.
-Yes.
-It goes like this. How many times you wake up in the night?
-Last night it was 3 times.
-Do you have to eat something?
-I put on weight, 3 kilos in 2 weeks because all the time I want to eat.
-In the night?
-In the night, in the day, every 4 hours. I'm hungry, I want to eat.
-But how is the burning in the feet?
-Something happened on my soles, in the right leg the skin is very hard, it's like callosity
but it's not this. It was yellow patch and after that...
-Is it hard?
-Yes and very hot and this place is burning.
-Not all the foot?
-All the foot but this place more.
-Is there any itching there?
-No.
-What about your desire for salt?
-More, more. I eat salt with food, not food with salt.
-And you said aversion sweets. You still don't like or you start eating sweets?
-I eat sometimes but I really don't like them.
I have another problem that this was in my past. Back pain in the lower region.
I told you that 7 years ago when I began to learn homeopathic study, I suffered from
the low back problem with the spine, the vertebrae.
-She must have an operation.
-She was told she must have an operation.
-She had hernia.
And every month I have to lie for 1 week.
I took Lil. tigr. and I was with very big aggravation and after 3 weeks all these things
disappeared and after 1 year I was OK.
And now this pain reminds me of that pain.
-But it is starting, it's not as strong as it was. It's only a little bit now?
-No. Massage is very good for me. Every morning I wake up with stiffness all the back.
I can't move.
-Where do you feel mostly this stiffness?
-All the back.
-Or from lumbar to here, or from sacral to cervical, or mostly dorsal?
-Here lumbar and shoulder but the dorsal too is stiffness, I can't move for an hour.
I come to wash my face not in this way, only in this way.
-And after an hour you get used.
-Yes.
-How is your thirst?
-With all the salt that I eat is strong.
-Cold?
-Ice cold.
-You like ice cream?
-I don 't like sweets but more ice cream than cakes.
-Your reaction to weather?
-Wet is very bad for me and cold too but wet especially. I like the sea very much.
I feel good in the sea.
-You feel rejuvenated?
-In emotional level too.
I feel that I'm very calm. If I have every day work I can get a ride to the sea in Tel Aviv
at the end of the week and I feel good.
-Do you eat fruits?
-Not so much.
-Not good for the stomach.
-The position in bed?
-Only to the right side.
Now after the Medorrhinum I like to be on the abdomen but not for long time because I smoke
and it's very difficult for me to breathe.
Dancing and gymnastic I feel very good after. Aerobic only. I have to jump.
-Do you feel very much in a hurry, you have to do quickly?
-Yes, I'm very intense because of that. I feel that thing inside, not always I come to
do these things physically quickly.
-When you dance you perspire a lot?
-Only on the head. It's like I go to do bath in the shower.
-Face or head?
-She knows because she saw me.
-How is your sexual energy?
-Volcano.
And he was here only 1 week. Maybe next year I bring him 2 weeks.
The evaluation of the remedy that she took. She has been doing very well in Causticum
and then in Staphysagria, then she sent me a fax for which I prescribed Medorrhinum.
Is Medorrhinum a remedy which is acting at this moment, yes or no?
-Yes.
-Let me see the fax what is was saying in the fax. Since the first fax, she sent another
fax before, I sent you my burning pain in my soles has increased. That is the last one.
There was a fax before for which I said nothing?
-Maybe Medorrhinum but wait.
-Mr Vithoulkas has read the fax and we are happy to hear about it. He says that there is
a possibility of Medorrhinum but you should not take it yet, seen that you are feeling better.
So please wait. So you waited and then you sent this fax.
In which you said the burning on the soles has increased.
Now it reoccurs every night especially worse 4-5 a.m. Maybe this is because of high temperature
in Jerusalem in Israel now but that bothers me a lot, especially during the night.
It's very difficult for me to rest.
I find it difficult to fall asleep and each night I wake till 12 to 1 and only then I fall asleep
but I wake up because of the burning feeling in my soles.
In the morning I'm very tired and during the day too.
Because it was very strange for me that you write only my soles are burning and I tell
you just take Medorrhinum. My last blood analysis results show a decrease in high LDL
and increase in low but in general I feel very good, I'm happy now with my friend etc.
I would appreciate...
I had a few strange symptoms that I can't find them in Repertory.
During my sleep I felt like a stone that rose from the stomach constrictive spastic pain to
the esophagus towards my throat and it's stuck there, the stone and after a few minutes
I have to regurgitate much saliva or stomach fluid but not sour and without pain.
I felt as a hand squeezing and I do not know what this can be.
My results are OK from the laboratory.
I would like you to know that my father died from stomach cancer.
Three symptoms were only 2-3 times but enough to frighten me.
In your latest fax you mention to take Medorrhinum. I didn't take yet.
If you still think I should take, please let me know.
Mr Vithoulkas finds that the font that you use to send your faxes is very difficult to read
Can you please send it in italic?
And I said you can take a dose of Medorrhinum 1M. So this is the whole story.
Now she took, she is already now 11 days. 21 of September? 10 days.
More or less, it's OK. 10 days is still close to evaluate whether the remedy is acting and
we have to wait, we can not give another remedy. The only thing we can say is that
maybe there is a possibility of Sulphur but I will not advice you to take Sulphur.
Just be patient, let the remedy act because your amelioration is quite strong.
-Very strong.
-So just be patient and wait, don't take another remedy and I think things will go all right.
Last time we decided to wait for the time being?
-No, I took Medorrhinum when I was here.
-Here it's written possibility Sulphur.
-No, I sent you a fax and you give an answer that I can take.
-Medorrhinum what potency?
-200.
-Where is the fax? This is what I say, there is no fax here.
Do you have the fax with you?
-No, no.
-So what happened? You remember why you asked me?
-I remember. I took before Medorrhinum, Staphysagria.
-You took yourself?
-No I took here in the turn before.
-And then you came here and you said that and you did not receive a remedy here in September.
No remedy.
-No, I took it 1 week before the last follow up.
-Medorrhinum 200.
-And why did you ask for a remedy?
-I had burning feet.
-That's all?
-But I couldn't walk.
It was very extreme this burning feet and at night especially I couldn't rest.
-If she looks at all the picture something very special happened.
-What it is?
-After taking Staphysagria I could confront my heavy and difficult things with my mother
with my daughter, all the difficulties, they became different.
-What does she mean different?
-She started to see all the things much more beautiful. She stopped being alone,
she allowed herself to know somebody but this man I knew was not honest enough for me.
I felt it from the very beginning but I really did not want to be alone and I went into this
relationship but I felt this relationship is not healthy for me and I had the feeling I fell
in love for the love, not for this person.
-Just because she was feeling good, she fell in love.
-Yes. I was very open and all surrounding was very beautiful for me and very easy.
The life was suddenly easy.
-And interesting again.
-Yes and I wanted it to live too.
-These feelings were due to the relationship?
-I don't know, it was after Staphysagria.
My work was easy and I enjoyed my work and I work very many hours the day.
-But in your mind you knew that this relationship was not good.
-Yes I felt it because I treated him before that. He was my patient and he had many problems,
he then was in a process of divorce himself. He needed treatment to calm
down and because he was in the same picture with me, I gave him Staphysagria.
-After she gave him Staphysagria, he felt much better and he stopped taking medication
but he also left her.
He went back to Argentina, his origin country to finish this business there and he left
and he took away with him 10.000 $.
-Her money?
-Her money.
She was for 3 months under deep depression.
-When it was that?
-They were here together in October and in December I was in this situation.
I couldn't sleep neither eat, I lost weight 8-10 kilos, concentration.
She took Medorrhinum in October, it was after Medorrhinum.
-What potency?
-200 and I have reaction, headache for 3 days and all the time I wanted to sleep but
I was very tired.
After Ignatia I also was for 2 months in deep depression.
I couldn't enjoy and I did not want to go out of home.
I did not want anyone to approach me or to talk to anyone.
I went to work much more intensively, much harder.
Something I had always, I told you from first meeting, this feeling of no lack,
no fortune in life is strengthened 10 times more this feeling.
That I'm unfortunate in all the life.
I took Nat. mur. 1M, I ate a lot of salty things then, I wanted to cry and I could not.
I had internal grief, very heavy, the problems that I had with my mother that I had no patience
to her came again, that time again I had a lot of arguments with my daughter.
I wanted just to be left alone, that's what I know to do, how to do and that's it.
So it's very hard, very difficult for me and I decided to go to psychotherapy. I think at the
end I started to treat this psychotherapist, I started to treat her.
I still feel sad, as if I don't have my place socially and I'm still staying home but
I enjoy work very much, especially that I have successes all my life and at this moment
I don't feel I need somebody near me but it's very hard with this loneliness,
with this being alone.
On the one hand I don't trust, I don't have the trust and this fear to be hurt again.
On the other hand the Staphysagria and the other treatment you gave me, did something to me
and I feel more a woman.
These two things is hard for me to confront. I have ups and downs.
It's easier for me to see the beauty, the nice things and colors.
When I go back home is again to get into my place, home.
-Restricted.
-Very much.
-She is still sighing?
-It's hard for me to talk about this now. That's why I'm sighing. Usually I'm not sighing.
Before I took Ignatia I had no air and I was sighing a lot.
Now I'm not anymore but I think part of this depression is left inside, I feel it in the down state.
-You can not get out of it. Tell me something.
The desire for salt is still there, strong?
-I like it more than other.
-And also aversion sweets?
-I eat but I don't like, I have no craving.
-Also your afternoon sleep?
-It's something that I forgot because it's pathological one. My suffering is more emotional
now but I want this follow up because now I wake every night a lot of times. I got to sleep
and after I wake up, I fall asleep easily but all the time I wake up and I have vertigo.
-When you wake up?
-No, all the time, when I work, when I raise up my hands I have vertigo for a few seconds
recently more frequently.
After taking Staphysagria and Medorrhinum and the fear I had I have needs like every woman,
sexual desire. Every night is more difficult and I take cold bath, it's very difficult
-To calm down. Let me understand something. After this man left,
did she take again Staphysagria?
-No.
-She took Ignatia and Nat. mur. What happened is, why she is in that state is because
Ignatia and Nat. mur. were not correct. She should have taken Staphysagria immediately.
-I took but I'm afraid to take more than 30.
-You have to take Staphysagria 50M now to get out of the depression.
-I think that it's something else, as an homeopath I distinguish my symptoms as Conium state.
I can't hold my head. It falls.
I have heaviness in my lids I sweat a lot in the night and I wake up with this perspiration,
I have to take a bath and this vertigo that I mentioned before.
-Did she take a dose of Conium 30?
-No, I didn't take.
-The vertigo as I understood is not strong vertigo, it's just for a moment.
-But after that I feel not very well, I have such weakness, I have to sit.
What bothers me is the need to be together and the fear to be hurt again.
Before Staphysagria I have good defense mechanics but the Staphysagria broke a little bit
my defense mechanism.
I had my life very strong and after that I got hurt, I was more open and I got hurt.
-What can we do?
-I'm not expecting that you will solve my problems.
-If she takes Staphysagria 50M in one month all these will stay back.
It doesn't matter whether she will have another relationship or not, it doesn't matter.
What will happen is the organism will feel more balanced and she will have less sexual thoughts,
more balance, more calmness and more defense. No Conium. If you want to take Conium
first take Conium. After Staphysagria, later you may need Nat. mur. but now she needs
Staphysagria after this disappointment.
She felt she was betrayed by this man because he was not only left but took her money,
it was a kind of betrayal. Now she took Ignatia she took Nat. mur. no effect.
She will take Staphysagria again and she will come.
-Mr. Vithoulkas is a very important question. If she takes today or tomorrow morning
Staphysagria 50M can she go on with the exam? It's very important for her.
-She does not have to take it today or tomorrow. She can take it on Saturday or Sunday
because maybe there is a reaction, I don't know. Maybe you have fever or you want to
sleep all the time.
-After eating I'm very sleepy and if I have time to sleep I don't want to sleep because after
that I feel very bad, dizziness and very bad, depression.
-What she says, I feel very unfortunate, she knows this is a symptom of Staphysagria?
-No.
-She did not know.
-It 's difficult to see myself. I know Staphysagria but when I have to make my decision
is very heavy for me to see me in this detail.
-That is true but still...
-I think I'm a little proud because of being beaten by life and I feel very hard.
-You see the problem comes with the mother mostly where she suppressed so much
anger that after Causticum, Staphysagria is coming to bring out the anger.
Now she goes back with her mother, with her daughter, she goes back to Staphysagria.
If you take Staphysagria, you will forgive them.
-If she takes Staphysagria 50M, she can come back to the course next year?
-Sure why not?
-I don't know what is going to happen. I don't know where I will be, which place.
Staphysagria did so much for her, by opening that she said, her defense mechanism
so who knows where?
I made a lot of mistakes after Staphysagria. It was a feeling as if it's not me.
-No, it's you, it's the opposite. If you want to have no feelings and you want to have closeness
that is not health.
Health is when you have feelings and all that.
Now you can look and not make a big mistake because you saw that this man is not good.
-I felt it.
-You felt it but you did not follow your feelings. Staphysagria was very good but you did
not follow it. You saw this man, you liked him, you said let's see.
You were open to him and that is natural. It's not real that because long time you stayed by yourself,
then you opened there is somebody etc. That is perfectly human and perfectly understandable
but still your organism said to you, don't do it. That's why it makes you very very sad.
Also it makes you very sad because you felt he exploited you and that is indignation.
-Very much.
-So this is indignation, you can not tolerate and you want revenge.
-After the three months that I took Ignatia and after that Nat. mur. I came back to my state
with a lot of feeling that if I take revenge, I will feel better and I go to the advocate.
-You tried to catch him.
-I'm still trying with a lawyer. This is a good feeling for me.
-With Staphysagria you can do it, you can go to the lawyer but the feelings will be good.
Different. You say he did wrong to me, he has to pay back the money with some interest.
He must pay some interest also.
-But the feat that Staphysagria caused her openness?
-Staphysagria does not cause openness. Staphysagria brought back her real state.
She is emotionally again like 19 years old, she is not a woman of 50.
You are 25, 26 at the most, that is the emotions you had by that time.
The organism comes back to the emotional state that was there as a girl, when you first had...
-When I was a girl I think that my feeling was that my mother stole my childhood.
All the time I run to test this, what is it and I stayed there and I feel that sometimes
I'm childish.
-You are not childish. In your mind you are very clever.
Also you have the experience of life but not experience in this area.
That's why your organism told you to wait but you did not know what to do with that and you went
along feeling very nice feelings for the first time.
It's like falling in love for the first time, when you are 19, 20 and always you make a mistake
during this period.
But to have such feelings is a blessing, it's very good. You have to enjoy it.
You have to bring back these feelings again, you will see take this and you will see what happens.
But if you want to close it's easy, you take every day Nat. mur. 1M, after a month you close totally,
no feelings nothing.
Later maybe you will need one dose of Nat. mur., maybe after a year or two years.
I don't know but first you have to counteract the anger, what is suppressed to have the
feeling and then...
-OK.