-Last time you were here we did not prescribe any remedy, correct?
-Yes.
-And what happened to these last 6 months?
-It happened that in these 6 months I had 4 times flu and now I have the 5th these days.
In March it was the worse because the flue started, I didn't treated it with something.
I said it will be OK, after one week it was OK and after one night the flu reappeared with
high fever and I said I'll take something; I took Aconite 5.
After 2 days the fever was still high.
-When you say high what do you mean?
-High means 39 or 39,5. It's unusual for me to have such fever.
-You never had in your life such a high fever?
-Only once but after I took the remedies. Before I never had fever.
And I must go for my work to Bucharest and I go with fever because I must be there and
when I came back I had pneumonia on both lungs. The next day I couldn't move from the bed,
I couldn't move the head.
I was without energy, I couldn't think, I was like vegetable in bed.
My husband gave me Antimonium tartar. 1M and the next day I was a little better.
The second day I can get up and do some work in the house but the cough remained 3-4 weeks,
I couldn't stop coughing.
Now it's the same thing. I start coughing and I feel very bad, I feel pain in all my muscles
and a bad kind of depression which you have in the flu. I can't tell you if I have or not fever,
I'm not sure but I can tell you that in the night here now I sleep with two blankets
and I need one more.
-So you feel very cold.
-And I became colder than before in this winter.
Also in this period I made 2 biliary colic. twice, very strong, it keeps 3 days each.
-Did you take pain killers?
-No,
I just drink tea, I didn't take anything, no remedies, nothing.
-Did you make an X-ray?
-I made an echogram and it was normal.
-There were no stones.
-I became very sensitive to the draft and to the cold weather. I immediately feel cold and
if I'm not attentive, I begin a flu.
A new symptom is that in the morning, quite often, I can not see very clear, it's foggy view
and I must rub my eyes but the view is the same.
It doesn't change and it appears also if I cry, the same thing that view is not clear
and it disturbs me. I'm not able to cry so easily.
If I start crying, after 2 min. I stop. I wish to cry but I can not.
I have great desire for coffee, it's very great desire for coffee and for sweets.
I have a little problem with the salt because my husband says always you make the food
too salty and I say, no it's enough salt. If I put less salt, I say I must put some salt.
No, it's good this time you made it well and the same problem is with the sour also.
It is the same thing. If I put in the soup too much lemon, he says it's too much,
for me it's OK.
-So that means there is a desire for salt and a desire for sour also?
-I don't know.
-But comparing to your husband definitely.
-Yes.
I became very sensitive to strong odors like vinegar, like the smell from the paint.
It produce me suffocation, I can not breathe and it's enough 20 sec. to be in contact with
the smell and I cough for 1 hour.
Another symptom that reappeared is that I wake up very early in the morning, 3-4 o'clock
in the morning and I go to bed at 12 o'clock. I'm not going to sleep after,
3-4 o'clock I can not sleep.
-And you get up in the morning at 7 o'clock?
-No, 3-4 o'clock.
-You get up?
-No, I stay but I can not sleep.
-You can not sleep until the morning when you get up.
-Yes. There are some mornings when I get up I feel the left hand numbed, I can not feel it.
-Only the left?
-Yes.
-And it's every day?
-Frequently.
It takes me some time to come to normal.
And I forgot to tell you when I had that pneumonia after 2 days of working in the house,
my husband wasn't at home.
-Your husband is also medical doctor?
-Yes and he also practices Homeopathy. He wasn't at home, I was alone and suddenly
I felt that I was not able to breathe. My throat was smaller and smaller and I became in panic,
I didn't know what to do, I haven't at home any remedy, it was in the office and I was scared.
At that moment I was afraid that I will die, I call a friend of mine, a homeopath also
and I said come to me because I'm alone, I don't know what to do and I'm scared and I'll die.
She comes and tells me what do you want to give you? Do you want to give you a remedy?
I don't know, I couldn't be logic at that moment and she proposed me to make me acupuncture.
I prefer to stay with that fear but not to put me needles.
I was terrified when I saw that needle and I don't know why and finally I said give me Apis,
what potency? Never mind, something give me. And she gave me Apis 30.
She stayed with me until my husband came and when he was at home, everything calmed down
and I didn't have that feeling that my throat was too small and I would suffocate.
-This feeling came out of the blue without any reason or you were with flu or something like that?
-It was 2 days after pneumonia and I have frequent problems with the throat because I have no tonsils,
my tonsils are operated and when I make flu, all my glands are swollen.
They are very swollen and very painful and all my throat is like a wound, an opened wound.
This is preparing, this is the symptom and after 2 days it will be like this.
-You know that after 2 days it will be like this.
-And it keeps 7 days and I cough 3 weeks, that is usual.
-I want to ask some questions, how is the constipation?
-It is still there and now appeared the hemorrhoids.
-Your nails are strong?
-They are strong, they don't break.
-How sensitive you are to drafts? Can you give me an example?
-Very sensitive. In the class now for me it's draft, if I go in a car with the window open it's draft.
I think I took this flu in the bus from the air condition.
-The desire for sugar is strong or it is less?
-I must eat something sweet after every meal.
-But compared with the last time I saw you?
-It's much more.
-What about the thirst? It's normal?
-I don't know if it's normal because in 1 day I drink 1/2 kilo, it's enough for me.
-Did you have any ecchymosis?
-No, they stopped.
-The desire for coffee has become more?
-More, coffee and chocolate.
-Do you drink coffee? 1-2 times?
-I had a lot of work last month. I think 3 times.
-I thought so.
-If I see coffee, it's impossible to resist. I will dream the coffee in the night.
-You desire forbidden things.
The swelling of the ankles is still there?
-Yes, now they are not swollen but when I came it was.
-The cramps in the night?
-Yes they appeared.
I drink 1 week coffee and they appeared after the coffee and I stopped coffee because
they are very painful and it keeps me 2-3 days, I can not walk.
-It's good, the cramps are your friend, they protect you.
What about vertigo from high places, have you noticed any?
-No.
I can say that this time I came alone, my friend couldn't come and I'm a little depressed
because I'm alone. I desire to be with somebody, to discuss.
If it happens that I sleep another hour, when I wake up I have a terrible headache.
-If you sleep?
-Yes, I wake up at 4 o'clock and at 5 o'clock I sleep again. At 6 o'clock if I wake up
I have a terrible headache.
-Also you had a fear of narrow places.
-I think it's still there, not so strong.
-Also the vinegar, if you take vinegar...
-If I smell vinegar.
-Now is the smell? The last time it was the same.
-I can not breathe if I smell vinegar, 5 sec. if I'm with the vinegar I start coughing and
if I stay more, I can not breathe at all.
-And this coughing still continues from time to time?
-I have a flu and I cough for 1 month.
-Yes but now you are in a period where your coughing is over or still...
-Now it starts. From today the coughing started.
-When you have coughing it's worse in bed, worse lying down?
-Yes, it's worse lying down. I must stay half sited and sleep in this position because if
I lie down, I can not stop my coughing. I can stop it for very short period, if I drink water.
-Cold water?
-I like and I want to drink cold water but I can not.
-Was any tuberculosis in the family?
-No.
-How is the anxiety about your health?
-Not too much.
-What about the desire for fish? Still there?
-Yes.
-Eggs?
-Yes, if there are it's OK, if not OK.
-How frequently this happens in a week to wake up from 3-4?
-In the last 3 weeks every night. In this time I watch TV for example, I can not stay.
And if I get up from the bed and do something, after a while the headache starts,
so I must stay lied down.
-There are any kind of dreams which are repeated?
-No.
-If you eat meat with fat it's OK, you can tolerate it?
-It depends, if it is well prepared, I eat it.
-You said you feel colder than before?
-Yes, I'm colder and the nails when I'm very cold they are blue.
-Where do you feel the...?
-Here in the neck I feel it.
And I still have desire to eat cream with sugar, I can eat a lot, on the bread.
-Now when you go to bed, you can not lie flat?
-No, I can not lie on the back because I have lumbar pains if I lie flat,
I must be one side or another.
-But as far as the coughing is concerned?
-I stay half and I put a pillow here in the lumbar region and it's OK.
-Perspiration during sleep?
-Not too much but if I'm cold I perspire and the perspiration is clammy.
-In order to sleep do you put socks?
-If it is very cold in the house, I put but usually not.
-Are you very irritable, very angry?
-Lately I'm quite irritable.
-In the constipation do you have a tendency to go for stool but you don't have an effect?
-No, it is the tendency, it is the effect but the stool is very hard and if I travel
I haven't stool at all 2-3 days.
-In cold dry weather you said you feel worse?
-In cold weather, it is not necessary the dry.
-Your vision that has become foggy as soon as you wake up or the whole morning?
-Not the whole morning, maybe half an hour, it depends.
And I still have those spots, I see little black spots when I read or when I look at the sun
or in strong light they appear.
I don't see great enthusiasm in the class. That is why I think...
You don't like homework I understand. I have avoided giving homework to this particular group
but this is a case which I have to study more, so if I have to study more, you better study also,
so you suffer together.
I was starting the case inside, in front of your eyes you could hear me whispering
but you don't like homework. That's why not only you will have homework but those who will get
the correct remedy they will get 50 points.
-100!
-50, it's not so difficult.
50 points for getting the remedy tomorrow morning, first thing in the morning,
not in the interval like we did at school, in the interval we studied.
Who has prescribed Kali Carbonicum? What happened? 100 and 1.
Who prescribed Causticum? 3. Who prescribed Nux vomica? 9. Sepia? 4.
Phosphorus? 2. Alumina? 3. There is a cooperation group there.
Well the remedy which I gave was Kali carbon. 200. Thank you.
Why? If you take the symptomatology Causticum is very strong especially with the last symptom
which she had. Causticum will come up in the repertorization of anybody.
Now we had to make a decision, I had to make a decision between these 3 remedies.
Was perhaps Nux vomica because she related a kind of constipation that looks like Nux vomica,
angry, irritable but what is the main problem?
The main problem is coughing and what is the position, if  she lies down she can not.
The second problem is sleeplessness after 3-4 a.m. and you go to the Repertory and you don't see
sleeplessness after 3-4 a.m. in the Repertory.
And I say this sleeplessness is a typical sleeplessness of Kali carbon.
It will wake up at 2 o'clock and can not sleep again.
-It says 2 not 3.
-There is 2-3 but she said 3-4.
So the second symptom according to my experience is Kali carbon. sleeplessness.
I see her as a human being quite composed, hard working and plus the sensititivity to drafts,
which is quite strong.
Kali carb. is one of the main remedies for affected from the draft.
They can spot a draft even if it is absolutely imperceptible by anybody else.
Silica also has this or Rhus tox, Psorinum, Nux vomica also but Kali carb. we especially stretch
when we teach Materia medica, the sensitivity to drafts so she has 3 keynotes, her main symptoms
are 3 keynotes of Kali carb.
In spite of the fact if you go to repertorization and Nux vomica may come up or Causticum may come up,
we still we have to start with Kali carb. The fact also that she goes into frequent chest problems
is another indication for Kali carb.
This is the logic for prescribing Kali carb.
-The coffee?
-The coffee is Angustura is this type. Shall we give Angustura?
Maybe she is an Angustura after all or no but if you have people who have been drinking coffee before
and you ask these people do you like coffee?
I have found out that many people stop treatment because they can not stop drinking coffee,
it's a strong habit for many people.
So it's not becoming a keynote the desire for coffee.
-Angustura has a strong desire for coffee but has no aggravation from coffee.
But she gets strong cramps after drinking coffee.
-The strong cramps I'm not sure, she said it is because of drinking coffee.
I think the coffee yes may antidote the situation and can tip her over to Calc. carb. or something
like this, that's why you have to avoid coffee absolutely.
You remember in my interview I said, how many times 3? She says 3 yes, I drunk 3 times.
I see in the voice, in the look, I hear everything, it's very difficult that they will tell me a lie
and I will believe it, sometimes I pretend yes, yes, yes. It's another story.
-I think people that need Kali carb. wouldn't tell a lie. They are honest and straight.
-Yes. Most yes. I did not take into consideration the 3-4, I looked into the Repertory
and I see no Kali carb.
Do you know why I did not take it into consideration? Can anybody tell me
why I did not take into consideration 3-4 and I took into consideration 2-3?
-Because the real time in which the Repertory was written was not 1 hour forward as we do on the middle
of the spring. In the middle of the spring we push watches 1 hour forward because we have decided it
like that, I don't know why they do it like this but the whole world pushes the watch 1 hour in front.
The Repertory when it was written it did not take into consideration these crazy ideas we had later.
So actually it means when she says 3-4 our time, it means actual time 2-3.
So we have to be aware of this idea because the Kali carb. will appear to be later in the aggravation,
if we are in the summer time.
Somebody also asked, I don't remember who asked, whether she is ticklish.
He asked for what reason? For Kali carb. But Kali carb. is especially sensitive in the soles
and they are ticklish in the sole.
-Would you have considered repeating the Calc. carb.?
-They were some keynotes missing from Calc. carb. that I had before and she did not have now.
That's why I prefer the Kali carb. Also during the phase of pneumonia, I think she needed Kali carb.
at that time, so maybe there is a Kali carb. which continues and to be there all the time
and that's why I prefer it.
-How is she now? I would like to know if there was any effect already?
-She can not know. How she slept last night?
-I didn't sleep at all.
-Very good.
-In the morning my nose was blocked and after half an hour I had pain which I have it now,
like a knife in the coxofemoral joint and I have since 1 hour flashes of heat.
My neck is stiff and I have less energy from yesterday.
-Very good prescription. Why you did not sleep? Why do you think?
-I don't know. I go to bed, I try to sleep but I can not. This happened when I start making homeopathic
treatment in Romania and my first homeopath gave me some remedies, 4-5 I can not say.
I have 5 months of insomnia, so I get up in the morning refreshed but I don't sleep the whole night.
I hope it will not be the same.
-No, tonight you will sleep. This kind of reaction is you can say it's good apart from the sleep.
You don't like that you give a remedy and they can not sleep at all, especially after Kali carb.
who complain of staying up the whole night but let's see tomorrow.
-And I have all night very dry mouth, I drink a lot of water and I still have dry mouth
not so strong like last night.
-Well, we'll see.
-We gave you a remedy for this acute that you were getting and tell us what happened.
You took it actually on Thursday?
-No, on Tuesday evening.
-It is 1 week.
-Yes.
The first night after the remedy I couldn't sleep at all, then after 2 days the cough stop
and also the sleep came, all this period I couldn't sleep. I fell asleep let's say 11-12
and I wake up at 2-3 in the morning, something like that. And I'm very tired because they
are also 6 weeks since I can not sleep at night but at home I drink coffee, so I wake up.
Here I can not drink, so I'm sleepy all the time and I'm very tired.
-You can not sleep at all after you wake up?
-After I wake up I can not sleep.
-And at what time you get up?
-6-7 I get up.
-You don't insist to see whether you will sleep between 6-9 o' clock?
-I must get up because I have work to come here, so I can not. If it happens, I sleep between 7 and 9.
Maybe I don't know, I try to find why this sleeplessness appeared and it is possible
to appear because of my new work. I started in April, I have some difficulties
I work in great stress and maybe because of this, I don't know.
-Do you feel the anxiety from your work?
-Yes I do.
-Whether you will have patients, whether you will manage to treat them, all this is an issue for you.
-Yes, this is one issue and the other one is that I'm in the beginning and if I do not have
enough patients, I will not be able to pay the expenses and this is another problem.
-So the anxiety is mostly financial insecurity and professional problems.
-Professional less.
-Mostly financial.
-Yes and I try to work more and more and sometimes I have the feeling that I work for nothing,
it's such a feeling. I work all day in the office, between 8.30 and 7 o'clock in the evening.
-Almost 12 hours.
-Yes and when I arrive at home, I start working with translations or something for
publishing till 12 o'clock. And then I wake up at 2 and it's too short to rest.
And since yesterday the cough reappeared and I feel bad.
-In the night?
-No in the afternoon and it's still there.
-In the night did you cough?
-No, now it's during the day. I feel like I have no energy.
-Of course if you don't sleep, you don't have energy.
-And because I'm tired and I cannot work this bothers me because I have no time to be ill or tired
and the desire for coffee is very strong.
-Yes. Do you have any other symptom?
-Since yesterday it reappeared the flashes of heat.
-Strong?
-So and so, not very strong.
-Anything else?
-During the day I have a moment between 2,30 and 3 o'clock where I can sleep anywhere.
The desire for sleep is so strong, I can not keep my eyes open and if I fall asleep,
I sleep 10 min. on the chair, it doesn't matter.
-You mean in the afternoon?
-Yes.
2,30-3 o'clock, something like that.
But I cannot sleep more than 10-15 min. then I wake up, I feel a little refreshed.
-Sulphur. I hear you sighing 2-3 times here, you do it more frequently?
-No, I observed 2-3 days here, I noticed myself.
-Why didn't you tell it? Not to misguide me so I give you also Ignatia,
you don't feel like taking Ignatia.
What about fruits? Do you eat fruits or not very much?
-Since last year I like to eat fruits.
-Before?
-Not so much but last summer I eat a lot of fruits.
-Perspiration where is mostly perspiration?
-In the axillae.
I'm always in a hurry and must do things very quickly and I start to do many things
at the same time and I must finish them all because if I don't finish them I don't feel well.
-Let me ask you another question. You had this change in your profession. You decided
to go privately etc. How do you feel that your husband is? He supported you or he left you
alone in this issue?
-No, he supported me but at the end of this year he has to pass an exam,
so when I come home I am alone and he is not able to support me because he has to study.
So I will be alone and he will not be able to support me at all.
-Did you feel any kind of disappointment from this situation?
-No, I'm not disappointed.
-Either from his behavior or something else that caused that grief?
-No, except from the fact that it's a new situation, it's a choice and I'm at the beginning.
I didn't work for 4 months because I had to do a lot of papers and have the permission to work in the office
and now I started, the patients are not so many because I lost the patients in that period of time,
so the problem is if I will be able to manage with this situation and if I will be able to have enough money
to pay all the taxes and to live also.
-Tuberculinum not Medorrhinum. With my first banana he makes me Tuberculinum.
-3 rubrics anxiety business about and sleeplessness midnight after 3 o'clock,
Nux vomica after 3 o'clock in the morning.
And not that Nux vomica is a very good remedy for sleeplessness
and she has a lot of thought about her work.
-A lot of thoughts keep you awake?
-Not all the time, sometimes if I can not sleep.
-There is a rubric that might be better. It's a mind fear of business failure.
-Do you feel cold or you became more warm after Kali carb.?
-I think it's cold because somebody told me you dressed like in winter, yesterday morning.
After Calcar. I'm more cold, after Sepia I was more warm. Now I'm more cold.
-Now you are more cold and the sensitivity to air draft is still there?
-Yes. I want to mention that the sleeplessness is for 6 weeks not for 8 days.
-The sleeplessness it appears to be the underline problem, the deeper problem from the acute,
so she had the acute and she had sleeplessness. So we gave a remedy for the acute,
the acute was touched but the sleeplessness was not touched.
We have to find what was underneath
and the interesting thing is that Nux vomica is complementary to Kali carb.
-And to Sepia.
-Nux vomica is a good idea, is the correct idea? This is what you have to find out.
Fear of poverty, anxiety about business you have to take out one of the two.
Fear of poverty, take it out. Do you have any constipation?
-Yes a chronic one.
-What type? No urge? 2-3 days no urge or there is urge but no effect?
-No, it can pass 2-3 days without any urge.
-And the stool is soft or hard?
-Hard. Now from the diet I eat something to have stool next morning, I must take care.
-But if you take care, that means if you eat zucchini?
-The stool is still hard.
-Is it like sheep dung?
-Yes.
-I'll tell you something. I was not in Nux vomica though the computer was saying,
I didn't want to give Nux vomica and I wanted to give a remedy which is similar to Nux vomica.
It contains the same substance which is Ignatia.
-But you persuaded me that your thinking with your computers is better than mine,
so we will give... what potency? Let's give 200 Nux vomica. See if you sleep tonight.