-I have to say that I'm very excited to read my report because old things came up and
have been actualized by the remedy.
I want to give the title to this report. An old wisdom is saying, die before you live.
After I've been home, I had a state of indifference for about 2 days and on the third day
a heaviness in my legs started.
It was a lead like heaviness, especially in the thighs which made it nearly impossible
for me to climb steps. Every step was combined with pains in my thighs and even going
up to my office, which means climbing up one set of stairs, I had to interrupt 3 times.
-So much. Most of the heaviness was on thighs or on legs?
-It was totally in the legs but the main point was in the thighs.
I didn't get enough air, I was completely exhausted if I was taking 3 times the 3 steps.
This state was going on for about 2 weeks and nevertheless I was able to go on with the
work in my practices, my patients even remarked that I was inwardly disturbed but
nevertheless I could follow the duties of my practices and keep going.
Very orderly concerning the orders I was conducting my practices.
Afterwards my back was aching, the lower part and for about 8 days it was nearly unbearable pain.
-In the lower part of thoracic region or lower part of the back?
-Like lumbago, in the lower part of the spine. Then this heaviness went up to my head.
And I felt like being surrounded by fog. And my thinking got very very slow and heavy.
An incredible tiredness overcame my whole body, my whole organism and I permanently
had the desire to lie down and just sleep.
But the pressure in my (?) region that later on had gone down to my stomach was dissolving.
Of course I had the most difficulties to go on doing my practices because of the
slowness of my thinking and the difficulty to actualize knowledge.
So often helped myself by sending my patients for 5 minutes back into the waiting room
to study the case again, to reactualize the knowledge because the knowledge was there
I just couldn't get and use it. And so then called them back after 5 minutes.
About 6 weeks later, I had a horrible dream.
I was called out of my bed at night, I was brought to Court which was consisting of
University Professors going back to the time when I was studying at University and in
this Court was my father too.
-As a Judge?
-No as a Judge, he was sitting in the room and they were accusing me that I had been
treating two intensive care patients homeopathically.
Which and I could prove this when I was defending myself, which got better by my
homeopathic treatment.
But they said that I had given away, I had betrayed the knowledge that I got from them.
I asked my father if he would have anything to comment on my behalf to defend me and
he said no, nothing. And so they judged me and withdrew my license to practice Medicine.
-Does he feel that he ever treated such cases?
-I have been treating two such cases, I really did this actually.
-And the cases in the dream were concerning these two cases?
-Not exactly but similar.
The following days were very difficult for me to go to my practices and a deep
sadness was coming back to me.
And so suicidal thoughts came up again. I wanted to drive, go to the mountains and
throw myself from a high mountain.
And because this state was really getting unbearable, I started repertorising and I
found that Sulphur is listed in the rubric one's to throw himself from heights and I
repeated Sulphur C200. That was about 6 weeks after the first dose.
After the second dose, the suicidal thoughts disappeared but it was clear to me that
my life would go on and in front of all I would never do this to my wife, to leave her.
-He was thinking of leaving his wife?
-No, he said that I was very sure that my life would go on and I would never impose
such terrible fact to my wife to leave her by suicide.
The next thing that was remarkable was that my sexual desire completed vanished.
I had the impression that my sexual energy was going upwards and spreading like
around the navel and going upwards into the inner part.
At the same time I had the feeling of a tender dedication ,devotion to my wife.
-The feelings about his wife became deeper?
-Yes. I wanted to talk about some physical symptoms that appeared.
Several times I got very sour lips and herpes.
Then the old symptom reappeared pains in my left leg that were impeding my sleep.
Then a new symptom came, strong, cramp like pains in my neck and the permanent
desire to cover my neck with a (?_.
-When he says neck, he means the back of the neck? -Yes.
-And he had to cover it because he was sensitive to drafts?
-Yes, I got very sensitive to draft and to wrap it up with a (?) was really ameliorating very much.
And it was going that far because we always sleep with an open window
I would protect my neck by wearing the (?) at night too.
The backaches, after this crisis of about 14 days duration, got bearable then but they
got worse by standing, they got worse by seating up right.
I always had to bend to ameliorate them.
Nevertheless I had a very strong desire to straighten up, to end to walk upright, straight.
And I had this inner feeling nobody is ever allowed again to break my back.
-One question. In previous years he was ever teaching in the University?
-When I was assistant at University, I was teaching too.
Then I got very sensitive gums. The mucus membranes on the gums got very sensitive
and it was easily bleeding.
A new symptom was that I got an urge to go for stool after eating.
And another symptom was that my finger nails were tearing the length, alongside.
Now it exists an irresistible desire for order and I do everything that has to be done on that day
and I never leave my practices without doing the least bit that had to be done.
So I was finishing every day with a good feeling that I could die, a good inner feeling
that everything is in order and if something would happen to me, I could die in peace.
There is still a lack of courage and an anxious feeling in the morning which are at least
ameliorated for about 50-60 % in comparison with what it has been.
Especially in correlation with a total disappearance of this pressure feeling in my thorax
and in my abdomen.
I'm still easily embarrassed and my memory got better though but still I have problems
to actualize, to immobilize my knowledge quickly.
In front of all I have these tormenting thoughts for words or sentences that I have read before.
-Repeating? Trying to remember?
-Recollecting.
There is still an indifference towards pleasure and enjoyment and that
is especially when around several people talking, I have to ask 3 times to find out what has been said.
But I have the impression that my inner energy is getting more and that I'm slowly
in small steps opening up to my surroundings.
I got very sensitive in my feelings towards my 3 daughters and I always have to cry
without any limits on the telephone when they talk to me or write to me, when they
say they have a very understanding father.
And it's terrible to think about it that for 40 years I have been able to give all this love
and attention and energy to my patients but that I have been unable to give, during the
age of rising them, the same amount of love and attention to my daughters.
-So he feels guilty for that?
-I don't feel guilty anymore because I know that my 3 daughters have forgiven me.
Often I'm angry and annoyed about my patients and I feel this anger and annoyment
against my patients and my profession which has been hindering me to show the same
amount of intensity and devotion for my family.
That I have really made a very important step in my development, I got to know, I found
out when this year I have been in England in an English family where I try to improve
my English knowledge...
-What year was that?
-This year, in March. This is connected to my desire to open more to my environment
to my surroundings and to be more able to communicate with them.
And with this family father at the same time he has been my teacher of English.
I had a pretty heavy discussion, argument with him and he had really deeply insulted me
because ha again tried to put me back into the form rubric of a Nazi, because I was German
but I was accepting this argument and later on he was apologizing and saying
that I might be different German.
That was for me the sign that I really made a step ahead, that I'm able to accept an argument and
too that it is possible by talking and speaking with one, another,
there is a sort of possible understanding.
That's the end of my report.
-I want to know if this sensitivity on the neck still continues.
-It's still there slightly but it got better meanwhile.
I forgot something very important.
After these few silent thoughts have not completely vanished, I took Sulphur 1M on the
24th of January 1999 and these thoughts completely vanished then.
-Also he was talking about this heaviness in the head.
This heaviness went away? Slowly is going down, completely gone or still is there?
It's still there for about 30%.
-His desire for order continues?
-Yes, it's still there and it costs me a lot to overcome myself. It's still very strong need and
desire for this order but at the same time it costs me a lot of energy to overcome myself to do it.
-The emptiness he had mentioned at 11 o'clock?
-It's still there.
-The waking after 4,30 in the morning?
-I still wake up very early, around 5 o'clock and I still have the desire to go for stool
around 6 o'clock in the morning. And vertigo in high places got very much better.
I think that's about 20% left and standing aggravating is still the same.
-Is any difference in his temperature concerning his body or feet?
-No, it's still there but I think the intensity of heat in my feet got a little bit less and I don't
put them out of cover, as often as I used to.
-Also if I understood well, it's an interesting symptom, where he said I want now to sit
upright and it seems to me that inwardly feels more upright. Is that correct?
-Yes.
-The desire for sweets?
-It's still there but when I eat a bar of chocolate, I would unfortunately finished it but
I don't go and buy that much chocolate anymore, not to be tempted much.
-Also I understood that his feelings are opening and still the joy of life is not there.
Or sometimes now it may come?
-Yes it comes because certain songs I would sing every morning.
-He started singing again?
-I'm not a great singer, I'm more concerned about the context, the words, it's very important to me.
I'm very much occupied with music and I'm playing several instruments too.
-Also I understood that he has a better idea to look after himself.
-Yes, that is true. That is correct.
-OK, thank you. Still he is sighing very much, during the interview he was sighing very much.
Is this something that happens all the time or only here it happens?
-When I'm excited and in inner turmoil, then I'm sighing.
-But is it something that he noticed to happen frequently?
-Not really anymore.
-OK.
-What is your decision? Who says wait? Who says repeat? Who says higher potency?
Who says repeat later?
So we don't have much to say about the case. The class is too good. Very good.
This is the right decision. I hope you have been convinced that you don't need to give
with everything one remedy. This is the message !
It's very important of course to evaluate correctly whether a remedy is acting or not.
This is another story because you maybe waiting on something
which has not acted or acted superficially.
Because, as I said, you give an Ignatia or you give a Nat. muriaticum, the patient comes
and tells you I feel better psychologically.
If you see the case has not moved, especially if you see there is no initial aggravation
the organism is shaken...
You remember what she says? If I have to go through all the pains, I don't want the same remedy.
Your remedy has to move the organism and then don't be afraid, let it act.
But if you wait on a Nat. muriaticum because he told you, he comes with headaches
with pains, with this, with that, she says I feel somewhere better psychologically and
you wait, you can wait for the rest of your life. Nothing will happen.
Because this is a very superficial prescription.
In the same way, I'll give you some more examples for you to understand what I mean
by superficial prescription.
Somebody comes and tells you that he has a pain on the right hypochondrium and
the pain is extending on the back. You immediately think Chelidonium and you give
a dose of Chelidonium and he comes back after 20 days and says, the pain from the
next day it was gone.
-Still is gone? Yes. And then you check the other organism and you see no other changes,
just this pain is gone. The most probable is that after some time even that pain will be back.
The fact that some pain will go away, it does not mean that your remedy is acting.
Maybe the patient feels that this is a good doctor because my pain goes away.
That is not the idea. Here you understood the idea of curing in a deeper level is to
see all the laws we have for a cure to be applied in the case.
Do the laws apply? Another thing which is new, even for Greek doctors who hear my
teachings since 39 years, the new thing is this.
When you see the acute arising this has to be evaluated how you are going to treat and
what you are going to give in conjunction with the treatment and usually, not always
as we explained, an acute means the case is progressing.
You remember for instance the case that we are speaking about that after Ignatia 50M
he had several acutes, which he went through without anything.
Bronchitis, bronchopneumonia, 1,2,3 acutes and after these acutes he developed
the picture of Sulphur. The Sulphur went deeper. He says, now I can stand.
I like to stand straight. We say, stoop shouldered.
It's very interesting to observe these things. In Sulphur we say, he is stoop shouldered.
It means that type where he tries to concentrate upon himself and to think and suddenly
the organism says no. Your real position is to stand straight. Forget this, your habits.
And he expressed it, not because he wanted to say, I'm not Sulphur anymore.
He just said what he felt. He felt he wants to sit straight. It's very interesting.
So therefore we conclude that this stoop shouldered position is a pathological condition
and it can be used as a symptom.
The idea is that I can not sit straight. They stand like this, tired all the time.
Not possible to stand for five minutes. Not that this symptom is enough for you to
prescribe, worse standing, Sulphur. Don't do this.
I'm just picking some symptoms. The 11 time aggravation, you remember he had this.
Why do you say wait therefore?
Because on the one hand we see he is doing better definitely.
On the other hand we don't see the picture of a new remedy.
Still he has Sulphur symptomatology.
Therefore the most probable for you, you don't prescribe but you have in your mind
that next time he will come, most probably he will be in a Sulphur condition.
But this is supposition, it's not a certainty.
You can not say take Sulphur and after 20 days you take it. You can not say that.