-You took Nat. mur. 50M on Friday afternoon.
-And about 20 min. afterwards my back pain was about 60-70% better and the back was
getting better on Saturday before noon it was getting better hour by hour...
Then it was stable and on Monday morning it got better again so that after Monday
it was being like 95% better.
Yesterday it was a slight aggravation again but together with some grief coming up.
Saturday I realized that I was much more sensitive to the sun and also to salt.
I had aversion to the salt of the sea, I got nausea.
-From going to the sea?
-Yes, I was swimming.
After swimming the back was a little bit worse and my hands smell so much salty,
although I had showered and it made me nauseous.
Saturday morning I was really angry. Not towards a person or circumstance
but just it was coming out.
-Anger which was against yourself or against anybody?
-No, just anger towards anybody. I realized that I was starting to allow myself
to have a bad mood which I didn't before, I was always trying to be nice.
Yesterday it was interesting because during these days I had talked with several people
and they asked how I was doing on psychological level also and I told them what I said
now also and they said, it's good for you and it's good for your marriage also.
And I had this same talk in German, in English and yesterday in Swedish.
I was born in Sweden and after this talk in Swedish I was really angry again.
It was coming up very much anger, so I was astonished why? I had exactly the same talk
just the language was different.
-What was your conclusion? Why the anger came?
-I found out after that, grief came up, that I didn't think before it was a grief situation.
That was the fact that when I was 13 years old, I had to move from Sweden to Austria.
My family was moving down to Austria, which was a hard time for me, it was a terrible
situation for me; I didn't like it. I didn't like the language also.
-The German language you mean?
-Yes, in some way I still don't.
I like the Swedish language much more but I'm still astonished, a lot of grief and pain
came up from this situation and I'm still astonished that this has such an impact.
But this age at 13 was the time when I had a major outbreak, I had juvenile rheumatoid arthritis
since 8 years of age.
When I was 13 there was a major outbreak with an infection and I was 3 1/2 months in hospital
and got a lot of cortisone, masses of cortisone.
After that, what I told you, the shaking, the stiffness of neck got really started.
My insecurity and timidity was there before and so this night I wake up again and
I was thinking further back to a point when I was 6 years old.
I had a bicycle accident when I was 6 years old and I always thought that this was kind of
the beginning of my social phobia, this insecurity in public.
I was going downhill with the bicycle and something came towards me and I was going
away with the head...
I had a brain concussion, I was unconscious and after that incident I started, when I would go to
children's parties, I would get strong nausea whenever we were beginning to eat.
At that point I would say, I feel so bad, I want to go home.
After that I started to avoid the parties and my parents told me that I was timid before that
but I'm not sure about it.
For me this was starting point and then tonight there was another thing coming up,
which is rather strange.
When I was in hospital with this knee infection, in the time of recovery, I had two dreams
which were in awakening state.
I wasn't sleeping but I was awake and those were really terrible dreams.
And I've been thinking about those dreams for a while and also during the treatment
that I have now, since 1995, after one remedy these dreams came back.
I was drinking tea in the evening and couldn't sleep and after work the next day
I went to sleep for 1 hour and waking up I was in this dream state again.
This state is so terrible that I know if it wouldn't have stopped, I would have shoot myself.
If I had a revolver in my home.
-During that dream state you feel so bad that you can not tolerate it for more than few minutes?
-I woke up and I was in that dream state and I run out to the kitchen and put water on my face
and ate an apple and got out of it.
Maybe I will tell you those 2 dreams.
-Originally was the same dream as the one that you are going to say?
-Yes. It was one of those two dreams.
When I was in hospital, when I was 13 years old, I had the feeling that I was a big
balloon and I was floating towards the city. And the buildings were like peaks...
-To break the balloon?
-Yes, and it was like threatening that if I go down there...
This was the first dream.
-That is when you were 13 in Sweden or in Austria?
-That was first or second  year in Austria. I was awake and I wanted to call the nurse
but I couldn't call.
The other dream doesn't have sequence of action. It's just a state or feeling that I always try to
describe it to myself and the best way I can describe it is this:
If you have a mathematical equation and you can't solve it, it's unsolvable.
That's how I can describe it in another way.
But that was the state that came back and this is so terrible and even when I was telling this
to my homeopath, when at first was trying to think about it, I would come back to that state again.
Now I think something happened tonight.
Maybe I'm not affected so much by it.
-That is the last time that you see it.
-Yes and what I tried to reason up, what is this about, one explanation that I came up with,
which I don't know if it's true or not, is that it has to do maybe with the accident.
Maybe these two dreams have to do with what I experienced in this accident going down
with the head and then with the state, I don't know, maybe.
-Well, I can give you my idea as somebody who is looking from outside, which is really you felt
by going into the new city that this city was so inimical to you that could kill you actually
and the moment that you have no protection, you are just alone and you are in that city,
which is full of spikes can just blow the balloon.
This is very characteristic of the state, of the sensitivity on which you were and the feelings
that you had when you were in the new city and also the second dream is a dead end,
you can not solve.
You are in a new city, you can do nothing.
You are going to stay there, you don't like it but you are going to stay there, it's a dead end.
But what I wanted to know is, did you cry at all these days?
-No. There was all the time very slight sadness coming up but I didn't cry.
-In the near future you will have an opportunity, something will touch you
and you may have to cry and ...
But it is very interesting what you are saying, especially the dreams and the state which
comes back as a pathology.
It is like a pathology which happened during that time and came back as an old symptom returning.
Anything more that you noticed?
-Maybe a slight more perspiration all over the body. Maybe it's also because of the heat.
-What about the eruptions around the genitals?
-I have noticed no change and I don't even know if these tissues are going to recover ever
because this is also wide.
-OK, thank you.
-This is an example of a case where we have an acute which fits also the chronic state.
The same remedy is indicated in both acute and chronic states.
The idea is now that he has to allow this remedy to go on without further interference.
That's the one. The second is concerning what we have been talking already that in his case,
there are certain psychological states which can be described in different ways.
If, for instance, you take down his case and you look for the symptoms, what symptoms
you are going to write down?
It is important to see whether you describe well, correctly the feelings that he has.
You see the difficulty already, if you want to describe a symptom. It's not easy.
Another dilemma that we will have is this.
The dreams, which he has, do they belong to Nat. mur. or belong to a general idea?
Can you say that dreams of being a balloon is a dream of Nat. mur. or can you say that
the dreams which depict that the individual is in a very sensitive state, dreams of being in danger,
of being killed perhaps, that would be better?
You see the difference when you want to write down his symptoms?
What are you going to write down?
If you write dreams of being a balloon is not enough.
Dreams of being in danger is not enough. What actually said is, I felt threatened by this new town
in which they put me and that was a terrifying experience, that this town was so inimical
that all the buildings have spikes that could blow me up.
But there is another new symptom which is much more easy to describe.
When we took his case, do you like salt? He says, no. I don't like salt. Why?
Because his organism receives salt with every substance he takes.
Anything, any food contains some salt, the organism absorbs it.
The moment you give more, then the organism is overwhelmed and he feels a salty taste
in his hands.
That is a symptom definitely, the way he described it exactly, you can write it down
as a new symptom for Nat. mur.
Because that is why we have in Nat. mur. desire but also aversion to salt.
And that one time, maybe not now, we talk about the primary and secondary action of the remedies.
This is a condition in which we have a secondary action of the remedy.
If he allows and does not interfere with any other remedy, then the real benefit of this remedy
will be shown in 6 months.
That is why it is important for you to understand that you have to wait, wait and observe
the changes.
He is going to cry because he did not cry most probably at the age of 6, of 13.
Now what was happening? All this grief was changing the chemistry of the body.
And grief always is a matter of chemistry.
It has an initiation because of a psychological event but this initiation brought about
chemical change in the body and the body keeps on the wrong chemistry
and keeps up the depression.
So depression and all the symptoms they have their equivalent into the body.
-Last September you took Nat. mur. 50M. What happened?
-I had the first follow up, a few days after, where I told you that a grief had come up from
the past and I had quite strong emotional pain for 3 days, after that, I felt it very strong.
-Mostly on the solar plexus?
-Yes and then one night I was crying out to know, because I still couldn't understand why I'm moving
from one country to the other, which was the cause of the grief.
Why that would affect me so much? So one night I was just crying out to know what happened
and in the moment I cried it was like a curtain was rolling down and the whole thing closed down.
After that the pain vanished which was strange because the pain was quite strong.
-If I understand well because I have a problem with your English pronunciation, you had
this grief in the past?
-The situation was that after the Nat. mur. I had a conversation in Swedish, I grew up in Sweden,
I was born there and after that I felt a lot of anger and grief coming up and somehow I realized that
this grief was about the fact that I had to move from Sweden to Austria with my family when
I was 13 years old and I told you 2 dreams and you interpreted those dreams.
But still I didn't understand why moving from one country to another would be so painful?
After that I didn't have much emotional pain.
-Which after that? After that night when you spoke and you cried?
-I just cried up to god to know why this would cause so much grief and
what this grief was all about?
I didn't understand why moving from Sweden to Austria would affect my life so much
and then it was like a curtain rolled down and the whole thing closed down.
So I didn't see anything. The pain vanished so it was OK for me.
Maybe I will tell you the main things.
When I was going back to Austria there wasn't a clear aggravation, there was a symptom
that I haven't told you yet.
-For you back pain you mean?
-No, back pain was OK.
-It was gone already by the time you left Alonissos?
-Yes, it took 3 days and then everything was OK.
I had aggravation symptom. I used to have for some years before that, cramps in the esophagus
which would be very peristaltic cramps when I would eat certain foods
especially when I was starting eating very fast and be very tense and the foods are
mostly like sour pears, sour apple, red wine, maybe pasta food, spicy food
but not all spicy food.
I'm not really sure what's the common thing with these foods, mostly sour and spicy.
-Will cause a spasm?
-I think as if the food gets stuck. I would sit on the table, I would eat, start eating normally,
maybe too fast and then the pain will come. I feel the peristaltic movements down here,
it's very painful, extremely painful and often I would have to get up from the table
and go to the toilet and spit it out because it is very strong pain and then the food
would come out with a lot of mucus.
There was a strong aggravation of that symptom in the beginning.
In the following months that symptom continued in the same frequency and the same intensity
but afterwards - I will tell that later - I had a fasting period where it disappeared
and since then I haven't had it.
There was a.. which ameliorated it.
I had a major dental work done the summer before I took Nat. mur. and after that
I had chronic pulpitis in all those teeth which they worked on and I couldn't chew with them
without pain.
There was a real amelioration of that, it's still there but I have been taking aspirin
for a month and it had become a little bit better.
In middle November I've told you about the collagen disease
I have lichen sclerosus e atrophicus.
That is a Latin name we use.
-What was the disease?
-It is a wide eruption of the glands of the penis where the tissue becomes fibrous
and it shrinks, there is atrophy.
As a result of that I had very strong pain when I had erection and coition.
In middle November I looked at my penis and it was gone.
-Just like that?
-Yes, the tissue was back to normal which I wouldn't have thought that it would ever be
but after 2-3 weeks it was back to where it was and still is. So it was gone for short time.
But it has not been painful since then. I have been able to have coition without pain.
Just maybe a little bit of sourness but not much.
Before that the mucus membrane would crack and would have to wait for 1 week to be able to
have coition again because it was so painful.
-Before, you had to wait for a week before you can have again because of the pain?
-There was pain during coition but the tissue was shrunk, so with the erection would crack
and would be wounds.
-But not anymore?
-No, no just a little bit sourness.
Since the end of the year I discovered white spots here on the forehead between the eyebrows
which I still have some of them and then in December and January I developed strong craving
for chocolate.
I was waking up in the morning and the first thought I had was how do I get a chocolate today?
And at the same time a craving for sex.
-In the morning?
-No, any time.
It was pretty strong. In February I started a fasting period where I was for the first 3 days
just with water and then 40 days with partial fast, leaving out one meal the day
and of course then I didn't concentrate on sex and chocolate because I didn't eat
chocolate at that time.
What was really striking to me was how well I felt during this fasting period.
It was like first time in my life that I felt that I had energy to do things.
Before I always knew I wanted to do things but I always knew I had very little energy
to do things, I was living on reserve energy.
But this was incredible, I knew I can do it.
-Very good.
-Also in that time the esophagus cramps vanished and after that I haven't really had them.
Maybe a little bit only.
What happened after the fasting in May, I had two episodes of hiccup for 1 1/2 day.
First time I've been in a Chinese restaurant with spicy food.
Second time it was in a Turkish restaurant also with spicy food and there would be
a constant hiccup.
It would be for 2 1/2 days and it would merely stopped for little while
and then it would come again and it was connected with the food I ate.
Especially the second time there were some eructations also and I would have an eructation
and the hiccup would start.
Also when the hiccup was there, the acid would thrown up to the esophagus.
First time it was connected with a cough, when I would cough, it would start also but
it was pretty strong hiccup, I don't know if I should describe this more in details.
I've never had it since then.
My main complains have always been and still is my inability to move in company
and in public.
-Still aversion to company?
-I don't really have aversion company. I don't have aversion to people or company but
there is a great fear and cramping in company, especially in front of people when
attention is directing towards me, which I had since my childhood?
-Yes, but how is that in comparison? Do you see any changes, 10 or 20%?
-Yes, I would say before I came to Alonissos it was 10% better.
Being here in Alonissos is even better, maybe 20% but how can I evaluate it?
People have told me that I have changed and I think so.
-Your timidity, you would say is 20% better, something like that?
-Maybe 20%. I'm a little bit more relaxed in company. Maybe I should tell you
the way I would describe it before Nat. mur. I read what you said about Nat. mur.
You said fear of being hurt, that fits very well. Sometimes I thought I don't go into
company because I want to avoid of getting hurt.
And also this constant self awareness you say. Maybe I can describe it like if I would
be sitting in a café and reading a book on a table and several people sitting around
when I would turn the page in the book, I would be thinking that I'd had to turn this page
in a way that none around can say I did it in the wrong way. One woman would be looking probably.
That was very strong and also like if I would cross a place with other people
I would think I have to put this page in a way that none can say I did it wrong.
That was very strong and was very sick and tormenting also.
-How is that?
-It's better.
-How much?
-I'm not sure.
It's more than 15%, maybe 18%.
What has become stronger is the emotional pain. What happened after the Nat. mur.
when I was sitting in the class and they were follow ups, I could hardly stand it because
people when talking about the sufferings, I think especially those who are talking about
emotional sufferings, I could hardly stand listening not because of sympathy but
because it reminded me my own pain.
And this happened now again since last Monday.
When I came to Alonissos I was perfectly well and happy and optimistic and I'm most of the time.
But when the follow up started, I started to feel this pain again and I had a full week
of very strong emotional pain, last week.
And I realized that what I mostly do when I get an emotional heat, the way I know how
to handle this is to just forget it, don't think about it and as long as I don't think about it
I'm perfectly well.
But this time I didn't, try to appear nice or happy. So I think maybe that's a good development
because I'm getting more in touch with emotions and maybe the mental symptoms
are a little bit better.
I have maybe two symptoms that I haven't told you of, yet. I have warts on my sole.
-Many warts?
-Yes.
-Painful?
-No.
There are only some left here.
-They were gone by Nat. mur.?
-No, I got Thuja before. I got for 1 1/2 year I got Thuja 3 times.
They were gone completely from Thuja and then they came back after Thuja.
Even before the Natrum.
-Now after the Natrum came even more or they are the same?
-I think they stayed the same. Maybe a little bit more.
Another strange symptom is that I don't eat sweets after 6 o'clock in the evening
because if I do, I can not sleep.
-The aversion to milk is still there?
-I don't drink it. There are some minor symptoms which only took a few days which
I can tell you if you need more information.
-Yes.
-I had directly after Nat. mur. still here in Alonissos, I had periods of bad hearing
especially on the left ear, which I have had in the treatment previous years also very shortly.
Then in the beginning of November I had a very short period of an old symptom,
which for many years had gone and also during the treatment getting hungry just before going to bed.
I would go to bed and get hungry and then I would get up and eat something.
But that was very short.
In January I had a period of forgetting what I wanted to say in the process of
concentrating upon something.
My memory has been bad since a cannabis indica experience that I had on 87
where I drunk a beer which was drugged. I guess it was. I drunk a beer which was dragged
and for two weeks afterwards I had Cannabis indica symptoms.
I don't know what was in the beer but I had also my memory got worse and the
memory is the only symptom that had remained from this experience.
-How much cannabis you took?
-I don't know. It was in Athens, I took a beer, I think there was something in there.
-Ah, you think there was something in the beer. You mean in a party?
-No. I didn't take voluntarily. It was someone who cheated me, I sat down in Athens
to drink a beer with a person I didn't know.
-And he put most probably cannabis and he told you afterwards?
-No, no. Then he asked me to go for another beer and actually I didn't want to but
somehow I was very strong bond to this person, I thought I have to be polite and I went
with him to drink a beer and there when I said I wanted to leave, someone very quickly
came and with a new kind of beer and they filled up my glass, which was almost full
and then I took one sip and I was almost gone.
-Unconscious?
-Yes, I really had to fight to stay awake after just one sip. So I got out there and
the effect of the second sip of beer of this strong effect stopped after 15 min. but
the effect of the first drug took the next day and the day after, on the train from Vienna
to Gratz, I realized that I was coming back into myself. I had been away and I was
coming back into myself.
The following two weeks when driving to work, I would go out of myself and I would
have to pull myself back again and I have fear of insanity.
-With panic state?
-No, it was not so strong, I had never had fear of insanity in my life but I know since then
how it is and I had fear of going to sleep and also my memory ...
-You lost your memory?
-Yes.
Before I would never had to write anything down, even if you tell me to bring yourself in a year,
I wouldn't write it down but since then I have to.
This period with the memory was for one week. That was in January but generally my memory
is not as good as it was since this experience.
-The Nat. mur. had any effect on your memory?
-No, I don't think so but it isn't really strong problem, it's just something that I realize.
-Have you finished? I want to ask you some questions.
-I just had a minor flu in December for two days where I had nausea, headaches and vertigo
when getting up, which I've never had before.
-Getting up from bed?
-No, from the chair.
-I would like to know about your thirst, how is your thirst?
-My thirst hasn't change.
-Salt?
-No.
-Still you don't like salt?
-I don't need it, I don't care much for salt.
-The sun how you react?
-I'm still sensitive, the same as before.
-And sweets?
-I think it's still more than before Nat. mur. a little bit more.
-Was the position for sleep did it change? You sleep in a different position now?
-No.
-Do you sleep right through the night or you wake up?
-My sleep is better.
-And it's more refreshing now?
-Yes, I guess so.
Mostly my sleep problems would be when I was nervous that I wouldn't
sleep well. I think that's a little bit better.
-The remedy from which pharmacy you took?
-The Nat. mur. I got from here.
-OK, what we have to do is just to wait.
Don't drink coffee of course and take other medication and I believe you may see
in the long run complete change, in a year.