-The last 4 months since my last follow up here, I most of the time had the feeling as
if I was not recovering from a severe illness. I'd like to describe some physical complains.
This time was characterized by recurrent pains in my legs of different kinds which I will
explain further in a short while.
Twice I had states with extremely painful cramps in my calves during the night, very bad.
These two nights when it's occurred, I tried to get up and walk around.
Every once in a while I used to have cramps in my calves before and then
helped me to get up and walk.
But this time with this incident now, the pain was so severe that I was not able to get
out of bed and my leg was drawn together in the knee joint; I needed 5-10 min. of
massaging my muscles to ease...
-You were shouting?
-Yes, yes.
And after that I managed to finally get up and walk around and then the pain
subsided and this happened twice.
I noticed that quite regularly I have cramps in my calves when I take off my gardening boots.
I work in the garden a lot and wear high rubber boots and every time I take the off
I have a cramp.
Now I'd like to say something about the pains in my legs.
Every time I had a lot of physical exertion, these pains developed over night into the
next day and they were stitching and cutting pains that I could not get out of bed the
next morning. And any movement aggravated.
Just quietly lying there ameliorated and almost always my right leg which was affected
and the central area of the pain was mainly in my hip, in my upper leg, in my thigh
and the quality was cutting and tearing and stitching.
And these pains I had in my hip and in my thigh extended downwards into my lower
limb all the way down to my ankles.
The first time these pains appeared was about the mid of June and it occurred after
I carried some very heavy stones but I'm absolutely positive that I did not twist anything
or have any torsion or something. It was just a muscular problem due to over exertion.
I then took vitamin B12 in high doses. I had an amelioration after 2 days with it and after
a total time of 14 days, the pain subsided.
-How much high is the dose of vitamin B?
-About 600-1000 mm. per day.
This incident repeated itself another 2 times. The last time was about 5 weeks before
I came to Alonissos this time.
-While he was taking the vitamin?
-No, I had stopped taking the vitamin after it got better and then when it happened
again I took them again but they hardly had any effect.
Then I turned to taking vitamin B6 and Magnesium and that made the pain barely
tolerable but I had the pains the entire time, these past 5 weeks.
I arrived here on the island with pain. I was able to walk but I constantly had some
kind of pain. Yesterday the pains had aggravated severely, I could not walk anymore
so I decided to stay at home in the afternoon and lie down.
Because lying stretched out on my bed, that ameliorates.
-The pain you are talking about is on the right leg, starting from the hip joint, going down?
-Yes but the center of the pain is in the middle of my thigh.
And I also have the feeling of a sore pain in the middle of the bone of my thigh.
-It means inside the bone?
-Inside the bone. And then I had a kind of intuition. I had cold feet, since long time
I didn't have that anymore. In the last times they turned colder again and so yesterday
I decided to put on shocks in bed and miraculously enough over night the pains
ameliorated quite a lot and so today I'm able to walk again and come up, here.
-Very interesting for the next remedy which is developing.
-Another complain which is already existing since 1 1/2 years but I think I never really
mentioned it in this intensity here in the follow ups is that I have bleeding of my gums.
It's started the moment I stopped smoking. Since then I suffer from it.
-How many years ago?
-1 and 1/2 years ago he stopped smoking.
They bleed immediately when I brush my teeth and also already after slight touch.
What I also had once was something I had had before in former times already
a short, very intense, burning pain behind my sternum, almost like cold, hot cold.
And for a short while it just takes my breath.
-This pain how long ago he had it?
-It started when I started homeopathic treatment here and it just reoccurs on and off
every once in a while I have it.
-He did not have it before homeopathic treatment here?
-Not this kind. I had had a pressure behind my sternum but never this intense pain
with such a burning quality.
-How long it lasts this and how frequent? One minute?
-It lasts one minute and it occurred twice in this time.
Then I noticed that these last weeks I feel an urge, a need to stretch in the morning
after waking and that does me very good.
I would like to say something now about my mental-emotional situation.
Strong slowness overwhelmed me. I'm very slow. I now feel the need to slowly and
thoroughly incorporate my knowledge, whereas in former times I was interested one time
in this more and on that and I was not so concentrated, not so focused on the subject
of my studies.
And I became extremely sensitive to cruelty. Before I could watch some movies, some
criminal movies and now I can not watch anything of that kind anymore, I can not take
watching anything with any hint of cruelty in it.
Concerning my fears I noticed that I have a special fear of insects, if I see a bug crawling
on the ground I always shudder and I'm also afraid of spiders.
I don't kill them anymore, that has become impossible for me to do but I really make
sure that I remove them from my room or from my house in any possible manner.
Right now I feel I would not be able to work as emergency doctor, taking care of the
wounds of people who have been in accidents, just having a clear mind and doing what
is necessary; right now it would not be possible for me at all.
I also noticed great difficulty to write down my thoughts on paper. The thoughts are good
but I can't put them down. If I want to sit down and write them down, at that moment
there is a kind of blockage, I just can't write them and I don't know why.
What I still have is the aggravation in the morning. These states of anxiety or sadness
or any kind of unpleasant emotional things are always come over me in the morning
while I'm awakening.
There is another thing which I think I have not mentioned until now, I can not tolerate
tight clothing nowhere.
But in spite of my slowness, which I have accepted in the meantime, I feel hopeful and  optimistic.
-I want to ask some questions. Originally he had mentioned a vertigo from high places.
Has he checked this out?
-I go on top of my roof because I have to but I don't feel well at all when I do that.
-The last interview he was mentioning about a lumbar region pain when standing.
He did not mention that pain now. It was not noticeable?
-It's true, I have the feeling that this pain in my back somehow moved into my legs.
-Last time he said there is a sore pain in the mouth, now he says bleeding.
-No, I do not have that anymore.
-In his dreams there is any particular form, issues?
-I had had two dreams which had to do with violence.
-I asked this because last time he mentioned dreams of accusation, that he was accused.
it did not repeat and I think because I closed the issue 'father' with the dream. I finished it.
-Also I would like him to tell me, his feet are more cold but in general he is feeling more the cold now?
-I think in general I have become a bit more colder. It's not so that I'm really cold.
I still have heat every now and then but I noticed that when I'm swimming here, before
it used to be a lot too warm, the water was too warm for me and now it's like a pleasant
coolness; so in general I would say yes I have become colder than what I was before.
-But in his feet definitely?
-I don't uncover them anymore.
-Also concerning his desires and aversions, has any change there?
-I now have a special aversion against milk, which before was not as strong as now.
And I still like to eat meat.
-What about sweets?
-I like to eat them but it's not I don't have to have them.
-The aversion buttermilk is still there?
-Yes but now not only buttermilk but also aversion to milk.
-And eggs?
-I like eggs a lot.
-More than before, the same as before?
-Actually I always like to eat eggs and still like to eat eggs. I also like hard boiled eggs
but there is a funny thing about it. My inner feeling says that the cholesterol of the eggs
is good for me but mentally I restrain myself from eating them.
-What about the herpes he had in his lips, the last time he was reporting.
Did not appear anymore?
-It did not reappear up to now.
-Also he had complained last time about sexual desire going down or not having.
The way I feel now mentally is that I'm slow but I'm thorough and very nit, very orderly.
-It's still quite low but for me I think it has to do with this general state of slowness
of sluggishness and this inner feeling of being in a recovery phase, which is not progressing though.
-OK, thank you.
-It is very interesting. We don't have to say very much about the case. Not really.
Why? Because we have a remedy which is appearing and rather clearly.
The changes are such that indicate the direction quite clearly.
Also it is interesting for us -and don't forget this issue - that certain desires eggs
always was there. You see what was happening?
If you take the case desires eggs, yes desires eggs can be manifesting in your first prescription.
-When he took Sulphur he was still in desires eggs.
-He took Sulphur when we know Sulphur has aversion eggs, he doesn't like them.
The vertigo high places was from Ignatia, was Sulphur, it did not go away with Sulphur.
It's waiting for another layer.
And then this going down towards ... indicates the correct direction and at the same time
points out to a great keynote of Calcarea carbonica.
Cramps in the night in the calves.
Aversion milk also. It is very interesting that the organism knows what wants and what
does not want, as far as microelements is concerned and vitamins, to take it from
different food.
So when he wants something from a food, then asks for that food.
That's why it is important for us to take into consideration the desires and aversions.
The very interesting thing that he says is that when he puts the socks, he is ameliorated
and shows how correct is our observation for Calcarea carbonica, putting shocks.
Calcarea carbonica has to put shocks in order to be able to sleep.
But sometimes this aggravation can reach up to the point of aggravating the pains.
The way he describes the whole slowness that we know from Calcarea carbonica.
How slow it is. But at the same time while he is slow, he is organized and is precise.
He is not scattered anymore.
From homeopathic point of view this is a beautiful case, where we have the Ignatia and
the Sulphur and the Calcarea carbonica.
And this state of Ignatia was there for 10 years.
That state it doesn't meant you have a grief and you have it for a period of time.
In some cases the Ignatia picture will remain for many years. You have to give it first.
If he had taken Sulphur without the Ignatia, then you could not see the effect.
You could not see the organism coming into order.
And I would like to ask have you taken Sulphur in the past?
-Once, 6 years ago in 200.
-What is the potency now that must choose? Who is in favor of 12? Nobody.
30? 200? 1M? 10M? 50M?
We have mostly physical symptomatology and I think we can start with 200 and then
we will see if he needs higher potency.
-George, usually when the picture is so clear you go high in potency. Can you explain what happens?
-Yes. I said when there is a big trauma in the soul, then in order to touch this, you have
to go high. You remember when we gave Ignatia, we gave 50M to touch this traumatic
experiences he was going. Now we don't need to go so high anymore because the
symptomatology is physical and even 12 Calcarea carb., 6X every day will do the trick.
So one dose of 200 now it will act.
You remember the case yesterday with Calcarea phosphorica?
She said I got one dose of 12 and it acted and took it a few times up to 30.
When we voted she was the only one who said give 30 because her experience is
that 30 can do the trick very well.
-I wanted to ask because there is mental symptomatology, he is afraid of insects
he is afraid of spiders, he is slow. So it's not only physical, we have complete picture
with mental as well.
-Fear of insects, fear of spiders... no. What you can say is that the sensitivity towards
cruelty is very characteristic of Calcarea carb. You don't need to go higher.
This is not a trauma, this is a sensitivity. It is different than trauma.
Now he is a whole human being, he cares. The only thing is that he cares a little bit
too much now because of his lack of Calcium which is not absorbed so easily.
We are going to give the organism the possibility to absorb the calcium that he needs
and you will see how this will be balanced.
Now if he is going to become a cruel person? No but he will react more natural to pain.
Calc. carb. cannot stand cruelties, cannot see an accident.
He says I can not work, he said it very beautifully.
Everything he said is a picture of Calc. carb. in spite of the fact, I told you, you don't have
to have the fat individual.
-The last time was Calc. carb. 200.
-Exactly.
-He can tell us what happened.
-I first want to describe the symptoms that have disappeared.
The first symptom which was there and which was the reason for me being treated
acutely was my sciatica on the right side, which after 3 weeks gradually and
very slowly disappeared.
The calves that I was describing having at night and when I was putting on my boots or
putting them off, they too disappeared for about 90%.
This wandering and burning pain in my thigh disappeared for 100%.
The pain in my left hip that would come up after a long walk or a hike that disappeared
for about 70%. This burning pain that I had underneath my sternum which had
appeared very strongly and severely about 3 times before I took the Calcarea
didn't come up again.
In the headline of my symptoms which were called the feeling of 'an inner enemy
my vulnerability and my weakness' the first one had disappeared.
I may now describe the symptoms that remained. On the first place I have the
massive bleeding of my gums that always occurs when I'm brushing my teeth which
now goes on for 2 years.
The pain on my neck on the left side is a little bit reduced but it's still there.
It's in combination and in connection with the sensibility to cold drafts and my desire for scarf...
-That means there is a sensitivity to this area to draft and he has to wear a scarf.
-If it's cold. I would even say that my inner temperature is dominated by the
temperature that I feel in my neck.
My feeling of numbness on the outer side of my right leg is still there.
My nails are pretty brittle. They have lines and one nail is still split in the middle.
My waking up in the morning between 4-5 o' clock is still existing.
Later on I'm going to add something in this symptom when I'm talking about mymental symptoms.
My sexual desire for the time being went very low. I rather feel a desire for physical
touch, for caressing.
And if at all my sexual desire is combined with this desire for touch and for feeling love.
Then I want to mention something that I didn't stretch last time that I have extensive
desire for hot drinks.
Now I come to mention the emotional and mind symptoms.
Concerning the 3 main topics that I had, my vulnerability is still existing.
-To cruelty?
-Yes, a sensibility towards cruelty and a feeling of being unprotected.
I have now the impression of being in this phase of my life of my childhood when I was
between 3-4 years.
-He means emotionally? In that vulnerable state?
-Yes, mainly because I had to live for months with closed eyes on both sides.
My eyes were wrapped up at this time.
That was at that time a therapy against strabismus. That means on the road, when I
was eating, everywhere I would just have darkness in front of my eyes for months.
I was not allowed to take off these bindings and I was threatened to be punished
heavily if I would take off these eye covers.
I think this in now the moment, the phase of a pronounced inner discourage.
And this is a strong opposition to the phase between 30-50 where professionally
would meet any decision directly with a lot of courage.
This is the one topic and the other topic has to do with the dream that I'm now
going to tell you.
I was together with a number of other people on a flight across a small trail
in the mountains and a big rock was just pending above us and I was standing
underneath this rock and all the other people would pass through this rock and when
the last one had passed, I couldn't keep the stone any longer and I would fall down.
That is the second topic that I'm feeling, I have the impression that I have to do
something for myself not to be lost.
-He was hurt when the rock and he fell, his impression was that he was hurt by this?
-I wouldn't be able to tell you because I woke up in the moment that I and the rock
were falling, I woke up. And determining for my life so far has been that the positive
results for my creativity and my power mostly were helpful for other people.
And so my life had been determined by the emotion of people around me.
And this as a special symptom has as a result that every morning I would wake up
between 4,30-5 o'clock full of worries and sorrows what is going to be there waiting
for me to be a 100% able to meet those demands.
more irritable, which of course I would withhold to the outside.
This is due the cause for me having to check everything to the door of my flat, the
door of the cellar, the door of my car, if anything had been with the car I had nearly
compulsory to check it.
Even though I would rather like to let everything just open.
-When he says to check he means to lock?
-No, I'm just going to check if it is already locked. I just go there to the cellar...
-Yes but he would like to leave it open.
-Actually I'd rather like to have it all open. But I can't leave my computer and all the
data of my patients open and reachable for everybody.
I think these are the main things.
-I would like to ask some questions. First of all I would like to know if there is still
the desire to stretch in the morning?
-That is still there.
-He was complaining last time that his mind is slow, he says I can not write down my thoughts?
-Yes, that is still there.
-The same as before?
-I think it is the same but by the fact that the two other mind symptoms, that I've just
been describing, it has been increased.
I have the impression that by this feeling my ability to concentrate is even more
diminished for the time being.
-Which feeling?
-By these thoughts that permanently circulate in me about these problems that I've
just been describing, this dream, this problem with my childhood and this problem with
the closed eyes, that I just described.
-I want to understand what exactly means. This vulnerability, he says there is a kind
of vulnerability which comes from this period of his life. What is exactly the feeling?
The feeling is fear, the feeling is anxiety, what is that which comes from that experience?
-It's the permanent feeling of apprehension.
-And the desire to be protected like a child who is unprotected?
-No, no that's not the case. This is not it.
It's just the apprehensions that have built up by this.
-Another is aversion to milk, still is there?
-Yes.
-And the desire for eggs?
-Maybe not as strong as before.
-What about the vertigo high places?
My desire for meat has stayed the same.
-What kind of meat?
-Mostly beef.
-Fear insects, spiders he has mentioned.
-It's still there but it is better. I try to make an agreement with these creatures.
-Would he say he is physically restless?
-Actually not.
-In bed he sleeps quietly or he turns?
-My wife says that in bed sometimes I'm really hitting about.
-He is restless during sleep.
-Yes but I don't realize myself.
-Does he realize that perhaps he is restless in his legs or feet or anything like that?
Do you have any constipation or stool is normal?
-I feel quite uneasy when I don't have stool, which might occur here and then.
I'm always very relieved after having had stool.
-Is this a kind of joy when he has a stool?
-No, he wouldn't be able to say that.
-Every morning wakes up at 4-5 with anxiety?
-Every morning yes, waking up with apprehension, not anxiety.
-I want really to stress that I'm not afraid of life, I'm not afraid of my every day life.
It just these apprehensions.
-Which are abstract?
-It's a permanent worry about other people.
-Mostly patients?
-Not only patients, other people too.
-Friends, relatives?
-Yes.
-Anxiety about other people.
-I want to mention something briefly. I don't have the feeling that my organism
desires a new remedy for the time being. I rather have the feeling that it is my own task
to work through the things that I experience that happen to me and maybe then it would
be possible to have even a clearer picture.
-Yes I see here from the repertorization that Calc. carb. is still standing quite high.
Most probably if there is a relapse on the physical symptomatology, he can repeat
the remedy in the same potency 200.
But there is a possibility that later Rhus tox will be indicated, especially if the organism
starts to desire milk.
Perhaps after 1-2 doses more of Cal. carb. there is a possibility that Rhus tox
complement the action.
It's very interesting also for me that his organism has gone back to this state where
the origin of the problems is. He is able to see, to feel this condition and to deal with that.
We agree we don't give him any remedy but, as I said, the possibilities are these and
maybe if we meet after 1 year...