-How old is the patient?
-She is 18 years old.
-You have been treating this case before?
-Yes but not just me.
-Other homeopaths as well.
-First other homeopaths and allopaths too.
-Can you fist give us your perspective of the case?
-In February 1997 she started having a ulcerative colitis.
After the first spell she went down on her weight to 42 kilos.
Because she was living in my neighborhood I recommended that she would see a homeopath.
At that time she got Ignatia and Nat mur without any success,
she was having relapse after relapse and then she had a real bad relapse
when the homeopath was on holidays and even though
she was getting high doses of cortisone, she was getting 15 mg of cortisone every day,
there was no amelioration and she was threatened that she would have to go to a hospital.
That would have been the third stay in hospital.
-She has been hospitalized another 2 times.
-So I said you are doing so bad even though you are taking cortisone,
so immediately you have to stop cortisone and we just search for the right remedy.
So first I gave you Aurum and I waited for 3 days and there was no success
and then she got Mercury.
-Which Mercury, solubilis?
-Yes Mercury Solubilis and the next day the symptoms were much better already.
-What potency?
-Q1.
Nevertheless 3 days later she went to hospital because everything
had been initiated before and she got again 15 mg of cortisone every day
and then she had diarrhea again.
4 weeks after she had the Q1 Mercury Solubilis the diarrhea started all over again.
Then I told her to take it twice the day, the Q1. 3-4 weeks later it started again,
so I gave her the Q4 and a month later it started again with the diarrhea,
so I decided to give her C30 and I gave it 3 times because there was no reaction
after the first dose.
Then she was again better for about 3-4 weeks, then it got worse again,
so I decided to give the C200 and no reaction.
-Is she taking cortisone at the moment?
-Since Thursday she stopped cortisone. 4 days.
-Give her now you mic and ask her what are the symptoms at the moment.
-For the time being no symptoms at all, everything is OK.
-So she does not take cortisone and she is free of symptoms.
-No cortisone orally but she takes clisma [enema] with cortisone.
-With bismuth together? Usually they give cortisone with bismuth together.
-Yes.
-She is 18 and by the time the ulcerative colitis started she was almost 16 years old.
What happened?
-She doesn't want to tell in front of the camera.
-Oh she doesn't want. Not this camera or this camera?
-This from television.
-OK you stop the camera, so you can continue.
-At that time I had my first boyfriend and my first sexual contact
and that friendship ended when he was going to America for a year
and that was when first the diarrhea started.
-How long after the boy left?
-The first week after he left.
-And before she never had any problems with her guts?
-Just when I was sort of excited.
-When she was excited she would get diarrhea?
-Yes.
-Before an examination for instance?
-Before the examination you would have to run 1 or 2 times?
-Once.
-And it was like diarrhea?
-Yes.
-And before that you got sick with something else? Do you remember?
-No, nothing.
-You did not have antibiotics?
-Yes when I had a cold I got antibiotics. Not very often.
-How many times?
-2-3 times.
-When she took antibiotics did she have diarrhea after? And what else she had?
-Rubella, measles and chicken pox.
-Tell me something else. How long you had contact with this boy?
-Half a year.
-Did she have any cystitis immediately after she started having sex?
-No.
-Did she understand what is cystitis?
-Yes.
-Did she have menses normal?
-When this boyfriend left the menses stopped for 1 year.
-What did you feel?
-I felt lonely, not understood.
-She thinks that the boy left for America because he did not love her?
-Yes, somehow yes.
-That's what she thought.
-Did she try to write or talk to him?
-We wrote quite often or telephoned but finally I terminated the relationship.
-Because it was painful?
-I thought the normal feelings left after this time, after half a year.
-What did she feel in her feelings? She felt that her emotions went down,
less and less emotions until she felt cold inside?
-Yes. When I didn't see him.
-In the beginning she was thinking of committing suicide?
-Not in that time.
-When?
-Recently yes.
-Recently she is thinking. How recently?
-Half a year ago.
-She feels depressed?
-Sometimes.
-Does she feel she has emotions now?
-Yes, I do have feelings.
-She has brother, sister?
-One sister.
-She has now another boyfriend?
-No.
-She does not want to have one?
-Not for the time being.
-Why?
-For the moment I feel better being alone.
-She is afraid she will be hurt?
-This too.
-Whom she loves most? Her mother, father, sister?
-My mother.
-The relationship with her father is good?
-Not so much.
-He hits her?
-No.
-Shouts?
-Yes.
-And she is afraid?
-Her emotions for her mother are strong?
-Yes.
-So she says she is thinking of committing suicide and at the same time
she loves her mother, how does she thinks about these 2 matters?
-For the time being I don't think of committing suicide but then
when I thought about it I was not getting along so well with my mother either.
-Why? Because of this incident with the boyfriend?
-No, it had nothing to do with this.
-She has a lot of blood in the stool?
-Yes during the spell a lot of blood.
-The blood is red or blackish?
-Red.
-Is she very thirsty?
-No.
-In her body is she feeling very warm or cold?
-Warm.
-She has any fears?
-Darkness, to talk in front of public, I'm afraid to embarrass myself,
afraid of examinations and spiders.
-She it intolerant of heat?
-No I tolerate heat pretty well.
-Cold?
-Not so much.
-Because you said before she can not tolerate heat.
-Yes, heat I can tolerate very well.
-She likes heat but she does not like cold.
-No.
-What kind of food she takes? She is careful with her diet or she takes any kind of food?
-She is careful what she eats.
-What she likes to eat?
-Fruits, vegetables, noodles and sweets too.
-And she can eat vegetables and fruits or this aggravates her?
-Vegetables I can eat anything but for fruits I have to avoid oranges and lemons.
-She likes oranges?
-Yes.
-What fruits she likes best?
-Apples and strawberries.
-Her mother or father do they suffer with similar problems?
-No, her hands are trembling.
-Show me.
-When she is excited it is much worse.
-Now she is not excited?
-Yes, but I don't really understand.
-How she can keep so calm?
-Yes.
-Her thyroid has been examined?
-No.
-Do like this and then swallow.
Now she has menses? Her period is back?
-It came back after 1 year but since the last spell of the colitis it has been gone again.
-When she had menses, before menses, a day before, 2 days before
she was feeling OK or she was feeling depressed, anxious, irritable?
-Totally normal.
-And she had many days of blood or only 2-3 days?
-5-6 days.
-How much water she drinks?
-About 1 1/2 lit per day.
-It has to be cold the water, from the refrigerator?
-Yes.
-She likes ice cream a lot?
-How many ice creams she can take the day?
-One at most.
-How much salt she uses?
-Very little.
-You don't like salt?
-No.
-She must be careful in her answers, to answer if she does not remember to say
I don't remember, if she needs to think, stop and think it's better than just giving us
the wrong information or if I ask her a question that she does not want to answer,
she can say I don't want to answer. Since when this trembling is?
-Since I can remember. I've known her for 10 years and for 10 years
she had been having this trembling.
-Only on the hands. Not the feet?
-No.
-And if you take this, hold this, if she takes a cup to drink she is trembling?
-Only if you are excited?
-Yes mainly.
-And the excitement is when she is in front of boys?
-Too but too at school.
-When the teacher tells her to come up.
-You are good student?
-Yes.
-Very good?
-Very good. She is very ambitious.
-She wants to be first in the class.
-Yes.
-Are you first in your class?
-Not for the time being because I had to redouble the year because
I was so much absent.
-Her nails are strong or brittle?
-Very brittle.
-But does she bite the nails?
-When I'm excited yes.
-Does she ever stammer?
-No.
The last 2 spells of colitis appeared when she was having a lot of examinations
at school and too when she was doing the driving license.
-Can she describe her character?
-Benevolent, loves animals more than people.
-She was loving these animals before or after the incident?
-Always.
-Which animals? Dogs?
-Dogs and horses.
-She is very fastidious? Very organized with her things?
-No, on the contrary.
-She throws things around?
-She is good friend with the niece of mine and in comparison with this niece
she is 100 times better.
What is remarkable about her is that she is very much looking for harmony
and very peaceful and she doesn't like struggles or fights
and she is always evening up the situations, equilibring.
-Peace maker. But according to her does she get anger inside?
-Yes.
-And then what she does? She keeps the anger and she holds the anger inside?
-She keeps it inside.
-She never expressed her anger?
-Never.
-This is a good job.
-At most towards my father but...
-But also with others.
She sleeps OK?
-Yes.
-Her feet in bed are cold or warm?
-Cold.
-There is any perspiration during sleep? Her nails actually brake easily
and she bites them?
-Yes both.
-Her toe nail maybe enters into the flesh?
-No, once but otherwise not.
-Does she ever have any perspiration?
-After doing sports.
-When she perspires she feels good or with perspiration she feels bad?
-Uneasy, dirty, when she is sweating she feels dirty.
-The perspiration is offensive?
-No. Not agreeable but it's not offensive.
-I will ask her now a difficult question but she can answer or not answer.
Sexually how she feels now? It doesn't matter, don't answer, you will tell me later.
-No desire.
-At all.
-Not for sexual things.
-She feels an aversion?
-For the time being yes.
-Does she have leucorrhea instead of menses, does she have discharge from the vagina?
-No.
-The vagina is dry?
-Yes.
-If she is in a situation, for instance on a queue waiting and somebody goes
and sit in front of her, will she tell him sir go back?
-She wouldn't say anything.
-If she is in a state where it needs confrontation with somebody, she will keep her anger
and then she will go away from this confrontation and maybe she will be trembling?
-It depends on whom it is. If I would know somebody very well, I would tell him my opinion,
but very reduced.
-She is afraid of dark very much?
-When I'm alone yes.
-In the house at night when she is alone, she would be afraid?
-If something would move or something would made noise, I would be afraid.
-Does she feel she has a lot of gas inside her abdomen?
The abdomen bloats?
-Yes.
-And then she has a lot of gas?
-What about burping?
-Too.
-A lot?
-No, rather gas, flatulence.
-Does she also hear the abdomen rumbling?
-Yes.
-When in the morning, when she wakes up, she feels tired or she wakes up
and she is ready to go?
-Tired, very tired.
-Even if she sleeps 8-9 hours?
-Yes.
-And how long it takes to come back?
-During the whole day I'm tired. It reduces a little bit but I'm not totally fit.
Since the colitis, the illness is gone no.
-What is her best time? When she feels best?
-Afternoon and evening?
-In hours?
-From 3 pm to midnight.
-And which is the worse time?
-In the morning between 6 and 10 o'clock.
-Sweets she likes very much?
-Every now and then yes.
-She takes sweets?
-Yes.
-That means not every day.
-Just every now and then, not every day.
-Because she is aggravated by sweets or because she does not care?
-Because they aggravate.
-Does she take raw onion in the salad?
-No. Since the illness has been diagnosed, no.
-Why? What happens?
-The flatulence is much more.
-That's why she avoids. In general if she eats onion, she will feel bad?
-Just the gas is worse.
-She likes onions?
-No, neither.
-What about oysters.
-I have never eaten them.
-Why?
-I don't like them and just the aspect I don't like them.
-She says that if the teacher calls her to tell the lesson, she feels very anxious, right?
-That's true.
-Why? Does she know why?
-I'm just afraid to embarrass myself, to put myself in awkward situation.
-Why, she does not know the answer?
-This too. It has been in the foreground been in the center of attention.
-If she has to go to some Authorities, to some work, she will do it easily
or she will also be afraid?
-That will be difficult.
-In bed she takes a position to sleep?
She likes to sleep on the right side, on the left side, on the abdomen, on back?
-On my abdomen and on the side.
-Both sides and abdomen. She likes to swim in the sea?
-Yes, very much.
-But is it possible when she is in the sea, for instance last summer,
when she was suffering with colitis, if she goes to the sea she will feel good?
-Last year she wasn't at the sea shore.
She is just saying that she had to give her dog an injection so that he would die
and they did it together both of them and consolation aggravates.
-She likes the sun when she goes to the sea, she will lie in the sun or she avoids.
-She lies in the sun.
-And no other fear? Except of darkness, being embarrassed and spiders she has no other fears?
-Examinations.
-In the darkness sometimes she feels that they are presents like ghosts?
-No. Before the colitis started she was having recurrent herpes.
Once right on the nose and on the lips and it was coming like once the month.
-Before the colitis, that means during the time she had the affair with the boy?
-Before this.
-Herpes in the nose?
-On the tip of the nose.
-And then she had also other skin eruption?
-Little abscesses?
-Where?
-On the legs and the arms.
-She never had the acne?
-No.
-And she puts some cream here in the nose?
-No, nothing. I got a remedy from him and that worked.
-Mercury.
-It worked for the herpes on the lips but it didn't work for the herpes on the nose.
And she had it for about 2 weeks.
-Do you have any problems with your teeth?
-No.
-She has written any other things in her notes which we didn't ask?
-Everything that I have written down yes.
-We have asked. Very good.
-I would like to add something which definitely I would not have said here
in front of the auditorium and I also needed a long time to find out about this
and I think it might be important.
I kept repeating the question since the colitis started after this unhappy love affair
whether she is still very attached to this issue and finally she broke out into tears
and said no, what is much worse is my mother had told me that if I also would move out from home,
she would kill herself.
And I think this is very important point for the occurring of the colitis which she,
herself can not say.
-So her mother has actually blackmailed her, if she goes out, I will commit suicide.
-You said that the mother said, if you also would move out, so does that
mean somebody else has already moved out of the house? The father or the sister
or maybe somebody else?
-Shortly before her sister had moved out.
-I just want to ask you as a first impression you have.
Which group you would place her from these?
-The second group.
-Who says 3? Who says second?
She is really on the lower second or the beginning of 3.
That is the idea. You can not say this is, no.
That is the idea, you are getting the idea of what you have to deal with.
Why we say that? Because of pathology and because of another reason also.
What is the second reason that we say she belongs somewhere here?
-The high doses of cortisone she took?
-Not exactly.
-The thinking of committing suicide.
-She gives many pictures of different remedies.
-That means her remedy is not clear. The pathology is quite strong and at the same time
the general state is not good at all. When she stays without cortisone, she may go...
You see her like this now but if you take away the cortisone,
you may see a totally different picture.
In one month you may see her lying in bed totally exhausted.
So for all these reasons we say that this case belongs to the beginning of the third group
to the end of the second.
We have to deal with a case most probably that will not be well with one remedy.
We have to give most probably a second remedy or repeating the remedy etc.
What is the special difficulty that we have with this case?
The fact that she gets these cortisone enemas and something else also that you have to have in mind.
Now she takes cortisone enemas and she feels quite good for I don't know how many days
but if she continues like that, only with cortisone enemas, there is going to be a time
where these cortisone enemas will not be sufficient and she will start having a relapse,
she will be hospitalized again. The fact that she remains better is most probably because
she has been ameliorated by the remedies she took so far.
And the question that we have to ask is whether... She took Ignatia, she took Nat mur
and she took also Mercury and Aurum.
As far as I understand she did not take more remedies than that.
-And Carcinosin.
-Carcinosin also.
So all these remedies it might have an effect on her case, maybe not a curative effect
but still they might have made the colitis less severe. Why I say that?
If the remedy is not curing how do I say and why do I say that in spite of
not having the correct remedy, still she may have been ameliorated in her colitis?
Can anybody tell me?
She said 6 months after this separation and the colitis going on,
she started having suicidal thoughts.
During that time we can say that the colitis most probably will be better.
Because some of the impact of the disease it goes to the psychological level
and the force of the disturbance is distributed to some emotional and then the physical.
When you see that it is like you have an amount of disease.
If the whole amount goes to one place, it's very strong.
But if this amount you distribute in different levels, then the local level,
the physical level can be ameliorated.
And this is something which may come from the effect of the remedies or from the conflict
she has with her mother.
The difficulty in this case is we have to work with this case while she is under cortisone.
This is very difficult always because by the time you take away the cortisone,
you may see a totally different picture but under the circumstances OK we have to work now
with these conditions and we'll try to see if we can make out what is
the most probable remedy for her.
I would like you to comment on the taking of the case.
The taking of the case was good enough for you?
Do we cover all the areas or you feel you want some more information?
You would ask something else?
-I would like to have some more information on symptoms to the disease,
the ulcerative colitis; maybe how is the stool and so on.
-This is a correct observation. I did not pay much attention to the quality of the stool,
the pains that she may had, only the amount of blood I was interested about.
So this was an omission on my part.
Whether this omission is important or not, maybe it's a matter of debate
but there was an omission, yes.
-I didn't feel that I got to know her enough, like she didn't talk about her dreams
and also hobbies, like what she likes to do in her spare time, more about her thinking.
-She is a good student, she is a shy person, it is difficult to push her
under the circumstances because we understand she is sensitive and we don't...
I asked her to describe her character, she said whatever she said and information
which does not forthcoming is not usually valid.
If you push a person, you can make whatever you like finally.
What you are interested is that which comes forward which is immediate.
That is an information which you grasp and you must have noticed in certain answers she gave,
she gave an emphasis. These are the important parts in a taking of the case.
-How about her dreams?
-Up to the time of this first love she had been a real child, very child like.
-Maybe you could inform us a bit more about her parents, I mean for example
for me it is very strange that when the daughter has her first boyfriend,
the mother gets so frightened that the daughter could leave the house
and threatens to kill herself.
Maybe you could give us some more information about the parents
and maybe also about the father.
-Looking at them from the outside they seem to be a perfect normal family.
The father works for the post office, he has a lot of Nux vomica in his picture,
he has suffered repeatedly from back pains which were always ameliorated by Nux vomica.
It's very, very difficult to get close to the mother, to approach the mother.
In my opinion she is Nat mur picture but in a very progressive state.
-When we take a case, we are interested primarily to see whether there exists
an exciting cause for the situation.
What excited a chronic condition that was dormant there and brought about
the present situation. This cause is important, if we can have it.
In this case can we have the cause?
-Yes.
-Yes because it's very obvious that the girl herself says, after the boyfriend left me
I broke out with this problem.
So that is enough for us to go and use this symptom as ailments from grief or ailments
from disappointed love or ailments from whatever is the problem.
Further than that it is very difficult to use information which you try
to investigate more and more.
Sometimes you may arrive to a kind of answer which might be interesting
but most of the times you will not find more than what she says.
That the boyfriend left and she started with the colitis.
So what you can use here is ailments from disappointed love or ailments from grief.
-I think that there was a predisposition to her reaction.
So this predisposition is maybe important for us to understand and I feel that
I would like to know more about her early childhood
and maybe that could help us in finding the remedy.
-Why do you say there is a predisposition?
There is any reason for saying there is a predisposition?
-Because not every girl who is left by her boyfriend reacts in that way
with ulcerative colitis.
-Yes except of that, there was any other points in the history of that girl
to point out that there was actually a predisposition, there was a preparation of the organism.
-She would have had diarrhea from excitement and before examination etc.
-Because she had diarrhea on the excitement. That already shows the predisposition,
what we call there is a predisposition already, that's correct.
The moment she was excited, she had diarrhea.
-We heard from her homeopath saying that the mother was the reason.
I think I would have asked her exactly what happened.
Because she said it's because of the boyfriend, we didn't go in very deep
to see what caused the whole thing.
I don't know if the boyfriend left her, maybe she wanted to go with him and she couldn't
because of the mother and the struggle between herself, if she could stay with the mother
and not with the boyfriend, that would make it. So we are not so clear about this point.
-This is what I said.
The fact that she is in grief or in disappointment is enough for us to  use it as a symptom.
Whether it was a combination of the mother pushing her to leave the boyfriend,
whether, whether, whether, it is still a symptom that we have to take.
Ailments from love disappointment, ailments from grief, if you want to make it more.
Combine the 2 symptoms and you have covered all the information that you may have.
That is what we have said. We have to compare what we know in the Materia Medica
with what we see in the patient.
Ailments from grief 3 times, diarrhea after grief 3 times, love disappointed 3 times.
All 3 are combined into one symptom actually. Fear of dark, biting nails, cold drinks desire,
onions aggravate, trembling of hands, sexual desire wanting, brittle finger nails,
aversion to coition, suicidal disposition, hemorrhage from anus,
you really you can not see?
Flatulence, rumbling, sweets aggravate, unrefreshing sleep.
What is the first remedy?
-Lycopodium.
-Lycopodium, Phosphorus, Staphysagria, Ignatia, Nat mur, Calcarea carbonica, Sepia.
-Can you tell me why you haven't used the herpes symptoms?
-Why not. She does not have herpes now, she had herpes before this condition.
So it's an old symptom, it's doubtful whether you should take it now.
What you would expect is that after the remedy, you may have a break out again
of the herpes. That you may have.
-One question, how was the herpes treated?
-It was treated by Mercury which took away the herpes on the lips but not in the nose.
Show me columns.
Lycopodium, Sulphur, Medorrhinum, Ambra Grisea, Plumbum, Silica... Causticum.
What is against Lycopodium? Lycopodium comes as a remedy covering most of the symptoms
and also the Expert System says I can not make another decision.
What is against Lycopodium?
-You once said in another seminar that when Lycopodium comes up and Lycopodium
has a desire for cold water, you should thoroughly think about giving Lycopodium.
-Correct. I said what is against Lycopodium, it is the fact that she desires cold water.
-But it's there.
-It is there, still it is the prominent remedy. The second point which is against Lycopod?
-She has an aggravation in the morning and an amelioration in the afternoon.
-No, wait a moment. The aggravation in the morning is with Lycopodium.
Lycopodium is aggravated in the morning, can not get refreshed from sleep, has unrefreshed sleep
and it's worse in the morning when it wakes up and wants to stay for a few hours before it
can feel better but in the afternoon Lycopodium feels worse and it's better after 8 o' clock.
Now she says from 3 o'clock until 12 o'clock, this is my best time. It is a mixing.
-Lycopodium doesn't have disappointed love, it is not listed in the rubric.
-Yes, but Lycopodium has a sensitivity on the digestive system. She has a sensitivity
on the digestive system, so therefore any stress which affects the digestion
and in this way creating a colitis, it might be a Lycopodium case.
What is this? Diarrhea after grief, Phosphoric acid. Phosphoric acid should be there
in a stronger degree and Lycopodium should be there also
because Lycopodium has an affinity with colitis;
so if there is an affinity, a predisposition and there is a stress and we have colitis,
the idea of Lycopodium should be there.
Ailments from grief, Lycopodium in a lower degree but it doesn't matter.
-Against Lycopodium speaks that ailments come not out, Lycopodium is famous
that it explodes when there is ailments inside. She is very kind in her character
and takes it all inside.
-No, this is not exactly like this.
Lycopodium will not speak their anger in front of everybody but only to those
who they can get away with this.
Otherwise they are afraid to express their anger in their school, their teachers, their chiefs
and only in the house where they know, the mother loves her, she can express,
in the father she can express.
Because they love and they know they get away, otherwise they keep the anger inside.
She appears not to be able to express her anger. Which is a main element in this case?
Not being able to express the anger and there is grief and ailments from suppressed anger.
So we have strongly here the idea of Staphysagria which does not appear
in the repertorization.
-The symptoms are not there, I did not put these ones.
-With Phosphoric acid I investigated the possibility, as you remember,
when I was asking about the feelings.
I was investigating where the feelings are dead or the feelings are alive.
If the feelings were dead, she says I'm indifferent, I don't care, I don't have feelings,
feelings are finished; then we have to investigate very seriously the possibility of Phosp.
But she said her feelings are alive. She had all that grief and all that grief
went into the guts and teared up the guts but not the feelings.
Therefore question mark for Phos acid.
There are two remedies, they have my name, it's not true.
The Buffo I have not said loves animals, I don't know how it got in
and also Pulsatilla has my name.
It is true for Medorrhinum and for Aethusa, it is true but Pulsatilla?
You see this also in order to be a symptom I have said many times, in order to take it
as a symptom you have to have pathology, that means collecting the animals,
sleeping with the animals, taking the animals, animals, animals. She is like that?
-If she could, she would do this.
-Even so, you can put this symptom but I will not pay much attention
because love for animals is rather what I consider a natural feeling.
If you take 3 or 4 symptoms, you chose the symptoms, you can make Staphysagria,
you can make Medorrhinum, you can make Sulphur, you can make Lycopodium.
With a few symptoms in this case, you can make anything.
So with the repertorization we get some ideas and then these ideas we have to process
and to see whether fits, what fits more, best, not completely. It's not possible
because as we said in the beginning this case is not a clear case
that we will have a clear remedy and we'll say that is a clear remedy.
So you see the struggle that we are having at the moment.
With Colocynthis how many symptoms?
-7 symptoms.
-7 symptoms, rumbling, flatulence, hemorrhage from anus, disappointed love,
4 symptoms actually because the 3 first is one symptom.
-She says that she wants to be the best in the class and with another homeopathic teacher
I learned that Lycopodium wants to be the best.
-This again is... to want to be the best, who from this class does not want to be the best?
You don't want to be the best, wait a moment. You don't want to be the best,
that means your want is I don't want to be the best. Please don't make me the best, there is no.
Therefore to be the best is again a natural state. When this becomes mania,
when it becomes totally engrossed with this idea I must be the best, I have to be the best
and I'm not the best and therefore I have a colitis, then it becomes a symptom.
But she wants to be the best, she is the best, it's not a symptom.
Show me the columns, Lycopodium is behind everything, show me Lycopodium,
why Lycopodium? 18 from 19? How can we get away?
-If the picture was not so clear, would you then say that we should reduce a little bit
the cortisone so to get a more clear picture?
-To reduce the cortisone is a very good idea but not in the island of Alonissos
because the moment that she gets through all that and she has to be hospitalized
and Lycopodium is not really the case and you try to find the remedy,
then you have some problems.
So I'm thinking another course of action.
-For 4 days she stopped taking cortisone orally.
-4 days it is not enough because the action of cortisone is still going on
and we will see the results in a few days, in spite of the fact she takes still enema.
If we stop the enemas also within another 3-4 days, will start with the problems
and then we have to study another 3-5 days and then what happens?
We have to send her to the hospital.
-I don't want to speak for Lycopodium. I want a general information about this desire
for cold drinks. Could belong to a lower level and popping up?
-Yes of course, the desire for cold drinks is not totally excluding.
-The interest of the question is can you comment when is it for you a symptom
against Lycopodium and when do you see it as a popping up symptom?
-Very good question. Let's see.
Let us say we were debating on this case between Lycopodium and Phosphorus.
Is this a case of Phosphorus or is this a case of Lycopodium?
In such a case where the desire for cold water is in favor of the other remedy,
then you say that is against Lycopodium. We are debating here between Staphysagria, Sepia,
if you like, Sulphur, Nat. muriaticum and Ignatia had been given, Causticum.
Also we have the possibility of Causticum. What is in favor of Causticum in her case?
Can anybody tell me? You remember from the Materia Medica of Causticum,
a characteristic which she has?
-She is trying to make peace.
-It's very interesting.
He wants to say the characteristic of Causticum and I see he makes a gesture
which has the characteristic of Causticum, so I say OK tell it.
He makes like that and I think he wants to say the Causticum has an eruption
on the tip of the nose.
I want to say the characteristic of Causticum, I say now you got it but he got the other.
The other characteristic of Causticum is of course the trembling
and the excitement just before examination. Can you show me diarrhea before examinations?
Acidum nitricum of course is strong, Opium is strong and then from the remedies
we are thinking Lycopodium is there, Staphysagria is quite strong and she will be stronger,
Sepia, Phosphorus, Colocynthis, Bryonia, OK.
In the beginning I also thought the possibility of Argentum nitricum because she says
I'm worse heat, did you hear that?
And then she changed it, most probably it was a matter of misunderstanding.
Worse heat, worse with the sweets and diarrhea on examinations,
this is case of Argentum nitricum.
The moment she says, no, no I'm worse from cold, not from heat the idea goes away.
What else I don't like for Lycopodium?
There is one more point which I don't like for Lycopodium, can anybody say?
There is one more point which is there, Lycopodium has the point
but she had to have it stronger for Lycopodium.
-She can sleep on both sides and Lycopodium ...
-...sleeps on the right side, that's also but there is a symptom which she has
but for Lycopodium you should have it stronger.
-The desire for sweets.
-The desire for sweets for Lycopodium, the way that she describes it it's not a pathology.
Take out the desire for sweets.
-I don' have it.
-You didn't put it, very correct. You don't have to take it as a symptom.
-In the rubric aggravation from sweets you find Lycopodium in second degree
and she avoids sweets because she knows she is getting an aggravation.
-Formally before she would eat more sweets, she practically was eating just sweets.
-Ah, that's important.
...Medorrhinum? Staphysagria? 37. Another remedy? Gelsemium?
Who has prescribed Gelsemium? No other.
Another case?
-Magnesia carbonica.
-Another case?
-Pulsatilla.
-Baryta carbonica.
-Another case?
Argentum nitricum.
-Sepia.
-Who has prescribed Sepia? Nobody.
Another case?
-Phosphoric acid.
-Can you show me diarrhea from anxiety? Has anybody done 3 symptoms?
Diarrhea from anxiety, diarrhea from anticipation, diarrhea from vexation.
This is a previous symptom which existed before the whole thing,
so we'd like to get an idea which are the main remedies for doing this.
Put also anticipation. Gelsemium will be the first.
Gelsemium, Phosphoric acid, Argentum nitricum, Calcarea phosphorica, Colocynthis,
Ignatia, Opium, Phosphorus and then everything else.
-Position 23 is Lycopodium.
-Put now bloody diarrhea and put rumbling 3 times and flatulence 3 times.
Put worse onions twice, Ignatia, Phosphorus, Kali phosphoricum, Lycopodium.
Give me the Expert System.
Another important symptom for this case? Amelioration in the afternoon. Amenorrhea.
The amelioration in the afternoon can you find it? Afternoon, evening,
worse morning on waking.
The amenorrhea started immediately after... in the beginning before she had the cortisone
and it is a replacement, that means she loses a lot of blood,
the organism immediately says I can not lose more blood, forget this.
Now it's more important that.
Of course the repetitions now is the fact that she is losing still blood.
It is like a balancing of the organism because she is losing blood,
usually if we have strong chronic hemorrhage, the menses stop.
-I found a rubric stool bloody and with mucus and this is typical for ulcerative colitis
because we don't have any mucus.
-In her case?
-In the beginning she had mucus and blood and I wanted to add something
concerning her menses.
Only about 3/4 of a year later, she told somebody that she was having this bloody stool
and all this time she didn't have the menses anymore.
Only 9 months later she told that she was having this diarrhea.
-Do you know what was her sexual desire before the incident?
Was very sexual, was very strong sexual desire?
-Until she got to know this young man, she was a child.
3 months before she met this guy, she was playing with dolls.
When this boy went for staying in America, she went to get the pill,
the impression was more the pressure from the side of this boy
than she was really desiring sexual intercourse.
-Well this I have not seen it in the case, she did not appear to me
that she was really lacking in taking responsibility, it did not appear to me that
she was lacking in mental acuteness and understanding.
Though she is short in stature and maybe later on we may be considering Baryta carbonica,
at this moment we have some pathology and we can not go away, unless we have strong indications
for Baryta carbonica.
If she had said, I don't want to grow up, I just want to go backwards,
I just want to stay under bed cover, I just... She did not express any of this Baryta carbonica.
The rest is projection from our point of view.
She looks small yes but she is first in the class, she answers questions quite good
and she is quite intelligent.
We don't know that Baryta carbonica has this tendency to go into diarrhea,
it's not of the main remedies.
-But I think it's also very important to mention what Sabine said
after the interview was over.
She said her mother told her, she would commit suicide if she would leave her as
well and I think there might be a long lasting pathology in this family
and this might have a much more impact on her than that the friend was leaving.
So I think we should understand this point, to really find a good remedy.
-But even if you understand and even if you believe that this is not because
of the boyfriend leaving and it is because of some deeper pathology,
still you have to find the remedy and still you have to find the remedy based
on the symptoms that she is having.
-Aversion sex?
-Aversion sex is doubtful.
-I wanted to say one thing. Yesterday when you advised her to speak freely,
openly honestly and so on, if you remember, I saw that the tears were rolling up in her eyes
and I talked to her afterwards and she told me that during almost the entire interview,
she was always fighting back, holding back her tears.
She was at any moment ready to break out into tears and she really wants
to consciously precisely do everything right and she had told me
that every answer she gave was to the best of her ability and knowledge.
-To add something. First of all this young girl left the young man,
she was the one who ended the relationship, if you want to put it that way.
On the other hand she definitely does not want to hurt anybody
and she is really paying good attention to answer precisely
and exactly, especially after you pointed it out again.
-Let me give you now my evaluation of the case.
My evaluation of the case is that I have been thinking strongly of 3 remedies.
The one is Lycopodium, the other is Staphysagria and the third is Gelsemium.
Primarily these were the 3 remedies that I debated, which one?
And Lycopodium as we saw in the repertorization had strong points
according to the symptomatology.
It is a symptomatology that fits Lycopodium.
So for me two things were before the pathology. Once the pathology has developed,
we see the picture of Lycopodium quite strongly but not typically.
She does not have the aggravation in the afternoon for instance,
that we expect to have Lycopodium, afternoon aggravation.
On the contrary she has amelioration until midnight.
Lycopodium has an amelioration after midnight. Desires cold water.
Lycopodium also is really a coward and do not like to oppose and to go against
authorities and things like that and she is a pacifier.
Now I'm not sure Lycopodium is a pacifier.
A pacifier is Magnesias and that's why I believe somebody suggested Magnesia.
Magnesias don't like fighting, they like peace and they try to make peace.
So in this case I do not have enough symptoms finally to prescribe for a remedy.
Then I try to go backwards and see whether some of her symptoms could give me an idea.
And I see two definite symptoms that she has mentioned.
One is the diarrhea with the excitement or with the anticipation
and the second is the trembling of the hands.
These are pathology symptoms which are definite, together with the character
which has not changed, that means a character who is weak in that confronting violence,
confronting rudeness.
So I say to myself, if I had prescribed for this girl before, what remedy I would have given.
Now the remedy is Magn, what remedy I would have given during that time?
I would have given Staphysagria? Staphysagria is really suppressing her anger etc.
but is this enough? Staphysagria is also from anticipation we don't know it.
On the contrary we know that Gelsemium is a person who is weak and trembling.
She said something else which continues until now, which is the general weakness.
She says, I'm very weak.
And Gelsemium is of the main remedies with weakness, general weakness and trembling,
ailments from anticipation, ailments from anxiety.
-Timidity appearing in the public.
-Timidity appearing in the public of course, the examination, it is an exam remedy.
If she has to take examination, then we give Gelsemium.
So in despair, because I can not find enough substantiated information at this moment
to prescribe on the pathology, Gelsemium is not very well known for ulcerative colitis, right?
But, as we all know, pathology can be in any remedy but she gave me the impression
from her symptoms, the trembling, the anticipation and the weakness, physical weakness
and weakness in facing the public that the best remedy I would have prescribed
before this condition, would be Gelsemium.
There is another rubric which says hearing bad news, just find me this.
Hearing bad news, that means suddenly without expecting, that is the idea of that rubric.
Without expecting, you suddenly hear and immediately there is a reaction.
Somebody calls you on the telephone and says, I'm leaving tomorrow for America.
In a case like this where she has been so naive, with the good meaning of the word,
she is a nice, pure human being which does not understand of the intrigues of the human mind,
that it may work on this way and that way and that way, she knows only one way.
Ailments from hearing bad news.
-Gelsemium.
-Calcarea phosphorica should be there, higher than this but anyhow.
Gelsemium we know it is a remedy that because of that weakness she has in the organism,
she can not support hearing something very bad and immediately there is a reaction.
Where is the reaction? Mostly in trembling but in this case we have the immediate beginning
of the symptoms of the ulcerative colitis, why?
Because she has a predisposition on the colon, irritation of the colon,
the colon gets irritated very easily.
Put it 4 times, see what happens. It doesn't matter, it imitates my thinking.
-George, all this was before the pathology. There are features which are still there,
she is still suffering from anticipation and anxiety but all this is before the pathology.
So do you think this is a Gelsemium layer now or it is underlined layer and she needs something?
-This is a good question. We might have given another remedy and we say most
probably Gelsemium is underneath, give this remedy and then wait and give Gelsemium.
If I was satisfied with another remedy, I would have given first this and then Gelsemium.
But as I'm not satisfied with another remedy, I will first try Gelsemium
which may fail but the most logical thing for me at this moment is to try Gelsemium for that girl.
-If you look at the symptoms, all the symptoms she has now, they are not from before.
It's all Gelsemium symptoms, also that she is getting better in the afternoon.
Here are all the Gelsemium symptoms.
-So Gelsemium actually covers quite a lot of her symptomatology and the peculiarities
of the symptomatology though it does not cover the bloody stool.
So Gelsemium 200 every day and with the idea to start reducing the enemas
and see what happens. We give her every day 200, dilute in water and take it 3 times.
You give it to her and then tomorrow again 3 times and after a few days we'll try
to reduce the enemas or to stop the enemas.