-And apart from that you had a psychological state which you described?
-After the remedy in the first week I was very nervous and at the end
of the first week all the physical symptoms had stopped, they are gone.
After a week I was calm, I had to sustain an exam and I was surprised how calm I was
and I felt well until January when I developed a fear of robbers.
I stay alone at my house and I wasn't afraid at all but since January I'm afraid,
especially in the night because I think that they can come in my house and kill me.
I go to bed late 12-1 o'clock, I pay attention to all the sounds in the house
and in the morning I wake up very scared to see if not somebody comes in the house
and to see if I'm still alive. If I come late in the evening,
not too late 8-9 o'clock I'm looking all the house to see if there is somebody in.
And if I come later 11 o'clock I never come alone.
I make somehow that the person which I come with, to come with me in the house,
inside and after I look everywhere the person can go.
-Tell me was any reason for you to think that maybe...
you had in the neighborhood some robbers who got in?
-No.
-With no reason. It just developed this.
-Yes and in the day when I'm walking to work or somewhere else I have all the time
the feeling that something wrong will happen to me and I will die.
-Somebody is going to kill you?
-Not necessarily. If I cross the street I just start to create by imagination what
could happen if that car would crush me and die or descending stairs.
So because at the moment I thought that it is madness to have all the time this feeling
and I started to keep my mind occupied and to work intellectually much more
and it's very difficult because the day I must be busy all the time
and the night I couldn't sleep because I was afraid for robbers.
After 3,4 days if I don't go to my parents house to have a quiet night
and to rest I couldn't go on.
-That means if you have company or if you have somebody then it's OK.
-Yes it's OK, no problem.
-Something else?
-In April I had a conflict.
I was very nervous and I stayed in a draft and I took a cold and
the first symptom appeared, this was for the first time that I lost my voice.
Then it started a cough, it was between 4-6 in the morning without stopping
and 7-11 in the evening without stopping, four weeks.
-And in the meantime your voice was lost?
-No, the first week was lost and then coughing started.
-First week it was lost without coughing and then coughing started.
-Then in the 5th week I couldn't resist anymore because it was too much
and I took two allopathic pills.
-What it was?
-I don't know the word in English, a medicine against cough, not very strong
and Tussilago mother tincture. After a week cough stops.
Another thing is that I'm nervous and irritated more easily and I say what I have to say
and then in 5 minutes I calm again.
It's no so rare as it was, it's more often but it passes very quickly.
Another thing is that I forgot what I've just done.
I lock the door, I arrive in the street, I come back, I go to work, I arrive to work
and I say, did I close the door or not? And the gas, the light, everything.
-You have to check again and again.
-Yes.
In February and March I ate a lot. I eat, after an hour I eat again, it's like
I never eat and after an hour I eat again and so on for two months.
-Then what you wanted to eat during that time? Anything?
-Anything.
-Not especially this or that or sweets?
-No.
-What about thirst?
-I'm very thirsty. I drink a lot.
-You want to drink constantly?
-Yes. Here in the class I drink 1 lit, maybe more , when I arrive at the hotel
I drink again the night I drink again.
-Do you drink little by little?
-No, large quantities. I have at home a glass of half kilo and if I'm very thirsty I drink it all.
-And it must be cold?
-Very cold, ice cold.
-You, yourself you feel the cold or not so much?
-Since April when I had that cold, I can say I'm a little more cold than usual,
I need to put more clothes.
-This fear of robbers is only in the night or it can be in the day time?
-In the day is less because almost all the time somebody is with me and I'm secure.
I stay quiet.
-Are you concerned about your parents especially? You worry about them?
-Not especially.
-You have brothers, sisters?
-No.
-You are alone. And did you develop any relationship all this time?
-It was something in December but I couldn't. I tried and I just couldn't.
-You tried, what do you mean?
-I tried to not be so cold and to accept him but I just couldn't.
-What was the feeling?
-No feeling.
-No attraction?
-No.
-But do you have an attraction for somebody else? You look somebody who is in the office,
a patient or in the neighborhood where you look somebody and you say, I like him.
-No.
-The menses are regular?
-Yes but they are too long, 7-10 days.
-A lot of blood?
-Yes, the first six days yes.
-During the time when you were eating a lot... but you lost weight from the last time.
-No, I put 10 kilos. I tried to keep in diet but it was impossible, I just couldn't.
-Now after two months the appetite is less or still is the same?
-Definitely is less.
-And you start losing now weight?
-No.
-And you like to eat something which is more sweet or salty?
-I can't say that I like something special but I like at the end of the meal
to eat something sweet but not all the time.
-That something that has to be sweet, it has to be chocolate or anything?
-Anything, it doesn't matter.
-What about ice cream?
-I don't like so much as I liked it before. I can pass near ice cream and not take it.
But in the past it was impossible.
-What do you mean in the past?
-Before I take the remedy, if I see ice cream, I take it.
-Tell me as a child you had this fear of robbers?
-No. 2-3 years ago they took my bag and tried to steal something but I was in a bus.
-You sleep well, right through or you wake up in the night?
-No, I sleep very lightly and I wake up with every sound.
-So in the morning you are unrefreshed when you wake up?
-Yes, I have an hour or half an hour headache and I have an edema here in the eyes.
-In the morning?
-Yes.
-Only in the right side?
-No, both sides.
-And eventually it goes away?
-After 2-3 hours yes.
-You are working for yourself as a doctor or you work in the hospital?
-No, I work at a factory, I'm a doctor at a factory but I don 't know if I will stay there or not.
-What about other fear? You fear the dark?
-No. Now no.
-Before?
-Before yes.
-Strong fear of dark?
-When I was a child yes.
-Do you remember if you were afraid of thunderstorms?
-No never. I have fear of earthquakes because I had the experience in Hungary.
-You have earthquakes in Hungary?
-Yes.
-How do you feel near the sea?
-Now I'm feeling well and I like the sun and since I'm here I feel well because
I have company but I like the sea and I like very much travelling.
-When you had this incident, when they took away your bag you were afraid at the moment,
you reacted or you did not react?
-No for the moment I couldn't do anything, I was paralyzed and then after a few seconds
I had a reaction, I shouted very strong, I started to tremble and then I had the courage to
look in my bag to see if they stole me something or not.
-So you manage to hold the bag or they took the bag?
-No they cut it but they didn't manage to take it.
-In what position do you sleep?
-On the abdomen.
-Always?
-Always.
-All your life?
-Yes.
-Do you take fruits?
-Yes, not especially.
-You like fruits which are ripe?
-Before the remedy I liked sour fruits but now it can be all.
-What symptoms you had that went away?
-My bag pains are gone.
-You had a lumbago by that time?
-Yes. It's still the problem with my eyes which now is worse.
-What is the problem?
-The problem is that from time to time when there is light, I see like a dark window.
Some spots, like dark hair and when I read I'm not sure if the book is clean.
-Did you see an ophthalmogist?
-Yes.
-What did he say?
-He said to take vitamins. He said that I have something like wool in vitrus corpus.
I don't know how to say it. The sheep has wool. Something like that in the eye.
-Between menses do you have any leucorrhea?
-Yes.
-Strong?
-Not so strong after Sepia but it is still. It had stopped for one month and then it reappeared.
-The menses became more protracted, you have more blood?
-Yes.
-Was any desire for sexual contact?
-Not at all.
-If it doesn't exist, it doesn't matter.
-Yes but I want so much to have children and this is not possible if I have no desire.
-But the desire for children, not the desire for sex.
-Yes desire for children.
-Would you like to have children even if you are not married?
-I thought this problem but I think it's no good for them. In our society is not good for
children without family and they will be hurt any moment and I don't want.
-You have to be married in your society, Balkan society.
-The gums are bleeding more easy.
-With company you feel...
-But when I'm sad I must be alone, I don't want to be with nobody.
-You don't want to be seen being sad?
-Yes.
-Would you say you have fear of death?
-Yes. All the fear that something will happen and ...
-Fear of death 3 times. If you eat something salty, you will have a reaction?
-No. I can't eat very salty.
-If it's something salty you feel bad?
-No, I just don't need it.
-The salt that you take is normal?
-Yes.
-It's not that you have aversion to salt.
-No.
-And the sweets that you want to take after food it is something very sweet or a cake?
-It doesn't matter. It must be something sweet.
-But very sweet? Like sugar, syrup?
-It can be.
-You still like it?
-Yes.
-Any perspiration during night?
-No, I do not perspire and I do not make fever if I take an influenza.
-Do you have any kind of to be fastidious, you need order very much.
-Yes, very. And if I start to make a thing, it must be like I want.
If it isn't I start again and again and again until I make it perfect.
-The way that it will satisfy yourself.
-Yes and I must do it in the shortest time possible.
-So you are in a hurry, you feel it inside you?
-Yes, in a great hurry.
-And your things, your clothes is in order?
-No, this not.
-Only you need order in your work.
-Yes, order in my work and in the house but with clothes sometimes I put them here and there.
-But are you particular with what you are wearing? You want to be fit in colors and to be nice?
-Yes.
-You say if you have company, you are not afraid.
-And you said you feel more cold than before?
-Yes it's about a week or two because I just finished the (?).
My colleagues observed that I'm much colder than before.
-Did you take any other medication during that time?
-No, I was afraid to take anything.
-OK very good.
I don't want to marry but I'm very happy because of that.
I don't want to have a relationship but I'm happy.
So the problem you come to be treated is not to find a husband or the problem is not that
I want to have a relationship.
So he comes to you to be treated for something, that something what it is?
How you will define it?
When she was rejected by this particular man because he left her, she was happy or unhappy?
-Unhappy.
-She was unhappy. She is so unhappy that in the scale in which we saw here...
I'm very impatient for these machines.
So why she came to be treated?
You will say she came to be treated mostly because on an emotional level she has
a depression which has gone almost to apathy.
This is why she came to be treated because she came depressed after this incident.
Before this incident she was a happy girl. After that incident she went into a deep depression
to the extend that went further than depression in an apathy state, no emotions.
This is what you are treating when you try to prescribe on this case.
So you have to have this idea where is the problem and what is the problem you are treating
and that's why she was given perhaps Nat. mur. and Ignatia and things like that.
Then we analyzed the case and then we gave a dose of Sepia.
What happened after Sepia according to what she said yesterday, this everybody remembers.
A week later she felt great calmness, she felt actually very good, correct? Correct.
She is feeling good and suddenly 4 months later there are some phobias, fears arising.
Where are the phobias? Can you see there?
I did not write this down, I've written it 20-30 years ago.
This is a photocopy from the page of the book the Science of Homeopathy written in 1976
and published for the first time in 1978. The observation by that time was that
this is how you attain a cure by treating several...
And I have said before we have to treat sometimes with 2,3,4 remedies.
You have 2,3,4 remedies that you have to treat the case and it comes like this.
It is not that you give the 5 remedies and you are on this level. No.
You are treating and as one level goes away, then the other, you are going towards a cure,
a general balance.
In this 3-dimensional , she comes to be treated for the emotional level mostly
with a deep depression, a shock that the organism could not handle it and said, stop the emotions
because they are so painful that I can not handle it.
This is the reaction of the organism.
That means her organism decided that if I keep on having emotions, I'm not going to be alive,
I'm going to die, I can not stand. The organism makes this decision
and brings the problem on this level, this is not unusual story what happened to her.
I have heard the story many times, that I was ready to get married.
Sometimes women are left in the church.
They have gone to the church, everything is OK, they go to the church and the man
does not appear, this is even worse.
I don't think this was your case, your case was similar but not so...
But for her it doesn't matter, for her it is a matter of life or death.
Therefore she goes into depression. What we are treating? We are treating a deep depression
and we have to understand that this is what we are treating.
Otherwise we may be thinking we're giving a remedy for her so she can have a boyfriend
or something like this, this is not the case.
Whether she will have a boyfriend or not it's a lot of other things, coincidence, environment etc.
Now you have given this remedy and the remedy has produced certain changes and the changes
that produce is on the first level, it is a feeling that I now feel better in my emotional condition.
Then some fears arise. Did you hear these fears in the first interview?
-Yes, fear of death and then her next fear was to remain alone.
And she was afraid of earthquakes and then she was also afraid of robbers
because they had broken into her house.
-What happens? As I have said many times, we gave Sepia.
This is Sepia and this is thenext remedy we're going to decide and the next remedy had a few symptoms,
just from the underline level, a few symptoms popping up because the fears which she mentions
were not appearing to us, at the moment of the first interview that this was the main issue. Right?
Did you get the impression from the first interview that the fears were the main issue to be treated?
-No.
-You agree all in that?
-Yes.
-So the fears were not the main issues because there was something else more important
and that something else was the depression. Once the depression is lifted then the fears appear.
The question that we have to deal with in this case, if we want to proceed with the correct treatment
is a big question. The next remedy is it clear?
If it clear there is big hope that we can improve her health very much and you may be seen
in another interview the third remedy appear.
But at this stage those who studied her case as a follow up, have you seen a clear remedy coming?
This is the question that you have to ask yourself. Is the next remedy clear?
If it clear there is big hope that the health can improve dramatically.
The moment it is unclear, we have to wait, we have this, we have that.
Now the picture of the problem that she presented is a totally different picture which has
another picture, another remedy.
Who says the remedy is clear now?
Do you all agree that this is the same remedy you're talking?
In order to do that we have to study again her symptomatology. You have it there?
Put the symptoms now, in order to study her symptomatology at this level.
The case is a case of phobias at this moment, correct? You agree.
-I have a question because there is something I don't understand because I thought that
normally the emotional level should be better at the first time and then...
-You thought? That is why in 1973 I said, watch out, it's not like this.
Sometimes you will have to go through the hierarchy and go from one system to another
and then you have a direction of cure.
In the same way you think almost everybody else was thinking by 1976 and that's why I said,
in order to have a cure we have to have a step by step system by system,
more and more towards health.
So this is what you are learning here. Otherwise if what you knew was correct,
you don't have to be here.
So what you are saying is correct for a case which is much more mild in which case we will see that
the emotional goes well and the physical goes worse.
There is another even more mild case again with some mental-emotional symptoms in
which mental-emotional and physical all go away and everything appears in the skin
and there is another more mild case that everything mental-emotional and physical just
vanish without any further problem.
So it depends on the depth of the case whether it is possible to do the first,
the second or the third possibility.
-Sorry but how can you explain that the fear of robbers which has been before...
-I don't have to explain. I said in 1976 when I wrote this book, which I presented to you
I said that it is deeper that the apathy and the sadness and the suicidal depression is
deeper than a state of phobia, why?
Because I have seen in treating thousands of cases that before you make a cure, you
have to go through these steps, unfortunately.
-I have a question. I have looked at this model and I appreciate that she has gone in the direction
that you are describing but in her recent case she spoke of being forgetful and
I couldn't reconcile that with improvement.
-Forgetful you go onto the mental level. Forgetfulness is very low in the...
See the mental level. Absent mindness is the mildest and then forgetfulness is very mild.
And as you go lack of concentration, dullness, lethargy, delusion, paranoid ideas,
destructive delirium, complete mental confusion etc. and then you have the schizophrenia
of course. So what is important in this case is, as I said, to find whether the next remedy
which appears, has the symptoms that she describes.
And the symptoms, just put them down. Can you all read the symptoms?
Copious menses, fear of death of course, which is the main issue, the fear of death which
underlines her symptoms as she described them.
What is the remedy? Some people put up their hands for knowing the remedy.
Which is the remedy?
-Arsenicum.
-The majority wins. It is true that I was vacillating between Phosphorus and Arsenicum.
Arsenicum and Phos. actually they are very close, it has first Arsenicum, then Phos.
Mama mia! We agree. If you remember I asked her whether she likes order and she said
yes but not in my clothes. Arsenicum really is orderly even in the clothes.
The feeling of coldness is both for Phosphorus and for Arsenicum, the fear of death is for
both and the fear for robbers is more strong with the Arsenicum.
Arsenicum, as we have said in the lectures, he is searching to find the robbers.
How is the thirst, I don't remember.
-Ice cold water.
-Ice cold water is in favor of Phos. and not in favor of Arsenicum.
-I want to add that she has a great deal of thirst for cold drinks in big sips and as far as
I know, Arsenicum has got thirst for little sips for water and this speaks rather for Phosh.
Find thirst and show them. For the lady that said that I know that Arsen. has thirst for
small quantities frequently, which is true, also true is that Arsen. also has great thirst
for large quantities, equally true.
So you are learning now that Arsen. has strong thirst equally for big quantities.
One by one.
The desire for child or no child etc. can not be a big issue here. If somebody will say
that I don't want children and states a reason why, it is not an aversion to children
because some choice is there.
Platina for instance. They don't want children or they don't want to get married or
they are afraid of getting married, therefore they say I will not marry.
This is Nux vomica but if they say, I will not marry because I can not support a
family, I feel I'm not well educated, I can not earn enough and I can not support a family.
This is not a Nux vomica case.
-This is a sure case of Arsenicum for 3 reasons. There is no fear of thunderstorms,
she cares for her parents and she wants everybody work really well and precise, as she does.
-Of course I said it.
-You said it but he forgot. Then it's my problem.
Yes I agree. These are the points on which also I was vacillating
between Phosphorus and Arsenicum.
She could be Phosphorus, there is no question and especially with the
bleeding which has increased.
This is a strong point in favor of Phosphorus.
There is no question and if Arsenicum fails, then definitely we go to Phosphorus.
But for the reasons that mentioned also first I would try... It was a difficult decision
because of the cold water and the increase in menses with a lot, much more blood
this is big change pointing to Phosphorus. And I was going for Phosphorus
but then I could not confirm it.
On the other hand the Arsenicum idea was coming up more and more clear.
-Aversion to sex?
-Still about the aversion to sex I feel that she needs time to digest.
You change the chemistry of the system but the system still needs to digest a traumatic experience
which took place so deep and created such a deep problem.
When she came, she was in despair. Today I don't think she was in despair so much.
-She says no, I was not in despair. She may not even have come for a second interview
and the third interview will say, we will say, will you please come? OK, what can I do?
I will come. But when the problem really is pushing, forget about it.
She was having big problems to appear in front of the class, it's not easy. Do you understand?
I hope you understand these things and you evaluate these things
and in your evaluation of the case,
these things have to be taken into consideration.
After the Arsenicum, when then she will think out things, she will try maybe once again
the experiment but under different circumstances because I believe by the time she had
the first affair with this man, she was not really in a healthy condition and that's why the
depression went so deep as to destroy the feelings totally.
Now once she will feel more strong, she will try and she will handle the situation.
-I want to say something. I think she is still very reserved she is not that open as Phos. is
and I think that the children, you asked her if she would have children without being married,
is a totally different thing and she said that she would not dare in this society
to bring children without being married.
-Exactly, if you have a reason... For instance the Greek society also is very conservative.
So you can not do outrageous things that you can do in USA.
She was just telling me what outrageous things are going on with the young generation in America.
For us here in Greece, they do crazy things but not that craziness.
-George, as you said, fear of death is the issue here, the closeness between these two
remedies is, the difference is only in degree and in her case we don't see the hypochondriasis
as in Arsenicum.
She was sick for 4 weeks with that terrible cough and she never prescribed for herself that
she could have all sorts of help, she went all alone and then she took a small remedy which
just helped her and the anxiety and the fear of death is more frequent, it's not just death.
Crossing the street I might have an accident.
Something might happen, so could it be Phosphorus?
-I thought you were saying all that in favor of Arsenicum.
You said exactly the opposite. I will tell you something, the difference between Phos. and
Arsenicum... Show anxiety about health.
Both remedies have fear of death but Phos. is much more anxious and hypochondriac
than Arsenicum. Arsenicum is not so much hypochondriac as Phos. is.
Phos. is more hypochondriac, has more anxiety about health where Arsenicum in spite of the fact
that appears capital in the fear of death, does not appear capital in the anxiety about health.
Is it correct what I said?
In the Synthesis Arsenicum is on the first degree in anxiety about health and then Phosp.
is in the second degree. That means in any case Arsenicum is less anxious than Phos.
You got it? Very simple. This is the idea where the fear of death is equal,
the anxiety about health is less in Arsenicum than Phos.
The Arsen. here should have been risen to the second degree from the first degree and
the Phos. should raise to the third degree instead of the second. This is the correction
if you want to do it.
But they have done it out of my lectures and things like that, they have added symptoms.
But those who said Phosphorus is a possibility it's very close, they might be correct.
We don't know yet. I will start with Arsenicum, what potency? 10M? 50M? CM?
It doesn't matter. 200. Arsenicum 200 will be good. Also these fears are not really deep.
You see, when I'm with company, I have no fears. I see her color. The color is very good.
The circulation has started. Now the emotions will start, don't worry.
The emotions will also come quite...
I will tell you a secret. If somebody is embarrassed and is becoming red, it's a good sign.
If he is embarrassed or fearful and becomes white it's not a good sign for the health.
Hippocrates used to do this. This is not Hippocrates, since it is my observation.
Also people who blush will tell you the truth more easily, people who become white while
you examine them, they will not tell you the truth, they will tell you what they like.
They are driven by the head, the head dictates everything. So if you can blush, it is a very good
thing, for men and for women, especially for women because women usually tell lies.
Oh my god!
I take it back. Actually my wife has never lied. Don't laugh because it is true.
The remedy is clear in this case?
-No.
-You see we have some difficulties. We said, if the remedy is clear then there is great hope.
Is this remedy clear, yes or no?
-No.
-Almost.
-Both are clear.
-In this case you say either this or that is going to work. That is clear enough for Homeopathy.
We have so many problems, so many troubles. Many times you see...
this and that but when it comes to the point where you say Arsen.
is quite strong or Phos. then it's clear.
So actually she is, I could say, quite clear for the situation.