-Tell us your story.
-I have this cough about 3 weeks and 2,5 weeks ago I took Ignatia 1M
because I wanted to be fit to be able to come here
but the amelioration was only for a while and now it's aggravating again more and more.
It's really bad in the evenings and in the mornings.
During the day it's not quite bad and it's changing, I can hardly tolerate cigarette smoke,
talking and laughing aggravates and cold air,
if I ride my motorbike home at night I have to cough.
-What I see is she has almost an asthmatic breathing now, how did it start?
It started as a cough, as a bronchitis, laryngitis, pharyngitis, where?
-It started slowly only a little bit in the beginning which slowly got worse
and after Ignatia M it got better and the cough got loose
but now it's getting continuously aggravating again.
-She was smoking?
-Only once for a while and I don't inhale.
-As I understand, it just started as a cough?
-Yes.
In the very beginning was only a cough, nothing else.
Now last week for 3 days I had pain in my throat, then I had pain in my left ear
and now I have a coryza but it all started with a simple cough.
I would like to tell you something about what preceded the cough.
From my very early childhood, since I can remember, I had frequent severe bronchitis
and this lasted until I was adult and I used to have a bronchitis 2-3 times every winter,
lasting for about 4 weeks, just always like that.
-Until what year?
-Until about 10 years ago.
Then I received Tuberculinum, that really helped me a lot with it
and you have to know that someone of the family had tuberculosis.
And about 3,5 years ago I developed a severe depression.
And for 2 years during this depression, I had no acutes at all.
I received two remedies. The first one was Aurum mur.
which really helped me out of the depression and then after 1 year, I got Ignatia.
After Ignatia I developed a very severe acute which lasted 1 week.
I had a very severe bronchitis, I was coughing almost constantly,
my temperature was 38,5 degrees Celsius and every night I was only able to sleep for 1 hour,
I was very severely ill.
Just about time we were going through this 4 group during your lessons,
I was very surprised and amazed to experience this myself.
-Is she a chiropractor doctor?
-Yes.
With Ignatia I was doing really very well.
I think I repeated it 3 times all together and really my life got very good,
I had a lot of joy of life, a lot of energy and if I had the cough,
I only had it for 2-3 days in between.
-When did she receive Ignatia for the first time?
-About 2 years ago, in November of 97.
-2 years ago and the depression came for what reason?
-My partner separated from me at that time and after that I fell into this depression.
This spring something happened. I had a relationship with another man for 2,5 years
whom I loved really very much and we came together but then we separated again and
after a while he came back to me.
This time I really believed him and I thought he is really serious,
so we engaged again in a relationship and after 3 months, he again separated from me
and that really almost brought me back to this depression.
At that time I repeated Aurum mur. which helped me out of it again
and I still was very sad but I was stable.
Then in August of this year something happened.
Together with some other people, we were doing a canoe tour on the river
and one of the canoes tipped over and one of the people got stuck in the canoe
and he drowned. That really shook me up severely.
For more than 1 week I was in a state of shock.
I was just sitting there and these images kept repeating, I kept seeing these images
and what was really bad for me, one minute after this incident happened,
I passed this place with my canoe and I kept thinking maybe I could have saved him,
if I would be able to do something.
-Who else was in the canoe?
-I was together in my canoe with somebody else
but I was the person in the back stirring the canoe.
-I want to understand. In the canoe where this boy was drowned was somebody else?
-He was alone on his canoe.
-She was on another canoe and most probably it was a rough water and she was in the canoe
with somebody else together and they did not realize he was drowning?
-The situation was the following. We could not see at first
because the canoe had been pressed under water and I did not know,
I did not see he was stuck in the canoe with his legs.
I assumed he was bringing himself onto safety by climbing onto some rocks,
which was not the case but things happen very quickly and you have to react very quickly
and it was one second which I had to decide which way to take.
And this second just passed very quickly for me, then I couldn't change anymore.
He was gone and it was too quick for me to make the right decision.
-They lost sight of the canoe?
-The canoe tipped over and it was kind of fold around the rock, as if it was made from paper
and he was under water and stuck in the canoe pieces.
His head was still above the water, it was only his feet that was stuck in the boat
but I could not see the boat and I could not see that he was still in the boat.
I kept having the thought that maybe there would a tiny chance to save him
if I had reacted in another way, although people repeatedly told me
you couldn't have done anything else than what you did and there was no other way of reacting.
-But what are her feelings after that? How she feels? She feels guilty?
-I thought about it a lot and I finally realized that in the situation I was in
I couldn't have seen it any better and I could not have reacted any other way
and now feelings of guilt are gone, most of them are gone.
My homeopath gave me first Opium and after Opium I came out of this shock state
and after that I developed a lot of fears, especially fear of death and fear of being alone.
After that my homeopath gave me Phosphorus and after Phosphorus I developed a toothache,
which I had had before but now it got really bad.
This toothache got so bad that I couldn't sleep anymore, I had to take pain medication
and that's when I made a mistake, just out of sheer desperation,
I started to take different remedies.
One of them was Magnesia mur., Magn. phos, the next remedy was Arsenicum
and my dentist treated the tooth twice.
She left it open, she made a new filling but the pain did not ameliorate.
Then she told me the tooth has to be removed.
After Arsenicum the tooth ameliorated but a couple of days later I had the operation.
After the operation I had bleeding at the area and I took Arnica 1M
and a couple of days later the cough started.
Then as I told you, I took Ignatia 1M with the cough.
What I also have to mention, on the day the accident happened,
that was the first day of my menstruation and after this incident it ceased immediately
and it came back after Opium, I think, but then it was very dark
and the menses then developed into leucorrhea and I also have itching in the vagina,
something like mycosis and the leucorrhea also was a bit offensive
and since then my menses did not come back. Do you want to know any other physical symptoms?
-Mostly I'd like to know her mental-emotional state.
-In general my mental-emotional state is quite OK.
After taking Ignatia I felt a lot better and before Ignatia I had a lot of grief
due to the situation in spring, I told you about, and here I feel quite stable,
quite all right being here.
Sometimes I'm a bit sad, it feels like an emotional exhaustion, as if all of this was too much
and a great fatigue, I need a lot of sleep but it feels as if something is underneath
when I'm not this calm.
Last night I woke once in the middle of the night, with palpitations
and then developed a kind of panic state.
Last week during one night, I woke with palpitations and then panic arising;
then I only turned from my right side to my left side and fell asleep again.
A couple of days ago, I had this bad nightmare after which I also woke
and it was frightening.
-In that same state?
-I have to tell you some more things about the cough. It changed in the last few days.
Right now it also gets quite bad, when I lie down to sleep at night,
then I have to sit up again.
It's such an attack which doesn't ameliorate at all and it goes so far
that finally I'm choking. My spittle is forming white and tastes salty...
-If she brings out some spittle, the cough is ameliorated?
-Yes but only for a short while. My lymph nodes are swollen in my neck
and a couple of days ago in the evening, I developed a pain in my ear. The ear closed.
I could hardly hear anymore in my left side and as a child I had frequent otitis
and this was the first time something like that reoccurred.
Right now I have a coryza and a thick yellow secretion from the nose.
What is also remarkable is that my eyes are swollen in the morning,
especially around the right eye below and above the eye.
I'm quite restless when I go to bed due to the cough and I'm trying from one side
to the other and I have attacks of perspiration when I have to cough really severely.
In these cough attacks, I perspire a lot.
-How does she feel with the heat-cold?
-Cold aggravates and I feel cold in general and like warmth. I really like the sun here.
I can stay out in the sun for two-three hours, it does me well and I feel good with it.
What's also important is when I have to cough, I always lose a little bit of urine.
So these are the acute symptom and I also had some tinnitus when I had this ear thing
and the ear closed, I had a kind of whistling noise in it.
-The pain in the ear, what kind of pain she had? Stitching pain, tearing pain?
-I tried to find a word but I can not describe it, it was not tearing, not stinging.
I can't find an expression for it. What also was in the last days is,
on Sunday we went for a hike and afterwards I was very exhausted
and then I developed a feeling which comes again every now and then,
as if my heart was weak somehow.
Also with palpitations and I remember having something like that when I was 23.
At that time I went to the clinic repeatedly to have my heart checked
because I though something was wrong but everything was OK.
-You have some other symptoms?
-I often have a tired feeling in my head and around the eyes
but it did ameliorate after Ignatia.
-She took Gelsemium?
-No.
I frequently have to do with headaches, frontal headaches, pressing pain,
especially if I have grief and I cry, it gets really bad
but this also has got better after Ignatia.
-She has taken Nat. mur.?
-Yes.
-Did it help her? How much salt she takes?
-Very normal.
-The fat she likes?
-Not at the moment, I used to.
-Fruits?
-I didn't like them until the first dose of Ignatia, afterwards it was gone, now I like fruits.
-What fruits she likes best?
-Especially juicy fruits like peaches, mangos.
-No apples?
-Not so much.
I often have a restlessness of my legs which was especially bad during the toothache
and now I'm also restless, as I told you in the evening.
-She is not restless now. She tries to control it?
-Especially it comes when I lie in bed and try to fall asleep and the last days
was not only the legs but the entire body.
-Sweets she likes?
-Especially chocolate.
-What about milk?
-I don't like it.
-Her thirst is normal?
-Here I drink a lot, I'm more thirsty for cold drinks, at home when it's cold,
I have problems with cold drinks.
-Is she very sympathetic?
-Yes.
-How much underlines sympathetic?
-2-3 times. For example I read in the newspaper there is an earthquake in Turkey
and I read about a child and I cry.
-Nails are strong?
-Strong.
-She eats eggs?
-Yes, normally.
-Salt she use to desire very much?
-Actually never but the thirst is very strong and I know the symptom of unquenchable thirst
for ice cold drinks and at that time I received one dose of Phosphorus in LM potency
and after that it was gone.
-She did not take Aconitum?
-No.
-Now she is not afraid of dying?
-That's what I wanted to mention about the fear.
This nightmare I had a couple of days ago was about a dead body,
I was pulling out of the water and when I feel fine on the upper level
I can not really sense it but I feel it's there underneath.
It's like somewhere down there there is something waiting
and every once in a while a door opens and something comes up and then it's hidden again.
I repeatedly had a very strong feeling of abandonment and fear of being alone
and that runs through my entire life.
I have to say something. I think in my childhood I was a Stramonium child.
I can remember awakening every night with fear and panic and screaming
and I didn't even want to go to bed because I was so afraid.
My parents coped with it for a while and then finally one night my father came and he bit me
until I shut up. And after that I got very closed.
This feeling of abandonment and combined with panic and fear of being alone
and all this is still down inside me, somewhere and I'm afraid in the dark
and I'm quite fearful of dogs and I have a strong fear of having an accident.
I can really imagine it, I can picture it in front of me.
-Has she ever taken Stramonium?
-Yes, I tried it in June after this incident with the man because I was feeling so bad
and I tried very carefully with Q potencies but I got a severe aggravation
and then I stopped it.
-Aggravation of what?
-The fears.
It was such a terrifying fear of abandonment and all my child memories came back
and they got so strong, I couldn't bear it.
And I also wanted to add that as a child I had an extreme fear of fire,
fear that the house would burn.
One other thing I wanted to mention which happened
after I have received Phosphorus 4 weeks ago...
-She took Phosphorus now lately?
-Yes after Opium, do you remember? After the incident.
-And this was the time when she had unquenchable thirst?
-That Phosphorus for the thirst was 9 years ago.
When I got the Phosphorus this time these feelings of guilt got very strong after Phosphorus.
And when these feelings of guilt got so strong after Phosphorus,
I also could make a connection again to my childhood days and I remember also suffering
from extreme feelings of guilt, as if I had done something so bad,
that if my parents ever find out, they would get rid of me, they would send me away.
-The parents are alive?
-My father has died and you must know I was raised very catholic
and the feeling was equivalent to doomed.
I have anticipatory anxiety, if something is approaching, I'm also very excited
and with cruel things I can not deal at all.
I can not see it in the TV either and as a child I was in a dream state most of the time,
I was living in a phantasy world from which nobody could get me out.
And this can still happen to me today, if I ride my motorbike
and I look at this beautiful landscape, it can really happen that instead of taking
the next curve, I just continue straight ahead.
And what I also wanted to say which is quite strong, if I am in company I feel much better,
if I'm alone I feel quite bad.
And I need this deep contact to people, I need real talks
and I also need physical contact tenderness.
-Sexual desire is strong?
-Yes.
If I have a relationship which is going well, then it's very strong.
And I'm scared quite easily.
-OK.
This is a really confused case, really confused.
You don't know what to give, there is no indications at all of a possibility of a remedy
except if you go and just take a chance.
You can take a chance with Aconitum, which may give some effect.
The possibility of Stramonium is very strong, I'm not sure that this is not a good remedy,
I think it's a good remedy for her but maybe not at first.
The fact that Stramonium gave such strong fears it doesn't mean that the remedy is wrong.
On the contrary, because she has already a lot of fears and the mental-emotional picture
is on that level, you may see an aggravation first on that level.
We have spoken about that and this is most probably what was happening.
There is a remedy which I would have given, just for the cough but this remedy is ...
Dry tight cough and aching in left ear, that's interesting.
Worse from motion, from heat wet, cold weather, from pressure and touch.
I found out that this remedy when somebody is having a fright
after seeing a dead person suddenly.
One of the remedies is Guaiacum.
But all these remedies that you can think, Phosphorus is a possibility but she took and...
The best reaction for me, from what she described from the remedies,
the best reaction she had was from Stramonium. What potency of Stramonium did you take?
-LM.
-High or low?
-Q1 for 1 week and Q2 also for 1 week once the day.
-And the reaction when it started?
-Immediately, even while I was taking it I found that psychologically I went down.
-If you touch the bottom, then you go up.
-I have to add something. I know you have these initials aggravations
after taking a remedy and I know it can be bad but this one was so severe, it was very bad.
Maybe after the Q2 I did feel stable for a while but then I also had problems
with my boyfriend and the relationship ended and then I felt bad again.
-When in time, when did she take the Stramonium?
-In June.
-Did she have the cough by that time?
-No.
-In time when the fright was with the boy who drowned?
-That was in the beginning of August.
-It means 1 month ago?
-Yes. It happened on the 7th of August.
-She does not have the look of Stramonium. This is not the look of Stramonium.
This is the look of somebody which something happened and has become weak
because of that fright and that has remained inside all the time.
It's not the fear, the fright but somebody who has been frightened ...
That's why I thought of Guaiacum.
I would suggest first you take a dose of Guaiacum just for the cough to see what happens
and the pain, you just take 1,2 doses of Guaiacum 200, then try Aconitum
and if this does not work then most probably you have to try one dose of Stramonium 200.
You have to understand the idea of aggravation, especially with the fears,
is the idea of facing fears. You can not always keep the fears under control
and under the conscious in a sub-conscious level.
-I'd like to know how long I should wait for one remedy to act before I try the next.
-With Guaiacum in 1 week you should have an effect.
That means if you see a big aggravation then you can wait longer, in the cough.
So you may be coughing for a few days and to start coming out with sputum.
What I see that the bronchi are affected already and you have a difficulty
in breathing really, that's what I see.
That means there must be a kind of inflammation to take out the problem.
So if you get an aggravation, it's OK.
If you get an amelioration immediate of the cough, that means is not a good idea.
That means it's acted superficially and most probably the cough will come back
in one week or 10 days, you will have back the cough.
If you get a mental aggravation together with an aggravation of the cough,
this is the best. Then you wait for a long time.
But in any case, your case you have to be careful
because you can confuse the case totally and nobody will be able to do anything, anymore.
-George I'm confused.
-You are not the only one.
-If her case can be easily mixed up, why...
-Because we see the remedies they have an effect upon her quite strong.
She takes Phosphorus, the thirst is going away, she takes again Phosphorus all the fears,
she takes Stramonium the fears...
That means the organism is easily affected by homeopathic remedy.
Such individual should be careful not to use too many remedies.
-So why you prescribe 3 in a row?
-No, I'm not prescribing 3 in a row. You made a mistake.
I prescribed one, if there is no effect, then you prescribe the second.
I give some ideas, I don't prescribe.
Actually she knows what to do when the symptoms come,
most probably she will take another remedy all together or maybe after Guaiacum
she develops a clear case of Bryonia.
She takes Bryonia and she is OK, it doesn't have to be the remedies sequence...
Maybe she takes Guaiacum and then the fear of dark becomes intolerant,
that is the time she takes Stramonium. Maybe she takes Guaiacum
and the fear of death becomes too strong,
I'm going to die in 2-3 weeks I'm going to die, then Aconitum.