-You can give us a follow up what happened after Ignatia 50M and CM you took last October?
-In the middle of October last year I took 3 times 50M and twice CM Ignatia.
About 3 days later I had the first reaction which was very heavy perspiration at night.
This sweating in the night which was very warm and not exhausting was going on for about 1 week.
Afterwards with a break of about 1 week, a sleeplessness developed.
The sleeplessness was such that I could fall asleep very well but I could wake about
1 or 2 hours later and then stay awake for 1 hour, sleep for 1/2 an hour, wake for 1 hour...
During this period of sleeplessness I developed an anxiety to what would come up to me
the next day, the events of the next day.
This state was going on for about 10-14 days and I was very tired throughout the day.
I had quite some problems to manage my daily affairs and to continue to do my office,
my practices.
During this time I was still smoking about 8-10 cigarettes per day.
It was quite difficult for me to manage without taking any coffee or any other things but I managed
After this period of sleeplessness was going on for about 10-14 days, it was practically
sleepless on 1 week I practically slept through, without any breaks.
-Day and night?
-Yes. And then this sleeplessness was over but 1 month later I developed a bronchitis.
This bronchitis was very painful, the fever would go up to 38.5 and would go on for about 10 days.
-You took no medication?
-No, I just put warm applications on my breast and that was the main thing. And that did me good.
About 8 days following this bronchitis, I was pretty warn out and couldn't go to work in my practices.
Then for 1 month I could do my practices without any difficulty and
then I got the next bronchitis and that was at the end of December, beginning January
and that was going on with about the same attitude like the first one.
I didn't do any treatment again and I have to close my practices again about 14 days.
-The bronchitis was, according to him, something stronger in the past he has experienced?
-I never really had bronchitis in my life. I only twice had lung infections and one was when
I was 16, I had a pneumonia and later on 1 bronchitis and that was all. Otherwise no bronchitis.
Then another month would pass by and I got my third bronchitis. Then this bronchitis
was very heavy, I had a hard time recovering from this bronchitis, I was very tired
dull in my mind, had difficulties to think.
-Nobody took down his symptom during that time?
-No. After that I had such a hard time to recover, I repeated in the beginning of March
50M of Ignatia. Then I recovered pretty soon, I realized that the energy was coming back.
And after this I did a hiking and fasting tour with some other people for 10 days.
This was very good for me again and after this third bronchitis I stopped smoking.
It was the first time in my life that I had the strength to stand through, work in my
practices and giving up smoking, without any relapse.
The main problem why I started smoking and why I was smoking in my past, was this
incredible pressure on my chest from the outside as well and from the inside.
And this nagging emptiness with an incredible feeling of hunger in my stomach.
And these symptoms got aggravated with a certain emotional stress situation and by
smoking I somehow could keep it low.
I may say so that the first remarkable improvement is that this blockage of openness
is starting to loosen up.
-He means in the chest?
-No, all together, mentally and emotionally.
-He felt more free?
-Yes.
-How is the emptiness in the stomach now?
-This emptiness is not very pronounced for the time being but for the time being I'm not
under strong emotional stress either.
I want to add something. When I now came to Alonissos I took a package of green tea with me
and I would take that as a substitute for the black tea and I prepared it for myself
and I realized that my energy would get low after drinking the green tea.
And when I left it out about 2 days ago I realized that my energy is increasing again.
I just want to bring into discussion that green tea might diminish
the reaction of the homeopathic remedy.
-When he says green tea is of a special herb?
-We have the green tea and the normal tea.
-The normal tea is the black tea?
-Yes.
-And the green tea is one herb.
-The green tea is not fermented, if you take the green leaves and not fermented.
-It's the same.
-I asked some people and found out the caffeine content is higher in the green tea.
-I want to ask him some questions.
He had an aversion to butter milk, is it still there?
-Yes, still there.
-The desire for fish?
-Still good.
-Is any change in his desires and aversions? He eats more fruits now?
-I eat some more fruits in the moment.
-Salt?
-Hardly but I never ate any salt to my meals.
-If he can give me a general overall view for his present state at the moment, he would I'm satisfied
or there are certain things that he would like to improve further?
-The important point is what I've been describing before. There is this inner pressure.
-The pressure in the chest which continues?
-It's still there but for the moment I feel so strong that even though I do my practices
I can fight against, I can deal with it. But it's still there without smoking.
-Still a desire to take a deep breath? This pressure is physical or emotional?
-In my opinion is more emotional.
-But he says it comes from outside and from inside also.
-It comes from outside and at the same time is from inside.
The bad part about it is that it blocks me in my thinking.
-His energy level how much he would put it at the moment?
-Do you mean my level of sickness or energy?
-Energy.
-I think energy is about half of what I feel inside.
The problem is that I feel a lot of energy inside but my physical body doesn't come
along with my energy and my creativity.
-When he took the last dose on March 50M, he felt an immediate effect from the remedy?
-It took about 3-4 days.
-His sleep now is good?
-I have no problems falling asleep but then I wake around 4-5 o'clock in the morning.
-And that was before or now it's a new?
-That stayed the same.
-Always 4-5 o'clock in the morning and he has to go for stool when he wakes up at that time?
-Not at that time immediately but often enough at 5.30 in the morning I have an urge to go for stool
and for years it's been the first thing in the morning that I go and have my stool.
-The temperature of the body has changed at all? Became more warm, less warm?
-Not really but like I said before heat I can't tolerate very well.
-There is any special desire for sweets?
-I like sweets and it may happen that I eat a whole block of chocolate in one occasion.
And without any problems after having eaten a whole chocolate, I can eat something sour.
-Still did he try the vertigo high places? Did he have an opportunity to see whether it
still is there the vertigo of high places?
-I realized that this vertigo of high places got a little bit worse.
I realized it when I was at home and I had to repair my roof.
That was very uncomfortable for me.
-Very good.
The remedy is correct, has acted correctly for several reasons. You know now
you understand the upper 3 level how it goes to level 2. It was upper 3 goes straight
away to 2 with 1 month, acutes are severe.
Now whether we treat this acute or not, it is of great importance.
This acute, if it had a clear picture, it could be treated and should be treated.
Then the organism would feel even more relieved.
If the picture was not clear but the bronchitis or the pneumonia which he may develop later on
is threatening, is severe, then we repeat the original remedy.
If the symptomatology is not clear.
In his case we are in a crossroad. Which is the crossroad?
The remedy has done certain things. We are eager to take his case further.
And usually that is the time when we jump into the picture by giving another remedy.
Which is the other remedy that we give in this case?
-Sulphur.
-You see how good you become, very good, Sulphur.
The remedy becomes clearer and clearer, would you give it?
-Yes.
-No.
-OK, who would give it? Who would not give it? What you will do?
You don't give it, that's correct. You don't give it at the moment, you have it in mind.
This is a case where Sulphur symptoms are developing, you have it in mind and then
you say, wait I want something more. What more you want?
An even clearer symptom of Sulphur. What is it?
-Feet out of covers.
-Very good. Simple things like that will save your life and mostly the life of the patient.
In this case, where you are already thinking of Sulphur, you have a keynote of Sulphur
certain moment is very strong, then you go ahead, you can give it.
In the meantime what you do? This case need more repetition of the Ignatia until he treats it more
because we still see symptoms of Ignatia and we see symptoms  of Sulphur, as well.
Ignatia has affected this case quite strongly, quite good.
What was the best thing you hear about this case?
It is sleeping for 1 week. This is beautiful.
-One weekend.
-OK I heard one week. I said my god!
I had a case with Aurum. He slept for 20 days and nights.
He got up, eat etc. and then fall back again and again and again.
He had to give up his job totally. During 20 days and then the whole thing recovered.
That's why when I mentioned in the middle reactions fever and sleepiness is a very
good sign to know your remedy is acting beautifully. Wait.
It's very interesting now he stopped smoking also why?
Because he is more strong but yet Ignatia we know has an aversion to smoking.
Maybe that helped him a little bit to quit smoking.
Therefore the course of action is whenever you think the organism is going down repeat,
since himself is a homeopath, the Ignatia. One course of action.
The other course of action could be giving 12 every day for a period of time.
See whether this slow action of Ignatia could slowly improve the situation.
You can start by taking twice the day and if there is an aggravation, you stop.
If you may see a continuous improvement, you continue and then you go to once a day.
After 20 days, you can go to once the day.
And as long as there is, even slight improvement, you continue especially if you can raise
the potency every 10 days, you raise the potency. 12,14,15 etc.
These are new things, I'm just giving you my experience and don't be surprised.
I think this is enough.