-In May she got the Causticum C200 every day and in addition to this
she had the cortisone enemas with 2.5 mg and after this everything
was completely normal.
-When she came here originally she was taking how much cortisone
and how much enema?
-10 mg of cortisone and one enema per day.
-One enema of cortisone as well together with ...
-... with 2.5 mg of cortisone.
-And what else?
-It was just cortisone in the enema and the 10 mg of cortisone she left out
during the time she was on the island in May.
On the journey home she had one diarrhea after eating sour food and within five weeks
when she was at home, she would gradually stopped taking cortisone enemas.
One week after stopping the enemas the stool started to get thinner again
and had blood in it.
In addition to this I got stitching pains in my abdomen again in the left side
and rumbling and flatulence and the pain got ameliorated by passing of the bloatedness,
the flatulence and after this I should take the Causticum 1M on a daily basis,
nevertheless it got worse and worse.
I had about 20 times stool the day and increasing amount of blood.
-Let me read a little bit of the report which I received through the fax at this moment.
She stopped taking cortisone last weekend. Since three days it got more and more diarrhea,
the pain is much more worse, she could not hold it on.
Also the diarrhea is much more worse, she must go to the toilet 10-20 times the day
always with blood and pieces of mucus. The blood is dark and it gets more and more.
She took Causticum but it got worse, yes continue.
-The back aches came back under the right shoulder plate and extending to both sides.
During this time I was in very bad mood, permanently tired and had nearly no energy.
The skin eruption from Alonissos didn't get better;
this double checking was getting better but still there was a little bit
and home in Germany I was having throat pains, sensation as if there was something
stuck in my throat, no pains at night.
Then there were eczemas behind the ears, what I had in former times on my hands,
on my arms and on my legs.
This time was itching very much and I had to scratch so long till the crust was going off,
it was bleeding. Trembling was going on too.
And the warmer it got, the more trembling.
And after this I was told to take Mercury corrosivus C200, 3 times per day.
Nevertheless there was no amelioration and with the passing stool, the pain came on.
With the urge to stool already, this pain came on.
When I was leaning forward I was pressing this spot and the pain was getting better.
Otherwise it was a cramping pain and it was stitching as if a knife was going near
and the pain would come up suddenly and only faded away gradually after passing stool.
I had no problems during the night concerning stool.
Only the last stool of the day before the night would come, was most painful.
The next day the fever would rise to 38.2, there was more blood and water in the stool.
On Saturday, the sixth day, the fever got less again.
During the night I had stool too but less and with blood in it
and on Sunday it was much worse again and after this weekend, I got a strict diet.
Only rice with a little bit of lemon juice and black tea.
On Monday I got Sulphur C200 and after this I got strong skin eruption,
as if I had fallen into urticaria.
It was terribly itching, especially at night lying in bed and after the sleep in the afternoon.
The amount of stool per day was getting less, only eight times per day.
It was formed stool.
-Also she forgot to mention that she developed thirst, quite strong thirst for cold water.
-During this time I was very hot in my face and at this spot on my abdomen;
otherwise I was freezing and in addition to this I got astronaut diet.
I don't know how you call it in English.
The skin eruption got better and stool was normalizing too till Thursday,
the second of the July.
On that day I had a car accident and on the place of the accident the diarrhea
and the trembling was getting worse.
-She forgot to say that she bought the car a few days before
and it was a terrible shock for her.
-Yes and I had a shock and later on I thought about what could have happened.
And the police took the accident, took the details of the accident,
my parents came to the place of the accident and brought me to Sabine and to her office.
In the evening we called Greece and after this you gave me Aconite 1M
and on Friday next day the colitis was very bad again.
The course of accident was as bad as it had been before the homeopathic treatment
and in addition to this I got strong cramps in my calves.
In the evening I got Causticum 10M and in the night from Friday to Saturday
I was so bad that I didn't want to live anymore.
I couldn't walk anymore and on Saturday night I got Causticum CM.
Nevertheless it was gradually getting worse and worse.
It was continuously getting worse and worse and as the amount of stool was getting
more and more and the fever went up again.
And I've seen her during this time and her stage was getting so bad
that I was really getting scared that she was dying under my hands.
On Sunday I couldn't still walk and at noon I got Colocynthis C200 diluted in water.
-Colocynthis? I did not give this.
-No, I gave it to her because it was continuously developing.
-Actually you said you could not get me on the telephone, right?
-Yes, nevertheless she was getting worse faster and faster and we waited
till six in the evening.
Then I took Mercury corrosivus C200 and during the next hour I only had one stool.
After this I fell asleep.
For the first three hours I slept very restlessly and then I slept quite calmly
and in addition to this I took one enema of cortisone.
On Monday I still couldn't walk and I was unable to go and see the doctor
and after this I took vegetables soup.
Within half an hour I could walk again and my appetite was coming back.
-But she didn't say, she was given cortisone but first she got cortisone
and then she got better? She was better before the cortisone?
-Much better.
It was all gone actually and the internal doctor gave her 15 ml of cortisone every day
but at that stage she was able again to walk and to go and see him.
On Monday the diarrhea and the pain was completely gone and on Monday they made
a blood sample and the indications for inflammation were very much up.
One was 1.70.
-Centimentation rate?
-Probably centimentation rate. There is an indication of inflammation.
-C reactive protein was high?
-Yes, it was over 70 and the internal doctor was insisting that I would take the 15 ml
of cortisone every day and after three days he was controlling the blood again.
And this inflammation indication it was gone down to 12 and so he went down
with the cortisone to 14 ml and at this week I still have to take 7.5 ml.
And from next week on, only 5 ml and the blood examination is completely OK
at the moment.
Already one week after this bad relapse the blood examination was completely OK.
At a certain time the internal doctor gave her injections of iron and vitamins.
-I just want to read from the report on the 30th of June.
She took Sulphur 200 in the night, a big skin eruption started,
12 hours after taking the remedy.
Most of the face and the neck but also on the whole body and the extremities.
Then she reports on 1st of July, two days later, the temperature is 37.8
and the skin eruption stays on, it's the same as yesterday.
It's more worse after sleeping in the afternoon.
The itching is terrible, the skin eruption behind the ears stays on.
After this starting of the cortisone I did not have anymore reports.
-She is feeling well all the time.
-My problem was the fact that she was given so much cortisone.
I don't think this was necessary at all.
With 10 ml at the most she will be OK and now she will be down to 2-3 ml.
She took much more cortisone to what she actually...
I did not know because we spoke once after this incident and you told me,
as far as I can remember, that after taking the cortisone she was better.
-No, before.
-Now you say before which is even more terrible that so much cortisone was given.
-The internal doctor had seen her 5 hours after she took the cortisone and he,
himself said, this can't be due to the cortisone.
-It's a pity.
-But I'm only dentist and I can't tell to an internal doctor what to do.
-Anyhow I wanted her to describe really the accident because she bought the car
and  few days later, she smashed it.
And she was in a terrible state, she said I'll never drive again and she was destroyed totally.
-I got this car a week before as a present and I was on my way driving to Sabine
to her office and on a crossing I drove into another car and this woman in this car
got so frightened that she was speeding up and going downhill
and this car was completely smashed and mine wasn't. Mine got repaired afterwards.
-Yes but still she avoids to describe how she felt.
I think Sabine may remember better to describe her state.
-What was remarkable was this Thursday.
On Monday she had got Sulphur C200 and up to Thursday everything was gone.
The skin eruption was gone, the diarrhea was completely gone, the stool were completely normal
and one hour before she came to me to the practice, we spoke to one another
and she was in a very good mood.
She was completely OK and she told me that immediately, directly after this accident
the diarrhea started again, on the side of the accident already started
and when she came to my practice...
I mean I've seen her excited very often but this was more;
she was trembling over the whole body and she was crying all the time.
If something would have happened to this woman, if something would have happened to this woman...
And then we called you and you said, I should give her Aconite 1M and then just wait.
But she was in this state for hours.
And the colitis before was going on for 10-11 days and that was less than the colitis
that she had had before.
It wasn't so threatening for me but after this accident it was getting so much worse.
It was like a train takes off. You can just look from behind and see how it develops.
It was like hour by hour you could see how her state was aggravating,
getting worse and worse.
It was much worse than the three spells of colitis that I have observed before.
It was developing to great extreme and I had the impression that the Causticum
did not act, did not get it.
At first I was orienting myself concerning the symptomatology of the pain
because I could not get hold of you and I gave her Colocynthis.
In the evening it was clear to me that it must a case of Mercurius corrosivus
because it was going so fast and I really had a feeling she is slipping from my hands
and I couldn't think of another remedy.
And when she finally fell asleep after one hour even though her sleep was restless
and her mother was there and I was there, we were observing her.
But for the first time during these 14 days I was sort of relieved.
-Just before getting the cortisone.
-In the morning she already didn't have big stool. This passing stool was over already.
She couldn't stand because she had this lack and imbalance of electrolytes
and I wanted that the internal doctor would give her electrolytes.
And another remarkable thing is that at noon she rang me and she was feeling much better
and she told me that she wanted to go for motorcycle ride with her best friend.
And I thought I'm going to get a stroke, I couldn't believe it.
So fast and so rapid this course of disease has been, as fast and as rapid
it was stopped too afterwards.
-And she kept on taking Mercurius corrosivus during all this time?
-Yes on a daily basis until today. And she should say something concerning her energy
since this day because this is really remarkable too.
-I have a lot of energy, I do a lot of sports, I go out a lot in the evening,
go shopping and 4 times the week I do sports for 3 hours.
Twice the week and in addition to this I go for horse back riding.
-Very good.
-I've never seen her having so much energy during the 10 years that I know her.
-Is it true?
-Yes.
-How do you feel now concerning the colitis?
-Normal.
-And your thirst is...
-I have noticed some more things. The thirst got less,
the drinks don't need to be cold anymore.
With the double checks I still do it but not as often as before.
I have a lot of energy. Here, on this island I get tired very early.
Nevertheless I have a lot of energy throughout the day.
All together I'm more aggressive than before, not so adapted anymore.
I hated for example is somebody asked me the same questions 3-4 times
and then I'm afraid that on the open sea I could fall into the water,
that somebody could grab me from below. This fear of examination is still there.
Then I have a strong desire for bungee jumping...
-What is bungee jumping?
-You stand on a high bridge with this elastic chord and jump down.
-My god. She wants to do that?
-Yes and parachuting.
The day before yesterday we jumped down from a cliff, me and Eva.
-With this parachuting or with the string that goes down?
-She has desire for parachuting, to jump out from an airplane to go out to parachute
and for bungee jumping.
-And she did it already?
-No, I want to start it now.
-Anything else?
-I have a lot of bruises. When I hit something, the trembling got more again.
It's OK for the moment.
Yesterday it was really bad.
-Show me both your hands.
-It's not so bad now she said. The other fears are like my first history taking.
When I first came here for telling my history, with spiders and so on.
I have a disgust for fat, eat very little meat, mainly vegetables and fruits.
In addition to this I'm treated by another natural healing doctor.
He says he is going weight with the big masters.
I only went to see this doctor because I wanted to get this internal doctor
out of the game.
-This new doctor is using natural healing?
-He is an anthroposophic doctor but he says he is gonna stay out of this homeopathic treatment.
But I have to have a medical doctor in the background.
-Yes sure.
-He only gives Biogain which is a remedy just to build up the flora of the intestines.
-That's OK as long as he does not give a lot of mixtures and confuse it.
-Aversion fat strongly, underline three times.
-Little meat, disgust for fat, mainly vegetables and fruits she likes, full grain
and yogurt and chicken.
-Sweets?
-Little.
-And thirst is normal, cold or hot.
-It doesn't matter.
-This excessive thirst for cold water is totally gone?
-Yes.
-Something else I wanted to ask you from the first time.
She had reported brittle finger nails, how are they now?
-Still brittle.
-Also she had reported aggravation from onions.
-Raw onions.
-She can eat now?
-I haven't tried it so far.
-Also she had reported fear of the dark.
-Yes.
-So she says now she has suppressed anger.
She says now the anger comes out more easily?
-Yes.
-And she feels good with that?
-Yes, I didn't really remark it, she told me. Other people tell me.
-Also she had involuntary urination while laughing?
-Only former times, not now.
-The feeling that she has forgotten to do things is still there?
-Every now and then.
-Also the sleep was unrefreshing. You wake up in the morning and you feel good?
-No, I'm still tired.
-But in comparison with previously is it better?
-Yes.
-Also how is her sexual desire, energy?
-The same as before.
-Not much interest. She had reported aversion to...
-Also she had reported timidity in public appearing.
-That is still.
-Bite her nails still?
-Only very rarely when I'm excited.
-Cold, hot how is the general state of the body?
-Warm.
-And she really suffers from that? When she is in a close room,
she has to go and open the windows?
-No, not to this extend?
-The feet are warm in bed?
-Yes.
-Burning, so she has to stick them out of covers?
-No.
-The skin eruption is not at all there?
-She is happy, she is quite happy with her life?
-Yes, for the time being.
-So you drive again?
-Yes.
-So you are a very healthy child.
-For the time being yes.
-OK, we'll talk in the class and we decide what to do with you further.
When we started the first day, we talked about this progress in the disease patterns
changing to different levels and if you remember we said,
in case we have here a physical element together with mental or emotional problems,
when you give the remedy here, then it's going to have a big reaction on the physical level.
Of course the moment that you see the mental-emotional and this is the problem
with all these cases, where together with the physical symptoms you see
mental-emotional symptomatology.
And you try to cure, then first you are going to have a severe physical reaction
on the physical body.
Where it belongs this case here in the scale?
It belongs somewhere here, you see?
Lower three. You need several remedies before you bring about a cure
and the cure is also doubtful in these levels. The final cure is doubtful.
Now with her case, the reactions have been too dramatic.
You just hear it but when you live every day with the fever, with 20 stool,
with blood and... then it's a different story.
And Sabine was on the telephone every day. Every day 8 o'clock
we had an appointment except of that weekend when the 15 mg were given.
This I considered it a very unfortunate thing to happen because I told you many times
we have to go back under stress.
Here what happened is while she was going down here she had this big reaction,
she is now going towards the next level.
In this phase she gets a big stress.
I mean you could here nothing here from the stress but the girl was destroyed
because she just had a new car and was damaged and she could not retain.
She was trembling, she was totally destroyed and immediately you see it starts with the point
where the weakness is.
And there is a mistake in potency.
Here I should have given Aconitum 50M or CM straight away.
You need a great fright where you decide this is a Stramonium possibility...
It could have been Stramonium actually.
I don't know if I gave the correct remedy here with Aconite.
I'm not sure it's the correct but anyhow I should have given higher.
1M is not enough to counteract.
Also you see the reaction in the skin. But you need the reaction in the skin permanently.
You need to have the skin permanently in a bad condition. Then you are more happy.
Because here what happens is the organism tries and then gives up and then
the skin eruption is back and then he tries and the skin eruption is back.
Now I believe that if in that stress period, if she had contacted me
and I had agreed to give cortisone, I would never had agreed to give more than 10 mg.
There is no question that the treatment so far has helped her a lot so far in spite
of the cortisone. And always it happens like this.
When you have to enter during this time with chemical drugs in general
and especially with cortisone, find out that much less cortisone than in the beginning.
Here she was given 12.5 mg when she came, 10 by mouth and 2.5 by enema.
Now if she receives 12.5 here, at the most she can get here during the crisis 10
and within 15 days it could go to 5.
Now she is for one and a half month taking cortisone and we have to bring it down of course
much faster to see what happens.
So at this moment you see how difficult it is to see the remedy.
It's very difficult because the child feels good.
She feels good but the cortisone is covering up certain of the symptomatology.
If we had a clear picture at this moment, we could stop the cortisone
and give again the remedy. Do we have? No. Let's see what says here the analysis.
Impulse to run? Who said that?
-The bungee jumping, shall I take it out?
-Yes, take it out.
Trembling of hands, fear of spiders, fear of the dark, aversion fat, desires vegetables,
fruits, brittle nails, public appearing timidity. No more?
Show me the Expert System. Medorrhinum, Carcinosin, Carbo vegetabilis, Gelsemium.
There is a possibility for both of these remedies but still we don't have
enough symptomatology and even if we had some indications towards...
more indications still I would be careful at this moment not to give a remedy
because she is under the cortisone and the moment that she stops the cortisone,
the picture may totally change.
So therefore the strategy which we have to follow in this case is to reduce slowly
the cortisone, very slowly.
That means in a month to reduce it to 2 mg and in the meantime see
whether she will develop a picture.
-One question.
As far as I understood she is still also taking Mercurius corrosivus on a daily basis.
What about that?
-Yes, she still is.
I will stop the Mercurius as well. I will stop the Mercurius together
with the stopping of cortisone.
Diminishing of cortisone, she can continue taking the Mercurius until this cortisone is out.
Once the cortisone is out, I will stop the Mercurius as well.
-Sorry for interfering but I'm really wondering why?
Why are you going to stop it at the same time?
Because then how do you know if she could stay due to the cortisone or due to the Mercury?
-Yes, so I will find out if I stop both but I don't want to stop the Mercury now
and leave only the cortisone and then from the cortisone... We would like to cure her.
If we stop both and she is cured, we say thank god it's OK. The idea is not playing tricks.
The idea is to find out exactly the truth. what is happening.
So what is the best way to find what I happening in that organism at this moment?
At this moment she looks so well but she is under the influence of cortisone.
So therefore we have to stop the cortisone. Why stop the cortisone
and then either we stop the Mercury immediately now and we stop the cortisone later
but I would like to have the influence of Mercury because I don't know how much is
because of cortisone and how much is because of Mercury.
So I will continue even the Mercury for a few days after stopping the cortisone,
I will continue, so I'll have the influence of the Mercury going on.
The idea of repeating cases of cortisone, repeating every day and perhaps twice
of three times the day, the possibility is that cortisone nullifies the treatment.
Therefore you have to repeat again, cortisone nullifies, again to repeat,
so you have a good condition.
-It is my impression that maybe she is already producing a bit of symptomatology
due to the Mercury with these ideas that she wants to go bungee jumping now
and parachuting getting these kicks from dangerous things. Is it possible?
-No. First of all I have not seen this in Mercury, producing ...
It is a tendency of Causticum.
Causticum children they go dangerous things, we have said that.
Causticum children they may climb in this window and look like this... They don't care.
Causticum children but not Mercury, I'm not sure. I don't see any symptoms of Mercury.
I wish she would have said, I 'm salivating, I wish I'd have seen some peculiar symptoms
of Mercury which shows that Mercury is still needed and still acting. I did not see.
I did not want to push her to say symptoms.
-I'd like to add something. Since she developed the colitis first,
she always had the relapses when she was down to 12 mg of cortisone.
Now in the meantime she is already down to 7.5 mg.
-There is no question that she is much better.
-If you want to see which result has the cortisone or where the Mercury is working,
why you do not continue to keep run the Mercury for a longer period of time
rather than ending at the same time or continue a few days and see in that result?
-If she feels good during the time that she finishes with cortisone and she continues
for a few days, as we said she can continue with Mercury for a few days
and she still feels good then we stop and we find out whether this case needs Medorrhinum
or Carcinosin or Causticum again or whatever, Sepia, I don't know.
-And the other question I had.
Once you have the mental-emotional at their high pathology and the physical symptoms come back
with a stronger symptomatology, at that point where there is this physical crisis,
are you saying is it preferable to use minimal allopathic medication
than homeopathic medication?
-Not at this case. This case she presented a very dramatic physical picture with fever,
with lot of losing blood, the anemia was very strong, she was freezing etc.
You have some pictures, then you have to prescribe.
Here you can't say let's wait and see what
happens, no. Sabine said I felt she was going out.
So you have to prescribe and if your prescription does nothing, then I said
you resort to allopathic drugs.
But not as a rule. Because I feel it was unfortunate she had this accident.
It was very unfortunate by the time.
It's like karmic. It's like something happens in the fate of the person.
The moment she is getting better, here comes another and says I will not let you be well.
-In her case it was karmic. The question I have is that you give whatever is required
from homeopathic remedies in that situation to get through the crisis?
-Yes to get her through as long as you see that there is some kind of action
but if you give here 10 remedies and no remedy is acting, what are you going to do?
-Is it possible at all in the situation where 1.5 becomes 1.4 and the shock develops
and everything, to find the correct remedy?
-Under the shock? If the shock helps you to find the remedy? What is the question?
-Presuming we do find the correct remedy, can we then always stop this relapse from happening
or is the situation too unstable?
-Here you don't call it a relapse. A relapse after the accident?
It depends on the severity of the relapse.
During this time where there is a stress, you may give a dose of Aconitum high
or you give a dose of Stramonium and things are controlled but you may need 2-3 remedies
before you can control this aggravation. It's not a relapse really, it's an aggravation.
You see the moment she is starting the physical body taking most of the impact,
you see the skin eruption is affected and the mucus membranes
but in such a way as to endanger life, therefore you don't wait and see or things like that.
Wait and see what?
You see she is going away... As long as you have the possibility to wait, you do wait.
-Before the accident happened you gave her Sulphur 200 and after that she had a good sleep,
she even slept in the afternoon and then...
-She developed a skin eruption, strong skin eruption and the stool went almost normal
or not exactly normal but much better.
-Yes and then she had the car accident and it changed all.
And you take it, you gave Aconite...
-Why I gave Aconite? Why I preferred Aconite? Because I've given Sulphur.
Sulphur has acted, we know that Sulphur and Aconite are complementary.
So we have a big fright.
The first thing I would think, she was in a terrible state,
therefore Aconite complementing the action of Sulphur but, as I said, the potency was wrong,
it was too low.
For this case the potency should have been 50M.
That's why I gave Aconite but I did not have...
Maybe if I was examining the case I would find out it's not an Aconite case,
it's a case of Stramonium.
-And you take it again and again and you lose the thing of Sulphur but the thing is that
I have an experience with my cases and I see it now after 9 years
when something like this happens, an accident, a dentist,
I lose the right remedy and after half a year I see what I did wrong.
-Yes, that is true because during the stress the organism produces another picture
which is similar but not exact as before, it's similar.
-What I want to know is why not go back to Sulphur 200 after the Aconite?
Why Mercury, why not Sulphur since Sulphur was working so well?
-I do not give her.
It was the time when she could not find me and then she made some decision.
Colocynthis seems to have been indicated and she was right when she gave Colocynthis.
-She said that the Causticum was given but just before the Aconite...
-Yes because of the cramps of the calves. This is typical, if you open the Repertory
this is typical of Causticum. It is the first remedy which started the whole issue.
Then I thought that's a relapse, give Causticum.
-I want to correct one thing. Eva has always been taking an afternoon nap,
ever since the disease started.
-Why this case is difficult? Do you know why? Because she has this kind of ideas,
these fixed ideas where she has to turn back and check and check.
That makes the case difficult. Otherwise it would be much more easy.
Without the ideas it would be upper three level, just the ulcerative colitis, upper three.
What is also showing the severity of the case is the fact that she has the C reactive protein so high.
That indicates a systemic disease, collagen disease and that indicates that in the process
of curing the case, then we may see some rheumatoid arthritis developing in here.
Luna, Jesus Christ, take it out, I can't see it.
The one who puts this, it says lunatic. Take it out.
Well I put as a test in the Journal, I put a case of Pulsatilla and say, what is the remedy?
About 12 people they wrote back and they said this is a Luna. I said, Luna what is this?
But if everyone gives Luna to all his patients,
I'm sure three patients will have a very good reaction.
Because of the placebo effect, because of different other factors.