-This is my second follow up. Last time you had prescribed Ignatia in C12, taken once every day
and every 3 weeks potentized higher. I now reached Ignatia C19.
I would like first to tell you something about the time between May and now.
About 8 days after starting Ignatia C12, while I was driving in my car to my clinic
I had a sudden, very intense, almost unbearable pain behind my sternum, in my chest.
The pain almost took my breath and actually I wanted to stop the car but I continued
after all because it slowly got better.
-The pain was behind the sternum?
-Yes. This was the only time that this pain occurred in such an acute intensity.
-It was there before? He had experience this pain?
-I've always had this pain but never so strong. I stopped Ignatia C12 for 3 days then
and since no further attack happened, I continued after that.
In the beginning of June, I then developed growing pains in my left hip and within one
week they grew so bad that I was only able to walk for a distance for about 500 m. That was all.
-Where exactly were the pains?
-In my left hip and my left thigh.
I continued taking Ignatia in spite of that and since it was my opinion of my idea
that mainly it had to do with muscle pains, I additionally took vitamin B6.
-Did he had this pain before?
-I did have those before but usually they only turned up after walking a distance of maybe 10-15 km.
The second idea I had concerning these pains was that maybe
they had to do with not having nicotine for a long time.
I stopped smoking completely at the end of March and since then I haven't touched...
And I thought that maybe it has to do with the drawal of nicotine.
This pain continued in this intensity for 2-3 weeks, I also had a pain during the night
and I always had this feeling as if I would have to throw my legs away.
And I also had this feeling in the night. And I always was very restless.
My wife told me that at night I'm tossing and turning very much.
-What he means, as if I have to throw to do this, to jerk or to stretch?
He had to do it, so it was restlessness of legs.
-No it was not the restlessness, it was the pain. The pain made me to do this movement
and that ameliorated it a bit.
-Stretched, jerking, made the pain feel better.
After the pain was over, then this tendency to throw his feet was gone?
-Yes.
In July was a time where energetically I did not feel so well. It was summer, it was very
hot in Germany and there came a time where, as well on my mental sphere, as also
physically, I felt a great tiredness, a great fatigue.
During this time I had the feeling that this pain behind my sternum wanted to move upwards
and get out. It didn't, it's still there, I can still feel it but I always still have the
sensation as if actually would like to rise up and come out.
-The pain?
- Yes.
-It's a similar pain with the one that was very severe, just less severe?
-This very intense pain was more a cutting pain, was a bit lower and was extending to
the abdomen, whereas this chronic pain is always here in this area and feels like a feast
which is inside there.
Now I would like to says something about my emotional development in these 3 1/2  months.
Overall I would like to say that I have the impression that I'm slowly getting rid of this
wall of armor, of being engaged in this armor.
I'm now able to express my emotional thoughts. I can not only put them into words but
they really almost press outwards, especially in discussions with my wife.
-With emotions?
-One I can put them into words and secondly I am able to express them.
I can bring them out, I can talk about them. The main symptoms I had mentioned was
vulnerability and this vulnerability has become much less.
Another thing that happened is, I used to have a very conflict loaded relationship with
the two children of my second wife before and within the last two months this has been
really resolved. Even though we have different opinions, we can talk openly with each
other and that has become much more at ease.
And what especially I have noticed and also my surroundings it that, maybe for the first
time in my life, I'm radiating a short of optimism and I also can notice this in my clinic that now
I'm able to lead and guide and accompany my patients on a way that can lead to real cure.
The other symptoms I had come to you for, were on the one hand side this empty
feeling in the stomach, the inner weakness and this feeling of an inner enemy.
And so I would like to add on some things about my symptoms and also about my mental sphere.
Maybe it's best if I start with a night. Once I asked my wife whether she had ever noticed
anything about my feet at night when she has to get up, whether they are covered or not
and she told me that the feet most of the times are uncovered.
What does that cause me some discomfort is that at nights I have certain attacks of
perspiration and I help myself by taking the covers of my bed and turning them around.
So the cooler outside then covers my body. I'm very warm at bed and actually you could
call me the constant heating of my wife.
-The heat who generates is rather recent?
-Actually I always had that but it got even more now. I wake regularly between 4,30 and 5
o'clock in the morning and then when I wake up always something very strange happens.
I have the sensation or this feeling as if they were two energies within me who are quarreling.
And in a way it's like my positive thoughts are always immediately being swallowed by a
kind of lazy dog like lying around there, too.
And he, then, immediately spits out negative thoughts.
I thought a lot of what it could be inside me, what I call my inner enemy, what it is ?
Because that has been really something that accompanies me all my life and has really
been using so much of my positive energies.
I think now I can feel it better or maybe I can express it in a better way.
I would express it the following way: It's a conflict, a quarrel between my positive inner
energy, which would be represented by the fire, and the negative energies, which are
a kind of sluggishness, meaning water.
This is a situation which lasts for about 45 minutes in the morning.
Then I get up, out of bed, I'm mostly quite warm then and I have to wash with cold
water immediately.
But after washing, if I don't immediately dry my skin with the towel, if I remain wet,
I develop such an unbearable itching of my skin that I find myself jumping and dancing
around the room because every scratching would only even more aggravated.
And the second thing that happens and this has also accompanied me most of my life
is that I get up with the urge for stool.
This occurs around 5,30-6 o'clock and that's actually the first thing I do, after I get out of
bed, I go to the toilet and the stool passing goes quick, it's thoroughly and it's taken care
within 2 minutes, it's finished.
-No diarrhea?
-No, it's a soft stool. Afterwards, since I'm still full of this inner feeling of the quarreling of
the two energies within me, I brew myself a hot thin tea, I drink that and this ameliorates
my inner feeling.
And my impression is that the almost extincted inner fire of the positive energies,
which were extinguished from the watery side, for me it is like this hot tea rejuvenates my
inner fire again and brings back the positive.
What I've always had is an increasing of this empty feeling in the stomach between
10,30-11,30 in the morning.
And I used to knock this empty feeling down with cigarettes and now I always eat fruit.
What actually has remained unchanged is that always in the evenings around 8 or 9 p.m.
I start feeling very tired and I would like to work but mental work is causing a great
exertion for me at those times.
Then I wanted to add something that I noticed about my physical symptoms, while I'm
here on the island. In May I enjoyed being in the water, I liked to swim, the water was
cold then and I swimmed almost every day.
Now this time the water is warm and I realize that I hardly swim at all, I hardly go into the water.
Now I would just like to say a few short sentences about my personality.
Basically I'm a very simple person who can't really do much with the refined way of
higher society. Just to give an example.
I had two car accidents once, they were only minor accidents, the only 2 I had within
45 years of driving and for me the situations always were quite clear.
I saw, I knew that it was my fault and I always admitted it. I admitted my guilt immediately
and always engaged in regulations, right away and I never went to get a lawyer or
any of these kind of things they do in our days.
Meaning first don't admit anything and start engaging in some legal activity.
And I'm a person who likes to live along with the rhythm of nature.
For example I live in a house which is solely heated with wood stoves and I get up
every morning to heat all the stoves and get things going and I also prefer to only eat
that kind of food that is seasonal, what's growing at that certain time.
It's not compulsive in any way, it's just what I feel is the right thing.
Then I have a very special relationship with money.
There is nothing worse for me than if I have to write my bills.
With every patient I wonder whether the amount on the bill really resembles the
quality of my treatment.
-When he has to write a bill for the patient, not to pay.
-Yes, when I write the bills to my patients. And I only remembered now that a long time
ago, people characterized me as a typical absent-minded professor.
I have a deep desire for knowledge and I actually want to know everything down to the
very bottom, to the center.
And I also like to do handicrafts and my favorite material to work with is wood.
Just a small side step into the elements of the Chinese acupuncture.
My greatest problem is dealing with people is not so much timidity, it's more embarrassment.
And this embarrassment actually is the thing which always paralyses me.
And I would like to say something concerning my fears.
I have fear for others, as well as for the members of my family, as also for my patients.
And this fear develops in the case of my wife, for example, if she doesn't come home
at the time that she actually would. And then this terrible negative inner energy starts
posing images where I see terrible accidents and I expect the police to appear at the
house and all kinds of things like that and of course I can't go to sleep then.
And the same with my patients.
Even though I have good inner energy, I always develop these images of complications
and since I've gained a lot of experience in Medicine, especially with complications
these are the images that come and haunt me, especially in complicated cases.
For an example, in an acute case if I gave a remedy and I ask a patient to call me
again that night at 10 p.m. and he doesn't call, you can be sure that at 10.05 I'm going
to be calling him.
-I want to ask a question. He had an aggravation while standing.
There was an aggravation reported back in the original. Is it still there?
-I still have this symptom. I still have this symptom but due to the fact that I feel I have
straighten up myself and also through being straight physically, the pain is not so
severe anymore, I don't feel it that strong but up to today for more than 10-20 minutes
still is impossible for me.
-Something else I wanted to ask is how is his desire for sweets, he did not report
any desire for sweets but this has changed? Now he's eating more sweets?
-I do have quite some desire for sweets, especially in the evenings but I try to suppress it.
-He had reported vertigo from high places. Did he find himself in a situation where he could test that?
-Yes, I still have it. I was on a roof for a couple of times and I still have it.
-Is anything else he wants to report?
-I would like to say something general about the generation of my parents.
I have a very great anger on the generation of my parents because they were not
able to deal with the fact of this great injustice, attacking innocent people.
I especially noticed that when these issues came up now with the gold that the Nazists
took from the Jews and put it to Switzerland and other places and also with this kind
of slave workers they had in Germany, large companies during the war.
That they were not capable of admitting this great injustice and it is now the sons and
daughters who try to equalize out this great guilt.
When I now meet somebody of this generation, I go up and say into his face, that's
something I could have never imagine doing before but I think it's really necessary
to go and to speak into his face because I think we can only maybe liberate
ourselves and our children, if also these people finally develop a quality, where they
can admit the things they have done and not just put the blame in some imaginary State,
meaning political system.
-But I think that they have, at least the official German government has admitted that
and has paid already - as far as I know - quite a lot of money to Jewish people and to Israel.
They still pay, I think, billions. But maybe on individual cases you still find some people
who feel they did the right things.
-Of course the political side gave this admittance and they needed it also for political
tactic but I just know they are so many people who still can not accept innerly the fact
that they have become guilty morally.
And they still don't want to admit what happened.
-These are difficult things to admit.
OK, thank you.
-This, as you everybody maybe is able to see, this is beautiful confirmation of the Theory.
When we say, you have to give the first remedy, then the next remedy will appear and
will become quite clear and then you can give it.
But how all the case opens up and develops, this is very interesting to perceive because
certain things, if you remember, from the previous repertorisation we did, maybe we can
put it back and you will see it.
We saw already, from the previous time, that this remedy was coming up and we still insisted.
Just push a little bit more. And you see you push the organism towards the right direction
and the remedy becomes clearer and clearer, until it comes now and you have a full clear case of?
-Sulphur
-Very good, that is the idea. And in spite of the fact, if you observe he still has the sighing.
From the previous time already we said, Sulphur most probably is going to be the next remedy but
still I did not prescribe it at the moment, because I still felt it was not clear enough. You see now?
You see Sulphur was coming already from the previous. That is when you have Sulphur
symptoms intermingled with Ignatia symptoms and I say yes, you prescribe on the upper
remedy and then the next one will push up.
Now show me the repertorisation you did now this time.
Some beautiful little changes which they push.
The time of emptiness 10,30-11,30. It is unbelievable.
This actually was a very good lecture on Sulphur which no teacher can do better.
Put the symptoms.
That means pain in extremities... you put all the symptoms.
This Expert System does absolutely.
Waking, stool on waking, everything now comes to Sulphur.
So what is the potency we shall give in this case?
CM, let me see CM? Nobody.
50M? 21.
10M? 35.
1M? 19.
200? 9.
30? 1.
12? Nobody.
In this case you are going to give a deeper remedy, quite deep, you are going to have
therefore some aggravation and it's going to make an X-ray of every system,
every organ, are you all right? Everything OK? Boom...
Because now it's deeper and of course you don't have reasons to doubt the organs
the organs are quite in a good condition, still you have to be careful. So the most wise remedy is 200.
To prescribe 200 is good enough to make an initial test, how this organism is reacting.
Also this time you don't repeat. You just give 1 time. Because it's clear, it's going to act.
If it does not act at all, that means the remedy is spoiled. Get another pharmacy.
Something else that I would like to point out from the experience you had so far with remedies.
You see that the remedies that you need to cure are enough. I'm concerning with new
provings, new provings and all these remedies that were given is new provings, new
remedies are not really necessary.
The remedies that we know already, most of these cases are covered.
Perhaps 2 cases we had that goes away from the main remedies.
Perhaps Acetanilidum, OK you say this is a seldom remedy.
But most of your cases should be treated and should be successful with what you know
originally.
Why this need for more remedies? Study the basic thing of the basic remedies.
And you will be a fantastic prescriber.
To go and read and more and more and something new, which is unreliable on top of it,
is wasting of time, wasting of energy and also misinformation which his blocking your eye sight.
Because if you put a lot how can you find out the few things that you want to rely upon.
Unless you base your knowledge on basics. What we try to do actually here.
Just learn the basic knowledge!
-George, I think most of us are waiting in vain for a lesson on potencies because you
have told us 50M or 10M if it is very clear. Now it's the opposite.
-But if you remember I said, when there is a child whom you have. He is not a child.
So if you give a very high potency, give a very big reaction. So you have to judge.
If he was 20 years old, I would give CM. What I said is absolutely correct, that means
the remedy which is clear, is going to check every organ and put back into order.
Every organ on the system work fully, then the system, the emotions, the mental
everything, the physical body... To do this when you are not 25, he is 2 times 25.
-More.
-Yes he is 60. Bring a man of 60 to the state of 26 is a big thing, you have to be a little bit careful.
You can give 50M, yes sure but the aggravation is going to be very strong.
Maybe he will start having palpitations for 20 days.
-Concerning the potencies I have a question. There is homeopaths that say if a potency
is absolutely right, there will be no aggravation at all. Do you have any thoughts to that?
-Yes sure, I have said my thoughts. This is nonsense. You can have aggravation with 12
with 30, with 200, with anything.
-Is it depending on the previous diseases? The diseases the patient has had and we
know them out of his history?
-Yes absolutely. Still you can not know the exact condition of the system, of the organs
of the body, even if all the laboratory examinations that we have available at this moment
don't show the real condition of the organs.
They are so grossly. But I'll tell you my opinion is that the breaking down of an organ in
the body is going like this. At this stage, which is X state, from that state onward
laboratory examinations become positive.
You have laboratory findings for the liver but the liver one day before, if you had examine it,
let us say you examine the day where it changes. It's one day before.
That is why you give the remedy here and 2-3 days later you see the laboratory findings
are gone.
But in the meantime how do you know in which condition it is? Is that condition which is
very good or it is that condition which is very close to break down the organ, the heart
the liver, the kidneys.
-I meant more the development of the patient. The miasmatic development.
-I don't understand the question. You're talking about this specific patient or in general?
-In general.
-Yes, you can say that he is not complicated in miasmatic conditions.
But he has been suffering for many years with all this 'jacket' and the 'enemies' he calls
that he has been battling and not being able to enjoy.
In spite of the fact, his miasmatic condition is not very heavy.
If it was heavier you would not see such a clear picture. You would see Sulphur but not so clear
and then another remedy would be showing already.
-I think you gave him Ignatia 10M.
-50M.
-Was that because it was mainly a mental disease, that you went so high?
-Yes, it was because I knew that was not the remedy, which is deeper.
It was the uppermost layer and the grief was very deep and I had to give a high
potency to get it out, the grief.
But the grief was a layer which was imprinted upon this organism.
He didn't come to life with this miasm, the Ignatia constitution, let's say.
The Ignatia was imprinted because of circumstances of his life.
It's needed as a first remedy. You may give him Sulphur, as much Sulphur as you like
before Ignatia, nothing. Now it's going to act.
-You have to give some remedies essentially high, like you always have to give Ignatia
in a 50M or in 10M or Nat. mur.?
-No. If he was a very typical Ignatia case with his constitutional Ignatia, I would have given lower.
But I could see behind there was another layer coming.
So I had to deal with this issue of grief that was upon his life and put him in a state
where he could not breathe anymore.
-I have a question. If I have a woman that has a dilatation of the left ventricle, she has arthritis,
the family history have a number of colon carcinoma and she has a lot of polyps
in the colon got a Nitric acid in a C30 which did very well and then a C200, can I go
further up to 1M?
-If she has done already very good in 30 and 200 and she has relapsed now, she can go
to 1M, yes.
Like in his case from 200 if we see the relapse comes after. If he feels good for a period
of years and an aggravation he feels good for 5-6 months, comes back, then we go to 1M
we go to 10M, we go to CM, no problem, as long as we go slowly as we go up.
We don't go straight away. You may give a high potency, there is no question but in 60...