The case I'm going to show to you is a classic case of the last strategy
where you have to take the essentials of a case.
Where we don't have mental-emotional symptoms and we have only gross pathology
and then we have to find which is the remedy
which combines the gross pathology of that case.
I believe that almost nobody has seen the case, maybe a few have seen it.
The case is here to give a follow up and after we have analyzed the case,
you are going to see the follow up.
-The report here says that this patient has a neprhotic syndrome
called by minimal change glomerulonephritis.
He also has an autonomous nephropathy with tendency to orthostatic hypotension.
He has been using steroids as well as cyclosporine and in periods cyclophamide.
He is now in remission and he has no symptom and uses no medication.
His latest blood test are included in separate copy and this was done on April 96.
There is some more information.
I was bleeding from the rectum and colon. It was quite steady.
It started about 10 years ago.
I came from the States after a Tour and when I came home it started with hemorrhagic colitis.
I was hospitalized, I thought I had some kind of virus, I didn't know what happened.
The bleeding was stopped and it changed to the kidney filter.
They found out that I got this loss of albumin very heavy, just the albumin.
All the other things were in tact.
At that time when I go home it started also the pupillary dysthony,
I was reacting very much to light. One pupil was much bigger than the other one.
Then I started to get edema, swelling, my albumin went down and I gained very much weight.
In 10 days about 30 kilos. I didn't get my urine out.
I tried several things to stop it and finally they had to give me sent poison.
A special poison they use for cancer patients. It's called sentoxan.
They may use it for cancer cases and they had to use heavy dose to stop it.
When they stopped it, I lost 32 kilos in 16 days.
The last weekend from Friday to Monday I lost 16 kilos just in water.
-Which had been retained from the body?
-Yes. I just got out the urine in buckets.
Of course at the time before I went to the States, I was pretty warn out,
I had a chiropractor myself, I had a private clinic in Oslo, a big practice.
I had several people working for me and my immune system was low at the time
I was in the States.
-Why? What happened in the States?
-I'm playing in a music band in Norway and we had a Tour there
and of course I was eating in some of these coffee shops and restaurants.
I thought maybe I got something in a fruit and because I didn't have any symptoms at all before.
-Did you take any antibiotics before because you had some kind of flu or bronchitis
or anything like  and you took some antibiotics before the colon started bleeding?
-No.
-Did you have any urinary infection?
-The only thing I can remember is that I was urinating a little more frequent than I usually do.
That's the only thing I can remember.
I checked my prostate but I did not find anything. My prostate was OK.
-But you did not take any antibiotics because of this frequent urination?
-No, I didn't do that. I'm a chiropractor myself and I'm against to the antibiotics
and my way of treating that thing, I would try to stimulate the nerve impulse to urine bladder.
I know when I studied in the States, I was interning with doctor [name]
who was supposed to be the best in my profession and he treated me once for that,
correcting the third lumbar in the spine and that took care of my frequent urination
at that time because I've had that before.
-So first you had frequent urination, then you went to America,
then you had ulcerative colitis that started with bleeding.
-I came home to Norway and I had diarrhea and I could see a little bit on my stool.
-So you had diarrhea not in the United States but on the airplane.
-Just when I went home it started.
-The first day?
-Yes it started a little bit in the plane but then it continued.
-And they you had what treatment for this?
-I was checked in a hospital and I took colonoscopy and they found out
that I had hemorrhagic colitis and then they thought that I might have
what they call Cronh' s syndrome or ulcerative colitis but they were not sure about it.
It was a slight bleeding.
That particular time too I was very sensitive for the fruits I was eating.
-I'm interested about the medication that you took at that time.
-First of all they didn't want to give me any medication, they were trying to observe me
in the hospital and then they tried to give me some cortisone.
-Cortisone enemas?
-Yes but still the heavy albumin loss started very slight and then it was like an explosion.
They had to increase the dose on the cortisone with not very much effect.
Finally they had to go to this sentoxan poison, they used it intravenously.
That stopped the albumin.
-Without side effects?
-The side effects I got from cortisone because I had to use very high dose
and it affected my mental stage, it is a stress hormone.
-How it affected?
-I felt a little aggressive, I felt that I had very much energy
that I could solve many problems at the same time. That's the main thing.
I was against and I have always been against any kind of medication
because of my background but I said that if I was going to take any medication,
I was going to take it for a short period and then to take the fire and then get it away
and they agreed to that.
What happened then, they stopped the albumin, I took a biopsy of the left kidney.
In fact they asked me which kidney they should take a biopsy
and one week before I went to a homeopath in Sweden.
He was looking in my eyes and he said there is something wrong with your left kidney.
So when they asked me in the hospital, I said left.
I asked the surgeon what he found in the biopsy and he said
that it was a very slight inflammation, not really much notable.
-When this biopsy was?
-About a month or three months after, this was 10 years ago.
I was against for the biopsy too because I know so many cases, I was afraid of bleeding,
there is a lot of side effects. So I had to be sure to get the best surgeon to do it.
So he did it and the conclusion was that I got nephrotic syndrome.
They thought maybe it could be some vegetable disturbance,
something wrong with the autonomous nervous system and that was interesting thing.
They sent me to one specialist, they tested the sympathetic and the parasympathetic
with all kinds of stimuli and what they found out was very special.
On the graph it was just one line. It was any kind of stimulation.
It didn't show anything and that was very special.
-How did they explain this?
-They couldn't explain it.
They thought it is very strange, the one who did the examination
never saw something like that before.
So they thought it was with any kind of stimulation it was not through the cord
but directly to the brain, but they couldn't explain it.
-Did you feel the pinch?
-Yes I feel the pinch.
-Immediately after they put the needle, you feel the pinch?
-In fact I'm very pain sensitive and of course all the blood tests I did
and different kinds of stimulations and both were no reaction at all.
Of course after that I noticed a lot of things, we did some tests,
my hemoglobin starts to go down.
I just want to make some remarks at that point. I hope you follow the case.
I want to make a remark concerning a no reaction from the neurovegetative system.
You remember I put a question immediately to him, when they pinch do you feel the pain?
Why did I say that? Because I was thinking of Opium, Cocculus and remedies
which do not give out pain, do not give out signals.
We have to have a remedy that really has this insensitivity or a lower activity.
He says no I'm sensitive to pain, so I get exactly the opposite answer than what I expect.
My mind says now most probably you are on the wrong direction.
Let's continue, find out what happens.
So far the description is for me to understand this, why the kidneys have broken down?
There is a lot of albumin, there is a nephritic syndrome, developing out of the blue.
How is that? He relates this ulcerative colitis and then the cortisone.
Is it possible that the cortisone itself has broken down the kidneys? Maybe.
What I'm driving at is the idea of having antibiotics which we know many times affect
the kidneys, break down the kidneys and the idea of having a urinary infection like urithritis,
gonorrhea, non-specific urithritis, taking antibiotics and then the kidneys are breaking down.
I'm trying to find out whether this is case of a deeper infection from the genitourinary system,
the infection goes into the kidneys and then we have this result.
It seems in his case it is not. It is rather genetic weakness of the kidneys,
which are breaking down under the pressure from cortisone.
-The percentages have been very high but now it starts to get down
and I go this orthostatic blood pressure.
In fact the orthostatic went very low, down to 60 over 40 and sometimes I had problem,
I was fainting.
-Fainting when arising from bed or from seat?
-Both the bed and seat. It felt like I'm losing the blood in my stomach
and I started to get used to it. But now at this time my blood pressure is about 80 over 50.
That's when I'm sitting. When I'm standing up and you take the blood pressure the other way,
it goes down, so it could be down to 60 over 40.
-Even now?
-Yes.
It's a very big change from sitting to standing and from standing to sitting.
Another thing I would say is that the last years I have had that problem
that I had to use my abdominal muscles to empty my urinary bladder.
I can urinate but I usually sit when I urinate because if...
-Urination is better by sitting?
-Yes because if I'm going to empty it all, I had to sit.
-Do you have to lean back also?
-Yes I really have to contract my abdominal muscles to empty, I can urinate
but to empty it I have to really press.
This is a symptom you look in your Repertory. Did you find it? Urination better sitting?
-Bladder urination retarded, must wait for urine to start, sitting only partial urine can.
-What is the remedy?
-Causticum and Zincum.
-So you search a peculiar symptom like that, you see only two remedies.
-There is another rubric, bladder urination dripling, sitting ameliorates.
-What is the remedy?
-Only Causticum.
-Another rubric. It is called urination retarded, must press with his abdominal muscles.
-What is the remedy?
-Magnesium phosphorica.
-Another rubric. Urination retarded, must sit to press, then only a few drops come out.
Abies nigra.
-Retarded due to spasm of the sphincter.
-What is this last symptom? Read the symptom.
-Urination retarded on account of spasm of the sphincter.
-Urination, can only urinate when sitting was Zincum and urination go backwards also Zincum,
if I understood correctly.
In the same raw we also have the rubric urination, can only urinate when sitting bend forward.
Sulphur is also containing this remedy.
-So this is the search you have to do in case you hear a peculiar symptom.
Peculiar symptom is why? Because we have only a few remedies producing such symptom.
So this is what we call a keynote. So far what we have is some pathology and one keynote.
And these are the remedies we may be thinking, Causticum, Zincum...
-To the stress because I have been very hard many many years and I had a really high load.
Of course now I'm fortunate to take just special cases myself,
I have other people working for me and I can concentrate on special cases
and take the time, I don't have any stressful situation with that.
I went through a divorce, that was about 15 years ago.
I was married about 15 years ago and I divorced.
But it went out OK, we are very good friends all the time.
It's no problem in connection with that.
-How old are you now?
-I'm 49 today, it's my birthday.
So I thought it will change my new life. Of course I don't know if you want me
to continue to explain or if you want me to ask questions
but I've been through a lot of different kinds of treatments.
I take Acupuncture, one of the best acupuncturists in China. He is working in my clinic,
a couple of times the year.
His name is Dr Sein He is writing a lot of books for Acupuncture
and he has been treating me with no effect.
He also took some herbs from China which didn't have any effect
and I had several other other kinds...
I don't have the names of all different types I had but it hasn't been an effect.
Lately I also went to a German who made a special ceremony for my own blood.
He is located in [place name]  in Germany and I was supposed to take these drops he made
and also intravenous, I should take it for about a year, I have taken it for 8 months
but no effect. Still this causes pretty frequent albumin.
The thing which had some effect on albumin to keep it stable was a special herb
from up the mountains, it is called cyclosporine, it's a special herb poison.
I don't know if you are familiar with it.
It is a special herb which come from North in the mountains in Norway
and they found out that that had effect to keep it but as soon as they stop it,
it comes back again.
I stopped that because you see what I did. I started with this herb
and I had to take higher and higher doses of it and didn't have an effect anymore.
Now I don't take it, I'm the moment I'm protein free, no albumin and I'm free of medication.
At that time the problem is that I know from experience that I get a relapse after some time
if I don't do something and I have very good belief in you and Homeopathy is a solution,
if you are able to find...
-Have you taken already homeopathic remedies?
-It's a long time ago.
-What remedies?
-I don't remember what kind of remedies, the name of it. I tried several combinations.
-Who has the names? Nobody. You took combination remedies, mixtures?
-I tried both. I got that from a Swedish homeopath, mixtures and the other,
the direct without any mix, the clean ones.
I was just thinking if it's anything else I should tell you.
In the hospital they don't think the stress situation has anything to do with it.
Of course they don't have any idea of all that.
But later on if it is interesting for you I can find out what remedies and I can fax it to you.
-After the chemotherapy you took homeopathic remedies?
-I stopped the medication for the chemotherapy and I never did combine the two.
I always stopped the one thing and then tried the other.
-Yes, you tried Acupuncture, you tried herbs and you tried Homeopathy after.
The medicines that you took from Homeopathy after that, what were? Do you remember?
-The name of it?
-Yes.
-That's what I was trying to think.
-They were mixtures?
-Mixtures yes.
-And this mixture was especially for kidneys?
-Yes.
-How do you know that there was no effect?
-The only thing I can say is that I see that I was getting edema again,
I check my urine very regularly.
I have a stick which I test it and I see if it's any slight proteinuria.
I know when it starts a little bit with the proteinuria then it's very difficult to stop it.
It is just like an explosion.
-Are you careful with your diet?
-Yes I'm careful with my diet. I don't eat red meat at all. I try to eat more vegetarian,
fibers and eat a lot of water and I don't drink alcohol.
The only meat I eat is white meat, like turkey and chicken.
Of course I might be a little heavy in eating eggs.
I like to eat eggs in the morning to get that metabolism. I exercise much.
In the clinic I have a big Clinic Center, so every day as a routine
I go through an exercise program.
Then I try to compensate the catabolic effect with the exercise.
-Let me say a few things to the class now.
I left this gentleman to talk because of a severe condition, as you understand.
We have liked to know what is going on as far as pathology is concerned.
What is not clear for me is how the kidneys were affected.
In order to have such an effect on the kidneys, we have to have either
a hereditary predisposition or we have to have some previous disease,
which had a repercussion or an effect on the kidneys.
Such diseases are venereal diseases like gonorrhea, urithritis and things like that
or we investigate the possibility of his hereditary condition.
We would like to know how parents are alive, what they are suffering from,
especially the father, whether the father had kidney stones,
in order to understand how the kidneys were so easily affected.
Because it seems that there is a predisposition, a weakness on the kidneys
and why this weakness has been triggered. Can you tell us anything about this?
-Yes it's not kidney disease in the family. The only thing I can say is that my father
he starts to get a little rheumatism.
My grand mother had arthritis but now to my father, they haven't diagnosed it
but I noticed the last month that he is complaining of pain in the joints.
-Not exactly this. This does not explain your sensitivity of the kidneys.
Another thing which I would like to know is whether you took a lot of antibiotics
in your younger age?
-I know that I've used some penicillin in certain cases but now I'm very sensitive to that.
I react upon that.
-If they make a test on you, you have a reaction?
-Yes.
-Why you took penicillin?
-I took it one time for an inflammation of bronchitis but not pneumonia.
-What age?
-I've had it several times.
It seems that every time I get a cold, if I don't stop it,
it's easily  affects the respiratory tract.
I also sometimes when I was working very heavy, I felt some pressure in my chest.
-As if you can not breathe properly?
-Yes, it seems more like cardiological. I checked it but everything was OK.
They couldn't detect any problem there.
-How many times you took penicillin?
-During the last 20 years maybe I took 3-4 times.
-For how many days?
-Just for about a week.
But now I know that I'm very sensitive, so I don't take it anymore.
-But do you take other antibiotics now?
-No.
-You don't get anymore these colds?
-How many years since you did not have anymore this sensitivity to colds?
-It's about 5 years.
-Since when did you find out that you had the problem with the kidneys?
-That was when I came back from the States about 10 years ago.
I took all kinds of tests for the kidney and they found out that kidney function was good,
my creatinin was good, everything was good except from that albumin.
-They found out about the albumin in the urine how many years ago?
-About 10 years ago.
-Together with the colon, the hemorrhagic colitis?
-Yes.
-So this started practically together?
-Yes, the first sign was the colitis and then my diarrhea stopped and 1-2 months after,
the kidneys started. Also the other sign was very sensitivity to light.
-The pupils stayed dilated?
-One small, one big.
-Which is dilated?
-The left one was big and the right one was very very small and very sensitive to light.
-All day or in the morning when you wake up?
-Especially in the morning and when I come down to the southern areas
where the light is very sharp, I couldn't see anything, I had to use dark glasses.
-In the morning you had to keep one eye closed for how much, two minutes or half a minute?
-Probably half a minute, I really had to concentrate on opening.
-Let me still understand the pathology.
You had the last budge of penicillin how many years ago?
-Probably about 5 years ago.
-And since then you did not have anymore this sensitivity to the respiratory
or you did have?
-Yes.
-But not as severe.
-No, but always I notice that every time I get a cold and my bronchitis
and I have to cough all the time and that's the same with my family.
My mother when she gets a cold, she always have it down there.
-The sinuses are not affected?
-No, down there the chest. right away.
-Did you smoke before?
-I never smoked and I take a glass of wine with the food but I don't drink alcohol.
It is very seldom but I can do it. I mainly drink water.
You see a lot of investigation which is going on not only on homeopathic way
but try to understand the pathology and being able to predict what is going to happen,
to know when something is happening in the future during the treatment.
Unless you do this kind of investigation you will not be able at a certain moment...
You will be confused because what is going to happen here in this case is as you treat
and if your treatment is successful, that means the kidneys are getting better and better,
then this sensitivity which has gone, it will come back.
So he will develop a kind of bronchitis again and you have to treat that bronchitis
by that time correctly with Homeopathy to promote his health and to bring back health,
if that is possible.
And that's why I make all this investigation, so I can see how it started
and how its' going to end up.
A little bit of colitis, some bronchitis may appear eventually, more easily colds.
I can feel because the pathology is so gross, you may not get homeopathic symptoms.
The disease is concentrated on the physical body.
-The special diet and it is under Dr [name] he is a specialist on biological medicine.
I went through it for one week, drink just juices and vegetarian things
because I had very much belief in that.
I was supposed to come over to you some years ago but at that particular time
I had taken cortisone some period before and also I got much edema.
I could feel that I was breathing very heavy, so I didn't take the chance to come to the heat.
-My thoughts at this moment are that first of all here we have a case
which it appears to have some severe pathology but at the moment the organism is in balance.
There is balance.
The peculiarity of the things that he has spoken is the way that he has to press
in order to urinate and that peculiarity reminded me of Pareira brava.
Pareira needs to press really but it goes down to the knees actually to be able to urinate.
When it becomes difficult the urination, it has to go down and press the abdominal muscles.
You don't have to do that. Did you ever did that?
Did you try to see if the urination was better if you had just go down to your knees
and bend forward and then press whether the urination would be better?
-No. I just know that I can stand and urinate for some time
but just the last I really had to press and of course if I press my abdomen
because I have pressed so hard, I'm afraid to get my bowel movement too.
Another thing I forgot to tell you is that on the last test my iron deposit is very low
and I'm also very low on Magnesium.
Of course I had to take some iron supplements in hospital but I react on taking iron
because my stomach is reacting. But I also take vitamin C and I take mineral supplements
and vitamin C and E.
I feel very little energy because my hemoglobin is low, my blood pressure is low,
all the values are low and after that situation it has changed dramatically.
My hemoglobin was more than 100% before and I've always been very active in sports
but now I can walk but of course it is very difficult in walking steps,
especially when I've been sitting and I start to walk, I always have a chance to faint,
so I have to take it very slow.
-What is your temperature of the body? Is it usually low?
-I just notice that I'm very easily freezing. I have a property in Portugal.
I'm living in Oslo and I have a wife and a child in Portugal.
I'm usually travelling down there once the month.
-There you feel better?
-Of course in Portugal some parts of the year is very cold there too
because it is near the Atlantic ocean and it is very humid but even though is not so cold
like in Norway for me it feels very cold. I'm freezing down there.
As he describes his symptoms another remedy which comes to my mind
and I'm  investigating is Acetanilidum.
What I wanted to ask, if in your experience has anybody heard about that symptom
where he says he has photophobia of one eye in the morning?
Has anybody had a case with onesided photophobia in waking up in the morning?
Nobody.
I have seen it a few times. This is a symptom which shows some serious problems in the organism,
which they may not develop immediately but you will see that something is going on
which is serious.
I've seen it in cases of Lupus erythematosus.
-Usually in the morning close my left eye, which is the weaker eye,
when I go out into the sun, this is weaker that I used to wonder some time,
it is a muscle problem but I feel that there is too much light generally,
so I close one eye but always the left eye, so I get less amount of general light.
So in a way of photophobia of one side.
-But that is a strong photophobia, that is a very pronounced symptom.
-I found in the picture that in the middle of the face it was always very white,
the nose and this part.
About the kidneys I was thinking, what was the separation made to him
because he seemed very quiet and he said the separation but still we are friends.
But then I thought when the kidneys in the Chinese medicine has something to do
with my life and my energy and many years later on after the separation
I had lost so much energy.
So I thought the kidneys might be affected by the separation.
-I don't think he said after the separation he lost the energy.
He was here during that time, during the whole course and we were observing him.
He had to sleep about 90% of the time, he could not keep, his energy was very low,
he had to sleep during the class 90% of the time.
That is what he describes here, I have no energy when I go upstairs,
when I have to move the energy is very low, the blood pressure is very low
and the anemia is there.
That is why at this stage I have been thinking of the remedy Acetanilidum.
It says here, if you open the Materia Medica and you read, it says depresses the respiration,
the blood pressure, lowers temperature, depresses the heart, cyanosis and collapse,
increase susceptibility to cold, destroys red blood cells.
Heart weak, albuiminuria, edema of feet and ankles.
You see, you can be trying to find this remedy through a keynote, through projections,
he has some of this, that. All that ...
Here you have to concentrate, you have to find the remedy.
He says when they took my reactions it was zero, it was no reactions
and Acetanilidum is exactly that, it depresses all the vital functions of the human body.
The respiration goes low, the blood pressure goes low, the albumin is lost
and then we have a very weak individual with no kidneys.
The kidneys are broken down, the heart is affected, the respiration is affected,
the blood pressure is affected, he can not...
Once you get this idea all together and put it all together,
you say this is the idea of Acetanilidum.
Are you going to find it through the Repertory? No. You try to find it as much as you like,
you will never get the remedy.
Because he was sleeping very much in Opium there is a keynote, you will give Opium.
But he is sensitive to pain, he says I'm pain sensitive.
Opium is not sensitive to pain, it is actually the opposite. They don't feel the pain.
-Found in rubrics eyes photophobia, pupils contraction, unequal, contraction is difficult.
In orthodox Medicine is clear that the contraction helps to overcome the photophobia
and the remedy in this rubric is Nitric acid, one single remedy.
-Yes but there is Natrum arsenicosum also that has this.
What I say is that if you go and look for these little things...
First you don't have the totality. What is the totality? There are no symptoms.
You don't have the essence.
There is no essence in this case, there is no the essence of Nat. mur. or Sulphur.
There are no keynotes to guide you.
One keynote says Nitric acid, Nat. Arsenicum, Opium and then you go to
what we call the essentials. The essential of this is the depression of all his functions.
These are the essentials.
Which is the remedy that produces that?
I don't know if you got the idea. Still it's quite a lot of interview.
The idea is that every now and then the kidneys break down, starts the albumin
and if he does not take the chemotherapy, this will not stop.
So he has to take several drugs at the same time in order to stop the crisis
and then he waits for the next crisis.
Then the kidneys break down and there is a flood.
So he had to take the sentoxan.
The problem that we have at this moment is how we can control,
so you give the remedy maybe is better, the sentoxan comes, then the chemotherapy comes,
it breaks down, back again, forward.
You see it will affect your treatment if you don't have the possibility to correct the basic.
Because he will put on 30 kilos, he will just keep all the water inside, it is also dangerous.
The idea is you find the correct remedy that may correct the kidneys, only then there is hope.
This is what I say. In every case there is an impact, there is a center of gravity.
If you go along and you look upon little things around...
As Hahnemann said, get the essentials, don't look for details, they are not important.
Find the aphorism, on which aphorism he says that.
In this case there is an information about his essentials, about the remedy
which I read to you, anemia, albuminuria, depresses, low blood pressure,
low temperature, freezing.
If we try to find some mental-emotional symptoms, it will be very difficult
because once you see the disease is so much localized in the physical body,
forget the mental-emotional.
It is personality things you will be mixing.
-I'd like to ask if he has sweets and how many eggs he is eating the day?
-How many eggs?
-3-4 eggs per day.
-In what form?
-I boil them.
-Soft?
-No soft, hard-boiled.
-I would like to give two observations. One is he is licking his lips quite frequently
and what really astonished me, when I saw the man for the first time last year,
to me he seemed so strong and so powerful and that was the same in this interview then.
It's so astonishing that with such an outward appearance, inwardly you can have
such a broken down organism.
-If anybody had seen the case originally, if you remember his color
was not the same as it is today, much more pale.
And we will hear what happened after Acetanilidum and he has to give a follow up today.
So we see the changes, we see how we proceed with such a case.
Actually he has two Professors of urology who are looking after his case in Norway
and when he told them, he is going to Greece to be treated,
they said well anybody who will cure you, he must go for a Nobel Prize.
The interesting thing, they said it in June and I got the announcement in October
but he said one of these two Professors are one of those who can nominate a candidate.
Not everybody can nominate a candidate, they allow certain Professors to do that
and one of these two Professors is one of those who can nominate. I said OK, just remind him.
A little bit later. We will see.
This kind of statement from the medical profession so many times
they have been surprised and so many times they kept quite.
They never said a second thing.
-That Prize winner should give the whole information, which height did you give?
-I will say in the follow up, I will give you all the details what we did with the potency.
-But as I remember, you said not to take anything until he has the albuminuria
coming again, if I'm not forgetting.
When we did the case, you didn't give immediately the remedy.
You said, if you have a relapse, then take it and we will see.
-Yes, he started actually taking the remedy because the relapse
was coming every 15-20 days.
It's not a matter of waiting too long to have the relapse.
Most probably he started immediately in June already, last June.
So you have to correct the kidneys, the anemia here, the blood pressure...
How difficult it is for established Medicine to correct all that?
Give him Effortil to rise the blood pressure and the kidneys will collapse.
Give him iron and his digestive system will collapse.
You know the ferrum is not tolerated very easily by people who have colitis.
You can aggravate colitis very easily because they have ulcerative colitis,
they go into anemia, they say take now ferrum and then the organism goes into pieces.
The Time Magazine, as you know, has an article on this [name]
who espouses the idea of herbs. Go back to herbs, eat garlic, garlic will cure everything.
Now Time Magazine has a big article about him and about another one.
And they are very critical of course about what he is doing.
They ask some medical people also but it is very strange that if there is a serious
methodology which can deal with diseases, which is Homeopathy, nobody is interested.
Like he investigated marihuana. He says marihuana is a light drug, you can take it
but when I see the cases who have taken marihuana and I evaluate these cases,
I see how much damage marihuana has done on the brain of these people.
They become slow, they become very mild, they become very gullible,
there is no will power, the will power has gone down, the mental acute,
the mental potency has gone down, they can not think consequently,
they can not sustain a mental effort...
All these things and he says why you make such a big fuss about it?
Make it legal, destroy the planet.
On the one hand he says don't take antibiotics, take garlic and onion
and on the other hand he says take marihuana also.
You see the confusion which is in the mind of these people unfortunately.