I would like to show you now the possibility of regeneration that Homeopathy has,
which appears in a case some of you have experienced, have seen it in Celle.
The gangrene case in Celle.
I will show you the follow up after 10 years in a very short way.
Who saw this case, the gangrene case in Celle?
Only 6 people.
Anyhow instead of showing the whole case...
This is a case which shows the possibilities that Homeopathy has for regeneration.
Regeneration of the cells, regeneration of the tissues of the body.
I can give you a nutshell of the case.
I was teaching in Celle and the first day we started the teaching,
they were about 300 students.
One of the student, a woman doctor, stood up and said my mother
is in the hospital in Celle and they are preparing to cut both her legs,
amputate her legs from the thigh and would it be able to do something?
I asked her when they were planning the operation?
It was Friday, they said for Tuesday.
We had Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday, 4 days to show maybe
that Homeopathy could start having again some circulation in the arteries
and the veins.
It was a possibility to show in the doctors in the hospital
that something is happening, so they can decide to delay the operation
and then we have a little bit more time.
I remember this was a very electrified atmosphere in the class,
waiting to see the results of Homeopathy, if it can have a result.
The interesting thing was that the woman had diabetes and she arrived
at a state of gangrene because of the closing of the arteries
and the developing of the gangrene, due to long time diabetes.
But while she was in the hospital and they investigated her, they found out
that she was suffering with adenocarcinoma of the lungs as well.
So this was a great challenge for Homeopathy, could we do something till Monday?
First of all she was in the hospital and we could not film her in the very beginning.
We could only have some pictures of her legs.
I will show you the patient. The patient is 6 months after the initial treatment.
I will show you the follow up when she came.
She was showing some effect in the arteries, the doctors
and to their credit I must say, I didn't expect, they said yes
we see some effect and we agree to wait.
They waited until one more week.
One more week they observed her and after that week the patient
was sent to another clinic, not to a surgical ward, to stay there.
She stayed there for another week or 10 days and then she was discharged
from that hospital as well and she went back home.
And treatment continued for 2 years.
I will show you now the first follow up 6 months after the initial treatment.
-In December 88, with an inclusion of artery right and the right leg,
they did a vasectomy.
It was tried to dissolve the fungosis.
They also found when she was in hospital that she had an adenocarcinoma in her lung,
in her left lower (?) discussing and I was operated in February 89.
Then she did not have any problems for about 2 years.
In June 91 she had an (?) on her right foot.
She got antibiotics but there wasn't any major improvement.
Then they did and angiography and they found that there was an occlusion
in her right (?) artery.
In June 91 she got a by-pass operation, by-passing the (?) artery
going from the (?) with her leg artery.
After some days this by-pass again got closed.
Her situation got worse in spite of medical treatment,
so in July she got into hospital in Celle and since you were here,
you looked at her then.
That was the condition by that time.
The foot was taken as it was at the time.
For 5 days she got Anthracinum C30.
-That is on 9 of September.
-This is 13th of September.
14th of October.
28 of October.
16 of December.
They remember, most probably those who have seen the follow up,
the treatment was continued for 2 years, another year and a half.
And since then I lost the case, I did not know what happened.
Lately I wanted to present this case to a Symposium here in Thessaloniki,
where about 20 medical Professors of Medicine and Directors of hospitals were present.
I asked my secretary to find the woman doctor and find out what has happened
after the 2 years of follow up which I was following the case.
Here it is her letter which I would like to read to you.
-How did you continue the treatment? Did you keep on with Anthracinum?
-No I will tell you the remedies.
Anthracinum was only at a certain point when the pains were unbearable.
I will tell you the treatment in the end. The treatment is not only Anthracinum.
She found her and she sends this letter on the 12th of August 99, last month.
She says dear George your treatment of my mother was very successful.
She was in a good condition till she died at the October 98, 26 of October 98.
At this morning she probably had a stroke, she was very weak and tired
and didn't want to get up.
She fell into sleep again and when we called the doctor from the village,
he recognized that she was going to die.
He observed her last minutes without interference.
She died in a very tranquil way. It was like her way to live
and I'm filled with gratitude. Your treatment was unbelievable.
It was like a wonder to change her dangerous condition
and I want to thank you very much.
Further the information is interesting.
In 96 she fractured the column femoris, she got a TEP and recovered in a short time.
No complication of the circulation or any other parts of the body.
After a few days she was able to walk and this condition continued
till the end of her life.
I showed a few such cases to these Professors.
As they confessed in the end, everyone of them said,
we came prejudiced against Homeopathy.
We came because some students of ours, medical doctors,
especially those who were in the army, army doctors,
they invited us to come but we came prejudiced.
After seeing all that, I showed them a few cases, we have to admit
that Homeopathy is something which is quite serious
and they did the first step for Greece.
They signed all of them a Manifesto in favor of Homeopathy.
For the first time it went to the Press and it became a major turning point
for Homeopathy in Greece.
At least they sat down and observed what we had to show them.
The turn, the change in their mentality was really impressive
because they came to me, knowing I'm not a medical doctor,
within all the medical doctors, they had to admit that yes,
there is something which is quite serious.
And they said, all of them, we were prejudiced, we didn't want to even discuss
but when we see things like that we can not really keep on with the same attitude.
What this case shows is the possibility that Homeopathy has in regenerating
the human organism.
This is what has to come out to the world, to understand
that this is not a method of treatment simply,
it is a method that regenerates the human body.
It makes the human body young again.
She was dying, there was no question.
There was a Polish surgeon in the class, he got up and said I have operated
1000 such cases. You remember?
-Yes.
-I showed this case with the Italian group, there was a surgeon,
he got up and said I can confirm in such cases we amputate both legs.
What is more interesting is the adenocarcinoma,
which is found out during the examination in the hospital
and still Homeopathy could keep up the organism with all these problems.
The treatment was, for those who remember, the treatment started with Arsenicum album.
With these cases you don't have much to go about but what I have seen it was
that it was June or July in Germany, in Celle.
The weather was quite warm and the woman in the hospital was covered
with 2-3 blankets.
Of course she was feeling cold in her legs but I saw she had a fan
and she was fanning her face and the pains were not so great at the moment.
Two of those toes, one in the one and one in the other leg, they fell off,
they were totally destroyed, they were totally black and gangrened.
There was no other measures to help her, with any other way and you could see
the healing signs that they were going on.
When the second day we had already an effect of Arsenicum and she started uncovering
and then we took the case constitutionally, to find out
what might be the constitutional remedy.
Who remembers what was the second remedy?
-Sepia.
-Sepia very good.
Most probably it was her constitutional remedy.
So we continued with Arsenicum, adding Sepia to the case
because there was no time to lose.
On Monday evening they had to examine and they had to find
that the arteries were pumping a little bit of blood.
Anthracinum came later on when these ulcers started being activated
and then the pains started and the pains were severe, burning pains with deep,
black ulcers.
And I said Anthracinum and then after Anthracinum it was Hepar Sulphur.
I can't remember now, it is recorded all the treatment but the most important
it was Arsenicum in the beginning, with Sepia together, intercurrently.
We give one Arsenicum and after an hour one Sepia.
-How?
-Orally.
-How high?
-Who remembers?
-11,12.
-C12.
-I think it started with 4X also, very low Arsenicum first
and then you went a little higher.
-It was a low potency and the main thing for us to see
is the possibility of regeneration.
We are not acting locally, we are acting on the whole organism
and that's why the organism can remain for years in such a good condition,
as she describes.