In the first case, let me see what it says here.
...Feels tired all the time, unable to resist any demand in his work, exhaustion.
He has developed constant anxiety, anxiety in bed at night, better after rising
in the morning, anxiety of conscience, as if he has committed some crime,
feels he is not good in his work, has not done enough for his patients,
he can not enjoy sex anymore, feels anxious after having sex, constant homesickness
for his home place, his parents, where he lived his youth.
He feels that if he could go there, he could become well but he can not leave his work.
Fears in dark, of embedded disease, of death, of fainting, of losing his reason...
Fear of suffocation when lying...
Have you done your homework?
Who wants to speak?
Nobody.
Nobody wants to speak.
-I will give him Carbo animalis.
-Why?
-Because he feels conflict and also the idea is the same.
-Only the fears, OK. Somebody else?
-The main characteristic of Carbo animalis I think it is the homesickness,
always having contact with his parents, also the feeling that I will be well, if I can go home.
This is the center of the remedy.
-But it's not enough because home sick we have also Phosphoric acid, Capsicum.
Show me home sickness. See how many remedies are there?
Mercury, I have not seen...
Carbo animalis, Ignatia...
But the main remedies are Capsicum, Carbo animalis, Phosphoric acid.
For me these 3 remedies are very strong home sickness.
Capsicum is together with a feeling of nostalgia.
-What led me to the idea of Carbo animalis in the first place was this being overwhelmed
from work, the inability to withdraw from his work and this paired with the home sickness.
-What it looks like this symptom with which other remedy we have been discussing?
-I think the difference to Capsicum is that Capsicum has strong other symptoms,
for spicy things and Capsicum is totally unable to do anything, he is lying there.
In our case he is still working, he is able to do his duty.
-This desire to do, to work and not being able to resist the demand of others,
we have spoken on another remedy as well.
Natrum carbonicum. This is similar, the exhaustion is similar.
Once I'm exhausted, anybody can come and ask me to take his case.
So they know, when I'm exhausted everybody comes and say take my case and I can't resist.
When there is depletion of energy, then you can not...
But some remedies act this way or that way.
Natrum carbonicum or Carbo animalis they can not resist.
They try and try until they collapse.
-I used the rubric fear of suffocation due to mucus in the throat and there
Carbo animalis is the only remedy.
Also in the rubric fear of suffocation on closing the eyes, there also is Carbo animalis
in there and in another rubric fear of suffocation while lying.
In this rubric there are two remedies Moschus and Carbo animalis also.
-Who prescribed Carbo animalis in this case?
Very good.
These cases I have manipulated it to make them more easy.
Don't think that you will get in practice so easy cases.
You add one or two symptoms there and you make it easy.
Still you have to start thinking rightly because this case it could have been without the fears
and home sickness with the tired feeling and not being able to resist,
that's enough for Carbo animalis.
Carbo animalis is very tired, it can not resist.
And if you have another keynote, while lying in bed they get chilliness, coldness,
when they first lie in bed.
A man suffering with duodenal ulcer.
... his business, his wife and his money.
He started building up his life again but since then he is suffering very much
with cramping pains that come from 3-4 after eating.
If he takes fruit that is bad for him but like onions, sweets... become worse.
His pains are better if he eats some biscuits or drink some milk.
The pain wake him in the night also but are worse around 6-7 pm as well.
...and then in the night at around 10 pm. No breakfast.
He used to be a very cool businessman but now he suffers with fears and anxieties.
Anxiety when alone, cramp in stomach, when hungry.
His anxiety arises from stomach together with pain but especially during sleep.
He is anxious about his future...
Who wants to speak about this case?
-I think that this case shows three remedies right straight.
Arsenicum album, Nux vomica and Kali Carbonicum and when you look at the fears
which are occurring in this case, they are resembling between Arsenicum album
or Nux vomica and I think these 2 kinds of fears I see on Nux vomica
because Arsenicum album has no fear of poverty. It is very strange in this case.
This man suffers from the first bankrupt and then he is still all the years
are committing by the fear already be without any money.
It is periodic on this case seems strange to go against Arsenicum.
This person is worse at 8 o'clock and it is periodic seems to be Nux vomica
looking at the Repertory at Arsenicum and it's worse at midnight.
All the other symptoms fit and in my sense to Nux vomica as the result and
Arsenicum is the second, Kali Carbonicum is the third.
-Who agrees with this explanation?
-If you don't agree you have to give your own version.
-I think that it is an Arsenicum case.
-You think it is an Arsenicum case? That means you agree with him.
-No.
-What did he say? He said Nux vomica finally.
Sorry.
-At least to my Repertory if I understood correctly it was stated that Arsenicum
does not have fear of poverty and in my Repertory it does have fear of poverty
and has tremendous anxieties.
This fear also being injured and suffering again as he had in the past was the fear
that I included, that's why I elected for Arsenicum.
-I thought of different remedies I might give him but then I looked at the rubric fear when hungry.
And for me this is a peculiar symptom which up to now I only knew from Iodine.
Also this combination with the anxiety that rises up from the stomach and
when you look at the entire pathology in the whole case, I decided for Kali Carbonicum.
-It is the first rubric, it's not the stomach, it is abdomen ulceration, quite another rubric.
A long time I thought about this, it is a different kind of rubrics.
All the problems he has are arising from the stomach but ulceration is not in the stomach.
-Take it out. Find abdominal ulcer.
-But there is a cross reference in abdominal ulcer to go back to stomach ulcer.
-There is a cross reference. This is not important because, as we said,
we have other symptoms, which are general symptoms, mental symptoms, so therefore
the local symptoms per se are not of great importance.
They should not change a prescription which comes when you take the whole,
it should not change the prescription. Even if there was a change here, I would not take it.
Put abdominal.
Show me the rubric in ulcers.
-Not Kali Carbonicum.
-But these ulcers do not refer to internal ulcers.
They do not refer to duodenum or anything to do with the duodenum.
Duodenal ulcer it does not matter whether it is on the duodenal, in the beginning of the guts.
People will show their stomach I have a pain here and the time element, so the location
and the time element goes for...
You have to find the time element and the location where the person feels the pain.
-Abdominal ulcers is not a rubric. I put it there underlined 3 times,
it doesn't change the repertorization.
-Who has prescribed Kali carbonicum? Very good.