Din câte am înţeles au fsot câteva discuţii şi neânţelegeri în grup,
despre cum ar trebui luat corect un follow up. Şi aş dori să vă întreb pentru a clarifica, cum trebuie luat corect un follow up?
Ok, vă voi prezenta ideea mea despre cum se ia corect un follow up.
Un follow up corect este cel care vă dă în primul rând impresia a ceea ce s-a întâmplat înainte şi după tratament.
Este o impresie generală.
Sunt mai bine în asta, asta, asta şi sunt mai rău în asta, asta. Sunt la fel, indiferent care a fost starea iniţială.
Deci putem să ne facem o impresie asupra sentimentelor subiective ale pacientului. Care sunt sentimentele ei subiective?
Şi asta are trei părţi. Una este mental-emoţionalul care este de o importanţă şi un interes foarte mare,
a doua este nivelul energetic iar cel de
al treilea este simptomatologia locală.
Deci în această ordine ar trebui luat un follow up: mental-emoţional, sunt la fel, sunt mai bine.
Energetic sunt mai bine, la fel, mai rău.
Şi pentru simptomele locale poţi de asemenea să spui ce s-a întâmplat.
Dacă ai o mică durere în ureche în data de 17/11/98 asta nu este important.
Decât dacă durerea este pănă astăzi. Din noiembrie
am o durere de ureche care a rămas acolo.
Altfel medicul, cel care va lua cazul, sau voi aveţi de gând să luaţi cazul, veţi fi confuzi
şi vei da mult mai multă importanţă unui simptom care nu are nici o importanţă.
Apoi veţi fi duşi în eroare şi apoi
veţi da remediul greşit.
Un pacient care nu dă un raport ca acesta,
poate duce în eroare pe orice, chiar şi pe mine.
Cred că pot fi indus în eroare pentru că am tendinţa
de a crede deşi sunt foarte atent
în observare, sunt indivizi care cred ceea ce spun.
Deci dacă ei cred ceea ce spun, voi crede
şi eu. Dacă cineva încearcă să mă păcălească,
înţeleg imediat şi nu spun nimic. Nu îi voi spune că încearcă să mă păcălească
dar voi încerca folosind aceleaşi cuvinte ale pacientului să dovedesc, mai târziu, asta este ceea ce spui,
asta este ceea ce spui, acestea
două nu merg împreună, ceva de genul acesta.
Pentru că nu este frumos să spui
cuiva: încerci să mă păcăleşti.
Dorinţa de a te înşela este: acum sunt cu
doctorul, vreau să obţin cel mai mare beneficiu.
Deci am şi asta, asta şi asta. Poţi
să faci ceva pentru asta şi asta şi asta?
Dar această dorinţă de a vindeca anumite afecţiuni vă poate duce într-un fel de recădere a întregului caz.
Pentru că în loc să aşteptaţi, daţi remediul care este greşit pentru că
dacă trebuie să aştept şi dau remediul, remediul este greşit. Trebuie să aşteptăm, eşti în procesul de vindecare
şi trebuie să aşteptăm, placebo, da, veţi da placebo. Dar dacă cineva nu vă dă impresia
de progres al cazului iar progresul ar trebui să meargă de sus în jos.
De la mental, emoţional, fizic. Aici în cele din urmă avem multe probleme. Putem avea multe probleme
dar totuşi va trebui să aşteptăm să
vedem ce se întâmplă cu patologia severă.
Trebuie să aşteptăm în special când acest proces este corect şi nu sunt situaţii grave.
Deci imaginaţi-vă pe cineva care vine şi spune: am o durere la ceafă şi apoi mai am o durere în lobul urechii
şi apoi o mică durere acolo şi vă dă 1000 de dureri care sunt peste tot, ce vei crede?
Şi nu vorbeşte despre energie, despre starea mental-emoţională; pacientul nu înţelege
procesul de vindecare şi apoi va trebui să întrebi pacientul, stai puţin care cum te simţi mental-emoţional?
Asta înseamnă fricile, anxietatea, depresia. Dacă pacientul a venit iniţial pentru depresie
se va plânge de multe simptome fizice, dacă tratamentul tău este corect.
Acesta este tratamentul cel mai de succes; altfel tratamentul tău nu a fost corect. A fost efectul placebo,
mă simt puţin mai bine şi apoi din nou mai rău etc., etc.
Trebuie să ajungă aici jos. Şi când ajunge aici
aici sunt simptomele. Dar pe aceste simptome trebuie să decizi, este remediul clar, da sau nu?
Dacă este clar ok, îţi dau un remediu. Dacă nu este calr, dar ai dureri, spui 'nu este clar nu îţi pot da un remediu'.
Aşa de strict trebuie să fiţi. Oh mă duc să
fac acupunctură. Du-te şi fă acupunctură.
Mă duc la chiriopractică. Du-te la chiriopractică.
Nu îmi pasă ce faci.
Ce îmi pasă este ce ştiu că este corect şi
trebuie să faci. Trebuie să stai şi să aştepţi.
Acesta este pentru mine ceea ce este corect de făcut în acest moment.
În nici un caz nu ai o depresie importantă aici şi nu vei avea nici un spasm acolo.
Asta este în detrimentul pacientului dacă
vă dă informaţia greşită.
De ce încerci să mă păcăleşti, este ca şi cum te-ai păcăli singur. Ce este asta? De aceea cele mai bune follow up-uri vin de la oamenii simpli,
nu de la intelectuali. Oamenii spun, da asta este mai bine şi acum am asta. Spui: o Dumnezeule cazul este clar
pentru că este un fel de claritate şi puritate în aceste nivele iar noi am învăţat: 'dacă îi spun că am asta, asta şi asta,
el se va strădui mai mult, îmi va da un remediu mai bun şi apoi voi fi vindecat'. Nu există aşa ceva.
Spune doar adevărul ce este acolo şi apoi
lasă homeopatul care ştie ce face.
Problema este câţi homeopaţi
din toată lumea ştiu ce fac?
Probabil voi sunteţi singurul grup pentru că ascultaţi teorie.
Toţi ceilalţi homeopaţi din toată lumea, arucă cu remedii. Aruncă remediul acesta, aruncă remediul acesta.
Pot prescrie remedii în 5 minute dar voi pierde toată esenţa, toată informaţia.
Vedeţi, vindecarea reală este un lucru magic. Ceva care este dincolo de abilitatea noastră de a o gestiona.
Spui, te vindec. Cine eşti tu? Ştiu homeopatie. Vezi cel mai clar caz şi eşuezi.
Şi crezi că este clar şi eşuezi. Spun ok acum ce? Uită-te la tine, du-te la oglindă priveşte-te şi spune
Te voi vindeca. Aşteaptă puţin. Homeopatia este o descoperire. Tu descoperi magia, această reacţie individuală a fiecărei persoane.
Observi şi descoperi. Câteodată
este un proces foarte obositor.
dacă dăreşti să înveţi homeopatie
trebuie să depui mult efort. Fără îndoială.
Mult efort în studiu, în observare, în aşteptare, depui mult efort.
Poţi spune, sunt plictisit de acest caz,
Acest caz tu trebuie să îl descoperi.
Aştepţi până când vei descoperi acel moment magic care va face cazul clar, este un moment magic.
Şi dacă parcurgi acest proces, atunci vei descoperi o comoară de simptome.
Vei descoperi că Sepia are multiple faţete. Asta poate fi Sepia, aceea poate fi Sepia. Ignatia, Calcarea carbonica.
V-am spus de multe ori, studenţii mei mă întrebau: de ce ai prescris acest remediu? Pentru că am ascultat foarte multe cazuri de Pulsatilla.
şi am văzut că Pulsatilla nu este singura
care te conduce cu uşurinţă şi te convinge uşor.
Nu este numai asta, mai este şi altceva. Când am descoperit asta? Când am ascultat cazul.
Da, dacă nu doreşti să asculţi cazul. Dacă sunteţi
un practician foarte ocupat atunci nu asculţi. Dacă devii prea repede,
prea faimos, oamenii încep să vină unul după altul. Acum te lăcomeşti fie să faci mulţi bani
fie să fii foarte faimos şi prescrii. Aceste lucruri am făcut, ştiu psihologia,
ştiu tot ce se întâmplă. De 40 de ani mă observ pe mine şi observ pacienţii.
Ceea ce vă spun nu sunt poveşti de pe altă planetă. Sunt poveşti din experienţa reală.
Dar în mintea mea era, George îţi lipsesc foarte multe. Într-o oră vedeam cinci cazuri.
Şi vedeam cum cazul era mai bine.
Sunt mult mai bine, ok, placebo, următorul.
Luam câteva minute pentru următorul caz care era nou şi poate aveam probleme.
Şi câteodată eram blocat desigur şi în loc să termin la ora 21-22,
terminam la ora 1 dimineaţa.
Deci este descoperire, această atitudine nouă şi
ştiu unde pot găsi o atitudine nouă.
Aveţi un caz tipic de Nat-m, agravat de soare, aversiune la grăsimi şi dorinţă de sare şi are cefalee.
Ah, Nat-m. gata. Dacă faceţi aşa, veţi pierde o multitudine de complexe interioare ale persoanei, penrtu că vedeţi
un caz tipic de Nat-m şi nu investighezi. Dai pur şi simplu remediul şi pacientul pleacă.
Aici, aveţi o comoară în faţa voastră şi o lăsaţi să vă scape pentru că acum veţi descoperi noi simptome
care aparţin doar acelui individ. Şi apoi descoperi că Nat-m are de asemenea asta şi asta,
această teamă, acea anxietate etc., etc. Acesta este mometul când stai şi investighezi şi asculţi.
Nat-m poat deveni foarte ipohondru.
Vorbeşte, vorbeşte, vorbeşte, cum ştii asta? Pentru că ai ascultat odată, altă dată sau altă dată.
Nu ai ascultat odată pentru a putea spune Nat-m este ipohondru, asta înseamnă că ai ascultat 10 cazuri
care erau ipohondre. Şi care te-au deranjat
cu mici simptome ici şi colo.
Crezi că este Nitric acid? Anxietate ipohondră, Kali-ars nu este anxietate, este teamă. Voi muri.
Nat-m este ipohondru
Asta, asta, asta, aia ... placebo. De ce?
Pentru că înainte era în depresie, acum are acest simptom minor, celălat, acesta, placebo.
Dar asculţi şi descoperi, oh este o ipohondrie, încă aparţine de Nat-m. Aştepţi, placebo.
Şi apoi vine în cele din urmă un fel de echilibrare.
Ce mi-am propus să vorbesc astărzi este despre miasme.
Definiţie. Când spunem miasmă, ce vrem
să spunem cu adevărat? Avem acest cuvânt pentru a specifica ceva, cred,
ceva neînţeles de fiecare
dintre noi. Ce este o miasmă?
Putem spune că o miasmă este această reţea
complexă energetică. Este o reţea, ca aceasta.
Aceasta este o miasmă. Apoi pui deasupra o altă miasmă, doar răsuceşti puţin şi pui următoarea reţea complexă.
Şi punem o altă reţea aici, o răsuceşti puţin şi vedeţi cum aproape toare găurile sunt închise.
Când toate găurile sunt închise, asta înseamnă 5 miasme, atunci putem spune că avem un caz incurabil. De ce?
Pentru că nu mai trece energie prin aceste găuri. Energia produce simptomatologia.
Închizi complet energia şi apoi ai
o stare de totală "adinamie," slăbiciune totală.
Nu ai simptomatologie, nu sunt indicaţii. Organismul este complet blocat în ceea ce priveşte energia
şi va merge în jos şi va muri. Şi asta
nu poate fi găsită în nici un sistem fizic,
nici în cel limfatic, nici în cel nervos sau reticulo-endotelial, nu este ceva ce vei găsi
în partea fizică a diferitelor sisteme ale corpului. O reţea ca aceasta poate afecta unul, două sau trei
sau toate sistemele organismului. Această reţea, această reţea complexă care blochează apărarea energetică a corpului,
pentru că vorbim în special despre condiţia energetică, poate fi îndepărtată cu 1,2 sau 3 remedii.
Poţi îndepărta ceea ce noi numim o miasmă nu doar cu un remediu, putem avea nevoie de 3 remedii diferite pentru a o îndepărta.
ceea ce noi numim miasma sifilitică sau sicotică sau tuberculinică.
Vedeţi aceasta este o altă reţea, vedeţi cum se închide. Şi asta este o altă reţea şi ai asta, o situaţie nefericită
în care dacă pui aceste reţele într-o altă perspectivă,
asta este ceea ce căutaţi,
pentru prima miasmă, aceste 3 simptome cheie.
Să îndepărtăm prima maismă, primul nivel. Nivelul şi miasma sunt idei similare. Singura diferenţă este că
o miasmă poate avea nevoie pentru a fi
ridicată, 3 nivele, 3 remedii.
Deci un individ care are nevoie de 3
remedii pentru primul nivel,
3 remedii pentru cel de al doilea, 3 remedii pentru cel de al treilea, este un caz foarte dificil de tratat.
Acum care sunt calităţile acestei reţele complexe
Avem câţiva parametri pentru a defini miasma.
Primul parametru este: când putem denumi un simptom complex, când îl putem denumi miasmă?
Când are la început, origine.
Are o origine specifică şi asta poate fi bacterie, microbi, viruşi etc., substanţe chimice.
Pentru că noi astăzi folosim substanţe chimice complexe, putem crea un blocaj miasmatic în organism.
Şi acestea reprezintă unul dintre cele mai periculoase lucruri pe care ni-l facem nouă astăzi, folosirea excesivă a medicamentelor chimice.
Deci are o origine speciifcă şi
b) poate produce un set specific de simptome.
Acum dacă luăm aceşti doi factori, punem toate bolile infecţioase aici. Care este cel de al treilea factor de care ai nevoie
pentru a o denumi miasmă, nu fiecare
boală acută poate produce o miasmă.
Avem nevoie de al treilea factor pentru a avea
ideea de maismă. Care este cel de al treilea factor?
Istoricul de familie? Ereditatea?
Predispoziţia genetică cred.
Predispoziţia genetică, dar toate acestea au un efect. Predispoziţia genetică etc. Care este efectul?
Efectul este că au abilitatea, miasma are abilitatea de a trece de la o generaţie la alta.
Are calitatea, capacitatea de a transfera
reţeaua la următoarea generaţie.
Aceasta este o condiţie, absolut
necesară pentru a avea o miasmă.
Deci trece la generaţia următoare.
Dacă acceptăm acest tip de definiţie şi acest tip de condiţii pentru miasme, atunci putem spune că avem mai mult de 3 miasme.
Hahnemann a avut o idee şi ideea a fost corectă. Care a fost ideea lui? Ceva bloca cazul.
El ar fi spus: Voi da Rhus tox la cineva şi va reveni din nou şi din nou cu simptome de Rhus tox.
În acest timp organismul era destul de puternic, astfel încâtî avea o simptomatologie foarte metodică.
Deci pacientul va reveni cu Rhus tox. Şi apoi când dai Calcarea carbonica unui astfel de caz, persoana este vindecată.
Ce înseamnă asta? El prin urmare s-a gândit, am dat un remediu mai profund pentru a contracara miasma.
Asta a fost ideea originală, ca o idee proaspătă care vine pentru prima dată. Ideea trebuie să fie gândită, pusă în practică, observată etc.
şi în cele din urmă adevărul iese la iveală. Ca la început, am spus, concepţia poate avea loc în faza unu
când organismul este într-o stare totală de satisfacţie şi echilibru. Aceasta este ideea proaspătă.
Acum dacă această idee va fi pusă în practică, unii ginecologi care se ocupă de fertilizare etc.,
vor încerca să găsească parametri de recunoaştere a acestor celule vii care sunt în faza 1.
Şi dacă ei le pot recunoaşte la microscop, iau pe ăsta, ăsta este bun şi fertilizează
în loc să aibă o rată de succes de 10-15 %, aceasta va fi de 85 %. Aceasta este ideea proaspătă care poate avea sau nu validitate.
Va avea validitate după ce va fi pusă în practică.
În acelaşi fel ideea lui Hahnemann
de maismă a fost o idee proaspătă.
Acum unii homeopaţi contemporani au luat această idee şi au făcut un del de dogmatism din ea.
Ideea este aceasta. Nu este o idee dogmatică. Avem 3 miasme şi atunci cum explici faptul că
atunci când ai tuberculoză în familie, dai Tuberculinum pacientului şi acesta este vindecat. Cum este vindecat?
Oh, tuberculoza este un amestec de două miasme.Sau ceva de genul acesta. Ce este asta? Asta nu are nimic de-a face?
Dacă este un amestec de 2 miasme: Sifilis şi Sicoză, asta înseamnă că ai nevoie de un remediu sicotic şi de unul sifilitic
înainte de a rezolva un caz de tuberculoză sau de origine tuberculinică. Dar ce a arătat practica este
atunci când dai Tuberculinum această miasmă dispare. Toată miasma tuberculinică dispare.
Şi mai mult decât atât a fost o neînţelegere precum că am putea găsi un remediu al persoanei
pentru că noi am înţeles maismele. Asta este complet greşit. Dacă cineva vă spune
'Am găsit între Merc. şi Nat-s., am ales Merc. pentru că am văzut miasma sifilitică în acest caz'.
Este un cuvând în engleză dar nu poate fi spus
în faţa doamnelor; aş folosi acel cuvânt.
Pentru că practic ce faci într-un caz de sifilis în care dai Medorrhinum. Ce este asta acum?
Spui că sifilisul a produs simptome sicotice sau simptomele sicotice de Medorrhinum sunt sifilitice.
Tot felul de idei răsucite pentru a justifica anumite lucruri care nu sunt explicate şi nici justificate.
De aceea această idee: voi şti remediul
dacă ştiu miasma este o concepţie greşită.
Asta vine iniţial de la Hahnemann dar cei care l-au urmat au înţeles greşit teoria lui Hahnemann.
Şi de ce Hahnemann a spus toate aceste lucruri. Hahnemann a fost corect când a spus,    este un blocaj
pentru că această reţea de miasme este un
obstacol, un blocaj care trebuie îndepărtat.
Şi este eliminat cu ce? Cu remediul corect, poate cu două remedii.
Acesta este un lucru. Alt lucru este: avem
un set specific de simptome pentru fiecare miasmă?
Şi spunem, trebuie să avem asta. Deci dacă ştiu setul specific de simptome, este mult mai uşor pentru mine să găsesc remediul?
Să luăm din experienţă şi să vedem
ce este miasma psorică.
Şi miasma psorică aşa cum spune cuvântul
este o miasmă care vine din erupţiile cutanate,
din supresarea erupţiilor cutanate producând ce?
Producând o stare interioară similară cu pruritul.
Veţi fi surprinţi de exemplu să vedeţi în unele cazuri că o erupţie cutanată care este foarte pruriginoasă,
produce o stare de nelinişte şi anxietate care nu te lasă niciodată în pace.
Produce o stare interioară similară. Aţi avut vreodată o erupţie cutanată care să fie pruriginoasă?
Veţi vedea că mergeţi la culcare şi apoi începeţi scărpinatul şi te răsuceşti din nou şi din nou.
Şi aceasta este o stare de anxietate sau o nelinişte care este, în acelaşi fel ca nevoia de a te scărpina,
ai nevoie să-ţi scarpini creierul. Sau pruritul ajunge în plămâni, apoi este o iritaţie pulmonară
constantă permanentă. Bine, spui ca ai o miasmă psorică. Care este remediul?
Te ajută asta să găseşti remediul?
Foarte puţine cazuri sunt clare în care spui, acum tratez acest caz cu remedii sifilitice,
începe cu Aurum, trece la Mercurius, ia Syphilinum etc. şi acum vine cu simptome de psora.
This itching, this restlessness, this anxiety has developed. Very few cases.
And you will see from the cases we treat how much more complicated are things, even with cases which are clear cases.
Let's take the case where we prescribed Ignatia 50M and then it came to Sulphur clear and then Calcarea carbonica clear.
What is this miasm?
Ignatia you have
to say belongs to what miasm?
And then because of this problem, those who brought up these theories for those who are interested,
they said Ignatia oh, Ignatia is syphilitic,
is sycotic and is psoric.
Sulphur, what is Sulphur? Oh Sulphur is primarily psoric, primarily syphilitic and primarily sycotic. What is really going on?
I had a student of Ortega here in Alonissos
and I presented a case of Medorrhinum.
A Medorrhinum which is very introverted, it cannot talk at all. It will not communicate, it's totally antisocial.
The words cannot come out. They cannot
stay with a group of people unless they drink.
If they are drunk they can communicate,
they can go out of the house etc.
I presented this case and she was down in the class and I said, what is this case? You tell me.
She was the best student of Ortega. She had in her mind this prejudice. She said, this case is a clear case of Calcarea carbonica.
I asked the other students. Some of them said this is a case of Medorrhinum because it's better in the sea
and desires unripe fruits and things like that
and because they were some other indications.
She said, it's a clear case but the remedy which cured this case was Medorrhinum unfortunately.
It doesn't matter what your ideas are and
your preconceptions or even prejudice.
Because if you have some prejudices you are going to have a problem with Homeopathy.
If you can become somebody who does not know anything when you see a case, my God I don't know anything.
If you have that state of feeling that I dont' know anything, then everything that the patient says
will be impressed upon you and then the anamnesis from what you know, eventually will come.
If you go with the idea that I know this, I know the miasms, immediately you cut down the possibility of information to flow in.
You have a preconceived idea.
Forget about finding the remedy.
You have to be like a blackboard on which nothing is written and the patient is going to write the symptoms.
And you receive all the symptoms and then you make an analysis and then you make a synthesis.
In the same way, the idea of the miasm
a lot of misconceptions have taken place.
The itch has a similar inner state. The
Syphilis also has an analogous inner state.
From conventional Medicine you know the stages of Syphilis, if they go in they can affect of course the vascular system,
it can affect the nervous system and it can affect the skin. So there are certain stages which you know.
Syphilis will follow. But what is the mental-emotional state of the syphilitic patient we don't know.
The only thing we know when it has affected the nervous system and then in the end of the nervous system
you see a distraction of the mental faculties, after you have seen the Tabes dorsalis, the paralysis on the nervous system,
then eventually you will see the distraction of the central nervous system as well. But before that,
there are some distractions that have been done on a subtle level with Syphilis which are interesting to study.
For instance if we had the possibility, that the Universities had students working in different subjects,
and we had a hospital, I could give them research projects that we could find fantastic things and to put in order
again back in order what is today a confusion in Medicine.
Then Syphilis is creating a state in the organism which is self-destructive and in order to prevent that self-destruction
because it is an organism that goes
into the body and wants to kill everything.
You intervene in that process and you save the patient, but the idea is to destruct and to distort and to kill.
So the organism in order not to die finds ways out. And what we see is perversions in thinking,
perversions in feelings, perversions in sex.
So a lot of perverted sexual practices which are happening in certain nations, I would say,
who they were under the effect of Syphilis, are due to great exposure to primary syphilitic infection.
Alcoholism, the use of drugs, when I say drugs
I mean the narcotics, is a syphilitic perversion
but these perversions in sexual issues
they take a lot of distorted expressions.
And depending on how strong the syphilitic tendency is there in the body, so bigger is going to be the self-destruction.
Why do we say Aurum is a syphilitic remedy?
Because it has this idea of self-destruction very strongly. In the same way Platina is syphilitic.
These are remedies which have all kinds of perversions and self-destruction.
So as an idea we may say Syphilis has self-destruction and perversions. And this is a theme, a general theme.
And it comes from the actual facts of this infection. Now if you go to sycosis, you have different facts.
In Gonorrhea for instance, which we're mostly talking about, we see as the immediate reaction
of suppressed Gonorrhea, we see condylomata.
That means the organism under Gonorrhea
infection has the tendency to bring out an eruption, a hard tumor.
It's like a volcano. It cannot retain it. It has to come out to the surface. That's the idea.
But when you see self-destruction tendencies together with condylomata, which is going to go first?
What determines what is going to go first are the symptoms. What are the main uppermost symptoms,
keynote symptoms on which you're
going to base your prescription?
If you don't know the theory of miasms at all, if you don't understand anything, still you can be a very good Homeopath.
If you understand the theory and you know the theory, it will make you a better philosopher but not a better healer.
You see your enthusiasm when I say, I' m going to talk about miasms, why? Because in your mind you had the idea
that if we know the miasms then we can
more easily find the remedies. Forget it.
I can tell you it can misguide you and you can give the wrong medicine. I have seen it again and again.
I say why did you give this remedy?
It's a syphilitic case so I thought of Mercury.
I said, Mercury did something? No. Ok, give Medorrhinum, see what happens with Medorrhinum.
We have an explosive character, we have an expressive character in Sycosis, that is true but they say, for instance,
Natrum sulphuricum, what is this remedy?
Sycotic, syphilitic or psoric?
-Sycotic.
-Mostly sycotic. They say, mostly sycotic.
Ok, take a Nat-s patient with an asthma case and try to show me where is this explosive general attitude, expressive.
It's not expressive, it's a remedy which is very composed in the mental-emotional, very unexpressive I would say,
but you need Nat-s, why? Because of the 4am aggravation. If you think that this is a case of Syphilis,
you will never give a Nat-s but you see the 4 o'clock aggravation etc. No, no it's a syphilitic case and will give
Syphilinum or will give Mercury. Again you go to tubercular miasm. It has a kind of overall picture.
What it this overall picture? First of all cachexia, it doesn't allow the person to develop properly.
Secondly you see easy infections,
especially of the respiratory tract.
Repeated infections of the respiratory tract together with a kind of cachexia, it has to give you the idea of Tuberculinum.
But in Tuberculinum you have to have the grinding of the teeth, the desire for fat, desire for pork etc.
Little things like that which will give you the clue.
What is the general idea of cancer, of cancerous miasm because you have found out many times when a person says,
my mother died, my father died, my uncles died from cancer, you give Cancerinum and many times
they will say that this was an excellent remedy for me. That means it took away a complex net
that was blocking the case due
to this hereditary predisposition
and then you find out more or less
what was taking out from this case,
what was the general indications and then that's how we came to know the symptomatology of Cancerinum.
And this is how we found out that Cancerinum has both types of people. One who is suppressed but nice
and the other which is angry and loose and just doesn't care who is going to kill around.
There are these two types of persons in Cancerinum. The one that is like a "bulldozer" they will go around the house,
their own environment, children they don't care, they don't care about parents, if they hurt them, if they don't hurt them.
'Just give me money, you are my mother you have to give me money. You are a bad mother'.
And then the mother says, 'ok take money'. 'Buy me a motorbike. I can't go to school walking, it's half an hour'.
He sleeps up to 10 o'clock, wake up, leave
me alone, wake up you have to go to school.
The mother says, 'I'm afraid because he will hit me'. That type can be a Cancerinum type, this explosive.
This is where we have the final stages where it destroys everything; the cancer destroys the body totally in a very short time.
-So you are saying it's not influencing your praxis and you never mention miasms anyway. But Hahnemann says that
when the best chosen remedy is not working with the patient, he was looking for the possible miasm,
Tuberculosis in the family which he treated with a kind of priority and gave a remedy for that. If there was Syphilis
in the family, he gave a syphilitic remedy,
so you didn't find anything like that?
-No. There is no such thing. You may do it and still you may be effective sometimes but there are no rules
on which you can base a prescription
concerning the knowledge of a miasm. There are no rules.
If you say at a certain moment, let me give some nosodes and some people do it as a regular practice, they give
Medorrhinum, Syphilinum Tuberculinum, they give Psorinum in the beginning of their treatment.
And they claim to have some effect. Of course, these people who need one of these nosodes will be affected.
What about the others? They have
taken deep nosodes for no reason.
-But you have a case which has had Tuberculosis before and has 1-2 keynotes of Tuberculosis.
-Yes, if you have 1-2. But let us say, you have a case which had Tuberculosis and you see a case clear Calcarea carbonica.
What are you going to give?
Tuberculinum or Calcarea carbonica?
Actually one of my students in Athens when she came first, she came with Tuberculosis and still was there.
You could see in the X-ray.
It was a case of Calcarea carbonica.
I gave her Calcarea carbonica and the whole thing disappeared. It cleared up and the whole organism
started developing again in 2-3 months. If I had this idea? Another case I remember of Syphilis.
Syphilis that was positive after years of treatment with penicillin, still was positive after the test.
And this was a case of Calcarea carbonica. I gave her Calcarea carbonica and the test became negative
and the woman felt much better.
Now if I had this idea of Syphilinum, why?
But from the very beginning I mistrusted because when I saw her, I did this one time, two times.
You have to observe, it doesn't work. Then something else happens and what is this something else?
It is these things here, the 3 keynotes. If you have 3 keynotes of Tuberculinum, you give Tuberculinum, there is no question.
With tuberculous idea plus 1,2,3 keynotes, you give Tuberculinum. On the other hand if you do have more symptoms of Sulphur,
you have to give Sulphur, nevermind what you know about the family.
I know that my father had Syphilis; it does
not matter, still Sulphur will be indicated?
Calcarea carbonica will be indicated? You give it.
I try to take you out of the frame of mind which is set on certain things.
Why do you think I do not give you indications
of what to do in different pathological cases?
Do you think I don't know?
I know very well and I know that if I put together 5 remedies I can make a specific composition
that will affect most of the individuals
that have that particular pathology.
But if I do that I will become very rich I can assure you because all over the world they'd be selling
these GV composite for rheumatic, whatever and then I would be very rich but I would have destroyed Homeopathy,
the possibility to really cure, to really regenerate a generation which is going down the gutter and there is no hope.
It's going to be degenerated more and
more. And if I do that what they will do?
They will go to the pharmacy and say, give me this rheumatic or give me this rhinitic or give me this headache pill
and they will feel better and they can go on.
But this better needs the second remedy and needs the third remedy
and when is the time for the second
or the third and what follows the first remedy?
And why after the first remedy it has to go to Sulphur, there are reasons. And I'm teaching you that and I don't
want to teach you easy ways. If you want easy ways you just sit in a chair and you meditate
what is your problem my dear child? My eyes are running and bla, bla, bla. I don't need anything else.
Take Euphrasia, Clematis, Graphites and Sulphur. And you become a guru.
I mean when I was in Pakistan, I met the doctor of the President of Democracy. He was his personal and I said,
can I sit with you to see your practice? Of course sit there. He was chewing some kind of red stuff, you know.
The patient would come, I could not understand of course but I could hear 2-5 words and then I could see him writing
a kind of prescription with 5-6 remedies. Take these remedies, you go there, he has his own pharmacy.
I said, 'very impressive. Do you have success'? 'Absolutely. He says, what are you doing?'
I said, 'maybe I've taken much more time. But you see so many people, how can you spend so much time?'
And I explained to him a little bit,
very carefully, so not to insult him.
Because he was my host and when
he is your host you are a little bit polite.
In the end he said to me, how much money you're earning with this practice? I told him something.
He says, I earn 20 times more than you.
I said, good luck. I don't know what's happening to him today but he was much younger than me.
But the idea is that you can do that with Homeopathy. Is this the correct way?
And why you are here? You are here only for that reason to see another aspect, another idea and I must show you this idea,
I must show you this aspect. My idea is not to give you easy solutions.
My idea is to give you the difficult and the difficulties and then the reward will come.
Because people will understand
eventually who is good and who is bad.
-The heritage, the inheritance, these nets are becoming more and more tight for our children, right?
Is it possible through correct treatment and through lifting one miasmatic layer after the other to make it possible
for our children and future children
to become more and more healthy?
And would it be possible in the end even to eradicate all these nets and miasmatic difficulties and if it is possible,
is it possible within one generation or how
many generations do you think it will need?
- A lot of difficult questions but I can give you my impression. It's not the truth but my impression is that yes there is a possibility
of taking away the miasms; to what extend I'm not sure. Yes there is a possibility of regenerating the race.
That means instead of your children being born in that state, if you take good Homeopathy for 3 years before,
your children will definitely be born better. But how many generations may take, it may take 3,4,5 I cannot say.
What I want to tell is this: let us say that somebody is using heroin which is the strongest of the recreational drugs.
And this person at a certain moment decides
to give up and become what they call, clean.
And he goes to a detoxifying community or whatever. He doesn't do Homeopathy and then he marries
and that person has a child. Is his child going to be affected by the heroine miasm, yes or no? Who says yes?
Who says no. Nobody.
I'll tell you my experience that each organism
has a kind of resistance to any chemicals.
Whatever chemical you give to my organism, it has a kind of resistance. So I resist, therefore when I say I resist,
I eliminate and no effect until such time when my resistance breaks at a certain point and my symptomatology
starts changing. Once this has
happened, there is a possibility
of a miasm which is going to be
transferred to the next generation.
That means the effect of the drug has been written upon my DNA. There is a DNA effect, further than that
with this particular drug. This particular drug
will create a miasm for my offsprings.
"progeny" that was the word I was trying to find. So therefore a person who has taken heroin
or has taken penicillin or whatever drug it doesn't necessarily mean that he has created a state of miasm.
The state of miasm is created once this
broken down situation has happened.
You know the people who have taken marihuana, they may develop a state of a miasm with a little bit of marihuana, when?
When you will see this person is going to a state of anxiety after that, they lose totally their inner quietness,
they go into a state of anxiety and fears,
esp. fear that they're going crazy.
Once they're in that state of anxiety
and fears and they have children, forget it.
Their children will be born with anxiety and fears.
But if you treat them homeopathically you can spare the children from these anxieties.
-George if I can come back to the story of the miasm, we study miasm to understand the different level,
to understand the process of cure but what is essential is always to come back to the symptomatology
and to prescribe according to how clear is the picture and how many keynotes and
how much confirmation we have
on prescribing the remedy.
-Is it correct?
-That's correct. Of course there are a lot of things to be discussed
and we can spend hours and hours to discuss in detail and there is also a possibility for reasearch in these matters
which can clarify for us much more issues but at this moment from a practical point of view what we need to know
is that we're dealing with that situation, that's the first one. We're dealing with a case of complex miasmatic conditions.
The second is to know that the elimination of such nets is done due to the correct uppermost remedy.
It's not possible to say, this person needs Calc, let's give him from the beginning Calc. No.
-Can you explain again the difference
between the miasm and the layers?
-Ok, this is a miasm.
What is a layer on the miasm?
This is a layer on a miasm and
this layer we call it Arsenicum
and once the Arsenicum is gone there
is this layer which is called Sulphur.
And perhaps even a third remedy.
And this miasm is lifted.
Let's go back to the case of A. with Pituitary gland extract that we gave. Which is the miasm?
You believe that by taking different
remedies you have the same effect, no.
You have to find the uppermost layer, nevermind what you call it. What is the miasm that was created under the vaccination,
let us say chicken pox or the triple vaccination etc. One organism is producing a state of Cuprum,
the other organism is producing a state of Stamonium, the other first Stam. then Pitu-gl. then Bar-c...
-What is your opinion about using the pills so frequent now and cortisone. I pay attention that the children
who received cortisone because of asthma came to school with restlessness, with hyperactivity.
And then they received Ritalin and this is
very complicated case for me to treat it.
-Exactly. This is the idea. I mean you take some chemicals in the body...they found out
ah, you want to have safe sex, you take the pill.
-Not only chemical. It is hormone. It is something very active for the organism.
-That is what I say. Hormones are deep chemicals which affect the organism tremendously.
It's not lightly that you advice a young girl,
just take the pill so you just have safe sex.
Because there are other ways to have safe sex after all. There are the condoms and there is no harm for anybody.
Why should the woman go into that state?
And then have children which are
born with cancer? Sterility?
This is the state which the whole of planet is going at the moment because we need easy solutions
and I'm not going to give you easy solutions.