I would like to ask you if anybody can tell me what it means when it says in the Repertory
hypochondriacal anxiety?
-There is a couple of references in the Repertory where it says I think hypochondriacal
anxiety is a kind of morose worry.
-Can anybody has an idea what is hypochondriacal anxiety, in practice what we see?
-A person who has a headache to say I'm having a heart attack...
-It's more the concern about the patient's health...
-It's over concern ...
-Everything you said it's correct and described it but I have here the manuscript of a
patient who gave it to the doctor, this is what I have and described beautifully what do we
mean by hypochondriacal anxiety.
I'm going to read you that paper which the patient gave and you are going to decide which
is the remedy. You look hypochondriacal anxiety, which are the remedies and then I leave
you that paper and then you tell me which is the remedy.
He starts saying in writing I have a tumor in my genitalia. He keeps on writing, later on
it proved to be a hernia.
He had an idea that this is a tumor, it was diagnosed as a hernia but still doesn't believe it.
He says I have a tumor. Where? Still the doctor may tell him "yes, this is a tumor".
He says I went to the doctor to some neurologist and he gave me Valium, Valium is a
tranquilizer. I went to another neurologist and he gave me Tryptizol 10 mg,
[drug name] and [drug name] for one and a half year. These are all neurological medicines.
Then I stopped these medicines gradually by myself and by the advice of the doctor.
I was very thin and I put on some weight. Advice of the doctor 72 kilos.
He means the advice of the doctor was that he should be 72 kilos. Now I'm 72.
I stopped taking the pills and from time to time I was taking [drug name] until now.
I do not have a sexual relationship with a woman and I said to myself that if I had a woman
I would stop taking the drugs. It happened that I had a relationship with a woman who was
married and I cut down the pills.
Stupid if I take them again. From 76 to 79 I was not taking any medicine.
During that period I met a woman who became my fiancé. No thought about marrying
her. Eventually start to have problems, difficulties. What are the difficulties?
I could not discover her character because she would speak very little and this...
I tried to let her go many times, underlined this and then I felt I regretted it and I could not
stay away because I felt sympathy for her and I came back to her because she looked
attracting to me.
Thoughts about marriage. Should I marry her or should I not?
Because of her character, because of her lack of a house, she didn't have a house,
because of her appearance, because of her class...
All these things are going inside, what about this, I have a tumor, shall I marry...
You understand what is going on eventually in the mind of that person, how much
confusion and how that is expressed through this anxiety about everything.
So it is not a hypochondriacal anxiety, it is not only centering around the health of the
person but it can center around everything.
All these thoughts together with some problems in the house, in my family lead me to take
again tranquilizers.
For quite some time afterwards I went to a neurologist, the symptoms were worry,
irritability, tendency to nausea, I could not eat, fixed ideas etc.
He gave me Tavor and afterwards by telephone he gave me Seroten 10 mg.
In the beginning I was doing well and then for one year, 1979-1980 I had problems with
the family. My parents do not want my fiancé, also thoughts that I may not satisfy her
sexually. He writes "quick seminal discharge" underlines it three times and
"not good erection"
This is what he writes himself, all this is exactly what he writes and how he writes it.
Small genitalia, at least I thought I had small genitalia, to divorce or not to divorce?
-He is not married yet.
-No, he is not married yet. To divorce means with his fiancé and the doctor who examined
him said his genitalia is quite normal, no problem.
Actually after one year of treatment this man got married, after we treated him.
One year afterwards he married finally.
Constriction of the throat, as a result tendency to vomit with the least emotion.
Because of too many thoughts and a fixed idea, should I divorce or should I not divorce
her. One person was telling me one thing and
another person was telling me another thing.
There came a kind of buzzing with my head, a constricted feeling and I had the impression
at that moment that my blood pressure was coming up.
Then there was a hit of the tongue and then I lose my memory.
I don't know anymore what I'm doing, life is becoming idiotic. It was very difficult to
overcome this crisis and many times I would call my sister to keep me company and then I
would relate to her my problems. She would understand me and the fears would go
away. The fear of being mad would go away, so slowly she calms me down and then I take
the Tavor and I go to sleep.
In the morning when I wake up I have spasms in the stomach since 1970 and the
intestines even in the fast as if I can...
Also if I see somebody else while I'm eating, I can not eat because I have a timidity, I can
not have somebody watching me while I'm eating.
As soon as I have an emotional shock my stomach becomes cramped I have nausea and
vertigo. I have to throw up everything and after throwing up I have problems with my
stomach which is painful because it is empty.
I start feeling that I'm not well because I'm not going to eat and I'm going to lose weight
and if I lose weight, then my nervous condition shall be very seriously sick and then I
become worse. I go to the doctor who gives me ... and finally by the time he is in the
allopathic, he takes 6 drugs says the doctor.
He has tremendous and unexpected reactions. I have vertigos as a kind of explosion,
tremendous worriness, I eat very little, almost nothing and I have great anxiety about my
future, I'm not going to stand it anymore and I'm going crazy, I'm going to have a brain
stroke. Tahycardias, arrhythmias, sleeplessness, the advice of the doctor: have patience.
That's the advice of the doctor.
By telephone the doctor gives him Stedon, I sleep and I become better, I become like a
chicken.
I didn't want to drink at all, I don't want anything, tremendous sleeplessness.
My father died and I had a whole change of situation, I had palpitation and trembling,
when I'm lying down and if I don't sleep I think I'm going to become sick and because of
that palpitation I feel that my heart is in my stomach.
Numbness of the head and a kind of tremor going through my head, some numbness on
the tongue. If I lie down and I don't sleep at night, I feel trembling of all my body and the
extremities and I had to stretch my body and I can not sleep. Perhaps I sleep a little.
Other symptom, as if I have spasm in hands and in the feet, some difficulty in
concentration with a certain book. I can not stand up or sit but I feel as if I want to move all
the time and would satisfy me if I move all the time, I go up and down, I don't want to stay
in the house but neither to go somewhere else. Nothing pleases me. I go there and
immediately I want to leave and go to another place. I don't know what I want.
When I see my fiancé I calm down for a while and if we go for a walk, it would be better.
I have a fear for new places, for instance they told me you go to England. I don't go. I'm
afraid of what shall I face there, how shall I eat since I can't eat in front of others and finally
if I go I shall die because I shall not be able to eat.
I have a kind of pessimism for everything that nothing exists but sickness, desperation,
that something is going to happen to me etc. Shall I never be well? Shall I go to a doctor or
shall I not? Is he going to give me a medicine or is he going to send me to hospital? Or
perhaps to the insane asylum? Or shall I have a brain stroke and 'finito'?
Finally he asks, does in my case perhaps there is a pathological background in my case?
Sexual pathology because my sperm is very little? If I take a medicine shall I be able to
have children?
I brought you that because you tend when you take a case like that, to say that's a
symptom you go and look it up, the next symptom you go and look it up, finally the whole
Materia Medica is jumping in front of your. You can forget it.
There are symptoms indicating remedies if you take them word by word.
The symptom which you take out of all this what in the Repertory is called hypochondriacal
anxiety. The hypochondriacal anxiety about everything.
If he can exist in London, can I go there, how can I eat, I'm going to have a heart attack,
I'm going to have a brain stroke, anything you can think of.
Now that case describes one remedy only and it is beautiful and the whole picture cleared
up and after a year he married. Can anybody tell me what is the remedy?
-Nitric acid.
-Nitric acid. Who agrees with Nitric acid?
-Another?
-Arsenicum.
-Who agrees with Arsenicum?
-Phosphorus.
Who agrees Phosphorus?
-Gratiola.
-Who agrees with Gratiola?
-Kali Arsenicum.
-Who agrees with Kali Arsenicum?
-Lycopodium.
-Who agrees with Lycopodium? Another?
-Lobelia.
-Who agrees with Lobelia? Nobody.
It is a difficult decision between perhaps Arsenicum and Phosphorus.
You are always concerned that I may be analyse two remedies and then I say take Thuja.
No, this is not the case. This is a choice between Arsenicum and Phosphorus.
There is something which can differentiate that this is not this and it is that between the
two remedies.
You are in favor of Phosphorus.
-...He never can focus, he seems to be everywhere.
-The hand writing is of Arsenicum.
-No, this is the hand writing of the person, he just said it to tape, I have translated in
English because it was not written in English, it was written in Greek. Actually it's a pity I
did not take the original, I could read on the spot here but she had missed some points
which were very interested.
-Did you say he is thirstless?
-I don't remember. Did I say that?
Arsenicum is thirsty also, basically it is a thirsty remedy like Phosphorus. They like to drink
a lot of water, cold water.
Sometimes of course Arsenicum wants warm water and warm food.
Great timidity.
In order to really understand him, what we want to understand is the real depth of his
character because we have some points in favor of Arsenicum and certain points in favor
of Phosphorus.
We want to go deeper as much as possible to differentiate between Arsenicum and
Phosphorus.
From the remedy pictures who has read Arsenicum from me? Phosphorus also? OK.
From what I said and from the impression which will come out as a person, who is more
composed?
-Arsenicum.
-Who is more diffused?
-Phosphorus.
-Who is more sympathetic and who is more hard?
You see real deep down there is an element of naivety, of sympathetic, of concerned for all
kinds of things but it is not this calculated. It comes out exactly the opposite, it is not
calculated, it is somebody who just lost himself, should I marry her, a grown up man asked
the first doctor, should I marry that girl? Imagine because I didn't see the person.
Arsenicum would never do that. And then I must telephone the sister...
How do you feel? I feel very badly. It's the sister, it's anybody.
Phosphorus can be pleased by anybody.
Arsenicum wants specific and he wants to know that this person knows what he is talking
about and he is not so much easily persuaded that there is nothing the matter.
I must be near my husband.
If you have really worked with these cases, with these characters, you will not make the
mistake but of course I have seen perhaps 10.000 cases of Phosphorus and another
10.000 of Arsenicum and that's why I can pick up elements easier.
I immediately prescribed Phosphorus, it's a matter of experience but do you see this?
Do you see the difference? Arsenicum is much harder, he will have that tremendous
anxiety, fear of death, fear about his disease, not so much concerned about the others,
should I marry, should I not marry? This does not arise so much for Arsenicum while for
Phosphorus, something is going to happen very strongly and another thing is, they say
fear of insanity in the Book.
Phosphorus and Arsenicum are both there and you know that the capital is Pulsatilla and
Calcarea and Mancinella and Cannabis indica.
Not everyone of these remedies will tell you I have a fear of insanity.
The remedy that will tell you most easily, that will express that is Pulsatilla and
Phosphorus.
Cannabis indica will never pronounce that word, you don't expect to get that expression,
fear of losing my brains. No.
They will go this way and that way to tell you that finally I want to have control.
Control of what? Of others and of myself.
I want to have control is the positive of I have a tremendous fear I may lose control.
What I don't want to say that I may lose control and they say I want control but to such a
tremendous extend that you translate it into fear of insanity.
Pulsatilla may say and Phosphorus.
Calcarea you try to get what is there. Tremendous anxiety and I just don't feel well.
Tell me. You have to tell her, do you have fear of insanity perhaps? She says yes.
It's a relief that you told her, you understood what was going on.
Mancinella will describe it as a stormy condition in the brain overtaken by situation where
the devils are concerned and the hell is concerned and what have I do, my life is this and
that and I'm going crazy. This is the idea because of the hell and of this and that.
It's not the first one will tell you. He will tell you all kinds of other descriptions and
psychological states which lead towards that portion and then you will have to take it down
and say yes. Do you have fear that you may lose your mind?
But almost except of Phosphorus, perhaps more the Pulsatilla, they will tell you straight
because they don't mind, they have contact, they can say anything, they will tell you
straight, it doesn't' matter for them. It is the kind of sympathy which they have for others,
they feel that others have for them. It's a state of mind where it is not protected from the
skepticism of others.
When somebody does not understand that the other person is thinking badly about him.
-Paranoia.
-No. He does not understand. You have the impression that if you say something bad, it
may be taken badly from the other person and he may interpret what you say and you
think that instead of this and you have all this in your mind and you don't say it.
This process does not exist in most of the Phosphorus cases.
They say it, no matter how you take it, he thinks you will take it rightly. He has no this
suspicion that you may misunderstand him.
'Ypopsia' is suspicion. He does not get suspicious about you, that you may be thinking
badly about him, that's why he is open, he will tell you I think I'm mad, I'm losing my mind,
he will not care whether you will go around and say he is losing his mind.
-Genuine.
-He is genuine, trusting where Arsenicum is not.
That element is very strong in him, he goes and says, tell me what to do, I must take this
and take that, do you think I have some pathology? OK I don't have.
This type of person is Phosphorus.
Some time ago somebody has asked me what is hypochondriacal anxiety and I tried to
describe it but when you try to describe it, it comes out ...
So you understand now what is hypochondriacal anxiety, what is meant when we go and
look in the Repertory for that symptom.