-...codependency and sex addiction. I was born into an alcoholic family system
and had an alcoholic father. I stopped smoking 10 years ago.
I have done my types of drugs ranging from LSD to marihuana.
I have been drug and alcohol free for 10 years. I have been sugar, flour
and wheat free for 5 years.
The last 2 years I seemed to get the flu easily and having a hard time getting rid of it.
My immune system does not seem to function as it used to.
My allergies seem to be worse than ever. I ache all the time around my joints.
If I sit for a while, I have a hard time getting up.
I don't want to go to bed at night and I don't want to get out of bed in the morning.
Why you don't want to go to bed at night? Because of over excitement?
-I just don't seem to go to sleep until I'm totally exhausted.
-I play my computer games for hours, I generally sleep about 8 hours at night.
I'm very sensitive to the chemicals, restaurants put on beef.
I think it is MSG and it gives me a case of running stool.
-What is this?
-Monosodium glutamate.
-I eat very little beef as it causes my anus to burn after I have a bow movement.
I have little interest in sex, isolate myself from others,
I'm usually in a hurry feel overwhelmed by life and depressed most of the time.
You have to have a really strong organism to survive all these kind of medicine
that he was given. I don't know.
The fact that he is in that condition, as we see him,
he looks in quite good condition is a miracle after all this.
That means he has put a lot of effort, a lot of will power this man to come to that condition
in which we see him today.
-After seeing the case yesterday I have a real fear that if I let go, I would be paralyzed
and cripple in a wheel chair, if I ever let go.
-You see what he says is very interesting "if I ever let go".
That means he goes on by sheer will power, he says another day, another day.
There is no enjoyment inside.
He will be very justified to take all kinds of drugs.
Because you find a drug, what is called "the trip" and he takes.
This life I can't live this kind of life.
Can you imagine inside him how he feels and what will power he needs to control all that?
And how the disturbance has progressed deeper and deeper.
He says the last 5 years he is constantly depressed. It's not his marriage.
What it has to do with his marriage? They destroyed his immune system and after that
he will feel all this kind of things.
In a case like that we have a very difficult case at hand.
There are two reasons. The one is that he does not give symptoms
on which we can base a prescription.
We do not have a clear case, as I said yesterday for the other case.
Here we do not have a clear case unfortunately.
Most probably it will be that we have to do a lot of work with him, very careful work.
He needs, in order to bring him around to health, he needs a lot of time and a lot of knowledge
from the homeopath to start with the right remedy and then continue in the right way
because one remedy will not do the trick.
We are going to have a series of remedies but the series of remedies
are going to be the first that is needed, the second that is needed
and then the third that is needed.
Of course with his history Medorrhinum was given and that was not a bad prescription.
From the first remedy that you were given, did you have any reaction you remember?
-The only reaction I remember from many remedies was one that I was given from my nose
to help the membranes inside my nose and if I would start with the allergies
and would start sneezing, if I would take this remedy, it would help stop sneezing.
-What was the remedy? Allium cepa?
-I think so yes. The rest I don't have any recollection. It's like...
-Having any effect.
-That's right.
-Scrotum and penis very sensitive almost hurts to touch. There is a pain or just sensitivity?
-My left testicle from the withered from the mumps it got big and then it shrunk.
-Now it is very sensitive?
-Yes.
-That means painful?
-Yes, sensitive and painful.
-But you have no problems, you have children.
-Yes, I have one testicle that works fine. I barely only need one.
-What I want to understand is you had excessive desire for sex and you lost that?
-Yes, it was actually compulsive. It was like an addiction but it's gone away.
Everything has gone away. It's really started going away with the drugs and the alcohol,
it was really the part of that.
-The drugs and the alcohol took it away?
-Right.
It was like having in an empty hall in the middle of your belly and the drugs and the alcohol
and sex and everything else was like filling up that hall but it only lasted
for a short period of time. Then you needed more.
I was really out of control with drugs and alcohol.
I was an alcoholic and drug addict and sex addict, all at the same time.
-As I say I wouldn't call it a miracle, I would call it a tremendous will power.
-I have a strong will.
All Canadians have.
-All Canadians have strong will?
-Yes.
-That's why you have a good country, organized, too organized I would say.
Your sleep is straight? That means you go to bed but you go late and then you sleep
until the morning or you wake up in between?
-Most of the time I wake up in between briefly.
Sometimes I have to go to the bathroom, I wake up.
-How many times you will wake up during the night?
-Two or three times.
I wake up when my body hurts. Like last night it was like a circle around my body
and the bottom of my rib cage woke me up because it hurt.
-Do you cover your feet or you like your feet out of the covers?
-Out of the covers most of the time.
-Because of that burning of the soles or because they are warm in general
or you do not know why?
-I just like to have at least one foot out. One foot in, one foot out.
-After he took the Medorrhinum, the incidence of herpes outbreak tremendously.
Before he took the Medorrhinum, he had it occasionally
and then after the Medorrhinum it happens more and more often and then after the Clematis,
the sensitivity in his penis and scrotum increased.
-OK thank you.
-Did you ever have any warts?
-No, I have some small little warts on my hand.
-Very flat. No, it's not there.
-How about skin tags?
-I have some skin tags under my arm.
-What I want to ask you is whether you cry easily?
-No. I cry much easier now than I used to but...
-But still not easy.
-I still control it.
-In your house, in your things are you organized? You put everything in order?
-I think I'm organized but I'm messy. I know where everything is if nobody touches it
but it's not neat.
-It's not neat.
-No.
My wife on the other hand is very neat.
-So there is complementary.
-I have a room where I can be messy and she has the rest of the house to be neat.
-That's better. It's good arrangement.
You see the palms are burning. Is it heat or is it burning pain?
-Like burning pain and it's worse if I have herpes outbreak.
My hands also feel swollen, especially if I use my hands like if I dig a hole,
just the least minor work. I used to work with tools but not anymore.
-Did you ever have any laboratory tests made? Blood test?
-Not recently. They always show normal. Everything shows normal.
-Liver test you have done?
-I think I had some.
I don't remember why, with the blood test a few years ago but I think everything showed normal,
cholesterol. They found it was an oriental...
-You like to put some questions?
-What is your response to temperature, hot or cold? I understand that you live in Canada?
-No in Florida now. I don't like the heat so much, I don't like the humidity
because I've been in Florida, I can feel the cold up here but I don't really mind the cold,
I enjoy it.
I really don't like humidity.
-Could you tell me your reactions to be indoors and outdoors to air in general?
How do you feel for example when you are indoors or you are in a room
and the windows are not open?
-I don't feel restricted. It feels fine.
-And if you go outdoors in the open air, how does that affect you?
-I like it as long as it is not humid. I like it being outside.
-Looking for aggravations, for low energy, sleepiness or hunger during the day?
-That's been changeable. Lately I seem to have fairly consistent low energy all the time.
I used to have spikes and then valleys but lately it just seems to be
just a general level of enough energy to do what I have to do.
-Do you have any hard time to stand up for a long time?
-Yes.
-In which sense? What is wrong if you stand up?
-My knees hurt, my feet hurt, my back starts to hurt, I have to move around.
I just can't stand on one spot and I can't sit on one spot either.
-How is the time passing for you? Do you think the time is passing fast or slow?
-Fast, very fast.
-Any problem with trembling?
-No.
-Does the humidity affect your joints as well?
-I don't know if the humidity affects my joints but it affects my lungs.
My joints hurt all the time and I don't have any... Of course is humid all the time in Florida also.
-You said that you wake up in the evening. Is there any particular time that you wake up?
-I don't really look at the clock, I don't know if there is a particular time.
-I'd like to ask two questions. One about the bump on you head and the other one is regarding,
you said you are affected by damp can you tell me if it's warm damp or cold damp?
-There is no cold damp in Florida. So it would have warm damp.
-The bump?
-The bump on my head I don't know what it is.
I had acupuncture treatments for a long time to make it go away. When I was 4 years old,
I got hit with the baseball and it sort like dazed me and I went home, crawled home, whatever...
I think the bump is ever since. It's a funny bump, it's like an egg.
-Is it painful?
-No, it's not painful.
-You have a growth on your right face like a mob, did you always have that?
-Yes, I have another one at my leg just like that.
-Could you tell us how do you feel to the suffering of other people?
-I have a great deal of empathy to the people who are suffering.
-What do you do? Do you do help if you see somebody...?
-Yes, as a matter of fact I'm in graduate school,
I'm working on a Master's Degree of social work.
-Could you tell me about the nature of your discharges? What color are they, thickness?
-I don't have any discharges now but when I had,
the time when I had gonorrhea... are you talking about... from the nasal...?
It depends if I'm having a flu is very clear or sometimes my nose just runs like clear water
and then if it gets thicker, then it gets like milky white
and then if I'm really sick it gets yellow.
So it varies.
-Are your hands dry or just normal?
-I'm a salesman for a living and one of the things I've learned to do is to control my hands,
whether I'm nervous or not, they are usually dry.
-Are too dry sometimes like really rough?
-No I wouldn't say that. They are little moist right now.
-I have two questions. How is your thirst?
-I'm not very thirsty.
-When you do drink, what temperature drinks do you prefer?
-Cold.
-Can you tell us about what fears do you have?
-You name it and I'm afraid of it.
-Could you be a little more specific? Give us some example?
-I have a fear of success and a fear of failure at the same time, I have fear of abandonment,
I have some fear of people...
I began not to trust people in the last few years, especially in business,
I have fear that I will not get well, I have a fear that I'm just going to wither away.
Sometimes I feel like, I don't know if you read Gulliver's travels
but when the little [?] going to the ground with the needles and threads, I feel like that,
that I'm stuck, that I'm not going to get out, that I'm not going to break out of this.
-Your food likes and dislikes?
-I don't likes vegetables very much, I like starch,
I don't particularly care for starchy vegetables, I do like potatoes but not some of the other ones.
-Is there anything that you hated before but you like it now?
-I hated salad before but I can tolerate it now. I eat a lot salad out of the knowledge
that I need to put vegetables in my system, not because I like the taste.
-Did you like something before but you hated now?
-Not that I can think of.
-How do you feel if someone shows you sympathy?
-It can bring tears to my eyes if someone shows me sympathy or shows someone else sympathy,
when I'm around. It's an emotional experience for me.
-Do you tend to be philosophical?
-Yes.
-Could you tell me a bit more about that?
-One of the things I have done is intellectualize my entire life, I supposed to emotionalize it,
it's just been the last two years that I began to even feel feelings.
Prior to being in therapy I only thought feelings, I would come to intellectual understanding
of appropriate emotional response and then model it.
I supposed to actually generating a feeling from within myself.
I do now have feelings. I feel like human being.
-Are your eyes bothered by light?
-I wear sun glasses all the time, there is a lot of sun in Florida. I don't like bright light.
I'm also going blind in the dark.
-Can you imagine an area in sciatica where herpes outbreaks?
-Yes sciatica generally precedes herpes....
-Where is the sciatica?
-Down on the right side, in the back from my hip because down my foot...
-Numbness, tinglings are the sensation?
-Just burning.
-When you were talking about your fears, how do you feel about heights?
-I'm afraid of heights but the reason I'm afraid of heights is because of my job sometimes
I have to go up in the air, in a tall building. And if I'm out in the balcony,
I have a tendency to jump.
-Are you afraid of spiders?
-Probably I'll kill them if I see them.
-Do you have any crack skin in your body and do you have any problem with your finger joints?
-Yes, my thumb joint hurts, my little finger on my right hand joint hurts.
The rest of the joints are OK. A cracking skin, I don't have any cracking skin.
-Have you been successful in your business?
-Failure.
-The history in your family, your parents were sick, well, they are living,
what disease did they have?
-My paternal grand mother died from heart attack at age 55,
my paternal grand father lived to be 90, my maternal grand mother and grand father
both lived to be 90.
My maternal grand father was gassed in the world war one and survived it,
he also was a Canadian veteran.
My maternal grand father was unhealthy but he lived through everything.
My grand mother never really got sick, she just put up with it.
My father died at age 55 with a heart attack, my mother is still alive and in her 70's
she had urinary cancer, total hysterectomy and had her one breast removed.
I think when my paternal grand father was about 89, he developed diabetes before he died
and it was just part of being old.
-How does water affects you? Itching your skin?
-It cools it off but it doesn't take the itching away.
-I will ask one more question and then we stop.
Such cases have a lot of symptomatology, tremendous lot of symptomatology
because the whole system is suffering, so whatever system is suffering, the eyes, the nose,
the mouth, the body, the extremities, the whole system is suffering so it presents symptoms
from all systems.
The idea with this case is to find where is the focus, homeopathically wise.
Not the focus in his pathology because there is no actually focus in his pathology.
You can not say the focus is the eyes or the nose or the stomach or the sciatica
or the depression.
So you ask all these questions, so you are now satisfied, you have all the information.
Now process it.
In this case, what is your process assess?
I will ask one more question. What is the question I'm going to ask?
Somebody is maybe clairvoyant from the audience.
I ask whether he is critical towards others? Are you a critical person?
-Yes, I'm very judgmental.
-Thank you.
Here we have, as I said, we have a lot of symptoms, it is a confused case,
not only because of several homeopathic remedies that he had
but also because systems like that, systems that are deteriorated in their immune system,
his immune system has suffered a lot, usually they do not give clear cut pictures.
Where shall we start? Yet there is one remedy that will give the optimum result,
not will cure, it will give the optimum result.
And we are trying, this is our objective now, to find the remedy
that will give optimum result for him. What is optimum results?
Optimum results will be a remedy that will set his organism in better condition
so that the next symptomatology that will bring about, will more clear.
This is my objective with this case.
When he started can you give me the symptoms, as he related them?
Heat of hands and foot, twitching on the inguinal region and loathing of life.
These were 4 symptoms, the first 4 symptoms that he related.
And then he related some more symptoms, give me the second step.
Already with this information, my mind was settled. This is the remedy,
not because of the 4 symptoms alone but for some other reasons that I will explain to you.
He said food and drinks, sugar aggravates, farinaceous food aggravate,
after vaccination symptoms and suppressed gonorrhea.
Then he related some more symptoms, just to remind us.
Genitalia sensitiveness, heat in the foot, uncovers them, burning in the palms,
standing aggravates and time passes too quickly.
These are some of the symptoms.
Give some more.
Suicidal disposition, ability for philosophy, loss of vision and censorious.
What's the remedy?
-Thuja.
-Carcinosin.
-Agaricus.
-Nux vomica.
-Nat. Sulphuricum.
-Pulsatilla.
-I only vacillated one time and the only remedy which I considered except from the one
that I will tell you is Natrum Sulphuricum.
The reason for that is his depression and also the injury to the head from the ball,
though there is no connection between depression and the injury to the head
because the injury was done when he was very young.
Also the aggravation from farinaceous food which is strong with the Nat. Sulphuricum.
The Natrums are aggravated by farinaceous and the Pulsatilla
also is aggravated very much by farinaceous food, flour.
Vacillated but only for a second and then I said, no.
The reason is that we have a better choice. What is the better choice? Show me.
Sulphur is the better choice for many reasons that we will see.
Can you show me Sulphur how much of his symptomatology is covering?
All the symptoms?
Foot twitching, loathing, drinks, farinaceous food aggravates, vaccination,
gonorrhea suppressed, let's see more.
Philosophy, loss of vision, censorious, critical...
So Sulphur it covers, it's not a choice arbitrary which I thought in the beginning
when you have a confused case in order to de-confuse it, in order to clarify, in order...
You are allowed to give Sulphur. Here we have a confused case that has a lot of
symptoms from Sulphur, therefore you are justified absolutely to go to Sulphur.
Very simple remedy but it has not been given so far.
But it may put the organism into a better condition,
so we may eventually see another remedy appearing.
You know the circle, Sulphur, Calcarea, Lycopodium.
It may go into that circle of remedies that eventually his body
will be more and more organized and balanced.
Apart from that, you remember when I read you the paper, on the food it says craves fat,
sugar but makes him angry, sugar makes him angry.
You remember somebody asked about standing, I did not want to make it
too obvious for you asking all the questions for Sulphur but somebody asked
because he was thinking of Sulphur also and he said exactly how Sulphur moves around.
He can not stand.
Put a Sulphur to stand in a chair especially, they can not.
What about the Aurum? Aurum also is a possibility.
He said when I am in a high place, I think of jumping and this reminded us of Aurum
in spite of the fact that he has been in such turmoil with his health,
he never attended suicide so far.
And he said, suicide no.
If that was a case of Aurum, he would have said, yes I thought a lot of times
of killing myself.
With this case I would suggest now to start with Sulphur.
What potency would you give to him, considering you remember what I told you about his wife,
that she had a sensitive organism again, she was abused by allopathic drugs
and we started very low.
What about his case?
-High potency.
-How high?
-I give him 1M, he is so strong.
-I think we should start no more than 12C.
-200.
-I would be very conservative and I would give him 30 and then repeat.
-Who is in favor of 12C? Who is in favor of 30? Of 200? Of 1M? Nobody.
It is interesting it started with 30, 40 people in favor of 12, 42 in favor of 30, 18
in favor of 200, one in favor...
So the majority, I will go with the majority.
No. In this case we can start with 200. He comes with a very strong constitutional organism.
This man like the AIDS people is very strong and he was abused with medicines and drugs
and that's why he has become like that.
His ancestors 90, 92. He is born with a constitution which is strong, he abused
that constitution but still the initial strength with which we are born it stays basically.
Therefore there is no fear to give 200 or 1M. So I will start with 200
and in case it gives no effect, then I will go low, 12X and I will give for a period of time.
But I believe the 200 will give some reaction and then some effect where he will feel better
for some time and then he will start again developing some symptomatology
and then I will judge.
I will pass judgment whether he will need a repetition or he may go into another remedy.
-How come when there is no effect of 200 to go lower instead of going higher?
-This I said it, you are right. When I prescribe a remedy, I prescribe it for good reasons.
If a potency does not give me the results which I expect, I will say maybe another potency.
His organism is in the frequency of another potency.
So if I give high, I will try low, if I give low, I will give high.
I do not give up what I have thought so long and so methodically to say it doesn't work,
I will give another remedy.
-How long you wait for one dose of Sulphur 200 before you give another one?
-One month, at least one month. In his case being particular,
the evaluation should be done within three months.
For three months definitely we should let him stay with that remedy
and in the end of three months you can evaluate whether the remedy has acted
and how it has acted.
It's not so common.
Why I was not impressed? Because it's not such uncommon thing.
The twitching is more but, as I said, in the beginning of his case
there is nothing in particular that had impressed me because when you have a patient like that
where he gives a lot of symptoms,
he can give anything. His organism can give all kind of symptoms.
It's not an organized whole where it gives these, some of the symptoms.
His organism is so upset inside that any little aggressiveness from the outside,
the dust, the food, the organism is intolerable. It can not tolerate.
Unfortunately I don't know when shall we understand these things in Medicine
and stop doing them.
They vaccinate such huge numbers and they keep on vaccinating and pushing the chronic diseases
more and more inside and bringing out more and more chronic conditions.
Where the fear of small pox I don't think there is a possibility for the Western population
to get small pox because the organisms are too sick to get small pox anymore.
So small pox is out by itself. Who from us gets small pox? Nobody.
If there are some healthy ones here and there, they may get small pox.
-It seems difficult choice between Sulphur and Natrum Sulphuricum.
I see that there are a lot of Natrum Sulphuricum symptoms suppressed,
aggravation by humidity and a lot of other things. And because [bad sound]
-There is the element of Sulphur and the element of Natrum which in his case,
as I said in the beginning, it was the only remedy that I vacillated.
Because they were some symptoms.
I would have considered it more in case his depression was directly connected
to the injury to the head.
If that was the case, you might have seen me, even with this kind of symptomatology to say,
we have to go to Nat Sulphuricum.
But there are some symptoms of Sulphur with him, especially worse standing, critical,
working with his mind a lot and burning feet, desires fat, sugar.
You have a lot of Sulphur symptoms that you can not ignore, you have a confused case,
so it fits you to give and you do not have...
As a second possibility, as I said, I will go to Natrum Sulphuricum.
-...to whatever he touches is a kind of characteristic of Sulphur mind?
Do you think is important for you to decide for Sulphur?
Like Sulphur would smoke too much, drink too much, take whatever he likes too much.
-Not really.