The father was out of control completely. The child, 4 years old, the same night urination.
Since I had seen the scene I gave Aconite.
It took me 6 months before I understood that that was much deeper situation.
Because with Aconite a few days better and then worse and then again Aconite.
You know this story, better, better and then back again.
Then after 6 months you say that case is quite serious. Then I went to see the family.
This one, I'm talking about, was one of those who attacked me.
He was strong, he hits me. Then immediately comes another picture.
The parents, what a sweet child. They forget that sometimes it breaks the head of some fellow.
What about he broke 3 heads already? Oh, that was an accident, the child is sweet.
Until I saw the child. Is he behaving like this? Yes, many times we don't understand why.
The aggression that comes up. Aconite does not have this aggression but you don't know.
Like you give Arnica, it falls down you give Arnica and many times it's not Arnica,
it's not working, it's Sulphuric acid, much more difficult to find.
Are you interested in this?
Because we try to satisfy the pediatricians a little bit but you also can see children. Be patient.
-He is more attached to you, than his father?
-Yes.
He is afraid of his father, he loses every control and then he stutters and...
He starts.
He just wanted to bite his mother.
-Do you like your mother to hit you?
-Yes.
-Your mother also hits you?
-Would you like that?
-Yes.
-If your mother hits you, you like it?
-He likes it but I don't.
-You never hit him.
It is coming.
-What does he say?
-Come and take the bread.
-Your bread is eaten by the cat. You take another bread.
Sit down there.
This is very difficult to show the aggression of Stramonium
because you will have to catch a child during crisis and that I don't know
if I will ever be able to do it, so you can see clearly what it happens but it's frightful.
You see that there is no logic, logic is gone.
The child is hitting, is biting, is afraid of the dark, is afraid of deep water,
he is sweet, affectionate and that's a Stramonium child. Typical Stramonium child.
Whatever is a surface which you can not see the depth, you can not see through,
it's a kind of surface but black, what reminds the individual, it reminds him of some
of the subconscious, the darkness in the subconscious.
There is a sense of something dark overtaking them, something which has no control,
it is not clear, they can not describe it and say, this anger overtook me and then I did it.
That lake reminds them or that subconscious, whatever brings in their mind
the anger of the subconscious. The Stramonium has an anger which has stayed inside.
When they see that depicted in any picture outside, that brings up a correspondence,
bring up a kind of reaction like they will have a reaction,
they will be terrified if they see a dog barking. This is what is inside, it's the same thing.
That reminds me of something terrible has happened here. The subconscious is coming,
the fear is coming now.
That fear is inside. We project. What do you think we do?
All the time we project the fears.
You enter the room and you hear a noise and you saw the robber already, he is there and he is gone.
It was my imagination.
Stramonium also is afraid of water per se.
That means if water comes over them, take these children and put them on shower,
not all the Stramonium but many, they can not breathe, it seems that a film is falling,
they feel that they can not breathe and will go into fits, they jump out of the water, they can not.
They are terrified, fear of water, fear of shiny. That's why they break the glasses mostly.
Stramonium is one of the remedies that breaks glasses mostly.
When you have a mad person in the house, they know and they have covered all the glasses,
all the mirrors. The person Stramonium will break them when it comes to a fit.
Fear of being injured?
They can yes. I can't remember now whether I have seen it but it doesn't matter
whether I remember it or not. They may have a fear, tremendous fear that they can be injured.
Very pathological fear that anything can injure them, that they may have an accident,
you may hit them, you may touch them.
That's not as simple as that. It might be a Stramonium.
It has to be a Stramonium case before it's helped. The Stramonium first of all
they will not be able to go into waters which are not clear, which they don't see the bottom,
they can not do it, they will avoid it.
If they can see it is clear, there is no so much fear,
the fear is when they see from outside a lake, a well. You know the well is always dark.
That is causing fear. You must get the idea.
They are mischievous.
These children have certain characteristics like fear of the dark, fear of in general
and the most is that Tuberculinum is not so aggressive, so violent as Stramonium.
Tuberculinum will break things, Stramonium also will break things
but Tuberculinum will break things, something he didn't like.
If you have a Tuberculinum child and you have this kind of dress that you like,
they will go and cut it because you like it and they can do things like that
which is more under control and more devious.
What you have to remember to these children, they are all very taken by a subconscious,
which is full of anger and full of irritability but overtaken, it's a state.
-What about Belladonna type children?
-I don't know.
Belladonna is different all together. The violence of Belladonna is...
First of all it will be very difficult to find Belladonna constitutional child with violence.
What you see in Belladonna mostly is violence during high fever, instead of having convulsions,
we see the violence of Belladonna.
Stramonium is indicated in all kinds of fevers from pneumonias and bronchitis to
meningitis, meningoencephalitis, to typhus.
Typhus, you can not see very much typhus. Has anybody seen typhus? You have seen.
-In hospital.
-Yes.
-Not very severe.
-So some of them can go to Stramonium cases where they really become violent,
they shout, they cry, they have convulsions.
That is where you see Belladonna mostly and you see the violence of Belladonna
where they might bite others, they get up from bed, they are in a state mostly of delusions,
delusional state where they seem to fight with imaginary phantoms.
Many times they have this peculiarity, they go and try to climb a wall.
They go here and they will try to climb, it's an aggressive thing to see.
I have seen it once and it's quite aggressive because it's fighting to climb this wall,
scratching with, putting his feet up.
-He curses but not very often.
-With grown ups also?
-Yes, shut up, go away and say very bad words.
-He hits grown ups and he tells bad words, he curses. What else he will do?
-Does he talk a lot?
-Very much.
-Loquacity, talks a lot.
-He can talk the whole day.
-It's also another thing that I noticed, I don't remember if this child has it
is that they are sexually very aware.
You will see this child pinching women, pinching the buttock of a woman, grasp her breast,
it's quite aggressive and quite overtly. They are not shy.
And I have seen in another child, he was sitting in the consultation room with his brother.
He was pinching his brother bottom and his father says, what are you doing there?
I'm pinching his bottom, he says which premature sexual awareness, quite strongly.
Some they recognize themselves when they were young.
Don't go and take Stramonium because it is difficult for one to judge about himself.
-From now you will be a good boy.
Give the follow up to see if he became a good boy.
That was 3 years ago. Most probably it was 10M or 1M.
It is the follow up. Do we have the date?
February '87. That is September '86, about 6 months later.
-...and also without light.
-He had nightmares?
-Yes, he has also nightmares. But not crying in the night because he knew I was there.
-Do you see any difference?
-He had myopia in his right eye, -10 and one eye doctor and he can see only 5%.
-He can see only 5%. So little?
-So little and this has caused him problems.
-He took Stramonium?
-Yes, we came back, it was beginning of October '86 and he took 3 potencies,
1M, 10M and 50M Stramonium and in the first time I could not see change
but later he get to start to be softer and these aggressions he has, they are better.
He has situations sometimes, where he can throw a knife to his brother if he is angry
but it is not so often.
With enuresis it is the same, there is no change and the reduced eye it is also the same,
he has now a contact lense in his eye but he gets problems with this because he gets
purulent activity sometimes. He had to give him also antibiotic in the eye
because it was so bad the cornea was also with ulcers, it became ulcerative...
-The enuresis is every night?
-Every night, I wake him up about 11 o'clock but in the morning he is usually wet.
I see the connection with sweet  juices and sweet drinks.
-If he drinks sweet, oranges and things like that?
-If he drinks mixed things, it is fantastic, in 5 minutes it goes away
and if it is in the night he can't hold it.
It was a period about 2 weeks a little bit better but I took him in the night
and in the morning he was dry.
-Why you stopped doing that?
-I do it.
-When it was these 14 days dry? It was in the beginning or after the medicine?
-About 2 weeks ago, after the medicine.
-Then the pattern came back as it was before or perhaps he was urinating twice
before the remedy and now once in a night?
-It was a little bit worse and now it is going to get better.
He is not wet like before he took the Stramonium.
-Did he get any other acute during this time? Any cold?
-No. He had no problems, only with his eye.
-How it was his appetite?
-He likes sweets and he doesn't like vegetables and if he gets sweets, sweet bread
and marmalade, then he likes it. In the last time he ate also salty things.
-He started to like salty things?
-Yes, primarily he had something salty to put on the bread and he took it.
It's a salty pasta.
-And he likes it now?
-Yes, he eats it in the morning but he eats raisins and bread, this bread with butter
and the salty thing. Sweet and salty together.
-What about his sleep? He sleeps quietly or he is very restless or very aggressive he shouts?
-No, he is quiet in the night. Once it was a time he doesn't want to go alone in dark rooms.
He doesn't want to go in the toilet. I had to go and switch on the light
because he would say, I don't go, it is dark there.
-But that was better.
-No, the last two weeks it is better but it was a time it was not possible to tell him
to go in a dark room and I had to go for him and switch the light on.
-Before did he use to get any acutes, like chest acutes? Any bronchitis, cough?
-No, he had nothing.
-Before Stramonium.
-Also nothing. He had one bronchitis in his life.
-Never again.
-Never.
-He is strong otherwise, only personality problems.
-Yes and the last year he could not hear well. He had a big adenoid and it was...
It went like this. It was a long time that he could not hear.
-When it was the time that he could not hear?
-Last winter, 85.
-His right eye is affected?
-Yes.
If he gets nervous, he wants to go to toilet, more times.
-If he get anxious?
-Yes and nervous.
-And his stool is diarrheic?
-Only if he drinks milk but he doesn't like milk.
He has a very... carries in teeth. The first teeth are very bad.
-But he has become sweet now?
-A little bit soft but only a little bit.
-Still he is aggressive?
-Sometimes but we can manage.
-What he says about his right eye? If he closed the left one, what he will say
that it is foggy or he cannot see at all?
-We made this test and we see that he can't see enough
but we have problems to put occlusion on the left eye because he doesn't want
and he put the occlusion away and we have to look for them, the glasses are away.
He hides them, he doesn't want to have all these things but when he has them on,
it is very astonishing how he manages.
When it's closed the right eye or he has to use it, he never falls or run against the wall.
-We try to put him on the ski and it was OK but if we make the normal eye test,
they see that he has only 5% of seeing.
-There is improvement with his eyes?
-No improvement.
For 2 months they closed the left eye and to let him look with the right eye
and it is the last year now because if this myopia doesn't go better,
in the 7th year it is like this and it stays. You have to take it like this.
-How long is now that he goes into the dark room, the last 2 weeks you said?
-About a month it was like this and now about 2 weeks he goes, the last weeks are better.
-He starts going.
-No, it is not a problem. They don't see it like this, they don't mention it,
I have to go every morning.
-But something that disappeared was the stammering.
-Yes the stammering. It was away.
-Thank you.
So what you will do? What remedy? The remedy has acted?
-Yes.
-You are not very convinced. This is where every homeopath goes wrong.
In any other case like that and you see improvement on the mental-emotional
that you are treating and you see improvement on stammering, you cannot say get remedy
because you are going to spoil the case.
Unless the child gets some antidotal influences, it will go better and better and better
and the child was already very much better. What we see here is 50% better.
What you have to understand is that these things do not just disappear like that,
do not raise the dead. He is a magician. We are not magicians.
There is pathology which has to follow a certain path.
The deeper it is, the longer it has to take before the cure is established.
In this case of enuresis, if you see a mental symptom going away, would you wait,
you would suppose that the remedy has acted and wait for the enuresis? I said yes.
Do you remember a case, a boy with enuresis, with personality problems and with asthma?
Some of you have seen, you have not seen the whole thing
but in this case we have the same idea.
Enuresis continued for another few months. The boy was 11 years old when we saw it,
with severe enuresis every day and it continued for several period of time
until the level of amelioration arrived at that point.
The amelioration had started from the inside. As soon as he comes in, if you don't see,
if you don't realize that the child is 50% better, you are not yet a student of Homeopathy,
not a homeopath, a student of Homeopathy.
You have to observe immediately the changes that took place and the changes
that took place emotionally are depicted upon the person.
You don't wait for them to tell you little things.
So I have seen outrageous things like for instance a patient is doing very well
and the doctor come in and says how are you? And he says, I have a sore throat
and I got headaches.
Yesterday I had headaches and you write sore throat, headaches and my pains are these and that
and I was very irritable with my wife. You write 3 pages of symptoms and you say now what?
The thing is why the patient had come originally to you?
And if he had come because he had depression and now he has all these symptoms,
it doesn't matter all these symptoms.
The person is doing well, there are certain rules of course
and unless a clear cut remedy is indicated now, you do not touch the case.
All the symptomatology will go away. Unless you understand that, you are not doing Homeopathy.
You are doing allopathic medicine.
Take this for that symptom, take that for that symptom, forget it.
I hope to be able to show you a case since 2 years, a case of encephalomyelitis,
exhaustion, exhaustion and all these kind of things.
And to be able to show you follow ups and to see the person in the end
and say if it is better or it is the same.
But if you see the written follow ups and what he says, you think he is not doing well.
I said no, placebo, placebo until you see the real miracle or you will never see a miracle
or you will see it for a very short period of time and then forget about it,
the whole thing will come back.
If you don't stick to the principles, forget it.
If you are not aware of what is going on in a person before even speaks,
it's very difficult to practice Homeopathy.
I have explained this so many times that anybody in the class can give you the explanation.
-What happens if you repeat now 1M?
-Terrible mistake.
I would consider a period of aggravation.
First of all the aggravation in these children, you may see for 1-2 days they are more aggressive
but maybe the parents will not take notice of that, they will not mention it.
It doesn't mean it doesn't exist. There is definitely an aggravation in the dark.
He was afraid of the dark but perhaps not so much for the whole month.
Things are coming in order. Where is aggression and where is fear of dark?
What is more important for the organism to fix first, aggression or fear of the dark?
It decides. The organism says fix first aggression and then comes the fear of the dark
and then comes the stomach and then comes the enuresis.
There is a sequence of events which take place inside and you can not force
another course of action.
This is the only course of action that you can take, give the remedy, watch and wait.
How is the right eye now?
- ...so often that it would disturb the child...
-The father says there is no problem with the vision but he has not examined...
In times we may have that feedback of that portion.
What you would expect an improvement of the eye of an order of 60%?
-Carries
-Can you tell us about carries in the teeth?
-No problem.
-The aggressiveness, as the father says, there is no problem.
But you see the child so much better, why you ask all these questions?
I have not asked all these questions, I can see it immediately,
there is an intensity which is gone. It's tremendous.
The remedy has acted, this is the main thing, just wait and you will see the changes.
Be unbelievers, do not believe anything until you see, not one time, 20 times
but when you see 20 times that's enough. Sit down and study, sit down and learn.
Once you understand you have given the right remedy, you wait and wait and wait
and you will see things falling into the right place.
The child came for three things, enuresis, aggression and his eye problem.
When everyone is going to be arranged we do not know, what we want to know
is whether the remedy is acting, you must understand immediately.
Even after 2-3 weeks, you understand whether your remedy has acted and don't touch it.
It is terrible to spoil a good action of a remedy
because you will never come back in that remedy again.
We gave Stramonium and it didn't work, now we give Hyoscyamus, we give Belladonna
and you will go through the whole Materia Medica and you will never see of course the remedy
because the remedy is Stramonium.