I want to give you a case and the follow up of the case, so I can show you a point which I
have said in my teachings frequently.
This is a woman 50 years old and she is suffering with varicose veins and some kind of
disturbance, a kind of colitis.
She says that she has pain in the right leg on the calf and behind the knee and
in the knee as well and in the knee also. So there is some pain in the calf,
pain in the knee and she cannot flex it.
She has varicose veins in both legs and these are worse standing and with stitching pains.
The pain in the knee is better walking.
She takes Brufen 400 ml; this anti-inflammatory drug that she takes, makes very little
difference.
She is wearing this orthopedic kind of shocks for the phlebitis, for the varicose veins and
because her work is mostly standing, she is working on a coffee shop...
She has bloatedness in the abdomen in the evening hours, the bloatedness is underlined
twice and worse after exertion.
She takes Tavor and she is generally worse after exertion. Exertion makes her much
worse, underlined twice.
She has anxiety in her work because she has to deal with a lot of people and she has
anxiety about her children and she is impatient.
She has right hemicrania, right type of headaches and mostly on the right temple.
Together with the headaches she has a inner trembling, loses her color and she feels very
much weak and she has to lie down at least two hours.
She takes [drug name] it is a major painkiller with caffeine inside and
after she's recovered from the headache, she remains in a state of exhaustion for many hours.
Constipated, sometimes she has to take laxative, small laxative, it's not a big constipation.
The blood pressure comes up to 170 and she takes this tranquillizer and brings the
pressure down.
Do you have any idea about the remedy? Do you have any indication what is the remedy
and for what reason?
I give you the symptoms. It is a person suffering from arthritis of the knee, from phlebitis,
from varicose veins and headaches, she is worse definitely with exertion.
Calcarea is the right thing to think under this symptomatology, wakes up refreshed most of
the time...
If she has high blood pressure, she noticed that she has burning in the eyes.
She had all the children diseases, she had tonsillectomy at the age of 20, she has an
appendix the same age.
She never suffers with any allergy or any skin eruption.
The father died from brain stroke and the mother died from brain stroke.
She perspires only during summer.
She says in order to drink water, she wants it a little bit sweet the water, therefore she
adds some orange, sweet  juice orange and she has a big thirst and drinks quite a lot.
She has a lot of urination, copious urination, immediately after drinking water.
She said I never cry in front of people, I go and hide myself to cry, sighing, she has a
flabby stomach and abdomen and she is wearing a kind of girdle.
Nails are good, she says she is a closed person, not underlined, she is rather optimistic,
easily offended, underlined once and she says she is worse in Autumn time, generally she
feels very much the cold.
Generally worse cold, underlined two times but the feet are always in good condition,
rather warm and in spring time she had to take them out but not in the winter.
She used to have a lot of cramps in the night, generally better in summer time and better
with the sun and better with Tavor, this anti-anxiety remedy.
She is easily disgusted but not underlined.
Desires, she has an aversion to fat only and she has a desire for milk, underlined twice,
fruits, underlined twice, she eats a lot of fruits, she does not like sweets at all unless it is
homemade.
And she has a desire for soft boiled eggs, underlined three times.
That's interesting for the follow up, I know it's not interesting the case for you.
Who knows the remedy?
The obvious remedy is the correct remedy here, don't be afraid.
Because I'm bringing all difficult cases here and you say it can't be so easy.
It is Calcarea carbonica. So Calcarea carbonica 1M was given to this woman and she
never came back for the follow up. She only came back five months later when she used
an expression with 'your medicine I flied'. There is an expression, if you feel very well,
you say 'I fly' meaning I was very well. She used this typical expression to show how well
she felt.
It stopped the anxiety she says, no anxiety, I was flying and I was absolutely well, no
distention, no dysphoria, everything was perfect, no drug and she took only one medicine.
She said that there was a great grief in her house. She does not rely actually what has
happened but she says that she was except of the grieves, which is one part, she does not
say what was the grief, she also had a quarrel with her husband and further problems with
her children, she does not relate what it is.
So she says I have again sighing, I can not take enough air inside me, it's very difficult to
breathe and I had to take tranquilizers again.
There are some stitching pains in the sole of the feet, I feel psychologically tired and I'm
irritable and I can not take up anything. I forget easily and I had too many things to do, she
didn't have the headaches also but now she says again I have anxiety.
So there is anxiety, there is psychological tiredness, she is not feeling well and she has
this syndrome of not being able to breathe.
In that case I would like to tell me what you will do?
You have a Calcarea carbonica which acted beautifully. It took away the pains from the
legs, the varicose veins and she had a grief and she comes back with that syndrome, the
anxiety, the irritability, the tiredness and the difficult respiration.
She was doing perfectly well but she says I had a great grief and I had a quarrel with my
husband and I had problems with my children and all this together brought about that
stage which she describes.
My question is what do we do? We have several possibilities. First question, is this a relapse?
It is not a relapse, it's a partial relapse.
What is that now colors the case? What is the patient she said I had that grief and then I
sigh, I can not take a big breath, I can not still be satisfied with the breath.
That is... she says that when she came for the first time?
-No.
-So we have a Calcarea case which did very well and then that person who is quite
healthy now but take on grief, she does not say what kind of grief.
She develops symptoms of either Calcarea phosphorica or what?
In a Calcarea carbonica case when it is done worse, when there is a relapse with anxiety
and difficult respiration, this sighing what you would prefer to repeat Calcarea, to give
Ignatia or to give Calcarea phosphorica and for what reason?
But I have to prescribe.
Who will be in favor of repeating Calcarea carbonica and for what reason?
Is anybody wants to speak up?
We don't have a description of the anxiety in the first place, the anxiety here is described
as a general state. What we had before is characteristic of Calcarea carbonica, it was the
aggravation from exertion, it was the phlebitis and the getting cramps and then worse cold
and then desire for soft boiled eggs.
They were the symptoms on which we prescribed Calcarea carbonica on the first case.
We do not know whether to start with anxiety which she has now, it is a different type of
lesser or not even intensity, we don't have that information. If we had prescribed on a
particular kind of anxiety on the first place and she had the same anxiety the second time
exactly, we can base a prescription, a repetition of Calcarea carbonica.
But here we have a case where it has done very well and then she has from that person
who may need a second remedy, Calcarea has done whatever it could, at least for the
time being.
It's not so easy for a Calcarea to come back, if you give a Calcarea or a Sulphur or a deep
action remedy and takes away a layer, it's not so easy to see the same layer coming back,
unless it is really some big stress.
What I have told you that there is many times an imprint of the remedy upon the person.
Due to certain stresses the remedy a picture of a remedy is imprinted upon the person.
It is the same way that we give Arnica, the idea is not that everybody needs Arnica.
It is a sudden shock of the tissues of the body that brings about a state, which is the state
of Arnica. That is why when you give Arnica to 100 people, it will act to 20 people, to the
rest 80 will not act because this 30% people may need Berberis, Rhus tox, Bryonia, they
need other remedies to cover the state which was brought about after shock and you give
Arnica and it does not work. Then you have to go to Rhus tox or Bryonia and it acts
beautifully.
So there is an imprint, we can have our organism which is imprinted upon a remedy and
this is my reason why I agreed with Ignatia and I have prescribed Ignatia.
Because Ignatia is a grief remedy, that person got a grief and got a symptom which is
characteristic of Ignatia. After a grief, a strong keynote of Ignatia.
If that person had tell you, I have anxiety, tiredness, pains in the sole again but she did not
mention at all this difficulty in respiration, until she has told me that I feel extremely tired
now, very tired and I take a lot of fruits, my mind would go to what remedy?
-Phosphoric acid.
-Phosphoric acid because this is the information and you have to base your prescription.
It changes the remedy, if she would tell me that she is anxious, tired and pains in the sole
but not sighing but this tiredness is accentuated to the grief after sleep, wake up from an
afternoon nap that she takes and she says I'm absolutely rotten, then...
Open your remedy generalities, sleep, aggravation afternoon sleep and tell me what is the
remedy? Everybody will see the remedy.
A grief remedy that says tired, does not have the sighing, after sleep...
Which is the remedy?
Grief remedies, ailments after grief, grief after an aggravation...
But the way that the patient said that symptom, accentuates that symptom so much and
she gives it to you then you would go to remedies which have it very strong.
Which is the remedy that has it very strong?
-Staphysagria.
-Staphysagria because the person gave it very strong in the same way that that person
gave strongly the sighing, I can not sigh because it is a peculiar symptom of Ignatia.
It covers the case and leads towards Ignatia. In the same way if it was said afternoon
sleep I'm rotten, I can not wake up which is a strong symptom of a remedy which has
grief and worse afternoon sleep. This is Staphysagria.
I had a case which was Calcarea and now she has gone to Calcarea phosphorica because
of the difficulty on the respiration, because that is all the symptom you have.
This tiredness is a general symptom, anxiety is a general symptom, too many remedies.
How many times in your life you have given Calcarea phosphorica after grief?
Very few times. That which is frequent...
For me it is very obvious, I don't know if it is for you, but for me it's very obvious.
Because if we have upper remedy, we have the development of another keynote, this
keynote will be the leading symptom for our prescription. If that keynote is of the same
remedy like before, I will give Calcarea carbonica but if that keynote is a keynote of
another remedy, which are the remedies that have that strong? Calcarea phosphorica and
Ignatia, either I would give Ignatia or Calcarea phosphorica.
Why do I go to Ignatia? Because first of all the state she presents to me is not anymore an
arthritic condition, that it has been taken care, it is not varicose veins, it is just the grief of
something that has happened to her life.
Grief brought about some kind of anxiety again of course,
with a strong keynote of a remedy which is more superficial than Calcarea phosphorica.
I would not go and give such a deep remedy for what I consider to be a minor symptomatology and
I do not have enough symptoms for Calcarea phosphorica to justify, giving such a deep remedy.
Now if she had said instead of...  but she has developed now a great pain in the cervical
region, which again is a characteristic of Calcarea phoshorica, then I will have no more
point to prescribe for Calcarea phosphorica and I would have seen that something is
going on in this area of the vertebrae and that is on the realm of the Calc. phosphorica
pathology but we don't see anything of that. We see grief and sighing, which is the first
remedy for grief?
You don't go and give deep remedies for that reason before we try the most obvious.
So the most obvious is Ignatia and we try...