Are you aware of this model I have given in my book, which are the 3 levels?
Mental is the deeper one, emotional is the second one
and then the outside level is the physical level.
There are a few things that you have to be aware
that once a disease is on this level on the mental level, it may go to the emotional
and eventually to the physical body in this direction.
Or if a disease is on a high level on the physical body,
then it may come down to another level, which is lower but still is high
and then eventually you may find going into the skin.
I want to show you a case where you will see that the child started with a skin eruption
eventually developed problems with his chest and then developed problems with his personality.
In this case of that child you will see several layers of his body affected.
First you will see the mental level and in this particular case
what it produces you will be surprised to see a very intelligent child.
A child that has jumped two grades.
It's very interesting also that this child on an emotional level,
has stayed very much behind and is immature.
You will say but the child is so clever, why do you say that it's not healthy.
No, it's not healthy. It can be stimulated to be very intelligent and it's not healthy
and I'm sure that some of you who have gone through the medical school,
especially during the time of examinations, some of you, you may have used amphetamines
and you see how clever you have become during this period.
When the amphetamines are acting, you go and give examinations
and you answer your questions with a great clarity and great precision under amphetamines.
That means the brain can be stimulated in an unhealthy way, the disease also can go
and stimulate the brain and can make a brain that goes zzz...
You remember last year when here for those who were present, how many of you,
you were present last year?
You remember Zinc? I gave zinc and I was jumping around and I was trying to show
you how is zinc and what zinc is producing?
You remember about a mathematician whose brain makes calculations and all these movements
and all these twichings which we see and the brain which is working very much.
And you will see it in this child.
And you will see also very clearly the emotional immaturity.
You will see this mental over stimulation and the emotional immaturity, combined together,
produce what we call personality disorders.
When you will see this child getting better on these levels,
you will see his chest will take all the force of the disease
and his asthma will become much more prominent.
Why? Because he does not have enough strength to bring out completely on the skin
to bring all the force of the disease.
And the child has chest problems and also enuresis, involuntary urination during night
and finally he has skin eruptions.
All this added together constitute the disease of the child.
When you see the child they bring the child, they will the child has a little bit of eczema,
can you cure it?
And you see how complicated is this condition where you see the personality disorders,
the chest problem, the enuresis and the eruptions appear at the same time.
Which means that the organism is trying to keep out and some of the disorder,
it keeps out in the skin, some it keeps it on the chest, some on the enuresis level
and some goes to mental, emotional situation and when under homeopathic treatment
how this is reversed.
-A case of a 10 years old boy, his main problem at the moment
is that he urinates the bed every night. Maybe even several times in the night.
The urine is always very much of it and there is a very strong smell.
When he was a baby, he had ...
-His main problem is enuresis. He loses urine every night.
And this is what the parents feel as a big problem because they have to clean the bed.
But is it the main problem? I would like you to tell me if you see the child
how much is the real big problem.
-(?) it was very bad when he was about 5 years old and that was the first time
he went to homeopath. He gets cracks on the hands and he had it on the knees as well.
Now he is (?) hands sometimes on the face
and he has always got one spot on the left leg and it's itching very much
and he scratches it a lot.
The skin gets very much worse if he drinks milk, he develops big (?)
which stick to the clothes, generally also he is worse from milk
and he doesn't have milk now.
He also has coughs and wheezing and he wheezes during the night especially in the damp weather
he is worse, better in the dry cold. For example on holidays to the mountain.
-She mentioned 3 problems, the enuresis, the cracks in the hands and on the face
and also the chest problems the wheezing especially in cold wet.
The cracks, the wheezing, the worse cold wet indicate a remedy.
When we have skin eruptions and chest problem worse cold wet,
the remedy can be Dulcamara or Rhus tox or Calcar. carb.
But when we have especially cracks, Rhus tox will be in favor of the other two.
-In the dark, in the past he had worse during the night at 5 o'clock,
mostly at 3 o'clock. He has seen quite a few homeopaths.
The first time that he saw me last September they came because he had lots of fears,
he had fear of death, fear that the world might end, and very strong fear of the dark,
and fear of robbers and in the night he would wake up crying, he want to die and so on.
-You see how he had developed fear of death, fear of the world coming to an end
that he was dying, he will wkae up in the night, I don't want to die
and you see now how the problem is distributed?
The skin, the chest, the enuresis, the fears.
-These fears he hasn't got now. His parents always complain about his temperament.
He can have very bad mood especially at home that if he doesn't get his way,
he hits things and he shouts very loud or slams the door.
So with his parents they have lots of fights, especially with his father.
I haven't seen him like this.
When he came to me he was always very shy and very polite
and most of the time he was sitting on his father (?)
His father says he can have irrational and violent (?)
-You see now the picture how it develops? The child has tantrums, irrational behavior.
He will scream without reason, he will do all these things but the child is intelligent.
It has jumped two classes. Why he behaves in this way?
Why he has developed all these fears? Why he sucks his thumb? He is 10 years old.
Why he has enuresis? Now they bring the child to us and say, OK cure this child.
What do you want me to do? If it was the skin more prominent, we say cure the skin.
If it was the child completely gone, mad, you will see no skin,
no problems in the chest, they will say, cure the madness, cure the insanity.
Whatever is the disease!
But there is no difference between the skin eruption and the chest eruption
and the mind eruption, there is no difference.
It's one disturbance that comes or it's diffused to the organism
or it concentrates mostly on the mind or mostly on the chest or mostly on the enuresis
or mostly on the skin. Where is best to be?
On the skin right?
Then where is next best to be? In the chest. And where is next to be? In the emotions.
And where is next best to be? In the mind.
When the mind breaks down, then it's finished and we have the insanity.
-He is very bad tempered in the morning, he is very impatient, he is very proud child,
at school they advanced him, I'm not sure if he jumped two classed
but he is with older children.
He doesn't like it particularly because it means he has to work very hard
to keep up with the others and he likes to be the best and not to work.
His mother complains about him a lot.
She says he is very selfish because he tells his friends (?) helps other people,
she says you shouldn't do that.
The other thing is that he always chew something or he chews his fingers,
he always got something in the mouth.
His desires there was nothing really marked, maybe his desire for salt.
-When I hear this story from the practitioner, I say to myself what is there,
what is the remedy, that is in what we are mostly interested. What is the remedy?
And I say to myself mostly it can be Rhus tox, perhaps Dulcamara
and these Kalis especially Kali bromatum,
because Kali bromatum has this fear of the catastrophe.
Is it a case of Phosphorus also because Phosphorus has (?) eruption,
wheezing and has fear of dying etc.
These are my thoughts going on in my mind when I see the child.
Now you will see something in the child.
What did you observe except of those who know the case?
Did anybody observe anything on the child?
Tell me.
-Mouth.
-Who also saw the mouth?
That's very important. You see now, as the interview goes on,
you see the activity on the mouth, it will keep on going like that all the time
and when this activity will stop I will watch his legs
and I will see his legs going like that.
Of course I don't remember if they have seen it in the video
but as I was next to the child and I could observe,
I could observe his legs going like that, when the activity here was calming down.
I would like you to observe a little bit more of this child and just see.
-What can you tell us about yourself? What is the problem?
-I can't think of anything.
-Are you good student at school?
-Medium.
-You like going to school?
-(?)
-Are you a quite boy at school or mischievous?
-I become more quiet in school.
-Are you (?) at home?
-Yes, yes.
-Very mischievous or just a little bit?
-Probably.
-You see the child is moving in two place, he can not do otherwise.
These movements are almost chorea type movements. Ticks.
But he appears to be playing with that but do you see the activity?
It's going on all the time and it is something that we see now
that the nervous system is in a state of excitement.
The nervous system is on constant irritation, stimulation.
The peripheral nervous system produces all these ticks
and produces also the stimulation in the mind.
Are you a good student? Medium. He knows he is supposed to be very clever.
Now what I know is that this child has been pushed to the limits by his parents
to become, to become, to obtain, learn piano lessons, take French lessons,
learn also Esperado ...
I mean whatever the ambition, playing the clarinet, playing this, playing that,
being first in the school, you have to be and this stimulates,
the nervous system is irritated all the time and then there is a time you say,
Joseph would you come to eat?
....  What happened? Why? Of course he behaves this way because he is stimulated
he does not know what is going in his nervous system,
he does not feel the balance in himself and therefore he will kick anything,
he will break anything, and the parents will say,
the child has a little bit of strange behavior.
I mean it's not the fault of the child definitely, neither of the parents per se
but the parents do not realize that this kind of behavior needs primarily to be treated
and the child should not be pushed.
This child is exceptional child but should not be pushed,
under such pushing do this, do that, the children break up. That is how they break up.
I have seen medical students after using a lot of amphetamines
to go through their examinations, I have seen them completely broken down eventually,
because of over stimulation for a certain period of time, then collapse.
I have seen students that they were genius in the high school.
They go the University, they go to the College first.
The first year in the College and something is wrong, the second year in the College
and they go to the bottom, the third year they give up, finished.
With all that stimulation the very clever, the very intelligent,
the brain that is always stimulated does not always indicate a healthy state.
Many times it's an unhealthy state and this is the case with this child.
Treated with Homeopathy, this child will go back to his age.
He will not be able to keep up with two classes in front of him.
There is a sign in this child that indicates an emotional immaturity
and as soon as you see this sign, I would like to raise your hand
and I will stop the video and you tell me, this is the sign.
As you watch the video, I would like to exercise your powers of observation.
Now that is a sign of immaturity.
There is a very clear sign of immaturity, you will see it in the child.
-You enjoy being mischievous?
-(?)
-What happens in you? You are temperamental?
-I'm angry.
-You don't know why. What things make you angry?
-Any excuse will make me angry.
-You see what he says? You observe also, it's almost a chorea state.
He says, any excuse I can be angry, that means any excuse to express that imbalance
which is going inside and has to come out to find balance.
That's why it says, every symptom that an organism presents is a defense,
a way of finding a balance, anything whether it's anxiety, whether it is depression,
whether it is movement, whether it is irritability which is expressed, it is to find balance.
And he tries to find an excuse to have an eruption, to have an outlet.
-What you do when you are angry? You shout, you swear?
-Yes. I slam doors.
-You like to hear the bang of the door?
-Yes.
-Have you ever taken things to break?
-No.
-Because you are afraid that maybe your father will punish you?
Do you have any fears now? Are you afraid of anything?
-The world of growing up.
-Is it a big fear?
-Yes, I used to have last year, I used to have really bad dreams.
-Dreams about the world (?)
-Yes.
-You look shy (?) You don't want to grow up, do you?
-No.
-You are afraid of that.
You are still thinking of the world growing up.
-Yes.
-And you are afraid that you may die?
-Fear of death they call it. How is in your mind? How you think about that?
You think that the world is going to blow up and you will die or you may die
because you have a disease?
How is the fear?
-I'm scared that I might die.
-Yes but when this fear comes? You are thinking of having an accident
or a disease and you will die or it just comes out of the blue?
-Yes, when I have a bad cough I think I just might die and I can't take a breath.
-Then it feels you may die.
Do you feel constricted in your chest?
Do you understand the word constricted?
-Yes.
-Like you can not breathe when you have the coughing.
-Yes, I can not breathe when I have the coughing.
-How frequent is what he describes?
-The last couple of weeks it could be nearly every night,
the coughing continues for long period every night
but it might be just once the month or 2-3 times the week.
-When this coughing comes?
-Yes.
-The eczema has from 5-6 years old?
-(?)
Did you hear what he says, by 5 years old he had badly the eczema, they had to do something.
They tried to give allopathic drugs, they could not handle it,
they took it to the homeopath, they gave some medicines,
eventually they tried to correct the diet and it appears that the eczema is much less now.
Still he has a little bit of eczema, here and there but nothing really serious.
Where has gone the eczema? You see the activity with the tongue?
All this activity that is going on all the time?
-It was a time when the eczema was quite strong.
-Yes.
-How did it go away?
-We (?) diet specifically.
-Did you give him allopathic medication?
-When (?) 2-4 he had a lot of (?) cream and (?) and then
because we couldn't keep the same thing about it,
to take more (?) we didn't want to go on like that, so we went to a homeopath
and even that didn't have a dramatic effect in curing.
(?)
-But it decreased?
-Not immediately. (?)
Things were very much restricted at the time.
-Did he ever have any severe attack of asthma, difficult respiration?
-To my observation it has never been as bad as asthmatic attack can be
but in the summer (?)
-It's very interesting if you observe now through the follow ups what took place.
Really you will see the differences.
He is 10 years old and you may say sometimes logically we explain things.
He doesn't put his hand to the mouth because he is in front of the camera,
everybody is here. What his organism leads him to do is an awareness.
Why don't you put your thumb and suck your thumb?
Because you have the awareness not to do it, once the awareness comes, then this will stop.
What we do, especially some women what they will do instead of sucking their finger?
They will do like that, have you noticed this?
It is a kind of ... They don't actually suck their fingers
but the awareness of being grown up, the tendency may be still there
but because they have the awareness they can't do it.
Something much more polite and much more acceptable socially.
What we are evaluating is the state that the boy is in and why he is in that state
and what is the real cause and then when we will give the right remedy?
Certain things have to improve but you will tell me,
is it possible from being immature emotionally, as we see him,
the child can be mature emotionally within 3-5 months? That's impossible.
Before I knew Homeopathy I would also it's impossible but after I know Homeopathy
and what Homeopathy can do, I will not say anymore it is impossible.
I will say yes, it is possible.
It is possible that this child will mature in 6 months and he will suck his thumb anymore.
Maybe he will do the same thing as the woman.
-To my observation he has never been (?) as much as he can be (?)
or if he has been moving around, he will have very (?) breathing and (?)
-You observe the irritability is around his hands now and also I don't remember
if they got his feet, the irritability in the feet maybe we'll have a chance to see it.
-Goat milk he can take?
-Yes.
-No problem and he drinks sheep's cheese.
-Also another symptom of zinc is that, if you notice, he licks with his tongue.
Licking with the tongue, all this activity goes on and also there is this licking
with the zinc cases.
He got zinc 200 and I saw this child 2 months later. Put the interview forward.
From time to time he remembers that he is sucking his thumb and he takes it out
but in spite of the fact he knows that it's not right to do it, he can not avoid it
and he puts his thumb in his mouth.
Go to the follow up.
What do you think about his father?
The child also, if you have noticed the whole interview, very frequently
will turn to the father for help, advice
and you see the dependence of the child from the father.
You will see the father also is an authoritative figure, he is there, he is closed up
and overwhelms the child.
You see in the previous case of Anthracinum that we saw, I said don't touch this case
in spite of the fact that it appears to be a new remedy coming up, don't touch.
In this case you will see something else.
-I saw his (?) and this is what she said to me. She said he had 4 basic problems
which are eczema, asthma, bad temper and enuresis. (?)
She said the eczema first, then he came he had some eczema on the fingers,
some on the cheeks, some (?)
It was very itchy so that his father had to put (?) because he was scratching so much.
-When you hear this, you like it. In a case like that, the eczema is becoming worse,
you like it but you will like it only if the rest of the child becomes better.
Don't always like it. If the rest of the child is better, yes you like it,
you want the eczema to be worse.
-He developed new eczema on the knees and on the other side of the face.
It's now starting to get better, the face now is nearly clear, the leg also, the hands are still very bad (?)
As for the asthma (?) wanting to take the remedy, he had a really bad night
that he woke up at 2 o'clock in the morning with fear of dying.
I (?) someone to stay close to him, the next few days he (?) the asthma
and he had to lie down a lot, which is unusual.
one month and the last two weeks he is breathing quite bad, he wakes at 5 am
and every morning he has to sit up and cough (?)
-Worse 5 a.m.
-The enuresis as a whole did not change. The first few days after the remedy,
he had a few (?) and now is (?) The temper, she said he might be a little bit less screaming
and a little bit (?) but they are not sure because they have (?)
She has become less strict with him. She has taken a stance the other day
until (?) of screaming and swearing. The restlessness is still very great (?)
So what she concluded is the eczema is worse, the asthma is too big
for the time of the year and enuresis is unchanged and temper is maybe slightly improved.
She mentioned two peculiar things. It was very hot weather
and he had asked for a hot water bottle every night to go to bed.
-You see the observation of the mother? She noticed two peculiar things.
One is that the child became very cold and he asked for hot water bottle.
These are changes that came after the remedy.
It becomes very important, in order to evaluate what has taken place.
So far you may be thinking that the remedy has acted, maybe.
It has acted if the child is better in his mental-emotional state
and if he is worse in asthma and skin.
What the mother says, maybe there is amelioration, maybe there is an amelioration
in the mental-emotional, the skin was better but it has come back.
The enuresis is the same every night and perhaps she says, 2-3 times the night.
So there are some changes, between these changes are
that the child has become very cold and is strikingly worse
because the mother says that's peculiar.
-Also he wears his warmest jacket, even in the hottest days and going to town
he won't go without his skin jacket.
-He is especially cold in bed?
-He seems to be cold also in the daytime because (?)
I ask him how are you and he says, I'm worse.
-How are you?
-I'm worse.
-(?)
You can see a few cracks, the dryness, that was much worse of course last year
after the initial remedy, as you remember, there was a big aggravation.
What you see here is very little. In order that this child will be cured,
one day is going to break out really bad outside on the skin.
What has happened is that the remedy affected the child
and took the child up to a certain extend. You will see now, the evaluation
that we are doing.
-After the remedy the eczema broke out very early?
-Not immediately, coming and going in waves.
What you noticed here in the follow up?
Apart from the child, concerning his father giving the follow up,
what you will notice is tha this father is not prepared to accept any change.
Anything that I will say, that the medicine has brought about, he will deny it.
He will try to say no, no, this is not from the remedy.
This has changed but usually this is what happens
and everything will be explained away to give you the impression
that the remedy has really worked?
And it is only my observation concerning the child, that will be your observation.
You remember the activity that was going on the muscles?
Now you observe to tell me if that activity is going on or the face
has become much more calm now.
You will see in the interview.
-When the eczema started?
-About a week I suppose after...
-And stayed for how long?
-For 2-3 days (?)
Did you see how long is the interview and he has not made one twitch?
The father will keep on saying, nothing has happened.
He will try to explain away everything and if you are gullible and if you are not observant,
I mean that was the main symptom of course on which we gave Zinc,
but let us say we are not observant, the patient can tell you anything
and you can swallow it, you can believe it and then finished.
Here, there is a big change and that's very apparent in the face of the child.
-The eczema broke out first in the face?
-Yes and then on the knees and then on the hands, the fingers.
-I see and how was (?) after the remedy?
-A bad one, (?)
and then about 2 weeks ago we had a very bad (?)
-Two weeks ago he had a crisis of asthma.
Did he take anything for asthma?
-No.
-He had fear of dying?
-Yes.
-And how is now the condition in the chest? You cough a lot?
-I cough (?)
-But it seems coming and going.
-Before the remedy how frequently he would get the asthma?
-Very irregular, it depends. This whole year you would expect him (?)
it's been less this year than other years (?)
Do you observe the activity? He will not shuck anymore his thumb.
Both interviews after that, he will no suck his thumb, not only that
but when I see the calmness in the face, in comparison with the first one,
I know how much the nervous system has been relieved.
Never mind what the father is saying and why the father is saying all these things
and he does not want changes.
The changes are there and they are very prominent.
Also he says that the last year the asthma was better than previous years.
In proportion that the asthma was better this year, his mental-emotional state is worse.
So when it has starting the amelioration, it's going to go through the asthma to the skin.
-Did you notice that certain things that you brought up (?) now did not bother you?
-Yes probably (?)
(?)
-I went down to town (?)
-That will be nice.
-Where you put the hot water?
-In my feet.
-Your feet feel very cold?
-Yes.
-And this is after the remedy?
-No, this is (?)
-Is it the first time that he feels so cold?
-(?)
He said, I'm not sure that he is feeling cold, he is just asking for a hot water bottle.
Can you imagine a child that wants to torture himself by putting a hot water bottle
the moment that his feet are warm?
Later on when he will say, the mother says (?) and this is July 15, middle of July
and he takes a warm bottle and he wears little jackets because he feels cold.
Now his father will say, I don't know if that is really cold
because he likes to wear little jacket. It's very interesting.
-(?)
-How is his character?
-Generally he is better but he has been under so much pressure and (?)
We think maybe he is better, he can not deny the facts,
still he tries to explain away everything in order to tell you
there is nothing that has taken place. There is no change.
That is the condition you have to face many times. Why?
Because in a family situation there are things and dynamics that take place,
that are very difficult to change and somebody in a family
who takes the responsibility of the family, if this responsibility is not required anymore,
it's difficult for him to change.
If he takes an attitude of protectionism towards the family
and there is no more need for protection, the mother protects the child, the woman.
I have seen grown up women 50-60 years old that they are protected their daughters
until the age of 35 and suddenly the daughter becomes grown up
and she doesn't need the protection and the mother goes into depression
and wants to commit suicide.
And says why there is no use for my life?
Is it possible that in this condition we may have a family dynamics where he is in control
and not only that, maybe there is a possibility that maybe he is
a kind of son-father competition towards the mother?
The boy has to stay there, where it is, with his weaknesses and complexes and all these things.
The picture that the father presents is, nothing has really changed,
this is the message I received from the father. What I see is a tremendous change.
Not only that but I see also and we will not have time to go into that,
I see also that due to the fact there is such sensitivity towards the cold
and due to the fact also that originally when I had the case,
I had a lot of Rhus tox symptoms, due to the fact that the restlessness
still is somewhat there, not as much it was with the Zinc but still
there is some restlessness, the worse cold and the symptoms of initial Rhus tox symptoms,
give me the conviction that the child has gone now into a state of Rhus tox.
There is now further from this interview, there is another interview
who has come on October, from July to the middle of October,
where you will see the next interview.
-Why the father came to the interview?
-I don't know.
You will see an interesting phenomenon where the child really gets better
the father will not appear anymore.
Now what is interesting for me and for you is to understand the dynamics
and not to be misled by these dynamics; you have to perceive what is going on
for the shake of the child. You are told, help my child.
This is what you are asked to do; so never mind how devious in many cases will be,
not straight because of these reasons...
You will see other dynamics where the person feels, I became by myself well.
Homeopathy did not help me, I did it. This idea, I did it, is a dynamic
which will come repeatedly in your consulting room.
They will try to deny any kind of amelioration.
They will try to deny and you will sometimes believe it, most of the times.
The difference between you and me is perhaps that because of my experience
I know what they mean, when they are there, I perceive the real facts.
And the real facts for me is that the father was resisting all the time,
apart from feeling the vibrations that were very strong at the moment.
I rely mostly on my observation.
Here is the child, he got a dose of Rhus tox 200 or 1M, let us see him.
-Are you OK?
-A bit better I suppose.
I'm better than I was a few months ago.
Isn't very interesting? Now he is coughing and he says (?) and the child says,
a bit better I suppose, this is an English answer of course.
The subtle way that the English people are answering the question.
He has learned to do that. Let us see how better he is.
-Coughing is (?)
(?)
There is the follow up which the practitioner gives, I would like to hear that
because it's interesting.
-The remedy was given at the 20th of July, I saw them on the 1st of September and they were very concerned
the cough was very bad and the asthma had become very very bad, worse than it was ever been.
Every night he would wake up (?) around 4,30 and again at 6 o'clock
(?) very short of breath.
(?)
the enuresis was worse every night (?) I gave him an examination (?)
I thought I had to give him something, so I gave (?) 200 and several times (?)
After that he asked me for (?) for several days, maybe a week
but then he was back again.
Here in this state, the best thing to do is to have an aggravation
after a remedy especially in asthma.
The best thing to do is never to give a homeopathic remedy to (?) down the aggravation.
It's better if you give some helping from allopathic drug.
If they can not go through the aggravation. Most probably, if there was no drug available
the child would go through the aggravation, without problem.
But you know the parents worry and what is important now is that the asthma
is worse than ever.
The skin is again worse. You see the reaction of the organism
that tries to bring down on a lower level the disturbance,
which is on the mental-emotional and then eventually bring it down onto the skin.
But it does not have enough energy to bring it out to the skin all together.
So it will go through this level of lungs eventually into the skin.
(?)
I talked to them again yesterday and I heard that the asthma was now
for two weeks quite good. He had a few nights where he (?)
His skin is not too bad at the moment, he has (?) on the face
and his fingers are covered. He has some eczema on the buttocks, which he never had before.
Enuresis every night except from last week where he had 3 dry nights.
Otherwise he has every night.
When you use this follow up, you are sure now that the amelioration
on the mental emotional level is going to be very prominent.
The last week the amelioration in the enuresis is coming.
Previous week 2 nights without enuresis, this week 3 nights without enuresis,
the amelioration on this level is also coming.
There was an aggravation that affected the chest and the skin and now,
as this is going on, the effects of the treatment are apparent.
-His temperament improved quite a lot. His mother said he goes to school
much more enthusiastic, prepared to work quite hard (?) two days ago (?)
-Are you OK?
-I get better I suppose. I'm better than I was a few months ago.
(?)
-What bothers you most now?
-Coughing.
-What hours?
-8,30 in the evening. (?)
Do you observe? The hand does not go anymore into the mouth. You see?
-Let me see your fingers. The outer body has any eczema?
-It's got better.
-The eczema where it was before a few months ago? Which places?
-My hands are very bad.
-Where else?
-(?)
-Now the only thing that bothers you is the fingers.
Can you tell me about your fears? Do you remember you had some fears?
-Yes.
-What they were? Do you remember?
-(?)
-Do you see (?)
-Not that much.
-Another fear?
-Fear of dying.
-How is that fear?
-No as much.
-Another fear?
-fear of dark.
-Now that doesn't cross your mind?
-(?)
-If you hear some noise?
-Yes.
-What about your temperament? You were very temperamental?
What happened with this aspect of your personality?
-I suppose it got better, it got better for a while and then went back again.
-This (?) was when?
-3 months ago.
-3 months ago you had a temper?
-Yes.
-You did the same thing, you hit things, you shout? (?)
-I still shout... to everybody.
-With the same kind of emotions now you shout? You are angry when you shout?
-Yes.
-Do you still confront your parents like you did or you don't need to do it?
-I think I still do it.
-What do you say?
-He is been a lot better, Initially he went through the time of being very angry and shouting
and then we had a period of being relaxed In the last couple of weeks,
he has been very helpful, very kind.
-This is the improvement that you expect, this is the type of follow up
that you like to hear.
You don't like to hear that the eczema is gone, you don't like to hear
that the chest problem is gone.
What you like to hear first is that the temperament is better and then from the inside,
the amelioration will take place to the physical, to the external,
to the complete amelioration of his skin finally.
Unless you have that type of amelioration, this child was treated homeopathically
from the age of 5 to the age of 10. What results? His asthma was better
and then he said last year was even better but what about his character, his tantrums.
He didn't want to do this, I'm sure the child did not feel like doing it purposely
but he could not help it and that is where we must concentrate in treating the cases.
Always, always you look mental-emotional general state of energy.
Mental-emotional better, energy better, wait. Wait until when?
Until you are sure that there is a clear picture of another remedy.
It's very difficult here because I'm seen this case in London,
I have to fly there to see the follow ups especially and I have to make a judgment
because the whole class attends, says what happened to the child,
we want to see and I'm also eager to see that we do not lose time.
I could have said, wait until October, until they will come back and wait
until I see the effect of the Zinc, the first remedy we gave.
Why did I go to the next remedy?
Because first of all I saw an aggravation and then an amelioration.
That means an aggravation and then it was an amelioration but the aggravation
that was coming in the periphery it stopped, went back.
At the same time there are constitutional changes that indicate for me
it is a clear case of Rhus tox now.
Because of the changes and pointing now to Rhus tox and if I had seen for instance
that the skin eruption was becoming worse and worse and worse
I would not have given another remedy.
But if I kept the child only with Zinc from the beginning,
now you would see the same thing as the last interview.
That means the action of the remedy Zinc did what it could do, the next remedy appears
and it's clear, you can give it.
Why? Because the child is still quite a lot sick.
The mother comes and says, well there is definitely an improvement in his temperament
his character, there is no question about that.
That is where you want to lead your patient.
That is not apparent, you can not see it like a skin eruption,
where the skin eruption goes away and you are very happy, you see it's going away.
You cannot see the eruption in the mind but what you see is the hyper excitability
that expresses itself through disorders in his personality.
You see that he became a sweet child and he is going to be a sweet child,
it's a very nice child, there is no question about that.
He is not going to be as bright as he used to be, there is no question about that
and he is going to go through with his chest and skin problems for some time
before everything appears in the skin.
He may need another dose perhaps but at the moment we leave the child.
It's good enough. Now the fact he starts going to the school
where the situation is aggravated, when he starts going to school,
then he becomes very agitated.
Then he had some reaction but always the improvement takes this kind ...
You see here it comes down for a period of time and goes up again a little bit down,
more down you wait and you will see again up.
On the whole observing the child in a period of 6 months,
you will see the upward tendency of the child, his health picks up constantly
and this is the idea.
From time to time you will see some kind of relapses or they will look like relapses.
But once the remedy has acted correctly from the inside to the outside,
don't bother, these relapses are only temporary and they will go away.
The Carbo vegetabilis acted partially. What it does is it takes away one symptom
or part of the case and ameliorates it for a week or 3-5 days
and then the child descends back, that means it did nothing. It was close but not exact.
It could have spoiled the case if this child was in a much worse situation.
His immune system, his defense mechanism was very much lower.
One dose of the wrong remedy, it could have done
that the asthma could have been ameliorated immediately and then his nervous state
would have been aggravated.
If you repeat it untimely, you may have opposite results than what you expect.
If now he comes 3 months later after Rhus tox and I don't see anymore the coldness.
When it was July his father was telling me that he likes to wear his leather jacket.
Why doesn't he come with leather jacket on October in London,
which is much colder than July?
But if you give now again Rhus tox, most probably will aggravate the case
without an amelioration.
His thumb is in the mouth, you will see it sometimes will go like that
but never really sucks his thumb again and that was one symptom
that was related from the beginning.
The mother says he sucks his thumb. Why now he does not suck his thumb after the remedy?
What is the difference? It's accidental or he got more mature
within the last 2 months or something? No.
I believe it's the remedy that brings about that kind of maturity
that let the freedom of the organism to develop and that's why the child
has the awareness not to suck his thumb.
That is the problem really. Once it comes to that state, we are going to have a problem
because the mother will press, the father will press, the child will press for a remedy
and we do not know what is the next indicated remedy.
Is still Rhus tox, is Calcarea, is one complementary remedy, is Bryonia, Dulcamara?
What is it? And we are going to be in a bad situation.
There is a stage where we are going to find difficulty in handling this case,
as the case progresses better and better.
Unless the parents understand the real improvement and what we mean by improvement.
We mean that the child will be really balanced in his organism in general.
Unless they understand that, we are going to have a problem.
Now it's a different thing when this child will come eventually with a big skin eruption.
It's different if he had come initially with a skin eruption to me;
we may have to wait for 5,6,8 months, 1 year before we can spot the next remedy.
I have been in that situation many times and I have been forced and pressed
and I made mistakes many times; that's why I warn you now, be careful,
don't be in a hurry to prescribe.
There was a time when they press me for a remedy and the remedy appeared to be Phosphorus.
The child would stay awake the whole night, scratching and the parents would scratch
and they would go mad the whole family.
It was Roger Morrison, he had the case. On the telephone day, night, evening.
And then he was telephoning me, what is going on?
And I said, OK let me see the child and I see the child, it was in a terrible state,
we can't wait anymore. 15 days now nobody had slept.
The child scratches and the remedy appeared to be Phosphorus but I was not very happy,
I was not 100% sure. I said I'm going to make a mistake if I give Phosphorus.
I said no, forget it, don't give it.
He said, they are going to put cortisone, they can not stand it anymore.
I said Roger, if we do it, I don't want to make a mistake, wait.
The next day the child changed the picture of Phosphorus to Arsenicum.
But when it changed to Arsenicum, it was so clear Arsenicum with the fear of  death,
with sipping water, with coldness, they had to cover the child.
I said, yes Arsenicum now give it.
You wouldn't believe it, it was crying.
They were holding him, it was a serious condition, they couldn't sleep
and I could understand all that but we gave Arsenicum in the evening.
In the night the child slept right through.
You would see his whole body was covered with eruption.
He did not know where to scratch, he was scratching and bleeding, he had a lot of wounds.
Within 48 hours you wouldn't believe the change. The skin was coming to normal.
48 hours and the boy get well.
If I had given Phosphorus, everybody would feel sorry, not only me.
Roger, the father, the mother, cortisone would be definite.
Because Phosphorus could not have helped the child
but it was so clear picture of Phosphorus,
drinking water, fear of the dark and wants his parents all the time there.
Roger pressed me, that's a Phosphorus case and I said, no it's not,
it is an experience of course that you have to differentiate between subtle differences
but for me there was not strong Phosphorus case
and I knew what a wrong remedy can do in that state.
I said, no still wait and then when it became really aggravated,
then the picture of Arsenicum became very apparent.
I know the problems with skin eruptions, they are terrible
but if you imagine the same skin eruption in the brain,
it's better I have it in the skin.