Those who had seen a case of a young girl from Austria 4-5 years old with menses...
Who has seen this case? Last year you have seen this case.
It’s called pubertas praecox syndrome,
that means a very premature developing of the human body
where the woman develops at the age 4, 5 except of menstruation,
hair and all these signs of a grown up woman.
This is considered a very difficult to treat situation
and I think in this girl was tried several hormones.
Where is the doctor attending the case? Can you please come?
She knows what happened with the case. Unfortunately as I said,
when people get better they say goodbye George, we don’t need you anymore.
The case number is 618 and the remedy was... So tell us what happened.
– The first time we have been here in 2006, we started with the case
and in this year we showed you the case in general and you gave Med.
– Last year?
– No, 2006.
After this the symptoms were just a little bit better but not so obviously
and the next year she got Lach., in 2007. In 2008, last year, she got Phos.
– And what happened with the last remedy?
– After Phos. as the father said she got warmer.
She had such tremendous fits of rage, beating around,
beating against furniture, beating her mother.
That was all less and she grew up more normal.
And the father says that she was more childish.
Before as you remember she was in the mood to talk about boys at the age of 6.
It was like puberty signs.
– What about the menstruation? The growing of hair?
– This was from the beginning suppressed by the hormonal injections
and as you remember the father is himself a medical doctor
and he was forced by the law to give these hormonal injections.
That was his fear that she gets the hormonal injections and he cannot stop it.
– What are the hormonal injections?
– It’s hormones.
– He stopped the hormones?
- She got the hormonal injections; he had to do this.
From the law. This professor in Vienna... They forced him to do this
because the law says she must get this school medicine treatment.
– So what did he do?
– He did this...
- Because of the law.
– And you told him that he should not tell the professor in Vienna
that we do another thing also. The hormonal injections only suppressed the menses
and the pubic hair but her general behavior and the general symptoms did not go away
and we saw that the case was bad, although the hormonal injections.
Maybe it brought some result in the menses and the pubic hair
but it didn’t heal the case.
Every half year they measured the bones
so you can see on the bones, if they are growing like in the age of 14 or of 6.
Before the bones were growing like in a 13 year old girl.
Now the bones are growing like a 6-7 year old girl.
– The effect of this syndrome is that the girl does not grow according to her age,
it grows according to the age let’s say 13 or 14.
That means the growing instead of being of 6 to 18, it is from 14 to 18,
that means the girl will stay very short in the end.
Because it stops the growth of the skeletal system.
If we manage to first of all to counteract the mental symptoms
that were created by suppressing the hormones when the girl was mad,
hitting, doing all these kind of things. Because if the hormones are there
and the organism is producing them and you enter with other hormones to stop,
that means there is a fight inside the organism,
and of course the girl naturally was very aggressive.
She wanted to express this aggression.
If the remedies managed to bring her to a normal state...
- Her age fitting stage.
– But what is her father saying about Homeopathy?
– He was open from the beginning because he is a close friend of mine.
He was open from the beginning and searching for help.
– But will he come here and give a report for his daughter?
This is what I am interested in. Will he come?
– If he will come again?
– Yes.
– Yes, he will come again next year.
– Bring the daughter and show us.
– He also wanted to come this year but I wrote you an email
and you wrote back that this is not necessary if everything is really good.
– Ok, I am too good! Everything is really well. I have to answer 50 emails a day.
I read that the case is doing very well, should I come? No. Ok, don’t come.
Just one word, I send the email, then...
- I think we can make a break for one year
because they have been at this professor in Vienna and he was very astonished,
how can it be, they measured her and he didn’t expect from the hormones
that this measure would be so good and it is a wonder
and we kept it secret as you advised. He said that hormones are working so good etc.
– We didn’t want to make him so angry! He would be really angry!
Who has interfered with my work?
– We know that this professor in Vienna is a real strict school medicine professor
and so you said to us that he would work against our work if he knew it.
So we kept it secret but he is very satisfied with the hormones
and we are satisfied because we feel that the remedies did their work very good
and you can see it on the emotional level.
She is from emotional state completely different,
The fits of rage are almost gone and she is warmer, she is not so jealous anymore
and she doesn’t pressurize so much anymore.
The father says what should I tell Mr. Vithoulkas...
- She is normal now and I am stupid! I should have told him to come here!
But anyhow the interesting thing will be that the professor in about 6 months
will write a report to the medical journal,
saying how well the hormones acted upon the child
and how the child is growing normally in spite of what we know that they don’t grow.
– And she was growing very fast already and she is now almost 8.
- My God!
– She is growing fast
but the bones show it’s more childish and normal, and not like in puberty.
That’s an interesting fact. She grows and it’s not so terrible.
The fear of the father that she may be small like a dwarf when she reaches puberty
and now she is growing normally.
– Is she still treated by hormones or the hormones have been cut?
– No, as he told me they reduced it, because it was running well
but still they are forced to give some of them
and they measure it so the father cannot lie.
– That is true. If he keeps on giving the hormones it may counteract the effect.
The father has to take some action and avoid them totally.
– If I tell him to come, he will come in 3 days. He can come anytime if you say so.
He told me if you say he should better come, he will come.
– Because after this seminar we continue with the complete,
in which case I will be teaching there for a few hours a day
and therefore he can come and give a report and so we discuss
and decide what is best for the child.
– Because we have been exchanging mails and said if it’s necessary...
- I did not pay attention because I have so many things.
You have seen me running back, looking and answering the emails.
Because everything which comes to me is urgent. Otherwise they would not write.
They would not care to write, how are you George? Are you having a good life?
– They had the impression that at this moment it was maybe really the right decision,
I also had the impression that maybe we can wait. But maybe...
- It is important that he comes because I am afraid that maybe he will interfere
and spoil the case. So, tell him if he likes to come within the next 2,5 weeks,
we will be here and we’ll take the case. We’ll show the case.
– Can he come anytime?
– Yes.
– He can fly on the weekend because he is a medical doctor and is very busy.
He can come on Friday to Monday...
- Every day. He can come any time and I can go anytime. Thank you!