This is a case of a young girl who was having a diagnosis of pubertas praecox
which means having menses very early in life
and one of the symptoms is that they don’t grow.
She is already 1,63 m by the time you measured her she was 1,64 m,
one centimeter more. Sometimes she had colds with fever,
a few times, she had a bad stomach with vomiting in the last year.
A bit of acne and dry skin. A bit of acne, I don’t see it.
Her menses is coming every month now. She also likes to eat a lot.
Before menses she experiences pain, is she anxious, is she crying more easily,
is she more irritable, is she more depressed?– Normal.
– Before menses.– No, nothing. She is normal.
– During menses she has pains?– No.
– Once in school there was some pain, she had menses but it was only a single time.
– She has constipation, she has stool every 2 or 3 days.– Yes.
– And big quantity. From this she has sometimes cracks on the anus and some bleeding.
– This must be very intense, the mother told me it’s very extreme.– The pain?
– The pain and the quantity, both.
– She is very lazy, dislikes sports.
She has to do sports in the school?– 2 times a week.
– What she likes to do? She likes more to study, to read stories, to watch TV,
to play with the computer? What does she like the most?
– She likes computer a lot and to play with the iPad.
– What would she like to become? Electronic engineer?
– In the meanwhile she understands you, her English is getting better.
– Most of it, I can see from her reactions. Sometimes she is really awkward,
she feels awkward. Is she pushing things as she passes by? Is that what she means?
– Sometimes she pushes things.
– She is not careful.– Yes. Spills some liquids.
– Especially when she doesn’t like what she has to do and has some little injuries then.
Very sensitive to critique and lack of self-confidence and irresolution.
Fear of not being loved easily. Sensitive to criticism. Likes to cuddle a lot.
Her fears are still to call somebody on the telephone. Needs the mother to do this.
But in general she is more independent now.
She can be very easily offended and also very loud.
When she is offended, how does she react? What is she doing, shouts, throw things?
– She doesn’t know. She throws the books on the floor sometimes.
– Not against somebody.– No.
– In general she feels more the cold or the heat or it’s normal, can tolerate both?
– She was always hot but more normal she likes to cool down,
she even jumps into a cold pool, she likes to cool down most of the time.
She prefers to be in cold rooms, cold pools.
– Quite often she has a very bad mood maybe from so much stress in school.
She is medium in the class or upper, lower?– This year she works very much.
Because in the first school she learned nothing, it’s kind of a Montessori school, no lessons…
This year she went in high school and learned back from the first year and the second.
She was medium and it was ok.
– She is very good and active with PC, iPad etc.
That is becoming a symptom lately! We have to treat it in the children!
– I think many mothers admire their children for doing this thing better than them.
– yes because they leave them quite, they are busy with the computer
and they can do whatever they like. She is still a warm person, especially during the night.
Sometimes sweating all over in the night, in the head also.
If I ask her what is her favorite food what would she say?
– Salad or meat. Wiener schnitzel.
– And what is that she cannot tolerate, she doesn’t like, any food?
–She eats onions?– Yes.
– If the meat has some fat in it, can she eat it?– She doesn’t like it.
– Has she lately noticed that she wants more salt in her food?
– No. she doesn’t like salt so much, only a little bit for the taste.
– If it is a little bit more she may not like it?– Nothing special.
– How she tolerates the sun?– She can tolerate it well.
– The school is mixed, boys and girls?– Yes.
– You like any boy particularly in the school?– Yes. 3.
– It was my prediction. Out of the 3 she likes one the most.
– No, 3 want her and she likes the one.– I want to ask
if she can urinate in front of others, in a public restroom. Can you ask this?
- I will try.– Strange question.
– Ok, forget it. What makes her feel more sensitive to criticism?
If they put her down, if somebody makes a bad remark
or if there is even the idea of a bad remark she may be hurt?
I want to understand how deep she is sensitive to criticism.
– Putting her down is the worst, especially from the mother
and not from the schoolmates. The sport teacher maybe making remarks.
– This is for her father; Is she an obedient child or disobedient?
Is she trying to please you with whatever you tell her to do or she will have a reaction?
– She is obedient most of the time. 90%- And she will try not to make you unhappy…
The relationship with her mother is good?– Sometimes a bit difficult.
She is easy-going with the father. For example when she is getting stressed with her
she wants to go somewhere for holidays
and the mother doesn’t want to hear about that, so they crash.
– Will she confront her mother?– She has a certain aversion to her mother
when her mother is just exploding because of this question, for example.
– She likes sweets? – She prefers chips, she prefers sour things.
– Chips are salty.– On chips she likes salt.
– She said she doesn’t like salt.– In the food. On chips salt is ok.
– Eggs?– No.
– What she doesn’t like in eggs?– The yellow one.
– She eats the white?– Yes, sometimes.
– If the white is not properly cooked and is still slimy she can eat it?– Yes.
– Fish?– She likes octopus, but not so much the fish.
– Calamari?– Yes.
– She has any other fear? Fear of dark, of thunderstorms?
– When she was younger she had fear of thunder but now it’s gone.
– How many years is she getting treatment, 5? No, 7 years. I am treating her for 7 years.
When you sleep your feet in bed are cold or hot or normal?– Normal.
– She doesn’t need to stick them out of covers.– Yes, sometimes she does it.
– She is lazy only with sports and lessons or she is lazy with everything?
– Most of the things.
– When you see her room, is it in order or it’s like a bombarded house?
– It is mostly normal.– So, she puts order herself.
– Sometimes her mother does, but normally she puts in certain order herself
but not extremely. But the mother says to me she is always minimalistic,
she doesn’t do a lot, she is generally more on the lazy side.
Absolutely what is necessary and not more.
– The sweating in the night is so much that she has to change clothes?
– Not so much.– And is it all over or in certain areas?
– Especially in the cervical region, she denies that the whole body is sweating.
– Mostly head and cervical.- Concerning the sweets we were talking about,
she likes sweet in the morning.
She eats sweets but in the evening she tries not to eat too much, to stay slim.
– But she likes sweets.– But before she said... hot chocolate.
– What kind of books she likes?– Phantasy stories with dragons.
– Science fiction?– Yes.
– Is she asking questions about life, about God?
– Sometimes I speak with her about God and what is happening in the universe.
– She wants to know, she is interested.
– Yes, but not every time. Sometimes I can speak with her.
How many of you know this syndrome pubertas praecox? Let me see. Very few.
It’s quite a serious condition, is considered so serious
that the government has some laws on this because children do not grow
and they are supposed to have menses at the age of 5 or 6 years old
and the consequences of that premature menses
and the anomaly in the condition of the hormones is quite serious
and they have a special treatment which the parents are supposed to give by force.
The treatment is hormones but with no much effect
because they try to suppress the menses again and again. This is not the idea.
She has been doing extremely well, she has been growing normal,
her menses came and stopped during the treatment, now she’s 12 years old,
with normal menses I see no problem,
no premenstrual syndrome someone would expect, no problem.
The problem seems to be a kind of oversensitivity to criticism.
This is the only problem I see in the moment. There is a kind of constipation
but still the colon is emptied it holds for 2 days
but the third day she has a lot of stool equal to 3 days stool.
I was trying to see whether there is a possibility for a remedy.
The first remedy I thought of was Nat-m. The second... is Carcinosin.
You didn’t hear me asking about how obedient she is,
she wants to please the parents etc.?
Also the fact that is very stressed in the report the sensitivity to criticism.
The last thought was about Sulph.
These were more or less the remedies I was thinking during the exchange.
What shall we do now? Which of these remedies shall we give? Shall we give a remedy?
When I ask you I really don’t know myself. Sometimes I play of course
but sometimes it is true that I don’t know. So I am thinking while I am talking to you,
putting things together again and again and trying to understand the organism
if it needs a push at this moment. I am always aware and afraid in conditions
which are quite sensitive and deep that we have a quite good effect on the long run.
By giving a wrong remedy you never know how much it can bring back problems.
Because it can be easily overturned. A wrong prescription in such cases
may cost quite a lot of problems to the doctor and to the patient as well.
So I want to be sure when I give the remedy that Nat-m. for instance or Carc.
I want to be sure the remedy is really indicated before I give it.
And in this case I really don’t know. I don’t see a very clear picture of a remedy.
Maybe Carc. is the best possibility but it is not confirmed.
I did not feel that the sensitivity was such, they had to describe to me for instance
that when the father said to her go and bring me a glass of water,
if he says it this way just because he is busy
and he is not careful a Carc. child could be offended. It’s like you didn’t pay attention.
You speak very harshly this is too harsh for a Carc. child.
So you hear stories, mother and father would describe this kind of sensitivity
which is extreme. I did not see it. So you want to ask questions?
– No question. I want to say that I wouldn’t give her a remedy
because she told that she hasn’t a good relationship to her mother
and she is only offended by her mother’s behavior.
Not at school, not by the teacher, not by her friends.
So I think the oversensitivity is not that deep to give a remedy.
Is she taking hormones now?–No.
– 1,5 year ago they stopped the hormones.– I think from the second year she stopped
and for 4-5 years now she doesn’t take any hormones.
– No, I think since 2 years she doesn’t take any hormones.
I think it’s not so long she is free of hormones.– 2-3 years she is not taking.
This was not allowed by the government.
You have to remember that the government has control over such cases.
And they cannot stop.
But if I remember well the agreement was to reduce the quantity from the beginning.
– As far as I remember, last year the father said to us
that he stopped already the hormone
although the doctor thought he stopped a little bit later.
I think we had this talk last year.
So, I think she is 2 years free of hormones and not longer.
– The question is from the beginning when you first came here
she was taking some hormones compulsory by the professor
and if I remember well we had agreed to reduce the amount
and I would like you to tell me what happened with the amount of hormones
and how long it took and how much of it.
– The growing continues nearly for one year then it reduces.
At the beginning she grew 1 cm in one month…
It took nearly 1 year till we went to the doctor in Vienna.
I was forced by the government in Austria to go to the hospital
but it took nearly 1 year and in this year she grew nearly 10-12 cm.
– During the first year, before coming to Homeopathy,
you gave the hormones and she grew…
- Nearly one year the growing reduced when I gave her a medicine called Enantone.
– You reduced it? How much?
– It took one year till it stopped from the beginning of the medicine.
– He doesn’t know exactly because they made blood tests every half year
and according to the tests they regulated the dosage.
So when she originally came to the treatment here
hormones had already been reduced a little bit
and so the first 4 years we were seeing here she was on hormones
and 2 years ago they stopped the hormones.
– They stopped the hormones because they found out that her hormones are normal now.
– They calibrated the height of the girl. They said now she is growing
and reduced the hormones because they hormones they give
in order to push the growing of the child. That’s why the reduced and stopped
because she was growing enough.
– Does anybody know the usual development of children with this problem?
Does anybody know how long it takes with the hormones,
what are the possible side-effects?
– There are cases where the menses come at 2-3 years.
And these girls start to develop faster than the others
and they reach a level of height very fast comparing to the girls of the same age
and they start the treatment, the hormonal suppression
in order to not permit to the hormones to close too early the cartilages of growing.
So, they permit to the organism to reach a certain height
and when the girls are mostly at the physiological age that the menses can start,
normally, they put out the hormonal treatment.
– In the books you may find this syndrome and we’ll have more information about this.
I don’t remember the details exactly.
The hormones were stopped 2 years ago, as you said,
and the menses came 1 year before. Am I correct?
– I want to ask you something.
When the menses have appeared in children of 2-3 years old in extreme cases,
when they suppress the hormones the menses will go away?
– Yes.– And then they wait? How long?
If they suppressed the menses they will not come.
– They wait until the age is close to puberty, before it.
And then they reduce and they totally stop the hormones when the menses come
and become regular.– I asked because he said that they also take the height of the child…
- Of course. Because if we let this child without treatment they grow faster
but when they arrive at the age of puberty their cartilages close
and finally they are shorter than other girls.
– When you say “the cartilages are closed” what are the symptoms?
– There are no symptoms, they just grow faster.– Without menses?
– Without the hormonal suppression treatment.
– I am not sure but anyhow we have to do some study about the case
because it is not clear. My understanding was that such children are in great danger
because they are prematurely old, because they start being women at the age of 3-4.
The treatment which they provide is not always successful, many times has side-effects.
Before I am sure I’ll see.– You want any more comments on this?
It’s exactly what you said; when you leave the children without treatment
then they become prematurely old and develop breasts and pubic hair,
so they start the hormonal treatment. Usually they measure the length
and hormones to see that they remain at a certain level.
At the age of 10-11 in some cases but mostly a bit later they start reducing
and they hope for the period to come. They start reducing at 10 for the breasts to grow.
There are cases where this development is delayed and in most of the cases,
as you were suspecting, there are lots of cases complaining later for menstrual problems.
– I remember some comments of the professor he had.
Do you remember the comments? There were some comments. We will call him back.
– What I wanted to say before in addition, she was at the age of 4-5 years
and she was very tall already in comparison to other children.
She already pubic hair and breast.
In case she did not take any treatment the body would be very early in certain height
and then suddenly would stop too early, like he said before.
This professor, as far as I remember, said that there was a big danger
because she was 2-3 years old when she got the menses
and she already had fit of rage to be dangerous in this age.
They said they must take the hormones because of all these
and the anger was suppressed by taking these hormones
because she was a little child having red head and exploding from anger.
You remember I think it was 2 years ago
she destroyed a glass door from made of safety glass.
When they stopped the hormones 2 years ago the anger increased
and this was the year when you gave her Stram. And since then the anger is normal.
– Anyhow, in this case I believe that the development has gone very well
and that is why at this moment I will refrain giving any remedy.
I don’t want her to take any remedy at this moment. The last remedy was Puls.
She has taken Stram. before Puls. and Phos. was before.
I have to study more about that syndrome so I know more things
and I can give you information. You can do the same.
– George, I think we are on the right track because the father really confirmed me
that she is really normal in every part of life. So for her father there really is no problem,
they came just to be sure that everything is going in the right way because it was severe.
– In order to understand the development you have to see the case since 7 years ago
when she was a very child, she was behaving like a woman, she was having sexual desire,
she was flirting with men etc. She is more or less normal, now.
When I asked her you like somebody she says yes I like but this is absolutely normal.
It’s not something out of proportion. In any case this is what we can do. So far so good.