This is a case we saw last year. It’s a case of a boy with autism and asthma.
He got as a prescription Hyoscyamus 200C
and the symptoms that have been ameliorated where asthma 30%,
eye contact and verbal communication improved, social interaction improved,
hyperactivity lessened, bowel motion in pants, disappeared, facial expression lessened.
What do you mean “facial expression lessened”?
- Grimaces.
– He was making a lot of grimaces. Anxiety lessened, handles crowds better,
movies scripting lessened. What is “movies scripting lessened”?
– He was repeating from the movies, movie talk.
Now it’s less but sometimes now he uses a portion of it and uses it appropriately,
he uses expression from the movie because he learns the language like that I guess.
– You remark here that 2 months after going back his eye contact
and communication improved so much that everyone at school, September 2012,
commented this change. So at school they also realized that. The boy was better.
Symptoms that have been remaining or got worse after the remedies;
sensitivity to reprimand improved just a bit,
however he is still very sensitive to any request
that are not presented to him in a very gentle manner or with a sense of humor.
If you say “do this”...?
– No, you have to be cuddly, how about doing this.
– During the affection you say why don’t you do that.
– And then actually he wants to do it by himself. You don’t have to order.
– He does not want to take orders?
– No.
– You explain that as not wanting authorities. Is that correct?
–Yes this is something at school, they have an educational assistant who helps with him
and sometimes when the woman doesn’t come to school, it’s always one woman,
the same one, if somebody else is ordering, everyone knows he refuses to cooperate.
If you are nice and firm but gentle then he corresponds and they know that.
– “Request that are not presented to him in a very gentle manner”...
Comprehension improved but still poor. You mean in the school
or when he is reading or looking at...?
– General. When he is looking, he knows,
but verbal comprehension. But in school and at home it is still the connection
between what you are telling him is not there.
Visually, pictures and if you explain him his is amazing, he gets it, he is a very smart boy.
– “Facial expression lessened but still present in the form of game with parents.
Anxiety lessened but still present.” How do you realize his anxiety? What are the signs?
– When we go to a friend’s house we prepare him, we use to show a picture
and then he would come to the house right away, he needs a preparation himself,
he needs to be outside, to get ready to meet people.
Now, in Serbia we were going to 3 houses every day minimum, family and friends
and meeting lots of people and he was ok with that. So much better.
So that’s one of the things.
– He remembered me?
– I think so. Do you remember mr. Vithoulkas? Well he told me before that he did.
We showed him a picture so he said he did. I think so.
He definitely remembers the camera.
– Asthma improved but asthmatic attacks still happened with humid weather.
Can you tell me if there are certain hours in the night that he gets dyspnea?
– Usually before the bed he gets worse, always like that.
Around 10 p.m. it starts worsening and then the peak would be at 5 in the morning.
– Between 4 and 5 a.m. or at 5 a.m.?
– I can’t tell you that because when it gets extreme then it is more often
and there is no time.
– But this 5 a.m. you said it, you know it,
you didn’t say it just like that.
– Yes between 4 and 5 a.m.
– There is an aggravation.
– Yes.
– Does he have breakfast?
– After breakfast have you noticed having diarrhea?
– No, not after breakfast.
– But you have definitely noticed humid weather?
– That’s definitely the trigger. It always was. Even two years ago when we came to see you.
– “Symptoms that may have been ameliorated and got worse again;
asthma better for 6 months after the first remedy,
after these initial 6 months it was fluctuating for the following 15 months.
With new diet introduced in February asthma suddenly disappeared”. What diet?
– There is a special that we introduced because of him.
– Without gluten?
– No, no carbohydrates, no sugar, no milk.
He didn’t drink milk so this was not affecting him cause he was allergic,
sugar he never wanted to eat.
– How does he know there is sugar?
– I don’t know. There was one time when he was touching and a little bit licking it
but that was it, I asked him to try a cookie and he tried it and he didn’t like it.
– He does not like sweets.
– No. I was very similar when I was young.
– I wasn’t obviously. (09:01)
- Is he in his play doing dangerous things? Walking on something dangerous,
on a high place where he can fall...?
– No. He always was a cautious boy.
– Is he afraid in the night staying alone? Afraid of the dark?
– No. Never was.
– Is there any urination during sleep?
– Yes, sometimes. Not all the time.
– You say that he had some asthmatic attacks on June 15, 29.
– Just when we went to Serbia before we came here.
– Was the weather humid?
– Extremely. And it’s not only asthma. First, he had wheezing and rattling, so that’s there.
When it is very humid then his stomach starts going inside
because he is struggling to push the oxygen and it was very scary
so we gave him the puffer, Ventolin, and at one point it wasn’t even working.
– The weather was according to your understanding humid
or did the weather forecast say that the weather is humid?
– No, it was raining every day and it was very humid, even visible, it was foggy.
– Generally you say he is much calmer, expresses more initiative in verbal communication.
Now can he verbalize everything?
– No.
– He can verbalize a few words.
– Not words. He can talk but...
- He can make a phrase?
– Yes. He asks for things, now he is very shy
because there are many new people obviously but if he spends some time with you
he will be different. So he can say what he wants, where he wants to go, what he likes...
abstract ideas.
– The fact he sits quietly here is because he is afraid
or because he understands he has to sit?
– Maybe he is a little bit anxious, I don’t think he is afraid. He knows that he has to sit.
I think he understands what we are talking about.
That’s why we are going to say that he is amazing. He is doing great now.
Talking so well and in school doing so well. We are very proud of him.
– Is he angry sometimes?
– Actually, when we came from Serbia he became a little bit more at me
but I have to say something about Serbia. When we went to Serbia first time with him
he was almost 2 years old and after that thing started we was developing ok
and then he regressed from 2 to 3.
So, at that time, at 18 months he stopped breastfeeding, he got MMR vaccine,
he got first ear infection treated with antibiotics then we came to Serbia,
grandmother passed away and he was there. She passed away in the hospital
but he was there until that day. So he was playing with her in the bed
and then that day when she went to the hospital he was crying
so he knew she was going to pass away.
Now it was the first time we went back over there, 8 years later,
I just wanted to mention that. And then the weather was very humid.
– His adaptability improved?
– Yes.
– He has more friends now?
– More independent and adjusted at school as seen by more teachers at school,
he is gentle, compassionate, smart boy with great sense of humor.
If you are not feeling well or his father he will be affected?
– Oh, yes, he would come and try to console or anybody else, ok, not the first time
but he would come and try to console. Especially if somebody is crying.
– There is any particular desire that he wants to eat, eggs, salami, meat, fish...
- That’s hard now to say because of his diet. He is restricted to certain things.
– Does he ask? Says why don’t you give me this?
– He was only asking for bananas, but I don’t think that’s a correct thing
because the other things he knows he cannot touch he doesn’t.
He loves the frozen juice, before we make the ice cream.
Frozen ice cream, frozen juice. That’s something he asked me the other day
and I made it with banana and he didn’t like it.
– Do you know if he grinds his teeth in sleep?
– Right now not, in Canada he used to, it was off and on,
I could hear him grind the teeth and tossing...
- Not anymore?
– Not now. Not lately. And in Greece now,
his breathing is much better, he is sleeping well.
- Is he thirsty?
– Not much. He used to drink juice a lot,
like orange juice, 2 liters a day, but we took it out because of the diet, he drinks water,
he used not to drink water at all, but now he drinks, but not too much.
– The water has to be cold? Very cold?
– No, normal.
I want to mention something about the sleep. He has a new bedroom as from last May.
– He has brother or sister?
– No. So he started sleeping in this new bedroom
and then he had at one point attack, in December and then he came back
and he is sleeping with us. So maybe that’s important.
He still doesn’t want to go back to his bedroom.
– He did not have a room for himself before?
– He had, but he never wanted to sleep.
So we made a new room.
– But still he does not want to go to the new room.
– He was sleeping by himself for 6 months and then he had attack during the night.
– He was not able to breathe, he got scared and came back.
– About the sleep, the new thing, that’s something he didn’t do before,
he sleeps on his back and sometimes with his hands up. Not all the time, but on his back.
He used to be different before.
When he is in a big distress with breathing recently with the asthma in Serbia,
he is all sweaty, a lot. Drenched in water.
But only when he has these extreme problems with breathing.
Usually he doesn’t sweat at night.
– You have to add something?
– Yes. He likes to be made laugh,
all the time when we are together we have to make faces and he laughs.
He loves to do that, to play with laughing. He likes funny things.
– Is he serious now?
– He is very serious.
– This is not time for playing. He is bored also.
– No. We also noticed that in Serbia
and here he seemed to be better when he is outside. That’s just recent. Breathingwise.
When he is outside and everything open, even though it was humid.
That wasn’t in Canada before. The last 3 weeks maybe, that’s the new thing.
– Is he crying easily?
– Yes, well it depends.
If he hurts himself physically, he is not crying, he doesn’t show physical pain.
Recently he had this pain in his leg, in the muscle...
- During sleep was this pain?– No, he woke up and started telling me.
But that was the first time he was crying for such a thing, usually he hits something.
But if you reprimand, if you tell him something, or I, or my husband raises a little bit
his voice, or just say “stop it! I am serious”, he cries. So he is very easily hurt this way.
– Perspiration during asthma.
– I have to confess something, I didn’t do anything wrong but it seems like...
We went to the dentist, one tooth was coming out and the old tooth is still there.
– You took it out?
– No. It’s still there.
So we went to the dentist, November 20th to see that,
just to monitor what we are going to do and I was entertaining him,
because he was so scared, the dentist put something
and he said what is that and said it was fluoride. I didn’t want to do that...
- Why he did that? To disinfect or what?
– God only knows.
– He told me for the gingivitis. But this is something he didn’t even tell me,
he didn’t ask me, he just did it. And I was furious
because his toothpaste doesn’t have fluoride.
– But otherwise he didn’t have any dental treatment. He is allergic to milk.
– But not only to milk.
– No. He had lots of allergies.
– The asthmatic attacks are usually in the night time or also on daytime?
– Also on daytime. But usually during the night he gets worse.
Whatever it was during the day, it gets much worse during the night.
He is also scared of animals but less now.
Dogs and cats terrify him but now it’s better but still there.
– If the animal is big like a cow, would he be afraid of that or you do not know?
– I think in Serbia he tried a little bit with the sheep,
so when he noticed that they were scared of him he liked that.
So he was chasing them a little bit. But keeping always distance.
He was playing with the sheep quite a bit. And as a baby he wasn’t afraid until 2.
He was feeding, we had a dog, a big black Labrador,
he was feeding him and everything was ok.
– What was the reason, was it the vaccination that preceded this situation?
– At that time also it was antibiotics. And that’s the only time in his life he had.
He had in November antibiotics and he was turning 2 in January next year.
And then on February he had 2 courses of antibiotics and that’s it for the whole time.
That was the timing also, 18 months I stopped breastfeeding
and then he also had MMR vaccine and then these antibiotics in between.
– The vaccine he had it how many months before you realized something is wrong?
– He had maybe 6 months or more, because it started after 2
and maybe 2 and a half we were sure something was wrong.
– MMR was in the vaccination?
– Yes.
– When was the vaccination?
– I think around 18 months.
We delayed it actually for 6 months to get it when he was 12 months
and he received it when he was 18.
– Why they delayed it?
– No, we did. We delayed all the vaccines. We didn’t want to vaccinate him.
– After that we actually stopped.
– You tried to delay and then you finally...
– I asked the doctor to give us 3 separate ones, not a combination.
We would pay, he said it doesn’t exist. I said without Immersol,
which is the mercury catalyst and he said we don’t produce it
and I said you don’t produce it now but you produced it a year ago.
But at the bottom line I could have said “change the doctor” but I didn’t change.
– You had information or an intuition?
– Both. We never believed in vaccines.
We also knew it was not the law but we couldn’t find out from the paper which form...
- It’s very hard to find a way to get exempted from the vaccines.
When he was around 3 we found Helen and he was officially exempted,
he didn’t receive any vaccine after that.
- But before that people would say there is a paper or form but nobody knew what.
– Nobody wanted to tell us essentially.
– I don’t know about that.
But we were raised in Serbia so we didn’t know that.
– Ok.
I think it is a lucky boy after his bad luck of being affected by the vaccination.
As I have said, as a general rule, which I have observed over the years,
autistic children who have started their problems after vaccination,
are much easier to cure than if they were born straight away with this syndrome.
So, in this boy for me it’s obvious because they say the boy was already speaking,
already behaving properly and suddenly he lost everything.
It was obvious that was the triple vaccination that had an effect.
Many times the effect does not immediately come,
it may come after a few months but the effect was terrible.
Fortunately we could see the first remedy
and now I believe his second remedy is also clear
for those that they know some Materia Medica of Homeopathy.
Who thinks he knows the remedy? That should be given now to the child?
One, two, three, four, five, six? Only six, seven, eight, nine.
I thought it would be more but it’s a new class.
Unfortunately the cases which come here, are, as you understand, the worst.
The most difficult. Because they have tried everything
and when they come here they are very difficult.
Otherwise a homeopath would have recognized quite easily. So it is difficult but...
What is the most impressive in the character of this child?
– Affection.
– But he wants affection or he gives affection? Both.
But what is also impressive is that when I asked whether the child is affected
if somebody is not feeling well and the child goes there and tries to console,
this shows a very affectionate child and sympathetic.
That means the person is suffering, that is what we call sympathetic.
Is not a simple sympathy, it is passionate sympathy,
that means I am suffering seeing others suffer. This is established there is no question.
What other characteristic comes from his character? He rejects authority.
If somebody is authoritative, tells him what to do he will not do it.
He just closes up and will not do it. He is a person against authority.
It’s a person who suffers a lot in humidity. In humid weather.
So until now you have been thinking of a remedy
which is very much sympathetic towards others, who is affectionate,
who is not accepting authority but at the same time he is affected physically by humidity.
And here we have the problem. Why do we have a problem? Michael?
– Because many times Causticum is better when it’s raining.
– Better in humid weather. We have been talking about
the characteristic of his character lead us to the idea of Causticum.
The remedy is Causticum. But Causticum is usually better in humid weather.
This child is worse in humid weather.
Not only that but the child is having the peak of the crisis in asthma around 5 a.m.
Now which is the remedy that has it?
Show me the remedy that has peak of asthma at 5 a.m. 4 to 5 a.m.
Natrum sulphuricum has this time of aggravation.
If you have a case of asthma where the person says
I wake up every night between 4 and 5 a.m. and I have my crisis that time
then Natrum sulphuricum is almost specific remedy for that.
You need one more point to confirm Natrum sulphuricum.
And this is that Natrum sulphuricum is worse in humid weather.
They are extremely sensitive to humid weather.
So that is why I was continuing to inquire,
because we have 2 remedies contradicting each other
and which one will be the uppermost at this moment to give
and follow with the other one etc.? So the decision is going to be difficult.
I was wondering whether anybody could tell me... Show me Causticum.
Is very sympathetic, you see repertory, it is in the third degree.
Mind anarchist, they don’t like authorities, sweets aversion.
It is a characteristic of Causticum. And this is impressive.
When a child has aversion to sweets then it is certainly aversion to sweets.
Usually children like sweets. He doesn’t like sweets. The fear of animals also.
Show me fear of animals.
Belladonna, Calcarea, China, Causticum is on the second degree. Show me fear of dogs!
You see Causticum is one of the 5 remedies. You see why you have the problem,
because you have 2 strong keynotes of a remedy for his asthma
and you have five keynotes for his mental emotional picture.
What should the decision be and for what reason you should decide this or that?
Maybe I am asking a difficult question but I will explain to you.
The cure of anybody should start from the mental emotional
and go towards the physical body,
so at this case we have symptoms from mental emotional sphere,
which are quite strong and symptoms from the physical body
which contradict the remedy that is needed for the mental emotional symptoms.
But if you give a remedy on the mental emotional
and the mental emotional becomes better
then the physical symptoms most probably will become worse.
If we decide to give Causticum, mentally and emotionally the child will be thinking better.
What we are interested here in, is not the asthma, it’s to build up again his brain.
This is the main target. The brain has been destroyed. Asthma is secondary.
Therefore if we have such a decision to make, the decision should be to give the remedy
that could affect the mental emotional picture and make the physical body worse maybe.
We have to go according to this rule and not the opposite.
Because if at this moment, you have to be very careful to what I say now,
we prefer to give the Natrum sulphuricum, the asthma will be better
but the mental emotional state will be worse. And it will come back
and they say the child is regressing, he cannot think again
and his starts having these symptoms... The asthma would disappear.
This is a rule that you have to think and it’s very clear in this case,
which means that if we give Causticum at this moment then the asthma will get worse
and most probably, at a certain point where his asthma will be much worse
and the asthma will manifest with great force between 4 and 5 a.m.
then Natrum sulphuricum will do the work. But the asthma will be worse at first
and that is when we say we have to choose the remedy according to a certain series.
You cannot give the third remedy underneath,
give it first because it will be pushing underneath symptoms
and confusing the uppermost layer. The problem with Homeopathy so far is exactly this,
because it’s so easy for one who hears and knows a little bit of Materia Medica,
who hears that the child has an aggravation between 4 and 5 a.m. asthma,
Natrum sulphuricum, and humid weather worse, Natrum sulphuricum immediately.
And that is wrong. That you will pay. Because they will come back
and they will say the child is not so good. When the child on a wrong prescription,
do you think it will go back to Causticum or to have Hyoscyamus?
Let’s say you gave the wrong prescription, Natrum sulphuricum,
the child starts regressing. Which remedy you are going to give?
You don’t know anymore because it may go right back to beginning,
to Hyoscyamus and instead of Hyoscyamus, because you thought of Causticum,
you give Causticum, another mistake. The series is Hyoscyamus, Causticum
and most probably the third remedy Natrum sulphuricum
where the boy will be in a quite good state,
maybe this boy can follow eventually a technical school,
can learn some simple technical things, he can be self – supporting,
but if you leave him like that, God knows how he will end up. Is it clear?
It’s a good teaching case by chance.
Because some of you who know quite good Homeopathy,
you will be thinking is it Natrum sulphuricum or is it Causticum.
You have been thinking of that strongly.
– If he will be having an asthmatic crisis, if he makes some aggravation, what shall we do?
– Give Natrum sulphuricum?
– No.
– No, I will tell you something about this because it’s a good thing she said that.
We were thinking of Natrum sulphuricum for the crisis but there is another remedy
that is most probably indicated or will be indicated when the asthma is full blown
and the other remedy is Sambucus nigra.
This is a remedy that has excessive perspiration during asthmatic crisis.
That is a keynote but with this keynote alone you may not do the job,
while Natrum sulphuricum has 2 keynotes; worse humidity and worse 4 to 5 a.m.
But if the asthmatic crisis changes from 4 to 5 a.m. to a constant crisis
in the night of asthma and perspiration you may give Sambucus nigra.