-Last time you did not take any medicine. You tell me after October what happened.
-The greatest change I can notice it that I'm going into much more direct and stronger
confrontation with my mother. For years and years I always tried to evade her and
in spite of that we kept having conflicts.
-And now she has the strength to confront her?
-I can endure better, I can stay there and listen and hear everything she has to tell me
without breaking down immediately.
-But does she state her own opinion?
-For months I tried to avoid the conflict, I did have contact but only shortly just as much
as I could take and then I went back into my house.
But then she, from her side was searching confrontation. She again started to accuse
me and to complain about me and I could remain in there, stay there, listen to what
she had to say and tell her my opinion. Then she really accelerated.
And I could endure it. She became really intense and there were many accusations
against me and at the end she cried but I could endure it.
Then I could also tell her all the things she had done to me which also weren't very nice.
-She managed to tell her what she had felt she had done to her?
-Not all, that's a long story but the most important things.
Then she was crying and shouting and expected me to understand her.
-How old is her mother now?
-85 but she is still completely clear at her mind.
-And I told her I don't want to understand you if you don't, for once, stop and say
I'm sorry for what I did to you or for what happened to you.
Then it took a couple of days and then she came to me and she still was angry but
she said, I'm sorry.
-For the beginning it's good.
-I can understand that my family was in a very difficult situation and crazy.
I can understand why some situations were the way they were and what happened
to me but I felt so much indignation that the situation was as it was and they put
me into it and I had to suffer and then making me responsible for it.
That was something I could not take. All these years my mother had the opinion that
it's my fault that she had to suffer so much because of me and I always felt such an
injustice but I could never express it to her, in any way.
I have to make a short break now because I really plan not to cry here again.
-It's OK if she wants to cry. No problem.
-I'm so embarrassed, I don't want it to happen. I would like to turn to the physical
complains. I had very severe pains the entire October and November up to Christmas.
-Where?
-Most of the time my right shoulder. The same thing I already had in May.
It continued for the entire year.
-The pains subsided in January?
-They start to change in a way. They were some days where they seem to ease off
a bit and I felt well I might be through this now but it again started and so actually up
to March I had long periods of time with pain, interrupted by few days with less pain
and then it started again.
-After March until now?
-Since March the periods with less pain have become longer and the painful periods
are not so painful. In fall the pains were so severe that I couldn't sleep for nights.
-Did she take any pain killer?
-No and when I saw Sabine I felt my own pains again so strongly I could hardly bear it.
But it got better. I now have less pains in my shoulder, my elbow and my wrist but now
the pains wandered into my knees. But it's not so severe as it was in the shoulders.
My feet are also very sensitive. They are often painful.
-Where?
-Mainly the soles of my foot when I have to walk much and sometimes I have pain in
my left big toe. It feels the way I could imagine gout from how I have been described it
even though I don't eat any meat and hardly I drink alcohol.
-Has she ever checked the uric acid?
-No.
-She can check it when she is back.
-The flashes of heat have become stronger. I never experienced such a warm winter
even though it was cold outside and sometimes it's alternating heat flashes and
perspiration, alternating with little chills suddenly.
The heat flashes begin in the face, my face becomes hot and burning, then it goes down
my neck and then it spreads down my middle part and then my entire body.
As very last thing, my feet burn. Everything is burning.
-But it goes from the head down.
-It starts on my face. I have to undress then and then I quickly cool down again and
feel cold.
My sensitivity towards dampness and cold together is still very strong.
Even in summer I can not tolerate wet clothing in my arms and if I wash my hands or
have to do anything else with water, I immediately have to dry off my hands again.
On the other hand I also can not tolerate great warmth or heat.
I like the sun but I can only stay in it for a short while. It is wonderful to see the sun
outside from here but if I come into the sun I quickly feel too hot and I become nauseous.
On the other hand I can't endure cold food from the refrigerator.
-So she needs either warm or room temperature? Or she needs warm food?
-I prefer warm food at least once the day even if it's only a soup. That's enough or tea.
When I'm thirsty I drink water with room temperature.
In the past half year there were times that I could not eat much.
-Did she lose weight?
-No. Like only half a croissant. Afterwards I felt satisfied, full, bloated and couldn't eat
anything. It's not always like that. Right now I can eat a bit more.
-From time to time.
-I got a cold in November. It wasn't very strong, no fever. I never have fever.
-We expect this year.
-I had pain in my throat and coryza. It was about one week medium strong, then it
got less but the complains lasted for another 5-6 weeks.
And on and off I repeatedly had watery discharge from the nose which was acrid and
hurting my nose. For a long time over weeks the feeling of mucus in my throat.
It was running down the back of my throat and I constantly had to swallow and hawk.
And couldn't speak so fluently because there was constantly mucus on the way.
-Her voice was affected? She had to clear her throat all the time?
-I wasn't hoarse, I had to clear my throat very often, the voice was somehow changed.
Between November and now the beginning of May a couple of times I had a kind of
vaginitis, the mucus membranes were sore and aching, partially it was so painful that
I had difficulty walking and I couldn't ride a bicycle, I couldn't sit on it.
-Such a thing she remembers having ever in the past?
-Yes. I was in homeopathic treatment for about 10 years and then I developed these strong
complains after one remedy. After it they gave me Kreosotum and then it was
gone.
-But does she remember if she was infected through intercourse.
-No, I don't think so. I can't remember.
-Previous to that was again, as a young girl, she had something like this?
-Definitely as a girl I did not have it.
-Does she remember having leucorrhea?
-Since the birth of my daughter almost 29 years ago, I almost constantly have more
or less leucorrhea.
-Was anytime that the leucorrhea was strong and she went to gynecologist and took
some medicine for it?
-Yes that was once around 1974 or 75.
-And if she remembers, she took medication for only 1-2 days or she took for a week?
-The usual time is one week.
-Does she remember if after this week, the leucorrhea disappeared?
-I can't remember.
-Does she remember what was the medicine?
-Clont was the name.
-There are some symptoms here which I would like to ask.
-You want me to finish before? -Yes.
-I repeatedly had inflammation of my gums last winter.
The last time was when I was on the island for 4 days.
-Concerning the leucorrhea now at this moment there is some discharge or very little
or nothing?
-Since my menstruation stopped completely about 3/4 of a year ago, I still had for
some months slight discharge and now it has completely gone.
-This inflammation of the vagina is still at this moment continues? It lasted how long?
-It lasted a few days. I had it for a couple of times and always lasted for a few days
but right now I don't have it.
-She had it several times?
-Within the last 3/4 of a year I had it a couple of times. I often have toothache, there is
one tooth which aches too often but the dentist can find no reason for it.
I had gastrointestinal infection at the end of December. I was kissed by a child that was
already ill, that's how I contracted it and within a couple of hours I was also ill.
-With diarrhea?
-It lasted for one week with nausea, vomiting and great prostration.
Diarrhea only the first day. What was really remarkable was that during this
gastrointestinal problem, my shoulder pains were completely gone and when I
recovered from gastrointestinal problems my pains were back, which just underlines
your theory.
From the beginning of February I had more energy again and sometimes I work for
24 hours at the time and continue the next day and sometimes I'm really amazed
that I bring up the strength to do all this, so I can't be that ill.
The problem is also that I often have an itching mostly on the upper part of my back.
I have to scratch until it burns and if I scratch till it burns and hurts, then the itching stops.
For a certain period of time.
-When this itching started?
-It has been long already. I didn't mention last time because there were so many other
things to tell, maybe 2 years.
-But if she mentions this now is more strong?
-Not really strong. I also sometimes have this itching in different parts of my body.
I always have to scratch something and when I scratch here it disappears from this
side and it appears to some other place. This can be anywhere in my body.
But I'm always scratching in some place. I had another cold in February also without
fever, with a cough, but I recovered quickly from it. It lasted 1 week but the cough
continued for 6 weeks.
When the cough and the cold were gone I started to have stomach pains.
Often I had a feeling about 1 hour after eating that I had stones in my stomach.
Very painful pressure.
-Is this a new symptom or she had it?
-I had stomach complains once before in 1968 or 69 when I had stressful job.
-Something similar?
-Yes but it was stronger including a gastritis. This time is not like that.
Another symptom reappeared. Sometimes my legs jerk and I can't hold them still.
-Jerking while sitting or in bed?
-When I'm resting, when I'm quite. Less when I'm sitting, more frequently when I'm
lying and before I fall asleep.
Then I had complains with my eyes. I feel as if I had sand in my eyes and there was a
constant burning, it was worse in the left eye. The doctor could not find anything special.
I'm supposed to wear my glasses more frequently and at the moment this is also better.
There is something I doubt quite a lot when the was in Kosovo started.
I felt great anxiety. This is going on for several weeks now and I seriously was thinking
whether I could travel into this area which is close to the war at all.
Very often every day I become aware how many people are affected by it and I compare
my life situation with the situation of those people who have to leave their country or
get bomb on their heads and I'm so glad that I'm OK, that I feel good.
But we never know what is coming towards us.
-I don't see here the trembling that was so strong before, external trembling.
Does she have it still when excited or just happen?
-I don't get it with every excitement but it was so strong because of the memory of my
childhood experiences.
-Last time interview she had it but now as she was relating the conversation with her
mother, I didn't notice it.
-I still need to bring up a lot of energy not to cry and not to tremble but it's true I've
got stronger.
-Also last time she had cracks in the corner of the mouth.
-This has not reappeared but when I have coryza because of the acrid exudation
I have cracks around my nose in the corner. And also during the time of vaginits I had
cracks fissures in the mucus membranes.
-How is her desire for salt.
-A bit less.
-What about the aversion for meat.
-My entire life I never liked meat and as a child I was forced to eat it.
Now I decide for myself.
-But she is a vegetarian or just she doesn't like meat and she eats fish or eggs?
-Coffee?
-Absolutely not.
-This is strong aversion.
-It is absolutely strong aversion, I can't even tolerate the smell of coffee. I had times when
I drunk a lot of coffee.
-That's all I wanted. Does she have anything to report?
-My aversion also to tobacco smoke has increased much. I can't breathe if a smoker
comes towards me. I think it's quite sad because many people I like a lot, they smoke.
But I just have to go away from them because I can't bear it. I developed varicose veins.
-Painful?
-Sometimes I feel pain in my right leg, the back of my knee. What I can not tolerate at all
is if I have to sit to some place where my feet have no support, I turn out to be a bit short
and most chairs are a bit high for me and my feet just hang in the air and I have no
support beneath them, I can not take it at all.
-She wants to give me an overall impression how she feels psychologically in general?
-Stronger concerning those things that I still have to take care in my life, that I have to
deal with, I have to get done.
What it also changed is that I noticed that sometimes I react more irritated towards some
people which I don't know from myself up to now. I think that's not so bad.
I can handle that once in a while.
-From the last time psychologically there is no much difference? It has been an
improvement or more or less the same?
-Yes I've become stronger. The main problem I see now for many years was this
confrontation with my mother and I didn't have such a breakdown anymore, the times
when she approached me and accused me and all these things. I didn't break down
anymore, that's good for me.
-OK.
-First of all you see the physical symptomatology following the right direction.
You say from shoulder, to elbow, to wrist, to knee, it's very good.
Another thing which pleases you to see is what?
-Discharges that make sores
-I'm pleased to see that the vagina's inflamed. This is a good sign. You are also pleased to see
from the physical point of view some old symptoms like the gastritis or the feeling of
the stones in the stomach. It is quite all right.
In this case I see 3 strong symptoms of another remedy.
You take the case and you see on one hand the direction is OK. She is more composed
she can express, she can confront the main problem that was the mother who had
suppressed her all these years, the trembling and you remember the state which she has
been before and all that is much more reduced.
All that it is solved but at the same time you see 3 strong symptoms of another remedy
and you have to ask yourself the same question, are you going to wait, are you going to
give another remedy and if you are going to give another remedy, the other remedy is?
-Staphysagria....
-No, you did not see the remedy.
-Pulsatilla is coming.
-Pulsatilla? No.
-Natrum muriaticum.
-Natrum muriaticum?
I'll tell you something. If you remember she had a symptom that did not fit with Causticum.
-Aggravation from cold and moist weather.
-Where Causticum is better with moist weather. She has an extreme aggravation from
moist. She can even have a little bit of water, she has to dry it.
But Causticum feels better when the weather is moist.
So this was a symptom that did not go with Causticum. This is one thing that you take
into consideration and then you see this symptom is not gone. So either it's going to go
away later on or the symptoms belongs to the underlying remedy.
Maybe you are going to search for underlying remedy which is worse with cold and moist.
Anyhow you have to ask, even if we come to the conclusion that most probably we have
an underlying remedy which is this or that, we have still to determine whether this level
which is the Causticum level has been exhausted.
Is this level out or she is still having the characteristics of Causticum?
She got a high potency 1 year ago. Is she out or maybe we have to repeat?
What makes you think that it is out or it is in?
She said another expression, which is very characteristic of the sympathetic element of
Causticum. She made a comment, who remembers? Before Kosovo.
Still she made another remark which showed me the sympathetic element still is quite
strong. And the injustice also is strong.
Can you see jerking of legs? Extremities, jerking of legs on falling asleep?
This is a new symptom? No. It's still a symptom that continues.
-Varicose veins is a new one she said.
-Varicose veins on legs so painful.
You see the new symptom that she develops is a physical symptom belonging to
Causticum. So what I'm driving at is, the sympathetic element is there.
Quite a lot of her symptoms are still there and we have the right kind of direction towards
the extremities and perhaps ending on the toes, fingers and toes which is Causticum.
Therefore in spite of the fact that maybe there is another underlying remedy
what shall we do? We wait or we repeat the remedy?
-Wait.
-I want to ask her what does she think?
She thinks that she needs the remedy at the moment?
We're going to repeat. We're not going away from this remedy. The remedy is acting
quite well but we're thinking whether we should give you another dose.
Do you think that you need this dose or you think, I'm good enough, leave me alone?
-Before I decide I would like to know what do I have to expect if we repeat?
-That's a good question. I can not guarantee.
-Why do you like to to repeat it then?
-I don't like to repeat it. I'm thinking, the class is thinking or some of the class is thinking
and we're asking you. You are only the patient now, you are not the doctor.
And you know how you feel and the doctor asks you, do you feel you need some extra
push at the moment or do you think things are developing quite well and I'm satisfied.
-Nevertheless I'm interested by my minds, I have an idea beforehand, do I have to come
with a strong aggravation or with a push to my development?
-Most probably she will have an aggravation again before she has the push.
-I have to work a lot the summertime and if I'm going to have such pains again I just don't
know how I'm going to tolerate, how to cope with this.
Do I have to expect such an aggravation like I had it last Autumn?
-Most probably the aggravation will be less. It's not going to be again so strong.
-Then I've courage enough to try it.
-OK. Now you hear your patient what she says and now you tell me who wants to
repeat the remedy?
7 courageous people plus the patient.
Who wants to wait?
We wait unfortunately.
Now concerning the remedy which I think it is underneath, which may come without
another dose. Once the sympathetic element is subsided or it subsides 50-60% because
she has her own character, she is not going to change, she always going to be on that
sympathetic.
But is she subsides 60% then you can say that Causticum has done whatever it could.
Therefore you can be thinking on the next remedy and I would like to have the symptom
aversion coffee.
She stressed, from her desires and aversions, two things. Aversion to coffee, no question
and aversion to tobacco, no question. Even people I like I can not stand their company.
Unfortunately I have to leave. You have to look in these two rubrics.
Calcarea and Nux vomica.
Show me now aversion tobacco. Calcarea and Nux vomica.
Now you look at aggravation coffee. Causticum is quite strong.
You can compare the two, the Causticum is in both.
Causticum may not take away certain symptoms. Those symptoms which are not taken
away by Causticum, belong to another layer.
that we had them originally in the Causticum, since they stay, they belong to the
underlying layer.
So the aggravation from wetness, this aggravation from coffee, this aversion for tobacco
-Belladonna, Ignatia, Nux vomica, Pulsatilla.
Therefore we may come to the conclusion that perhaps underlying Causticum, there is the
possibility of Nux vomica.
Do we give Nux vomica? No, forget it.
She said, I'm very irritable lately not too much but never happened before which is
something new for you. But if she comes to the point where she will come in the
consultation and say, I had a terrible fight with the mother and I told her what I thought
and I hit, you will see the anger being expressed and she will complain but it is too much
now. I express the anger too much so it creates a disturbance all around me, that is the
time you may think of giving a dose of Nux Vomica, not now.