-Last time what was the remedy?
-After Calcarea we prescribed nothing and then I got the acute.
-Just describe a little bit the acute.
-Now?
-Yes.
-I don't remember but it was I think an acute influenza that came suddenly
after being wet after perspiring. And you gave Arsenicum 200.
-The way you say it, it's very simple.
The way your friends were telling us it was very  dramatic, you could not move from bed,
you had high fever, you did not want to take any medicine, leave me alone, let me die etc.
-Not that much.
-Then I asked you to take Arsenicum 200, we did not see the case, you did not come here.
And then what happened?
-I fell asleep for a couple of hours, after taking the remedy
and it was in the middle of the day and I woke up feeling much better.
The fever felt as it had gone down a little bit and I had more energy and there was
less pain in the lungs. So I was much better after some hours.
-You actually had pain on coughing.
-Yes and the whole chest and the lungs.
The next morning we had to get early to the airport
and I felt pretty good and I had a refreshing sleep and normally I don't experience that.
That was the first time I can sit in Skiathos and don't look around
because all the other times I had to be the watcher of the suitcases
while the others were shopping.
-This time you went.
-Yes I felt very good, still I had a lot of clothes, still a bit aching.
Being outdoors wasn't in the beginning so good either but very fast it got much better.
There was a change when I got home because it was getting better so fast
but when I got home I had to see my parents, to pick up my cat and then I was confronted
with a lot of negativity for many hours.
-What kind of negativity?
-My mother especially was hysterical and angry because my brother had been married
for many years and his wife had just left and all this anger towards her, condemnation
she just poured out on me for 3 hours and I was sitting there. So I had a big reaction.
When I come home, I cried, I got depressed all kind of things and I suddenly felt
that all fell apart again, that all the good things that I was building up.
-How much lasted this disintegration?
-A couple of days I was able to slowly come back.
But I felt the acute and the coughing and a lot of things from the influenza stayed on longer
than it might have been without this incidence.
-Did you take another dose of Arsenicum?
-No, I was thinking but I did not.
-Very good.
-I don't know if you want all...
For about 5-6 weeks I had very exhausting coughing and hoarseness and stitching pain
in the lungs and mucus and different things, I don't know if you want all these symptoms.
-As you said it, it's good enough.
-Other reactions after Arsenicum. I noticed the first week I did sleep better
because that is one of the main problems for years, the sleeping.
-Tell me something. Before, that you have taken a lot of medicines have you taken Arsenicum?
-Yes.
-Continue.
-But there was some things that disturbed the sleep after one week, so then that
I didn't tell but it was mostly noises from outside my window.
A lot of construction work and big tracks and digging and explosions.
This is lasting even now. So when I come home ...
-This apartment is yours?
-No, I rent it.
And also other things like more frequent urination started again.
So I was running back and forward, back and forward, several things disturbing my sleep.
But the first week it was good. I slept 10 hours and after about one week I had sudden diarrhea
and a lot of distention and gas and lasted for some days and that is symptoms
that I had for many years earlier, 15 years earlier.
-What was happening by that time?
-It was during period with bulimia, anorexia, I took a lot of laxatives to lose weight
but I did have no constipation, I was dancing but it's many years ago, almost 25 years ago.
-And since that time these symptoms of sudden diarrhea was left with you or it was
many years since you didn't have this symptom?
-I had it on and off but for 15 years I had diarrhea. 10-15 times the day.
-With blood some time?
-No, I don't think blood.
-So that's another thing that you now tell us, that you have been taking drugs for...
-Yes it was terrible, I don't want to remember this thing.
Another thing after Arsenicum I got very much less thirst and I wanted mostly warm drinks
but after 3 weeks the thirst started coming back and I started having bigger sips again.
-You still have this type of thirst? You need sips frequently?
-Yes but it changed a little bit again, I don't drink so much as before.
After the remedy I felt a little bit more at ease, I'm not so restless, especially
when I sit down to do some work.
I usually get very restless when I have to sit and that was better so I could concentrate more
and I was also a little bit better with the confusion.
My head was a little bit clearer. After about 1 week I started having lots of lacrimation.
-Sudden lacrimation or when you are in the air?
-Yes mostly the fresh air made it and in the evening was worse and light.
But there was a lot of symptoms from the eyes, itching and rubbing and swelling.
-Like you are having a hay fever or allergy?
-Yes.
-Did you have this before? You remember?
-Not so much but I think after taking Phos I had this hay fever reaction also.
-In the past?
-Yes 4 years ago and it was like sand in the eyes and itching and very photophobic.
And I could hardly hold them open, I wanted just to close them and don't do nothing
and I could hardly see, it was kind of blurred.
-Because of excessive lacrimation?
-Yes.
The whole area around the eyes was swollen, especially the upper part.
-In the morning when you wake up?
-Especially in the morning after sleeping long but the whole day, it's like bags.
It never has been so much before, I had a lot of this swollen thing around my eyes for many years
but this was...
-Too much.
-Yes and I also felt the eyelids were inflamed and hard and all the area around the eyes
is very sensitive to everything and that also got aggravated.
I can not take water or any cream, everything irritates and the tears get very excoriating,
like burning.
-As a child you did not have hay fever in spring?
-I don't think.
-You don't remember.
-My brother had it but I don't think so.
A little from laying on the grass and also I got more hungry for different foods.
-What kind of food?
-I wanted to have cheese and more bread and all the things that I don't really tolerate
so good and I started having butter and this gluten and more fruits
but it started a lot of distention and cramp and pains and a lot of problems started again,
which is much better if I keep a strict diet. So I don't know if this is the remedy.
-But you continued to take bread?
-Not so much. I decided I take once in a while.
-You mean every second day you take one piece?
-Not so much, it was for a short while but dairy products, butter and cheese I started taking.
-And milk you can take?
-No.
-You take cheese and yogurt?
-Cheese and a lot of butter I desire.
-The most strong desire you have now is butter?
-Bread and butter and ice-cream also, mostly ice-cream. I can eat many times the day.
-And you take it?
-No, I try not to take it but sometimes.
-You are afraid to put on weight?
-No but if I start having sugar, I get this craving and restlessness and all this,
a lot of problems and sleep is getting worse. So I noticed if I'm not eating sugar,
I feel much more calm and peaceful and much better.
And also with changing this diet, I also felt a lot of old problems
with the dropping of blood sugar, sudden hunger and cold sweat and shaking of the hands
and I just have to eat and very much restlessness.
-Hypoglycemia?
-Yes, I used to have for many years very low and it did not change so much after eating.
A lot of problems with that, since I was a little kid.
-But what you did in the past?
-I tried different diets and I was better eating protein and I tried different things
but this was since I was a small kid and I didn't know what it was.
-But I don't remember telling us before this symptom. Now you have it again, that means
you had it before.
-It has been better for a while. After Arsenicum I started having some dribbling of urine
while coughing and I don't think I had it before and it lasted about 3 weeks
but after about 4 weeks I started to feel stronger.
More optimistic, more happy and also self-confidence was improved a little bit
because that has been a big problem and after some weeks also from many remedies
I get also perspiring and the odor of axilla get more strong, so I wash and wash...
-What is the odor?
-It's difficult... maybe like garlic, sweet, I'm not quite sure and it's like
you can not wash it away but it's especially if I'm anxious like now, it comes.
I also got aggravation from neck pain, I told you about this injury of my neck
and several years with that terrible pain.
-How is this pain now?
-It's still comes and goes but it is better than in the beginning but still it's there
and especially after sleeping, I wake up as if it's out of place, as if something
has changed in the vertebrae and first thing I do is this.
-In the morning?
-Yes and also several times during the night.
It is better but it has been acute, I had to wake up and do it many times during the night
but it is better and also a headache comes from this neck pain, I wake up
and have headache in the occiput for several hours usually especially if I sleep long.
And after I start walking about and moving, it starts to going away.
I also had some acids coming up that I don't think I had so much before,
sometimes if laying on the left side, sometimes if I sit down and get a pressure up here
but it didn't last for so long.
And there is also problems with dyslexia.
I don't think I have told you that either but it started actually getting worse after Calcarea,
progress, getting worse and worse but now I think it's getting a little better again.
It also brought up some pain in the sacral, lumbar area but I did have a fall in the winter
time, I fell on the ice and maybe it was this. Rheumatic pains came back.
-Where?
-Everywhere in the body, especially knees, legs and cold draft always makes it worse.
This came back.
-Joint pains. She calls them rheumatic, she has mentioned here wrists, mostly the right wrist.
-That was something for a short while, I had this carpal, it was after a remedy.
And I also noticed when I eat butter or this gluten, I got more diarrhea and loose stool.
Also I got a strong need to create more and more order around because I have
a lot of chaos in my house.
-So to put in order but most probably you have the energy to do it also.
-Yes, I have more energy but I was not able to keep up right, not really able to keep order.
-It's good enough.
-I think I should mention a little bit about that because that is a real problem
to be organized, to structure, to make a plan, everything is a mess and I had piles with papers
and things I can not organize and I suddenly find old letters and bills that I have not seen
and I put it away. It's very difficult for me and I try to make this, a small clear.
-Very good, you have to be more organized but you felt the need to be more organized.
-Yes, I can not relax seeing all this mess around, I can not sit down reading something.
-So you want first to put an order and then start working.
-Yes. Also some cystitis problems came back and pain in the bladder and pressure here
in the urethra and that I also had much before.
But after a while I got a little sleep because of this noise, so I started going down again
and got irritability and bumping things and dropping things because I was so tired.
Also I had an aggravation, I told you last time I can wash and wash
and never feel clean enough, this also got even worse. I can stand half an hour in the shower
and scrub myself with this hard.
-Do you feel that you stink because of the perspiration?
-No, the feeling of not being clean enough.
Also when I'm at home I can go and wash my hands 20-40 times the day.
-Why? For no reason or you touch something, you think it's dirty and then you wash?
-Yes I touch.
-When you gave us your history was any sexually transmitted disease?
-No, I don't think so, I might have had chlamydia but I'm not sure because they
had an operation because of infertility, some years back and afterwards they told me,
I might have had it because I had a lot of ...
-You get what?
-Adhesions after operation? Tissues which become hard?
-No, they grow from one place.
-Cicatrices outside where you can see?
-No, it's inside.
-Adhesions all right.
-So I might have that and I also had venereal warts but I don't think I had gonorrhea.
I also noticed that the change in the diet I was more peaceful, before I was more restless
and the whole nervous system gets more easily excited
and itching as everything was more sensitive.
And the clammy feet started a little bit again, not as much as before.
-And the perspiration during night?
-It was last time?
-I'm asking you.
-During the acute? It can be, it comes and goes, it's not always but I can have that
a lot in the night but if I take the clothe on and covers off I start to get cold immediately,
so I have to have a lot of covers.
-Do you feel the cold more than before?
-Yes.
-Do you feel you are restless more now?
-Not really.
-Did you have any suicidal thoughts?
-No.
-Did you develop any fear or you have any fear coming back or anything?
-I mentioned this fear of dogs.
-Which is strong or you will underline it once or twice?
-It got a little bit worse, it was very strong but now I think it's going back a little bit.
-Also the stiffness you had was quite strong but you say still the stiffness is there?
The same as before or worse now?
-I'm not sure.
-When you lie in bed do you feel restlessness in your legs,
moving your legs mostly or not so much?
-Yes, I can be very restless in the legs, yes I can.
-Also you have said that your menses cease when you lie down.
-Always.
-This continues?
-Yes.
But I think I got more in a hurry again, the feeling of never have enough time.
But I had an acute, so I'm taking a remedy.
-What do you take?
-I took Eupatorium Perfoliatum.
-Because you had an acute.
-It was in the beginning of February.
-What kind of an acute it was?
-It was very strong influenza, very sudden and people told me this can last for weeks
and at that time I just had started a work with children in school, so I needed to get well.
-You wanted to get well immediately and you took Eupatorium perfoliatum?
-D200.
-And it helped you?
-Yes after 20 min all these pains, I had terrible aching pains in all inner organs,
everywhere and I couldn't sit, I had to lay down, the back was as if broken, very strong.
-Very strong, very sudden.
-But again one hour earlier I had been very cold on my feet and this often comes and
also I was afraid of pneumonia again but it was bronchitis with a lot of mucus
that I couldn't get out.
-Afterwards?
-No from the very beginning, it went right down. Very sudden.
-Very sudden it went down and you started coughing and the coughing how much lasted?
-I have to tell you but I was really depleted, I could not hardly stand on my legs,
I was really ill.
The first day I went to work, I managed because this was the first day, so I felt I had to go.
-What work?
-With children 6 years old in school, just an assistant to help some special kid needs
some special care and I had not been working for so many years, so I wanted this so much.
-And you managed to go after Eupatorium?
-Before I took.
-And then?
-No, I had to stay for a week in bed. I tried but it was impossible, I had very high fever
and usually I don't get fever.
-I remember the last time you had fever it was Arsenicum and you said
that was the first time in your life.
-Yes.
-But this time again you had a high fever. Did you call any doctor to listen to your lungs?
-From the very beginning, I went to work and I went to the doctor just to see
if it was a pneumonia but that was in the very beginning of the flu and he said bronchitis
at that point, with a lot of mucus and he said it was a special influenza
that really stayed for a long time.
-You did not take any other remedy except of this?
-Yes, because it stayed for a week and a lot of the symptoms did not go away,
the pain and all the aching went away very fast but...
-Then you needed another remedy, what remedy?
-Causticum.
-You took Causticum, that's why I see some Causticum symptoms. What happened?
-A few hours later my cough was better, it was not so hard, not so wild, more loose
and I could get out some mucus, so very fast afterwards and I had a lot of nausea
during the acute and that got also better and I had no appetite and aversion to food
and all the appetite came back.
I wanted very much now cheese and bread and butter, even more.
And generally I felt better after a day and more strong, so I could go to work,
I had to stay one more day because I reacted so strong to the draft and to the fresh air,
so I stayed one more day, to be sure but even though the cough went worse again,
after going outside. So after Causticum the draft has been really strong and the cough.
-The sensitivity to the draft and the cough became very strong.
-Yes.
-Why didn't you take Rhus tox straight away from the beginning,
because you seem to have had strong Rhus tox symptoms and the last time we repertorised here,
we saw Rhus tox was coming, you remember?
-No, you have mentioned Causticum but Rhus tox I can't remember.
-I see the repertorization here from the last time. Rhus tox was the first remedy.
-But in the beginning of this acute, Eupatorium I felt was really indicated
because the main problem was really this aching in the bones.
-Yes but the same is with Rhus tox, the main problem is aching all over. It doesn't matter.
It's OK.
-But there was a lot of other symptoms I did not tell you that go for Eupatorium.
-You were feeling cold you said, it's started with feeling cold in your feet
and then it became very painful all over the body and then you had coughing.
-Yes but I thought I had caught something from the children.
-Sure you had influenza, there is no question but I'm just wondering whether Rhus tox
might have been better than Eupatorium. But Eupatorium acted so immediately,
maybe it was correct.
-Between that time I could hardly think. I had no energy to repertorize, I was too sick.
-Then what happened after the second acute?
-I got and aggravation after Causticum with coughing and losing urine,
that was getting more strong and after some weeks it stopped again but Causticum
also made me more cold, more freezing and all this aggravation from the draft.
I think I started going outside in the fresh open air a little too early
because it came back.
-You wanted to go to work and not to lose the work.
-I felt so ashamed you know, it's irresponsibility.
-It's like the devil interferes.
-Normally I would not have taken anything.
-It's OK, no problem.
-But Causticum helped me a lot getting all this mucus out because it was all stuck
but for some days this bronchitis and these pains lasted.
After Causticum, after 14 days I got a new, I don't' know if it's an acute
but constant mucus from the nose and I use a lot of papers, all day and night,
it lasted for 10 days and the hoarseness got very strong again and I had difficulty talking,
I lost my voice trying to talk and the lachrymation from the eye started again.
A lot of sties in from the eyes.
And a lot of itching and problems around eyes and also coughing started again for a while.
But it did not last so long, about 10 days. The hoarseness was a problem after Causticum
because at that point I was doing an audition, I was singing and I could not sing
for almost 2 months.
That I had a lot before, irritation from air, if I was talking loud or singing, even crying,
I had to stop crying because I started to cough so much that I almost vomit.
I can not cry because this irritation, so I had this a lot.
And after Causticum also a lot of these rheumatic pains came up again and especially
in the knees, the legs, the neck and the back coming back and with a little bit of draft,
I lose my voice.
But after some weeks after Causticum I generally felt much better and more optimistic again
and more joy and more open to people and more confident, I wanted to be more with people
and more centered in a way in myself and more energy, more strong
and all this chronic fatigue it helped a little bit but the weakness in the physical got worse.
The muscles, the legs, I can hardly walk. I used to be able to go for walks
but no other exercises because I was too weak, no energy but now I don't' even walk much.
-Here how you come? By bike?
-No, I've been trying usually with the car.
-You said you can not walk when you feel like walking?
-No, I feel more weak in the physical, just rising my arms and put some clothes up
I'm tired for nothing.
After Causticum even more stiffness, especially after sleeping.
2 months after Causticum I also had an acute with vomiting very sudden,
it started in the middle of the night and it continued the whole night and then I got diarrhea.
-You had eaten the previous day something...?
-No, I don't think so.
-How are you so sure?
-I usually am very careful, at that time I don't eat so much.
-No, if I eat outside I very often get this, not vomiting but diarrhea.
-You had not eaten outside.
-No.
-Did you take any medicine for that?
-No, it lasted for a couple of days but I got nauseous after that and that's about it
but things that are bothering me today is postponing things, if you can underline that 4 times.
It's a big problem, it gives me this stress and I don't know why I do it.
-You seem not to have enough time to do whatever you want to do and that's why
you postpone a lot of things, it's not that you are involved into many things.
-That also but I think is as if I rebel in doing and being organized, as if I have
a kind of an aversion to it and wait to the last second and I really want to change this
because it is so much problems and I think it also has to do with being with not so much energy
and I have to push myself, so adrenaline and I get this energy and I have to
and I get more energy out of that, it's like a kick.
With this I have to sit down and write and go home from the class and do
and not follow  the lesson because I postpone.
-Is anything that makes you interested to do, is anything that gives you joy in doing?
-Singing and dancing, I love to dance but I don't have the energy to dance so much
but I used to love it very much.
-So singing and dancing is your best thing, you look forward to doing it, correct?
-Yes and if I go home from here, the first thing I do is I put the music on
and start to sing always before I get into the house, the first thing and music,
Music in general ameliorates many, many symptoms.
-Here with this weather, which is quite warm, with this jacket you don't feel very warm?
-I'm pretty warm now because I'm anxious.
-In general?
-I'm so cold, very cold and this winter I've been thinking of moving away from Norway
I can not stand this anymore and this is not warm enough, today I've been really freezing
2 wool shocks and wool sole underneath and I was freezing and then the wind came and
then I had all this cold, the whole body and in the back and the draft.
-The draft now you feel even more than before?
-Yes, the draft this morning was terrible for me, I got so cold and I went home
and I put the blankets and I had a lot of croissants. But maybe I should say I took this test,
the blood sample, the thyroid and this level was quite low and all people said to me
this is not normal, I'm so cold that everybody else is warm.
-How many times you had hypoglycemia?
-So many, almost all my life.
-But I mean now, the last few months, you would just have it twice or you had it 20 times?
-Maybe 10-20 times but not as bad as before, it was not like I was fainting.
Some of the times were strong and some others lighter.
I also have headache from strong odors and I also get constriction, not able to breathe
and I feel very terrible.
-Your thirst is less than before you would say and for cold as before or not so cold?
-More cold but before I drunk room temperature but now I drink a little bit more cold.
It's not good because my whole body gets cold, I start freezing.
-The milk you don't drink it because it affects you badly or
because you don't like the taste of it?
-I don't like it so much but I also tend to get diarrhea, I used to like it more
but I had one yogurt here but it did not taste so good.
But after Causticum I also had some anger I was able to get out
and I said "no" and that felt good.
-Did you speak at all to your mother, did you have a special discussion?
-A little bit.
-Did you tell her something of what you hold inside?
-What does she say?
-As usually she just pulls away from me and she doesn't call, I'm just the big problem.
-But you want her approval or her consent that she has really done something wrong with you?
Do you expect that she will... or do you want it?
-Of course I want it but I start to understand I can not expect it
because she will never give me, so it's better for me not to expect
because then it just hurts me again, so I try not to expect anything.
-Later on your mother got away from this anger with your sister in law who left?
-It's a little bit better but if I talk to her, it's the same thing.
And she is so powerful this woman, it's like the whole house is vibrating with her.
Even is she is not there.
-Is she huge or she is lean like you?
-It's about my size.
-What about sweets? Only ice-cream or sweets also?
-Sweets also, a little bit more but I decided not taking no sweets, I can be able to control it
but when I taste a little bit again, it comes back.
So I had ice-cream a couple of times here and then I feel desire for sweet again
but it's not as much as before, but it's mostly ice-cream.
After Causticum my menses came 4 days earlier and that never happened before.
Usually I'm very later but also less scanty, even less scanty, hardly anything.
-Menses get scanty, not less scanty because if they are less scanty, it becomes more.
-It's been scanty always but after Causticum even less.
-Now it's worse.
You have said last time lying in bed in general makes you worse, you feel bad,
do you still have this idea that lying in bed is no good for you?
-It's not that I think I told, it's mostly an anxiety going to sleep
because of a kind of fear for the bad or for the night.
-This was the idea, yes.
-Maybe it's a little bit better.
-Also you had very strong problems with your memory. How is that?
-I have to read.
-I can see you have to read but you also have a lot of things to say also.
-Yes, I think it is improved a little bit and when I started this work
I had to face 17 new kids and I remembered all the names and that was very new
but the teachers I still don't remember the names but with the children
I remember the birthday.
-Very good.
You come inside in the analysis so if we want to ask you something we can ask in the class.
-But maybe I should mention that I found out that the vitamin B12 was very low
and it was because of antibodies towards these intrinsic factors and I did not know,
so it was for many years being low. So now I have to take these injections.
-For vitamin B12 you take some injections Why don't you take vitamin?
-Because of these intrinsic factors it doesn't work with vitamins,
you have to take injections and after that I also feel my memory...
The day I'm going to take the injection I feel more
clear, especially that day I have more energy, I feel I can do more.
-What about the second day?
-Yes but...
-What about diarrhea, you said sometimes diarrhea?
You have stool every day or you have constipation?
-Never constipation.
-And the stool is soft or formed?
-After this acute with diarrhea and vomiting, it has been very soft and often diarrhea.
And anticipation is also a problem.
-How many symptoms you have all together?
-29.
-29?
-But I have a couple more. After Causticum I started losing so much hair.
And cigarette smoke I can not tolerate. But I also desire tangerines and oranges.
-Lately or all your life?
-Yes, as long as I can remember.
-You crave for oranges.
-Yes and spicy food also.
-What about fear of thunderstorms?
-I used to love it but it has gone a little less.
-What about dark? You switch off the light, you go to sleep with total darkness
or you want some light in the room?
-In the beginning I like some light in the room but it's no problem, I can have it.
-Do you think you have some anxiety about your brother, your mother, your relatives
do you have any anxiety about their health?
-Yes but I try not to because I feel it's too exhausting, I try not to especially
for my mother and father but they don't listen to what I say and they keep on
doing their stuff.
I try to make them work less because they work and work and my father has a lot of problems.
-What your father is doing? What work?
-He is a mechanic in the airline and they also have a shop and he used
to have a lot of work before, day and night, he hardly slept but now I try to push it away
because there was too much pain here.
I cannot help them, I try.
Even when my mother talked for 3 hours and put this to me I tried to help her but it's useless.
I was asked to speak about a little bit concerning repertorization,
what kind of repertorization we can be using in cases in general.
So I have some guidelines which I was thinking I would give you or you know most probably.
But let us say that you don't have a computer and you are using manual repertorization.
The manual repertorization basically has 2 types. One writing all the remedies
and you have in front of you all the symptoms and all the remedies.
This is almost impossible to do and therefore usually they reduce this
to some important symptoms and you look through these symptoms to see which is the remedy
which mostly goes through this.
The other way of repertorization is the eliminating repertorization.
That means you start with one symptom and has 50 remedies, then you start with another symptom
which has 35 remedies, you start with the third symptom which has 25, 3,4 and perhaps 1
and then in the end you see which remedy comes through.
This is the way I used to repertorize also before the computers.
The problem is, in both of these repertorisations, whether you want to write all these.
This eliminating repertorization, every time you put a new symptom
less remedies come through the repertorization.
Here is 50, here is 30, 20,15, 8, 5 and here comes 3 in the end.
Between these 3 you chose one remedy. This is eliminating repertorization.
This repertorization has the problem that you are leaving out certain symptoms
that maybe are important.
This repertorization of writing everything, all the symptoms, all the remedies,
sometimes there are 250 remedies and you have a problem in looking through all the symptoms
and choosing between them the right one.
Therefore the computer has made definitely much easier this manual work.
With the manual work, the best repertorization, of course, is the eliminating repertorization
but you have to chose the correct rubrics.
If you don't chose the correct rubrics, from the very beginning you may be losing the remedy,
which you should give.
And now I want to, on the occasion of this case which Margaret has inserted 28 symptoms
between 28-29, you have a problem because in the bulk of these remedies
you may lose actually the correct remedy.
What you will do? There is a solution.
After you hear all these, this and this and that you go back either by your memory
or by asking even the patient what are the really strong symptoms
and the really bothering, strong, clear, bothering.
So you go back and you say in this case for instance, let's do the test to see
how many people will give the 5-6 symptoms out of the 28, which are really there.
And you put them either in eliminating or you put them in just flat repertorization.
From general symptoms, tell me one.
-Sensitivity to draft and cold.
-Worse cold and draft. Do you agree with this? Is anybody who does not agree?
So what you think is correct, that is a strong symptom. Give me another one.
-Lack of vital heat.
-This is a problem if you do it because you will insert into your repertorization
twice the same symptom. Lack of vital heat, either you take lack of vital heat or worse cold.
If you take both because you underline 3 times or 4 times in her case, you will get Arsenicum
or Calc carbon, Rhus tox.
So you have to be careful in repertorization not to use 2 similar rubrics
which indicate the same symptom.
So you say worse cold is enough or lack of vital heat, yes you take lack of vital heat,
either the one or the other, not both.
Never do this because you will come down to the wrong remedy.
-She has strong desire for bread and butter.
-Bread and butter. Who agrees with this desire of bread and butter,
one of the first six strongest symptoms.
-No.
-Who does not agree? They do not agree.
-It's a very strong symptom because she eats a lot, so much, in my family we use
the packet of butter for a month and she can use it for a week, so it's very strong desire.
-This is good but if she has said it in this way, it could have been.
The way she said it it's not.
She minimized the importance of this symptom by saying it in such a way.
Never mind what you say is a strong symptom.
-Another symptom is menses ceases on lying down. You can take that symptom.
-Music ameliorates.
-She did not say ameliorate, she said?
-Yes.
-What ameliorates?
-Her singing.
-Who says ameliorates? What? All the symptoms? She wrote it. Where is she?
-Music ameliorates a lot of my symptoms, in general I feel much better.
-Music ameliorates.
-That also yes.
-If you are so certain, I did not hear it as being so certain, you can take it, better music.
-Only two remedies, Tarentula, Aurum also it can be ameliorated by.
-She has a strong aversion to cigarette smoke.
-I didn't see it as so strong.
-Mind postponing things or not enough time to do things or short of...
-In a hurry.
-She mentioned that she doesn't have enough time in the day, that's why she postpones.
-What is the difference in the rubric?
-I think one comes from the other.
-Where you search in the rubric because she says, I'm in a hurry.
-I'm not so sure it's in a hurry because she is postponing, that's why she is in a hurry
because then she has very little time left.
-If there is a symptom, for instance, I think I'm walking on the clouds,
it's a very nice symptom but you can not find it in the Repertory.
Now what you say can you find it in the Repertory?
-Mind postponing things.
-Yes sure, you put it.
-Postponing everything to the next day.
-Which is the remedy? Medorrhinum, Nux vomica, Platina and Silica. Postponing.
How many symptoms you have? 1,2,3,4,5 one more.
-Desire to wash.
-Washing her hands.
-Now we have 6 symptoms.
-Now what you do in repertorization, you take the most...
As you chose 6 important symptoms you start putting them in your repertorization
whether manually... Make another case.
-I made a new case now with these 6 symptoms.
-I wanted to go more slowly, that means you put, let us, worse cold, worse draft,
menses ceases and postponing, music ameliorates wait, later on.
So you have 4 symptoms and you can make a repertorization.
Immediately you go and look what is the suggestion out of 4 strong symptoms,
it says Silica and Medorrhinum and then all the others come almost...
-Only Silica has all 4 symptoms.
-It's very interesting that Silica has all 4 symptoms. So you get an idea, then you think
back. You say, this case can it be Silica?
Postponing, female genitalia ceases, very interesting, what you need for Silica?
To be constipated for instance. Usually Silica is constipated. She is not.
But Silica is really very cold and very much aggravated by draft.
Let's go now and add one symptom by one symptom and then you put in a hurry and
look again at your repertorization.
So if you are doing it manually, Silica will be eliminating and Silica only will be coming down.
Already by the 4th symptom Silica will show as the only remedy going through.
Where do you feel the draft mostly, can you tell us?
-Along the spine I think. In the bones.
-Not here?
-Also there, the upper part of the body and also the abdomen today
and in the wind I got pain in the uterus and the patella.
-Bread and butter it is true what she said?
-Yes I eat much.
-Is it true?
-Yes.
-Why don't you say it? She did?
-Not in this way.
-OK, put desire bread and butter. What symptom you wanted to say?
-Worse exertion.
-You said that we shouldn't give 2 similar symptoms like drafts aggravate and cold air aggravates.
-No, they are not similar, they are different symptoms. Similar is lack of vital heat,
worse cold, general.
The draft it may be not aggravated by cold but aggravated by draft, it's different.
Aggravation by draft is very strong.
Bread and butter, did you find?
-Yes.
-I want to ask you is it a desire butter, is it a desire bread and butter
because there is a big difference.
-What you would say? You desire butter?
-Both but very much bread because I used to keep a strict diet and I want this
because I didn't have and I desire very much bread but I don't take it.
But I also mentioned anticipation is a big problem.
-Anticipation.
-I've been worrying about this exam for many months and I can get diarrhea from this.
-OK put ailments from anticipation and strong symptoms. Bread and butter put 3 times.
-I think she said that she had a strong desire for ice-cream.
-Put strong desire for ice-cream, one by one and every time you put one symptom,
show me the effect. This is real repertorization.
Whether you do it by hand or by computer you should come to the same conclusions.
The idea of Pulsatilla is not there? Remedies? Psorinum but Medorrhinum and Silica
still are leading.
Now the next? Washing hands we put, postponing we put, OK.
You can continue putting the symptoms and every time you look, tell me the next symptom,
put stiffness on cervical region. Make it more on waking if you can find it.
Very good, put it 3 times.
-I'd like to add something because I told you I was thinking about moving to some warmer place
and lately I've been thinking that I realized that I can not live in a place
if it is not near the ocean. I have to be near the ocean.
-Ahhh!!!
-I told you this before also.
-Put better in the ocean, she said desires oranges, put desires oranges. She said it.
And she says really butter and she says bread also, she said it,
she expressed it now not inside. I will tell you in the end of course.
Now you do all this analysis and you do it especially in the cases
where it is not a case where you have worse from the sun, worse headache from 10-3,
desire salt 3 times.
Then you don't have to repertorize but in this case, you have a problem, 29 symptoms.
She gave symptom, symptom, symptom, you have a problem and that is why
I show you how you start repertorising and getting ideas about the possible remedies.
Then you study like this and you go on and putting symptoms, more and more.
Now you go back to the previous one that you've done inside with the 28 symptoms.
When you have put a lot of symptoms Pulsatilla and Silica, Mercury is also coming
but Silica is pressing. Are you going to give Pulsatilla in this case?
-No.
-It's a bit difficult because she says, when I go out actually I feel worse
because of the air so you don't give Pulsatilla in spite of the fact your repertorization
may come down to Pulsatilla, correct?
But you have in mind Silica and finally in this repertorization put amelioration from the sea.
-I think she doesn't have only mania of washing hands, she has mania of washing everything.
You can ask her.
-We can not find the washing everything, so we put washing hands.
-Washing.
-You have it?
-Yes, washing, desire for wash, cleanliness, mania for cleanliness.
-Yes that's it, put this. Show me.
It didn't change anything.
-It's the draft that has aggravated very much lately but I still have a desire for fresh air,
being outside, always. I feel my mind much clear.
-She says that she always has and had desire to be on open, so Pulsatilla, Silica.
-But draft aggravates with her.
-Yes put it 3 times and take out draft aggravates. Desires open air but still draft is better
symptom, it's more accurate for her, correct?
Show me now the repertorization and we put another.
You put also dancing, everything, menses scanty.
-Another symptom, head pain from strong odors, Silica is there too.
-That's correct and this is a confirmation for Silica, put this.
Sulphur, why Sulphur jumped into the picture when she put the last symptom?
Just put it once, this head pain from strong odors, underline it once.
So Pulsatilla, Silica, Sulphur, Medorrhinum, Mercury, Kali Carbonicum.
-I should say she loves animals, small insects, she takes care of everything.
-Love of animals I told you, it's a natural symptom, it's not unless
you pick up all the animals all around from your neighborhood, bring them home, feed them
teach them how to stand in their two feet.
This has to be really pathological and pathological also is to be afraid of a little dog
like this but if you are afraid of a big German shepherd, who is going not to be afraid?
Everybody.
-What seems strange to Pulsatilla, she is very cold inside she says, very cold not only chilly,
very cold she says.
-Either you take lack of vital heat, which she suggested, or you take worse cold.
Whatever you take is the same.
Now what I want to show is, you did your repertorization in a very nice way,
that means you tried your best.
You went through one after another you went systematically and what has come out,
certain possibilities but no certainty.
We agree?
Then we go back to the case and we ask ourselves, if at this moment of examination
we don't have a clear picture, we have to ask ourselves one basic question.
Is this patient doing better and how much better? What is the answer to this question?
-Much better.
-Great.
-I don't want you to tell me she is doing better or she is doing worse
but you have to justify your statement, she is doing better because of 1,2,3 things.
I don't want more.
-She is doing better because she is going to work, she hasn't work for years
and she started working.
-The number 1 amelioration is the fact that she is going to work,
I thought you spoiled my lesson, I thought somebody would not say it or say it in the end.
When you have a case that she herself says, I have not been able to work
and for the first time I go to work, this is a tremendous amelioration.
You have jumped a level already just for that, it does not matter now she says,
I don't have the suicidal disposition, still is good that she doesn't have it
but even if she had said, I still have the suicidal thoughts,
the fact that she is going to work, she is determined to work, she tries to keep it,
in spite of the fact she got sick, she wanted to go to work, that is a sign
she is in her health tremendously better, that means she has jumped 1 level definitely,
from 3 level she has been to second with strong acutes.
The symptoms become more, the physical symptoms, the organism may become upset
or it looks upset but as a whole she is doing better.
So on the one hand we have the confirmation that the patient is doing better,
on the other hand we have from the repertorization that the remedy is not clear,
are you going to give a remedy? No, you don't give a remedy after all this battle.
But if the remedy was absolutely clear and nobody would doubt about that remedy,
we would say yes in spite of the fact that she is feeling better, we can make her even better.
You just give the remedy, Medorrhinum or Pulsatilla or Silica or Sulphur
but these remedies I can not differentiate really that she needs the Medorrhinum
or she needs the Pulsatilla or she needs the Silica or maybe the Rhus tox,
as the repertorization the last time was coming to Rhus tox
and which I believe that during the acute the Rhus tox would have done good job in general.
-Because she did well on the last remedy, wouldn't you give her the same remedy,
maybe one potency higher?
-Arsenicum? No, I would not give. What I saw with great pleasure is that she says,
I never had fever in my life, that means at this moment her organism never was so good.
Perhaps only when she was 5 years old she had such good organism
as to bring out twice high fever.
So in this case of course it is very fortunate to treat the acutes with the correct remedy
and if we go back to my statement when somebody was giving...
You gave her case last time?
-I can not remember details. I can remember she was in a terrible state
and she was just laying there and we were quite worried about her.
-You can put back the playback and you will see the dramatic way in which she gave.
You had to travel next day and you were lying down, don't want anybody, just lying down
there in an exhaustion, in high fever, you were coughing, you were in a mess
and when we took the case we asked certain questions.
The case became for those who don't remember very clear Arsenicum
and then I said now after this Arsenicum you will see the real difference in her.
You saw the difference she got a job.
That is the difference which I meant when I said, now you will see the  difference
and if you like we play back the case and you will see what I mean by that.
So when you have this case studied so well and at the same time you know
that she is doing so well, the first is because she got the job, because she got the acutes
and because she doesn't have the depression, for these reasons we come to the conclusion
she is doing very well and we don't touch such a case unless we are sure.
Get this inside your mind very well.
Get it really inside, otherwise you are going to spoil your cases,
I can bring you innumerable such cases to show you.
And it's a pity because you give Silica and if Silica is not, because it's close,
Silica is going to upset the system or you give Medorrhinum.
Medorrhinum is going to be needed at a certain period of time, not at this moment definitely,
why we should be in a hurry and we want to make her quickly well, she is well enough.
No, I'm not.
-Right in the beginning of this follow up, one could see how lively she is well
when describing her symptoms.
Before when she was presenting her symptoms was lifeless as if she was dead.
-Exactly. Another very strong impression is that she was going in the beginning...
now she goes...
Before I knew where she was, she was on the next symptom, too fast, too much, too fast.
For those who remember the original case, you remember the Picric acid state?
To think is an effort, so therefore don't touch.