What was the main problem?
– Pubertas praecox. It’s early puberty.
When she was already 2 years old she got her menses.
– What was the original remedy?
– Medorrhinum and then last year you gave Lachesis
because there was a lot of jealousy in the case.
The fear of the parents was that she doesn’t grow anymore after 7 years
because the puberty was stopped when she was 7 and then she remains small,
that was the biggest fear in the case because now she is growing very fast
and after this will stop.
– Now she is 7?
– In 30th August she will become 7. Should I say from the last year or from the basics?
– From the last year...
- From the last year I got a report from the mother that she doesn’t see
and changes since Lachesis, only that Nickola is more independent
but she thinks because she is going to school now and it’s normal for her age.
The mother cannot really realize any changes and in school she is good
and there are no complains and the mother says she got some challenges now
because she needs some challenges, she’s got much energy...
– She’s got much energy and she needs challenge?
Does she attack her mother verbally?
– And also they fight.
– With fists?
– Yes.
– Not so often with me but very often with her mother,
she punches and cries very much. She cries to her mother “you don’t love me”.
–“I hate you, you don’t love me” and kinds like this.
For example says she is very demanding.
When she wants something then she wants to get it immediately
and cannot stop after to demand. For 2 hours she is demanding,
you hate me and you don’t give me that,
there is no stop for 2 hours after demanding something when she wants something.
She has much energy and the mother says thanks God she is in school now,
where she has some challenge.
– Much power!
– But that she already had it before Lachesis.
She always had a lot of power and fits of rage coming back after the Medorrhinum.
Medorrhinum brought back the suppressed fits of rage.
– Now when she sleeps she needs a light or can she sleep in darkness?
– Her mother says there’s no problem, she prefers little light but not too much.
– She used to talk in her sleep. Is she talking in her sleep?
– Sometimes yes, she is talking during sleep.
And a certain fear of thunderstorms and rains.
A little bit, not much, and also for rain a little. Now she says no.
– Is she seen masturbating?
– No, it was 2 years before she was here but not now.
– Neither you have noticed doing it in her own, when she is in bed?
– I don’t know, I don’t live with her, I haven’t seen it.
As I remember the mother also doesn’t know.
But what was very intense is that she is always playing the leader among the children
and when they play something she wants to be the first and the leader.
She is demanding to other children and when other children leave her she is very sad
and she says they don’t like me.
But she is provocative that the mother says that it’s no wonder why they leave you.
She is very demanding and aggressive and dominant.
– She does this with you also?
– She tries it.
– To be the most important person the mother says.
She always seems to be the most important person. She wants to be in the middle.
– But she does it in another way with me.
– She tries to make you do things.
– Yes, with smile.
– With the mother she is more aggressive.
And when the mother explains something to her, for example you caught a cold
and now you cannot go to the pool, she explains to her because you can catch a cold
and I don’t want, it’s cold already and it is evening,
then she is very sad and shouting you don’t love me!
When others forbid something she cannot accept.
The father says to me that the mother has another outcome of vibration
and she reacts on this and he is another person,
has another vibration so she is reacting completely different
and the father says this is because the mother has another vibration.
–She is more aggressive, low energy and this vibration makes her nervous.
– He also doesn’t feel sometimes very comfortable in her presence.
He offered the mother that she can come this time with the girl to Greece
and the mother refused
because I think the mother isn’t really understanding this treatment.
It’s a little difficult also for me to explain how that can be a miracle and work.
It took long time till May till the mother was ready to come for a follow up.
She doesn’t believe in that way.
– I told her that she should come with us but I told her only for 3 days
and it’s stressing flying and going by boat. She said, no I don’t like it,
but she wants to come here if 1 week of holidays will follow.
– You could pay her.
– Yes, I think so.
– Her height is still growing fast?
– It’s normal now.
– Her height is within normal range?
– She is 10cm too high for her age.
– Snoring in sleep is still there?
– Very much. But not every night.
3 months before she was sucking her finger.
But she is finished now and now she takes dental device for her teeth to be in order,
dental correction.
– You don’t know if she still talks in her sleep.
– Her mother says she still talks sometimes.
– She has impulses to kill?
– No.
– But strike?
– Yes. But not kill.
– Ask her if she wants to strike and she holds back, tries to control herself.
No response. Is any salivation in the night in bed? Saliva running in the pillow?
– It was before but now there is no sign.
– Her gums are ok?
– They are ok, teeth are ok.
– And she had previously any otitis?
– Sometimes if she goes to cold water. 2 months ago she had otitis in one side.
– You gave a remedy?
– They didn’t call me.
– They gave antibiotics.
– No antibiotics. She hasn’t get any antibiotics in her life.
– But the inflammation went away by itself.
– Her mother gave her anti-inflammatory drugs.
– She had fever?
– No fever but very much pain in the night, right ear.
And she got a packing aid pharmacy and she got anti-inflammatory drug
but only one time because she was weeping with pain.
– Does she have the habit of spitting frequently?
– No.
- I got that she feels like an outsider. Although she is a dominant person,
directing everybody she often feels like an outsider, nobody loves me
and complaining the others go home.
That was very dominant when talking with the mother.
She loves dancing and loud music but only when she wants it.
For example she puts on loud music and dances when she like it
and when the mother another time she puts on loud music she doesn’t like
and says to turn it off.
– Who gave you this information?
– The mother.  After many months I met with her, it was not so easy.
– The fear of dark and ghosts she gave originally?
– It’s not much. Little bit.
– Sometimes I ask her if she sees something that is not real of if someone speaks to her.
I asked her yesterday and she told me that grandpa
who died 2 years before he speaks to her.
– She is having no constipation?
– Sometimes.
– How many hours she sleeps?
– Very long from 8 p.m. to 7 a.m.
– Almost 12 hours. But in the morning when she wakes she is not in a good mood,
very irritable. Because during the week she has to go to school.
– She is very irritable in the morning.
– She has to go to school and she doesn’t like it?
– No, she likes going to school
but going out of the bed she doesn’t like it.
– Does she eat a lot of sweets?
– In the morning?
– During the whole day. Every day she needs sweets?
– Sometimes, not every day.
When she was younger she was 5 she asked me for sweets every day
but now she asks for apple or pineapple.
– What does she like to eat now?
– Pizza, fish still, ice cream very much.
–Big thirst?
– No she drinks less. Her mother told her to drink more water but she doesn’t like.
– You do not know if she grinds her teeth?
– No. I asked her mother and I can see in a kid if someone is pressing the teeth.
– She’s very capricious? She wants something and then she doesn’t like it.
– Yes, she has that. She demands something and then the next moment...
- When I get her a present she looks, play and...
- In front of you she does this?
– Yes, looks, plays and...
- You told me once she is almost as demanding as the mother.
The mother demands from him good life-style and she demands the same
and he was a little upset because of this.
She is on one hand she is coquettish like in puberty and she like movies
and TV shows with super models and super star shows
and she also has longing for horror movies
but her mother doesn’t allow her, of course. She is fascinated by these things.
It’s not fitting to her age. He tells me that she already watches films
like the Pirates of the Caribbean with Johnny Depp,
it’s a film for adults already one year ago and she was not in fear of it.
She can stand all these films. He says he wouldn’t have stood them at that age.
– Was there any times when she had worms in her intestines, in the stool?
-No but sometimes she has pain in the abdomen but depends on the stool.
– She has pain and then diarrhea?
– She has pain when she goes to the toilet and then it is finished.
– After stool the pain is gone. But she was vomiting quite a lot, I think.
– Vomiting at 6 a.m. sometimes. But not every day.
Every 3-4 weeks I think this could depend on what she has eaten.
– She has a big appetite? She eats a lot but she does not put in weight?
– Yes. The Professor in Vienna told me when I give her hormones
her weight will increase but it doesn’t happen.
– In this year how many centimeters she grew?
– Nearly 3-4 cm.
– Fear of thunderstorms is still there?
– Yes but 2-3 years before it was more intense.
– Now the menses are appearing or not?– Not at all.
– She is still gets the hormones.
– Her nose bleeds sometimes?– No. I haven’t seen it.
– Never?– Never.
– Does she complain that her tips are numb?– No.
– Her knees are very cold?
– No knees but feet are sometimes cold.
– Still likes ice cream a lot?
– Very much. In summer if it is warm 3-4 ice creams.
Give me ice cream! She likes strawberry and mango ice.
– Chocolate?
– She likes.
– If you are sick she will care, she will be anxious, have you noticed anything like that?
– She takes care, if I come and my head is aching she comes but she is not anxious.
– No fear but she takes care.
– But fear of dark and ghosts is less.
– In the medium, not panic but... When she sleeps she wants a little light.
– But when there are thunderstorms she gets really panicky?
She said yes, she answered herself. She has not said anything else.
Concerning the evaluation of the treatment so far,
I don’t think that homeopathic remedies have done anything so far.
If i take the reports from the mother as being true. The remedy at this moment that appears is...
repeat capriciousness, dictatorial, fear of thunderstorms,
irritability in morning when waking, striking, talking in sleep,
vomiting early in the morning, stool after pain ameliorates,
snoring in children, fish desire, ice cream desire
and you see her behavior is of course the behavior of a grown-up woman.
There is also aggressiveness and therefore I thought for a moment of Nux-v.
That was showing also in the repertorization. I said put this symptom
and then showed me Nux-v and the symptom went right on the top.
Between Nux-vomica and Phosphorus... Definitely there is a Phosphorus... Tuberculinum also.
There is any tuberculosis in the family?
– As far as he know there is no TB.
– My father and my grandfather were in war...
- We don’t know whether there is TB or not.
Phosphorus and Nux vomica are possible remedies.
– What is her feeling for consolation?
– If she has pain, she comes to me and cries and then I take her and then it’s finished.
– That’s in favor of Phos.
– I wonder if she still puts things in her mouth.
–No, he says she has stopped. A few months before she stopped sucking.
– Can I ask why you did not take the symptom of early menses?
– Is too early! That’s why! I don’t know if that fits. You can put add early menses.
If you add this there are going to be quite a lot of remedies. 126 remedies.
– Menses appear before proper age.
– Add this 3 times.
– What is your opinion about Carcinosin in the case?
– Can we use the symptom precocity?
– Yes precocity should be there. Mercury is there? Where is Mercury?
Use this 3 times. Use it 2 times. Use it 1 time.
– Is there any sweating?
– George about perspiration.
– On the armpits. Precocity is usually used in little children
who do not have this problem. She has problem in the hormonal system.
So she acts because of hormones as a grown woman.
Precocity has to be taken with some precocity. But still you can use it.
– Calcarea phosphorica.
– He lost some weight, I don’t like that he has to put on some weight!
– He is very controlled he doesn’t want to get fat.
– I was thinking of Veratrum album because she is a little girl being so dictatorial,
disappointed if the others go away, she is vomiting in the morning,
desire for ice, not ice cream, is in favor of Verat. The enuresis...
- How is Verat.?
– How many? 8 symptoms. Put precocity in 3 Veratrum album comes up.
– His opinion is that both remedies Medorrhinum and Lachesis brought something
but the mother cannot realize it but he says she was not so childish anymore,
she got better constitution.
– She became calmer.
– Not so much crying with red head.
– The father says with the remedies we gave she became calmer,
she is not beating so much etc. Veratrum album is a good idea. I don’t know.
The salt she needs is a lot? What about lemons? Takes a lemon and eats?
– It’s not so good, it’s very sour.
– Ice cubes, maybe she likes them but lemon;
she puts it in the mouth but doesn’t like it so much. Restlessness? Sometimes.
The thing that makes me think of Phos. is the fact that after all these questions
she answered she is afraid of thunderstorms.
So I think we have to take into consideration this.
Also we have to take into consideration the fact that she cares
and also the fact that the father says if I take her in my lap she will stop.
Everything is ok. That means she needs affection.
Is a child who needs a lot of affection and then the other thing is
that she would be bleeding quite a lot if she hadn’t taken the hormones.
I would prefer Phos. But take it 30C every day for 10 days
and if there is an effect and see it
and then it can go 32C for another 10 days 34C another ten days etc. for a month.
I don’t know what changes may be observed.
The problem is we don’t really have the real symptoms
because they are covered by the injections. You cannot go back...
Do they measure hormonal levels? If you go before the injection.
– For how long this treatment he says must be given?
– Professor Waldhausen in Vienna told me
that the hormones will continue until she is 150 cm. Then it won’t act anymore.
Now she is 134 cm. I think we have 3-4 years time to continue.
But we are forced in Austria to give hormones by the law.
– One of the characteristic of Phos. in connection with this child is what?
Grows fast. Phos. has this characteristic, Phos. children grow very fast very soon.
So she has this characteristic as well.
We will see whether this treatment may have a more dramatic effect.