GERMAN LC681 FU1 06.06
I saw this child last September and the diagnosis was pubertas praecox
which means that the menstrual period had started already regularly at 2 years old
during which time she used to catch a cold with a sore throat and
fever and she became very pale in her face during the menses
she was very aggressive and violent temper fits with red face and perspiration
in the face. She usually shouted stay away, leave me alone.
She usually hit her mother, didn’t want to be touched,
you could see strong anger in her eyes.
The father says he felt he was helpless and could not deal with her energy.
At the age of 3 she grew very fast with breast and pubic hair started to grow.
She had received hormonal treatment and this was done by law.
Since that treatment no more temper tantrums, occasionally she hit herself.
She has a cold now, she has a bronchitis.
– Since about 2 weeks but not so acute.
In January I talked to the father and he reported her emotional state
had greatly ameliorated but in the beginning it was really bad,
after taking the remedy. She had temper tantrums like before
she had started the hormonal therapy.
He was really upset what all came out after taking the remedy, she was so harsh…
So intense. The same kind of intensity and anger and temper tantrums
as before the hormonal therapy. This phase lasted for 2-3 weeks and I was happy
as we homeopaths are when the emotions come back.
And I could calm him down when things settled also.
Now in the long run she is more stable and pleasant with her like before.
What was surprising to the father is that in some situations she started behaving
more like a child again and for him this was a good sign and
the hormonal examinations showed a little bit more
normalization compared to before.
The father also said she was more cheerful again and her laughing was coming
more from the heart. One time she had a cold for 2-3 weeks,
the stool was rather hard, the sleep was good but nonetheless was tired
in the mornings. Every now and then she still speaks in her sleep.Talks in her sleep. She expresses and kind of emotion more clearly than before,more strongly.
She can get very angry if things don’t work the way she wants them to.
She has many ideas. A strong desire to cuddle.
And in everything she does she needs a lot of time and hates being pressurized.
The father says she is actually very sensible and has good ability to talk
and express herself, rhetorically she is strong.
Wants to relate a lot, talk a lot and concerning foods it’s still the same,
she eats everything especially meat, she likes a lot.
The only thing she does not like is whipped cream.
My general impression is that a lot have been taking place,
this is confirmed by the lab results but the father likes to talk about that himself.
Maybe we do that in the end, we brought some papers with him.
–Ok. Now what happened with growing hair in pubis continues or what?
– She does not have any pubic hair anymore since
they started the hormonal treatment, it all fell out again.
– No menses?
– No, since the hormones. A couple of months later I also talked with the mother.
The mother related she actually could tell no change.
The mother felt that child very often was strenuous and very demanding.
The mother says if the child wants something, laments more than necessary…
She can be very intense or violent,
impulsive and also beat the mother.
She also beats furniture but she did admit that this thrashing around has got less compared to before.
Then she also confirmed that Nickola can be sensible and thinks a lot.
The mother also reports that the child is very lazy and lets her mother
serve her a lot. And nothing may be abrupt, no sudden things,
because she cannot tolerate at all.
And I ask what happens if something abrupt happens and the mother says
she becomes irritable and screams no and starts to beat.
Mother’s nerves are really wrecked because the child always says
you are so mean to me. The child accuses the mother is being mean to her.
– I want to ask the father a thing. There is a kind of controversy
between mother and sister.
– Which sister?
– I think it’s a controversy between mother and daughter taking place.
The mother is a rather nervous type who cannot tolerate stress.
– There is no jealousy against the daughter because the father
pays to much attention to the daughter?
– That’s possible.
The relationship between the parents is very tense
as we related during the first interview.
But the situation between the mother and me has got better,
it’s not like what it used to be.
– But the child is attached to her father rather than the mother?
– That’s possible. When the child is together with both parents
she becomes completely off-balance, that’s a very difficult time for the child.
– The child is jealous of her mother?
– No, I don’t think so.
– She has no fever all this time?
– She never had fever.
She coughs since 2 weeks mostly in the mornings and in the evening.
– When lying in bed or before lying?
– Mostly already before and also
when she lies down in bed, not during sleep.
– Have they noticed if the child cannot tolerate something around her neck?
– She doesn’t want that but I really didn’t pay attention up to now but she just said she doesn’t like to be buttoned up.
The mother says she is very sensitive to touch,
for example when the mother combs her hair and also very critical.
She tends to try and blackmail her mother and she is easily offended
and she still has the temper tantrums but at night she cuddles so close to her mother
and always touches the nevus of her mother
and concerning her general development her mother has the feeling that the child
sometimes talks like a child in puberty talking about those stupid boys
and things like that.
– Precocious.
– The mother just reports that she reacts like a child in puberty. Sleep is good.
She sleeps in every position. No saliva. No perspiration.
And she tired in the morning. She like to eat everything especially fried things.
She also enjoys fish and juicy fruits, even lemons.
– Oysters? – She never tried.
But concerning food she is not complicated at all. She eats practically everything.
She is afraid of the thunderstorms.
She is even afraid of rain.
– Is she afraid of the thunderstorms very much?
– Yes.
– She will hide under the table?
– She comes to me or to her mother and wants to be held and cuddled.
– Is it true that what it was written she is normally quiet
and confident only out of balance when parents are together.
This still is like this?
– It’s true but it has got better. Finished.
They have said she was snoring in sleep, is that true?
– That’s still the case.
– How much water she needs?  A lot, normal, cold water?
– I think she takes normal amount of juice and water.
– Asks for cold or normal?
– She drinks any kind of temperature.
If something  has ice cubes in it she will take it just as she will drink warm,
no special affinities.
– Do you see the growth of the hands? Do you check it?
– This is a longer story. The growth of her hands is being checked once a year
by Professor Waldhauser but when she was 4 years old the growth of her bones
represented a child of 8,5 years old. Last year at age 5 they checked it again,
the growth resembled to a hand of 10,5 years and this year in April
they checked it again and there it still resembled the age 10,5
meaning that the growth has stopped.
– Is she still continuing taking hormones?
– She gets an injection of hormones once in a month.
Legally I am obliged to do this, I am not permitted to stop.
– For how long?
– According to the experience of Dr. Waldhauser
this will be continued till she is in the age of 10 year old.
Up to age 10 and weight of around 50kg because then from all experience
the injection with the hormones does not any effect anymore.
– What is her weight now?
– About 27kg.
– She shows any sign of masturbation?
– Well, she still does every now and then, sits on her knees and starts rubbing with
her feet, it has got a lot better, in former times this happened often and stronger,
and she was smiling at me while she was doing it.
– She flirts with grown-ups?
– Sometime but very rarely. If she finds a man sympathetic or
she likes a man she tends to do it.
– They say that she does not like to be touched.
Can you explain this?
– That’s in combination with anger.
If she is angry she says go away, don’t touch me.
– But somebody touches her otherwise she will accept?
– That’s no problem. My impression is that she is even seeking physical contact.
When she sees me she comes and hugs me.
– No constipation.
– Concerning the constipation now she has stools every day or every other day
and very large amounts. Because I have to wipe her and that’s why I notice
it’s a large amount.
– Her mother does not pay much attention to her.
Who pays more attention the father or the mother?
– The mother has more time for her because she is only working 20 hours a week.
– Ask her who she loves more; the father or the mother?
– Mom. – I think she loves both each in individual ways…
- Is she going to school?
– She will start coming September.
– Does she know how to read or…?
– She is better able to write already, reading only a  little
but she also knows the numbers.
– In general she is excitable,
talking a lot or she is reserved and closed?
– If she knows somebody well or she is together with her girlfriends she talks a lot…
- Ok!
With the Medorrhinum it increases normally, with hormones is this way…
- She takes hormones since when?
– 3,5 I think.
– So this time it was almost continuous to there…
- This was hormonal therapy and Medorrhinum…
- Impressive but you cannot really see it.
We will speak about the child. To my understanding this is a quite deep
hormonal disturbance and most probably will need a series of remedies
before we can bring about the best possible effect.
At this moment the Medorrhinum seemed it had done some work
especially because we had an initial aggravation and then it was an amelioration.
Therefore we know it was the first correct remedy and now the problem
is how to continue. And what information we have concerning the child.
We don’t have much information. At this moment it seems to me to be a good sign
that there is a sub-acute inflammation of the lungs which is going on and
this is one thing we have to take care of,
the other thing is to be guided by the psychological state of the child because
we don’t have much on the physical level.
What would you think as guiding symptoms at this moment?
Can anybody give me what do you think as a guiding symptoms about this case?
Nobody talks… - The very strong fear of thunderstorms.
– That is correct. One…
- She is beating her mother and she is angry.
– What that means...
We are impressed of course by the fact that at this age there is a kind of tension?
Jealousy. It comes from jealousy but it’s a kind of controversy… not controversy…
competition! Woman competition.
It’s like two women competing for the man.
Actually for me it is very strong the jealousy of the child towards the mother
but also the jealousy of the mother towards the child.
So it is from both sides but that child really has a kind of a competition
and jealousy towards the mother.
So this was there before and continues to be after Medorrhinum.
Maybe a little bit less but it is because the aggression of the child has been reduced.
Therefore the expression of the jealousy of the child is less prominent.
The child still has a competing feeling with the mother and definitely she is jealous.
But now you will ask, when I ask her in front of the father,
who do you love more the child says my mother.
This is the cunning thinking of a woman.
You have to go into the psychology of the child, the father is there,
the question is direct and what she does, she thinks first before answering,
very quickly she comes to a decision,
I’ll tell my mother but she turns around to her father and she says ok we manage.
Her whole behavior towards the mother points very clearly
that there is a woman who challenges the mother and she says he loves me more.
My father loves me more than you and if he loves more you then I will hit you.
The element of competition and jealousy is very strong and it is there.
Therefore our mind should go to Lachesis. You remember I asked,
thinking of Lachesis, if she can tolerate tight clothes, she said no,
I cannot but maybe the child did not know the importance of this question and
she answered not thinking very much.
Do we have other points for Lachesis to support?
– She is tired in the morning on waking.
– Also coughing on waking in the morning and coughing in the evening before
and after sleep. That’s one. Another one do you know what it is? She says…
- The father told us that she is talking a lot with her friends and to other people…
- She is very talkative when she is at ease.
– Also she has a lot of ideas,
fantasies this is also a sign…
- A lot of activity in the mind.
There is one more point which is clear. You know that Lachesis when she has a pain
does not want to be touched. And when she has a psychological pain she says
don’t touch me, again one more point for Lachesis.
She says does not want to be touched when she is in bad mood.
Therefore we have several points to support the idea of Lachesis.
The idea of Lachesis and the precocity of the child… Show me precocity of children.
Medorrhinum, Lachesis, Veratrum album are main remedies.
So this is a precocious child. I believe it’s a child that will be flirting almost
in a sexual connotation with men and she will behave much older than her age.
This is precocious.
– The tendency to masturbation to children you find Lachesis
in the third degree too. Considering her moment state can you really take this
as a symptom?
– Yes, you can take it as a symptom.
In children who have a tendency to masturbation you can take it as a symptom.
It only means that the hormonal system is not balanced.
Therefore the expression if this imbalance is through masturbation.
A child of 6 years who masturbated that means is a child whose hormonal balance
is not correct. Actually when the sexual activity should start together with puberty,
this idea, is ok. Many women even delay feeling having sexual symptom and
they develop sexuality when the find a partner later 20, 25.
So at this moment we want to push forward the organism and
help her with the bronchitis which is when she wakes up and before going to bed
this is the time Lachesis has aggravations. Therefore Lachesis 200C and 1M,
first day and second day will push forward.
The problem in such cases is that the organism will not develop
because they give a hormone that stops the development, actually the general
development of the organism. The conventional medicine knows that the child will
remain in this height. We will go against these hormones because it is by law,
as she said, we cannot stop the hormones. I don’t know why this law is there,
first time I hear there is a law… We don’t want to go against,
we are not a revolutionary group. Lachesis 200C and 1M
and we’ll see the child next year. Ask the father how is her height
since last September. Did you check her height?
– Since last September she grew 2.5 cm, Every month she grows about 0.5 cm,
sometimes 0.4, 0.5, 0.6, it depends. Where the normal is… who knows?
– The professor in Vienna says that a child of this age normally grows up about 4cm
every year on average. We will see. We have an acute case. One question.
– In the paper I see that the Medorrhinum has been given once a month,
I suppose this was due to the hormonal suppressive therapy during this time,
would you give the Lachesis once a month also?
– No I would like to give it only once,
see if there is an effect and then I will decide.
- Why this difference?
– This level where she is now, with mostly the jealousy and the bronchitis,
I consider it as an intermediate level. I believe that later on
we will have to give remedies maybe like pituitary gland, Baryta carbonica, I will see.
But at this moment I want to see the effect on mostly emotional level and
see how kind of boost can be given.