This was a case of epilepsy that started in 2009
and started after a conflict that the child was observing
and at first she developed cramps on the jaws with distortion of the face
without losing her consciousness and during these local fits she can’t speak...
Sometimes with retching, sometimes with reclination of her head and neck.
Neurologists diagnosed Rolando Epilepsy. I don’t know what it means.
In 2011 a primary focal and secondary generalized epilepsy
and the EEG shows an epileptic focus parieto central left. That was in June 2009.
She had received several remedies; Carcinosin, Stramonium, Ignatia, Helleborus, Sepia, Nux vomica,
Tuberculinum, Kali bromatum, Hyoscyamus, Cicuta, Oenanthe crocata, Ignatia again, Thuja...
So when we discussed the case we had symptoms, how many symptoms were used...?
Indigo actually was coming tenth
but it was chosen because of the peculiar aura of the epileptic fit from abdomen to head.
And because Indigo is a remedy that has given epileptic fits.
Indigo was prescribed in low potency 12X twice daily, she was doing very well.
The doctor had not seen her, only through the phone.Till now she had 3 epileptic fits, 2 in August.
When did she start the remedy? End of June. 2nd, 8th and 10th July and in November 2014.
Before the attacks she had the same abdominal sensation.
Also sensations in head and jaws, difficult to describe,
as if the blood vessels are blocked followed by a free flow of blood.
It is interesting for this case to keep in mind this sensation of vessels blocked,
followed by a free flow of blood. It’s a feeling like after running very fast.
During this sensation she is unable to think clearly.
She had a fall on her back and she was given a dose of Hypericum 30C
and she was told to continue with Indigo 15X and there is no other fit until today.
No stage of confusion anymore and she has pain in lower abdomen before menses. That’s all.
Otherwise you feel good? She did well in school?
- For the time being yes.
– What’s her position in the class?
– In the middle field.
– Do you have any complaints for your health apart from the pain in the abdomen?
– Recently I was quite often sick and weak.
– Ill with fever?
– It was feeling like fever but it was no fever.
I was just weak and when I was climbing the stairs I had to lie down because I was so weak.
– How many time did this happen?
– Twice but each time for one week. End of April.
– You did not go to school?
–No.
– The pain in the abdomen is before menses only or during menses?
– It is always before menses starts and in the beginning after menses start.
– The menses are with a lot of blood or scanty blood?
– It’s rather strong bleeding.
– So the pain stops once the flow becomes strong?
– No, there is no correlation between the blood flow and the pains.
– Do you have black clots in the blood.
– No.
– The blood is bright red or watery?
- It’s just as if you have a cut and it’s bleeding. It’s not watery. It’s just normal blood.
– And there no headache or anything?
– Pain in my back.
-  When she felt ill she had headaches.
– But did you put a thermometer?
– 37C.
– Very little fever. Is she still biting her nails?
– Yes, I do.
I stopped for a short time, I tried to stop and I had success but now I started again...
Did she gain height?
– Yes I think so. Her shoes are 43.
– She is going to be very tall. How tall is her mother?
– She 1,76 cm and her shoes are 41. But her husband is...
- The same height as me.
– She will be taller than you.
–The mother says her father is very tall.
– In her character she is ok now?
– I would say so.
– She is a nice child?
– Yes.
– In your class are you mixed boys and girls?
– Do you like fruits?
–Yes.
–What kind of fruits she likes the most, soft and sweet or green?
– Rather the ripe and soft, sweet fruits.
– Sweets she likes? She take a chocolate a lot.
– I would eat chocolate but it’s not I feel a desire and would look for something sweet.
When there’s something sweet around I will take it.
– Eggs?
– Yes, I can eat them. It’s not a passion, not very big desire.
I don't really have a favourite meal, I like some sort of meat with sauce.
– When the meat has fat in it will she take it?
– No. I don’t like it.
–In general she feels better in warm climate, cold climate, fresh air?
–I can tolerate everything.
There is no special climate that would make me better.
– She has any fear? Fear of high places?
– Slight fear of high places. I do have it.
– I don’t really know if you could call it a fear but I’m stressed when I see somebody smoking,
then I get anxious that some friends or somebody in my family could start smoking.
Then I get sort of panicky.
– Does she have any anxiety when there is a thunderstorm?
– Not really.
– Fear of the dark?
– In former times it was more, now it’s ok.
– In the time when she was really bad, it was strong that she would not stay alone when it was dark.
But that’s much better now.
– Any other information from the mother?
– Concerning the actual situation?
– The health of the child.
– I wanted to tell you something about these situations that she was slightly confused.
There were 2 situations, which were in November and December 2014.
She was in school, she went to the toilet
and didn’t find the way back from the toilet in the school into her classroom.
That had never happened before. That was something very new.
It wasn’t that dramatic, you exaggerate. There were the 3 rooms of Biology
and I ran out of the toilet and didn’t find the room.
– Tell me what potency she is taking now?
– 18X.
– Twice a day?
– Three times a day.
– Continue to raise the potency every month. Ok, so no problem.
I don’t think we have to say much about the case.
The only thing I can say is one of the accusations
that people outside have accused I never prescribe low potencies
and I never prescribe small remedies. Both these myths are destroyed by this case.
The case is doing well. It is a learning process if you read the reports
you can remember the way she describes her situation you can learn something more about that remedy.
This is the important thing about this remedy. I also read the remedies that had been given before.
Which were based in good analysis and repertorization.
Yet, sometimes, in small remedies we cannot get the remedy through repertorization.
You remember in the first day when Hahnemann in paragraph 153
he said pay attention to symptoms which are rare, strange and peculiar.
And this is the way that you have to look in a case.
Find the most strange and peculiar symptoms
and take them into consideration. This is the teaching for this case.
You may ask why don’t we stop the remedy.
As I said in the morning there are a lot of questions in my mind which are unanswered.
So I am trying to find the rules and the principles concerning these cases.
Another thing I can say about this case is that until she has an acute with high fever
we cannot be sure that with the least provocation especially with wrong remedy
we can topple the case and have a relapse. Once this case develops a strong acute with high fever,
then from that time onwards the relapse will be difficult.
And then this acute has to be prescribed correctly.
Because it is prescribed wrongly,
this means if the acute is kind of suppressed even with homeopathic remedies then there is danger.
You have to be careful.
– I am a bit confused about the potency.
Because in the video it is mentioned 12C initially and then 12X or D.
What was actually given to the child?
– 12D or 12X. Decimal not centesimal.