-So the boy is 13 years old and the problem is...
-The problem is that since 1 year old he has a daily sort of vomiting. Even more.
-A specific time?
-No.
It can be any time. It can be in the morning, noon, afternoon, in the evening.
-Why does he think he has this vomiting?
-The problem started in the beginning of 97, about 2 years ago.
The problem was that Johannes got teased in his school and mainly because of his
height. Because he was too short. And that's how a big grief started and
in the midst of 97 he changed school and he went to high school.
On this school he was about the smallest of all pupils in this school and there too
he got teased. It wasn't that bad in the old school, it got much worse in the new school.
It was not his own class that would tease him, it was more the other pupils in the school
that would tease on him.
It was not that bad in the old school but when he was in the new school,
it was really bad.
Then a sort of continuous vomiting started. The normal examination didn't show any
results and so we went to an endocrinologist and in Autumn 97 this doctor found out
that the function of the thyroid gland is diminished, not enough.
It' not enough the T3, the T4 level was OK.
And I found out that this malfunctioning of the thyroid was caused by the hypophysis
and I gave him some homeopathic remedies.
-What remedies he took?
-Silica C200 and C1000 but there was no result. So I went to a homeopath in Berlin and
shortly before we went Johannes told me for the first time about this grief.
Before he kept all this grief inside himself. I saw that he was having something that
was troubling him but I didn't know what it was. It was visible but I didn't know
what it was and this homeopath gave him in the 20th of October 97, a Nat. mur. 1M.
I realized right before we got there that it should be Nat. mur. but it was not me but
finally the homeopath that gave it to him.
Within 3 weeks the function of the thyroid gland was OK again, it was normal and the
endocrinologist before had to give him tablets with thyroid hormone, a substitute and
I stopped these tablets afterwards. Then I asked the endocrinologist why he thought
that it got in order again because the second examination showed that everything was
normal again and I knew that the endocrinologist was an enemy towards Homeopathy.
He said, the first results we took must have been wrong, must have been a mistake.
-Always it's a mistake.
-The thyroid gland got in order again and took the grief that was pressing the soul
and getting better. Since this very moment the situation is as following.
He is vomiting 46 times every day and the vomiting is as followed.
He sits at the table, he gets up from the table, goes into the kitchen to the dustbin
and open it and throws up and what comes out is water and some indigested food
and then he goes away and it's finished. It's an action of 7-8 sec.
-He is not having nausea before, it comes suddenly?
-It comes all out of a sudden.
-He has to say something else?
-I have a slight headache but it's constantly.
-Where?
-In the front region. All over.
-All over the head or all over the forehead.
-Just the forehead. Very strong or mild?
-Not very strong. This headache is constantly there but it doesn't impede him
from doing what he wants to do in school or playing football.
-How is he doing in his school?
-Very good, in school last time he had a very good average of grades.
-Very good means within the first 5th of his class?
-The second best and he is excellent in mathematics.
-Every time that they speak about this subject he cries?
-Often. In his class he is well accepted, it's just when he goes to the toilet, the other
kids tease him and fool him.
-If in the family they speak about this, he starts crying there also, outside of the school
like now I see he is crying every time he thinks about it.
This is only specially here at this moment or it happens in the house also?
-In the school the tears don't come, he won't cry at school.
Just when I see homeopaths or other doctors the tears come.
-Is he a child that needs affection, ask the father.
-He wants attention, not that he needs direct consolation but he would need attention.
-Is anything else from his medical history?
-Besides this he has strong constipation but that doesn't seem to bother him very much.
Concerning his emotional state of affairs, he is at the moment a little bit under shock
because just an hour ago he rent together with his father and got a blow in the nose.
After this Nat. mur. in October 97, six weeks later, I went to this homeopath again
because this vomiting was still there and then he told me to give C12 of Nat. mur. daily.
And we did but there was no result.
On the 1st of February in 98, we saw this homeopath again and I had the impression she
didn't quite know what to do about his case either and then she finally said give him
Nat. arsenicum in C200. He is freezing a lot and often he has icy cold hands.
Over all he is more at the freezing side but especially the hands are very cold.
Then we didn't see this homeopath anymore and then my story of lacking successes
in treating my son started.
In 98 I gave him because of the constant headache Ferrum metallicum C12, no result.
Then on the 23 of March I gave him, because of this severe constipation, where
sometimes he really had to get out the stool by hands, I gave him Nux vomica in C12
no effect. Then I consulted a homeopath from Berlin and she said it could be
Medorrhinum because he is biting his nails and he had a small wart on his thigh.
But there was no effect in Medorrhinum C 1M.
I was quite desperate because he was vomiting every day, with every meal we took
he would vomit.
In April I gave him Rhus tox because of his restlessness.
He is very restless and when he sits at the table eating his meal, he would kick with
his feet all the time, like playing football. The restlessness is mainly concentrated
on the lower part of his body, he will sit in his chair but immediately after eating
he will get up and walk about in the room. To finish the story, there was no effect of
Rhus tox either.
Then I thought of Ignatia, in April Ignatia C200, no effect and in May 98, Arsenicum
album in C200 and 1M, no effect.
Then we had the seminar in May here, in Alonissos, and then you told children remedies
and with vomiting in children you mentioned the remedy Ipecacuanha and then I tried
Ipecacuanha C200, no success and the last remedy in June was Lycopodium, no effect.
-So he is restless while sitting and after eating he becomes restless?
-When I come home from the seminar for example, he won't sit and read or lie on his
bed but he would stand and having a racket on his hand and play with the ball with the
squash racket and play the ball against the wall, all the time in movement.
And a restlessness, especially in his legs.
-What he likes best to eat?
-It varies. For 2 weeks I like this, for 2 weeks I like that, it changes.
-He likes ice-cream?
- I do like it but I wouldn't say more than other kids.
-You have an objection?
-I would say that he really likes it very much.
-The friends of mine eat ice-cream daily, I eat ice-cream every 2 weeks.
Not in winter of course, just in summer time.
-His thirst is normal?
-He is very thirsty.
-For cold water?
-If it's with bubbles, I like it in room temperature, if it's without bubbles like here
in Greece, I do like it icy cold.
-Does he like also ice cubes to eat?
-No.
-How much salt he puts to his food?
-Not much.
-I would like to make some comments generally on his nutrition.
This got less now but about 1 and 1/2 year ago he would control all what he was eating
exactly concerning the content of fat. He would take the things he would eat and control
the content of fat, how much fat.
-What does he mean by that?
-When we went down in the super market for shopping, he would take all the different
cheeses and look on what they write on them, how much fat do they contain and
if it was more than 1%, he would say not this cheese I can't take, it's too fatty.
Because he says, my experience is when it's too much fat in it, I would vomit more.
- He is very correct. He used to eat fat before?
-Yes.
-He liked fat?
-Not especially.
-Butter?
-Yes.
-Even now he takes butter?
-No.
-Because he is afraid he may vomit more easily?
-Yes.
-There is in his medical history, there is any serious acute condition?
-Every now and then he got an otitis and they had to put little tubes in it.
That was the only thing. I remark two things. When we came to Greece, we saw a lot
of badly fed cats and he takes a little pot with milk and carries it outside and
wants that the cat will eat it or when we eat pizza, he will take a piece of the pizza
and give it to the cats, he has a lot of compassion with the cats.
-Only with the cats or with every animal?
-Yes, too.
-He has frequent nose bleeding?
-Recently not that much anymore but formally before he would have it quite often.
Normally before 1 year he would have it once the week from the right nostril.
Always right. And if I hurt myself and gets nose bleeding, it's always on the right side.
And when he got this stroke on his nose right now, he got strong nose bleeding
just out of his right nostril and it was brightly red and at the end there was a clot
coming out.
-The vomiting is like a rocket?
-Yes. Very sudden.
-He is talking about philosophical matters, asking questions?
-Not that much about philosophy but he likes to talk and he has an excellent memory
especially for prices. From about 5-6 super markets in Berlin, he would know exactly
the prices of about 20 different items.
-He is biting his nails for a long time?
-Yes.
-Is he shy?
-Not at home that much but at the school I would say yes.
With strangers he would be reserved.
But in the school where they don't know me, I think I'm shy.
-He is very thirsty.
-Yes, he drinks more than 2 lt and when he drinks he takes big sips, a lot at the time.
-Does he have any fears?
-Fear of thunderstorms?
-No.
-Fear in the dark?
-With his class he can answer questions, if the teacher asks a question?
If he knows the answer, he will put up his hand.
-In the class yes, no problem.
-He is still constipated?
-Yes and sometimes during and after stool he has a prolapse of the anus.
-Ask him in how many times he wants to stop vomiting?
-Today!
-Does he like salt?
-He used to like chips but not so much anymore, I can't really tell because my
sister takes extremely much salt. So I wouldn't know.
Sometimes he likes to eat chocolate but not very often.
-What about lemon?
-Yes, not extremely but with the tea.
Concerning his intellectual development he is very far ahead.
But concerning his physical development he is back, he is a bit retarded and he is
suffering, his height is 1m 42 cm and the others are sometimes very much taller.
-When we see him in 6 months, how many cm he wants to be higher?
-I would really like to be 20 cm higher than now, I know this is not possible but
I would really like it.
-20 cm is rather difficult.
-Some colleagues in my class are 1m 85 cm.
-My god. The German race is coming taller and taller.
OK, we decide in the class now.
With the right remedy how long it will take for the boy to stop vomiting?
Who can predict?
-One day.
-Tonight.
-This is interesting because I thought in the beginning that's the remedy.
Until the end, where I said, maybe I'm wrong.
Give the symptoms that you put in the Repertory so that you will get an idea what
are the symptoms that you use.
Vomiting, ailments from grief, dwarfishness, nausea after mortification, ailments from
mortification, sudden vomiting...
You put too many times grief, mortification.
Nausea after mortification make it 3 times.
-On this rubric there is no remedy.
-There is no 3 times remedy?
Vomiting sudden, constant pain in forehead...
Constant vomiting make it three times.
-Sudden vomiting while eating is a small rubric because he is eating and he is
standing up, goes and has a sudden vomiting, this is a small rubric.
-He said that it can be anytime. Is it during eating only, it is during eating
most of the time or it is anytime?
-Maybe 60% it is during or after eating but the 40% is on another time.
-A nice child who is sitting in front of you and cries in a such a nice way,
as this boy.
When he hears about the problem, it is a case of Pulsatilla, especially when it says
I try not to eat fat because fat will make me sick, will make me vomit.
This combination is a Pulsatilla combination only.
Put the columns.
All the time I was thinking of Pulsatilla, Pulsatilla, Pulsatilla.
Then the thirst came, thirsty, thirsty, thirsty, very thirsty.
Then came the idea of coldness, freezing.
Then I started thinking maybe I'm making a mistake thinking of Pulsatilla.
So Veratrum, Silica, Sepia, Pulsatilla. Show me Pulsatilla how many symptoms covers
of this boy? 10 out of 19.
Show me Veratrum, 13 out of 19.
So the choice for this remedy should be between Pulsatilla and Veratrum album.
Why Veratrum album? Because of restlessness.
Restlessness after eating, show me this.
-It already starts after eating, at the very beginning, maybe already after 1-2 min.
after he starts eating at the table, he gets up, dances around, plays around with
the ball in between he vomits briefly, then he sits down again.
-What is interesting here is that the boy is vomiting suddenly and like a rocket.
This reminds of the vomiting of Veratrum album but there is one symptom which made
me actually go to Veratrum, which is this symptom?
There is a symptom, if you have studied you would have found it.
Which is the symptom which finally made me jump from Pulsatilla, I was certain even
when he said he is freezing I was still Pulsatilla, when he said thirsty
I said still Pulsatilla.
But when I saw that symptom finally, I said forget Pulsatilla or we have it as a second
possibility, the first possibility should be Veratrum. Which is the symptom?
A symptom which is clear cut and which is clear cut also in the Repertory.
Epistaxis on the right side. Show me epistaxis on the right side.
This was a clear symptom, always in the right. I say my god and then I'm thinking of
Veratrum album and then I saw this and said that's it.
The problem is that I don't want to give first Veratrum and then Pulsatilla and then
take 24 hours before we cure the child. The child must be cured tonight.
Because he said I want to be cured tonight. I don't want to vomit again.
We said about Veratrum, if you remember, is a boy who is advanced in mental level
and very clever but has been retarded, mostly in emotional level.
Emotionally is not mature. For instance this type of children who become first in their
class, you remember we described they are first in their class, they even can go to
special schools because they are so intelligent, they put questions, before you ask
the question, they know the answer etc. Yet these children, where you expect that at
the age of 13 the boy is starting to get interested in girls and emotionally becoming
involved in that kind of thing, you don't see it in Veratrum.
You see they are totally disinterested in this area. There is one side a hyper development
and on the other side lack of development, which here maybe goes together with under
development of the physical body. At the same time we see restlessness.
The children are very restless, they will not sit, they will get up but usually
I have seen a desire for salt, which I could not get it.
Maybe his sister is Nat. mur.
In Veratrum album we have vomiting after vexation, exactly the symptom we're
looking for. for. You see it?
Vomiting after vexation is Veratrum and Chamomilla. Two main remedies.
I like that symptom. Where did you find it?
-I put vomiting in Veratrum.
-I like it.
What potency? I would like to hear about the potency. 200, 1M, 10M, 50M, CM?
-OK, 50M, why? Because this is a deep mortification, a deep grief, a deep trauma on
a very deep emotional level. Therefore we need a high potency to counteract it.
So tonight you get a 50M Veratrum album and tomorrow we have a consultation.
We'll have a consultation before you leave, because we have 10 days for observation
and we hope, because many time you think the remedy is absolutely right and you get
no effect, we'll see.
-I had reported 3 days ago that from 22 September on, meaning from the day where he
received Veratrum album in XC, the frequency of these very short vomiting attacks
got higher, they were more attacks per day. They were 1-2 days where he vomited
6-7 times but yesterday it was 10 times again.
And I don't know how much it has been this morning, up to now. 4 times up to now.
The attacks are not bad, they don't incapacitate him in any way,  that's very remarkable,
he can immediately afterwards continue doing his sports or study something.
It doesn't seem to influence him in any way and he has no nausea with it.
-The attacks are different in any way or the form is exactly the same?
That means there is less force, less quantity, because to vomit 10 times that means
nothing is staying inside.
-I was not able to watch it because he usually has these attacks when
I'm attending the seminar.
-He says no change.
-I remember when you described the case the child was quiet, restless, especially while
eating, after eating, how is that?
-I would say the restlessness has ameliorated by about 20%.
-Constipation, how is it?
-Before the remedy he had stool every second day, meaning every second day he could
not go to the toilet and within the last 5 days, once he had stool on 3 successing days.
That was a bit remarkable. I saw the stool are usually dark brown and not very formed
more like a paste.
And what I noticed is that he is very compassionate with the animals, very sympathetic.
He feeds them every night, he takes plates, he feeds them with milk, he puts that out to
the cats, he keeps asking us if we still have anything left in the refrigerator, cheese or
something that he could still feed them.
-This, in Germany as well?
-No.
We do have a cat at home, he also takes care of it but what he does here is really
remarkable. But it's possible since his friends are not here and he does not have so
much distraction that he tends to care more of the animals.
-Last time when we analyzed his case, we were battling between Veratrum and Pulsatilla.
He takes milk?
-I don't take that much milk, no.
-Ice-cream?
-Not that much, I would say average.
-How is the restlessness of the feet?
-I, myself can not judge it very well I think.
-Nose epistaxis right happened once?
-No.
-Cold water desire still is there? His thirst is increased?
-But not especially for cold water. It can be normal temperature.
-One thing I noticed, we rented a bicycle for him while we are here and last night
the chain popped out and he was angry and I tried to fix it. We went in the room and he
was so angry that suddenly kicked the chair and he was shouting angrily, loudly.
-He never did this before?
-No, he does it sometimes.
-This pain in the forehead, hands icy cold how is that?
-Now definitely are not cold but of course in Greece is a lot warmer than in Germany.
So I don't know how it will be when we get back home. He never got icy cold hands
during summertime, it was always in winter or spring, fall times.
-How is his mood in general? The same?
You will pay for that. It's very good. You do whatever you like.
Don't bother about anybody. Don't translate what I'm going to say now.
He will know everything but what I want to ask is if he drinks milk, if he drinks
he wants the milk to be cold?
-There is an intolerance of fat and so he doesn't drink normal milk because the fat
content is too high.
-Show me the rubric, fat aggravates.
I want to ask him if he remembers by the time his class mates, if he remembers
something specific that they said, somebody said this or said that?
-It was not my class mates who tease me, not them. It was just some others
I didn't know who were from the same school, for example when we were in the toilet
and they tease me that I was too small.
-Is that what he hurt you?
-Yes.
-And he is putting a lot of effort into trying to please me, he is so considered,
he keeps asking, is anything you would like? What about this strawberry yogurt,
I think you might like to eat it. Can I buy you something father?
Or do you want something that I could still get it for you? Very strong.
He always ask, can I help you in any way?
-Right now is a period where I found many things boring on this island,
there is not that much to do really.
-He does this only here?
-No, he does it also at home.
-Show me this rubric, wants to please others.
The desire for salt, how much is it?
-Middle, normal. He says he has not the impression to be spotted on the island
but he is still vomiting.
-It's even more. It's clearly more. 80% more.
-The vomiting has anything to do with the drinking of cold water?
When you drink cold, is it that comes up after a period of time or immediately or has
nothing to do with the drinking of cold water?
-I didn't notice it up to now.
-Vomiting comes independent of eating, it can come before eating also?
-About 50% of the vomiting is in relation with eating, the other 50% is not.
-Thank you.
This was a good possibility that we have to reexamine the case. What do you think?
This is definitely an aggravation, I would say already it's 10 days.
For that, what he has, it's a long aggravation already but the question is there is any
amelioration, in any level? This is the question.
The answer is no. Who says no?
There is amelioration. Where is the amelioration?
-He didn't weep anymore when you talked to him about his humiliation.
-I said don't translate what I'm going to do but then I asked some other questions
and what I wanted to see is the emotional condition of the boy but he should not know
that I was checking on him.
So I asked him about the milk, about hot, cold and then I brought the subject into the
heart of the matter. What they said about you? This was recalled.
No cry. Did you see the deep crying on the first time?
Do you think that because it's 10 days later he will not cry? Of course. He's crying for
the last 5 years, is he going to stop now?
-We had about 4-5 history taking in Berlin, after he had been vexated.
The time that he hit the topic of this vexation, the tears came.
-Here you have an aggravation on the physical level, then you have to know whether
this aggravation is because of a mental-emotional amelioration.
This is very important, otherwise you go wrong.
And this child emotionally is already much better, even when his father did all this and
he was embarrassed, he still managed to say, you're wrong and he managed to ...
His defenses on that level were very correct. How he responded to his father.
So it is the opposite of what it was said. His shyness is much less, there is no way that
a Baryta carbonica child would sit here and even talk, would even open his mouth.
You ask him and would look and he wants to hide, there is nothing to do with
Baryta carbonica. Dwarfishness is not the idea.
I have seen this in Sulphur, children develop from some problems in hypophysis they
don't develop and then Sulphur, you see them next year, they have 20 cm.
It's not always Baryta, a child Baryta will never do this, will be able to face the class
to answer questions in such presence of mind. No timidity, whatsoever.
And when you bring the subject which is very painful all the time, this time is not.
With the physical aggravation, you say wait. That is where the whole class has gone wrong.
What I can see is that this emotional problem has brought about some very deep
changes in the physical body, which will take time to be corrected, it's not just a
functional thing, it's much more than that.
Therefore we have to be very patient and wait and I will give you an estimation.
What I think is that in 3 months his vomiting will almost be gone.
So we wait, though I would have liked even a higher potency, a stronger but still
now it is OK for me because definitely there is the aggravation at the physical level
but at the same time an emotional amelioration.
This deep trauma is not anymore here, it is somewhere in the kidneys or in the stomach
or whatever.
-Considering that you wanted to give him a 50M in the beginning and you didn't have it
but now with this aggravation in the physical level, there is no possibility to give him
the higher potency of Veratrum?
-I don't want to, now. I see this amelioration which is very apparent for me.
Otherwise you would have seen the child in front of the class?
We say he knows the class. Who knows the class? He was in the room crying.
He comes in the class and still is on that state, he would be teared into pieces.
What I did was a little dangerous because you could see the child crying and then you
would say, why did you ask him this question.
But I had to do it in order to decide. It's very important for the life of this child,
for me to understand what has taken place. It's much more important, it may be cruel
to ask again the same question but at the same time I want to be sure that
my evaluation is correct. Because everybody would say, give another remedy,
give Pulsatilla, give Phosphorus.
Phosphorus and Pulsatilla is a possibility for later on, we'll see how it develops
but the intolerance to fat and milk show that the digestive system is at fault
for the time being, we'll see how it will develop.
It's a very good case this one for you to be more careful in your evaluation.