He was born normal child and he developed autism after,
when he was a year and a half, he was immunized
and shortly after that he became severely autistic.
However even before there were certain...
- What were the vaccinations?– MMR, mumps, measles, rubella.
– That’s all? Previously did he have other vaccination?
– A few, not all, because we were postponing everything. I don’t like vaccination.
– Why were you postponing? Were you afraid?
– I didn’t like vaccinations at all but I could not find a way to get rid of it
because I knew in Canada it’s not a law but I couldn’t find a way...
- To bypass?– Yes. Everybody was telling there is a paper
but I could not find how to get the paper.
So I did get find out from Helen when he was at the age of 3 and he didn’t have after that any.
So I was postponing all.– That means he had at the age of 6 months he had some?
– Yes,some.
– Do you remember to give me an idea of what exactly happened with the vaccinations?
– He only had one reaction.
– When was the first vaccination and what was the vaccination?
– I think he was 2 months old but I don’t know what...
-Usually in Canada at 2,5 months they do diphtheria, tetanus and pertussis.
– That was 2 months. Then again?– I don’t remember. I have a paper.
– But you don’t have it with you.– But he didn’t react to them.
– There was a preparation on the organism by these vaccinations
and when the third time came the vaccination then the organism broke down,
it doesn’t break down like that but the last vaccination...what was it?
– MMR. And it was an anamnesis? It was given this before and repeated?
– No, it was the first time.– And it was 1,5 year old.
– At that time also I stopped breast feeding him, so he was breastfed until 18 months.
He got rubella and 2 months after that he got his first big fever,
with sore throat, treated with antibiotics.
– You gave him antibiotics?– Not she, the doctor.
- She is a doctor?–No. The doctor gave it. And then we went to Serbia,
because we are originally from Serbia and my husband’s mother died,
then we went back to Canada, the kid got again throat infection,
again treated with double antibiotics too
and after that I noticed something he was... lost.
– So there was a vaccination,
then after the vaccination there were several times tonsillitis, 2 times or 3?
– 3 times. First, before Serbia and then after Serbia in a 6-month period.
– And the last time he needed double antibiotics?– Yes.
- He needed double antibiotics because the fever would not go down?
– Yes. So sad.– Also the trauma.
She mentioned to me that when she stopped breastfeeding he became very sad.
– He never reacted. And it surprised me because I went to a friend for 2 days
and then I came back and... he loved breastfeeding and he never reacted.
And I felt terrible because we were sort of talking to each other
and I was asking him are you ready to cut off?
So we cut it off and he didn’t react to it and I found it very strange,
I felt as if I had betrayed my child because he didn’t react to something he really liked,
he never asked about anything ever. He suppressed his reaction.
– When you cut the breastfeeding there was vaccination
and after 3 days or after 3 months you stopped?
– I think it was before.– He was 1 year old, when she stopped breastfeeding.
– No, a year and a half.
– He was a year and a half when you stopped breastfeeding.–Exactly.
– Then he was vaccinated.– Yes.
– How long after that?– Maybe a few days. 2 weeks the most.
– And then the tonsillitis, when did it come?
– This was 15th July, tonsillitis in the beginning of November. So that’s 4 months.
– 4 months later he develops severe tonsillitis. Very high fever?– Yes, 40-41,5 Celsius.
– Gave him antibiotics, for how long? One week?– Yes, one week.
– Then you go to Serbia.– There was a big emotional reaction.
He really liked the grandma, he was playing with her on her bed, she died of cancer,
so the day that she went to the hospital, he was crying,
he knew that she was going to die.
– But by the time you went to Serbia he already was 2 year old?
– Not really. It was December.– 22 months. Has he started talking already?
– No, he was late with talking. No. After that his talk diminished.
He was talking before that...
- You told me that 9 months he talked.– When he is 1,5 year-old,
when you cut breastfeeding, you were communicating by words with him? Yes.
– Was he saying yes or no?– Yes.
– And he could understand what you were asking?– Yes.
After that he drank rice milk, I said bring the bottle,
he went to another room and brought the bottle.
And then at the age of 4 my son couldn’t do that anymore.
And he had words, we were reading the book,
what the cow says, moo, he knew all that.
– You must tell that to the authorities.– I know.
– They don’t want to listen.
– There were a few problems before with him
because he started teething very early at 4 months he got his first teeth
and then his teeth at the age of 2 crumbled. In that period they were getting bad.
–And the teeth fell off at the age of 2?
– No. Crumbled with lots of cavities.
Especially the four front. When he was 1 year old all his teeth were out.
– Then when I first saw him in the beginning of 2008
he was completely not communicating with anybody.
He was just running around in circles and making noises
and she said that I cannot communicate with my son I cannot get through
and she started crying.– By that time he was 3 years old.
– First, I didn’t know what to do, just running around,
I repertorized her and gave her Staphisagria. She’s on one remedy per se.
– You gave to the mother?– Yes. I do that with the babies too,
I give the mother remedy at first. He also had Staphisagria symptoms with the teeth,
they were all covered with yellow stuff.
– She was not breast feeding him.- I know. I thought it was the right thing to do.
But he reacted to Staphisagria, he started sleeping through the night,
so after that I thought about it some more and gave him Carcinosin,
he was doing very well on Carcinosin and half a year later, gave him Tuberculinum,
he had lots of severe allergies. And he was grinding his teeth
and was very restless at night and sweaty.
– But he had no teeth. How was he grinding?– No, they were there, just crumbled.
When she said all his teeth were out she meant all teeth were coming out, not falling off.
There were there just crumbling. He still is grinding his teeth sometimes.
– Yes, on and off. I would like to say about the allergies.
When he was a month and a half old from my husband’s side his younger brother
had extreme eczema, as a result of food allergies. But they never tested him.
He developed a severe eczema in a month and a half,
my mother in law gave him to lick a little bit of chocolate.
– One month and half he developed an eczema all over the body.
And what did you give? Not homeopathically.
– The prescribed cortisone, of course and what I tried, I knew cortisone was bad,
we did put some times, not all the time, and then I was testing him through me
because he was breastfeeding, I would test him through me for the allergies,
meaning I would exclude wheat for a week and then watch my child,
then I would exclude milk for a week, so by his 5,5 months I had a list by testing him
and then he didn’t need remedies. That’s what we did.
– How do you know that it was not suppressed by the [cortisone] cream already?
– Because they were coming out, if I ate something it would come out, it was really bad.
– Again?– Yes, again and again it comes out.
– But after the finally going away of the eczema did it come out a month later
if he ate some allergic food.– I didn’t eat anything.
– Sometimes you may have accidentally eaten something.
– It suddenly comes out. For example, he was allergic not only to food but perfumes.
So if a lady with a perfume and touches him he got eczema.
If your detergent is really strong and he scrubs on your detergent he gets eczema.
That’s not very bad because you can wash it and it goes away.
The problem is when it goes inside by food, through the inhaling of perfumes etc.
– The eczema came through many times when I was treating him.
– It was so bad as if he had third degree burns.
–During your treatment, did the eczema come back?
– Yes. He had fevers, like when I first gave him Carcinosin and Tuberculinum.
Not very often, every 3 months or so he had extreme fevers like 40 Celsius or more.
– With tonsillitis?– No. Mostly cough. Tonsillitis never came back.
But in between the fever or after the fever he would often get eczema too.
And fevers were very long lasting. And often after the fever he would get better mentally.
He also developed infection in his mouth a few times,
so I gave him Mercury, Belladonna, Pulsatilla. He reacted very well with his fevers.
He stops drinking, becomes extremely clingy to his mother.
– He is very attached to me, still. Pulsatilla state.– His father is very detached?
– He is a Lycopodium but he is a very nice guy. They are very good parents.
– He is not detached, he likes his son but he just didn’t know at the beginning,
before Lycopodium how to play much. Now he is different.
– So he always had this cough as he would get in the acute, there is lots of mucus,
but last year, exactly the day before I came here, he started having severe dyspnea,
that’s the first time, a year ago. Ended up in the hospital.
– They gave him inhalation?– Yes. Mentally he is so much better
every time after most of the remedies, he would get so much better.
– That’s the only one we give him some times. He had one dose that time of cortisone...
– Does it contain cortisone?– That one doesn’t. It’s the only one that doesn’t.
But that time, when he ended up in the hospital last year,
they gave him one dose of cortisone to swallow, not only to inhale,
plus cortisone liquid and it changed his behavior in 3 days but Helen gave him a remedy...
- After the cortisone did you notice any change in his behavior.
– He was hyperactive, I couldn’t talk to him. Not anymore, though.
– The most important thing that I see here is as he gets better and better mentally,
his asthma gets worse and the remedies start shifting too like,
in the start Antimonium worked for probably almost a year, last year,
and though there is still a little bit of rattling always there left, it stopped working.
Then the picture started changing more often. In May he was an Arsenicum,
because he developed very burning discharge and some other symptoms,
for 3 weeks Arsenicum worked perfectly and then it stopped.
Before that Phosphorus worked for over a year, probably,
Phosphorus had a tremendous impact on him mentally and emotionally.
But since last year, asthma episodes started getting worse
and now they have to use inhalers every time there is an episode of asthma
because he cannot breathe and so I started using the remedies more often.
Like right he is on Antimonium which worked by 3 weeks ago.
Now he is in Antimonium 200C and 1M once a day.
– Is he coughing?- No, but you can hear wheezing.
Sometimes. Now, he is really good.
But what we noticed when he started getting remedies often
like every day a certain amount, he got better. He is better mentally.
But the remedies are shifting from 2 weeks.
–The Antimonium did not stopped working last year, totally and now it works again.
Also tried Pulsatilla last time and did not work at all.
And he doesn’t have high fevers anymore, fewer and milder,
he does not have these high fever episodes anymore. Last month he had 38,5 Celsius.
– I will see him. Will he easily respond to questions?
– He does may not appear, especially when he is anxious,
but he understands everything, he knows everything.
They were in Volos, last week, they went one way from the hotel
to wherever they were going to take another route, he’d never been there before,
and he said no we go the exact same route. So he knows everything.
He is extremely sensitive too. Not even to criticism.
He is very afraid that his mom is angry at him.
So, if she just raises her voice just like that, he is already so scared,
why are you angry with me, what’s going on, he wants to please her all the time.
– He says so or his eyes look so?– No, he says mom what’s wrong, are you ok.
– He needs approval. At school when they say well work
and they will tell mom he had a good day at school, this is a motivator.
Big approval of mother all the time. Of both parents!
– Overboard you mean, really, all the time makes you tired saying “you are so good”?
– Yes. You have to tell him all the time.
– If his father is strict with him he doesn’t get frightened or upset. But if his mom is...
- It’s worse.– The approval he needs from you only or from his teachers?
– From everybody but mom is the highest.
– However sometimes, he gets into periods he is very upset at her,
if she leaves for work without telling him, then she comes back,
then he goes into his room, closes the door, doesn’t want to talk to her
and she has to beg him.– I have to come and say I am home,
I’m sorry, I had to go, I apologize.
- And another thing he does, punish them both if, for example,
they don’t let him swim for the entire day,
he is not happy with his parents, he soils his pants.
– As a punishment to us.– Yesterday we didn’t go swimming
because it was so cold and he loves beach and water,
and he would punish us by soiling his pants, making his statement.
He holds a grudge against somebody, if you are not nice to him,
there was cousin who wasn’t nice to him, 9 months he wouldn’t see her,
she is in the room, he behaves as if she doesn’t exist.
Not anymore as extreme but holds a grudge a lot if somebody pushes him away
or pushes him down, offends him in any way.
– And a few times he had very close friends, they left, he suffered so much.
I gave him Ignatia a couple of times. He became very sad and depressed.
– But that’s understandable because he doesn’t have many friends,
people don’t connect easily to him and when he has people they have patience with him,
because he is very smart and he can give a lot but just cannot communicate as much.
He gets upset if people go away or they don’t pay attention to him.
He gets stuck on one food often and just eats one thing for a long time.
– He wants to eat only one food?– Once he eats spicy salsa or spaghetti...
– Every day spaghetti?– Not every day but he is narrow-minded with the food,
he wants 3-4 things, he can maybe eat 50 but he wants now 5 things only.
So, I always have to push to new stuff...
- You have another child?– No.
– She is afraid to.– You had enough with the one.
– It’s not enough, but I am afraid for him too, not for me, it’s our struggle but...
- It’s ok but why don’t you have another child?
– She is afraid it’s going to be autistic again. That’s what I say, it won’t, right?
– They told you that the other child may be [autistic]?
– No, they didn’t tell me. I am just afraid.– There’s no such a chance...
- I am trying to persuade her.– Because you are healthy
and your husband is healthy, the boy was born healthy.
It was made sick with vaccination and antibiotics, that is very clear.
Everyone who will be hammered by all these introduction of the chemicals into the body
will break down. So, there is no problem.
– Can I tell you about his eating?– His eating habits.
– Yes. He doesn’t drink water at all, he drinks juice, orange juice.
– Aversion to water?–Yes. And he doesn’t crave for bread.
Here because he didn’t have much of his teeth he didn’t want to eat bread
but at home he doesn’t want bread. Doesn’t like sweets.
I didn’t like when I was a kid but he really doesn’t like sweets at all.
- This is very unusual in Canada not to like sweets.
– His father likes sweets.– A lot!
- Is there any other peculiarity about him?
– He doesn’t like to try new food or new way it’s made.
Like tomatoes; he likes everything from tomatoes, like salsa, but not the fresh.
– His feet always sweat and smell sometimes.
– Sometimes they are offensive and often wet.
–I remember I gave him Silica at one point during one of the fevers.
– Salt?– He likes salt.
– That means he adds salt? Takes the salt and eats it?
– No, he doesn’t add on his own. If I put on the cucumbers lots of salt he likes and licks,
he likes salty but he doesn’t ask for things yet. Not everything.
– He eats meat?– Yes.
– Sausages?– Not anymore. He used to like sausages, not anymore.
Now, not deli, just meat.
– When the meat has some fat in it, he likes it?– I think he’s ok.
– He is not picky on that one.– Likes cold food. I warm it up and he waits...
- This is the reason why I have his Silica.
– Your language is French or English?– Our language is Serbian
but with his we are speaking English. First, we started speaking Serbian.
– What do you say?– He is very anxious right now.
Sometimes he is scripting from the movies that he likes
and picks up the sentences and repeating them.
Now, he knows he is being observed so he is anxious.
– I think he is observing other people...
- When it is safe at home he can communicate way more.
– He articulates properly?– He speaks and reads and writes
and does presentation at school. He is just very nervous right now.
– Plays by himself. Autistic children cannot play by themselves.
He plays, he is creative and he uses his imagination. Plays with other kids too.
– Eggs, he eats?– No. He is allergic to eggs.
– Allergic but do you think he likes them?– We tried but...
- He refuses anything that contains allergens.
– After Tuberculinum he started eating cheese. Dairy allergy was cured by Tuberculinum.
– Something peculiar; he likes opening holes.
If he has a hole he puts things in it and makes it big...
- He also touches his genitals often.
– He is performing now.–Yes.
– He always likes people watching him.– He likes touching his genitals often.
– That started 2 years ago, on and off, sometimes more sometimes less but it is still there.
– Also he likes sensations on his skin of something soft like he will take a blanket
and put it in his pants or shirt...-... He likes rough games.
– In the summer he likes to walk undressed?– No.
– When he goes to the toilet, he goes by himself?
– Yes, he can go. Sometimes we go together, but yes he goes by himself more and more.
He still cannot wipe himself, yet.–Does he play with the stool?
– No, he doesn’t play. I didn’t see him play. I don’t think he actually likes mud and paint.
I like to paint and he doesn’t like to paint, get dirty...
- He would ask her to wash his hands. He used to play a lot in the sand
and then he would just wash his hands, he doesn’t like them dirty.
– The sensation of sand calms him down.
– Has he shown any aggressiveness towards some other children?
– Never. He likes having people to console him when crying. Big empathy.
– He likes to put fingers in his mouth.–Not all the time but occasionally.
– He loves music and dance, water, fishing, beach, sea, ocean.
– You mean the sea water or swimming pool?– Anything...
- You caught a fish?– I got a fish.
– Do you like fishing?– I like fishing.
– We are going to go to the beach today.– Is he sleeping by himself?
– He sleeps beside us.  He was sleeping in another room when he was 1 year old.
We put him in another room because he was breastfeeding all the night.
I couldn’t sleep at all...
- Was he grinding?– No, he was breastfeeding all the night.
And at year one we put him in a nursery in another room
and he was there for almost 1 year
and then Helen told us that maybe he needs to be put back to our bed.
But he wasn’t breastfeeding so I didn’t matter anymore.
– Was he ever afraid of the dark? You had to leave a light on?
– At that time I don’t know. Definitely, he didn’t like being alone in a room in the crib
but there always was a little light. It wasn’t completely dark.
– But now he is in the dark and when he wakes up he is totally ok.
– Are you now working yourself?– Part time.
– What kind of work?– I am teaching at the college interior design.
Like inside architecture.– You studied that.
– And she is a painter too, she is an artist.
When he wakes up in the morning and it’s dark now he is fine.
– No problem at all. He likes to garden with mama.
– Have ever given him a lemon to see how he reacts? If he eats the lemon, desires lemon.
– We don’t know.– It’s hard testing new food on him
because he doesn’t want to try anything.– Oranges?
– He loves oranges and orange juice, he drinks it like water.
– Fresh orange juice?– Not we don’t make it, we buy it.
– He drinks fresh orange juice here, so he can drink it.
– You don’t have fresh oranges in Canada?– He eats fresh oranges.
– Other fruits he likes?– When he was 2 years old he ate everything.
I was making everything for him because he was allergic.
So after that he started being picky, now he eats cucumbers a lot, me too,
oranges and bananas, sometimes apple, but he can eat all the fruits,
he was eating them before, he just doesn’t want to eat them now, watermelon.
So watermelon, oranges and sometimes banana and apple.
– He is also very sensitive to sunlight. He used to be much more. Not so much now.
Yesterday he accidentally hit his leg against my shoe
and he wanted to kiss my leg right away. I thought he was going to kiss my shoe
and told him oh no don’t kiss my shoe.
He went like that and he crawled under the bed because it was a little bit too loud
and he thought I am angry at him. He is so sensitive.
- He got afraid of the sound?– He accidentally hit my leg with his leg just slightly
but he thought that he hurt me. So he wanted to kiss my leg.
And I saw that he was going to kiss my dirty shoe
and said “no, don’t!” and he got scared of my reaction.
Closed his ears and crawled under the bed. You cannot talk even a little bit loud to him.
If he is upset or cries he is very upset.– He has sensitivity to sound.
It was really bad at one point, last year actually,
when you left for Greece and after Carcinosin...- He got much better after Carcinosin...
- He was much better after that. Now it’s  just high pitch noise sometimes...
- If it is deep sound he can handle it.
– I don’t think he is scared I just think it hurts him, he has a sensitivity to it.
– Sensitivity to hearing.
– With autism it is common that they get overwhelmed with everything.
– He wants harmony, that’s for sure, he doesn’t want any problems,
anybody being hurt, angry or sad...
- He doesn’t like his food to be changed but he loves to travel,
he loves the change in a big, not in a small level.
He needs his surroundings to keep him calm and out of anxiety.
When we told him about Greece and about airplane, he was so excited,
he wanted to go, he enjoyed the whole trip,
but when we got to Athens he asked for his orange juice.
He still wants his little meals to be prepared the way he likes it.
But he likes to travel, see new places, new people,
so he has this adventurous side in him. He likes running like auto-stimulation,
in a room sometimes goes back and forth, not as much, before it was in circles.
– As stimulation or to calm him down?– That one yes! To calm.
– He is riding bicycle at home for the same thing.
– But if he runs too much he starts getting some asthma symptoms. Ok, thank you!
First of all I must say that the improvement from the original state is quite impressive
and most probably it is due to 3 remedies out of those you gave;
Carcinosin, Tuberculinum and Antimonium tartaricum.
The question is what I see at this moment, what is the most probable picture.
It is not a clear picture. There are several possibilities like Causticum,
Hyoscyamus, Palladium also is a possibility, Asarum is a possibility
but I don’t know how it will develop.
In order to come down to the most probable remedy at the moment...
which is an interesting feature of the boy from what we observed.
There are some strong symptoms of Causticum. But what impressed you?
Looking at the child what impressed you?
– I noticed that it was very restless
and obviously he was anxious at the beginning when he came in.
He wanted to hide when he came into the room
but then he started peeping out from behind to see what was going on
and after a while when he was more comfortable he was actually quite outgoing
and was performing with his dinosaurs trying to spy you out,
so he came over quite open then, as far as he can, of course, in his condition.
He was communicative but always going back to a safe place of the mother
or the father to hide. That’s from the external only.
– It’s very interesting for me to see how much usually
the mother almost never the father is identified with the children of that type.
The mother tries to understand, explain and need to explain why the boy is running
because a logical explanation that the boy will not do something beyond logic
and they need that and they identify themselves so much.
– Singing all the time, the boy. Nobody noticed that.
During all the interview he was singing.– Is this correct Helen?
– I think he was whimpering, he was a little scared,
he was whimpering into his mother lap.– Was he singing or making noises?
– He actually moans a lot. When he is sick with asthma or anything,
he moans, he moans in sleep...- Anyhow. Moaning.
– If something happens like after a really really bad asthma episode his mother said
“ok, you are safe now” and he cried and cried for very long time.
I think it was after a trip to the hospital, cause he couldn’t breathe at all,
he gets very bad dyspnea. So she said you’re ok now, you’re safe now
and he started crying and he does that from time to time if something happens.
The child is in his own world, not communicating.
He wasn’t affectionate when I first saw him.
He became like that later on and this is when I prescribed Phosphorus.
When I saw his being affectionate, there was such a difference,
I think it was one and a half year ago, I suddenly saw an affectionate child,
he wasn’t like that at all at first, he was all in himself, like a little animal.
– There’s a big improvement, there is no question.
– But seeing him being so affectionate I prescribed Phosphorus
and then he was much better. And Phosphorus worked on his asthma for a long time
and then stopped.
– For me watching him, the most impressive is the playing antics,
the grimaces, this is what in our repertories is seen as playing antics.
Show me the remedies. Hyoscyamus is the only in capital, Belladonna...
But this is a characteristic of Hyoscyamus, actually, quite strongly.
What you saw is what we know Hyoscyamus is doing.
And grimaces also, another expression. Playing antics means he is performing. Grimaces;
Hyoscyamus is there as well. So Hyoscyamus seem to be the indicated remedy
especially because he says lately he is touching his genitalia.
That was confirmed by the mother quite a lot.
So if we see the symptoms covered by Hyoscyamus, handles his genitalia,
grimaces, aversion to water also is interesting that Hyoscyamus has aversion to water
and grinding teeth during sleep, moaning, respiration rattling, sensitive to noise,
asthmatic respiration and desire to hide also with the playing antics combined.
From this remedy missing the fact the has aversion to sweets so strong,
which we would like to have, the desire for oranges, the aggravation from eggs,
offensive foot, discolored teeth, aversion to sweets that comes from the mother also,
it’s almost a hereditary thing, so it’s quite deep,
maybe later on will go to Causticum with the affection
and the sympathetic element will remain
but I think Hyoscyamus is going to help further the development of the child.
– What are we looking for after that?
– After that the aversion to sweets will remain the sensitivity to others
and the sympathetic element will remain, most probably,
and I don’t know what effect will have on his allergies.
He has an allergic asthma, it is quite severe,
I don’t know how much Hyoscyamus will control this or you will need the next remedy.
Most probably will make the asthmatic condition better
but he will need another remedy, definitely
and most probably he will need Causticum as the next remedy.
But at this moment where the shyness, you see no shyness at all, he can perform,
he can do whatever he likes, he doesn’t care what you think,
that kind with playing antics and the grimaces and all that
and the touching of the genitalia plus the other symptoms
brings us to the idea of Hyoscyamus and what is the potency?
You see the child was damaged by vaccination and antibiotics,
the combination actually, and that is why you were able to bring up such improvement.
Children who are born, straightaway, autistic are very difficult to improve,
but if they are damaged through antibiotics or vaccination
or the combination of them it is much easier to have some good effect.
I believe this child can be quite improved
and maybe at the age of 15 or 16 he will be almost normal.
You didn’t see him when he wasn’t anxious, there is a tremendous difference,
he was a little animal, now he is a human being.
– This is amazing what Homeopathy can do in such cases where no other treatment,
as far as I know, can have such an effect.
– I wanted to ask; he had a big desire for oranges like Medorrhinum...
- Medorrhinum is also a possibility.
– Also the mother said, when they didn’t allow him yesterday to go to the sea,
because it was cold, he punished them because he really wanted to go.
– Also another thing is with Hyoscyamus, I forgot, this stool,
to have stool is Hyoscyamus symptom.
– But he didn’t say about stool if I understood well...
- It’s an explanation of the mother, he wants to punish.
This is just nonsense that a normal child would punish by doing that.
It has to be a symptom. There is another explanation,
he wants to punish and he has stool.
Of course the fact that he allows a 7 year-old to have stool is a symptom.
– But did she say stool or soil? She said soil.
– It’s the same. I like the explanation. The mothers explain away everything;
he does this because of this, he does the other because of that.
In fact, you have to see the whole picture. It’s a child that plays antics,
touches his genitalia, he cannot still control his stool etc. And then becomes a picture.
– He does it when he is angry.– She thinks.
He does it under certain psychological pressure. Whatever it might be.
– Hyoscyamus has a strong fear of water.– No. He says aversion to water.
Does not want to drink. Not fear.
– He loves to play with water, that is what the mother had said,
and Hyoscyamus has strong fear of water.
– Also a lot of other remedies have fear of water.
The fact that a symptom is missing from a remedy does not mean anything.
– It’s not missing, it’s the other way around. Someone who has fear
and somebody who loves water.
– Yes, but what is the problem? There’s no problem.
That’s natural. Liking the water is natural.
He, simply, does not have fear of water, he has aversion to water.
– There is also his sycotic background, he loves the sea...
- Correct. Most probably later on he will need some Medorrhinum,
I didn’t want to embarrass the couple asking whether the father...
- I asked...- He denied?
– No, I don’t think. His father reacted to Lycopodium perfectly...
I said his sycotic background is from his mother who is a Staphisagria,
which treated her depression, her neck pains, her throat, everything.
This might have contributed to his problems too because she was really an abused child.
At the age of 13 she would clean the whole house and prepare food for her parents,
her mother would come and say “why didn’t you clean this?”
and “why didn’t you do that?”. At the time he got sick there was a very difficult conflict.
– You belong to the feminine movement?– You said you will give him 30C?
– No. I did not. The potency you can start with is 200C.
You give 200C every day for a few days, see the reaction
and then if he is better and then worse
then you may repeat as long as he keeps on playing the antics,
doing all this kind of performance. When that keynote is gone,
most probably you have to search for the next remedy
which I think can be Causticum, Medorrhinum, Palladium or Asarum.
Because he has high fever we can consider him to be curable.
Just because his immune system has the possibility of developing high fever.
Is curable. Level 5 or 6.
– If he had more vaccinations or more antibiotics...
- The fact that cortisone interfered during this,
that was bad but you immediately saw the reaction,
you said the boy was chaotic immediately. Can go down to level 7 quite easily.
– Why do you consider Palladium?
– Because he needs so much approval from others.
That is a characteristic of Palladium and if that remains. Of course it is just an idea.
The most probable are Causticum, Medorrhinum.
– For this little boy, he had his teeth at 4 months
and he was talking at 9 months so he was really early.
– He was talking quite early. 9 months.
– Do you consider it is a factor of sensitivity...
I mean he is early on the development, maybe also on the brain system,
so maybe he can be touched much more than any other,
because a lot of children have a lot of antibiotics
and vaccinations and don’t have anything?
– What you are saying is correct. Most probably, has a relevance.
That means because the organism was fast in developing.
He had certain extra sensitivities and because of the interference of the vaccination
and the antibiotics brought the organism down.
– As from experience can you please guide us
in what cases we should move to X and C potencies?
Some books suggest prescribing X potencies multiple times but so far,
until now, I have not received any final standpoint from where we should go on X
or we should go on C.
– When you want to go low you may go to X. 12X, 8X, 9X.
If you want to go very low you can go to quintecimal potencies
which are very light. 1 to 50000. These are very light remedies
and you can repeat them always. LM pontencies.
But in my experience I don’t have to use LM potencies so...
If I want to go low I go to 6X. Very low. 6X is the lowest.
– There are some questions.
You had not told which pharmacy you are using for your practice.
The authenticity of the medicine or the genuinity is of big question of today.
– I use all the kind of pharmacies. But if I see I give a remedy
and does not work but I am sure the remedy is correct I use from another pharmacy
and I throw away the previous one.
Many times with the pharmacies here we have a problem
because I prescribe a remedy, no effect, higher potency, no effect
and then goes to another pharmacy, takes the same potency and there is a big effect.
So, I call the pharmacy and say to throw away your Rhus tox 200C.
Make a new one. We have this problem.
– In that particular case I have one more question to finish with them.
If we go to 1M then to 10M then to 50M and then to CM,
still the same remedy is indicated then...?– MM.
– We don’t get MM.– You prepare. Ask a pharmacy to.
– My question is, I have a case of...
- Actually in the old times they used to give these remedies MM, is not a joke,
but what they did they put a jet of water and then they had the potency
and the jet of water went into washing out all the time
and they had calculated that if they let this, for instance 3 hours,
the water that goes in and out within 3 hours is 1.000.000 times.
Still they said it worked, I don’t know...- So after CM...
I have a case of motor neuron disease, it is a case of Causticum.
I started with 200C, I raised the power and now is on CM.
I give him CM whenever he has an exacerbation of the problems
otherwise I stick on placebo. Now I am stuck up.
Indications are seen but I don’t have a rising potency. What is your opinion on that?
– Take the CM and potentize it a few times. Just to make it a little bit stronger.
And if that does not work then you can start all over going back to 12X
and start with repeating it frequently.
– In that case, Erik has taught us that higher potencies antidote low potencies
so suppose a patient comes to us and we have given him CM potency
and if he comes after 6 months or 1 year, should we start with CM or from any potency?
– You must normally start with the last potency.
– He has already taken CM but he comes after 1 year.
– You give again the last potency that was CM.
Also concerning his question this child had no fear of water
therefore you will not give Hyoscyamus, this is not correct
because in 100 cases of Hyoscyamus perhaps the fear of water will be in 2.
The rest 98 cases have no fear of water. 98% do not have fear of water.
– Once again I had a doubt here.
I see that you don’t take into consideration a symptom that was apparently very clear,
ailments after antibiotics and ailments after vaccination
because Hyoscyamus doesn’t have any of these symptoms...
- You speak a little bit fast for me. I did not take into consideration that...?
– 2 symptoms that ailments from antibiotics and vaccination.
Hyoscyamus doesn’t have them.– So what should I have given?
– Stramonium because Stramonium has both of them.
And Stramonium has all the rest; the antics, the grimaces...
- Stramonium is much more aggressive.
He will hit, provoke, shout, see nightmares. It’s another picture.
And fear of the dark is strong. Thank you!