This is the 8th follow-up of a young girl we saw 9 years ago
with the diagnosis of pubertas praecox where very early menses started
and for this syndrome it is compulsory, I think, in your country to take hormone treatment...
- Every 28 days.
– So we started treatment with Med.
which she has received in several repeated doses, she had Lach., Phos., Lyc., Stram.
I prescribed Stram.?
– Yes, each year. I didn’t touch the case.
– Puls. She has not taken any other homeopathic remedies?
– Only Bell. in acute state.
Or Dros. once but nothing else.
– Now, as you can see she has developed quite nicely,
she’s not taking the hormones since a few years already...- Since nearly 5 years.
– She was supposed not to develop according to the standards.
She’s good in school and catching some cold rarely, otherwise she feels quite healthy.
Her menses are irregular, what do you mean?
Misses menses, sometimes very short menses?
– Very short. It’s different.
Sometimes it’s too long period, sometimes it’s too short, it’s not arriving every 28 days.
– Before menses your psychology changes, you’re irritable, depressed, anxious?
– No.– Her problem is that she has a certain sleeplessness, falling asleep takes a long time.
What happens? You go to bed and you start thinking?
– Yes.
– And the thoughts are about real things in life or imaginations?
– Real life.
– Can you tell us what the thoughts are?
– About friends and school.
– Inside you, you feel that you are fighting with them, they have hurt you by their remark?
– Yes. This kind of things.
– Dreaming a lot in the morning hours. You remember your dreams?
– Yes, sometimes.
– Do they have a theme? You see water, the sea, flying,
that you are in a specific place, is there a constant theme?
– Not really.
From films. But different subjects. After having seen a film on the TV.
– You write that her fear is what others think about her. A lack of self-confidence.
She is a good student?
– She is very good in the school.
– Medium?
– Medium.
– Do you study a lot or as much as you need to pass?
– The second.
– Are you interested in boys?
– Sometimes.
– The father is here but... You want me to send him out?
– No, it’s alright! There are no secrets.
– She feels better in the evening, she loves the sea. She likes to eat bananas, sweets,
ice cream and vegetables, chicken, sea fruits?
– What is sea fruits? – Fish, mussels.
– She eats nothing that puts on weight.
She drinks, mainly, water, the water must be cold?
– Yes.
– In the evening she is quite disciplined.
– She has aversion to onions.
– Anything else that you cannot eat?
– No.
– Do you use a lot of salt in your food?
– Normal. You like sweets but you avoid them.
– I know from the mother that in the evening she is very disciplined not to eat a lot of sweets.
– She stays with her mother mostly?
– Yes.
– All the time?
– Half-half.
– You cook for her?
– Sometimes, yes, if I have time.
– She tries to remain cool when there are quarrels around. She likes peace.
She likes discussion with friends. She does not like obstinate people.
According to my understanding she is quite good and we should not interfere at all.
Let her develop normally and she is quite a healthy child as I can see and I can also read.
There is no need at this moment, she has developed nicely. She’s almost at your height!
– But she was not here last year and I thought it would be better for you to see her.
– Yes. It is good to see that she is developing and she may marry and have children,
then I live until 250. Ok, that’s it, no medication! Thank you!