-It's 11 months old boy, it's born 20th of October 96, he was one week late,
and the umbilical cord was around his neck and the delivery was
-Speak slower and more clear.
-His weight was 3.620 gr, his height 53 cm, the anamnesis of 5th of January 97 was
the following. Parents removing from one flat to another but it was a neighbor flat and
the mother was very nervous, everybody was very nervous and there was a lot of fuss
going on. He had milk crusts on his head with bad smell and around the size of a palm.
-How old he was by that time?
-Half a year.
-And how this went away?
-He received Sulphur 1M and after that it went away almost, to a little small like a coin.
-You have treated the child so far?
-I gave him Sulphur but after that he received Calcium.
-Calcarea carbonica?
-Cal. carb. 20th of August this year, 200 Calcarea.
-And Sulphur?
-1M, 5th January 97.
-When did the child develop the neurodermatitis?
-It was middle of June, end of June. In the beginning of the year he was very restless
his hands and arms were always moving and he was showing with his arms to the air
just like this.
-Before Sulphur?
-Before Sulphur. When being in the baby carrier, he was calmed down, also when we
were driving, the vibration did him good, he falls asleep in a couple of minutes when
he had been softly vibrated.
Also when he was hearing soft music or all kind of music, he likes it, now he is even
clapping his hands when hearing the music.
When he was being dressed up for walk and gets warm, he starts crying very much.
-Crying, not scratching?
-No. Why he is crying? When he is dressed up?
-It was winter and if he is getting dressed up, in January and he was very soon too warm
then he started crying.
-And if you take out his clothes, then he calms down?
-Yes. He was sweating easily, he has smelly perspiration in his hairy scalp and around
the nose, there are always little drops around his nose.
-Only the nose?
-Scalp and the nose.
He was a little too late when he was born and he had already the finger nails and he
was scratching his face very much, immediately after birth, which is considered to be
relatively normal.
He sleeps 7 hours at night, best on his belly.
-This report when it's written?
-In January.
-Before you gave Sulphur?
-Yes. Afternoon sleep is very bad because of restlessness, he likes warm bathing
with his father, 38 degrees, he doesn't like to be alone in the bath.
-38 degrees in the bath but he cries when he is dressed?
-Yes.
He wants to feel his parents, specifically his mother close, otherwise he screams.
This was in January. We tried to let him sleep without breast feeding during sleep or
in the beginning of the sleep but he wouldn't accept it. He would scream.
-He was immediately feeding before go to sleep.
-Yes he would fall asleep during breast feeding.
He likes very much to go out and play, mainly with other children, still now.
After receiving Sulphur his mood was 95% better, his sleep was much more calm and
he slept now from 7 until midnight without waking and he would wake at midnight
he takes a breast and then after he sleeps again.
Then there was a vaccination from 24th of January to 20th of March, he received
hepatitis B, TB, diphtheria, haemophilus influenza all intramuscular in the right thigh and
the first and last state combined with polio.
Everything together.
-All this is compulsory for Germany?
-No.
-But until that time there was no trace of neurodermatitis?
-No, nothing.
-Some of them at least they need a repetition. When it was the repetition?
-Of the vaccination?
-Yes.
-It was 3 times, these 3 months from 24th of January, 20th of February and 20th of March.
-So the last vaccination was 20th of March. After that he was not vaccinated.
-No.
-And the first signs of neuro-dermatitis when?
-3 months later.
-What happened after vaccination? Did he have a reaction in vaccination?
-No. No fever, no restlessness, nothing. No problems. He continued to sleep well.
-He has some problem with his breathing?
-No.
it was first diagnosis of fungus infection antimycotic drugs didn't work on it.
On the 10th of July there was the diagnosis as neuro-dermatitis. He was very red
and it was now in both legs, very red and rough, he had small spots in the cubital fold
he had behind the ear, he was sweating, he still has some behind the ear
-What is this? First time he does like this?
-No, he does that very often. That is his way of expressing himself.
-It was on the knee folds.
-Is he a boy or a girl?
-Boy.
-Spreading first down and then upper leg, it was a time when he was beginning
to crawl on the floor, so it was maybe because of this.
On the hands, the back of the thumb the first finger was very red as well.
The whole back was red, face, cheeks and under chin, he received therapy with  (?)
which contains Dulcamara and he wasn't reacting to drops of Dulcamara.
-Only, nothing else?
-Nothing else. Dulcamara mother tincture?
-I think so.
-Not potentized?
-No.
-And the mother why she was taking this?
-I used to have neuro-dermatitis.
-And how this went away?
-It ended with the birth of the child.
- Further therapy for the child was now ointment with olive oil and aqua cream
and she baths him with soya bean oil once the week.
It has been significant high Klebsiella oxytoca in his stool.
He was fully breast fed until 8 months but now he eats bananas, apples, carrots,
corn, chicken, buns rice waffles and milk powder and biscuits.
He needs nursing to fall asleep, motorically he is an early developer since 97 he is
crawling, since beginning of June he tries to walk and since August 16 he walks.
His teething was late, first tooth came in July 97, nine months of age, his weight and height
according to percentile. 10th of May he had an intestine flu.
-How it was treated?
-It was just diet and mother milk.
-No medicine.
-He still has some slight milk crust he received Calcarea carb. C200 in 20th of August.
-What was the effect of Calc. carb.?
-He reacted very well to Calc. carb. You can't really tell in detail because at the
same time we went to the sea.
-Which sea?
-Northern sea. I don't really know if it's the effect of the sea or of the Calc. carb.
-After Calc. carb. anything else, except of the eczema changed?
-No.
-The child perspires during sleep in bed?
-When I'm nursing so that he falls asleep, before he falls asleep he gets wet at
his neck.
-He is constipated at all?
-No.
-There are other symptoms that she has noticed?
-Another thing that we remarked and which puzzled us was that he never scratches
what we know otherwise from neuro-dermatitis. He never does that. Never.
-Does he eat eggs now?
-No.
-You don't give him or he doesn't like?
-He doesn't get any.
-She does not give him.
-No.
-I don't see this child to be sick, considering that he had all this vaccination, he should
be much more ill, than he appears to be. Most probably both Sulphur and Calcarea
have acted and Calcarea followed Sulphur well and both these remedies have acted well
and you just wait to see. Because I don't see any problem with his skin at the moment.
So that means the remedies have acted well and he should not take any other
remedy at this time.
-We thought was that shortly before we flied here to Alonissos, it started all over again.
It got worse, I can show you where it is.
-Now it is full blown or it is medium or it just started?
-It is pretty decent for the time being. Not very much at the moment.
-Show me.
-You see these red pustules
-And he was absolutely clear before, in Germany?
-No, the only thing was it wasn't red anymore. It still had this roughness. Dry and rough.
-And no itching?
-No scratching. I don't know if it itches.
-Yes, you will know. In her case it was the same place?
-I only had it in my arms, my hands and my face.
-Also you did not scratch?
-Yes, I did.
-It was itching?
-Very itching.
-Now she has nothing?
-Nothing.
-The moment that they came here, the eruption became better?
-The second day yes.
-How much better, 50%?
-Yes, you can say 50%.
-And what is the position in his sleep?
-On his tummy.
-Flat or he puts his hands like this?
-Sometimes he lies completely flat and sometimes he bends his knees and his elbows
both.
-Is he groaning and moaning?
-He moans a lot when he is tired and if he doesn't get what he wants.
-But does this make her irritable?
-Partly yes. I leave the room for 5 min. I count up to 10 and then come back.
-Then you have an exercise.
There is a lot of salivation?
-When he is teething yes and during the first 3 months too.
-How many teeth have come out already?
-Five.
-When they put him in bed in his cradle, he always calm down?
-During the first 3 months yes. When he was smaller.
Now he is more interested in looking around than sleep anymore.
-Did he have any rash around his nates around his genitalia?
-Yes, redness but it was never been a candida.
-I didn't ask about candida, I asked if that redness was like an eruption, very red.
-No.
-How she will describe his character?
-He is strong willed, very happy, normally he laughs with everybody, he doesn't feel
strange to others, he is not shy with strangers, he is interested about nearly
everything, he looks for flowers and what he sees he is very interested.
-How much milk he takes now? He takes outside milk than his mother's?
-No, just mother milk.
-Liquids other type he takes a lot?
-He drinks a lot of herbal tea or water.
During the pregnancy I have been treated with acupuncture because of my hay fever.
I don't know if this is of any relevance.
-Probably it is some hereditary predisposition.
-I was in the airplane together with this child, they sat aside of me.
The child constantly came up, crawled on my lap and wanted to drink out of my bottle.
And always when he returned to his mother, he was dominating, being a little tyrant
towards his mother. Like she said, when she gets angry she counts to 10 and she
doesn't show anger but I have the impression she doesn't have any control over this
child. And I had the impression with the child run out of the room yesterday, it would
have gone with everybody and would have been happy.
Me too I would give Medorrhinum.
-I thought of Medorrhinum because he was ameliorated by the sea, when he was in
they came here to Alonissos, she said he is now OK.
He was bad a few days ago and as soon as they arrive here, he was OK.
-Concerning his sleep I just wanted to say that his improvement was just in the beginning after
12 o'clock he was waking very frequently in our days, up to 20 times the night.
She just told me that yesterday he woke up all the time during the night.
Not in general but very often he wakes up and he always need her breast and then
he goes to sleep again.
-In a case where you are doing a follow up, that is a follow up after Sulphur, which was
successful and Calc. carb. which seems also to be correct, you are doing a follow up
after two correct remedies. You have to judge on two things.
Whether the pathology which is there justifies a prescription, absolutely justifies the
prescription and the second consideration is whether the remedy is clear, you have any
clear indication.
Pathology and clear remedy. In this boy we have some symptoms.
Which are the symptoms?
There is the pathology which is eruptions on bends of joints and the second is
what is the main symptom of that child on which you could think of a remedy?
Medorrhinum, Calc. phosp., Kal carb. mostly.
What other symptom you have for this child?
Amelioration at the sea. What else?
-She was already describing an anal eczema, an eczema around the nates.
-Not really.
-Sweat around his head and his neck.
-By the time he is falling asleep. During nursing.
-What is remarkable too is he doesn't like to be dressed up warmly but he loves the
warm bath and that is amazing.
-He is too warm and he likes warm bath.
-It was mentioned too that he sleeps better when he is pushed around his stroller or
by the vibration of the car.
-He only can sleep when he has been eating before.
-No.
-Concerning point one he has redness behind his ears together with pus.
-You can not make a prescription with all these?
-He said he developed quickly but his dentition was slow.
-He walked early because usually it's over one year, so it's early.
You wrote down all these symptoms and the question you are asking is the second
question, is this clear? Is this presenting a clear case?
You can argue with any of these symptoms that they are not symptoms.
With every one of them, even the eruption show something without itching, why you
bother? Knee-elbow position, all the children are...
and then amelioration in the sea, doubtful. Was the remedy, was the sea?
We don't know.
Sweats on scalp, only during nursing and a little bit.
After vaccination. There are so many vaccinations which he took ,we don't know
which one.
Too warm, likes warm bath. You can not make anything out of that.
Better vibration, it's not there anymore.
Finally you don't have a real, clear symptomatology like him, he had this drop
it was very clear. He does not have.
At the same time the child you would expect that the child would have some
disturbances, especially after so many vaccinations.
He, throughout, has a deeper tendency for allergy but not aggressively.
The child has all these good qualities, are you going to give a remedy to this child?
You have to wait and see how it develops. The whole issue of this may stay on
a very mild level or it may even disappear.
Then once you have really some pathology to deal with, then you don't interfere with
a case that has taken two correct remedies.
You may disturb the child and you may see this eruption with Sulphur becoming
unbearable.
Especially with the last information that the child wakes up frequently for breast
feeding.
If you put it there, you will see Sulphur.
Also the child, according to me, was moaning, he was crying with little reasons.
There is a tendency for moaning, which again shows the possibility for the
Calc. phos. which is a possibility for the knee-elbow position.
But you don't give it at this moment.
At this moment, after two correct prescriptions, don't try to make things better than the
organism can do because you may have the opposite effect.
The child is developing nicely, his bone structure is good, Calc. carb. is out of question
in spite of the sweating in the scalp, the sweat is not so great, you do not have the
desire for soft boiled eggs, no.
The child must not take a remedy because none of these symptoms we wrote down
are strong enough to persuade us that some deeper disturbance is going on.
There is a possibility of course for Medorrhinum, for Calc. phos. and maybe he may
develop into Calc. carb. It was already given and it seems that it has acted.
Maybe he will go back to Calc. carb. and needs repetition.
Maybe he will go to Medorrhinum, especially if he develop a rash between genitalia
and nates all this area in Medorrhinum children becomes very red and painful.
It is an eruption, it's not only a redness, it's very strong, dark redness.
Therefore the answer is no remedy.
Who wrote no remedy. Very good.
You see you are getting so good.