Since 2006 treated with Medorrhinum, Lachesis, Phosphorus and Lycopodium.
With Stramonium 200C, that was last year. She is in general quite well.
The fits of rage are less, the mother says.
It’s because there is less pressure now in the private school. She attributes it to that.
A good development of her personality. She seems to be more independent,
stays alone for hours, meets friends for shopping,
she does not like taking decisions by her own.
Ask her what she is indecisive in? Even for little things?
– Always asking her mother, what should I do, what should I say. You should say.
– Is this correct?
– But sometimes when she goes shopping with her friends
she shops alone.
– She decides.
– When shopping with her girlfriends.
– But when the mother is present
she will ask the opinion of the mother.
– Yes, the mother says.
– You don’t seem to agree.
– It’s ok but I never went shopping with her mother.
– When you shop with her, she asks you to decide?
– Not every time.
Sometimes when she likes something she takes it and asks can I take it and then I say ok.
– Her decision is her own?
– She decides, yes.
– In a certain point it might be normal that the girl always asks her mother,
what do you think mom? I was the same when I was a child.
– She is reasonable, reliable more than others in her age.
She had 3 times fever in the last year. Once 39,9C with vomiting.
What was this last acute without taking any remedies?
– I think once when he gave her Belladonna and this acted properly.
– One time Belladonna 30C and on the next day fever was gone.
– Do you know what it was? Tonsils inflamed? What was the reason for this?
– She came back from school and told me that she is tired and we went home
and then at 18:00 she had fever increasing and then I went for Belladonna
and on the next day fever was gone. I don’t know why the fever came?
– She didn’t complain of pain in the throat.
– No pain. She was tired, she came back from school very tired and wanted to sleep
– So they stopped the hormones?– Yes.
– We stopped the hormones last year in July. But I didn’t tell it to the doctor in Austria.
– Sweating easily. Where does she sweat mostly?– On the head.
– The hair or the face?– In the hair.
– In her sleep?– On the back. Not a lot in the night. On the back maybe
– She is lazy?– Yes
– She admits she is lazy?– Yes.
– She admits herself that she is lazy?– Yes, sometimes.
– She does not like to study.– She doesn’t like to do homework or anything.
– But this year she was in a private school
and the name of this school is Socrates school in Austria.
There are no lessons or homework to do at home.
– They let the children do whatever they like?
Be free and develop their own initiatives and their own ideas.
– It was one year of holidays for her.– She likes school?
– Sometimes, but sometimes it’s boring.
– She is generally feeling hot or cold or normal?– Normally she feels hot.
– Has she noticed in her sleep whether she sticks her feet out of covers?
– Yes. She has hot feet.– When the reaction is like that, I say it for the class,
you take it into consideration because she gives it with a very confirmative mood.
Her self-confidence is not very high. She has fears of phoning somebody
or fear of new situations or people. Other fears are of thunderstorms,
fear for test in school. And she needs some light when going to bed.
Sometimes complaining nobody loves me, has aversion against explanations, mostly.
What is this?– Her mother says, she tries to explain her
that it’s necessary to do  homework or something
and she dislikes to have such conversations, advices.
– Her things are in place or is she sloppy? Throws her things here and there in the room,
the room is like bombarded?– Five days she is sloppy and then she is making order
– Suddenly one day she decides to put some order.– Yes.
– The next day starts again the bombardment.– Yes.
– She is born on the 30th of August, she is Virgo.
Double Virgo will take care of the place but she is the opposite.
- She disproves astrology. You like sweets?– Sometimes. She is not that eager for sweets.
– Eggs? A little bit. What about fish?– Some years ago she liked it a lot.
Not so much anymore. She likes shrimps.
– But not fish.– No, but calamari, squid, shrimps, lobster.
– How much salt does she need? Normal?– Not so much.
– Often feels very hot. Love water even when the water is ice cold.
Does not catch a cold easily. She likes to be in cold water. She likes to swim in the sea?
– Yes, swimming pool.
– Sometimes vomiting in the night with a bit of fever.
What times does she go to bed to sleep?– 9, 9:30.
– And she sleeps easily or does it take a long time?
– When she is tired she quickly falls asleep.
When she is not so tired she is reading a book for a quarter of an hour.
– What kind of books she reads? Romantic or?– Esoteric books.
For dragons and phantasy stories…
- She is afraid of dragons?– No.
– Aversion of beans, spinach, carrots and peas. Tired in the morning.
Likes to sleep till 10:30 a.m.. If she sleeps at 10:00 p.m. can she sleep until 10:30 a.m.,
12 hours of sleep. – On the weekend sometimes she sleeps at 11:00 p.m.
and then wakes up at 10:00, 11:00 a.m.
– She is constipated sometimes. Stool every 2-3 days only.
I don’t understand every 2-3 days...- Sometimes she misses 2 or 3 days.
– The stool is formed or unformed?– It changed when we stopped the hormones.
When we took hormones, it took sometimes 4 or 5 days
but now the stool is every 2 days. It is formed.
– When she is in a high place and looks down, she has a problem?– No problem.
– How much water she needs?– Normal.
– When she is eating outside of her house, at a friend or in a restaurant
does she have any disgust sometimes, that maybe the food is not clean?
– No.
– Does she have a brother or sister?– No, she is alone.
– If her mother has drunk from a cup could she also drink from that cup?
– Yes, she can.
– When there is a thunderstorm, is she afraid very much or a little bit?– Very little bit.
– The water that she drinks must be cold in general or she prefers hot drinks?
– She likes cold. Her mother mentioned that she is very sensitive, easily offended.
– She is 11, yes. In her class are boys and girls together?
– Yes, there are boys and girls, younger and older children, they are all together.
From 6 to 10 years old.
– But also boys 15, 16 years old.– Not so old.
This school started last year in September, for the first time.
– She likes any of the boys in her class?– No.
– From higher classes?
– In this school there is only one class with younger children and older. From 6 to 12.
– She likes anybody in her neighborhood?– Yes. His name is Philip,
he is as old as she but he is very small. They play together.
– He is just a friend she says, not a boyfriend.
– She likes the company of children of her age, younger or older age?– At her age.
– If there is some fat in the meat, will she eat it or she will take it out?
– If there is a big piece of fat she will take it away. A little bit can stay.
– In general she is shy?– Sometimes, not in every situation.
– She cries easily sometimes?– Sometimes.
– She likes butter?– Not so much.
– Milk?– In the breakfast with cereals, yes.
– Meat she likes?– Chicken.
– The best. What about pork?– No.
– When she is not feeling well and somebody goes to console her, how does she feel?
– She likes consolation.– She needs a hug.
Her organism seems to be in a much better condition in general.
She went out of the aggression state which was due to imbalance in the hormones.
The hormones seem to be quite balanced at this moment
and the remedy appears to be quite clear and most of you know the remedy.
Who knows the remedy? You don’t know the remedy yet but it needs some experience,
to see many cases and then you will be able to recognize quite fast the remedy
which is of this type. It’s one of the well-known remedies, it’s a remedy that is very hot,
likes to be bathed in cold water, cold makes her feels good and feet out of covers
because they are burning during sleep. She likes consolation, she does not like fat.
Who knows the remedy this time?
What happens is that you are mixing with a lot of other points
which makes you side tracked from the remedy.
You are taking into consideration what about that she is lazy for instance.
So we are quite right the case for me when I first saw just for a while it looked like Sulph.
But Sulph. was not confirmed on its keynotes. I would expect to hear I eat the fat,
give me meat with fat. No, she did not say that.
She also had some others symptoms of Sulph. Sulph. does not like fish very much.
So you could have confused it because I was thinking of it for quite some time
that Sulph. is the remedy. When you investigate a case then this is very important
and you have an idea of a remedy and you investigate according to this idea,
do not stick to this idea. Let always doubt yourself whether this is correct or not
and you want more and more confirmation.
The moment that you search in this way the truth will come.
Maybe Sulph. will come next as a remedy. Maybe the laziness is quite strong like Sulph.
and it will come up. Show me the analysis. Want of self-confidence.
Also this kind of fears she has and the hesitation to decide is more for Puls. than for Sulph.
Puls. is not sure about herself. Wants the confirmation and the support of others,
the opinion of others. Want of self-confidence. Ingrowing toe nails.
Show me ingrowing toe nails. Sulph. is on second degree where Puls. is not.
Show me aversion fish. Graph. and Sulph. is strong while Puls. is not there.
Sleep prolonged. Sulph. is there. Puls. is not there.
But forsaken feeling. Puls. Put it on third degree. Puls. will be even stronger.
Consolation ameliorates. Without consolation ameliorates still Puls. comes first.
Show me the results. Puls. and Sulph. is second. Puls. is strong.
Most probably the underlying layer is Sulph. which will come up later on.
Puls. 200C and Puls. 1M next day and we wait. Easy case. This was an easy case now.
In the beginning it was a very difficult case to start. But we started it correctly
and therefore the development was such that this case could be helped.
Otherwise it is considered a very deep pathology.
Not easy to be treated with Homeopathy. So, do you have some questions?
– You think that Stram. clarified the case.–  Yes. Stram. pushed the case.
All the remedies, so far, have been doing something good for her organism
until now where she is normal.
The last time she had much more aggression for which Stram. was given
and has helped her quite a lot.
– Why do you ask if she likes to play with children at the same age, younger or older?
– Good question. When we first saw her at the age of 5 she was interested in boys.
Do you understand? She had the instinct of a woman, already.
Because she was driven by the hormonal imbalance
and by checking this I checked the balance in the hormonal level.
The normal is to be interested at 11, maybe. But she is totally normal now.
The androgens are not high. This was the meaning of my questions
and I insisted on that in order to understand exactly what is going on.
Can you give it back?– Why next day Puls. 1M and not only 200C?
– You are aggressive!– I have emotions. I am not aggressive.
– I am joking. If you were aggressive you would jump on me,
then I would have a problem. The other day you made a good remark.
Why did you give this and not that, I remember that. With Thuja.
– I saw Thuja but in the second level.– Which was a good remark
because there were strong points for Puls. I give now because I am afraid…
you rely on one potency ok, maybe it is not properly potentized
so if you give 200C maybe nothing happens. For a year nothing will happen
so you take one more. In this organism I can give them,
even if both are good she can take the aggravation if there is any.
– I want to ask whether she needs a remedy. If we didn’t give her a remedy at all
because she is balanced now and the hormones…
- That’s correct and you can say she does not need a remedy but the case is quite clear,
the problem is quite deep, I do not consider it as totally completed
and if this organism shows me the next remedy I will prescribe it.
The idea is now that she has to have normal menses
so it’s a little bit early the menses came she already had two times
so Puls. will regulate even further.– In her case I think there is another observation
that it worked very well. She is quite tall.
– She is growing normally, finally.
And maybe I have predicted she will be taller than her father, finally.
The reason is, I know this from the experience with children treated homeopathically
invariably they grow higher than their parents, to be taller. I don’t know why.
It seems that there is some inhibition on the gentic level
and I have seen children of parents who are really short 155 cm.
I remember a child I was treating with Tourette syndrome for a long period of time
and she became a soccer player in one of the main teams in Athens and was 192 cm.
But invariably all the children I have treated for long time, not just once,
those who came again and again they grew up to be high tall. Thank you.