This case we saw 4 years ago. The diagnosis pubertas praecox and received Medorrhinum 200C in 2006,
Lachesis 200C in 2007, Phosphorus 30C, 31C, 32C each month in 2008 and last year Lycopodium 200C.
You say the process is very successful. The parameters;
bone tests got much better so the original bad prognosis that the
child would stay small like a dwarf is not to be expected anymore.
And the doctors in Vienna are talking for big luck. So the present symptoms?
– The mother gave me the symptoms from last year and
basically she could not see many changes after Lyc.
But she is not a homeopath so maybe she did not notice so carefully and these symptoms that
she told me are that she still catches colds very easily but now are only mainly in winter.
– With high fever or not?
– Low temperature. 37C, 37,3C.
– And how many times did she have a cold this winter?
– One time it took nearly 6 weeks.
– And was continuous?
– Yes.
– Sometimes she has temperature 37,5C and this stays for a long time, her mother told me.
– Mostly bronchitis with cough?
– Yes. Sometimes very strong.
– Was the coughing more when lying down in the night?
– Yes when she goes to bed and laying so flat… but if she goes up a little bit more coughing gets better.
– With some pillows?
– Yes, 2 pillows and then she was a little bit better.
– Her mother thinks that her immune system is weak from the hormones she still gets once a month.
So what do they say about the hormones in the hospital?
– The hormones are good for children.
– Yes but do they propose something to stop taking the hormones?
– No, but the young doctor told me we will stop next year.
– If she is doing quite well.
– They say the parameters are very good and so they are intending to stop.
They think there is no need anymore.
They will leave her out of hormones in the puberty, because she is going to be 10 next year.
– To have normal puberty.
– Yes. This is a good sign that they expect that she will have puberty again and this is not stopped.
And the bone parameters are all showing they got less so they are like a child bones, like a girl in puberty.
– The bones of the hands, they make each year some X-rays and they are normal.
They don’t grow.
– Before it was really scary. This is a big miracle.
– She does not drink enough and she is constipated.
– More or less.
– She goes to the toilet every 2 or 3 days.
– She has a bleeding hemorrhoid sometimes.
– Did she put on weight? She is 40kg now.
– Although not getting taller at the same time.
– Since when she is on that height? How tall is she now?
– 1,48 meters.
– Quite high.
– And since when she has this height? When did you measure her?
– She is tall compared to others. She was always taller.
– She is 10cm taller than the other children.
– But 1,48 meters, since when?
– She cannot tell me.
– My impression is she is taller whenever I see her.
I see her every 3 months and seems always a little bit taller.
I have the impression she got taller in the last 2 years.
– You have to measure her, so we know how she is growing.
– I’ll try to do it more carefully.
– She is 40kg now, she likes sweets a lot, she eats everything but no salt and no spices.
What about meat?
– Yes. She likes chicken more.
– If the meat has some fat in it will she eat it or will she take it out?
– No fat in meat. She doesn’t eat it.
– But she takes it out carefully?
– Not very carefully.
– She will take it out if there is a piece of fat.
– Yes but not so extremely.
– I guess since September last year I saw her eating lamb chops but I think she wasn’t really disgusted from the fat.
– Is she eating pork? – Yes, sometimes.
– She is very uncomplicated with food. She eats everything.
They always tell me that she is eating everything. Very easy in tasting.
– She prefers vegetables and rice.
–How do you know that she doesn’t like salt? If the food has a little bit more salt she will leave it?
– She doesn’t eat it if there is too much salt.
– Do you know if in her sleep she grinds her teeth?
– No. I don’t live together with her mother and her. I live in another place. When I sleep with her she doesn’t grind.
– Sometimes he sleeps with her in the weekends or holidays.
– I often look at her teeth because I am a dentist and I can see if she is grinding.
She is not. – She likes sweets a lot?
– Every kind.
– Likes to dance, music, wants company, motivation from outside. She prefers to fight and to be wild.
Like a boy? – She beats me.
– She beats other children? – Not so much.
– I think she loves to fight with adults.
– Fear of thunderstorms is very strong?
– Medium.
– Fear to be alone? In the house she always needs somebody?
– We can leave her alone for 10 mins. But it’s the longest.
– Fear in the dark, she has a light when she sleeps in her room.
– When she goes to bed there is a light but in 10 mins we turn it off and there’s no problem.
– She wants company. She wants somebody to be with her.
– Friends.
She likes to have some friends and especially school friends.
– In general she likes to talk to others, being the center, is
dominant, is interested in books about animals, history, geography.
Loves to be outside, needs much space and to be free. Spends her energy while playing. She likes to cuddle but only when she wants.
Asks for hugs and she needs to cuddle. If she is crossed or crying and
her father goes to console her, does she like it or say leave me alone?
– Sometimes not always. Sometimes she says stop and sometimes she comes. It depends on the situation.
– She cries easily?
– Not so often. – She doesn’t like changes and likes to plan. Likes to be in the water.
Swimming pool? – Yes. – And in the sea also? – Yes. She is very good in swimming. – The sun? She likes to stay in the sun?
– Yes. – Prefers to be cold because of sweating easily. Where is she sweating?
– In the axilla.
– Not in head? Not here in bed, she perspires in sleep?
– Yes. On the neck. – Sometimes after sleep.
– The perspiration smells? – No. – In general she is covered when she sleeps.
Does she stick the feet out? – Yes. Feet outside the covers.
– In general she is better in a cool atmosphere or in warm like this?
Or there is no difference?
– She likes more the cool atmosphere.
– She has girlfriends?
– Yes but she also has boyfriends from the school.
– She likes boyfriends?
– I think so. She prefers boys.
– But she plays boyish games or she likes to play with dolls and girly games?
– She prefers games boys normally play.
– I saw her playing football.
– She has very good muscles. She is strong.
– Sometimes she fears playing with a ball, catching a ball.
– She complains that the boys are too wild in school. Because they play games with balls.
Although she likes playing with boys, sometimes in the same moment
she says they are too heavy and she doesn’t want to catch the ball.
Though she wants to play with boys at the same times she thinks they are too strong for her.
– If she cries and somebody goes to console her she likes it or not?
– Half and half.
Depends on the situation.
–In which situation she likes it?
– She likes it if we watch TV together or she reads a book to me. She likes these situations.
– But if she is angry and she cries and you try to calm her will she accept it?
– Yes. She accepts it. Most of the times.
– Really she makes like this but mostly he can calm her down.
– This is my situation with her. With her mother she is sometimes different.
– He always says that her and her mother have different situation. Their situation together is more calm.
With her mother it’s more fighting and emotional.
– They have more conflict. She likes ice cream? – Yes, very much.
- How many can she eat?
– 3-4 times a day if it is summer and very warm.
All kinds of ice cream. – Milk?
– Not so much. She likes hot chocolate but no milk.
– The water she drinks must be cold or normal temperature?
– Normal temperature, not so cold.
– The food? She wants warm or cold?
– She prefers warm food. – Soup?
– Yes, she likes soup, chicken soup, meat soup.
– Is she afraid at all looking from a high place down? From a balcony?
– No.
– Does she like fruits? All kinds?
– No. Orange not so much but strawberries, apple, banana.
– She likes more fruits which are ripe and sweets or fruits which are unripe?
– Sweet fruits. – Lemon or vinegar?
– Not too much.
– Is she organizing with her things and fastidious or she leaves things all around?
– When I come home with her she throws in the clothes and the shoes all around.
– But I think she is a bit fastidious in being pretty.
She asks me what I should wear tonight. She wants to be well-dressed.
She tells me all the clothes we have brought with us and then asked me what should she wear.
She is a bit fastidious.
– And she comes to me, should we go clothes shopping…
- She likes going shopping. For example this shirt she was searching for him, she chose it.
– She took me from the hand in the shop and said you will buy this one.
– A dictator?
– A little. But I think it will grow.
– Today, he wanted to stay in Roussoum because he was tired and he was begging please let me stay in Roussoum!
She wanted to go to other beaches and see places…
- Her sleep is constant or she wakes up during the night?
– I think it’s constant.
– When she wakes up in the morning is she in good mood?
– It became better this year. Before she was very naaah.
– Before she was very often in not so very good mood. I think last year it got a
little bit better in the morning and even the self-confidence got better, I guess.
Although there is still a symptom that she doesn’t want to phone anybody.
She is shy in phoning her friends.
– Why?
– Maybe it is lack of self-confidence, a little.
– When she wants to phone to friends then she asks me to do it for her, I don’t like it.
– Ask her why she does not like to phone.
– I want to see what she says.
– She doesn’t know. She cannot tell. One more thing; she is sleeping in her mother’s bed now.
She will become 9 and still sleeps in the bed of the mother.
– She needs somebody next to her. When she sleeps with you she sleeps in the same bed?
– We have a big bed for her.
– She has expressed some fear of being alone in the night sleeping?
– No fear in the night, she is not very fearful.
– But she prefers to have somebody around. No panic at all. – Not depending?
– No panics or extreme fears. Just normal. She prefers to have somebody near her.
– She would cry easily?
– Not so much.
– She does not complain, why don’t you give me this etc. in a weepy mood?
– No if she likes something she tells it to me immediately but not crying. Sometimes she demands it.
– How many sweets she can take?
– We don’t allow her to eat too much. Some chocolate but then it’s finished.
– She likes to drink alcohol? – Sometimes a little beer.
Only tasting. – But she complains?
She likes ice cream she likes beer? Does she like beer?
– Only tasting, not drinking.
– I asked her if she likes a little bit of beer and she says yes.
– Ask her if she needs a whole bottle or glass.
– No glass. Tasting. – A spoonful.
– Wine? – No, she didn’t try it.
– Her mother says about her that she is organized or very sloppy?
– She is very sloppy.
More this. I guess her mother will say the same. She is fastidious with her clothes and her looks but not with things around in her room… George,
he told me just now that she can get very angry if something is not just. She can get angry.
– When I am not just with her she will be very angry.
– She can complain he is not just.
– She can express her feelings and her emotions very easily.
– Always has strong emotions. Expresses her emotions.
She got calmer since last year. Before there were fits of rage.
In the beginning, maybe you remember before Med.,
she had heavy fits of rage.
She was always wild and emotional.
– She is having normal stool or constipated, diarrhea?
– Her mother told me only every 2-3 days.
More constipation. – There is odor from the mouth?
– No. I never realized it. – She talks in her sleep.
– I don’t know.
– She is turning around.
She sleeps quietly mostly but sometimes she is turning around changing the place. The school stuff is in order.
Not so sloppy. – The school books you mean?
– Yes they are in order.
Not so sloppy.
– Ok.
I don’t know if you know this syndrome. Girls having menstruation too early and they don’t grow.
It’s quite serious condition with deep hormonal disturbances
and actually they have to take hormones all their lives.
They usually stay very short. This case is going quite well actually. Has responded very well.
An interesting thing when seeing the present state of the girl, you see actually a healthy organism.
There is no something mentally or physically to indicate that there is still a need for a remedy.
That’s why this time it was very difficult to discern the remedy at that state.
Because the girl has come to a balance, mentally, emotionally. In the beginning she behaved like a crazy person, absolutely uncontrollable rage.
Mental/ emotional changes. At this moment she is in a quite good condition.
The best prescription for her at the moment is placebo actually.
The right remedy is placebo. There are some indications for either Pulsatilla or Sulphur.
But neither of the 2 is clear so therefore, I wouldn’t go ahead and give any remedy at this moment.
I see she is going quite well and we’ll see.
Once she stops the hormones she is taking, maybe we can have a clearer picture,
maybe the next remedy will manifest itself but she is doing extremely well actually.
You saw me I was trying very hard to find some way but she is very good girl.
The fact that she throws things around and her looks go towards Sulphur.
The desire for sweets also which is quite strong. The feet out of covers.
Yes I was not happy with the full picture and I don’t want to spoil an excellent reaction which is going on.
With this case we have reached almost the end of our encountering. You may put some question if you like.
– I would like to make a remark to this case.
She is still getting the hormones but the hormones fit to a case which is not treated homeopathically.
They fit to a case where a girl will be very small and now together with your treatment and the hormones she is getting much too high.
She is already too high for her age. They should reduce the hormones.
– I don’t want to interfere because they are responsible for the hormonal part, not me.
They have to decide sooner or later to interfere and stop the hormones.
I agree but I cannot decide myself.
– Of course, not you personally but I just wanted to mention the
hormones must be stopped otherwise she will get 180 or 190cm tall.
– I believe as they already said, that they have to stop the hormones.
He said next year, maybe they will decide at the end of this year to withdraw the hormones.
That maybe will leave a clearer picture for us, I believe.
We will see how the hormonal system will work whether she will have natural menstruation at the age of 11.
Anybody wants to ask?
– Why don’t you just not give her a remedy? Why do we need the placebo?
– It’s not a matter whether I want to give placebo or not.
It depends on the doctor who is in attendance feels that they must have something or not.
It’s a matter of being more calm they are taking something and the child is not left.
The matter of placebo is an individual thing for the homeopaths to decide between the homeopath and the patient.
Actually because in the older times, one remedy, one time will be very suspicious for many people.
They say I came here, sat for one hour and you give me one dose and you say goodbye. It’s no good because of these reasons.
I used to give placebo in every case when I was treating patients in Greece. Always placebo for one month. One remedy and placebo.
And the results were actually fantastic. Second month if people still felt they needed a continuation,
second month placebo, third month placebo, fourth month placebo and then I tell them don’t come again you’re good.
Some patients felt more secure to see us because we were charging very little actually.
I said ok if you like to pay me every month come, but I tell you you can stop. So they decided to stop many of them.
Actually sometimes we had to ask them to stop and forget it and don’t come anymore
because they were too many people wanting treatment and we did not have the time.
So we had to tell them stop coming and come only if there is a real problem or something manifests.
But these periods are more difficult with the pollution.
Anyhow in this case I don’t say to the doctor to give placebo.
She will decide herself. This is up to her.
What I meant is that at this moment we don’t have enough information to give a prescription.
Next question. … Alcohol desire? Sulphur.
When children need Sulphur they like beer or anything.
They would take a glass of beer and drink it, at her age.
That’s an indication for Sulph. Desire for alcohol.
But mostly beer and whiskey. Some they try!
The desire for sweets is the same as alcohol.
Either a lot of sweets are needed in the organism of Sulph. or they take it from the alcohol.