-How are you feeling now?
-I think emotionally I'm more strong and centered, I feel better and mentally also a little bit,
still I have long way to go.
-Yes? I don't think so.
-With the memory but I think the confusion is better.
-Much better I would say, you are afraid to say much better.
-I think it's better but I still have from time to time, especially after eating
and under stress I don't remember what to say, like now. And energy I also think it's better.
-But can you give me an idea? It's better it doesn't say anything. How much better?
-Last time I told you I had a new job and I had not been working for many years,
I did not had the energy and also the sleep made it very difficult for me to work.
I'd been able to keep up this work and also work a little bit more but the sleep problem
is still there but after the Causticum I have been able to tolerate a little bit better
the lack of sleep. I don't go to pieces as before and start crying when I'm too tired.
Now I'm able to go on still with less sleep.
-What potency did you take?
-200 Causticum.
-When?
-In the end of February I think.
-And it was during an acute that you took it?
-Yes.
-You said, Eupatorium perfoliatum, Causticum and Arsenicum, all the 3 remedies?
-No, Arsenicum you gave me before while I was here.
-Then you had an acute, when?
-In the beginning of February.
-And then you took Causticum and then you had another one, you took Eupatorium?
-No, I told you last time when I was supposed to start this work I got this acute
and I wanted to work and I could not be there the first day, so I tried the Eupatorium first,
it was the same acute.
-Yes, you said the same thing in the previous interview.
-Yes but still I'm much better in the evening and if I'm not working and if I have the opportunity
I like to sleep late and go to bed late and sleep along in the morning.
-How late you would like to go?
-It can be 5-6 o'clock in the morning.
-That's a good time.
-Almost all my life I've done this.
-But now actually what time are you going to bed? 12 o'clock? In Norway.
-In Norway when I have to go to work I try to go to bed not later than 2-3 but
sometimes I go a little bit earlier but I have to be really exhausted to go to bed.
And I have this kind of fear of bed still, so when I'm tired I can not sleep, it's not enough.
I have to wait until I'm completely exhausted and if I sleep good one night,
the other night I can not sleep.
-And you sleep in your abdomen mostly?
-Not really, I like to sleep in my abdomen but my neck is so stiff, I can not tolerate this position.
-It's the position that you like.
-Yes, I lie on the side so much that is almost.
-I'd like to have some questions when you finish with your report.
-The sleep is also very restless because I feel I can not completely relax and restless
in my body, I have to get up and urinate and wake of the least noise, sound.
-How many times you need to go to urinate?
-I think that's improved, it's better but I still have to go 3-4 times and sometimes more.
It used to be 10 times every night, so it's better. This acute hearing makes me wake up a lot.
And it's also other things that make me no sleep, it's difficult to find the right temperature.
I take the window open and then I close it, it's too cold and more blankets
and the electricity on and then I don't tolerate the electricity and take it off again
and so I go back and forth.
-Do you feel cold?
-Yes, even now I wear socks.
So no remedy has really touched the coldness.
I'm still very cold and now with the change of temperature I was so cold, my whole spine
and back get stiff.
-In the past have you received Silica?
-No.
-You still have diarrhea or this is gone?
-I was better for a while but now I change my diet again.
I told you last time I had desire for bread and butter and it is and I've been eating that
and I have more diarrhea and I lose stool.
-Real diarrhea or soft?
-Both, it can change.
-How many times is diarrhea out of the week? An average.
-It depends on what I eat or if I'm excited but it's better, I used to have much more.
-The butter desire is still there strong?
-Yes, but the fat I don't tolerate very much, I get like a stone in the stomach
and get very heavy and get really drowsy after eating.
-There is any salivation during sleep?
-I don't think.
And the worse time has always been the morning of course, in the waking up sometimes
I feel trembling and get perspiring, it's like a shock to hear the bell
and I always want to sleep more.
I'm never refreshed. I remember recently I have felt once in my life the wake up at 9 o'clock
a normal time almost and felt refreshed once.
-Only one time? You are improving.
-Not this time, it was earlier, just to know how it feels like.
Still it's not refreshed the sleep but I'm able to cope with it, after Causticum.
-All the good happened after Causticum?
-With the sleep yes.
With the memory I think is a big problem, even though it is better because I want to study
but I can not.
-Can you give me an example? You forget names?
-I forget names and places and things, what to say, what to do, what to write,
what I've just been reading, what I did last day, the name of things.
-All this?
-Yes but I think not so often, I don't feel so confused but it can be all these.
I think it's a kind of blockage also, when I sit down to read and write I feel restless,
I feel bad, I think it has to do with something from school.
-From examinations?
-Yes also but I think I can't concentrate but it can also be rather bad,
I can not concentrate at all.
When I sit down to study, I read the same page over and over again and I don't seem able to ...
-Have you ever received Baryta carbonica?
-No.
But I was pushing myself to study but it made such a negative stress on my whole system,
so now recently I just decided I give up, I can not do this. It feels bad because I love Homeopathy
and I love to help people and I love to work with this. It makes me frustrating
but I like to go faster of course, it's not so long time till the exam.
-Tell me more.
-A lot of mess.
I think the bad memory makes me feel very insecure, feel lack of self confidence,
it's a big problem, so I don't dare to start practicing, open my practice.
I feel I don't trust my memory and I'm so scared that I can hurt somebody
to give the wrong treatment, it stops me.
I noticed now when it was getting colder it is very much underneath,
the coldness I feel in the knees and in the spine and the bones and the neck and the feet.
-You feel also the draft or general you feel cold?
-Both, the draft I feel very strong, it troubles me, it makes me very restless and uncomfortable.
I can get headache or stiff neck from the draft.
Something that came back more now and aggravated again is a chronic distention and
bloatedness which was better for a while but I don't know if it has to do with having strict diet for
a while and now again I eat bread and cheese.
-And all these things that upset you.
-Yes.
-So that means you don't actually make any diet now, you eat freely.
-I do have a lot of problems with the digestion, I have a lot of pain in the stomach from this
and a lot of gas and bloatedness and often when I eat something I can start hiccup
and belching immediately.
-In the past you have taken Lycopodium?
-I never took Lycopodium.
-Medorrhinum?
-Yes I took Medorrhinum, you gave me. Good reactions.
-I don't remember you had gonorrhea?
-I had condylomata, not gonorrhea.
-How is your desire for sweets now?
-When I start eating a little bit again it comes back.
-You try to avoid actually?
-Yes, it's not so easy for me but I don't eat as much as before, I think.
-I wanted to make clear, in the evening you feel better emotionally and mentally and physically?
-Everything.
-You become more alive?
-Yes.
-And in the sea, you still like the sea very much?
-Yes, very much.
-You swim every day while you are here?
-Yes.
-What time?
-In the lunch break.
-For how long?
-It depends but when it's as warm as this, I like to stay for a long time.
-For one hour?
-Not so much.
-You have anything else?
-I remembered that this bloatedness and the troubles with my digestion started
when I was 17 years old, then I got some kind of hormonal treatment.
My menses had stopped for a year and a doctor gave me some injections.
-And the bloatedness started after the injections.
-Yes and the difficulty to tolerate several food started after this.
Also the same time I had a lot of these fillings in my teeth, I certainly got a lot of troubles
with my teeth and I got the amalgam. So a lot of problems started after this.
-How are your menses now, the last 2-3 months.
-Two times came 5-6 days earlier and this never happened before.
-Do you still have menses stop when lying down?
-Yes. It's very scanty.
-Like it used to be.
-Yes.
-How is your sexual desire?
-I got a new boyfriend, so it starts changing.
-Drastically?
-Yes because it was almost like an aversion, almost like I had this fear of going into
a relationship, trusting anybody again and to be intimate again, give me the creeps
but now it has changed.
-Your hair is still falling?
-Yes but maybe a little bit better.
-The desire for oranges is still very strong?
-Yes, juicy things but the ice cream I desire also still very much.
-Here?
-No, all the time, I eat a lot of ice cream.
-Your thirst?
-My thirst is a little down after Arsenicum I think.
-Is it for more quantities, frequently?
-No, I can drink more, not only small.
-How is the hurriedness?
-After deciding not to take the exam, it is better, I can relax more but it's till there,
it's a kind of restlessness because I have a lot of pain in my body physically,
I'm not at ease I have a lot of tension, so it's a kind of restlessness but I'm working with it.
But I can have a certain weakness after eating.
-After eating sweets?
-General after eating I can feel very weak.
-That means sometimes you feel, sometimes you don't.
-Yes and it comes out of the blue. Recently I just had some spaghetti and cooked
vegetable on it, I had some cheese on it and my boyfriend was sitting there and eating
but I almost collapsed for several hours, I could hardly even talk to him.
Maybe I ate too much but I don't think it was that much. I think fat more and more disturbs me.
-What about bread?
-Yes also.
-The bread definitely. The bread it was something you discovered that it was aggravating you since...
-Since I was 17 and nobody told me, people told me everybody tolerates bread, so just
continue and I could not understand.
-And it could create diarrhea for you?
-Yes and I gained 10 kilos and eating has to do with my memory also.
When I fast I feel very clear in my mind and also if I keep a strict diet,
it really makes me easier to think.
It's like an intoxication almost from food.
-Yes exactly.
How is the washing of your hands?
-It's still there but I try to force myself not to be so obsessive with this but it's still there.
-How is your postponing?
-I had to go home now to prepare this because I postponed it and I have to go out
and I have to do it in the last minute.
-The rheumatic pain in the extremities, the joints, you were complaining last time
for pains in the joints. You don't remember?
-Not specifically.
-There is any perspiration now?
-When it's warm of course I perspire easily when I walk.
-Is it odor offensive?
-Not really I think but after a lot of the remedies I can have more strong odor from the axilla.
-This desire for open air is still there?
-Very much.
-Though you feel the cold, the desire for open air is still very much.
-Yes. Generally I feel also better in the open air, walking slowly in the open air makes also
the mentally part better.
I can think more clearly, sitting is really bad for me, to sit still I feel restless.
-Anything else?
-I also feel the circulation in my whole body is no good, the legs and the neck.
-You feel the draft in the neck?
-The circulation, I feel there is no enough oxygen to my brain, it's like it gets stuck
in a cramp, in a block in the neck and I'm always much worse after sleeping.
-You had several examinations in your life, I believe.
It was any time any problem with your liver?
-Not in the blood examinations.
-Never found anything or you did not examine it.
-The blood examples never showed I think but I had believing that it all came from my liver,
it had to do with my liver but it didn't show in the blood but all therapists told me this also.
I was drinking too much alcohol before and I was having medication for years.
I noticed now that I react very strongly to noises, I need a lot of peace and quietness.
I need to be very much alone, to feel the inner state, to meditate.
-In touch with yourself?
-Yes and also to talk with god, I need this very much, to feel happy and complete.
So every time I can go alone, I feel joy and relief.
-You feel good.
-And small noises really annoy me, people scratching and talking,
especially talking and the voice.
I also noticed that this sudden weakness can come after grief or mortification, disappointment,
I suddenly lose all strength but still I have a big problem with electricity.
I noticed this with all the computers.
-You feel the effect?
-Very much and always I have a very bad time during the whole winter
when I have to put electricity on. Sometimes I even think of buying a cottage, living without electricity
it's really bothering me and it also has to do with the studying.
I have to study in the night and I have to put some light on and the light disturbs me so much,
to have it near by my head gets like a bursting feeling in my head, I'm very restless.
-You must avoid transformers. The lights which transform ,
these make a big electromagnetic fields.
Still I'm over sensitive to all extra impressions, noises, cruelties and if people are angry
the suffering of others.
-Did you show any anger during this time?
-No.
-With your parents you communicated?
-Not much.
I showed a little bit anger to my mother.
I was able to stand up more and not feel only weak but I still like to have some more protection
because I always go alone to protect myself.
-When you say protection, you mean some physical protection or emotional?
-I want to be more strong.
-Somebody to protect you, to have somebody who look after you.
-No, just to be able to be with a lot of people, I get weak from talking and it takes a lot of energy
for me and I can feel the feelings of others in it, it drains me from energy
but it's a little bit better after Causticum.
I'm not so open and with the fears I think the fear of dogs is a little bit better
but still there and the fear of heights is also better but a new one has occurred.
I had 2 times the dream with this huge wave coming towards me 100 m and I started having
some fear about this.
-A wave in the sea?
-Yes, a wave rising up 100 m.
-A flood coming over you?
-Yes.
-When did you dream that?
-2 months ago.
-When did you have this boyfriend?
-It was similar time.
-Do you understand what it is?
-Yes.
-I don't have to explain.
-Fear of earthquakes sometimes.
-You ask the Greeks, they say the amount of sedatives, they have gone sky high,
the whole population is using these sedatives to be able to face this fear.
-And all these videos make me feel nauseous. I also desire to hear very much music and
when I'm here I don't here so much and I feel abstinence, it really makes me feel very good
and also to be out in nature, I need this a lot.
-Your boyfriend is here with you?
-No.
I don't think I've told you before, I 'm very sensitive I don't tolerate any tight clothing anywhere.
Maybe because of the bloatedness, it gives pain.
-How is your desire for salty things?
-A little bit more.
-For pepper?
-I like spicy food but I don't tolerate so much, it gives me diarrhea from spicy food.
I'm very sensitive to odors, I usually get nauseated and even though I'm very cold
I don't tolerate too much heat on my head.
I noticed on the beach yesterday, I got very much heat on my head and I had to put it under the water
and I got throbbing, this heartbeat in the air, it feels like bursting.
And it's the same feeling as if when I walk if I walk a little bit and have exertion,
if I walk fast I get the same feeling all this congestion to my head and it can also be
with blurred vision. So it makes not do any exercise, I cannot do anything.
-It's OK.
-You want to say to the class what you told me? You can, say it.
-I just told that with this boyfriend I had a very good feeling of being very childish again
and play around and he is helping me like cure my inner child and he sings for me
and I really can relax and sleep, I feel like this little child.
-He lullabies you to sleep, he sings for you to sleep.
This was an important information.
What shall we do?
-Homework.
-No homework again.
-I just tell you the remedy and then we go.
No, I have to explain why should I give the remedy, again?
Can once give a remedy without explanation?
-No.
-When I was in India, in the Calcutta College, there was Dr. Bose who has studied with Kent
in America and he was considered as very good prescriber, very fast and very good.
He was 84 years old by the time I was there, in 1964.
He was 84, you can imagine being in America in the end years of Kent.
He used to describe Kent as a very irritable man.
He says, if you did not know the Theory, you could forget that you pass the class.
Anything else you could forget except of Theory and he used to prescribe,
see a case what do you have, OK.
Before the patient was speaking he had written a remedy
and always the students we asked him why?
He never gave an answer, go and study, he had a strong voice, go and study, he never said anything.
He never explained why he gave.
Most probably because he did not know of course. He could not justify.
In India you could see a scene like this, we were about 30 students around
and he was sitting there and there was a big queue of patients that he had to finish within 1 hour,
about 100 patients.
The patient was coming and he was putting his hand here or here, wherever he put his hand,
he gave the remedy because we could not hear the symptoms.
And then I had somebody who would explain to me Hindi, what did he say? Nothing.
What did he say? Nothing. Go and study. You are more spoiled, I would say.
The remedy at this moment or the choice should be between Lycopodium and Baryta carbonica.
For both of these remedies we have quite good indications.
Which one of the two shall we choose? When I was coming to the class I choose Lycopodium,
before entering the class she told me this story with her boyfriend.
You understand now what I'm going to chose.
The idea is of course the memory, the self-confidence which is lacking,
the lack of concentration, can not read, can not study, can not remember what she studies
and the idea of like to be cuddled.
She described it very well. She said, he sings and I sleep and I feel like a child.
This is a good description for Baryta carbonica. So Baryta carbonica.
What potency? 200.
She also suffers with a syndrome which we have been discussing for Norway
which is mal absorption syndrome. She is suffering with that and we actually treat that syndrome.
She is improving already, she has improved but it's very interesting what she says,
I don't believe it exactly as she said it, after the hormones but she had degraded her organism
through taking different drugs etc. and then hormones came and the whole system went down
and she developed the pathology in which she lived for 20 years?
How many?
-I'm 43.
-More than 20, I thought it was less than 20.
Anyhow I think with Baryta carbonica now which we have a better picture,
she will have quite a good jump. Did you understand what it means the waves that she saw?
You understood?
-No.
-The big waves that came over her?
-Phase one?
-It is the overwhelming feelings that raised because of this meeting with this man.
They are strong feelings coming inside and she felt in her sleep that she will be drowned
in these feeling, there are so many that she can be drowned or there was a danger of being drowned.
Is this correct? Say yes more strongly.
So it's not actually reading her thoughts, it is knowing and understanding human nature.
This dream is characteristic when the emotions are over flowing.
And usually occurs at the beginning of a love affair.
When you see such a dream, you know what state you are, phase one.
-Tell me what happened, on October 99 prescribed Baryta carbonica 200
and you will tell what happened.
-In the beginning of December I took the remedy because of some very strong symptoms
I wanted to wait first. I had no initial aggravation but
because I went to dental root treatment, I think I antidoted the remedy.
-When was the dental?
-Middle of February, 2, 5 months.
-Did you repeat after dental treatment?
-I repeated, this thing to the root I had terrible pain and suddenly came to the weekend
and I had no pain killers, so the first thing I did, I repeated once.
And it took away the pain for 1 hour and then I had a really good reaction
because at the same time I was having  these tooth problems.
One week before I had a very strong flu, so I was lying in bed I was really exhausted and very weak
and immediately after the remedy, I felt muscle power that I never feel, I feel so no power
and I was doing ballet for 1 hour, from lying in bed for a week, I was dancing around
but then that pain came back and then I got weak again. And then I tried Hypericum because...
-You did not repeat again?
-No.
-Why you did not repeat again?
-Because I was not thinking.
-Because you did not like the remedy and you wanted another.
-You did Hypericum and what it did?
-Nothing, then I tried to get some pain killers, not to take anything more.
Hypericum helped me because these problems have been for a long time.
-Yes but not this time.
-But it had saved other teeth, so I don't have to do the root treatment.
-So what did you do finally?
You went to the dentist?
-Yes I had to, I was maybe 10 days.
-And then he had to kill the nerve?
-Yes because it was dead already.
-It was dead maybe from the pain.
-I don't know, for a long time, it was a big infection and I had pain all over.
-What other remedy except of Hypericum, did you take another remedy?
-No.
-You took pain killers and then you went to the dentist, how long it lasted the whole thing?
-I had to go several times because it was so much inflammation.
-He gave you antibiotics which you did not take.
-I did not take.
-So I know your character by now.
-Taking nothing more.
And I had a milder acute in April with coryza and bronchitis, it lasted several weeks
but it was not so aggressive. So generally I feel better, more centered and together,
I think that's slowly from several remedies, I feel more inside in me.
-In contact.
-Yes and a little more peace.
-It's about time.
-Emotionally, I feel very good.
I have this wonderful relationship and I'm still in love and this is very good
but physically I still have a lot of the symptoms remaining and also mentally.
-Can you tell?
-Mentally is the memory.
-You are not happy still with the memory, the memory is not as it should be.
-No and I have difficulty in following, it's difficult to evaluate, is it better, is it worse,
so much happening in my life now.
-With the patients you mean or here?
-Everything, with you is OK because you talk slow but I really have to make notes
and I don't follow; so it's annoying.
-Next?
-The chronic fatigue I think still is not so much better.
-Still is a problem?
-The self-confidence also has not changed so much.
-You are not having enough self-confidence.
-No, it's really disturbing my life very much. I feel mal absorption you mentioned last time.
I have lots of problems with the food and with the digestion.
-Still you have reaction to food. Which food and what reaction?
-It's a lot of food.
-Like?
-Like bread, vinegar, everything mixed with several things, it's mostly...
-You said vinegar?
-Yes, a lot of things contain vinegar.
-In food.
-Yes.
So I often choose not to eat, I feel so much better going on a fast, then I also feel hurriedness.
-What about others like rice, spaghetti?
-Spaghetti is not good, the energy is going, I can drop during while I'm eating
and I have to lay down.
I think I never mentioned that when I get so nervous I get so dry in the mouth, very much.
To the unrefreshed sleep I think Causticum really helped me.
-So you don't have unrefreshed sleep now?
-Yes but the time I took Causticum I'm jumping...
-You took Causticum?
-That was earlier, that time I told you I took.
-Yes but what I did not understand about Causticum,
it helped you with the unrefreshing sleep, what did you say?
-Yes, I didn't feel so bad in the morning. The unrefreshed sleep is really the problem.
-At this moment it is one of your main problems.
-And the things I told.
I told you last time about the sleep problems with the difficulty of falling asleep and
frequent waking and it's difficult to find the right temperature, I'm always cold
but I can have flushes at night of heat and very restless, so there is a lot of disturbances around
the sleep still.
And what is really bothering me very much is, because we try to find a place to live,
a house or rent, it's very difficult to find a place to live because I have all these allergies
to all the different things.
-You mean in Oslo?
-Yes about Oslo.
So all the things from inside the house, the carpets, the materials bother me so much
and the electricity is a huge problem. I've given up to read, to study because
to sit underneath electric lamps is very much a problem.
-Next?
-The postponing, my boyfriend tells me, tell him this.
-Postponing for small matters or only for big issues?
-Most things.
-Next?
-I still feel I have problem with too much coming in that I can protect.
-You are affected by emotions of others or by something happens outside,
an accident something happens and then you are affected?
-Everything.
-Or just any emotion that other people have, you are affected by this?
-Yes.
I hardly see my parents anymore because it's very difficult to have contact,
it's very chaotic and nervous, tension and 1 min even though I come in piece, in 1 min
and I fall apart.
-They can disturb you.
-This also was better with Causticum.
-Which is the worst time for you?
-Always waking up.
-The next worse?
-The getting up in the morning, always better towards the evening and the night.
-Night you mean even after midnight as you were saying last time you feel amelioration?
-Yes and then also I'm more clear in my head and everything is going easier,
I feel also more strength in my body.
-Do you have a lot of gas from wrong food?
-Yes a lot.
-I told you last time about this distention.
-It's there, correct?
-Yes and also eructation.
-How much sweets you require?
-A lot.
-Do you have still this weakness after eating?
-Yes if it's the wrong food which I have intolerance to, it can come so sudden, very sudden.
-This coldness in the spine do you remember?
-It's still there, I feel the draft.
-The coldness in the knee?
-Yes in the patella, little draft, little cold is in the spine, in the back and in the knee,
in the bones.
-As much as before?
-I think so.
-Perspiration?
-Easily at exercising or just walking and at night could be not so much perspiration
but I feel really warm and flashes of heat but I don't get really wet.
-The lack of self-confidence is the same as the last time you think or it is less
or is it more?
-I tried to evaluate, it's difficult for me.
-You have something else, otherwise we finished.
-The coldness is very big problem.
-But still you like open air?
-Yes.
-I'll give you Pulsatilla, no? You like it?
-Even though I'm so cold? OK.
You know now why I like India, she will bring my tea before I ask her, she will bring the tea.
Now what happened with her case is that Baryta carbonica unfortunately was not left alone to act,
there was this interference.
So we don't know how much, how far it could have taken the case but my question now
is from what she says, because the patient always stresses that which bothers him in the end
and I could see the problems that are bothering her at this moment are problems
that belong to Lycopodium.
Therefore previously symptomatology Lycopodium, now symptomatology Lycopodium.
So the indication is that most probably the remedy which is coming is not anymore Baryta carbonica,
maybe Baryta carbonica will come back again but now at this moment the remedy
which is coming uppermost is Lycopodium.
Who has not seen this case from the beginning?
It's not the summary which is important, to see the real case from the beginning will be different.
Do you remember? There is any difference?
-Sure.
-What did you say?
-There is big difference yes.
-But you did not say when you were sitting down there. Now shall we give Lycopodium or
we'll punish her because she did not say?
We'll punish her to wait.
She will jump on me, I have to go out. Don't punish her, very interesting
but it was very interesting when I did something I can't remember where 2 Causticums
were in the class and jumped on me. Oh my god.
You see the difference between sympathetic Causticum and sympathetic Phosphorus.
Phosphorus will not be aggressive revolutionary, there is a kind of aggressive reaction
from Causticum towards someone who is suffering,
they will not just say poor him like Phosphorus, no.
They have to do something, they jump and say, you bastard come here.
They will pick a fight on the street with an unknown person, even if they know
the other person is stronger they can not resist, they will just try to kill him
because he is doing something to the animals or to humans.
So Causticum is very sympathetic but acts upon that, Phosphorus is very sympathetic
but suffers mostly. They don't act especially violently.
Therefore what shall we do with her, I don't know.
I'll tell you something, I leave it up to you, when you feel like taking a remedy,
take Lycopodium. A big decision.
She can not take a decision, so I know it will take 6 months before she takes a remedy,
which is good.
I have to see what Baryta carbonica has done finally. When finally decides to take Lycop
that means the Baryta has done all it could, it has brought her to a point to make a decision.
I'm very happy with the development of this case, I'm very happy
and Lycopodium is really she will need it because at this moment most of her problems
coming from digestive system, there is no question she is suffering with mal absorption syndrome,
celiac sprue  what they call and there is gas, distention, burps, eructations,
unrefreshed sleep waking up in the morning, there is lack of self-confidence,
she is still not very much happy to speak in front of the public
but has Baryta carbonica finished its action? This is what I'm ...
-Since the Baryta carb worked so well in the acute situation after which she then
had the treatment in pain killers and so on, I could imagine it acted
but it was used up very quickly do you think it is worth repeating the same potency now
because there is still many indications also from Baryta carb to see if there is
any further action before changing to a new remedy?
-Well this is a good thought and one of the things I'm thinking but if you remember last
time the main thing she said, my memory, my lack of self-confidence,
it was absolutely clear what was bothering her. When we came out the other things were there
but they were mentioned as secondary.
Now she says, my main problem is I can not get up in the morning, I can not be refreshed,
I'm very tired in the morning, I'm better after 10 o'clock in the night, I'm more clear,
12 o'clock even better.
These are all keynotes of Lycopodium plus the distention is there.
Baryta carbonica takes away whatever it could, whatever belonged to Lycopodium
as an underlined remedy, Baryta carb did not touch. Now Lycopodium has to be given, when?
This is my problem because of the interference of the dental treatment. That's all.
Otherwise I would be able to judge but this interference you see how confuses you.
-She antidoted the remedy with the dental treatment?
-Not entirely, partially. Maybe, I don't know.
-I would like to know if you have seen more often people after the right remedy having
inflammation of their nerves.
If their teeth have been bad before, I have seen it after the right remedy it came very immediately.
It's because of the treatment, they have closed them up the teeth, so you have to open them
and leave them open which they don't do anymore, it's really a problem.
-This is a good remark, I have seen it many time with the right remedy the teeth,
the gums become inflamed and you have a lot of problems around the teeth and the gums.
As soon as the organism becomes strong, it brings out an inflammation
and where is this inflammation?
Many times in the teeth and the gums, that is true.
I don't want to spoil the case. I believe that you are in a level of Lycopodium.
-I also have experience of dental problems coming up after giving a good remedy and
having an aggravation.
I guess my question is, are you recommending that dental work be held of for a period of time
or would you recommend homeopathic treatment prior to any dental intervention?
It's being my experience that the majority in my cases the main complains have been ameliorated
prior to the dental work and then after the dental work, the nature of the case changes
and a new remedy picture comes up.
-I can not say that but it is true when the dental problems are strong, you can not say wait
because it's very bothering.
It's also true that many of the dental problems have been cured by homeopathic remedy,
instead of sending them to the doctors you give a remedy and the patient goes alone.
It's also true that you give a remedy or 2 or 3 and nothing happens or very little happens
and you have to end up by sending them to the dentist.
It is also true that after dental treatment there is a relapse, it's also true that sometimes
after dental treatment there is another remedy which is indicated.
So we have all these possibilities.
Would you like that?
You take a Lycopodium 200 one month from now, if your case remains as it is.
The same more or less, you take Lycopodium 200 but wait one more month.