-So you have been quite anxious last time when you appeared here.
-Very much, it was so severe that I was not in connection with myself.
I was trembling and my heart was beating very fast and I was like an Opium state.
I felt so bad after the interview that I cried without stop, not right after
but in that evening, so I didn't sleep, I was just crying.
Then something very interesting happened. It turned into pictures.
-And you started having in front of you pictures of feelings?
-It was feelings, it was visions. The interview was in a way far from me
but it touched something very deep and it was the relationship I had with my father.
As I told you, my parents died when they were very young.
In the interview I couldn't cry and now I won't stop.
I had these visions, my father died 20 years ago and I had these visions of him,
very clear and very calming and I woke up very much refreshed in the morning,
although the sleep was unusual to me. Woke up very refreshed and happy
and I wasn't sure I wanted to take the remedy.
-It was like as if you were cured almost.
-Yes.
It happened before I took the remedy and gave me a deep inside about interview
and case taking and something I started to do Homeopathy this year every day, very intensively.
It gave me a very deep inside of the case taking and what can happen
and that's why I'm telling you; it may be not connected but that's why I'm telling that.
-Very interesting what you are saying.
Actually one of the subjects which I have programmed for talking is about the meaning
of the interview and the effect and the relationship and all that.
-Although I was a bit angry that I had shown such a character of myself here in this interview
that it felt very bad. On the other side I said it's lead to touch things in myself
that are not every day. Every day with people I'm very open and expressive and I don't have,
it's very rare. So it happened, it had a significance for me.
I brought it up here because it was just before my son went to the army.
I represented it as if I had a fear of him going to the army
but actually I didn't say the real reason.
Because I have 4 children and I'm not that worried person in the daily life,
I let them do things and I can sleep before they come back at night, I'm not that worried person
but something with my oldest son is very significant.
It is deep, deep fear that I have towards him is ever since
and it's maybe connected to my fear from maybe clairvoyance but it is something psychic
that I have, a tendency to these places. I couldn't even express here, I was so frightful.
You asked me the questions and I was so frightful even to express my fear for him.
I don't know if it's in a dream, in a vision that I saw blood around him.
-And since then you have this kind of anxiety, this kind of fear concerning specifically him.
-Yes. Whenever I was with him I had no comfortable feeling. I wasn't calm with him.
I have 3 sons and 1 daughter, my third son is so wild and he is doing unreasonable things
and I'm not worrying.
Just before I came to the seminar, he drove a bicycle without helmet at night
and he had an accident. I got a call that my son had an accident and my heart was beating
but they said he is OK and I knew somewhere inside that he is OK.
It was a very severe accident and he wasn't even scratched.
I'm not worried for him but for my oldest son I have something as if he is connected to my father.
It's not my delusion. He is very similar to him, in his internal appearance, he is very strong guy
and his inner will is strong and very radiating and I want to prevent this fear.
Because I feel that this fear can harm him, that it can hurt him I do a lot of meditations
and prayings but it is still there.
When I was a kid 5 years old, I told my teacher, my parents are dying.
It was quite strange but when it happened, they were quite young 50 years old, both of them,
I was in touch with this feeling that I had from my childhood, that they are going to die young.
It frightens me a lot.
-When you were 5 years old you told your teacher, my parents are dying?
-Both of them. Both died, very close to one another.
-And they died 3-5 years later?
-No, they died when I was older.
It didn't occur so quickly. I was a child and my father died when I was 20 years old
and my mother died 5 years later.
But I had this connection with these feelings which I had always before that.
It's not that I predict things to happen. It's a fear,
it's more fear than I think something really psychic.
Maybe I will tell my symptoms what happened after taking Phosphorus?
-Yes.
-I took it just on my way back home and my energy level went very high.
When I'm here I always need more sleep, it's tiring these seminars
but also at home I couldn't do mental exertion late in the evenings and now I can do very easily.
I go to sleep and I didn't need more than 6 hours sleep and during the day I could very alert,
working, wake at 7 o'clock in the morning and I come back,
through the day I'm very busy in work and I felt more energy.
-You have a busy practice already?
-Yes, very much indeed.
It's more than what I can do but I'm not working on my own.
I also work with another homeopath with whom I do what we call stage practice for him
and we do two days together, we want to do research and we work very intensively.
I'm very much into Homeopathy. I got my menses one week earlier and it was very astonishing
because I used to get it in a regular date and it came earlier.
Also I didn't feel well before. Two days before menses I felt really bad.
I feel more tired but nervous, I feel a bit ill. Last time I had a flu before, 24 hours before that.
I don't feel good before menses. I used to have it since my first delivery
but after I took Carcinosin, it stopped and I had very exact menses and no PMS.
Now it came back again.
My sexual desire increased a lot after taking Phosphorus and my husband was very happy,
I became more thirsty for cold drinks.
I didn't drink cold drinks before so much but I started to drink, not with ice
but I drink quite a lot.
The symptoms of the menses, when the flow starts, it feels much better.
You told me if the remedy would not work, I should take Pulsatilla
but right after taking the remedy I started eating butter and some other fats
and I don't like meat but I ate more butter and things like this.
I also started to perspire, which I used to have long ago in the past
and when I came back to Israel the weather was very hot.
Here I'm not perspiring like that but when it's hot I perspire here, in the lower abdomen,
in the pubic, I have to change my underwear and also very much in the inner thighs
and I used to have spots there and I got it again. Even I couldn't walk.
-When you used to have that?
-20 years ago, even more, in my high school time.
-How it went away, by itself or you put some cream there?
-I didn't put anything. I think with the remedies it changed.
I have leucorrhea a little bit but now after the menses and after taking Phosphorus,
it was little pieces of cream cheese coming out.
Also I had again what I used to have before I took Carcinosin,
I had the tendency for constipation, it came back very strong.
Not that I'm constipated many days.
If I take the right diet, it won't happen, it's not more than two days
but the tendency wasn't there and it came back.
I always feel very good after stool. My hair is extremely falling.
It was like that always in the recent years but not so extreme, like since the Phosphorus.
Also my nails became very soft.
-Softer and brittle or not breaking?
-They can break easily.
I had fibrocystic breast and I think it was much better after Carcinosin and I didn't check it
but I feel in the left side, it came back. I can feel the area.
-If you finished I have to ask you some questions.
-What also became very strong to me, I'm very sensitive. The weather in Israel is very hot.
We have also mild winter.
I'm very sensitive when there is any air condition and I get to the area with the air condition,
I can develop sour throat, even the teeth and all my body acts like I have flu.
It happened to me 3 times since I took the Phosphorus.
I don't like the winter in general, I don't like the summers, they are very extremes in Israel
but this weather here is just perfect, I'm not hot, I'm very easy and I like it like this.
I used to suffer as a child from tonsillitis.
-Your tonsils are out now?
-No.
But from last time I got fever from tonsillitis was when I was 20 years old.
I remember when I went first time to homeopath, it was 20 years ago
and I didn't know anything about Homeopathy.
I asked her to bring me back fever because I felt very good.
-After the fever, clean.
-Yes, also it was important to say that the times I got fevers during the recent years,
last one was in 1993 was after tremendous shock from the body.
Last time I got after 10 days after an operation. I didn't want to take antibiotics
after the operation and 10 days after I got very severe fever, I didn't take anything,
I felt very good during that fever.
Even though it was delirium, even illusinations I felt very good.
I can remember I had also after the third delivery high temperature.
When my body is after very severe emotional stress, it happened to me once in the army.
It was the last time I got tonsillitis, it was after a very severe emotional shock
that I developed that.
As I said before, when I was a child I was born 5 years after my parents holocaust.
I thought a lot of this because I was a very sweet child and timid and withdrawn.
I had a real problem of speaking in the class. Something with teachers and big group
I had problems, I was very good always in one to one relationship.
I was never told that I was born after a death of my sister from polio.
My parents came after a real drama and then in Israel in the beginning of the 50's
they had this polio epidemic and my sister that was before me, died.
My parents never said a word of anything concerning their past of this trauma they had
and they were very expressive people. The whole thing was kept.
But I know as a child I was very sensitive to all this kind of impressions
and I could feel them very strong.
When I was 6 years old I could know to myself that he is from their land.
I said that because I think my problem from speaking and trembling comes maybe
from over excitement and being excited and very easily impressed. This is how I see it.
Another thing that I wanted to talk is about my fears.
I mainly fear from cruelty, from violence. We never had television at home, in my house.
Part of this is cultural thing that we don't really like junk, not in food,
mainly not in spirit but also I'm very sensitive to see human cruelties.
Recently in Israel we were very involved with the earthquake in Turkey
and people were very afraid. I don't have any fear from natural, cosmic disasters.
I just don't fear it.
I don't have fear from thunderstorm and fears from cosmic catastrophies
but I can get very agitated and excited if something is happening by people.
I live in a very violent place. So it's maybe a reason for me to be there.
It's very difficult for me this thing.
-When you were in the army you had problems? Because army by its definition is cruel.
-I was professional in the army.
-What profession?
-I had a very rare job.
The education department unit in the army established something of researching nature
and archaeological and historical sites and teaching the soldiers about various places
in the land of Israel.
Then Israel was much larger because we (?) in the desert and I had to study a lot,
the whole thing was new and a lot of archaeology and nature and geology.
I knew the army very well but the army itself...
-But you were outside of the fighting units.
I went into the army during a war that was very severe and I was more touched
with the casualties that I saw and the emotional shocks that people had during the war.
What I mean is more, a couple walks with the children in the forest and an (?) came
and murdered them in such a cruel way, out of the blue, this or vice versa, that can kill me,
that's very hard.
-The fact that you don't see television was decided by you or by your parents or your husband?
-My parents had television and my mother liked it very much to see these violent things.
-So it's your decision.
-Mainly it's my decision but my children went through this very harmoniously
and now that one of my sons wants himself, he bought, he lives in a little unit downstairs
and he has his own. I respect it, I don't want to have it in our place.
-When you finish you tell me because I have to ask you some questions.
-My colleagues told me to tell you, it's very difficult for me to ask money from people.
-You have a timidity. Everybody who starts has difficulty.
Hahnemann himself suggested to his pupils, you have to take to show respect.
The others must respect your work and the respect is shown by just paying something
for what you are doing.
What I want to ask you is, I see here in the notes that the warm room
you said it was bothering you. Is it less bothering now?
-Not a warm room, the warm room will not bothered me, it is stuffed room.
-Then you did not mention anything about sweets last time. How much you like sweets?
Do you like sweets, you don't like sweets, is any change in that respect? Sweets and salt.
-I don't add any salt in my dishes. Sweets is a difficult question to me
because I'm very aware of nutrition and I don't know how much in my impulses
come from my understanding. I do like to have some cakes. I'm not a chocolate eater
but I used to love it when I was smaller but I'm not addicted to sweets, I can be without it.
I don't like ice-cream so much. I can eat but I'm not craving.
-Your feet in bed are normal temperature? More hot, more cold?
-They used to be very cold in the previous years, I suffered from cold feet
and perspiring feet but after taking the Carcinosin it changed and it's more normal
but in the winter I always go with shocks in bed, I can never unwear the shocks in the winter
but not in the summer.
-This feeling, what you said you feel much better after stool, you mean psychologically
or physically?
-Physically. I feel more light.
-Can you say you feel more happy?
-Sometimes definitely.
-And the tendency for constipation is back.
Have you checked lately how is your fear of high places?
-When we were checking some friends, they were talking about bangee jumping they were doing
I could collapse there, in a place. I never, never had any desire to be in the air.
Even in the times that I was hiking a lot and I liked hiking and I love walking,
they were people who were so enlighted up there but I wasn't. But I'm not afraid,
I can hike to a high mountain, I'm not attracted by this.
And I told you last time, if I see my children there then I will sink down.
I can not see them in a high place. I have this unease, my husband has to hold me back
and let them go. I'm very much...
-Have you noticed if you perspire except from lower abdomen?
-I do perspire in other places but this I had it long ago and it came back
and the perspiration in the feet I had it more than I have it now.
I have a little bit but not as before.
-Perspiration in the head? Do your perspire in the sleep?
-I don't think so. I never felt it very directly here.
-What about the flow? You said once the flow is coming, then you feel good.
Is it a flow which is clean, red blood or sometimes it has some clots,
not so bright red more dark?
-Usually it is bright and at the end I have some dark spots, specially since the Phos.
But my flow is not so strong. Maybe 2-3 days.
I also mentioned that after taking Phosphorus in 1993 I had some skin eruptions coming here.
Now it's all over the place.It's like skin fungus and a little wart came out but very little.
-Do you remember having warts on your fingers?
-I never had.
-You like fruits? All kinds of fruits or you like more ripe fruits or green or sour fruits?
-I don't like that much oranges, I like fruits, I eat them. I don't like meat very much.
I have aversion to meat and I don't like milk too, I do like yogurt and feta cheese
but not milk. I can drink milk in a tea, it's not aversion to milk but I don't like it by itself.
Maybe I did not stress enough the point that I dwell a lot about my family history past
it's not so much grief although you see that I'm almost crying.
It's not grief but it's dwelling on the past.
After taking the Phosphorus something interesting happened. 20 years I wanted to go
and see my parents place, especially my father's place is in Hungary where he was born
and I did it very spontaneously, after taking the Phosphorus
and I wanted to do it for 20 years; it was very fascinating trip.
Your thinking is between either waiting or this remedy. Correct?
This is your dilemma, shall we write waiting or shall we write this remedy?
It's not very big dilemma therefore.
Taking the cases and investigating really it is a adventure of discovery
and you will discover more and more, if you keep on taking the cases in this way.
Discover human nature, discover a lot of things which are happening
within the human soul and mind.
And maybe if we have time, in the subjects that I would like to discuss,
though they may seem to be a little bit theoretical,
it is the subject of what is the meaning of taking a case
what is the preparation of a homeopath to take a case, what kind of an attitude
and the psychological state he should have, are you interested in this matter?
-Yes.
-We'll see if we have some time we'll talk about that.
Who prescribed wait for her?
Who together with wait prescribed a new remedy appearing?
Who prescribed that the new remedy is Calcarea Carbonica?
The class is getting too good. Very soon you'll be better than me.
This is exactly the idea with this case. She is doing quite well
and the next remedy appears quite clearly. This is the beauty of Homeopathy.
This is real beauty.
This is what makes you really happy and I believe you also feel that
because you see it you discover it.
What are the symptoms which lead you to the Calcarea Carbonica? First the cruelties.
Then the perspiration, then the constipation, then the coldness of the legs, then?
Where is my notes for this case?
Soft nails, brittle nails, vertigo high places.
You see the vertigo high places was there and remains.
Better after stool, happy after stool, show me this rubric.
This you should have noted immediately. That is a symptom of Calcarea Carbonica.
Calc. Carbonica, Nat. Sulphuricum is very strong, Nat. Carbonicum, Borax.
Cheerful after stool, that she said it very clearly.
The moment she said that, immediately your mind should go there and then she said
I can not see cruelties and the soft nails the case is going towards Calcarea Carbonica.
The problem is will you give it yes or no?
In this case because she is doing quite well, you can still wait until when?
What do you want more?
-Cold in the summer.
-Or perspiration around this area.
-I would like to know your opinion about Carcinosin. To my understanding she got before.
what that did to her because she said after Phosphorus this and this came back.
-Correct. This is the next subject that you have to discuss and make clear
what happened with the Carcinosin?
Because she took Carcinosin and several of the physical symptomatology
which has gone away with Carcinosin, has come back.
We have to investigate that matter. In order to investigate that matter
and to really know the answer, we have to know ...
-Many major essential symptoms leading towards Calcarea Carbonica
but at the same time she has a main fear about her oldest son.
My impression was that this fear is torturing her a lot.
Why would it be a mistake to prescribe Calc. now at this moment?
-Not really. You are entitled to prescribe Calc. Carbonica at this stage
but as the case is progressing, you can still wait to see how far Phosphorus
will take the case and where it will stop.
She will have to take Calcarea Carbonica definitely.
There are symptoms which indicate that she must take it; she can not avoid it.
Now you are entitled but even a better answer would be wait for a period of time
and then have in mind Calcarea Carbonica. This is quite a good answer.
She comes in the same group like the little angel.
Both Phosphorus changing into another remedy but we suspect the remedy,
we don't prescribe it.
We can still wait because we see they are doing quite well.
Now concerning her fear I perceive, she is a very sensitive individual as you understand
and very perceptive.
She, herself said what I perceive is not a fear, it is an intuition almost.
This intuition makes me uneasy, anything happens, oh what might happen to my son?
It's not exactly the fear you can control with homeopathic remedy
because she has a conviction that her perception is more or less correct.
She will stay with that conviction. It is difficult to take it away by the remedy.
I don't know maybe after Calcarea Carbonica she will have less of that.
-One more point for Calcarea Carbonica that I didn't mention.
When I put on shocks in the night, it's never in the morning.
I always take it away during the night, which I think it's also from Calcarea.
I told my friends that I felt Calcarea is coming but artificially I came to you this time
because the seminar is now. Normally if you would be my homeopath in my country
I wouldn't go now because I, myself still feel that the fear is better
and Phosphorus is still there and I don't want to lose the action of the remedy;
I wouldn't take now another remedy.
-Very good. This is a good confirmation, what she says.
I'm quite happy, I will not go to a homeopath yet, I will not bother so much
by something which is there.
Therefore wait. So our estimation is correct, to wait but what I want to stress is this.
In the past I went to different countries and I prescribed live cases.
I take the case and I prescribe.
80% of these cases were spoiled by my students who later on, 5 or 6 or 20 days later
because the patient complained of certain symptom, they give another remedy
and then another remedy and another remedy.
I go next year to see the case and of course the case is in a terrible state.
I had the opportunity to see that when I was prescribing myself.
But now you have the opportunity to see what happens when you wait,
when you can evaluate correctly you wait, then how the case develops.
This is the beauty of Classical Homeopathy. Don't be in a hurry to prescribe.
Her feeling is very correct when she says, I'm really feeling much better
and I don't want to lose this. It's the first time in my life that I feel so well,
don't give me another remedy.
She says, it is not that I don't want to take your remedy. If you insist,
I will take Thuja and I say no. Don't take Thuja yet, wait.
Because she is not anxious to take another remedy.
Like in the same way, Hava is not anxious to take another remedy.
But why do we give the Sulphur in the other case?
They are 3 cases which have reached the point
where the second remedy has become apparent and clear. 3 cases. Like the Sulphur case.
Why do we give the Sulphur case?
Because the Sulphur case has some symptoms which are bothering him.
The fact that he wakes up in the morning and then the picture also of Sulphur
is so clear, so typical that is going to benefit him absolutely.
It is a blessing really, I can tell you.
-We still wanted to discuss the question of Carcinosin please in this case.
-The Carcinosin question is like this.
If the patient tells you that I took Carcinosin and I'm better in my menses,
better in my breast, better in my headaches, better in this, better in that
but my anxiety was worse that was a suppression.
But if she tells you that I was better, better, better in everything and now is back,
that means we are in a state in which ...
I have explained to you these remedies that go into a cycle. Sulphur-Calcarea Lycopodium.
Sometimes we see Ignatia. Ignatia many times is followed by Sulphur and then Calcarea carbonica.
That is another cycle.
In this case there might be a possibility, if there is a big stress in the organism
to start all over again Ignatia-Sulphur-Calc. carbonica
but the difference is that the cycle now is on a higher level.
You started with this unraveling, you reached there; now you have to make the same thing
but on a higher level. The same cycle but on a higher level.
I do not know and it has no meaning in finding out,
because you are led by the present symptomatology.
So if she gives me symptoms of Calc. carbonica, I will give her Calc. carbonica.
If later on, she will give me symptoms of Carcinosin again,
then I will prescribe again Carcinosin. Or I will never prescribe Carcinosin again,
depending on her symptoms. Is she going to give me some symptoms, yes or no?
No symptoms, no remedy.
-Can I say something? I thought a lot about this issue of suppression by the remedies
because I was treated by Carcinosin ever since.
I started my treatment with Homeopathy in 1982 and I was prescribed by one of your students,
I got Carcinosin.
They were impressed, it was after the death of my parents, they both died from cancer
and it was very in fashion to give Carcinosin. Then I got it 4 more times.
I would say to this question that only last time, 2 years ago, I was benefited some things.
But I can say today it was suppressive remedy because simply what I studied here.
I never had symptoms going back. I never had any of (?) in my case.
I was so happy to get again perspiration, to get again sour throat, I never had it
after taking Carcinosin. So I thought it's not the right remedy, it was not correct.
It was the theme that I had. It wasn't prescribed on symptoms.
-I agree with what she says because there is one Greek who never studied with me.
He studied in Germany and he is practicing now.
He claims that 90% of his cases he gives Carcinosin and he claims that it has results.
I asked him to make a resume of what are these results,
can he give me some picture of Carcinosin?
What he did is, he copied whatever it was written for Carcinosin
and gave it to me without anything new.
If you give 90% of your cases Carcinosin,
you are definitely going to get some peculiar cases of Carcinosin that you have some effect
or some proving and therefore if you are careful you are going to collect a lot of information
concerning this remedy.
Therefore I believe that Carcinosin has been misused quite a lot in different countries
without real indications.
It's very interesting that the physical symptoms, almost all of them have come back
while the mental-emotional is clearing.
It's very impressive, it's very interesting, it's very instructive and we are very happy.
-I would agree that Carcinosin as a remedy is not understood well
and is prescribed too frequently for the wrong reasons.
As well as people who read the Organon decide to give Sulphur at the end of every case.
The understanding of Homeopathy is the thing that's lacking
and if there is a cancer in the family, immediately they give Carcinosin.
I find that there is a danger especially because it's a strong nosode that can do provings
and different complications.
-On Saturday we asked Frederick Schroyens why Carcinosin was coming so often in the VES?
He explained to us that if you repertorize and put a desire for food
and then aversions for food, you will get Carcinosin automatically.
-Because a lot of these symptoms have been recorded for Carcinosin.
The moment you record a lot of symptoms in desires and aversions,
of course always you will see Carcinosin.
This is another problem that we have to discuss.
Perhaps I've made some time to discuss a little bit more in detail
how to improve the Repertory.
In the way that our Repertories are done today, just damping anything
which appears this is a very dangerous practice.
It's going to make the Repertory finally a useless tool.
Can you imagine what is going to happen when all these rubrics are filled up
with 100,150,130 remedies?
And they are going to fill up because the way the information comes in,
a lot of information, all the rubrics will fill up with remedies.
You will lose the individuality and the specific personality of the remedy,
like some teachers who are teaching Materia Medica or if you read Materia Medica,
you read Medorrhinum and there is no difference from Sulphur, no difference from Aurum.
All they have depression, all they have fears... where is the individuality?
Here we're looking for the individuality.
What is the real quality of that particular case of that particular remedy?
-To clarify my mind that the symptoms now of the Phosphorus came back,
does it give me a hint that before were suppressed by the Carcinosin?
-Yes. It gives you a hint.