We can start. Who is speaking? The father?–Yes.
– Very good. Tell the story.
– From the beginning?
When she was neatly 1,5 year her breast began growing.
– Pubic hair?
– Yes. Hairs were growing and she got having menses.
– At the age of 1,5 year?  Yes.
– Do you know the mother had taken hormones during pregnancy?
– Not at all.
– To deliver?– No.
– Do you remember if they gave hormones to the mother in order to
deliver the baby in time?
– Not at all.
– He told me that they never gave hormones, no treatment
and the pregnancy was normal.
– At what age did your wife have menses for the first time?
– I don’t know.
– How can you know? You never ask such questions!
– But her mother told me that earlier when she was 10 she also had breast. She told me.
– When you met your wife what age was she?
– 35-36.
– And you were 36?
– I was 40-41.
– And she has been given homeopathic remedies?
– I have given only acute remedies because for the chronic situation I didn’t give anything,
I didn’t want to confuse the case, it seems to me very unclear...
was not sure so I waited.
– She took hormones?
– Yes. One time in a month I give her injection.
– You still give?
– Yes I am in Austria and forced by the law to give it.
– Why?
– The law says that she must get hormones because of this diagnosis.
He went to the doctor and they forced him to give the hormones from the law.
– And you can’t say you are giving them? The doctor is always behind checking?
–  Yes. They are very strict. If you don’t do it you have to pay money
or go to prison because the law is if you have a child and it is minor...
- Do they control the hormones of the child?
– He is with a professor in Vienna and he controls it.
– What are the estrogens?
– What is the remedy?
– It stops in pituitary gland (hypophysis) the growing of breast...
- And the menses went away after this hormone treatments.
– The main problem was the before I gave her the injection
she grew 1cm in a month. Too fast.
– What are the somatostatins?
He does not have any hormonal examination?
Testosterone is very high?
– Estrogens were high but now are lower.
– She 5 now.– Yes but growing stops after hormonal treatment.
– You see trembling at all?
– No.
– And during menses she was very angry, aggressive?
– She got fits of rage.
– Red face and perspired a lot.
– At sometimes I saw that she beats herself but not very often.
– She told me it was just once but more against the mother, she beats the mother.
When she got the menses at this age.
– She shouted go away, leave me alone?
– Yes.
– It was a kind of crazy feeling inside.
– Yes. Red head and argh!
– After the hormonal treatment it went away.
Everything was suppressed for me to see very clear what to give.
– She didn’t want to be touched.
– She said leave alone, go away.
– Like this shouting?
– Leave me alone and argh!
– With anger?– Yes.
– And here you write if she was in that rage and you took her in your hands,
you walked with her or you moved her like this?
– She stops. I took her mother taking her and then she stopped.
– Took her in her lap or just embraced her?
– Embraced her.
– In order to stop the rage the child had to be carried?
– Yes but with power. Hold her and then she stops.
– Tightly?
– Yes.
– Even that she is sitting not moving.
– Sitting and embracing with power.
– She will calm down.
– Yes, it was the only way to stop her.
– You say that she was born out of some sexual contact you had with your wife,
not real love?
– Yes.
– And now you live together with her mother?
– No, I don’t live together.
– Who has the child?
– The mother mostly but every day I can see my daughter.
– He lives very close...
- The mother is here?
– No, she is in Austria.
– Why didn’t she come?
– I didn’t know if I should take her.
– He didn’t know it’s so important. His interest to cure the child, mostly.
– When you had with your wife you had drunk alcohol before that day?
– No. I drink very little alcohol.
– And you in your young age you had rage?
– No.
– You mean vaccination against rage or just rage?
– Rage. Anger.
Great anger that had to fight with others.
– No. I didn’t fight.
– Your wife... you met her only once that night and she got pregnant?
You never had sex again?
– No, I was together with her for 5 months.
– She was a secretary of his he is a dentist.
– And she was working in my praxis sometimes.
Not fix but in the summer she helped me for 2 weeks and then...
- It happened! She speaks during her sleep?
– Yes, sometimes.
But I didn’t sleep with her but her mother told me that sometimes she speaks.
– Snoring is more.
– When she sleeps she was telling “I will see dolphins”, such stories...
When she was sleeping, for the last 4 weeks she said I will see dolphins.
– She was speaking about dolphins during sleep.
– Now she beats herself like this?
– Yes.
– Very rarely.
– But before she was doing it?
– Yes.
– Is she very restless?
– Yes, sometimes, in the feet.
– Do you know if she likes to dance, puts music and dance?
– Yes, she likes it very much.
– She puts music herself, puts the radio?
– TV and then she dances and sings. She told me that she will become a dancer.
Sometimes doctor, sometimes dancer.
– She says she eats everything but is she eating very fast?
– No.
She eats meat, chips, soups, McDonalds, fat.
– No McDonalds. Very seldom. Not very often.
– She fears thunderstorms very much and ghosts.
– Yes.
– Do you know how much water she drinks? She drinks a lot?
– Yes, water and juice. Normal water.
– Are you sure?
– But she likes sweet drinks, Fanta...
- She drinks cold drinks.
– Fanta, Sprite, she likes very much, not very cold.
– She loves sea?
– Yes very much and sun.
– Now you are here she goes to the sea or have you just arrived?
– Yes. They arrived yesterday evening...
- But after we will go to the sea!
– Today.
– Her face is red like this always?
No she was in Italy for one week with her mother bathing and now she is brown.
– Are you married with another woman?
– No. No time.
– Your wife has been married again?
– No.
– Did you marry her mother?
– She married later on?
– No, she lives together with her.
– And she has lots of boyfriends?
– I don’t know, I don’t ask her.
– But what is interesting; when they are together he with her mother
the child doesn’t feel well. She feels good when she is alone with the father
or with the mother, not together.
– Wrong energy.
– Not good energy if I see her mother...
- You feel upset?
– No, but the mother is very aggressive to me.
I feel she’s aggressive to me but I don’t know why.
– There’s tension and aggression when they are together.
– How many times you had sex with her mother in 4-6 months?
– In the 4 months we were together 2-3 times a week.
– The sexual attraction was strong on her part?
– Yes.
– Very strong? Excessive? Like an obsession?
– No.
– You were attracted sexually to her?
– Not really but her wish was to take me, control me, I think.
– He says that maybe the wife wanted to have a good life, he is a doctor...
- Not working. It was her interest to take me and marry me.
– You were 42...
but you had a lot of other women before?
– Yes, many.
– You were infected by one of them?
– Yes, when I was studying I was 25 years old I had gonorrhea.
– You went to a doctor, he gave you some antibiotics...
- 2 times.
– And after 6 months did you see any condyloma developing?
– No.
– You like to go to the sea? Are you rejuvenated in the sea?
– Yes, very much. When I was young I was sailing.
–You feel rejuvenated in your health?
– Yes. Very good.
– Do you like to eat fruits which are sour? Unripe fruits.
– No.– Oranges but not sour.
– He didn’t want sour, only sweet fruits and drinks.
– How much salt she takes? She puts a lot of salt in her food?
– No. I haven’t seen it.
– Do you put a lot of salt in your food?
– Sometimes, if there is no salt in it.
– Your feet are warm in bed?
– Mine?
– Do you stick them out of covers?
– Yes, when I am in bed I stick them out.
– How frequently she takes these hormones?
– Once a month.
– Each 28-29 days.
– What is the character of the child? Sweet?
– Sometimes sweet but if she doesn’t get what she wants
she can also be very aggressive, arrogant and obstinate. She has very strong will.
– She sleeps by herself or with her mother.
– She sleeps with her mother.
– We have tried for her, her own room and bed but she doesn’t like it.
– She needs somebody in the night. Most probably she is afraid of the dark.
– Not too much. Sometimes she asks me if there’s a ghost here.
She asks if there is someone...
- Do you remember at what age she started asking this?
– 3 years. 2 years ago.
– When did she start the injections?
– July of last year. She is getting injections for more than 1 year. 1 year and 3 months.
– Her character has changed since the injections?
– Yes, she got quiet, no rage...
- Everything suppressed.
– Can you describe what she has become now, her character?
She is obstinate and afraid of thunderstorms.
– Very much, but now she is like other children. And she goes to kindergarten
and the lady in the kindergarten told me she is a very gentle child.
– No problems.
– Most problems come when she, her mother and I are together.
– Had you noticed before the injections if she was flirting with boy/man?
If a man/boy came, if she was flirting?
– Sometimes, I think so.
– Was she masturbating?
– Yes, I think if she sat she was making some movements.
– Not anymore?
– Very rarely.
But before I thought she was sitting here and she was doing...
- In food, in meat, if there is some fat she will eat it?
– No.
– To me he said she eats fat but maybe not so much.
She doesn’t like fat, she puts it away.
– She likes fish?
– Fish, shrimps, too much.
– Ice cream?
– Very much.
– How much affected is she if you don’t feel well or her mother?
– She has a good feeling. Sometimes I told my head is aching,
she comes and tries to heal me.
– Not really scared. She’s not afraid, she wants to help.
– For how long have they said that she must take these hormones?
– The professor in Vienna told that when she’s 10 years old we can stop.
– 5 years more.
– Do they control the hormones each time?
– Yes, each 4 months I have to go to Vienna with her,
they take blood and control if there’s a problem.
– We cannot stop this now and if this treatment helps
they may reduce the amount of hormones, if hormones are in good level. Otherwise...
- Now I have a problem, 2 months ago I was in Vienna for controlling
and the professor made an x-ray of the hand, the growing of the bone
and he told me that the growing of hand bones is at the age of 10 years
and he told me that the height could be only 145 or 150 because the epiphysis will close.
– What is her height now?
– 130.
– The growing has totally stopped?
– Not totally.
– Not yet but it could be too early.
– I control it at a home and in 4 months she grows 1cm.
– Before the injection she was growing very quickly.
– She was growing very fast and now she got the injection and the level has gone down.
– Has it hone down or almost stopped?
– Not stopped yet.
– What was her height when she started and what is now?
What is the difference between July 2005 and...
- She grows nearly 4 cm in one year.
– Can I write it down?
– Yes.
– When did you measure it? Was June and June?
From which time you compare? Last June, September?
– I measured every month, 4 or 6 weeks.
– Her mother is good-looking?
– Yes.
– Depends.
– Medium.
– Do you know if her mother was also infected with gonorrhea?
– I think not. She told me nothing.
– But she was 36. She had lots of affairs.
– Not so much.
– How do you know?
– She told me.
– In one year she grew 4 cm. Not 18 months?
– No it was one year. Last year July and then July had controlled and it was 4 cm.
The professor had me to make a list and I control.
– And he looks at it.
– Ok.
When the father gave some more information,
he says the professor in Vienna told that there are 15 other cases,
quite rare syndrome and 80% of them are girls.
I asked him whether he know if his wife had gonorrhea he said she didn’t ever tell him.
The father does not know if the mother had any venereal disease.
The professor says we don’t know the reason why such syndrome appears.
Because it looks that the pituitary gland had gone mad producing hormones
which are not needed.
– She is also producing excessive growth hormone,
so the problem is actually even higher...
- The pituitary has gone crazy, I said producing a syndrome which is called acromegaly.
Is producing hormones on these levels. Show me the control.
Medorrhinum, Tarentula are the main remedies Lycopodium, Tuberculinum...
Show me why. There 27 symptoms and 17...
Anger from contradiction, anxiety for others, sympathetic, fear of the dark,
fear of ghosts, obstinate, restlessness in children, striking in children,
aversion to be touched, masturbation disposition, sea bathing ameliorates,
fish desire, ice cream desire, seaside amelioration and desire.
These are symptoms on which you can base your prescription on Medorrhinum.
You may say why not Phosphorus.
Because there is lack of thirst according to what he says, if it is true,
which you would expect that a child will have
and on the other hand we have the information that the father had really gonorrhea.
Do you remember the theory which I have for the children being born healthy,
the best conditions. The best conditions are when the 2 people are really in love
not sexually attracted. This was purely sexual attraction.
The hormones played a major role, not the soul, not the feelings
and I had explained why children are born best when the two people trust each other
and feel melted away in one to the other and they enter one in another.
This is the best time for a child to be conceived
when the ego of each of the two parts is totally eliminated
because of the erotic which overwhelms the two people.
That is the time when the organisms being in an almost ecstasy
they’re in the best possible condition.
Because the moment that one is really very happy all the chemistry of the body changes
and we have different chemistry within the sperm and the ova in that condition.
The chemistry changes and you have the two people giving the best of themselves
to the child. And if two people are coming because of an only sexual attraction
and a child is born, the child will be born with a lot of problems
which will be mostly on hormonal level. Somebody is calling...
Don’t say more! This type of cases show me that the theory is quite correct.
Not only proved that if they examine the sperm of people in love they will find chemicals
which are different from people that when the sperm comes out without real love.
Not sexual attraction, it’s not enough.
The idea is that in a love affair each of the two develops the desire to be together
and especially the woman has to resist. That’s why the old people said in India,
wait until you get married. So, there is an attraction, don’t go, they don’t come together.
The attraction is more and more
and when they come together it’s like the highest possible pleasure.
Because now you have what you desired all these years, flirting, playing etc.
and that is the time when the child will be born with the best condition
and usually the children in western civilization are killed, forced abortion.
Because they say at your age you are too young, you cannot have a child
because you are too young, because you are not married,
because this or that, different reasons.
Most of these children are killed because this erotic idea
and possibility happens when people are in a young age.
So the woman loses the child and then loses the boy she loves
because he is not the proper boy,
you to marry a boy who is in a good position in the society,
marry someone in the bank, marry a doctor etc...
then it’s the mind interfering with emotions. And then is self-interest involving
and then the lower parts of the humans will go into the child.
What is calculating, only sexual attraction... you become the animal type...
Sexual attraction. Sexual attraction can also give a child but of what type?
Another thing is that such children of calculation they will become scientists,
they will become economists, they will become scientists with twisted minds,
they will try to find what is the best gas to kill people, they will discover the best gas,
they will discover a clever bomb and tell to the government
we have found the clever bomb. Clever bomb is a bomb that kills only the people
and does not bring down the buildings.
People are killed the buildings can now be occupied by the enemy which comes inside
and takes over. That is human mind how it works
and why we have produced such minds in the west.
Why don’t they produce such minds in Mexico, in Argentina, in India?
Because most of the people are healthy.
In the west people are born under these conditions.
Calculating, self-interest and also egoism. When 2 people keeps himself...
says you are there I am here and come together in a sexual act
they don’t give the best out of themselves but they give the animal side.
So you are doctors you have to know these things
it doesn’t matter what happens in your life. You go back and meditate upon.
The main thing is that this information is maybe correct
and if this is correct we are making a big mistake
in letting all the young women to have abortions.
Of course a child can be born this way also, sexual attraction, you go one night
and the next day you find yourself pregnant. This is not good either.
So you have to have resistance and discipline. Oh, George is religious!
No, I am not religious! I say it purely from a healthy point of view.
It is much better if you resist than having the experience.
First, we have the experience with different people and then finally we get married.
That is wrong! That is the type that children will be born with this condition.
It’s not a matter of religion at all.
Now the problem with this child is we are going to give Medorrhinum
and now what is going to happen?
Because if they don’t control the hormone levels what is going to happen...
we don’t know anymore what is happening
because the organism under Medorrhinum will try to balance itself,
bring the pituitary gland work better.
If we don’t have a control to see whether the amount of hormones is still necessary
we’ll damage the child through excess of hormones.
So they have to control all the time
and to able to tell to the professor listen Mr. professor
the child is also taking homeopathic remedies
and maybe that will change the levels of hormones.
If the professor is open-minded he may accept it,
if he is closed he will say nonsense and he will continue giving the same hormones.
Medorrhinum, what kind? This is a problem.
I want to give a dose Medorrhinum 200C once a month together with...
not the same day, the day after...
it’s better after the injection, next day you give Medorrhinum. Once a month.
Within 6 months we will see whether the amount of hormones
which are given still necessary or maybe if he is careful...
In case he is against Homeopathy the professor
they must not tell him anything about Homeopathy otherwise he may do it on purpose...