This is the case of pubertas praecox of a young girl
who came here in September 2006 for the first time, 3 years ago
and the first remedy that was given here is Med. 200C every month.
She took for how many times?
– For 1 year. I think it was for 9 months from September till June,
when we came for a follow up
and then you gave her Lachesis as a second remedy 200C and 1M.
After another year in 2008 you gave her Phos. 30C, 31C, 32C for 3 months.
We are talking about the different layers.
- What was the result?
After this remedy all the special emotional states calmed down.
After Med. the child was stable, after Lachesis this jealousy you discovered
was much better and a year later after the Phos. she got a warmer.
Before she was inside herself, her fears went away.
She had fear of rain, fear of thunderstorms. All these got better.
Beside all these all the school medicine criterias [?] got better.
The school mediciners in Vienna are confident all was fine
and they don’t know we are making homeopathic treatment.
They say it is almost a miracle, everything is developing fine.
The bone tests meet their criterias, if the bones are growing like a child
or like a teenager and it was more like a child again. That gave us hope.
– Let’s say it for the people who do not know this problem
that when there is such a syndrome then the child does not develop actually,
remains very short, the bones are not developed
because they don’t have the force of development of a child but of a grown-up person,
that grows very slow and the person remains quite short.
– Because the puberty ends at the age of 7 and then she could have the length of a dwarf.
And that was a big fear of the parents, the bad prognosis but now the school...
- Is it growing according to her age now?
– Yes.
– The height is according to her normal age.
– It’s almost like the normal age.
The growth and the weight are in the normal, the curve of growth is ok.
The growth of the bones is also ok. And they measured the bones of the hand
and since 2 years it’s stable. Before it was unstable.
– So, she develop normally. We’re lucky.
The epiphyses normally after puberty are fixed and they are still open
and the child is still growing still and that is also a sign for the school medicine
that the child grown normally. They are very confident.
– How does she feel?
– Fine, she says.
– She has good appetite?
– Yes.
–She eats quite a lot or not? She eats everything.
– Fruits she eats?
– She eats everything, nowadays she eats vegetables.
- Not enough fruits.
But if I cut them and I put them in a plate and look beautiful the fruits then she will eat it.
– What does she ask for food mostly? Eggs, meat, fish, vegetables?
– Vegetables she doesn’t eat. She likes creamy soups, lasagna, ice cream very much.
Spaghetti carbonara, soft things not hard. And she doesn’t like vegetables.
– How much salt she needs?
– No salt. No pepper.
– Sweets?
– Normal
– In sleep she perspires at all?
– Sometimes.
– Ask herself if she perspires in sleep.
– No.
– In sleep she stays in one position or turns around? What position she sleeps in?
– She likes to sleep on the back and the arms not so... but here.
But she changes her positions. And so often on the abdomen.
– She is afraid of the dark?
– Yes.
– She needs light in the room?
– She likes a little light is enough.
– Does she ever she any nightmares?
– Normally not
but sometimes she talks during sleep and sometimes she wakes up with open eyes
but she is not here. Not very often. The most of the times she sleeps quietly.
– Her nails are strong or brittle?
– She has good nails.
– She seems quite healthy.
– Thirst is normal or too much?
– She drinks not enough. I cannot control.
– But she is not asking for water?
– I must give her, I must say please drink, sometimes she drinks one glass,
a little glass all day long. She doesn’t go to the toilet.
If I ask when she says no she doesn’t drink...
- If she drinks cold drinks or tea is it the same?
– No she drinks water...
- But not tea or...
- No. She drinks cold and warm water.
– Cold drinks I mean like Coca-cola.
– No. Lemon Fanta or orange Fanta.
But always Fanta with water mixed. She doesn’t like too sweet drinks.
– Is she constipated?
– I think her stool is hard.
– Does she have pain?
– Short before she must go to the toilet she has little pain
and then she springs and then I know...
- After stool she feels good?
– She feels much better. I can see it on her face.
And before she is...
- Ask her if she feels joyful after stool. Ask her.
– I will take a picture before and after. Hahah.
– Eggs?
– No. She doesn’t like.
– Sometimes she eats soft boiled eggs but once in the month.
If there are eggs in the salad she puts them aside or eats only the white not the yellow.
– Is she crying?
– Yes, every day.
– When she cries she has to go in her room or cries in front of you?
– In front of me.
– She feels better in warm or in cold weather?
Is she a hot person, likes open, fresh air or she is cold, likes to cover?
– She is warm, not freezing. Warmer than me. She is quite warm.
– She can stay lying under the sun in the sea?
– Yes, she can but very often she goes in the water quite water,
she can be in water for one and a half hour, it’s her element.
– Even today it was cloudy she was to go to the water.
Even then the lakes were cold in Austria I think she is a warm person
longing for swimming and cold but not tremendously.
– When there is some fat in her meat will she eat it or take it out?
– I cut it and I make this for her, I don’t know if she would do it herself.
I think she would make it. I think she would not like it.
– Butter? Bread and butter?
– Not really. I like more butter.
She takes the jam without butter. She eats bread without butter.
– She generally doesn’t like meat so much but fish.
– She like more fish?
– Yes.
– She likes wiener schnitzel. All children in Austria like this. It’s baked veal.
– She likes beer???
– She has tried it. But she doesn’t like it. It is too bitter.
– She used to snore very much. How is it now?
– Sometimes her tongue goes a little back and she snores. Sometimes not always.
– She sees dreams, she remembers her dreams?
– No. She says that she had a dream but she cannot remember it.
She knows that she dreams but she cannot remember.
– In the morning she is always tired. And I am too.
– She needs to sleep more?
– No, if she goes earlier to bed she is tired too. Morning is not her time.
– And concerning her emotions I have different impression from the mother
than from the father. The father says she is very stable and without fits of rage anymore.
But with her she has more emotion, more fights.
– She fights with her mother?
– More. I think it is very different what she tells me than what the father tells me.
– She behaves different to her mother than her father.
– Her father is more friendly.
– She tries to behave in the way her father likes. With her she has fights. It’s typical.
The mother is responsible, she lives with the mother and they have more fights.
– They are separated?
– Yes. The father doesn’t live.
– When did they get separated?
– They’ve never been together.
The father comes every day but they don’t live together.
– She is sighing sometimes?
– Yes.
– She says “I have to do so much!”.
– She sighs because she has to do so much.
– I think she says this because I say this.
– Is she sad sometimes?
– Yes, sometimes.
– What is the best time for her?
– The afternoon is a good time until 5. When I come it is not such a good time,
maybe from 5-7 p.m. and later she will be better again. She cries in this period.
– I think in this time she will get a little but tired, she feels not so good
and then she will be very sensitive in this time
and later she feels better again after 7 and then.
– She can stay until 12 a.m.?
– Yes.
– That’s enough. We know what to give.
– He has some special questions and then he knows!
Ok, you saw the first case and the analysis.
As you hear it was followed by one dose of Lachesis next year
and the third year by a dose of Phos. according to the symptoms that she developed.
Which again points to the fact that complicated cases are not going to be well with one remedy.
When we hear that a case was cured with one remedy
most of the times it doesn’t mean the case was cured
unless we have patients on the first,
second or third level this can happen. But these are few cases,
most cases today are complicated and they need a series of remedies
and they needs a remedy at a certain point . The problem is for instance in this case,
if you havew given Phos. instead of Med. as first remedy nothing would have happened.
If you had given Lach. Nothing. Now the problem is that you give the wrong,
the underlying remedy because you have symptoms of the remedy which is underneath,
so you prescribe it and finally you give the correct remedy
and then the picture of the remedy you have prescribed in the beginning comes up again
and you say I have given this remedy and had no effect
and you go and give another remedy.
You see how you can be confused to really take a case
and progress it it’s a matter of absolutely precise prescription,
that’s why I don’t believe all these nonsense with new remedies.
They do not know the usual remedies.
I found people who cannot recognize a Calc. or Sulph. and they give a new remedy.
I have been practicing with great success without the need of any new remedy.
We have already here 780 remedies. Why do you need more?
You say ‘modern medicine’. Absolute nonsense!
What happen is that people think now they found a new remedy and so what?
You may need once in your life maybe a new remedy if it was really proved properly.
But even the provings of the new remedies are fantasies.
So Homeopathy is going according to the symptoms you can see.
I will tell you something. They wrote to me from America today, I received an email,
that I practice and I have great success with the new remedies
and why WHO are acting again Homeopathy? They say Homeopathy is no good.
They say it because there is no effect. If you claim to be a homeopath
and you prescribe correctly once in 100 nobody is going to take notice of you.
Here in Greece where my students have been practicing properly
we have one hospital ‘Gennimatas’ that has a department in Neurology department
with Homeopathy at the moment.
One of the biggest gynecological hospitals are carrying
a research for sterility ‘Helena’ hospital.
In the university of Aegean we have an master’s degree in Homeopathy.
With four M.Ds and dentists.
We are preparing a special school of Homeopathy in the island of Kos.
How these things have happened? Only because of the effect.
Because politicians want to be treated, judges, lawyers, scientists come and see effect,
also professors of medicine come and see that here it is a serious condition.
How they can resist? Why in Greece we have such an explosion of Homeopathy
and in London they close down half of their practices?
Because there is not effect with those nonsense they are circulated.
I want you to tell me what do you understand
that we should do at this point in time with this girl? Shall we wait?
Shall we give a repetition of the last remedy which was Phos.?
Or are there some indications for another remedy? Difficult problems.
I don’t see anybody jump into the answer...
- I think at this moment the girl is in a good state of health
and there is not another picture of a new remedy and I think it is better to wait.
– The same. I think we have to wait because the bone condition is very good
and the mental condition is also good.
– I think there are some keynotes for Ignatia.
The fact that she is sighing and there are some days that she is weeping
and the desire for fruits is less. But it’s not a clear picture.
– I think that Phos. picture is changing a little bit.
The fact that she is not well between 5-7 p.m.
and after 8 a.m. she can stay up until 12 a.m.
and also her worst time of the day is morning.
So these are some keynotes of Lyc. The mother said she cannot wake up in the morning.
And you asked her does she want to sleep more that was your question
so you were trying whether there is an indication for Lyc. or Nit-ac. or a Magnesia.
This is what I observed.
– According to me there is no clear picture at this moment but there are 2 possibilities.
One is Ignatia as she said and the other Lycopodium.
Because she says in the morning she cannot wake up
so she is unrefreshed no matter how long she may have slept.
That’s one keynote for Lyc. The other keynote is
that she says that between 5-8 p.m. she is in a bad mood and not feeling well
but after 8 she can go on and she is more alive and she is much more aware,
clear and happy. This 3 symptoms are symptoms of Lyc.
But at the same time it is very interesting the idea of Ign.
Because of the fruits and the sighing I don’t remember one more symptom
that pointed to Ign. But anyhow.
You remember I was asking about the situation with the parents.
That means that the child has definitely perceived a kind of grief
because of the separation. She is tormented, torn between father and mother.
She likes the mother but she fights with her
but she likes more the father with whom she doesn’t fight etc.
You see an internal struggle in the child. Therefore the idea of Ign. is definitely there
and most probably will develop. It means that as she grows up she will be more
and more aware of the real problems within the family,
the moment she will be really aware then the picture of Ign. will pop up quite strongly.
But at this moment we are justified to give a dose Lyc. 200C
and wait for the time either Ign. or Nat-m will come up to make the grief a little bit better.
– The mother asked me to add that she has tremendous fears
and we didn’t talk about it yesterday
but the mother asked me to tell you she has fears to call somebody even a friend,
she always asks the mother to do this.
– This is very interesting concerning Lyc. Because it is a coward person,
who has no courage so needs to call somebody
and she has fear if I call somebody what he will say.
– The mother says it is really a big problem because she is in an age
where other children do this for example other children go for ice
and she always says mom do this for me.
– That means that is a confirmation that Lyc. is going to help quite a lot. 200C Lyc.
and we’ll see next year.
– I think this is important
because there is a kind of shyness because on one hand she is sportive,
she has courage for swimming but on the other hand she doesn’t talk to people,
she didn’t talk with you. Kind of shyness, not enough courage.