What are the results? You had a test.– From yesterday.
Yesterday I was in Vienna, in the clinic and the doctor made a list of the growing
and the weight of Nikola and it was normal.
The normal is between 11 years and 7 or 8 months.
And also the X-ray of the hand bones was normal, nearly 11 years and 7 or 8 months.
– So what says the professor? Is he happy?– He is happy.
In the last control in December he told me that in summer we can stop the medicine,
but now he told me we should go on until December to take the medicine. For the next 6 months.
He told me it’s better for her to take the medicine.
– He thinks the improvement is from his medicine?– But I didn’t tell him that we will come here.
He cannot believe it.
– Has he seen another case like this?
Did you ask him if he have seen another case improving with a conventional medicine like this?
– The old professor didn’t work now. There is a younger doctor.
– The old professor is in pension.
– I think the younger doctor hasn’t seen so many cases,
I think Nikola is a very special case because she began before she was 2 years old.
– Before 2 she had pubic hair, menses, and her breast growing.– It was quite a severe case.
And I remember the professor said...- In the very beginning when we came to the professor,
we were forced by the government to a professor for an injection.
He told me that he never had seen before such a young child with this sickness.
– But what was his prediction? What did he tell you?
– He told me that in some years she will stop growing at the height of 1,50 m but now she is 1,53 m.
And she will continue. Not so fast but she will.– So it’s a normal condition now.
What was the last remedy that we gave you?– Last year she didn’t get any remedy
because you said she was in a very good condition and she could make a break from remedies.
She got nothing.
– But now the same doctor said she will continue.
Last year the doctor who saw her said... Last year was it the young doctor?
– Yes already.– You mean the same doctor.
– Yes, it was always the younger one.
– Only the first time was the older professor?– Yes.
– But did you tell him at a certain point that you are giving her homeopathic treatment?
– No. Never.
Because you always advised us to keep quiet because they are really school mediciners.
So it was better to hide it.
– That is correct but I remember last year he said, 6 months more or something like that.
– From the hormonal treatment?
– He told me in December that we could stop with injection now
but yesterday he told me it would be better for 6 more months.
– You had not stopped the injection already?– No. It’s not allowed.
I am forced by the hospital to make injections. Because if I didn’t they would take me to the court.
– So she took Med. 200C, it was the first prescription in 2006. One year later, Lach.
200C, one year later Phos. 30C, 31C, 32C for 3 months. 2009 Lyc.
200C and 2010 Nikola develops very well.
She is in general very good state so that year she needed no remedy.
So last year we did not prescribed any remedy.
Until September everything went well but then the father realized
that she seemed so symbiotic with her mother.
What do you mean “symbiotic”?– She wants always to be close to her mother.
Symbiotic is not an English word.
– Attached to her mother?– Yes. Very close to the mother, only the mother.
– And kept distance from the father?– Yes.
– Without any obvious reason. She rejected him even when he wanted to hug her. Very strange.
Was she manipulated by her mother? They are divorced.– They never married.
And the relation is still bad as always.
– We don’t live together in the same house.– They never had a connection.
I only talk with him or with her, never together.
And he told me that it was so strange; normally she liked him very much
and always wanted to be with him and there was a period where she was rejecting him totally
and it was so strange. He always had the impression that she manipulates the daughter against him.
It’s not the first time he has this impression.
– Since 2009 in June, she hasn’t received any homeopathic remedy.
– Yes.
– In school it was going up and down in general,
she has lots of quarrels with her mother concerning her studies.
Still she can have fits of rage, sometime ago she even destroyed a glass door. She kicked the door.
When did this happen?– I have only seen the destroyed door.
– Yes but in time. Was it one month ago?– It was 4 or 5 months before.
– The last 5 months, did she have fits of rage?– Only with her mother.
– How do you know since you don’t live together? She tells you?– Sometimes I see it.
– When you are present?– He is in the house every day.
He lives 5 minutes away but he spends all his free time in the same house.
He is in the house most of the time.
Only for sleeping he goes to another place because they live in his house
and he wants to sleep somewhere else.– It’s his house where they live.
– When Nikola was born, I bought a house and her mother lives with her in this house and...
– He went away.
He sleeps 5 minutes away by car in another house and when Nikola goes to bed every day, he leaves.
So he spends a lot of time with her in the house. But not as normal parents.
– Did she do anything aggressive except of breaking the glass door?
Did she throw things, did she do something aggressive, not as bad as breaking a door but...
Can you describe?
– She was crying, her mother was crying but no more aggression.
It was the first time when the glass was broken.
- She didn’t destroy anything else so far.
– Did she hit her mother?– When she was younger but now she stopped that.
– When she was on hormonal treatment she was striking a lot.
It was when she started having menses between 2 and 3 years old, she was striking.
– When she was very young, 3 – 4 years old she was crying and had red head...
- But was she striking, attacking, hitting?– Yes.
For some minutes, but then she stopped.
– But after the hormonal therapy she stopped entirely.
– She weeps or screams, occasionally with more or less fits of rage.
She is snoring a lot. She had constipation.
And if she eats eggs, she has constipation?– Yes. Sometimes.
– But soft boiled they are ok. She likes soft boiled eggs?– Yes, sometimes.
– Sometimes, not always.– Yes, sometimes she eats but not every day.
– She gets nausea after sausages, especially fat.
She desires sweet and sour food and lots of salads. You talk with her mother...
- Seperately.– And the mother also talks about her having a lot of anger.
– Yes. The mother says the same. Sometimes fits of rage
and for example when they have fights concerning her duties to do some homework for the school,
she doesn’t want to do her homework and so they have fights
and she doesn’t want and then she screams and so. And then she can get very aggressive.
She feels forced to it.– She is quite angry I can see.
– But with me there are no problems.
– He always observes that the anger is only at the presence of her mother. And not with him.
They are very harmonic together, very easy going.
– But I think she feels that he doesn’t harmonize with her mother.
– She has the feeling of a tension.– She feels tension when the mother is present.
She can have fits of rage, aversion to do homework and she thinks her mother does not love her.
– Yes. She says to the mother you don’t love me
when the mother says you should study, you should do your homework.
Then she says you don’t love me and screams.
– She doesn’t want to get advised, give explanations, has a total aversion towards them.
– This is the view of the mother. It’s her experience.
– It’s her impression.– Yes.
– She is in a terrible state at this moment. I can see, she is so...
Ask her if she just wants to get out of here.– No, it’s ok.
– It’s just the same.– She seems to be in inner despair. Like to explode sometimes.
Has even the tendency to throw things around, to beat at things or herself on her head.
– The mother is saying this.
– Sometimes she screams while let herself falling on the floor and knocks herself around.
Do you know if she talks in her sleep?– When she was younger she did sometimes.
– Nightmares?– Sometimes when she was younger she told about dolphins in her dreams
and she was talking in the night about dolphins etc.
– She spoke in the night, in the dream? Or that was happening in the daytime.
– No in her fantasy.– She is impatient.
She sweats a lot on her head. She is hot and has a strong desire for cooling down herself.
She loves water. Ask her if she wants to have a shower,
if she can stand the shower over her head and the water running.
– Cold water?– No, it doesn’t matter.
– It’s ok.– I have the impression the first thing she wants to do is to go to the pool.
She always wants to be in the water. And she also likes the shower over her head.
– Is she afraid of anything? Does she have any fear?– Thunderstorm.
– Dark? – When she has to go out in the night to do something...
- But in order to sleep, she doesn’t need light in her room.
When she was younger, she needed light in the room.– Yes.
When she was younger she needed the light.
– She sees bad dreams, has nightmares?– No.
– She remembers her dreams?– Sometimes but not often.
– Usually she feels more the cold or the heat?
Is she aggravated by hot weather or by cold weather?– She loves hot and cold weather. Both.
– Her feet usually are cold, normal or hot? – Normally warm.
– She has constipation and most probably she has hemorrhoids because there is blood in the stool.
– They are rare but sometimes there is blood in the stool.
But I think that it comes from the fact that she goes to the toilet once every 3 or 4 days,
or sometimes 5 days. I think it’s constipation.
– Ask her if she is perspiring during her sleep around her neck.
– No.– Her self-confidence can be good or bad.
But she is doing things by herself more than before.
With her friends she has less conflicts in the meanwhile
she is still lazy only doing absolutely the minimum. Her nose is mostly blocked.
How is the pubic hair?– In the last year it is growing. Not strongly.
– Have you noticed a special interest in flirting with boys?– I think so.
Sometimes she is playing with boys, especially with her friends.
I think she likes to play with boys but also with girls.
– But have you noticed any sexual tendency?– No, not until now.
– Masturbation?– I cannot tell.
– Only when she was very young, 2 years old she masturbated.
– You did not ask her mother.
– I asked in general if the development is normal from this side and she said yes,
it is normal, she doesn’t know any more. If this question is very important we can now phone her.
– This is not so much important. Most probably yes, she is having some sexual development now again.
I can see. She is mentally and emotionally disturbed because of that.
Do you know if she is jealous?– Yes.
When we go together and if I meet some friends she says let’s go now, be with me, not with the others.
– What did you ask her?– If she likes to stay here or not.
She likes to stay here.– No she is calmer. I can see it. Before she was really angry.
– She is a typical young lady.– I don’t know.
She still likes dancing?– Singing and dancing. Sometimes she sings more than dancing.
– She used to snore in the very beginning.– Yes.
– Heavily. She is still snoring.
I think it depends on her teeth because the upper jaw is smaller than the lower jaw
and I made her some orthodontics regulation for nearly 4,5 years.
– Do you know if she grinds her teeth in her sleep?– No.
– Because she wears this, you cannot see it.
– No, if she doesn’t wear the orthodontic, she doesn’t grind.
– I don’t understand, if she wears the orthodontic device does she grind her teeth or not?
– She does not.
– If she does not wear it?– She also doesn’t. She doesn’t grind her teeth at all.
– If I wouldn’t have done orthodontic treat there would be a very prominent upper jaw.
But now it is normal.
– Is her mother a scientist?– She is a secretary. She works in real estate.
– She hasn’t studied in the university.– No.
– But she has a very strong personality.– Yes, sometimes.
Sometimes her self-esteem is very low. But on the other side she is very aggressive.
– She hit you?– No.
– Have you seen her striking her hand on the wall?– No I haven’t seen it,
but I thought if she would become angrier she would but it didn’t happen.
But this happened short time ago. Yesterday when we were in Vienna she was stung by a bee.
No reaction.
– Of course we didn’t give anything.– Ok. Thank you.
It is a quite serious condition
and I don’t know why the government feels that this condition has to be treated
otherwise the parents go to the court.
Anyhow this child was doing impressively well under the homeopathic treatment
and also the hormones to the extent that last year the doctor who measured the development said that
most probably she could stop the hormones
otherwise I think the hormones would continue for years maybe, I don’t know how many.
– She started the hormones when she was 3, now she is 9.
For the last 6 years she was under hormonal therapy.
– For how many years normally...- It depends on the case, on how severe the case is.
This case was very severe because she had menses since she was 2.
– The hormonal disturbance was very severe.
– Normally they stop the allopathic treatment when the girl is ready to enter puberty.
About 11, 12 years.
You stop the hormonal treatment and you hope that the system is not totally destroyed
and she would develop normally.
– My evaluation Is that she was doing quite well until 2 years ago
when she received the last remedy and last year she was doing so well
as the professor who was attending her case said that she would continue the hormonal therapy
for a few more months and then she would stop.
The interesting thing is that she received no more homeopathic remedy
and it appears to me that there is a regression in the case for several reasons.
You understand the regression? Because she started having the psychological state
which she had when she was 2 years old, with the fits of anger. That’s the one.
The second is the growing of the pubic hair. The aggression because of the hormonal disturbance
and also the growing of the pubic hair shows that
the good development we could see last year is not there anymore.
This year we can see a regression that means we see a picture of her condition
when she was 2 years old, only not as severe as then.
The picture tends to be similar to the 2 year old picture, with the explosions,
the rage and the growing of the pubic hair.
There definitely is an environmental factor which is important in the case
that means she has some kind of antagonism with her mother because of reasons everybody understands
and what I wanted to understand
and he can tell he said there was a period when she was attached to her mother.
Which was that period exactly?
– This was last year in September, October so she was very fixed to the mother .
- This is an important information.
Why is it important, can anybody tell me?
September, October last year she was in very good terms with her mother.
What is the reason for this? She has always been against her mother.
Why was she against her mother? Because she felt like a woman, an antagonistic woman instinctively.
She was against another woman who is taking away her lover who is the father. It is very obvious.
So she is against the mother. She wanted to hit the mother, kill the mother, destroy the mother.
Understood. Suddenly she becomes friendly with her.
Why?– I think she became the 2 year old girl when she was close to her mother,
like a 2 year old girl would be.– I think it is an emotional improvement.
This year 2010 is a good year from any point of view; physical and emotional.
I think the remedy has also worked on these levels.
– This is correct but you could say it more clearly.
By September, October the hormonal changes were so good
that there was no imbalance producing the female hormone to such an extent.
Therefore she is not a grown-up woman anymore who sexually understands things.
She stops understanding this and she becomes a child of her age.
That was the best point in the development of her case.
Later on, she starts fighting again with her mother.
Therefore we have to conclude that the hormonal treatment
that was continuing was doing damage to this organism.
If they had stopped giving the hormones the child would be totally normal.
At this moment due to the hormonal treatment they brought back an imbalance
which is the opposite of what the treatment is aiming at.
She becomes a grown-up woman again who is antagonistic with her mother.
Unless we evaluate these things we cannot understand and advise what to do.
Therefore the hormonal treatment is doing damage from now on to that child.
And by disturbing the hormones the child feels at a state of anger all the time
like she was in the beginning of consultation. You saw her.
You saw how she was disturbed and leave me alone.
You didn’t see maybe but I was close and I could see more clearly. But this was her condition.
Therefore I consider this as a kind of relapse of the beginning of the case.
If she is left without any homeopathic medication this condition will grow more and more
and they will not realize that the hormones they are giving are bringing the opposite result.
The treatment she took for 3 years brought her to the best possible state
where her hormones were really balanced and became a child who loves her mother, naturally.
It’s not another woman against whom she has to fight.
The moment that the female hormones are in a much increased state
then the mother becomes a symbol of an antagonist and then she will fight and kick the door etc.
What will we do?– Stop the hormonal therapy.
– We have to treat the professor.– The professor doesn’t know.
They have a protocol, they don’t evaluate, and they don’t know how to evaluate.
They have a protocol and the protocol says you have to take so many years of treatment.
You have to continue. Why the professor said you have to continue? That’s another question.
Last year the same professor said wait, most probably we finish, we don’t need anymore.
This year the professor says I see some signs of regression.
You see how things are fitting together.
That means the professor saw a kind of relapse in the growing of whatever they measure.
And then they said I made a mistake last year I told you to stop, you have to continue.
This is correct, he is a good professor from the point of view of conventional medicine.
He is careful; he observes things are not going well anymore like last year.
Now I see some bad signs so I’d better continue.
He does not realize because he does not know that the result was not because of his treatment, it was in spite of his treatment.
That means the treatment overcame the injections.
– On Tuesday when I will go home I will phone to the professor
and tell him that Nikola doesn’t like the injections.
– He wants to tell the professor that Nikola doesn’t want to have the medication anymore.
– Maybe it can work.But the injection is given in the hospital?
– I give it every 28 days.– He is forced to do it.
The father is forced to give her the injection. From his point of view he wouldn’t do it.
But he must do it because of the law.– This is not my job. He can decide whatever.
This is my analysis, after that he is a doctor and he knows better.
What I have to say is that the remedy which is indicated at this moment is Stramonium.
I will show this.The first is Tarent., Stram., Lyc., Hyos., Staph., Bell., Tub.
Why I prescribe Stram.
It is because the very beginning of her state as they described to me was a picture of Stram.
which is coming back now.
The aggressiveness, the grinding of the teeth, the whole picture,
the darkness of which she was afraid etc. For me this is a relapse of the original state.
If this stays without homeopathic remedy
and they keep on giving the hormones she will have a severe relapse.
– The first remedy was Med.But you also considered Stram.– I don’t remember.
Now the way that they describe so clearly the original case...
The problem is now that they did not come with the original case.
They came under the medicine, the hormones,
so I did not have the aggressiveness that much then I took into consideration the present symptoms
which were under the hormones and gave Med.
But if she had come without any hormones I would have given Stram.
straightaway. Now she is like starting all over again.
That’s why I say if she is left without the homeopathic treatment she will go into a deep relapse.
– What is also very interesting for me is that the state
when she was very close to the mother in September you considered it the best state
but for me it was interesting that the father mentioned that for him it was very strange.
He didn’t see it as a positive sign.– But the father cannot evaluate the case the way we do.
He doesn’t know the facts.– But it was strange.
– Yes, also the father has his reasons to believe that the mother manipulates the child
and most probably she tries to do it
but the reaction of the child comes out of the inner disturbance of the hormonal system.
That’s why she has this kind of reaction.
The child likes to touch the father, likes to be the woman of the man. It’s obvious.
Therefore the mother is the antagonist.
But once the hormonal balance comes back she becomes a child who loves her parents.
– But I cannot understand why we cannot give Med. again.
– I explained it but you did not understand.
When she came in her original state she started having fits of anger and pubic hair,
they took her to the doctors, they said this is pubertas praecox syndrome
and has to be treated with hormones.
She had been treated with hormones for 3 years before they came to me.
By the time she was taking the hormones the picture had changed
and the original picture was gone.
Now according to my understanding the original picture is coming back.
If she had come in the original picture I would have prescribed Stram. The basic picture.And Stram.
would have brought back the child to normal condition without further need for hormonal treatment.
This is a science. You have to realize it.
Everything that happens follows some rules and if you know them you can understand the process.
Medicine today or the understanding of diseases is I got a cold and then I got this
and then suddenly I start having headaches, now I have chronic headaches,
now I take some Lonaryd, painkillers and then one day I start having fasciculations,
I start having diplopia and then I start having numbness in one leg
and then paralysis starts and you have now Multiple Sclerosis.
They never connect what was happening before to what is happening now
because they don’t know the rules.
They have no idea that the organism is always one and doesn’t change.
It’s not an organism who has now headaches and the next day has another thing, epilepsy.
It is a continuation. There is a continuation with acute and chronic conditions.
Acute conditions can change and chronic conditions can also change.
A person with chronic rhinitis or hay fever for years has this puffs they use for opening the nose
because they cannot breathe and the edema is reduced until when? The edema comes back the next day,
then again reduce the edema then it comes back then my nose is closed again
back again with the cortisone until there is a time when the mucus membranes of the nose
will be dried up and become dead. They cannot react anymore.
But the original problem is inside the organism.
Therefore he will bring it out on a deeper level.
Which is a deeper level? This is the uppermost respiratory tract.
Then you have the larynx, the trachea, the bronchi.
Suddenly it becomes chronic cough, take anti-coughing drugs
and then eventually dyspnea, eventually asthma. So this is a continuation.
You cannot say this is different than the original hay fever.
It is the same hay fever which continues now on a deeper level which is the asthma
and the treatments that they are prescribing are much more powerful now.
It is very important that the theory which exists with Homeopathy
should be taught in the Medical Schools of course.
How many cases would be saved if this was taught and people would realize
that they should not do these things.
You saw the other case that started with an eczema on the folds
and then ended up in juvenile diabetes.
It started with this! The same thing! And then from here went to the lungs.
You press this inside then the lungs are inflamed, it’s not the skin anymore,
it’s the lungs which are inflamed and then you treat this heavily,
you don’t allow this to express there and then the problem goes even deeper, in the pancreas.
In the older times we used to have acute rheumatic fever as epidemics.
Now many of such cases would end up with a cardiac problem.
The mitral valve was usually collapsing, was eaten up.
Mitral valve, problem after acute rheumatic fever. After suppression.
If this was cured there would be no problem.
But if it was suppressed the inflammation went from the joints to the heart.
And they don’t realize. They know a cardiac condition after an acute rheumatic fever.
They know because everybody understands that this is so.
The patient knows, the doctor knows, they write it down.
But this is not taken into consideration. So when you treat a case like that
and it is successful you have to expect that at a certain point of the development
while the heart will be returning to normal,
then you will have inflammation coming back on the joints.
And if you don’t know the rules what will you do,
you will give again anti-rheumatic drugs and then back again to the heart.
I had such a case with a woman who was not allowed to have a child
because it’s very dangerous in such condition,
the cardiologists would not allow a woman to become pregnant
because it would press the heart and death can take place.
I had such a case many years ago, back in the 70’s.
A woman came with a heart problem and her doctor said she could not have a child.
She said I want to try Homeopathy to see if something can be done.
So one of my students was a cardiologist who was already a professor in the university.
He was an pathologist and cardiologist, 2 specialties, so I was teaching him Homeopathy
and it was in his first lessons and I sent the patient to him and said can you check the heart?
He said her mitral valve is destroyed. What do you expect? I mean at this case,
I understand you don’t realize how serious the problem is and
that is why you send me to check whether she is better and I can tell you,
this case cannot be better. It’s a valve which has been destroyed through the inflammation.
I said ok, don’t shout. I continued. 6 months later I sent her again.
She was feeling much better. Before examining her he said George, I told you.
Don’t send her to me because this condition doesn’t change. Finito.
I said please make a cardiogram, look and tell me. He looked, I told you she cannot have a child.
1,5 year of treatment, I sent her again.
He calls me, he says I want to tell you that I cannot tell her anymore not to have a child.
She can have a child. He couldn’t believe it.
The cardiogram was normal and she could have a child.
And she had a child, it must be now about 30-40 years old. She was 40.
– And the mitral valve was really better?– Yes, absolutely.
It grew again to the extent that is functional.
Why did this happen? Because the original inflammation from the rheumatic fever
was transferred to an inflammation in the heart which destroyed the valve.
In this condition there is not any more an inflammation with high fever,
it is a sub-acute inflammation which continues to destroy.
But the inflammation is there like in all active chronic conditions.
This is an idea which is new of course in medicine.
Which I have said many years ago with great restriction.
I said to the class, I will tell you something which maybe appear to you as far too much an idea;
that all chronic conditions are of sub-acute inflammatory nature. All.
As long as the inflammatory or the sub-inflammatory condition continues,
that means the chronic conditions are getting worse and worse,
there is a possibility for a cure, for a reverse.
If the organ on which the inflammation is, is totally destroyed,
then there is no more possibility.
But as long as the sub-acute inflammation is active,
there is a possibility that the inflammation will restore
if the defense mechanism is properly stimulated, the inflammation is there to restore,
not to destroy. The inflammation is not something you have to subdue.
The inflammation is the defense mechanism of the organism
which says this is the best way to fight this invader, this morbific agent. This is the best way.
I will bring an inflammation on whatever, on the lungs, on bronchi, tonsils etc.
Don’t push me because if you push me too much I will give up on that level
which is the tonsils and then the inflammation will go deeper into the bronchi and next time,
instead of a tonsillitis you will have a pharyngitis, a laryngitis, a bronchitis, pneumonia.
In the old times they used to say your tonsils have pus, put them out quickly
and they took out the tonsils almost in every child. They also took out my tonsils.
It was terrible, this is the defense of the organism and you take it away. It’s madness.
Then the inflammation comes deeper
and deeper and there is a time where the organism cannot produce anymore high fever.
It is like an organism which is very tired and cannot really react
but still is going on but in a much lower pace, instead of running and fighting,
it tries to survive. This is the condition of a chronic situation.
But as long as there is a process there is a possibility for a cure.
This is a wonderful thing which is not understood in medicine unfortunately.
Anybody wants to ask a question?– About Stram.
that you advised, I learned that the patient can’t stay in the darkness,
that is afraid of animals, of water, but when she was interviewed,
she didn’t say she cannot stay in a dark place or is afraid of water.
– Yes. That’s correct. I said this is the beginning.
If you let her for another 6 months without a medicine she will go into the states
where she will have more aggressiveness, more fears
and most probably will have the pubic hair developing so fast… But it is the beginning,
it’s like before a full case is developed in any condition.
There is a process, a picture is developing more and more fully.
Now she has not a full picture of Stram. as I said.
But as it reminds me of the beginning that she had a full picture during that time
and as I feel that because of the hormones she returns back to the original disturbance,
she is going to develop the same picture.
It is like giving the correct remedy with the beginning of the symptoms.
To prevent from the full picture. Very good.
– I want to ask the father the name of the allopathic drug she took.
– The name is Enantone.
– And what is the allopathic mechanism of action? It stops the process of producing estrogens.
– But in this case if the estrogens are blocked why she develops now the same symptoms
like in the past when the estrogens were increased?– The estrogens are suppressed now.
We took blood and they are suppressed now.
– The estrogens are suppressed
because the full picture of the original condition was not developed.
The idea that the hormones will block the estrogens works in the beginning
but now through homeopathic treatment we made this organism normal,
so we have now a normal organism; last year for instance September, October the organism,
as far as hormones are concerned, was normal.
We take a normal organism and we inject with hormones blocking the estrogens.
What happens; in a healthy organism we inject some strong powerful hormones without any reason.
The organism will react but you don’t know how.
Is it going to block further, is he going to react the opposite way? This is what happened.
– Is she actually proving the injections? – She is proving the injections
but she is not only proving because proving is not so deep disturbance.
Here we have a clear deep disturbance right now.
It is very deep disturbance it brings back the whole syndrome without any reason.
Because of a protocol.
And it’s so obvious that if they had stopped already last year
when the professor who checked said it’s ok now, I don’t think she has to take anymore,
if he had stopped the hormones the child would be normal now.
– Another question. Will she develop this Stram.
picture later in the future maybe or not?
If this professor would give up the injections is there a possibility she will develop a Stram.
picture in the future?- It is possible that after giving Stram.
and then she calms down and becomes again friendly with the mother etc.
but if they continue to give injections most probably there will be a relapse.
And she will develop again the aggression and all this syndrome.
– It amazes me that in spite of the hormones the remedy acted so well.
But in other cases we must say stop, don’t take allopathic drugs
because the remedy will not work. I don’t see the difference between these cases.
– Yes, that is true but there is a difference here.
First of all when they brought to me the case I said...
I don’t remember the analysis, that was 4 years ago.
Maybe in the analysis I was not so sure that we could cure such a case.
The second thing which is related to your question is that hormones usually
are not as bad as chemical drugs. Because hormones are natural products of the human body.
In a case where you have a thyroid problem and you replace with thyroxin,
then you may still prescribe homeopathic remedy without reducing,
and the homeopathic remedy will act.
So under hormonal treatment is easier for a homeopathic remedy to act.
– Don’t you think that what you call regression
can be due to the approximation of the real puberty of the girl?
Her mother had a puberty at 10.– Good question.
I would consider it as approximation if she did not come back with the psychological state.
The psychological state, the aggression in normal puberty wouldn’t be there.
In a normal puberty also you will not have the increase of the female hormones
to such an extent that she will become again the antagonist of her mother.
All these things give me the impression that she is in a relapse
which is pathological and not a normal puberty. Later on, after Stram.
she may go into a normal menses condition but with a totally different psychological state.
Her psychology will be like a 12 year-old child, normal.
At this moment the aggression with the mother and the antagonism
and also the rage which is coming back again; there is definitely a regression.
– Right now she is reacting to the hormonal treatment that she is getting.
So that’s the allopathic intervention but will she stop reacting at some point and go deeper?
Do you think if it continues?
– It is going to be a terrible situation.
It’s already quite deep. The situation is quite deep.
If that situation becomes deeper God knows what is going to manifest as the next pathology!
– I just want to ask which potency Stram. and in which condition?
Once a month? Only one time?– Only one time, 200C. And we will see.
And repeat in case she gets better but then again there is a kind of relapse to the rage state.
Thank you!