She is a 13 year-old girl with recurrent epileptic fits.
- The attacks started focalized only in the face and over the years they have developed
to full blown grand mal epileptic fits.
She has not taken any anticonvulsive medication yet. No allopathic medication.
The first diagnosis was a Rolandic epilepsy, in 2011,
they altered the diagnose to a primary focal and secondary generalized epilepsy.
In 2009 the attacks started with a distortion of the muscles with clenching of the jaw,
twitching of the eyelids. Clenching, she could not speak,
she could not move the lower jaw.
– This is how it started and then developed into convulsions?
– Over the years it developed more and more into convulsions.
– Now, when she has convulsions she first starts with clenching?
– Nowadays it starts differently. When it starts today she becomes altered in her mood,
she becomes withdrawn, she starts developing a staring gaze with enlarged pupils
and this lasts for days so that the mother knows something is coming.
– How long after that starts the convulsion?
– Sometimes there is no convulsion, sometimes it takes only a few minutes
and sometimes it takes days until the convulsion comes.
What is very prominent nowadays is that she has an abdominal aura,
she has an odd sensation in the abdomen,
wandering pains in the abdomen before the convulsion.
The mother just said the very last attack she had,
she had very severe abdominal pains before, so severe that she had to scream
and then she had the fit which immediately eradicated the abdominal pain.
– Mention all the remedies that you have given so far.
– The first remedy was in May 2009, Ignatia.
There were problems in the marriage of the parents.
The child was sad and was sighing a lot.
The sigh went away but the localized distortions remained. She is a very sensitive child,
sensitive to what others say about her, sensitive to rudeness, sensitive to quarrels,
starts biting her nails and the skin around the nails. She had a desire for cold milk.
Then I give Carcinosin 1M, no effect.
In October 2009 she had the next focal fit
in addition this time the head was drawn backwards,
the pupils were dilated before and during the fits, her teeth were grinding during sleep,
so I prescribed Stramonium 200C, no effect.
In the same month she had another 2 focal fits,
she had a great desire for company, needed to be magnetized
and cuddled wanted to sleep in the bed of her parents and had fear of thunderstorms,
I gave Phosphorus 200. After this remedy she developed her first wart on her right hand.
In December 2009 3 strong focal fits. She received Belladonna 200C.
In January 2010 she had the first epileptic fit where she fell.
The day before she had had an adjustment of her cervical spine.
The day before the large attack she had an adjustment of the cervical spine
because she had had an injury of her spine in the year before in May.
She was very sad at that time, she was sighing a lot
and also was sad because her schoolmates witnessed this epileptic fit where she fell.
I gave Ignatia Q3 in a daily basis, no effect.
In February 2010 she had another seizure of falling.
This time we could observe a chewing motion of the jaw. I gave Helleborus 200C.
After this dose I lost contact with her for the next 2 years.
For these 2 years she had received homeopathic remedies
from someone else alternating Zincum, Cuprum, Silica…
- Alternating means in the morning this remedy, in the evening that remedy…?
– Even at the same time. Even all 3 together.
– I would like to know all the remedies.
– Silica as Schόssler salt, Cuprum metallicum 200X, Zincum (iso)valerianicum 30X,
then again Cuprum, Zincum, Stramonium when indicated,
Bufo 6X, Ignatia XM, Arnica, Bufo 6X… that was it.
In December 2011 the patient came because of persistent abdominal pains.
In the meantime the generalized attacks came every 3 weeks.
During the abdominal pains she was restless, had an amelioration from warmth,
had thirst for small quantities, teeth grinding during sleep,
desire for company so I prescribed Arsenicum 200C
with a temporary relief of the abdominal symptomatology, no effect on the seizure.
– At this moment she already has her menses?
– No. The first menstruation was in December 2013.
– From there on is her menses normal?
– You wanted to know if in December 2011 she already had her menstruation…
- No, if she has now normal menstrual period.
– It’s not that regular yet, overall it comes approximately every 4 weeks
but the bleeding itself is not stable. Sometimes she has bleeding for 1 day then it stops,
then she has 2 more days.
– Usually has interrupted menses?
– Up to now, yes, this was the case.
– The color of the blood changes also?
– It’s red and sometimes brown. The patient says it gets brown towards the end
but the mother remembers that in the last menstruation was brown in the beginning.
– More or less the color is steady.
– Yes.
- Ok, continue.
– In January new cramping pains in the abdomen with nausea,
this is when this odd feeling in the abdomen began which she cannot describe very well.
–Is it checked if there are worms in the stool? She has never been aware of such a thing? Itching in the rectum?
– No. After this abdominal aura she develops a tension in the lower jaw
then she makes a short sound, the extremities are twitching and jerking
and from time to time the thumbs are drawn inward.
In the attack her face is first pale and then it turns bluish
after a few minutes the attack ends with a deep breath
and afterwards she is either sleepy or sometimes also confused.
She received Cuprum 200C and 5 week later in March she had a similar attack
with the same symptoms and we gave her Cuprum Q3 daily.
In the end of March I prescribed Hydrocyanic acid Q3 daily
because of the terrible nausea before the attack. No change.
In April she developed warts close to her fingernails.
Complained of an electric-like pain in her head, or like a lightning pain.
– For the first time?
– Yes. Due to the periodicity and her irritability
and moles I prescribe Sepia Q3. The attacks remained unchanged,
the aggression even increased and due to this and the abdominal cramps
I prescribed Nux vomica Q3 afterwards the irritability got a bit better,
the attacks remained unchanged. She continues to be afraid alone,
has a desire for company, wants to be magnetized, is afraid in the dark,
still grinds her teeth in sleep.
– Fear of the dark when was it developed eventually?
– It was there before too and she had a desire for cold milk
and the mother has asthma in her medical history
so child received Tuberculinum 200C and 1M.
– There is a history in the parents or grandparents of epilepsy?
– Not that we know of.
– How old she was when she had the child?
– 21.
– Was it the first time she was having sex with the husband?
– The husband was not the first man.
My first boyfriend separated from me when I was 18. 6 months later I developed asthma.
Later I got to know my present-day husband
and after 3 years we were together I got pregnant and then we moved in together
in a common apartment and then I lost my asthma and then it never came back.
Either because I moved out from my mother or maybe it went on to her, I don’t know.
– But after her first contact with the first man she had any cystitis or vaginitis?
– Cystitis and vaginal mycosis I’ve had frequently until not too long ago.
– But when it started? After the first contact with the first man?
– I think only with my husband, not with my first boyfriend,
I think it only started after I met my husband
but as a child I had frequent cystitis with pain.
And she adds; in general no abdominal problems
but her mother had severe abdominal problems all her life
and actually the doctors told her mother that she would never have children,
so the mother of the patient and her sister are miracle children, they were not expected.
She never had a regular menstruation. Not she, her mother.
She, herself, never had problems but her mother always had problems.
– Sophia has a boyfriend?
– No.
– Is she interested in any boy? Before menses she has pains?
– Stitching in the abdomen like right now. In July 2012 she received Kali bromatum
because of her aggressiveness constantly playing with hands,
fingers and cracking her knuckles and the students in her class
were shunning her more and more due to her disease.
– Inside the class has she ever had any attacks? Have you seen the attack?
– Mother has.
– Can you describe the attack how it is now.
– Can I also demonstrate it?
– Yes. Wait.
– It starts with a frightened expression in her eyes
and starting jerking in the face with a wide open mouth.
– Her distortions in the face are somehow scary?
– For me it looks as if she is scared. Wide open eyes and mouth.
– But for one that looks at her is it very aggressive distortion?
– Not aggressive kind of distortion. The face of the child is as if she had a great fright.
– The idea is that the voice comes by inhaling? Not exhale.
– Let me recapitulate to get it right.
– When she demonstrated it it was very clear that the voice was coming inspiring the air.
– It’s true. When I demonstrated it, that’s what I did.
But if I think about it, it’s an exhaling cry.
Let me say a few things she added verbally to the attack,
when she described the fit she said for once she turns blue
and secondly when she collapses a while she still trembles
but then her breathing completely stops. And then she goes limp.
And then after a while there is one deep breath and after that deep breath she goes limp,
is unconscious in this time and only after a while the regular breathing
starts to set in on its own and then she is kind of confused, tries to get up,
moves around with her arms and the mother keeps telling her stay down
and then afterwards she falls into a deep sleep.
And if she cannot have this deep sleep then she would develop severe headaches.
– What does she feel during the headache?
– When I have the headaches I actually would like to get up
but I know it is better for me if I sleep then but I don’t want to sleep.
At home she sleeps but if it happens in school
or if they are at the campfire she always tries to get up. It’s a great desire to get up.
– But still she doesn’t describe her feelings during the headache…
- The pain is on both sides of the head and if I bend forward or if I move
or if I bump into something or if the head is jarred
it increases the pain even more than before and it feels like a great pressure.
– But the pain is stitching, throbbing, tearing…?
– She doesn’t know how to describe it,
the only thing she can say is that it is not pulsating but it is an ongoing pain.
– Is she a good student or medium?
– I think actually she is a good student if she studies, unfortunately she is a bit lazy
but she is a very gifted, talented and intelligent child and she grasps things very quickly.
The doctor says this is what you believe…
Immediately after Kali bromatum she had 2 large fits on the following 2 days.
She was contrary with her parents, she had extreme wide pupils,
saw things coming from her closet and fear of darkness
so I gave Stramonium on the 9th July 2012, no effect.
In August 2012 I prescribed Hyoscyamus 200C
because of her long-standing jealousy towards her 2 younger sisters
which has been there from the very beginning.
And shortly before that she also had her first epileptic fit where she lost urine.
Before the attack she also complained of pain in her ears with alternating sides.
In September she developed a new wart close to her fingernails.
With the next epileptic fit she had the head drawn backwards very strongly
and complained of pain in her neck afterwards
plus she had a very strong abdominal aura with strong pain and sensations and nausea.
And she also had the staring gaze so I gave Cicuta 200C.
After Cicuta she had very strong nausea and these odd sensations in her abdomen
and had to stay at home for days. I think it was an entire week she could not go to school
because of that. Then she was afraid that she would have an attack again at school
with everybody witnessing it. The attack she expected came in October
and then she received Oenanthe crocata in 30C daily for one week.
2,5 months after that she had no attacks.
In January 2013 she had 3 epileptic fits with loss of urine.
Plus a new additional wart close to her nails, so I gave Causticum 30C.
2 months later she was in a car accident with her grandmother,
she had a strong shock and complained for pain on her neck, otherwise no injuries,
she received Aconite 30C once, 10 days later she had severe angina tonsillaris,
no fever which was better by warm drinks, worse after midnight
and thirst for small quantities, Arsenicum 30C ameliorated these complains quickly,
afterwards one dose of Causticum 30C because she had a new wart on her finger.
2 days after Causticum she had 3 epileptic fits in 2 days.
In these 3 epileptic fits she developed a new symptom
which was that milk aggravated her abdominal pains.
Before she had always liked to drink milk, now symptom;
the abdominal pain gets worse after milk. In addition the thumbs were drawn in,
the pupils were wide, her sleep was very deep and long after the convulsion.
I gave Aethusa 200C. In May 2013 she had a great grief,
there was a horse she was caring for and she was not allowed to care for it any more,
she was withdrawn, she did not talk about her grief, had abdominal pains
and recently developed herpes labialis, so I prescribed Natrum muriaticum 30C.
In the middle of the month she had 3 grand mal fits one after the other
and I prescribed Natrum muriaticum 1M. In June, another attack in the same way.
In this month she developed a new symptom, which was strong desire for eggs,
fried eggs and soft and had strong perspiration
and so I prescribed Calcarea carbonica 30C daily. In June she had another grief
because a girlfriend rejected her, just stopped all contact, ignored her completely.
She had another attack with a very long phase of not breathing
which scared the mother greatly and I gave her Ignatia XM.
The Ignatia did not bring about any change concerning the kind of attacks
or the frequency but then the mother told me of an incident that had happened
which was invaluable. At this time the mother told me about an incident
which had happened in 2008. At the time that was before the attacks started.
At that time the child came running after her mother, saying
“Mommy the boys locked us into basement and we couldn’t get out”
and she had a great scared expression on her face and she was talking very fast
and the mother tried to calm her down and said, well, come on, slow down
and tell me about it and stay here. She didn’t let herself calm down
because she wanted to go right back down and play.
She didn’t want to stay with the mother and so the mother thought,
well it can’t have been that bad if she wants to go back down again.
But after this, a few days later her voice dropped, the tone of her voice became lower,
that was noticeable. It was very odd.
– Was there a second fright perhaps? She noticed her parents fighting?
– Well, there was a situation between my husband
and me which might have scared her but that was already in autumn of 2006,
maybe, 2 years before she had the attacks.
But 1 year before attacks started lots of things happened in our family.
Her parents are divorced. The wife second wife of her father died of cancer,
in the same month I gave birth to my 3rd child, which is her sister.
And in the very same month the brother of my father had an accident
which made him fall into coma, he died 6 months later.
– Ask the child directly if she remembers all these. She does not remember.
How old was she?
– She had just turned 7.
– But she does not remember all these.
– Well I can vaguely remember that this happened but I have no idea how I felt.
– Does she remember she was locked down by the boys?
– A little bit but I don’t know who it was.
– If the mother can describe her reactions, what would she say?
How she reacts in the ordinary life? Is she very calm, very angry, very anxious…?
– On the one side if something really affects her or hurts her feeling
she withdraws into her room and does not talk.
– The first reaction is withdraw.
– That’s the one side.
On the other hand she really knows what she wants and if there is something she wants
and she cannot get it, she can become very clear, demanding, even aggressive
and wants with all her mind to get it. And she manages to get it,
even if she doesn’t get it from me. She gets it from the neighbor or somebody.
– Is she eating fruits?
– I only like certain fruit.
– Does she like unripe fruits or ripe fruits?
– Sweet. Ripe and soft.
– How does she sleep? Which position?
– Often on my left shoulder, sometimes on my right shoulder, I hardly ever lay straight.
When I wake up in the morning it’s mostly on my back.
– If she takes a bath in the sea, how does she feel? She likes the bath?
– I like it but I prefer a sand beach because sometimes I am still afraid of the fish
and I don’t really like the stones that much. The pebble beaches.
But the mother says she is in the water all the time.
– She is not afraid she might have a fit during swimming?
– If I have the sensation there might be one coming, I don’t go into the water.
– Ok, then you gave Opium 200C and repeated Opium and then Pulsatilla…
- Because of strong headaches which were ameliorated from cold applications.
She was crying from pain. Pulsatilla helped very quickly.
Afterwards she developed a new wart. One week later she presented with gastroenteritis,
strong aggravation from everything that was fat. I repeated Pulsatilla.
- Is her stool normal or is diarrheic? Soft or hard?
– It’s not too hard and not too soft and I asked whether it is formed
and it is soft and formed.
– Wart in index finger, you gave Thuja.
– In the end of December 2013 she had her first menstruation.
– And she was actually 12 years old. A difficult case.
– The pressure is increasing also from the side of the school authorities.
That’s an easy case again. All the good remedies have been given. There is nothing left.
What shall we do. Is the mother a student?
No. Is there anybody who wants to ask a further question I did not ask?
She wants to ask. Ok.
- I would like to ask if the girl is going in her room alone early in the evening
and stays alone there. Probably masturbating.
– Once she is in grief.
– Probably masturbating, this is the question.
– Whether Bufo has been given. Has everybody understood what she asks?
Yes, everyone except of me. Very good.
She was asking for the remedy Bufo and she is correct. She looks like Bufo, right?
But the girl is quite clever actually;
I did not except that she would give answers of that type.
She is not the Bufo type though she looks like. That look is different.
I can explain to you why she has this but it’s not proper for me to do that.
– About her character; is she dictatorial? I mean why have some of her friends left her?
Is it like she wants to dominate?
– You want to give her Lycopodium?
- No, I just want to know for what reason they have left her
because she is very strong and her mother says if she wants something she will take it.
And why her friends want to leave her?
– If she is dictatorial what would you give?
– I just put in my analysis dictatorial…
- Put it and tell me. If you put dictatorial what is the remedy?
– There are many of course…
- Lycopodium. I saw it.
– Generally she is a quite sweet and shy type of girl.
Only before she is getting to have a fit she is getting to be more demanding
but I wouldn’t say dictatorial and concerning the friendships that are sort of dissolving,
this is girl is 11, 12, 13 years old and she is having fits
and the other girls are pointing with the finger to her, saying “look! She is having fits!”
This looks horrible.
– That’s correct. She is in a very difficult situation
because they have not given any antiepileptic drug so far,
therefore during school time she was having fits and everybody was looking,
so it’s a very difficult situation emotionally and the girl is quite sensitive
because you see, when she is insulted,
when she is in grief she withdraws, she goes inside.
That’s why they gave several times Ignatia but it is very interesting in the analysis,
I will tell you a few things. Very interesting points in her case,
very interesting points to understand what has happened.
So this class will end up having more silence than talking.
These cases are so difficult, we have to put together.
– I found very remarkable that the mother was telling about this incident in the basement.
At that time the girl was 8 years old, she can’t remember.
I think this is really remarkable
and I really wonder what really happened down in that basement
because shortly after this incident the focal fits started.
What really happened in the basement and what did this incident do to the body
and especially to her nervous system.
– Your observation is correct, I was also was wondering why she cannot remember.
She has pushed it into the subconscious, something was taking place there
and most probably, everybody knows what was taking place
but nobody will speak about it. What do I mean?
You agree but if I ask you, you have to know what happened.
– I would be interested in the following question.
Hahnemann says stronger illness pushes away weaker illness
but she is developing warts, gastroenteritis and angina.
Is this a try of the organism to get rid of this illness
or is it just that they accidentally come in addition?
– Definitely the manifestation of warts is an effort of the organism
but this is not enough because it’s not pushed by the right remedy.
All these remedies have been given according to the symptoms
and are good prescriptions but still they are the wrong prescriptions.
They did not bring about a curative action,
the organism is still trying to get rid of the problem but cannot,
so we’ll see what really happens in the afternoon.
One more question. My voice has not stopped.
– The father was really seemed having affairs.
– Does she know? The woman told you?
It’s not something you know. She already knows.
– In 2009 they had a crisis in the marriage and they were close to divorce.
And at that time her husband was studying in Vienna and was having several girlfriends.
– He was having several at the same time, together…
- Well at least not only his wife, to put it this way.
– That is quite possible that the father had gonorrhea,
because they married she starts having vaginitis,
she starts having leucorrhea, she has itching.
He has given her an infection of a gonorrheal type.
There is no question about that but also this confirms,
because a man who has so much sexual desire has to run, he runs there,
that means one time he will get it definitely. Because at a certain moment,
when there is no real partner, he will go to a prostitute or to find easy sex and then,
that is the time they get it. So he was having gonorrhea
and gave to her before their marriage and then she was born
and then we will give Medorrhinum. Who agrees with Medorrhinum? Only 2, 3, 4, 5, 6…
Not enough votes for Medorrhinum. This is a very interesting case for me
because it is a big challenge. I will explain why.
From what you perceive from my talking to you now
do you think I know the solution of this case or I don’t? Who says I know?
From my talking you understand I know. I think I know. That’s different.
That is true. But we will see the effect.
I want to make a statement in the beginning.
As you have seen the case was going from bad to worse,
within 4-5 years progressed to the point that…
what scared me a little bit was the fact that the mother said lately she had an attack
which was not coming back and this epileptic fit scared the mother. Do you remember?
Did I understand it well or not? It will appear that perhaps the homeopathic remedies
were actually pushing the disease deeper and deeper. Correct? Correct. This is not so.
The actual and the usual progress of an epileptic person is exactly that;
if you let it without medicine epilepsy has the characteristic
of becoming worse and worse year after year. This is the normal.
What you do not see perhaps is that they don’t have fits
because they get antiepileptic drugs,
but if it is left alone like in this case the normal progress of an epilepsy case is like that.
So they start with one grand mal in 6 months, then it comes in 3 months,
then a month and then once a week and then several times a day.
I would accept the remedies were not correct.
But that does not mean, as many of you thought,
that the homeopathic remedy pushed the disease deeper and deeper.
Simply did not do anything if not helped in certain cases. It might have been worse.
I was told that by Mr. Hahnemann this afternoon.
He says tell them that because they will think that my method is suppressing.
I told him ok I will have this in mind, I will tell them. So my mission is accomplished.
Now we go to the actual facts.
The remedies that were prescribed were quite to the point.
That means the one who prescribed except of the mixtures, he had some good idea of the Materia Medica.
If we go to the causative factor, what caused the beginning of the problem.
If there was a hereditary predisposition you could say mother,
father or grandparents had epilepsy so she had a predisposition.
She did not seem to have a predisposition.
She seemed to have a weak nervous system that was very much disturbed by several factors, I believe.
What are these factors? The fact that the girl got such a fright on the first
when she went back to her mother trembling in a terrified condition, something happened to her,
nobody know she cannot remember, therefore the trauma must have been quite deep.
Because children will bury the trauma, they don’t like to remember.
This was the first shock and most probably there was a further shock in the family
where there must have been some conflicts between man and woman and most probably the child
felt she is going to lose the parents. That’s another fright.
So ailments from fright is one symptom that you can use.
You will say why you thought this way and why we cannot think the same way as you.
I will ask you this; what was the most peculiar symptom for her that strikes you. She has raised her hand.
– For me it was that it starts with a terrible pain in the abdomen and also bending backwards
which point to one remedy.
– What she says is correct.
The most peculiar thing that was coming again and again it was a connection between the abdominal upset,
pain as a precursor of the attack. For one moment during the prescription this symptom started going away
but fortunately it came back that was the key to the solving of the case. Why was it the key to the solving of the case?
I will show you now. If you go to that symptom that Ilana had pointed what you would have seen… show them.
The aura of an epileptic fit comes from the abdomen and it says Indigo.
As soon as you see this remedy you should immediately go to the Materia Medica to see what this Indigo is doing.
– But there is another rubric; abdomen, epilepsy, begins in and there is only Bufo here.
– Stupid! Put this. Wait. Abdomen… your Bufo is coming back.
She was thinking of Bufo. Abdomen, epilepsy, begins. Also mydriasis
– Epilepsy before. Eye, pupils, mydriasis, before are also 2 remedies Argentum nitricum and Bufo.
– Also the excitement from the fright.
– That’s correct. Show that. And has given Bufo. Who prescribed Bufo?
–It was 2 years ago.
- It was a mixture. Very low potency.
Now, go to the Materia Medica, this is the process;
you notice this, you go to the Materia Medica. We show the Materia Medica of Indigo. Materia Medica;
marked action on the nervous system and of undoubted benefit in the treatment of epilepsy with great sadness.
Excited mood and desire to be busy. Neurasthenia and hysteria. Blue color. Stricture of esophagus.
Vertigo with nausea. She mentioned nausea again and again.
Convulsions. Sensation of a band around the forehead.
I was trying to see because there is a peculiar symptom where the person feels that may have water in the head,
so I was asking to see whether she would give me, I didn’t want to ask a direct question but she could not say.
She said that she felt her head frozen. Ears; Pressure and roaring. Excessive sneezing and epistaxis.
She had epistaxis? No. Metallic taste. Eructations. Bloating. Anorexia. Rectum; Falling of rectum.
Aroused at night with horrible itching at anus.
Constant desire to urinate. Urine turbid. Catarrh of bladder. Hysterical symptoms where pain predominates.
Excessive nervous irritation. Epilepsy; flashes of heat from abdomen to head; fit begins with dizziness.
Aura from a painful spot between shoulders. Aggravation during rest and sitting and this remedy is better,
she has the feeling that if they get up and move they will feel better.
So at a certain moment she said when I have the headache my inclination is to get up.
But then logically I say it is better to stay here but I want to get up and move.
So we don’t have enough information about that remedy… Let’s go back to Bufo. Show me Bufo.
Acts on the nervous system and skin. Uterine symptoms marked. Lymphangitis of septic origin.
Arouses the lowest passions. Causes a desire for intoxicating drink, and produces impotence.
Of use in feeble-minded children. Prematurely senile. Epileptic symptoms.
Convulsive seizures occur during sleep at night. More or less connected with derangements of the sexual sphere,
seem to come within the range of this remedy. Injuries to fingers; pain runs in streaks up the arms.
Anxious about health. Sad, restless. Propensity to bite.
Howling; impatient; nervous; imbecile. I try to find out about her sexuality. It’s a very sensitive issue.
The mother was there, the girl is 13. Are you masturbating, I could not ask these things.
So I wanted to get information and in an indirect way. So what did I ask; are you interested in boys?
Do you have a boyfriend? No. Are you interested in any boy? Yes.
That means in her fantasy, she fantasizes something. I don’t know what she fantasizes and I could not go any further.
But then if you remember I asked what class she was and if she is good at school.
For this reason; to differentiate. To see her mental condition. She said she is a medium student.
And then the mother started saying something and I whispered almost what she was going to say,
she was going to say that she is not studying properly so if you listen to the video carefully you will see me telling
before the mother what the mother was going to say because I saw the IQ of the girl was not for Bufo state.
She is a hysterical girl. You see the make-up of the girl; it’s a hysterical girl who wants to get whatever she wants…
But she is not… You see Bufo… She has some thicker lips and keeps the mouth open but Bufo
brings the tongue out much more obviously. The real state of Bufo is one of constant pleasure of the lowest type.
Do you know that there are pleasure of higher order and then middle order and low order?
So Bufo is on a constant pleasure on the lower side.
Seeing the symptoms we say he seeks solitude to practice masturbation.
He seeks solitude he wants to be by himself and enjoy. But that pleasure is all the time.
That means the hormones are in such condition that they arouse the lowest feelings and sensations of the human.
So, she did not give me this idea. Also the fact that Bufo was given before and brought about no change
though I investigated I was not happy with the prescription.
Therefore the description of Indigo is much more fitting
her personality, a hysterical girl with fears, with tendency to get frightened,
frightened she may lose her parents, because the boys did whatever they did to her etc.
This shows an excitable person, nervously, which is afraid, which has a tendency to get a fright quite easily.
Therefore the description, what I saw in Indigo, fits more than Bufo.
Now you may say Indigo is going to cure the child?
No. But it is going to reduce the epileptic fits quite substantially
and most probably the next remedy that will be needed will be… Medorrhinum.
The next remedy that she will need will be Medorrhinum,
but when I investigated whether Medorrhinum is at this moment indicated,
I did not see any of the keynotes of Medorrhinum. Therefore it’s not the time to give Medorrhinum now.
Though it is an epileptic condition which is primarily guided by the fact that she has a sycotic miasm,
how do we know that? By the warts. The warts which come out show that there is a sycotic miasm,
that means infection from gonorrhea in the past, either the parents, or the person herself,
or even the grandparents can pass the predisposition to the children.
Therefore I would think Indigo will affect the case. Now which is the potency? This is a big question.
What is happening in an epileptic fit? Here is an inflammation of a certain area in the brain.
There is an inflammation and the inflammation every year becomes bigger and bigger
and the inflammation comes from time to time, it’s not all the time there.
But at this moment it has covered a big area of the brain because the fit remains quite strong and quite long.
The mother says, I was afraid she would not come back. So, we have an inflammation but it is quite deep in the brain,
we have some indications about a remedy… which potency?
Who will give 10M? 50M? CM? 1M? 200C? 30C? Majority. 12C?
I try to gather some more points for 12 you see. Somebody else maybe? 12X? 12C? Was it the first question?
The centesimal. 12X is the decimal. 1 over 10 is much lower. Well, 12X is my decision if not even lower,
repeated 3 times a day, every day for 1 month and the next month 13X, and the other month 14X for 2 -3 months,
in which time I believe it will start showing a reduction of the intensity and the frequency.
This is a very teaching case, in case the remedy acts. Why do I say that. Can anybody tell me?
You are homeopaths, you are looking on a case,
you have discovered a new remedy you never thought about and you have some points and you give it.
What is the benefit?
– I am thinking not only the benefit of the case
but our benefit to discover more symptoms for Indigo. If some proving symptoms will appear.
– But more specifically?
– She is not under allopathic drugs.
– She is pure it is a benefit.
But the real benefit that you would never imagine in your life to see
it was the performance of the mother who imitated the attack.
When you see it again you may happen to be in front of an epileptic fit and what you have seen,
stayed in your memory, will never go away. Because an epileptic fit has so many different types.
And you saw the imitation of the mother. This is something very interesting from her description.
I said did you inspire? She was inspiring making the noise? When she performed it was like taking a deep breath.
When the case was finishing, how did it finish? Like a deep breath again.
An epileptic fit starts with a deep breathing and ends in deep breathing.
If Indigo cures the case, then it becomes keynote for the remedy. See how you study the remedy.
What more? How much you learn. You have learned certain things in the medical schools.
All are mechanical things. Useful but mechanical. So what else you learn from this case?
It is very interesting that her problem is connected to lack of oxygen.
The brain is at a certain moment depleted of oxygen. Why do I say that?
– During the epileptic fit she has cyanotic lips and this is an expression that has a deficit of oxygen
and this is disturbing the brain. Damage is progressing with each epileptic fit.
– So what we learn further?
That Indigo affects the nerve which gives movement to the lungs, which is the vagus nerve.
Which is cramped. And the moment it is cramped, in a hysterical person,
you can understand the inner structure of the organism. What happens; there is a kind of a stricture,
a kind of a cramp on the vagus nerve and the lungs stop producing, giving out oxygen to the brain.
Then the brain says I am in danger and then either has to faint, fall down, or in this case, because there is a problem,
the person becomes unconscious. Why in fainting you become unconscious? Because you don’t have enough oxygen,
you faint unconscious so you don’t need so much, the brain can survive without the normal amount of oxygen.
Do you see how the pathology is connected according to my understanding?
This is how I understand and how I observe. I spoke last week in London.
They had a meeting in which all the famous homeopaths of today were going there to show solidarity.
So they asked me George please come to London, I said I cannot come to London and it’s very good
because most of them were my students.
I said it’s good for you that I will not be there so you can be free to express your crazy ideas.
Because if I am there you will feel a bit shy, timid. They pressed me to come, I said ok, what I will do,
I will send one of my lectures and after the lecture I will answer questions for half an hour.
They showed the lecture and then opened skype so I spoke to them.
I told them you must know that I love you very much because most of you are my students but
also you must know I do not agree with the crazy things you are doing. So now you put questions.
They put some questions which were not important. But some clever guy who was there,
said can you tell us how did you make your Materia Medica?
He thought if he told us the way then we can also make our Materia Medica.
So I told them what I just showed you in practice. This is how I made Materia Medica.
But now if I see a second case and has similar symptoms and I prescribe Indigo and is doing well,
then immediately the picture of Indigo becomes alive.
And this was the idea originally because people were saying we hear all symptoms,
we don’t hear something concrete and complete and alive.
So when I gave the Materia Medica everybody was excited because I have done these observations.
I don’t know if I have prescribed because they are thousands of cases but as far as I remember
I do not remember an epileptic case in which I prescribed Indigo. But this case now it is like a first case for me.
So I put this in my memory and I will have it as a model. If I see it again, repeat it, acts, the third time I am sure,
this is a case of Indigo. This is how I made Materia Medica. I gave you all the secrets.
So you do not have any excuse for not doing the same. Hyoscyamus is the first one.
You changed the symptomatology. Some more symptoms of Bufo. As far as I know the Bufo epilepsy,
it’s an epileptic fit which comes usually in connection with sleep, it comes during sleep,
it is quite convulsive, not what she showed me,
this trembling convulsion and after that deep sleep follows for quite sometime.
– I feel that you are not 100% satisfied with Indigo. Can I make another suggestion for another remedy?
– Yes, I would be very happy to hear it.
– I found some arguments for Artemisia.
– I have never prescribed Artemisia but...
- In the books it’s a good remedy…
So you want to see whether Artemisia has any of the symptoms. Can you find for me Artemisia?
Convulsions from fright, ailments from fright, eyes staring, bladder, urination, unvoluntary, convulsions,
during, face, lockjaw, extremities clenching, thumbs.
Not bad but still no effect because it does not take the main symptom which is
the abdominal aura from which starts the epileptic fit. That is going on again and again.
– But I have the symptom with Artemisia, it’s under stomach, I will look for it.
Stomach, convulsions, spasm, epileptic aura. There is Artemisia.
- It’s not in aura. It is an aura which starts from abdomen.
– But abdomen and stomach are not so far away.
– It is interesting also in Indigo that in the
pathology, in the Materia Medica, it says epileptic fits
from worms which is definitely an idea that the abdomen is involved…
- Epileptic fits from anger; Indigo…
- But the guiding symptom which brought us to the idea of Indigo was the connection between
the abdominal aura and the epileptic fits. That was all along the description.
After a certain time in the development of the case the abdomen was involved.
Pain preceded the epileptic fit. Somebody wants to talk.
– For me it was also striking that during all these
epileptic fits this symptom persisted. It was related to
abdomen. So what she said is that at the end of this
story she describes a feeling which wanders up and down,
sometimes more, sometimes less. Abdominal aura. So we have this kind of rubric; generalities; convulsions;
epileptic aura abdomen to head which, so Indigo is the only remedy that has this symptom.
– That is the idea.
The whole prescription is based on that particular strange, rare and peculiar symptom.
Only one remedy has this. That’s why I feel quite certain that the remedy is correct.
– Something more; without knowing anything about Indigo I just went as you said in Materia Medica and
then there is said these epileptic fits with great sadness. So it’s related to Ignatia,
there is the sadness and the cramps, it’s said they are even.
– Exactly.
And you remember the girl as soon as she felt a grief, it was deeply, inwardly sad.
– What I want to say is that Vithoulkas compass is excellent.
Without knowing a remedy you just put the striking symptoms and it will…
- Bring it up.
Compass is programmed according to my way of thinking of course.
That’s why with 2-3 symptoms the remedy comes up and shows it and you have to investigate. Says be careful.
– George, I would like to know how you estimate the chances of healing for this girl and
on which level of health you consider her to be.
– The level must be around 7-8.
If the remedy is correct there are chances of healing. Because later on we may have the possibility to give Ignatia
for her grief and we have the possibility also to give Medorrhinum because of her predisposition with sycotic miasm.
Ignatia was given frequently but did not act. Because in the uppermost layer there is another remedy.
Unless you give the uppermost layer remedy forget it.
The grief is there but upon it there is another layer and this is Indigo.
Unless you give it forget the cure. For 5 years he is struggling. Last question.
She is not sure she wants to ask a question but she will ask.
– I always of the girl in the basement what happened there and afterwards it started not much later and maybe
there was something of a sexual misuse…
- Maybe.
– But maybe all these things in her abdomen, we think they are strange but I think this...
- This is going a little bit too far… Epileptic fits from fright…
- It started with convulsions only in the face.
– She got a fright, that is enough for us.
And then started convulsions. Which are the main remedies for convulsions from fright?
– Calcarea carbonica, Hyoscyamus, Ignatia, Indigo and Opium.
The main remedies. Therefore this fright supports the idea of Indigo.