-Mainly grief and depression, confusion and forgetfulness, not being able to work.
-So much?
-For many years.
-Why? What happened?
-A long story.
Mostly the upbringing, the childhood but also when I was 13 years old I got much worse.
I suddenly got caries in my teeth and going to the dentist all the time
and all this amalgam and after that this confusion and trembling and always hungry.
-But you are not, you eat a lot but you are thin.
So you have no problem eating a lot.
-Not so much.
-What remedies you have taken?
-I don't remember.
In 1984 I took several remedies. A therapist that diagnoses from the tongue,
she was giving me so much remedies and she did not know about Homeopathy
and at that time I didn't know either.
So I had 13 remedies at the same time and repeated every day, whole boxes all together
and I don't really remember.
All different things and she said this is the way to give me minerals.
-So you had lack of minerals and she had lack of brains.
-It was also Silica and Nat mur. I mixed all together.
-Already 13 years ago.
How old are you now?
-41.
-So you were 28 when you started with this nonsense and at 30 years old
you went to deterioration.
-No, this started with this teeth problem at 13.
But not much happened after all these remedies and in 1986 I also got
several remedies at one time.
-Again from a similar person who diagnoses on what?
-No she was a homeopath.
-What remedies did you get?
-That time I don't remember but in 1989 I took Ignatia D200 and it was for every day
for a month.
-And also another crazy person gave me Mercurius D12 and I repeated every 30 min.
5 days, 2 boxes, every day.
-For 1 month or what?
-2 boxes.
-What it means?
-I can't remember, I was completely confused.
-And then?
-Then a homeopath in 1994 gave me Medorrhinum 200 and after he gave me
Carcinosin 1M and then Sulphur 1M. In may 1995 I got Aurum 1M,
I took Rhus tox 200 and Calc. carb. D200 and Arsenicum 200.
Now at first of April I took Phos D200.
-You prescribed yourself these remedies?
-No, some of them. The Phos and Arsen and Calc but I was in communication
with my homeopath.
-He agreed.
-Yes.
-But you say you gave up working? When did you give up working?
-I actually never started.
-Because of that confusion?
-Tiredness.
-What exactly do you feel?
-Tired, no energy. Grief and depression.
-Why grief? You have your parents, they are alive?
-Yes.
-They live together?
-Brothers, sisters?
-I have a younger brother yes.
-He is OK?
-Yes, he is fine.
-And did you go to school?
-Yes.
-Did you pass classes?
-Yes, amazingly.
I was looking out of the window and I was just daydreaming, I did not pay attention.
-What do you like to do mostly?
-I like to dance very much and sing.
-When you dance you feel good?
-I feel better yes.
-But not good.
-I used to do but these late years I got more tired and then I can not enjoy to dance
that much as I used to do.
So now I try to put myself together and force to do things, I'm not really enjoy that much.
-Emotionally how you are? Did you have an affair with a man?
-I have almost 18 years living together with a man.
-You are with this man?
-No, this relationship ended 7 years ago.
-That means you were together with him from the age of 19 to 36.
-Yes.
-Why it ended? What happened? You liked another man or you went with another man?
-He left but actually I wanted to leave him for many years because it was not good for me.
I wanted to end the relationship.
-Why?
-He suppressed me very much.
-By what? By shouting?
-Psychologically, he told me not to do this, not to go to these friends, he was very jealous
and he wanted me home.
-And you could not get away from this man because of your lack of self confidence?
-Yes and because he was begging me, he was so afraid that I leave.
-Finally you left him or you made him leave you?
-You can put it that way, when I told him that now this is final, I go,
then he changed completely his personality and then in a couple of days he found another woman
and then he left without much talking.
-Did you find another man?
-No.
-You didn't want.
-Not so much.
-You did not have this sexual drive or because you felt tired to be with somebody or you
had no desire for sex at all, no desire to get involved?
-Mostly I was scared of... he had been lying so much.
-To you or to anybody else?
-To many people. I suddenly realized that he has a psychopathic behavior
and I felt like my whole life had been a lie.
-So after these 7 years you never tried to have an affair?
-I tried.
-And you did not succeed?
-It was not the right person.
-Who was not the right person? The original one or the one you met after?
-No, I met another person and it is not the right person for me.
-After how long you found out?
-About a year after.
-So you had actually an affair with another man and another one also later on?
-It was a little earlier, just a short one.
-It was a short one and then this of 1 year, still you felt it was not the right person.
All these separations affected you?
-Sure.
-You cried or you were depressed?
-Of course after 18 years with this man it was terrible.
-You cried?
-Much.
-And did you tell your brother or your mother, did you discuss with anybody?
-Not much.
-You didn't want to or you didn't have the confidence?
-I did not have much communication with my parents, so I told them
only one and a half month afterwards this happened, so I tried to manage alone.
-Now you are living alone, not with your parents?
-Yes, not with my parents.
-And how do you support yourself since you don't work? You are on a pension?
-Yes.
-How is your memory? If you read something do you remember?
-Not very much. One day and I forget what I read the day before.
-Totally you forget?
-Yes and that makes the confidence low.
-And you are in this apartment in Oslo?
-Outside of Oslo.
-In the suburb.
You are not afraid staying by yourself?
-No.
-You like it actually, to be by yourself?
-Yes.
-Your sleep is good?
-No, that's one of the biggest problems because I never get refreshed at sleep.
-Unrefreshed always?
-Unrefreshed always.
When I get up in the morning is like a comatose. I need a couple of hours to just drink tea.
And my whole life I turn night to day and day to night, I switch.
-You stay in the night awake and then you sleep during the day.
-Yes.
-You cry easily?
-But you say you cry easily, you can cry?
-Yes definitely.
-When do you feel better? Do you feel better in the night? More awake?
-Yes, more awake and better in general.
-Do you have any discharge from the vagina like leucorrhea?
-Not much, seldom.
-Did you have discharge and you took some medicine for that?
-No. But I have had condylomata.
-And you cauterized them?
-Not took away but something very strong.
-Like podophylline, you put something on?
-Some liquid yes.
-And then they disappeared?
-Yes.
-Where? In the vagina?
-Not inside. Outside.
-Did you have warts on your fingers?
-Not on the fingers but under my foot I had a couple of warts and after Medorrhinum,
I think, they went away.
-It was on the sole underneath?
-Yes.
-Did you feel better with any of these medicines?
-Yes, I didn't actually finished.
After Phos I took recently and Phos did change much.
-To the better?
-I was little better with the depression but I got pneumonia, bronchitis,
after Phos these came.
-And how you treated this?
-My homeopath gave me Nat sulph and I repeated once and after repeating
I was very very depressed, suicidal.
That was 5 days before I come here and then I took Sulphur and then my lungs are better.
-Did you ever try to commit suicide really?
-I wanted once.
-What age?
-25.
-Why? Do you remember why?
-I was in a deep depression for 5 years.
-Because of this man?
-And also very much of my parents, no communication.
-Because you felt they don't love or you don't have the attention of them?
-I felt hatred.
-By them?
-By my mother.
-Your mother hated you because your father loved you or something like this?
-No, I don't think so.
-Your father also?
-My father was very influenced by my mother.
When she was so angry with me, he also got angry with me. He was worshipping her.
-And you felt that you worth nothing.
-Yes, I felt abused psychologically.
-You never reacted? You never said bad words, swearing at them or returning back their abuse?
-Sometimes.
-With your boyfriend did you fight back?
-Yes.
-Physically?
-No.
-Never physically. He was stronger than you?
So when he said something bad to you, you said also bad things for him?
-Yes sometimes.
-Who was saying more? It was always him who was saying the last word
and you had to shut up or he had to shut up because you were?
-No, it was very difficult to communicate with him because it was like talking to the wall.
He would just go and no reaction.
But I isolated myself very much because I'm so sensitive to the surroundings.
-In what way? You feel the emotions of others or the thoughts?
-Very often.
-You seem as if you want to cry now, is it true?
-Yes because this makes me feel so hopeless because it's the story of my life
and also I try not to look at newspapers and at news because all this suffering, I cannot take.
But I grew up with a mother who was very dictatorial and wanted to control me.
-And what you did?
-I tried to fight back.
-At what age you left home?
-18.
-Until that time did you take drugs with your friends? You tried marihuana?
-A little and then sniffing glue.
-And what were your experiences with these drugs? You had good experiences,
bad experiences or no experiences?
-Good.
-So you did it every day?
-Not every day, just for a short time.
-For a period of 1 year? When it was this time that you were?
-From 17-18 years old I tried some marihuana and this glue.
-LSD?
-No, cocaine but not much.
-Now you are totally out of this? Do you feel that these drugs have done some damage?
-Yes and I also I could not sleep so I was taking sleeping pills for 15 years
and also a lot of anti-depressive and a lot of alcohol mixed together.
But that was mostly 10 years ago.
-Now you don't take alcohol, not at all?
-I try not to.
-You take from time to time?
-If I take a little, I want more.
-What about marihuana? You take sometimes?
-No.
-Why? Are you afraid?
-Yes, I felt it was not good for my health, I get more and more tired.
-Do you ever have this feeling of getting crazy?
-Maybe. I like to be around people who are a bit crazy because then I can be more...
-You are going to panic states?
-No, resignation.
-Never mind, whatever might happen, will happen. Like this?
-It was like this but now even though I don't want to live, I feel I can't end my life, it's not
right. So it's like everything is a struggle, to get up in the morning, to come here is a
struggle. So I force myself very much to be able to do very small things.
-Do you like to eat sweets?
-Yes.
-What about salty things?
-I eat more salt now but before was not much. But now I drink more.
-You drink more after Phos?
-No, it was after Arsenicum I started drinking more and a little bit more salt.
-But always you liked sweets?
-Yes, I feel my blood sugar dropping and then I need something to take.
-What you feel is the first thing you would like to get rid of.
-I want more energy so I can work.
-But what about the mind? The mind you want to be more clear or you want
to have more confidence or you want the memory to come back or to remember things?
-The grief.
-You like fruits? You take?
-Not much.
Less and less and I think I can not. If I eat fruits, I feel uncomfortable,
I get more hungry from eating fruits.
-But you have to eat and feel better.
-Yes and I have to eat in the night also.
-For what? For the emptiness of the stomach or what, just out of boredom?
-No, for the emptiness and a sudden hunger, very sudden.
And sometimes if I don't eat I can faint.
-You have fainted sometimes, many times?
-Just a couple but I also had when I was 20 years I had anorexia and bulimia
and I took a lot of diuretica and then I fainted.
I had to control it and sit down so I didn't faint. So I took a lot of laxatives.
This is a long time ago but I still feel my digestive system disturbed.
-Show me your tongue. It's usually white?
-A little bit in the back maybe?
-In the sides?
-No.
But when I eat food I very often get my pulse rate very much and especially
like sugar or coffee, alcohol, tea makes the heart go fast and the pulse can go...
-You feel exhausted, you feel so tired?
-Yes.
-How is your sex drive?
You have sexual desire?
-Yes.
-Strong?
-No, medium I guess.
-How do you manage since you don't have a boyfriend?
-I did after this relationship, I had less sex drive.
-Which relationship made you feel worse? The first?
The grief was coming from this?
-Yes, yes.
-The second, the one year relationship also brought you grief?
-Not so much.
-You didn't care so much.
-We were more like friends.
I found out this was a friendship.
-Do you paint?
-I want to, I want to express but it's hard to express. It's like the creativity is very blocked.
-When you speak on your own language, do you sometimes forget words?
-The name of things yes. It feels terrible.
-As if the mind is blank.
-My head always feels very light, as if it is all empty, as if the brain is out there somewhere.
There was a time like I was meditating much and then I felt like leaving the body
and I looked at the watch and it was 5 hours and I thought that maybe 1 hour had gone.
-And you were on another level.
-Yes.
-Have you been taking drugs during that time?
-No.
-Meditating on what?
-I wanted to get closer to god.
-But you were meditating with the idea of coming out of your body?
You were doing repetition? What you were doing? Or you just sat down?
-I just sat down and listened to a music and then I go out in the nature
and I could feel being one with everything.
-When it was that?
-It was very much in the last 5-6 years with this long relationship, with this man.
He was like manipulating me, you hear this, I was like brainwashed from this.
-He was saying what to do. He was like a guru to you?
-Not a guru but he made me believe that he had some kind of contact and when ...
-And you wanted also the contact.
-Yes but there were times when I thought that this was not right and it's difficult to tell
but he suddenly changed very much after I wanted to leave him and I think
he went into schizophrenia I think.
But I have suppressed very much a lot of things because he always made me think that
everything was my fault, so I don't think much about it.
Once he tried to strangulate me and he made me feel this also was my fault.
-He tried to strangulate you and he said that it is your fault that he did that.
-Yes he made me feel that. So I don't even talk about it.
-You made him so angry to do it.
-He just reacted.
-During that time when he wanted to strangulate you, what did you do to him?
-He was scared by a sudden...
We were quarreling and I was angry and I throw away something,
not towards him and this broke into pieces and one piece he thought,
he just started because he thought it maybe could hit him but I throw it the other way.
And he reacted just like an animal, this is the first time all these years I saw him react
and that he wanted to kill.
And at that time somebody rang the bell, otherwise I could not breathe I could not talk, nothing.
-He meant it.
-Somebody came by chance, somebody that I haven't seen for 4 years, he never come
and then he came back to himself and he also told me that he didn't dare to be angry
because he didn't know what he could do.
But this I did not talk about, I thought this was my problem.
-When you had an affair with him, sexually you were very alive?
-Yes but he also wanted to control that, he wanted to control everything.
-The way you were doing sex or what?
-When.
-And, according to you, it was too little or too much?
-Several years he didn't want touch.
-And then he said that he got a message that he had to grow spiritually
and blah, blah, blah so he could not touch.
-So you did not have any contact for several years.
What you did, your sexual energy
what you were doing with it?
-I had a couple of affairs at that time.
-And he knew it?
-Yes I told him.
-And you were very active?
You needed to have sex every day 2-3 times?
-No.
-How much?
-It's changeable.
-You could have sex if you like this man,
you could have sex 3-4 times the day?
-No.
-Not so much.
If you did not have sex, did you have to masturbate?
-Sometimes yes.
-A lot?
-No.
-But you felt you had to release this energy or you did it out of boredom?
You do not know.
The first remedy which comes here in the repertorization is Platina and then it's Cocculus
and then Staphysagria and Nat mur.
You took Staphysagria?
-No.
-Platina, Cocculus? No.
-Did you put sighing?
-Yes, I feel I don't get enough air, never.
Sometimes I feel so tired that I have to think I have to breathe because I just want
to breathe out and disappear.
When I wake up in the morning I'm breathing very fast like if I've been running.
But I feel what has affected me most is my mother, the hatred, the feeling of abandonment
and forsaken feelings and all this, this is what's bothering me most.
What ameliorates very much is being with animals.
-You like especially dogs or cats or any animal?
-Any animal.
I also feel very much hurry inside and so much guilt and shame,
the guilt feeling is very strong.
-Guilt for what?
-Not working.
I feel that I should be more able to do much out of my life and I feel very much guilt
and shame, hopelessness and despair, all these.
-But which is the most disturbing feeling for you, the sadness, the depression or the fact
that you can not push yourself to do something.
-Yes but then many things, I want to work.
-To do something and you can not.
-Yes.
I'm always very cold.
-Very cold?
There is another thing that I really want to get help and that is osteoporosis.
-You have that also?
-And my back started to degenerate very early.
-Do you sometimes get a clairvoyant feeling? When you see something it's going to happen
for others or for yourself?
-Just a little bit, I had a couple of dreams that came true but also
that I can feel very much the vibrations.
-Tell me your emotions are alive or are tired like your body?
You have emotions?
-Yes I think so.
-Your emotions are quite strong? Mostly painful emotions?
-I can also be very accelerated, excited and accelerated.
-Do you have any fear?
-I had 2 car accidents and after that I'm a little afraid to drive motorbike or a car.
-Other fear? You used to have fears?
-From high places I used to have. I used to want to jump but now this is not so much.
-Other fears you used to have?
-No.
And there was something happening that gets me... I did not have fear of death
but something happened. 4 years ago that I was so much detached from the body
and I could not control, I could not come back.
-There was a time when you were out of the body and you could not come back
and then the fear came, fear of dying.
-Because usually I was seeing nice places, with nice color but this time it was just
black grayish and it was like nowhere. It was terrible and I could not move my body.
And after that I don't relax very good because I feel that the way I can balance
is to someway be in a day dream or being out of my body because it has been too painful...
-To be in the reality.
-Yes. But after this thing happened, I try to be more here,
in the present but it's very difficult.
-The other situation scared you very much? It was like a process of dying.
-Yes it was. I felt I really gone but at that time I made a decision because
I was longing for death and I was triggering and pushing it to the edge very much
and then I had this experience and I said, I'm gonna try, I want to live.
So it changed many things.
I also had another experience with this and it was like being with a group of people and
we were and somebody was taking us back to the time...
-The time of birth?
-The time in the womb.
-And what you experienced?
-The most terrifying, it was like torture because I could not be in there and she put on
a record of how the child can hear and the heartbeat of the mother and this was unbearable.
-She was a psychologist, a therapist?
-A therapist and all the other people had just nice experiences and I was crying, crying
and I said to myself, I was hiding underneath the blanket, I tried not to disturb the others
I said I have to go through this but then I leave my body there. Then I also had that out of
body experience because this heartbeat was unbearable.
-Did you feel that your mother had bad feelings?
-Yes I told you, I feel this hatred from her so strong.
-Already from that period you mean.
-I had decided to take Ignatia or Nat mur to do something with the grief and then
at that night I dreamed, the whole sky was lightening Phosphorus, Phosphorus,
that I should take Phosphorus.
-So you took Phosphorus?
-Yes.
-You are not a simple case.
-I know.
-About this case I think that the initial cause of the problem is the hatred of the mother.
She repeats many times the mother etc. and it affected in very early age and after that
the stress is continuing to the relations with the boyfriend or husband
and is going on and on and she gets weaker and weaker.
-The stress is on emotional level where the organism has decided to place most of
the disturbance on the mental level, therefore is a confusion and weak, I can't work.
What is your worse problem? I can't work, I feel guilty but these are the side effects
of not being able to concentrate, not being able to think.
-Isn't possible that the mental level was so much affected because of the drugs?
Because very sensible people if they take drugs...
-Yes correct. Here the stress is not only emotional because she goes to different other
stresses and she takes the hallucinogenic drugs and what other stresses she has mentioned.
-Alcohol.
-Yes alcohol plus drugs.
-Remedies.
-Yes this is the worst, plus the remedies. Now all this came through the physical body.
The stress came from physical body but the physical body transferred the stress,
she didn't have a liver problem, she has a problem on the mental level.
The stress, alcohol and drugs is on the physical body but the final effect is on the mental
and then remedies which are beyond the mental.
Mental-emotional-physical and here is the vital force and the remedies affect here directly
and then the body distributes the disturbance.
And it goes like this, more, more, more it distributes in the way it can do the best.
So disturbance of the remedies is on the vital force.
-When she was 13 she received a lot of fillings with amalgam and she said after that
the confusion started.
-I'm not sure about that.
Don't forget, otherwise we will be confused, what we're discussing is mental-emotional.
I see 65% of the class says it's mental. Why is mental?
There is a possibility of the amalgam and she says, after amalgam I felt... alright
but there is a but and the but is that according to some people what they said is,
some disturbance has preceded the caries so therefore we can not attribute everything
to the amalgam. That's one.
The second is, which I would like to answer this question,
this person answering your questions he says, I did not see the problem on the mental level.
So why she was answering the questions?
Is this a mental disturbance we're going to treat or primarily...
If you remember I asked her, how are your emotions? Do you have emotions?
She says, I have. I said, they are quite alive? Quite alive.
Then don't forget that she is talking, as somebody says, she is talking for this inability
to concentrate from very young age. So this level is already affected from very young age.
She was not aware.
Most probably whatever emotional issues are here today, which she is clear,
my mother hates me, this issue is clear but she said, I had some suicidal thoughts
but what was happening my mind went out of my body, I went out of my body and in this
I realized certain things and I came back and I said, forget this issue of going out.
So the issue from very early age is the issue of not being able to concentrate,
a weak mind. These are facts which 65% of the class saw these facts, all right.
This is how you should go about trying to see whether you can help this person
by a remedy and what might be the indicated remedy.
Can anybody tell me why she answered my questions?
He says, well I can not see any mental problem with her or much less, I see more emotional.
Why? Because she has answered your questions. She was with you, understood your question
and answered to the best of her ability.
Can anybody from observing the video tell me why she was able to do that?
-It seemed to me during the consultation that she was desperate to get the right remedy
from you, you could see her eyes, she was pleading with you all the time.
-She was all there. Can she live with that intention all her life,
she can muster everything for 1 hour because it's a matter of life and death,
you see her eyes how intense they were.
That is mustering everything which is possible to understand the question and
answer the question as much as possible. Can you live in this condition?
Normally is you see her now she is not looking like that.
The next question that we're dealing is, whether this case is treatable, yes or no?
Can we treat this case or we shall leave this case free of any remedy for about a year
perhaps, to see what settles down in this case?
Before we answer this question, maybe you may say we must find out whether a remedy
is apparent in her case. If a remedy is apparent then we can give it. If it is clear we can
give it, no problem. Now in her case is a remedy apparent? Clear?
I mean you say, we don't have enough experience and therefore I have to answer
this question for you and say, no her case is not clear.
Her case is very confused from all points of view.
It is confused because of the hallucinogenic drugs? I don't know.
From alcohol? I don't know. From other remedies? I don't know.
From mental-emotional shocks? I don't know. From all of them?
Most probably, all of them have contributed in her state, all these stresses, mental,
emotional, physical stresses have contributed into bringing about this.
The problem is that she took several remedies in high and low potency repeatedly
and that creates what I have said many times a state of weakening of the mind
and weakening of the body.
-George I put 24 symptoms in the computer and under the first 20 remedies there was
not one remedy which fits the case. It's a totally confused case.
-Then I turned on the computer when I was enquiring about Platina, you remember?
Because computer in the analysis was showing first remedy Platina and second remedy
Cocculus which is interesting possibility of course. And then the third possibility Nux vom.
-She didn't say anything about vertigo.
-She never said but the computer analysis showed Cocculus as a first remedy and then
it became second and then Platina came up as a possibility and I was enquiring about
the possibility of Platina and I pressurized her a little bit more than I should.
Did you enquire whether she had gonorrhea ever?
-Condylomata.
-But real prime gonorrhea?
-Not that I know.
-You would know if you get.
I have to make too many comments. You say why yes, I will say why not in each remedy.
My problem with Cannabis indica is that Cannabis is full of delusions in that state
where the mental is involved. She has a lot of delusions. She did not mention delusions.
The going out of the body is typical of Cannabis Ind.
Also I did not see with her where there are no delusions, there are a lot of theories,
theorizing. I will tell you why I have this why I have that.
I also did not notice that element for Cannabis Ind.
That's why I was enquiring about Cann. Ind. then my mind went away.
The same with Phos acid which are good prescriptions.
Phos acid I was thinking in the beginning. The problem with Phos acid is that affects
mostly the emotions. You can not say that yes the emotions are also affected.
No, Phos acid has to affect 75% the emotions. Here, 60 or 70% is the mental
and the emotion is 40%.
So the impact is more on the mental level which goes for Cannabis indica.
Cann indica affects mental level, much more than the emotional but I said why not this.
Staphysagria is a good prescription because she repeated said she has been suppressed
by the husband, 18 years actually is your husband and by the mother, father whoever.
If we go Medorrhinum, there is a strong symptom for Medorrhinum which is feeling better
in the evening, it's very strong for Medorrhinum plus the condylomata.
Did you take Medor already?
-Yes.
-So she took. So Medor did not have an effect. She took Phos. Did you take Nat mur?
-It was long time ago when I took all these remedies together,
I think Nat mur was one of those.
-With Agaricus I have the problem that I did not see the anxiety and the fear of cancer.
Fear of cancer was not there, the anxiety and the hypochondriacal thing about health
I did not perceive. With Phos she took Phos and we saw the result.
Are you happy with the results? Some people may say, what we can do? Maybe we cannot do better.
I'm not happy with this result and Cocculus is a good prescription because it has this slowness,
as she shows but Cocculus usually has the dizziness which she is lacking.
Carcinosin, Platina we reason out, we took it out. Anhalonium is an interesting possibility,
especially if she has said she had some kind of ecstatic state. It is really a remedy
which goes out of the body and has some experiences but here what I was concerned is ...
I read from a remedy. Lack of will power, disinclined to work, they don't like to work
muscular debility, heavy tired feeling, weakness on the mental level, brain fag,
great weakness, tired, heavy feeling all over, especially the limbs, worse exertion.
Brain fag with sexual excitement.
The remedy for me which is somewhat indicated at this moment is to strengthen this area
which we say, it's very weak, she can not concentrate.
It is a remedy that we give to people who are mentally tired. They have students,
they have worked very hard and then the brain gives up, it says I'm not going to learn anything,
I can not learn anything, I just don't want to learn anything more.
It's not possible for me to perceive anymore information.
Which is this remedy which we give in such cases?
Picric acid.
So in these cases when we see this brain fag, she says if I put some energy I will do it.
Then I collapse. She said it very well this lady who described her case.
They put all the energy which is left, the students and then they collapse
and you give Picric acid and they continue.
Now Picric acid is it going to be a remedy with dramatic results or very impressive
results? No. It's going slowly to strengthen that area with the possibility of reducing the
effect on the mental level and the next remedy might be apparent or more apparent.
If she develops some delusions, then she may go into Cann indica, if she goes out
of the body all the time, if she develops this or that she may go to another remedy
and slowly somebody has said, she needs constant attention, constant  careful attention.
So slowly within 3 years she may gain back her mental strength. With Picric acid
she may even go to work but this is not all, she may have to do a lot of work
because the mental level then will appear, the problems and then it is the time.
Why Nat mur has not acted? It was given Ignatia, Nat mur, all these remedies were given
by a homeopath who knows a little bit of Homeopathy, all these grief remedies.
No effect, on the contrary. But if you start on the right direction then the organism
starts going up, so she needs little pushes, that means low potency repeatedly
to strengthen the mental primarily, strengthen all the organism but primarily
with the stress on the mental level.
The genius here is the remedy which has a brain fag, a tiredness in the mental level
and that is Picric acid.
-Just one more question about Phos.
Could you explain more in detail why you don't like the results which produced?
-Phosphorus did not do anything according to what she was saying and what I see,
all the mental confusion is left there. Maybe it's even more.
-Yes but she immediately got another remedy, I think shortly after Phos,
I don't think she was treated correctly.
-I don't think she was treated correctly. Maybe Phos is an underline remedy
which was given prematurely, that's another story.
After Picric acid, maybe Phos will develop, maybe Staphysagria will develop,
maybe Mercury will develop.
There are points for Merc, for Staph, for Phos acid, for Cocculus, for Nux Moschata, for Phos
and they maybe develop, Phos may develop as a second remedy but at this time she has not.
Otherwise, if Phos had worked, she would not appear in front of us.
-What I don't understand with Pic acid is that it says there that Pic acid has not hunger
but this woman even gets up at night to eat.
-Pic acid is not going to cure the whole case, we don't take all the symptoms
and to say because of all these symptoms we give Pic acid.
We give Pic acid as the uppermost layer in this case which is affecting the main symptoms for her.
Here is the main symptom and the other is lower and there are symptoms from other remedies
coming up but the remedy that will show and affect in this case, possibly is Pic acid.
Pic acid does not cover all the picture, it's not the constitutional remedy or something like that
but what I say is, low potencies like 6X of Picric acid, twice the day and then
raise the potency every week.
Every week she goes to 7X, 8X etc. twice the day and I believe in about 2 months
she will have another picture with more strength on the mental level and then maybe
it is Nat mur the picture she will develop, maybe the picture she will develop is Sulphur,
maybe Iodum or Phosphorus. We don't know.
-Did she connect this in this way?
-Yes, this is what I said and it was very obvious, it was very clear,
a difference started at that point.
-Do you still have the amalgams?
-No.
-What you did?
-Slowly I removed them.
-OK. Thank you.