-Let his father tell us what happened after Veratrum album 10M.
-Already in the days here, on the island, there was a slight amelioration.
Mr. Vithoulkas said we would have to wait up to 3 months to see a definite amelioration.
After 3,5 months concerning my opinion there was a definite amelioration of the vomiting.
Before he was vomiting from 6-9 times per day, he is going to describe it by himself,
but I think it went down to a 1/3 of what it has been.
During the last weeks, I didn't perceive it myself, I'm not so much together with him
so he is going to tell what is really going on.
-What about his height. Did he put on some height?
-I don't really know, I actually don't measure myself.
-But we have to know about that because we know the height before treatment.
I think he is at least 5 cm more. Yes we can measure him.
How high was before?
-1 m 43cm.
-He must tell us how is the last month.
-There is definitely a clear amelioration and my vomiting is about one time per day
and about 4-5 times per week I can go for stool, to the toilet.
And I actually I would prefer to get definite questions from you.
-Very good. During that time did he have any epistaxis?
-On Sunday and since Sunday he had twice epistaxis but otherwise,
at home is not so often.
-What his father says?
-I found it very remarkable that during the 5 months it was every now and then
but since he is here on the island it was twice, a very strong nose bleeding
from the right nostril and it was with clots in it and a lot, big quantity.
-Also we must tell the class that I had asked for Veratrum 50M but we could not get
and he took 10M. I want to know if he still bites his nails.
-I don't know, I don't realize myself.
-But he most probably does.
-Yes it could be.
-I see him quiet where before he had restless while sitting, quite a lot.
Does he remember this, he has noticed this?
-Yes I do remember.
-Now this is better?
-Yes.
-Concerning his constipation, he said 4-5 times per week, before how much it was?
-I would say 3-4 times. Before he could go every second day and
now it's more frequent.
About 50% amelioration.
-He says, I would consider not 50% amelioration.
-What about his coldness, he said his hands are very cold, how is that?
-In winter is still very extreme but he agrees I don't shiver so much
because you can't really compare to Germany.
-In Germany it was the same as before?
-It was the same like half a year ago, feeling cold that was even before.
-He had complained about pain in the forehead.
-It's still there every now and then.
-Does people in his class still tease him or he is affected by them
or he doesn't care so much?
-The new younger people are coming is all right for the moment because
they are sometimes even smaller than me. So he isn't the smallest anymore.
Before he was the smallest child of the whole high school and now this is changed
because younger people came.
-What about his thirst? He drinks quite a lot still, cold water?
-In Germany I drink either room temperature or warm drinks but here in Greece
I would take ice cold drinks.
-Ask his father.
-I observe that in Germany he orders a soda with ice cubes he takes the ice cubes
and eats them.
-Is that true?
-Yes but only when I feel bored.
-Have you noticed any change in your desire for food, you like more this or that?
-I can't tolerate the fat still.
-How is he doing in his class?
-I'm one of the better students.
-What I would like to see is to measure his height and then we go inside.
-There is still certain restlessness left over, it's about 50% better
but still when he is eating he can't sit still, he is moving his feet
and wanting to play football. It's not that he can't stand still at all,
he can sit still for 3 min and then he starts moving.
-It's interesting question for me also that you see some action of the remedy
and you feel that it's not good enough.
And I wonder whether the 50M really was needed.
Still he is good enough but he could be better, if we had a stronger impulse.
And now  we have the same problem that we have in most of the cases.
What shall we do? What is the situation? Shall we now go to 50M?
Let his father talk, maybe he didn't say something important .
-I didn't want to embarrass my son or bring him any problems in front of the public
but according to my observation the vomiting has ceased completely within
the last 1 and 1/2 months.
Before he vomited 9 times the day and what, in my opinion, speaks strongly for Veratrum
is that he repeatedly had this epistaxis from the right nostril.
But he still has a certain restlessness, for example he loves to play
with his game boy for 3-4 hours every day and he likes to eat ice cubes.
-In this case we see the keynotes of our prescribing, they are still there.
What is interesting is, he says in the last days the epistaxis on the right side
on which we had actually based a lot of the prescription is back definitely,
the coldness which is another keynote,  there is icy coldness on extremities,
especially the hands and that is why Veratrum will be indicated
very frequently in rhino cases.
What is interesting for you to learn concerning the Materia Medica of Veratrum is this.
When the Veratrum goes through grief, a usual reaction is vomiting.
The outlet of the organism is to vomit and to vomit easily and that is why
we say Veratrum vomits like a rocket, it comes out very easy and forcefully.
There is a tendency of the Veratrum to vomit very easily to go into diarrheas very easily
and that is why also Veratrum will be indicated in cases of cholera,
but you don't have to have cholera, you have to have a similar type of food poisoning
which you may see mostly vomiting and diarrhea.
Once you see this then your mind immediately should go to Veratrum,
especially if they complain about coldness in the body and especially the hands.
So it's a good learning experience, also it is something for you to remember.
When you have a deep grief and symptoms because of deeper grief,
don't expect the organism to react immediately, it will take some time,
just give time and wait.
If you have decided on a remedy, after you have studied well the case.
What shall we do? What the class says? About wait, repeat, go higher, go lower?
Again the problem is that he comes here at this time and you have to make a decision.
You don't have the possibility to say, come after a month, two months etc.
so I can evaluate the situation and decide accordingly.
1 cm per month is this good enough?
Anyhow I was writing 5 cm higher than what he was when I saw him. That's the idea.
What the pediatrician would say, ask her in his age what is the rate?
-Generally you can't really tell because they have this time of going up quickly
at some age between 12 -18, even later but in his case I also would expect
with the 50M to go much quicker. It's slow for his age.
-What is his age at this moment?
-14 years old.
-As I said last time, all the children who take homeopathic treatment from young age
if the treatment is correct, they become taller than their parents.
So at least he should go over his father. I don't know his mother.
-I want to ask if for the next month this epistaxis would become more and let us say that
the vomiting will not reappear. I think that we should repeat then. What do you think?
-The problem is when to repeat? Now, to give another dose of 10M or we just go 50M
and let him vomit again for a few days.
It's a difficult decision. The symptomatology is there for Veratrum album still.
If he relapses, that means if he is going to relapse, he is maybe going to start vomiting
again after some time.
-I had asked him to measure his size in between and then he always said,
no I don't want to, he did not want to be confronted with this issue.
So from that I assumed that he has still a high sensitivity concerning this issue.
-Because what I was thinking is that if the grief problem would have been resolved
and it would be only on the physical, if we could lower and repeat
but if it's still on the mental we should go higher.
-No, this is a case where we have to go higher in any case, we have to go either repeat
or go higher. Now the grief how much better it is? In this particular case it is proportional
to the vomiting.
The grief corresponds to the vomiting, so if you see the vomiting goes all together
then there is going to be a residue left but very little beyond the vomiting.
That means the grief is so much that causes this repulsion.
Once this is gone some grief will be staying over which may take a few months or years
to resolve it totally once he feels back again that he is normal
and he is like all the other children.
-Last year still on September-October there was a kind of idiosyncratic aversion
against any small tiny amount of fat.
It has to be no butter, no any amount of fat anywhere.
He would refuse totally to eat it and by now you can offer him dishes
that have been made in the frying pan with a little butter underneath to prepare the food
and he would eat it, so I would say the aversion against fat has reduced by 10%
of what it had been.
-There was an arrested development definitely.
This arrested development would not bother the child unless the other children
have tease him about his size.
So it's not the arrested per se which affected him but the teasing of the other children,
you are dwarf or whatever. They tease him and the grief was imprinted in him
because of the teasing of the other children.
Now there is some anger, maybe I don't see the anger. I still can see and hear
in his voice when the matter was discussed for a while, I can hear the sensitivity
towards that matter.
If you could hear his voice changed a little bit, that shows that there is a residue
and the residue is going to stay, not all the grief will go away.
If we have so much grief, if it goes over this level starts
causing vomiting in Veratrum children.
So if this grief starts coming down here, it will leave the child without vomiting
and of course better assimilation because the vomiting is not just a vomiting.
It is bad assimilation, if he vomited 9 times the day, there is a problem of course.
The organism rejected what he was eating, so the whole idea that
we corrected his assimilation of food, as a result reducing as well the grief
and at the same time giving him the possibility to grow a little bit more,
so he is not teased so much by the other children.
-This is a general question about treating children.
Since they are usually attached to the parents and live together,
to what extend would you enquire about the essence, about the character of the parents
and how they influence about this interrelation, what extend according to age or
what would you enquire?
-Not very much, it is true that, what my experience is, you give the correct remedy
and it will correct the child and correct even the misbehavior of the parents.
Because the parents sometimes do not understand that the behavior of the child
is due to some pathology. If the child is restless and they say, you don't stay
in one place, you just sit down and don't move and the child does not understand
he is restless even and then of course the parents can create problem.
But if you give a remedy which corrects the restlessness, then the parents stop doing this.
So what I found out is that the dynamics in the family are more or less rearranged in
some matters especially, so the behavior of the parents is modified but in this case
I did not see any problem at all, even to think of some kind of wrong behavior on the
part of the parents.
-I'm not referring to this case of course but sometimes the whole problem start
from some projection of the parents on the child, so it might happen again and again.
-Yes, that is true but for instance you remember a case we saw together from Israel
a lawyer with tremendous headaches?
I believe this is a case created quite a lot by the pressure of the parents that
the child becomes really something and his spine was like this and then the headaches
and then we predicted that this is going to be very difficult case.
It was difficult, I have been treating still the case and he is doing better.
My experience is that these children, very short children from very short parents also
with homeopathic treatment, they become much taller.
I've told you parents of 1,50 m both 1,50 m they are almost like this child
and they brought the son for chorea. The son at the year of 10-11 he started jumping around
and we treated him for at least 3 years before we could manage to cure his chorea.
For 4 years. So he was 15-16 by the time he stopped.
This boy became a football player and he was one of the tallest in the team.
He became over 1,85 m, all the children I have seen.
So you have to know if you treat your child with Homeopathy is going to become very tall
have that in mind.
The decision is one dose of Veratrum album 50M.
-The last time we were here my son received Veratrum album in a C50.000,
that was on May this year, it was the second dose of the remedy;
before he had received it in a 10M.
His main complain was a sudden, severe, violent, projectile vomiting
which could happen 6-9 times every day.
After Veratrum 10M the frequency vomiting was reduced but it was still there constantly
every day 4-6 times. And now reporting what happened after taking Veratrum 50M
which he received in May of this year, according to his words in the past 4-5 months
he still vomits about 1-2 every day.
But he doesn't have any mental or emotional complain from it, he doesn't really care
and he also is not nauseous or has any other physical complain with it.
I think one of the reason why George Vithoulkas prescribed Veratrum among the many
vomiting remedies we have is that my son has a very specific bleeding from
the right nostril during the night, epistaxis.
So I tell you now the new symptoms that have developed since, vomiting as I said
had remained in low frequency.
What changed now is that the epistaxis from the right nostril got so severe
that every time it happened he needed between 4-5 handkerchiefs just
to collect the amount of blood coming out of his nose.
The blood was bright red but the frequency of the epistaxis has reduced quite a lot
in the last 3 weeks, he told me it happened once or twice.
What appeared new in August, when I was here on the island with my wife
to consult Mr. Vithoulkas, had inflicted a small wound on his elbow
while was playing football with me.
This wound was not healing properly, so one evening we went to the local pharmacy here
in Patitiri and then they put some kind of liquid, I think it was iodine
or something else into the wood and also applied a certain spray over it
and when the pharmacist put the spray on the wound, from one moment to the next,
my son suddenly fell over to the side.
I just managed to grab him and he was lying there on the ground collapsed,
he was conscious but he really collapsed from one second to the next.
-It was his height, he would not grow and then it was a problem for him
especially psychological problem because he would feel he was very short in his class.
How is that developing?
-There is no grief anymore concerning his height but he won't let us measure his height
he doesn't want it. Usually he refuses us to take his height.
-What is his impression?
-2-3 cm within the last 5 months but I have no chance of measuring it.
He continues to bite his nails down to the flesh and he still is constipated,
he only has stool every second day and I had a phone call with him in the meantime
to make precise report and he confirmed that after every stool,
he has a real prolapse of the rectum.
He has some aversions and desires, he developed some aversion to meat and
he likes to eat chocolate, not that strong, you maybe underline it twice
and he has an aversion to butter, he would rather not use butter at all
or very, very thin on his bread.
-He used to take butter?
-No, he always had an aversion to butter. It's not a change.
He still complains of very cold hands, he always says his hands are colder than his feet
and I asked him how they are and he says, icy cold even now in August and September.
-Prolapse in children, show me this?
Podophyllum, show me the analysis.
Yes! Because I thought maybe I start having an anxiety with the Podophyllum
jump into the picture.
-I forgot to mention that he has very strong thirst for large quantities
and I asked him on the phone whether he prefers cold drinks or hot drinks and he said,
cold from the fridge.
-We are very happy if the information is so, if the information is reliable
because immediately with the sudden collapse, with the excessive bleeding
you just put the two things together and you have a case of Phosphorus
but you just give one dose of Phosphorus 200, that's all and I would like that
in one year he picks up 20 cm.
-OK.
-Not 2-3 cm.
-I would like to say a word in front of the auditorium I want to thank you very, very much.
There is hardly anybody who has done so much for the health of my family as you.
-What is his height at this moment?
-At this moment I measured 1 m and 58 cm.
-And it was when we measured it here, do you remember what it was his height?
-1 m 48 cm one year before when we started. So there is 10 cm more.
-And in every other respect he is going to school, he has no problems?
-No, I don't think there is a grief when other boys hurt him, he was the smallest boy
in the whole school, now he has grown up and this problem I don't think is really
a problem for him.
-So his height is almost normal now.
-He is in the lower border but I should go to an endocrinologue to check.
-I don't think anything will be found at this moment and I believe he will have
a completely normal height, if not too high.
-He is now 15 years and has no real signs of puberty. I was also late in development.
-I don't think you will have a problem, we'll watch.
10 cm in a year, if is going to be every year, another 5 years that he still can grow
he will go into 2 m and 10 cm. It will be no problem with his height because I believe
the pituitary gland was arrested in the development but now it is released.
I know this because many, many children who do Homeopathy they grow to be much higher
than their parents, so he definitely can be taller than you.
-So he can be confident.
-You can be confident, he will be taller than you, I don't know how much but definitely
you will remember this in a few years and maybe one time you bring him here
and I measure him again with you.