This case is a boy, how old is he?– 10 years old.
– I saw him 2 years ago. 3 years.
First consultation, was given Hyoscyamus 200C and 1M
and last years was given Causticum 200C, 4 doses, once a week. How is he?
Give me an overall impression of how the boy is doing.
– He has been fantastic, emotionally better to express himself, mentally improved.
So he has been really great in school this year. This year he has improved the most.
He is now on the level of his peers in Math, this year he got up with the curriculum
and he is now on the level so he is doing fantastic with the other kids
and then another thing; in the beginning of the year he began a second language,
French and I wanted to pull him out, because it was too much for him,
but they told me that all the kids will be learning a little bit of this a little bit of that.
Apparently, in a matter of 2 or 3 weeks... They asked us if we speak French at home
and we said no we don’t. He is doing fantastic in French
and got even awarded for his excellent achievement in French.
He got the award and he is fantastic in Math, he is able to work more
and we know that because we work together with him at home.
So he is able to concentrate more, he is willing to do the work.
Before he was always oppositional, probably because of the struggle he has to do...
Cognitively he is able to understand more obviously, he is responding more,
he asks question, so communication is more initiated in a conversation.
With strangers not so much, he hides behind us a little bit.
Asthma didn’t improve much, with Hyoscyamus it was fantastic,
now asthma throughout maybe 30% of what it was with Hyoscyamus,
there is always asthma lingering there in the background.
And it was going a little bit to the max right now in this weather with the humidity,
even in Greece. Before he never had problems in Greece. Now he has also.
So asthma remained there. – So the main problem is asthma now.
– Asthma and autism definitely.
– New symptoms that may have appeared during the last year? Fear of animals is less.
– Yes, he handles it a little bit better, so it’s less.
– He has nose bleeds from right nostril in the morning.
– Actually it’s alternating sometimes it’s the right, sometimes it’s the left.
This is a new thing.– Last year it was mostly right
but in March is actually started more on the left. That is maybe once per month.
It’s not very often.– Teeth yellowing.
– He got the cleaning done of the yellow deposits so it was yellow which is unusual for a child.
– Bad breath occasionally?– Yes.
Can I just add with the bad breath that also something fairly new after the report,
sometimes he has at the corner of his mouth a white. I guess it’s connected with that.
– He understands everything.– Yes.
– He is feeling a little bit shy. Very good boy.– In the evening he turns on all the lights.
– Yes he goes from room to room and turns on everything.
– He likes the light even in the night?– No, he sleeps in the dark
because he still sleeps with us in our bed. So it’s dark.
We don’t need light when he sleeps.
– He sleeps with you?– Yes.Still.Could be because of the asthma.
Because his asthma crisis is happening in the evening
and then escalates during the evening so during the night he could have a problem.
– Do you have another child – No.
But when his cousin comes from Toronto he sleeps with her. He is 3 years older.
They are very close together. So his sleeps in another room with her.
– He needs some company in the night.– Yes.
He slept maybe 4 or 5 months alone and then he had bad asthma attacks
during the night and after that he sleeps with us.
– Did he complained during these months? Did he get out of his bed?
– No, he was sleeping. We believe it’s just fear of asthma attack.
– Because he can stay in the room in a house and I go around...
- He doesn’t have fear to be alone. But to sleep alone yes. He does not like.
– But he slept for 5 months.– Yes and then he had really bad asthma attacks
during the night. He woke up and started crying...- What time was he waking up?
– It was not this year, it was the last year, sometime in May.
– No he asks what time in the morning.– Around 5 a.m. in the dawn.
– Not 4 to 5 a.m.?– It could be. I can actually check if have written down.
– Did he have an attack at other hours or only that hour in the morning?
– Mostly, 95%, it escalates during the night. - Now it’s mostly in the evening.
Between 10p.m. and 12 a.m. is the worst period. We give him a puffer
and after that he calms down.– Do you give him anything during the asthma attack?
– We have to. Ventalin. That’s the only one that doesn’t have steroids.
– Did you try to avoid giving Ventalin to see how he does?
– Of course! We give him only because sometimes,
when we say bad we mean his stomach rises so diaphragm works,
the lungs don’t have oxygen so we need to give him at that time.
So we tried to postpone and then...- Now as soon as he starts with the crisis,
you give him immediately or you wait half an hour? – We wait.
– For how long?– We wait until the stomach really pushes inside
and that’s the sign that there is not enough oxygen as far as we know, so we give him.
And he is ok to wait. He knows the level, he waits himself.
– This asthma was in childhood?– No. It appeared 2011 in July.
One year before we came here first time
and our homeopath Helen tried to do something and we couldn’t so
that’s why 2012 we came here to see you and you prescribed Hyoscyamus
and it worked amazing with asthma too.
This time Causticum worked magically in the mental level and emotionally,
he is able to express himself.– Ok, let me ask you something else.
How much of his asthma is back again from the original state?
If you compare how he originally was with his asthma and his asthma now,
would you say it is 50% of what it was? 30% or 80%?
– You mean before Hyoscyamus? At the very beginning, 30% of the very beginning.
– Now it is 30% of the original state.– Yes.
– Have you seen him touching his genitalia lately?
– That was before with Hyoscyamus very much.
Now, maybe I saw him 3 times in a year, so that’s why we didn’t put it in the report.
Plus he is 10 years old.– How is his thirst? Normal?
– I would say a little bit below normal, at home he wasn’t drinking much
but here, probably because of the bottles, this is a new thing,
he drinks from the bottle in Greece. We are here in Greece from June 7th, 10 days.
So before that I would say it was below normal
but he drinks a lot because of our diet, he drinks broth soup,
I make it every day. So with every meal he drinks a cup of soup.
- He likes soup.- He loves it but it’s also a part of our diet so it’s sort of necessary.
- You like soup?– Hmm yeah.
– Good expression.– Yes, this is another thing.
He closes his eyes when he has to answer
or he closes our eyes when he has to answer something that somebody is asking.
– What can I do? That’s life. Very good. If you want to describe his emotional state,
what would you say?– I think he is very open now to express with us,
the biggest difference we saw in Hyoscyamus and now is when he is sad, he is crying.
He is expressing. Before he would just cry if I said no, scolding him or something
but if somebody close is not very nice to him, he would suppress
and then you would see the regression. He would not show. Now he is different.
– That means you will see a kind of sadness coming after somebody has insulted him?
– No. Now we see, before we didn’t see anything.
It was just nothing and then you would see maybe peeing in the bedroom at night,
you would see that he is more serious, not laughing,not very playful.
But now he comes and I ask him if something has happened particularly in school,
in March I asked him if something happened with his best friend
and has was very sad for 2, 3 weeks but he was crying
and then I would ask him what happened
and he wouldn’t like to talk about it much but he was crying.
He was showing his emotions and then I would just say it’s ok to be sad,
it’s fine until he stops crying and we move on. He was crying for 2,3 weeks.
That was a very traumatic moment.– What happened? Did you learn?
– Yes, I sort of found out. Somebody told him
that he and his best friend are like little babies who eat snow. Both of them.
– He likes to eat snow. And there is a lot of snow in Canada.
– So somebody told him they are like babies. He didn’t mind that
but the other kid is very small in size and he is very sensitive to that,
so I guess after the comment he wasn’t playing with him anymore
and joined the bigger group and he is the best friend,
they were together from grade one.
Obviously he did not understand that like I wouldn’t understand that,
so his reaction was normal. After that peeing in the bed during the night started,
he started having little accidents during the day, not much, just a little bit
and that lasted for a month and we gave him Causticum at the end of April
and in May for four weeks once per week and then the peeing disappeared
and around June 10th everything was ok. The last 10 days were just normal.
So one month after basically all these during the night and during the day things,
even though he was expressing, but there is also that part there.
And before, with Hyoscyamus he would have accident peeing the bed
but he would also regress a little bit mentally,
like you would see the difference in his speech.
That’s how the deep suppression was at that time.
– Except accidents, everything else was normal.
– When you say he closes the parents eyes when asked to answer a question,
what does he do? He puts his hand?– Yes.
Because when I ask him for example to tell me something in French he wouldn’t
and then I try to help him at the very beginning, I was trying again and again
because I am bad in languages, he would tell me mama only in English please.
You are a hopeless case for French.And then later when they told us how great he is
I asked him to tell me something in French
and he would not demonstrate his knowledge.
Then finally he agreed to say something, he closed our eyes so that we...
- He closes your eyes in order to give you the answer?– Yes. Sometimes he closes his.
For example if you would ask him if he can close your eyes, he closes his...
- The hours of aggravation of asthma, when I gave him Hyoscyamus,
were the same as now?– No.
– The hours at that time?– At that time it was more from 1 a.m..
So he would fall asleep for a little bit
and then around 1 a.m. to 4 a.m. it would escalate more and more.
Now it starts in the evening, 7 p.m. or 8 p.m. and then slowly until maybe midnight,
and then throughout the night he is ok. We give him the puffer, Ventalin,
and he sleeps through the night but before with Hyoscyamus, even with the Ventalin
he wakes up and aggravates until 4 a.m. maybe...
- For how long is he taking Ventalin? These last months.
– He is being on and off very frequently. Maybe 2 or 3 days he doesn’t have it
and then the 4th day he needs it.
– Everyday?– No.
But when it’s humid like this he needs it every day. Maybe even more than once.
A few days ago there was rain then in the evening it was sunny
and the morning it was sunny and that’s the worst.
– He had a dental treatment also?
– I know. I didn’t want to do the dental treatmentbut ...
- Ok, did they give him injections for anesthesia? – Yes.
– When was this?– February this year. But we went to the holistic doctor.
So they don’t use the fluoride at least.
– The asthma started or became worse after the dental treatment? – No.
it happed before when that silly doctor gave him fluoride and I didn’t even see,
that was before Hyoscyamus, at that time his asthma was very bad.
But this time there was no change in the asthma, I didn’t notice
and we went to that other doctor.– When did the return of the asthma come?
Not here I am talking about this time.
There was a period after Hyoscyamus that there was no asthma.
– 3 months after Hyoscyamus he was almost without asthma
and then September 2012 it started reappearing and after that it never completely left.
– So after Hyoscyamus the asthma was better only for 3 months.
– Yes. And then slowly it came.– What does he like to eat?
– Well again because of our diet we don’t know if it really reflects
but he loves to eat watermelon.– What else do you like to eat?
– Peach. He loves peaches.– Fruits?
– Yes. He likes meat.– You have limited him?
What is your profession? Are you a teacher?– Yes, I am a teacher.
We are trying to do something about teaching. I am teaching interior design.
So nothing medical although I am interested in.– But you are teaching grown-ups.
– College kids. Older than 20 years.
– Does he like fruits in general?– Yes but not many fruits, he is very picky.
He doesn’t like berries, strawberries. He loves cucumber
and not much fresh vegetables.– Cucumber is the best for him?
– Yes.– Salt? How much salt he eats?
– He likes, not very salty but he likes.
– He likes to add some salt?– Yes.
– Does he like taking salt and putting it in his mouth?– No. He likes meat. Chicken.
– With fat in it?– Yes.He loves fat and now the new thing,
because I make this broth and I am taking the bone marrow,
he loves everything around the bone, he peels off the bone. Every meat around.
That’s a new thing, before he didn’t like the bones, now he likes ribs
and everything with a bone. He loves duck and lamb. This is the newest one.
– Does he like sweets?– He never liked at all.
– That’s the reason why he likes watermelon that has sweeter taste.
– The water he drinks must be cold from the refrigerator or not?– No.
We usually give him regular so he doesn’t ask for cold water.
– Ice creams?– Not now.
He used to be allergic to milk so I was making the juice and freezing it,
now we are getting there with our diet.– But he doesn’t mind cold.
– He likes the cold things but he doesn’t ask for them.
– He eats the snow.– That’s right yes. Quite a bit.
– Is he good in Math?– Yes. Like his father.
– His mother is also good. She is just shy.
– Is the father also a teacher?– No. I am a mechanical engineer
and I am working as an IT, in computers.
– Not in the CIA? You said information, I am joking.
Did he ever have an otitis in the past?
– He had an ear infection when the whole thing started, when he was 2 years old.
But after the Causticum, after the second week, we were in Greece, Chalkidiki,
he was there and during the night the right ear was aching
and then I put a hot compress and it went away in the morning.
We were hoping to get worse...
- But in the past, he had any severe otitis?– No. Only that when he was 2 years old.
– When he was 2 years old he had a severe otitis, in which the ear was discharging?
– No, there was no discharge. He was just given antibiotics 2 times and that’s it.
- Two series.– Why are you saying “too serious”?
– Well, not too serious. It was November and then February, he had one otitis,
one antibiotic and then February they gave him again antibiotics
and another course of antibiotics back to back. Two series he said. So 2 times for 5 days in a row.
Once and then again.
– The autistic problems started after the otitis?– Yes.
– About 6 months later you noticed?– Yes.
– You don’t know the type of antibiotics that were given?– Amoxicillin.
– And you had given him vaccinations as a baby?– A few. Not everything.
We were postponing. We didn’t want to vaccinate him
but in Canada you need a paper. I didn’t know because I am from Serbia.
So until I found out how to get the paper and go to the lawyer to understand
he had to go because he had lots of eczema
and we were taking him to the doctor very often at that time
and the doctor was pushing and maybe I was too weak as a mother.
– Last one he received was when he was 18 months
but in Canada that’s already 10 vaccines in total.– No he didn’t get 10 vaccines,
he get maybe 4, 5. I can give you the list, I don’t want to know.
I want to forget that but...- You have to repeat unfortunately
because I did not understand.
– He received 4 or 5 groups of vaccinations in Canada at once, that’s how they give it.
He received at birth, he received at 6 months, at 9 months, at 12 months,
already delayed and then he received at 18 months and then we stopped.
Then we got the paper and he didn’t receive anything after that.
– But even these vaccines they were postponed.
– Actually the vaccines that were supposed to be received at 18 months
were received at 2 years. So we delayed them as much as we could.
– But after all these vaccines he had the otitis crisis.– Yes.
– And then he had the antibiotics.– Yes.
– And then again antibiotics for how many days? 10 days?– Yes.
– And about several months later you noticed the problems.– Yes.
– The original eczema, where was it?– Everywhere.
– Everywhere or mostly on the bends?– Everywhere and not a little bit.
It was like 3rd degree burns. Oozing.
- If you remember, the oozing if you touched it, was it sticky?- Yes.
– Like honey?– Yes, like maple honey.
– So it was a matter of one doze of one remedy to save the child by that time.
- I understand now.
– Does he like music?– Yes. He likes music and he likes to dance.
– Is he happy when he hears music or sometimes he becomes a little bit sad?
– Always happy and moving. Well, sometimes he likes to play with the sticks now,
like a wand, like wizards from the movies and sometimes he has choreography,
he does something with his stick, he shuffles and it’s like he is dancing.
He has one more thing which is maybe important.
During the night in Canada for the year he is tossing a lot
and turning and tossing his covers off. It wasn’t before with Hyoscyamus.
– Restlessness in bed?– Very restless during the night.
And then tosses off his cover and then he is sneezing, he is cold.
But still tossing covers. Also, a new thing, there is mucus and hard stuff,
so he cannot breathe during the night, so we have to put the pillows up
because of all this mucus...- He is sleeping like this.
– Sometimes bends his knees up. That’s very different from before.
And he is sneezing in his sleep as well. Also in his sleep, he makes a sound,
not grinding teeth, sometimes he is grinding his teeth, but like slurping,
I can’t even make it. Like sucking your saliva in and also likes his arms uncovered
even if it’s cold, very cold he keeps his arms uncovered.
It’s interesting, the restlessness in sleep now we came to Greece, it improved.
He is actually sleeping very nicely in Greece.
And another thing, before he didn’t want to start swimming, he always loves water,
but he was scared.- He loves the water, what did you say?
– The previous years, he loved the water but was never relaxed enough to swim,
he always kept in shallow. This year he just went swimming without any training,
that was it. Yes. He was ready to start swimming last year but he was holding himself.
This year, no problem.– So maybe letting go anxiety, fears...
He knows when he is ready. Very certain.
For example I asked him to learn to ride a bike, he doesn’t want to ride a bike.
One day after 2 years, he sits and he rides.
So he really knows when he is ready to do something.
Very certain , not many people are.
– Does he like fish?– Not really. Mama made fish last night and he didn’t want to eat it.
– He eats it occasionally but he doesn’t like it.– Maybe a big thing.
He was allergic to fish and then we gave him last year, after 3 months of diet,
a little bit and we tried again and he was ok. So he ate it a few times
and then after that he did not like it.
– The problem is that you have to know
in the process of treatment the original eczema may come back.
You now that?– Yes.
– And that would be a good sign. Also the otitis.
– That’s why when it happened a little but last year, I was hoping.
– have you read my books?– Yes, I have read some. Can I ask you one question?
When you tell Ms. Mitsakis for a remedy,
can you please also tell us when he has extreme asthma what to do then?
Should we repeat the remedy or not?– No.
Don’t repeat the remedy during the asthma attack.
Try to avoid if you see the asthma crisis is not very strong, he may suffer a little bit more,
but he may overcome it. But if you see him suffering a lot, you have to help him.
But eventually we have to cure the asthma and then the eczema which will be worse.
– So not repeating the remedy when there is a crisis. Ok, that’s all. Thank you so much.
Some of the analysis you hear and some of my thoughts you could follow
when I was taking the case. Now it’s very clear what has happened to the child.
The child was born absolutely normal. But the vaccinations originally
and then the antibiotics brought about the state of autism as they diagnosed it
but this is the case as I have said before, that the child was not born autistic,
was made autistic by vaccinations and drugs. Such cases are much easier to treat
and to help than the originally autistic children.
Children who were born autistic very little advance.
In his case they avoided the repetition of vaccinations
and that is why the damage done was not so severe
as to be able to have this kind of improvement that they relate.
If they had given full repetitions of all the vaccinations
then we would have to battle much more
before we can bring the child to that state in which he is now.
Always remember that when you give a remedy and the remedy has acted, wait.
Do not jump and give another remedy because what you will have...
In the beginning you give the remedy which is not needed. You notice nothing.
Then you give another one and you notice a little change
and then you give another one and there is a little bit more change
and eventually you find out that you have managed to bring back the whole situation
by giving wrong remedies but now the original remedy will not do the work.
So it’s very important to understand when to say
wait, let the organism fix the rest, the little things that are there”
In this boy it is interesting that he has this habit of closing his eyes or the eyes of others
which can be translated as timidity, shyness.
And which is the remedy that has shyness? Baryta carbonica.
How many of you thought of Baryta carbonica?
I will tell you something in continuation to what I said yesterday
concerning what we treat and what is the personality of the person.
We don’t treat the personality, we treat the pathology upon the personality.
Concerning this the boy was doing, did you notice anything which impressed you?
In the interview we had, I was talking and said ok the boy is doing like that etc.
Did you notice something which impressed you? I will tell you what impressed me.
When I said something, I can’t remember now what to the mother,
when I said something the mother was holding a paper. Did you see that?
She took the paper and went like that. Did you notice?
– No.– Nobody noticed? Who noticed that the woman felt timid, shy and...?
You did? Oh, yes I said you are a teacher. What is the boy doing is this.
So that means there is some genetic predisposition that passes
from our parents to the children. This genetic predisposition is something
that forms the characteristics of our character, our personality.
For instance, taking myself as an example, since I remember,
since I was a very small boy I always wanted to understand
why this person reacted this way, I had to analyze, to understand
and inside me I would find the reason why he said that, why he did that etc.
It’s my character. If you say now this character is being very critical
because in our repertory we have rubric which says “censorious, critical”
If my tendency to analyze and to understand becomes annoying to others,
that means I always analyze them and I tell them,
then this natural tendency characteristic of my personality becomes pathology.
That I have to tell, to annoy others. If I don’t do that, this characteristic is normal,
if I overdo it and I annoy others by my critical mind,
then the remedy Arsenicum, Sulphur or Veratrum album
and all the remedies that are very critical will reduce that
but will bring me back to the normal characteristic of my personality.
I am talking to you about the last day with the child. I said this child now is normal.
He says 70% is better swearing. Yes, sure.
That is normal for him because he has the tendency in his character to tease,
has the tendency to draw attention to himself.
If this is overdone by throwing tantrums, making a lot of fuss then you give the remedy
because this is too much. Then this tendency will be reduced
and will come to normal, to what is normal in his character.
So if you want to understand for yourself what is my normal character,
you have to go back to a period when you feel good in general.
Maybe that was 10 years ago, or 20, it doesn’t matter. Maybe it was yesterday.
When you feel good. How you behave when you feel good?
My wife says one more word and I say ok, forget it.
This is my normal character because I tolerate. But now this characteristic changes
and my wife says something that aggravates me and i am flying, i am responding, i am answering.
That is the pathology that has started.
The natural characteristics, if they are exaggerated and are manifesting in such a way
as to disturb others, then can be treated but you cannot treat a personality as such.
Personality is the total amount of thinking, feeling etc.
that a person has in his normal state.
Once he is not aggravated by somebody trying to irritate you,
is not aggravated by pollution atmosphere,
is aggravated by an injection you have given...
You go to the doctor, you go to the dentist and he gives you 2 injections of anesthesia
and you go home and after that you feel lousy
and you are not anymore your normal self.
A weak constitution will remain in that state after the dental treatment
and a strong constitution will get it out.
This boy was not able to throw out the effect of the total vaccinations
and antibiotics and where he was affected? Right in his mind.
It is so important to understand these things.
Because he had an eczema originally,
the eczema was suppressed and it went into the lungs.
Eventually the interference with different drugs and vaccinations
suppressed the asthma and affected the brain. You see how the disease is manifesting.
This is the way. That boy shows you exactly the way diseases manifesting
and how dangerous it is to interfere on an organism with chemical drugs
and all these kinds of vaccinations,
because vaccinations are targeting the immune system,
to change your immune system.
Your immune system is not able to counteract an epidemic
and you interfere by saying you will be able to counteract in epidemic and take this. And the immune system changes
but in changing the immune system it changes the whole structure of the human being
and whatever changes you brought about in the immune system
in order to prevent an epidemic from taking place,
all these changes are diffused in the rest of the human organism
and then you have results of that type.
You know how many children have attention deficit disorder?
Millions today. Attention deficit disorder.
Next are children with Asperger syndrome, much heavier but not yet too much.
Then you have the autistic children and then you have the born autistic children.
You will see all these, put it together and see how many millions there are today
of all these categories and you will see what we have produced in the human race
by wrong interference. Nobody will do a research
and if he does a research of that type, will never be published.
They find 1.000 reasons why this has happened to the human race,
especially of the Western Europe and America. They will never find out,
they will never say that this is because of the medicine and the vaccination.
They will find pollution in the atmosphere, competitive society...
They create confusion so people do not know the truth, they cannot find the truth,
they cannot come to the core of the matter.
I think if I had enough voice I would show you a case with a nice man.
I was battling with him, I knew he had got gonorrhea but he refused it.
I tried this way, I tried that way, the other way,
no it was not gonorrhea, no I don’t remember, no...
I wanted to give Medorrhinum but I wanted the confirmation.
His symptoms were not clear. I said ok, take a dose of 30C, just to check out.
He comes after some time and says I had such a bad aggravation,
he wrote me a very bad email, I had such a bad aggravation,
you gave me this and spoiled my health...
That showed most probably that you had gonorrhea, that’s why you have the reaction.
Then he writes a very impolite email to me and says forget it.
Yesterday or the day before yesterday, after 2 years of Medorrhinum 30C
I wanted to show you the case, he wrote and he said I must apologize.
I feel better all over. 2 years, one dose of Medorrhinum 30C and he made me crazy,
I knew he had gonorrhea because of some other things and he would not accept.
So one dose and now what he writes.
Most probably the symptoms are coming back after 2 years,
so he writes to me I am thinking of using now Medorrhinum 1M.
I pretend that I didn’t read exactly the email,
I read only the mail where he says
I have been only for 2 years in a very good condition etc.
and I said thank you for your good words and stopped.
Today in the morning I received another email,
he says if in the beginning I had told you that I had gonorrhea,
what potency would you have given me? You see how the human mind works.
He puts the question but he does not say, shall I take a dose of 1M now?
No, he says if I had accepted... Now I made him feel a little bit bad because his son,
who was an autistic child with very bad behavior
- his mother came and by biting her she was blue all over...
the child was so because of his problems also and he thought he could get out
and not say what has really happened.
If people do not give you the information, you are lost but also you have to search
Going back now to the case. How many symptoms you have used? 21 symptoms.
Show me. Fear of being alone in the night, timidity, epistaxis, sneezing during sleep,
offensive odor, discolored, asthmatic respiration difficult at night,
respiration wheezing, restless sleep, skin eruptions suppressed, chicken desire...
I asked put chicken desire instead of duck, he says duck! I looked at him
and he really felt if I had a piece of duck now I would eat it! This was the idea.
He was so expressive. So I said put desire for chicken. He said also chicken.
So what is the remedy? Look a very strange phenomenon.
The remedy that comes first...
I have found this myself. I think it was not originally in Kent.
But anyhow, show. Graphites. He has used 21 symptoms and Graphites has only 11.
But Graphites covers some very interesting symptoms.
Aversion to sweets is all along strong.
We gave Causticum because of aversion to sweets
and yet this symptom was not taken away by it.
Because this symptom also belonged to an underlying remedy
which again had aversion to sweets.
That’s why aversion to sweets continues staying there.
So aversion to sweets and suppressed eruptions and restless sleep...
Graphites has restlessness in sleep quite strongly on third degree
which the boy really has started the moment he entered the idea of Graphites
he has restlessness in sleep. Strong restlessness in sleep as she described.
Perspiration in the night, fish aversion also,
is known that Graphites does not like fish, sweets and salt.
If you have these 3 symptoms you can cure a boy with whatever he may have.
It’s very simple because what we do...
In this case of the boy the brain is retarded and we take some signals of the organism
and through these signals we stimulate the organization in his brain.
We stimulate it through a remedy which we discover through little symptoms
like aversion to sweets which is so important.
Because the sugar level how much an important part of digestion and combustion is.
This is very important part. And the organism says don’t give me sweet
because you will poison me.
You give me sweet by force, they forced the child to take fish, ok I take it
but I don’t like it because it is like poison for the organism of that child.
I draw your attention to these things because you are medical doctors
having been trained to think of pathology. What is the pathology?
It’s bronchitis, what is indicated for bronchitis? These antibiotics, take them, finish.
And here it doesn’t matter whether it is bronchitis, pneumonia,
cystitis or psychotic episode. Aversion sweets becomes important in all these cases.
The organism knows quite well what needs in order to function
so you have to pay attention to this.
In Nitric acid they take the fat from the others
and they eat it because they cannot digest it.
If you see the stool of Nitric acid is full of fat that’s why it is floating.
Because the fat is not absorbed. So the organism says give me fat!
In Natrum muriaticum; give me salt!
I can’t take enough salt from the food, give me salt!
Some people make their food white
and other people say for God sake how can you eat this food.
And yet their organism cannot absorb. In this boy there is another desire for cucumber.
Show me desire for cucumber. You will see Graphites is not there.
Antimonium crudum, Phosphorus, Sulphur, Veratrum album.
My question was, as you may have understood from my questions,
was it a case of Phosphorus after Causticum? This is not a good idea.
Because Causticum and Phosphorus are supposed to be inimical.
So if Phosphorus or Causticum had acted do not give its inimical
because it will upset the system. But Phosphorus was having the desire for cucumber.
So there are 2 possibilities here; either after Graphites the desire for cucumber
will be gone in which case Graphites has that symptom,
desire cucumber but is not recorded yet, or the desire for cucumber will remain
as the next remedy will be Veratrum album or Phosphorus. Possibly Veratrum album.
This is how we conceive the progress and what is going to happen in this boy.
I had another autistic child that went they brought it to me in the first place I said,
most probably Homeopathy will be able to help this boy so he can go to the university,
it did not go to the university school he is in a technical school now learning decoration
but the difference between this brain to an organized brain...
he plays chess much better than me, I am not a good chess player
but he will beat me very fast, he beats the computer,
playing computer chess is very difficult to beat it even the first level.
He beats the computer even in level 10. Like the child.
Like the child likes Mathematics.
The brain comes organized more and more and you observe this
and you feel really that Homeopathy is worth being established
as a complimentary health medicine. Just don’t forget this. Thank you.