-So since May you got no medicine and tell us what happened.
-Generally if I summarize all this year, since the first remedy which was in September
last year, the main problem remained the same, no change.
Actually I see some kind of aggravation. It's slightly worse I think.
-What you consider the main problem?
-The main problem is an inflammation in the prostate, in the area of the scar.
There was an operation 10 years ago of hernia. Since then there is a pain in the scar
of the operation and since then I think there is inflammation at the area of the scar
and I think it's in the prostate but I can't be sure about it.
-When was the operation?
-10 years ago.
-Where?
-On the left side on the inguinal area.
-You had a hernia left side on inguinal hernia and there you have a pain.
-Since then there is a lot of pain in the scar itself. Many times there is a sharp pain
and I need to press the scar and to bend like this and then the pain is relieved.
Otherwise I can't, it's really very painful and I feel that around the scar there is
some inflammation which I can't be sure where it is exactly.
I feel it's somehow related to the scar.
-But how you say prostate? Is the same pain that you attribute to the prostate gland?
-Whenever there is an effort to give stool, then there is some discharge coming out
and they examined the discharge and it represents inflammation in some place.
They took sample of the discharge, they examined it and they found out inflammation
signs in the discharge.
-But when did they take this?
-2 years ago.
-Not again.
-1 year ago as well, I don't remember exactly when.
-But not now.
-Not lately.
-What other problems?
-Generally there was constipation which has gradually improved.
Right now there is tendency to constipation but it's much compared to what it used to be.
There used to be very severe weakness last year, right now is slightly better.
I don't feel as I used to be but it's slightly better compared to last year.
-When you say slightly, can you put it in percent?
-40% better.
-Then what else?
-I went to India this summer, over there I got sick a few times and the process of
getting sick is always the same for me. First day I'm very weak, second day there is
pain throughout the joints and then there is a severe diarrhea.
This kind of cycle happened for 4 times in India and the 4th time I had no time to let it go
by itself, so I took one dose of Mercury 200C and then within one hour everything had gone away.
All the pain, all the weakness, within one hour everything was finished.
-Did you have fever as well?
-Yes.
-How much fever?
-Slight, not too much, maybe 38, 37.5, not too much.
-Did you have any excessive salivation?
-It comes and goes.
There is period where I see more signs of it and there is period which I don't see
any sign whatsoever.
-How is your psychological condition?
-Since last year when you gave me the remedy, I feel generally everything is less extreme
and the tendency to be extreme somehow became very mild.
When you gave me the remedy last year I felt that my personality wants to do
something in extreme fashion but the body, the organism stopped me.
I felt to go to study, let's say 24 hrs the day, but after 5 hrs I collapse, I sleep.
I felt as if the body does not allow me anymore to be in extreme and this kind of thing is still now,
I feel that all the extremes things in my life become more and more mild.
-All this tendency you had to do extreme things because you did a lot of extreme things
this has vanished totally or still there is some memory of that?
Sometimes you will say why don't I do that thing?
-My tendency generally is to put all myself in what I'm doing, like right now if I'm in
Homeopathy I will put all my energy into it, day and night, this is the tendency.
But I feel that after the remedy the organism does not allow me to do it.
After a few hours of doing something, something will happen. I will fall asleep
spontaneously, I will feel very hungry, I must go to eat, something will change.
I can't be in the same pattern of being so excessive about something.
As well something which changed, I used to be very protective, as if everybody is an enemy
in the Repertory...
-I remember that.
-Right now is less, I feel this tendency is less but generally I feel this tendency of feeling
as if people...
-They can't hurt you.
-This is less but I feel right now there is tendency of sadness and some tendency of depression,
which is more than as it used to be.
-This sadness has a reason? You are sad because you can not go there or you cannot
do this or that or it is, you would say, without any reason?
-There are two things in it. When I feel very tired or exhausted, it is followed by sadness.
I have tendency to be sad or depressed when I feel very tired physically.
Let's say I worked or learned for many hours.
-After physical exertion you feel sad?
-Whenever I feel weak, physically or mentally after hard work, generally comes with certain kind
of depression or sadness or want to be alone, leave me alone, don't touch me or engage with me
and then I have tendency to speak very fast, very hasty speech and to want to be by myself.
Then there is another thing.
I feel that this sadness relates to certain kind of feeling in myself, where I feel that I want
to express something and it's very difficult for me to express it emotionally or socially.
I feel as if in me there is a wall that I can't break through and that thing makes me more sad.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
-Yes.
What else was there and there are other changes?
-In me I used to be very aggressive, with more anger, with tendency of negativity and
right now I feel that all this is much less. I don't so much tend to explode in myself.
As well I feel as if there is in me two parts. One part is very mature, very old, almost too
old, as if I'm going to old too soon and one part is very childish, very young, needs protection,
needs somebody to protect me, there are two sides.
The one is as if I'm getting old too quick, as if I'm not in my age, 45 whatever...
-You are 45 now?
-No, 30.
-You feel as if you are 45.
-And from the other hand I feel as if I'm very young, like 5 years old, need protection
and need to be hugged.
-Did you have any change in temperature wise? You became more warm, more cold?
-I think generally more cold. In my basic constitution I think I'm very hot.
When I was younger, I used to perspire a lot and to be very hot in the body, I used even
to take the bathing suit, in the winter and take a shower in the rain, I was so hot.
Right now it's more cold.
-Would you say that now you cry more or you cry more easily?
-Generally it's very difficult for me to cry, I can't really say.
I can say that until the age of 12 or 13 I used to cry a lot, I used to be a very crying boy
and something around 12,13 completely stopped cying.
-It was out of an indication by your mother or your father, he did something to stop you
or by yourself?
-People around, the social situation was such that people were laughing at me when I was crying,
so there was a few situations where I was very offended, I was very insulted by children in my age
that were laughing at me and then I got completely closed since then.
-How is your sleep? You sleep how many hours?
-Sometimes when I 'm after many hours of work, I can sleep 10-11 hours, even 12 hours.
-And you wake up refreshed from that sleep?
-I feel good but it takes me a few hours to be totally awake. It takes 3-4 hours until I will
be totally awake.
-Do you take a nap in the afternoon?
-Never.
-So most of your energy what time comes?
-More in the afternoon and night. More at night.
-When you say night, after 8 o'clock or after 11 o'clock?
-After 9,10, then I feel that my concentration is much stronger.
For me learning is the best early in the morning or late at night.
-After 10,11,12 you feel awake or early in the morning, as soon as you wake up.
But this is opposite to what you said because you wake up and you are not awake and
you need 4 hours.
-But still I can be very drowsy but I can be very concentrated.
-In the evening you feel also better psychologically, emotionally?
-Always for me in the evening and night I feel better, even my confidence is better.
-How is your confidence in comparison with before?
-Improved, better.
-Do you feel more calm in general inside, more in peace with yourself?
-Generally yes. I feel more as you said. I used to be very agitated in myself.
Very irritable.
-Is any change in your desires-aversions for food?
-Lately I feel less need to eat, I don't feel so much to eat and I feel more need for meat
and for yogurt and for sweets. Sweets are always there for me.
There is always a desire for sweets.
-What about salt?
-Much less than it used to be, as well thirst much less than it used to be and as well with thirst,
there is more need for hot drinks. Because the temperature of the body is tends to be cold,
I feel like warming the body with hot drinks.
-You remember that you had an eruption coming out.
-Yes, there was two waves this summer, on the forehead, around the nose, behind the ears.
-Waves you said?
-Yes, twice this summer, as a wave, it came twice. One month ago and three months ago
coming and going, for 1-2 weeks and then it went away by itself.
-When you were in India, what time?
-May after we finished the course in May and then in July and August.
-You were in India, so the shin eruption came while you were in India.
-Yes and later on in Israel.
-Did you have this eruption after Mercury or before taking Mercury?
-Before and after.
As well there was a funny symptom which came a few times.
There was one symptom where I felt spontaneous tears coming and it feels like oil.
Lacrimation from the eyes and feels like oil, like cream and another thing which I noticed,
which is very strange, I sit or walk and I feel as if somebody is pouring cold water.
-Where? In the back?
-Through the body, shoulders, hands, feet and then I'm looking and the area is dry
and always it's surprising me, just sitting and feel somebody is pouring water and
then I look and the area is dry.
-You have the sensation of cold water.
-As if somebody is coming and pouring cold water, like this.
-In the whole body or in your feet, sometimes in the back?
-More in the extremities or legs but it can be anywhere. This has happened many times
and I remember it seemed to happen when I was child.
-This time is as strong as that time when you were a child?
-Now it's much more actually and it's very surprising me. I'm sitting very relaxed
or I'm walking and I feel actual sensation, as if someone is taking a glass of cold water
and pouring on me...
I'm looking and touching this, feel cold water but ... I'm amazed by it.
As well sometimes during the summer there was a few situations where I felt that I'm becoming
very sensitive, very delicate and as if the vibration of noise comes through my body,
as if I'm transparent.
It's feeling more the sensation of drops, not the whole water.
-Do you get any cramps in your legs?
-No.
-You feel that you have become more sensitive, you mean in your health, your strength
or emotional sense?
-My feeling is more a matter of spiritual and emotional sensitivity.
I can feel things which are very delicate, like I feel your vibration, if there is a noise,
I feel the vibration of the noise entering the body and leaving the body,
as if the body is more transparent.
As if I'm not in the body and I can feel things which are outside, entering and leaving.
-But would you say that this is a feeling like clairvoyance? That means you feel the
vibrations of the other person and you feel that this is happening or that is happening?
-Not so much, it's like let's say I feel the wind, sometimes coming through the body and
leave the body or the noise, I actually feel the vibration.
-But in your education, studies you have been taught, because you were doing healing
you have been taught to perceive this?
-Yes, for many years. Still I'm doing this.
-But this feeling has become more? You are more sensitized you would say?
-Yes, more easy to perceive vibration of different things and people also.
-You are in a hurry feeling inside?
-Generally yes.
The tendency is to feel as if I'm late always, as if I need to accomplish things
before whatever will happen.
As well this summer was much more back pain. I have a back pain for many years and
the lumbar region is very easy for me to pick the stress.
Whenever I'm in any kind of tiredness or stress the lower back will be painful, will feel unease,
will feel something is wrong over there.
-How is the perspiration? You perspire more?
-Not more than usual, actually less.
-And does the perspiration bothers you? It makes you feel uneasy, irritated?
-Generally yes, it feels very humid and hot area, I will feel very unpleasant with perspiration.
If I'm in a climate where I perspire a lot, I don't feel good.
-Do you have problems with your gums, teeth?
-The gums sometimes tend to bleed and sometimes tend to swell.
-When you say sometimes? Once the week or once the month?
-Once the month and when they swell, it becomes very painful.
-When did you have last time the swelling?
-A few days ago.
-It comes and goes like this?
-Maybe once the month or once every two months.
-Do you have salivation during sleep?
-Yes but that thing as well for the last two months I didn't have and for the last few
days I have, so I can't really say.
-Your breath is offensive?
-If I don't eat nothing in the morning, then after a few hours it will be heavy breath.
If I eat in the morning, then no problem.
-What about the taste in your mouth, do you have any particular taste?
-Not particularly.
-Metallic taste?
-No.
-The skin eruption the last time how long it lasted?
-About 5 days, 1 week.
The pattern of the skin eruptions is always very much the same
it's red, the skin becomes very rough ,very scratchy, I have to scratch it a lot.
When you touch it very gently, you feel good but if you scratch a little bit, it's very painful.
And it feels like you take a cube of ice to put on it, it's burning, you want to cool it down.
-How do you feel in here? Do you go to the sea? Do you swim?
When you arrived here in Alonissos, did you go to swim?
-No.
-The previous years you have swam in the sea?
-Yes but I'm not so much in favor.
-You do not care about swimming?
-Not much, I'm afraid of the cold lately more than usual, I know it will be cold.
-When did you notice this oily lacrimation?
-When I was in India.
-Your perspiration is not so oily now?
-If I'm heavily perspiring, then it's normal but if I'm perspiring slightly, then it's more
like cream, it's a creamy perspiration.
-Extremities are cold, hot, especially or they follow the body?
-They follow the body.
-Do you ever stick your feet out of cover?
-Never.
-Any problem looking down from high places?
-Would you say that you are suppressed? I mean from you mother, father, your girlfriend
and you are easily suppressed, you don't express your anger?
You get angry and you don't express it?
-Generally I feel more suppressed than not suppressed.
Not easy for me to express anger or any emotion and the anger in me will be aggregated,
aggregated and then it will explode. It won't come, I feel angry I will shout immediately.
It will aggregate.
-You keep it inside.
-And then after some time it will...
-And then what you can do? You can throw things?
-No, I will shout, criticize, I won't come to a violent state but I will be shout a lot.
-Are you especially afraid of physical pain?
-No.
-Very good.
-You have conclusion?
-It is very interesting in his case and something which is quite clear in his case is that
you know Mercury cannot stand extremes of temperature.
Mercury cases feel bad in extremes of temperatures, either cold or hot.
And he says, my character is to go to the extremes, that means the organism has
the tendency to go to extremes. You apply cold, it goes to the extremes it becomes very cold.
You apply heat, it goes to the extremes it becomes very hot.
The same thing is happened psychologically. It's very interesting for me also because the
first time I hear it, the way he described it, extreme sensitivity of Mercury.
Applying cold, becoming very cold, I cannot stand it, applying heat, I can not stand it.
And he has it in his character and he says, now I'm more balanced, not so extreme.
So it's the first time I had this expression and I wanted to make you aware of that
possibility. Yet you should not try to find this element in every Mercury case because
I don't believe that you see it again, unless you push the patient to say these things.
The question with this case is this. Mercury has done everything it could do for him?
Still Mercury is indicated or another remedy is indicated or placebo is indicated?
So this the question that we have to solve with his case.
Is he going to another remedy does he need to go higher on Mercury or we need to wait?
You see the dilemmas because he is doing quite well on mental, emotional and physical.
The whole organism is coming back to balance, yet the pathology remains, is it worse or
is it the same or it is a bit better?
5-10% better or worse or 20% worse, what is it?
-The last 10 years, every year there is gradual aggravation and as well this year I see
that it continues, there is more aggravation generally.
It's not too much but still I can see a line of aggravation.
-So actually it's becoming worse but little worse.
-10-20%. As well something which I forgot to mention, the last 2 months there is a sensation of water
in the right ear. When I walk or when I move my hand, I feel as if the right ear is full of water.
I can feel the movement, I don't know if it means anything.
-Sensation of water in the right ear, has anybody found it?
Antimonium crudum, Graphites, Menyanthes, Spigelia and Sulphur.
In the left ear? Only the right ear, Chromic acid, it comes and disappears suddenly.
-We have found it in chapter chill water.
-Where, in the back?
-Over the body.
-Chills as if water? What is the rubric?
-In chill.
-There is another rubric poured over him.
-It's like small drops of rain.
-Can we take it?
-It's not a matter of taking or not taking. When you study the case, you have to battle
and search all the Materia Medica to see if you can find exactly the symptom which the person has.
Search the whole Materia Medica because that may give you the clue of the issue.
Why do we search for this symptom? Why do we spend so much time?
-Because it's peculiar and new.
-Why do we search and spend so much time on that stupid symptom?
-Because it's 153 symptom.
-Because it's a new symptom and we are interested, is he going to another remedy?
What kind of remedy? How do we find if he is going towards a new remedy?
It is the new symptoms which will point out whether he is going towards a new remedy.
It seems that a lot of remedies have this symptom. Aconitum, Glonoinum...
and Thuja.
-Trinkling in many parts, this is what he said, he said sometimes is here, it's in
different parts.
-If this symptom belongs to Mercury, it is a different thing than belonging to another
remedy. If it belongs to another remedy, is it enough for us to prescribe on the strength
of that little symptom?
No. It's not correct that we jump into the picture and we just give him a dose of Thuja because
he has that peculiar symptom.
So his picture, in order to give Thuja, his picture of Mercury has to slowly disappear
go out and the picture of the other remedy has to come in.
What do you do?
-I would like to ask if this sensation of being transparent does bother him or not and how
would you explain George? Would you take this as a hint or as a symptom or not?
How do you see this?
-The sensation of Thuja is that of brittle, they can describe it in different ways.
Mostly they describe it concerning the spine, the vertebrae that are fragile.
If I move, suddenly my vertebrae might break or I'm fragile, made out of glass.
So we have to investigate whether this is the sensation what he said transparent or
he means a totally different concept.
-I feel as if I'm stepping outside of myself and I feel that the body is just empty and
things coming in, going out and I'm just standing aside and observe it without any
feeling to it and the body is very transparent, very hollow.
-It's not the Thuja feeling.
-This is a feeling of Cannabis indica.
-Yes, this is a feeling of Cannabis indica or Cannabis sativa and if Cannabis sativa
has the feeling of drops as well but the sensation is single drops and it's very clear
sensation. He looks, am I wet many times.
-It happened once when I was sitting in a bar and suddenly I feel as if there is drop of
cold water on my shoulder and I was jumping from the chair to catch the man who
is throwing cold water on my shoulder. And then I see it's nobody, I check it's dry.
-It's quite clear, quite strong symptom. Still you say the prostatic fluid is running out
when you press for stool? It's still running out?
-That thing still happens, still there.
-As much as before, less or more?
-I think it's either the same or more, definitely not less.
And the quality of the discharge is very sticky, like what you described as Kali bichromicum,
very stringy.
-It's not so easy.
Except of the pain, which is the other symptom that bothers you?
You will say that symptom bothers me also.
-The symptom which bothers me the most is the pain of the scar. Once more, if it's very painful
I have to bend down and to press it and then the pain is relieved, only like that.
If I do like this, the pain will be aggravated. If I bend forward it's better.
-And lasts how long?
-Maybe 1 min, maybe 5 min and then it will go away.
-Pain on the scar you have it? Cicatrices?
-As well there is another symptom, every time when I'm growing my hair there will be
a lot of dandruff and then it will develop into skin rashes. This is why I always cut the hair
because if it goes a little bit then full of dandruff, like snow.
-Dry?
-Very dry and then it develops immediately into...  or eczema.
-And then it will be oily the eczema?
-Burning sensation, red and dry sometimes, more oily but sometimes I see an area which is very dry.
-There is a rubric with this bending forward ameliorates in the generalities.
That's what he said, right? He bends forward and he feels better.
-It's the pressure, the pain is relieved by the pressure, pain in abdomen relieved by pressing.
So if you want to find pain bending double, ameliorates pressing you can be looking.
You see Staphysagria is one of the remedies which has pain in the incision and that is one of the
remedies we can be thinking and we would have liked that he has these drops that symptom Staphysagria.
Find this, find the type of cutting pain in abdomen, better pressure, pressure ameliorates
you don' have. Find in pain, pressure abdomen ameliorates.
It is pain cutting after operation 10 years ago, that's it no more.
-If Mercury works so well when he was acute ill in India, would it have done that if
it had been the right remedy?
-No, sure. The question we have now is Mercury has done all it could and now has
gone to the second remedy.
This is the problem and if he has gone to the second remedy what is this remedy?
And we are going to be guided by the new symptoms he has developed.
And the new symptoms he has developed are old symptoms that he had 15 years
ago, even more, 20 years ago he had that symptom.
That means 20 years ago he was on another remedy and then eventually Mercury
came. You give Mercury and the next layer is coming up and what is the next layer?
And what you have to deal here is a scar operation.
What we do? Who can tell me?
These are the remedies we may be thinking, either repeating Mercury, giving Staphysagria in
the pathology, giving Thuja because the prostate gland is affected and because he is having a strange,
rare and peculiar symptom or Thuja and Sulphur because it covers the totality of the symptoms.
And the most easy is placebo, why we bother?
We bother because we are. You are always concerned.
For me there is a problem.
He had an operation 10 years ago and he has this symptom since that time
and you give a remedy and he goes back 20 years ago when he had that symptom.
What has happened? Unless you understand really what has happened, you have a
layer, 20 years ago he had certain symptoms. Did you have warts?
-There was one wart for long time on this finger. Maybe for 5 years.
It disappeared the last year and didn't come again.
-There was only one wart since childhood?
-I can't really recall it, maybe there was one small wart on the hand, maybe 10 years
ago but I can't really recall that.
There was one which I definitely remember on the finger in the right hand.
It was maybe 5-10 years in this time, I can't remember and last year
it vanished after the remedy.
-Very confusing. My thinking would be like this. He was having a layer here and then
Mercury and on this layer he had the operation. Let us say this was a Thuja layer.
On this layer he had the operation and started with the pain and then eventually this
layer changed to another layer due to certain factors in his life.
We give now Mercury and this layer seems to go away.
What is left here is the supposed Thuja layer or it is another layer upon Thuja because
of the operation, which is Staphysagria.
Do you have to give Staphysagria and then Thuja or do you have to give Thuja?
-A few months before we start to learn here and before I receive the remedy, some
homeopath in Israel gave me Staphysagria and there was no effect whatsoever.
Otherwise I felt more tired and generally bend and I felt no good at all.
-This does not mean that this time he may not need Staphysagria.
This does not exclude the possibility of Staphysagria now after Mercury but it's good
that you give this information.
Your prostate gland has been examined?
-Yes, it was, he said it's perfectly normal, the size and everything. It's only the fluid
which comes out and in the fluid there is signs of streptococcus and staphylococcus
which represent inflammation.
-And that examination was 2 years ago or 1 year ago?
-Before the remedy anyhow.
-Do you have any affect on your urination?
-Sometimes if for any reason there isn't any possibility to urinate, it's accumulates
then it's very painful in the bladder and as well there is pinching pain in the urethra.
-When you go for stool, during stool do you have a running nose ever?
-No, I can't recall that.
-George, are you sure that the Mercury level is through are we looking for new remedy the picture
is not clear, only two new symptoms have been added, one for Sulphur and the other one,
I'm not sure which remedy Thuja maybe. But he is psychologically, emotionally,
mentally so much better after Mercury.
All his physical symptoms are only slightly better or maybe not better at all, is it not worth to try
to give one Mercury higher than the last time to see if the physical would respond to that,
before we move to another one?
-I'm afraid that if we give now Mercury, we will have no effect.
If there is a relapse, let us he goes and drinks coffee or he has an acute and the acute
brings a relapse, then Mercury will act. Now I'm afraid because of this symptom
we have the next layer, which most probably is not Mercury.
There is a possibility still is Mercury if this trickling was a symptom found in Mercury
yes I may repeat Mercury or repeat it many times but I'm afraid that this is the underline layer.
-I'm trying to remember while you're speaking and I remembered there was a few warts
when I was very young in age, on the hands.
-How they went away?
-Spontaneously, without any treatment.
-Definitely he has some symptoms of Thuja and if you repertorize everything that we're searching,
Thuja is coming many times.
-How frequently you have this pain? Every day?
-No, it generally can come once or twice the week or sometimes once the month.
There isn't any clear pattern. Definitely it's related to stress.
Whenever I'm stressed the pain comes.
-Give him Thuja 200.
-So this is the third follow up, you had another two follow-ups.
The last one was in October 97, so two years ago you had the last follow-up
where you took, the last remedy was Thuja and the first remedy was Mercury.
Tell me this period.
-Let me evaluate. I took also other remedies apart from Mercury and Thuja.
Let me tell you what I took and what was the effect of each one of them.
Let me begin from the first. First of all Mercury, you gave me a 10M, which I told you that time,
you didn't believe me so much, I say it again Mercury had an effect for 24 days exactly.
On the 25th day the action was absolutely finished.
What was the effect of the Mercury? Constipation was gone, I felt energy better, I felt
generally better, exactly for 24 days, I took a few doses of Mercury so I noticed that
each dose, even if it was 200 or 10M or 50M...
-Lasted only for 24 days?
-Exactly, absolutely.
-That's the first time I hear that.
-With the Mercury some people said, give me a reflection if you changed, I can't really
say I felt any difference emotionally from the Mercury.
I noticed that the main problem, the scar tissue which is inflamed and the prostate gland
also is somehow inflamed because of that, got aggravated once I was under the Mercury influence.
Then after a year you gave me Thuja 200C. The effect of the Thuja for me was very bad.
I felt very bad at any level. One day after the Thuja I got a few things which happened
immediately after Thuja, first of all constipation was gone in physical level, then I felt
for a few weeks sweet taste in the mouth, in such an extreme where everything which
I would eat would be also sweet, even if it was salty or bitter, everything which I ate
-Left a sweet taste.
-Which was gone after 3 weeks.
On the emotional level from the Thuja I felt really horrible. I felt as if there is a kind of a
war between me and the world, as if I'm covered with something and there is isolation
feeling and I felt really not so good and also the energy was depleting as the time went by,
then I sent you a fax, you told me to take Mercury 50M, I took it and it went back to
the original condition.
Then I had this incident, which I told you before, in Israel with people saw me in the street
and told me how are you doing and all this and I decided I'm not going to be here
anymore as a live case.
Then I think it was last two seminars where you described Staphysagria.
And after you described Staphysagria, I felt so much fit into it, so I took it by myself a few times.
-What potencies did you take?
-I took 200 and 1M and so I felt no difference at all. Then by advice of other homeopath
last year, one year ago exactly, I took Alumina 30C, daily dose for 10 days.
The reaction which happened from Alumina was a reaction that the constipation quite
immediately was gone and I got after a few days, a skin disease which later on I found out the name
of the disease was pityriasis rosea.
The whole body from the neck up to the elbow, up to the ankles, the whole body was
covered with skin rashes, which begun in the previous area and begun to go to the extremities.
So the whole body actually was covered with very severe skin rashes, which were not
itching, not oozing, just the skin was peeling off very dramatically.
This disease continued for 6 weeks, then for 2 weeks gradually went down and then it went away.
Then after about half a year, the homeopath which gave me Alumina, advised me to take
Nat. mur. which is the first remedy, which I really felt change emotionally, from the
remedy. He gave me Nat. mur. 50M and really this is the first time that I can really tell you
that I feel difference from the action of the remedy emotionally.
I felt much movement inside and I felt that things have opened up and something good is happening.
That time I was in India already, and I took Ignatia because I had an older condition
where the sighing was so severe and the pressure on the chest...
-Because of some grief or just out of the blue?
-No, because of some incident which happened.
And the breathing was so difficult, I actually had to stop and to concentrate on the chest
and to breathe slowly, so I can actually breath. I took Ignatia 200C, very good results.
Then after a week again I felt a grief, salt and thirst, I took Nat. mur. 1M.
Then after a week, after that again, sighing, can't breathe, Ignatia.
After a week again, thirsty, salty, grief, Nat. mur.
That went on for about 3 times to each remedy, Nat. mur, Ignatia, alternate.
Then in the middle of July it finished. I felt that I'm stabilizing and I'm feeling well.
Then the last remedy which I've taken it happened about a month ago, I was still in India
that time and I got very severe stomach poisoning. I drunk some milk, some yogurt and
one hour after that I got 40 degrees. And I was burned in fire, with delusions
and delusional condition.
There was one delusion come, take Belladonna.
I take Belladonna, I had an aggravation where I actually almost died.
Then the day after, I thought to myself every movement is aggravating, take Bryonia
I take Bryonia, no effect. Third day I thought Mercury last time was helping, I took Mercury,
also I had very severe aggravation where all the lymphatic nodes on the body were swelling and
were very painful, without an amelioration.
Then I took antibiotics because I was really in a bad shape, really in bad condition.
With 40 degrees and losing water, extreme diarrhea, extreme headache, the headache
was in such a degree where I could actually feel that the head would explode.
I took antibiotics for a few days which of course helped and as the disease begun to reduce,
I begun to develop a kind of very severe flu, sneezing and running nose and coughing.
And I didn't want to take any other more of allopathic medication, so I took Nux vomica.
That was the last one which I have taken.
-How long ago?
-About a month and a half ago, which helped for the symptoms of that flu which appeared
immediately after that condition but it did not help in the recovery of that acute condition
which I had before.
I mean the weakness, which I had, continued until a few days ago actually.
I still felt very sluggish, unbalanced and I felt not so good.
Only the last week I feel that I recovered fully.
After Nux vomica I felt that there is some disturbance of thinking, I feel heaviness in the head
and I can't think, I can't concentrate and right now it's still there.
I think it's coming from the Nux vomica, there is a kind of disturbance in concentration
and some heaviness in the head.
These are the remedies which I've taken so far; out of them I can tell you the only one
which I really feel it did something for me is the Nat. mur and Ignatia, as complementary.
All the rest I don't feel really did something.
-But you have taken before Nat. mur. in the past, 5 years ago?
-No, I didn't take. In the past I took only 2 remedies, I took for some years Staphysagria
first and then Stramonium.
-Before coming here?
-Before coming here I took only two remedies.
-You don't remember well. I will tell you, it's very simple. When you came here, you came
with 40 fever, a pneumonia, you were exhausted, you were in a terrible state and I gave
you Belladonna and after you go out of the acute, I gave you Calc. carb.
-That's right.
-You forgot already to mention two major remedies.
-I hope you remember how you were when you came here after antibiotics.
At that time you had again antibiotics but your condition was really very severe.
-Very similar condition happened to India this time, very similar condition.
-And that's why also if you were a little bit patient and you kept on taking the Belladonna
you would see with Belladonna you would finish.
But you were too fast, changing the remedies.
Because the explosion, what you described, even little things you described, seems Belladonna was
again indicated. If you had waited a little bit more, you wouldn't have to take antibiotics but anyhow.
If I understood you well you say the last week, you are back in good condition.
-The last week I feel that I am normal.
Let me tell you right now the symptoms which are rising the last half a year, more
prominently, more severe. First of all of course the same disease, which I' m here for
is the scar tissue, which is inflamed inside.
-The scar tissue where?
-In the inguinal left sides. I had a hernia operation.
-And still there is a pain? Cutting pain there?
-Tearing pain, cutting pain, knife like pain. Also there is discharge, once there is constipation
and there is the effort to pass stool, there is discharge.
-Discharge from the prostate?
-Yes.
Now they examined twice the fluid of the prostate and they found out that in the prostate fluid there
is a bacteria which can be found only in the large intestine.
A bacteria which exists only in the large intestine.
Because of this they sent me to colonoscopy and they found nothing. The examination was fine.
-How do they call the bacteria?
-Staphylococcus type D.
Whenever there is indication of the scar over there, whenever there is bloatness of the abdomen
or constipation or there is lots of urine which aggregates, when ever there is
stress in this local area, the scar tissue is extremely painful.
I can actually feel that inside is like this. If you take two pieces of meat and you begin
to stretch, this is how it feels.
-That is called tearing pain and it is very painful.
-If there is bloated stomach from flatulence or there is constipation or aggregation of too
much urine, because of let's say I'm sitting in movies and I can't go for two hours...
-The pain starts?
-Yes.
-This is for always but symptoms which arise and become lately strongly more
this symptom begun many years ago and there is extreme pain on the left side of the
hip, the hip is extremely painful, very painful up to the level that most of the time
I'm limping, I cant' go straight.
Another symptom which is happening the last two months, I have small warts over here
in the thumb, over here in the left leg, some in the abdomen and even though I speak to
them, they still resist.
Other symptom which is very old symptom and lately the frequency of that symptom
begins to come more and more, is that I have once for a while a pain in the liver
where I feel as if there is a hard ball below the ribs.
And the pain in the liver, definitely in that disease, in that acute it was very painful in the
liver area and also was swollen.
The liver is more painful when I become generally exhausted.
If I'm pushing myself too hard, if I'm learning too much, if I'm pushing myself too much
to the extreme, the liver becomes somehow sensitive, I feel some discomfort.
-Any headache?
-Not specifically.
Constipation tendency generally is still there, with a lot of flatusness.
-The flatusness comes with certain food?
-No.
-The dry eruptions that you had in your head originally, what happened with that?
-It didn't come back anymore.
-The constricting in your throat when speaking, you remember you mentioned?
-Yes, I think that Nat. mur. changed a lot also in this respect.
-What about salivation during night?
-This one is a symptom which is still there but much less and it comes and goes.
There is a period where it doesn't at all appear, especially when I'm becoming very weak
this is the time where you see saliva more, but if I'm generally OK, you won't see it.
-The aphthae?
-Again when the general condition is deteriorating, there will be some aphthae on the
gums, only on the gums and also the gums tend to inflame in general.
-Did you have this after this incident in India where your body went down very much?
-Yes.
-How is your self-confidence?
-Increasing gradually but still I feel that this is an area in myself which requires much
more improvement.
-What about the offensive breath from the mouth?
-After the acute was very strong, extremely strong but now it's not so strong, it's OK.
-And the constipation is better you say, than it was originally.
-From the original condition is much better but the tendency is there and I need
somehow to be aware of diet.
-The perspiration that was oily, is still oily?
-No.
-The tears were oily you have said.
-Not anymore.
-Also you have said a water sensation in the head, as if cold water was pouring...
-It also disappeared, I think that Thuja somehow took it away.
-And general amelioration in the evening, in the night?
-Yes, this still I feel it, when the evening comes, I feel more ease emotionally.
-How you feel after the stool?
-After stool I feel great, I feel that the sky is open, such a relief, the best time for me
to have new ideas, after stool.
The remedy is clear, what is the potency?
I did not look.
The remedy is there. What is the remedy?
Who says Nat. sulp.? Let me see the hands? 85% of the class, very good.
The remedy is Nat. sulph. I made it a little bit easier for you with the last question.
-Yes.
-There is a kind of very deep inflammation, which is going on there for so many years.
-12 years.
-12 years he has this inflammation and stays there, that's why the different remedies that
he has taken did not touch the case. But now is the time where most probably he will
have an effect on his prostate gland, which is there.
Show me why Nat. sulp. Show me the remedies.
You did not put the last.
Hip joint pain, liver, constipation, cheerful after stool.
So instead of Nat. mur. it's better Nat. sulp. What potency?
We start with 200 and repeat it accordingly, you wait, see what happens, if it's better
then you may have to repeat it several times to fight this kind of very persistent inflammation.
-Day by day?
-No, if you need it after 3 days, there is an amelioration after 3 days and you feel back the
pain, repeat it. But I would suggest also like the other case that you take 6X the salt, take
it 3 times the day, every day.
-OK.
-3-4 times the day you can take tissue salt.