-What was the last remedy?
-The last remedy I got was Natrum Muriaticum, 50M.
-One dose?
- Yes.
-What happened after Natrum Muriaticum? This you received in May?
-In May, on Tuesday, I can't remember the date.
I got immediate reaction concerning as if something was waving outside my head.
It was very strange because as if it was more strings or more the magnetic field.
It was not inside my head but outside, something stretching.
And it kept on the whole day, the first day and beside that I got itching around my nose.
I had to sit like this all the time because it was really annoying;
then it came a pain in my neck, it went forward to the front head, on both sides I got a pressure.
Then I got a sudden need for urinating.
-Sudden urinating. A lot?
-When this came on I suddenly had to go to the toilet.
Then I got a stitching pain in my upper abdomen. That was the first day.
The second I woke up refreshed, as I always do but about 10.30-11.00 o'clock
the head pain started again, the same kind.
I got a lump in my throat, I started to get a feeling I wanted to cry.
-Without reason?
-Yes without reason, so I had to swallow a lot just not to start crying inside.
Then I got a pain in my left knee.
-For how long?
-Just that day, it went cracking while walking.
I could hear the sound. In the evening when we went eating, I usually don't eat ice cream
but I got a sudden craving for it that evening.
And the next day too. The third day my intestines were rambling a lot, I told you about last time
that I was very bloated. This was very intense.
The stitching pain came in my right side in the liver area and it went towards this side
and it was just after eating that stitching pain.
In this area it was before eating and when I was eating it went on to this side.
All these days while I was staying here, I only stayed for one week
because I went to a course in Denmark and all this time my eyes were very sore,
it was like if I had stones or sand inside and I got some pus but that I already told about.
-Pus?
-Some yellow pus in my eyes.
The same headache came on and I was generally very tired, it started again, exhausted.
-Which day is this?
-The third day. I was a bit tired the two first.
-But the third day it was more.
- Yes.
As the time passed by, it got more and more and more.
So I couldn't nearly keep on with the lecturing in Denmark, I had to lie down for each break
to sleep and I just vanished.
While lying...
-Immediately you slept?
-Immediately I slept.
But then something changed with the head pain because in the beginning it started at 10.30
and 11 o'clock but after these 3 first days, it started to come on in the evening at 6.30-7.
My voice started to vanish ...
-Started to vanish without having a cold?
-Yes I didn't have any cold that time. I was swimming a lot.
-Swimming where?
-In the sea, down here.
-You are talking still while you were here?
-Yes.
And I also got a pain in the left side, in the lower abdomen and that had stayed until today.
-That pain in the left ovary?
-Yes. I don't think it's the ovary, it's the large intestine.
-How do you know it's in the large intestine?
-Because somebody told me, not a doctor but somebody else told me that it was in the intestines.
-OK we'll see.
-Just a stitching pain and sometimes is also pressing.
-Then when I got to Denmark, I told you I was very tired and I also thought
that it was too much with all these people.
I was really having a hard time because they were people all around me,
I couldn't go anywhere to sit by myself because I was living together with another student.
So I felt in a kind the way I described you about the house that in a way I was trapped.
But the feeling went away after one week at home, so you did a marvelous work.
I had a marvelous summer and everything has been to me in a way like coming home into myself.
I would like very much to thank you for this.
-Thank Homeopathy, not me.
-But not only the Homeopathy, it's the right remedy.
-The right remedy of course.
-I started to get the 23rd of May, I started to get eruptions on the skin
as if I was bitten from the mosquitoes. Most came on in this part on both sides.
I think I had two, one on my arm and one on my leg.
-Did you have this eruption before as a child?
-No.
I can have them when I drink white wine, I had it once in Germany but then they came on this spot.
-When you say then you mean with the wine?
-Yes with the wine but they look like the same.
It's stayed nearly for two months before they vanish; so in the 27th of May
I got this therapeutic blister on my left labia, it came on again.
The same head pain kept on in the evening and it started the itching in my right eye,
as it was a small spot but it's not like a pain but more like a soreness in a spot.
I had a period of time where I kept on this pain in my stomach, just after eating.
3rd of June I started to itch all over my body and that I have had several times.
There and there.
-Without eruption?
-Without eruption yes but it nearly killed me.
It' s just moved on and I started to have the cramping pain in my left hip;
that's also a symptom which I told you about, pain from the hip extending to the leg
and I got more irritated on the herpetic blister, it was more painful than it had been the last times.
At 10.30-11 o'clock I got so tired. Usually I go to sleep at 1.30 in the afternoon,
because then I need to go to sleep, so I take a break with my patients.
-1.30 in the afternoon you take a break?
-Yes because then I'm too exhausted to keep on but now the time changed.
I also had a lot of acid in my stomach in the evening.
I felt like I was hungry or wanted to have something in it because it was too much acid.
I also felt that the hemorrhoids wanted to come out but it was just a feeling,
but it actually didn't happen, it was a bit irritating.
During the whole summer I've drinking a lot of water, much more than I usually drink.
Normally I would have it a little bit warmer in the daily temperature
but now I have to have it cold, really cold.
But when I drink, when it's cold, I get pain in my teeth and because of that I urinate more
but when this bloatedness in my lower abdomen comes on, I feel that when I urinate
I'm not finished, so I have to ...
-To wait. Some drops are coming after?
-It's not only drops, it's a little amount of urine.
-Interrupted urination.
-And the same happens if I wait for a long time to urinate.
Generally I'm taking a little more sweets which I nearly not eat at all
and I'm very tired in the evening and that's unusual for me because I can't be up to 12 o'clock
and wake up at 5.45 and be refreshed.
But I have to go to sleep at 8.30 in the evening and I've got a stiffness around my ankles.
It's not a pain, it's not a swelling, it s a feeling of a stiffness.
-Stiffness in the ankles?
-Both ankles yes but it's mostly while sitting.
I've done a lot of study and if I sit for a long time this sensation comes on.
I'm itching much inside my hands without eruptions.
The hip pain, which I told you about, I have observed that it is much more intense
the day after having intercourse.
Then it really hurts and sometimes I feel as if they are coming on cramp in my leg,
but it's mostly if I do some exercise.
I got a warts in my front head, so I have to pick it away because it's dry.
The whole summer I had pain in my teeth, so I had to go to the dentist
because it was aching and really feeling bad.
-What the dentist did?
-He examined, there was nothing wrong but he said it might be this upper part of the teeth
which the flesh has drawn back.
Generally I'm very warm, but I've never been sweating in my hands before.
Now I'm wet in my hands and my feet and hands are burning.
-And you take them out?
-Yes this summer I had to.
-Mentally and emotionally I'm very good, I'm not so restless, I enjoy the daily life more.
I think I can speak more freely, it's easier to take contact with people and have a conversation.
I realized how easy I got hurt before during this period and how sensitive I've been to criticism,
so now I can hear things and I can see them but I don't feel them anymore.
It's a very strange way of recognizing or being aware.
I also have seen how afraid I was to say or do anything wrong,
so I'm much more free to speak, in a way.
I'm also much more sensitive, my eyes get wet when I talk about something that's good
or when other people do the same.
-You are touched.
-Very much, I get gooseflesh and tears and generally I feel more organized.
It's easier for me to keep things, one at the time and not have 10 things going on
at the same time; that's also something I have realized during this period
that I had too much on at the same time. I've got lot of sexual power.
Actually so much that sometimes I get embarrassed, myself;
so to me now it's a kind of problem.
-But always as a young woman, at the age of 18-20 you had a lot of sexual energy or never?
-No. Sometimes at the age of 24 or 25 I had it.
-You returned to that age. Everybody will ask for your remedy.
-But I have to tell you, after coming down here, the last mense period started a week later than usual.
But at that time I went to have my first lecturing in esoteric philosophy,
so perhaps it was because I was a bit upset doing new things and give lecture...
-You stressed yourself.
-Yes maybe, that was what happened. But while coming down here I started to get some stringy,
bloody discharge and it went on for 3 days and then it started to become like bloody water.
It's not much, it's just drops.
And generally I perspire a lot here.
-Yes it's quite warm.
-But I don't get the skin eruptions anymore, I've been to the sun. That's good.
-How you feel in the sea? Are you swimming?
-I'm going down 6.45 swimming in the morning.
-You enjoy it.
-Yes but I noticed that in the morning while swimming alone, I'm aware of what is underneath.
In a way, I might be a little afraid of what's underneath while swimming.
-We don't have sharks here in the sea.
-I just noticed it and I also get pain in my throat and yesterday my voice was vanishing again
but today is OK. That's about it.
-You gave a very detailed information, we don't have to ask more questions.
Did you ever have any gonorrhea?
-No never.
-You eat fruits which are unripe?
-No but I've started eating more fruits.
-But ripe, sweet fruits or not? You don't need sour?
-No but when I eat the dinner, I put a lot of this lime lemon.
Wait, new remedy, same remedy, higher potency? Which is for higher potency?
Same remedy? New remedy? Wait?
It is understood we can proceed, we have to wait, wait, 1,2,5 years,
as long as you don't drink coffee, you don't take any medicine...
And be careful also the Natrum Muriaticum cases, you have to tell them, not to take the mint.
The mint is affecting, washing your teeth with menthol toothpaste.
-I've done it several times.
-Change your toothpaste.
-It's a mouth wash, that's no good.
-I use some drops while having patients, I put them to my mouth.
-No, be careful. You use something else if you want to refresh your mouth, not menthol.
Last time you did not take any medicine,
so your last medication was Natrum Muriaticum 50M, one year ago.
Tell me how you are, how you feel.
-Psychologically I feel good, I have some problems with writing letters.
I suppose it's because of Natrum Muriaticum, I don't know, I've never had it.
-What do you mean writing letters?
-When I go to take a "d" I write "g" and I also when I want to say something,
sometimes words don't come out; that's also something I'm not used to that.
It is not often but as I stand and talk with people...
-As if you stammer?
-No, I can't find the word.
But my main problem is physically.
I'm so warm, I'm sweating in my hands, all my life I've been very dry in my hands.
-And now you are sweating extremely. Only on hands or on the whole body?
-During the night time when I have the menses, I have profused sweating.
I'm totally wet on waking in the morning.
-What time you wake up?
-I've started to wake a little bit later, about 6.45.
-Every night you wake up with perspiration?
-More during menses but I'm always very, very warm.
I have to have my feet out of the covers during winter time.
-Before you came here from Norway, did you have this sweating?
-Yes all the winter time but not like this.
-Now it's too much.
-I have to have the window open while I'm sitting and working and my patients always say my god,
how can you sit here? They are freezing for half an hour but I say, I have to have this cold room;
otherwise I couldn't work because I start sweating immediately,
when I start working with the foot reflexology.
And I started to write to you twice because this has been really a problem.
-You like to have a lot of water or cold drinks?
-I have to drink a lot.
-And you need cold water or warm water?
-Yes, more cold than I needed before. Much more cold.
-And big quantities or all the time just a little bit each time.
-No, I drink a lot like a glass of water.
-Do you also like to take more sweets lately?
-Yes, I've done that. Not much but I'm never used to sweets, so to me it's...
-It's a new habit.
-Yes, it is and not a good one actually because I gain weight.
I also have eruptions during the winter time when I'm sweating and I get cold,
I have to scratch on my bag and in the back of my head and in this part...
-Of the palm.
-Yes, that I still do, itching here.
Eruptions, itching. But something that I've never had before, it has also come up lately.
I feel a pain in my chest, I feel that it's difficult when I walk upstairs, if it's a hill.
-You have a pain on your chest.
-I wouldn't call it a pain, it' more like something is there in a point.
-Discomfort.
-Yes and I went to a colleague because I started to get afraid that I will have a heart disease.
-You did a cardiogram?
-No, no just to a reflexologist and I didn't say what it was but he told me
that the aorta hurted under the feet. And I'm smoking a lot,
so I was afraid that I got a heart disease.
-You smoke a lot? How much 20?
-Yes.
-Not 20, it's 25 actually, I saw it in your eyes.
-Maybe some days.
I know I smoke too much.
I also noticed that two days before menses are the most cold days for me.
-You feel cold?
-Yes and then I get some shivering.
-You like a cold or hot bath?
-I like to bath in the sea but I just got the menses,
so these two days before I didn't want to go to the sea but I'm swimming 4-5 times
when I come, cool bath.
-And hot?
-Not so much I don't like it because usually my husband is on the shower
more hot than me so I have to put it down.
-What about the odor of the perspiration? There is any odor?
-Sour. But it also could smell a little bit under the axilla while I work hard but mostly is more sour.
And I also got a lot of pimples in the neck.
-On the margin of the hair.
-During the winter time I had a lot of headaches.
-Did you find yourself in a high place looking down, can you tell me your experience?
-I can't tell because I haven't been out in high places but sometimes I get a little bit dizzy
just for a little moment, feeling that I don't have the balance.
-In high places?
-No, even in flat ground, it's coming suddenly and I have to do like this;
I feel like I'm having a vertigo in a way.
-You did not mention the pain in the left ovary.
-Yes I have it but it's more in the right now. And it goes from one side to the other.
This time was more on the right side, stitching pain.
-As strong as before, more, less?
-I think it was very strong this time. More strong than before.
-How is your organization? You're organized or disorganized?
-I have to pull myself up to be organized because I put things away.
-You just throw things around?
-Yes I do. It's a mess.
-You are disorganized actually.
-Yes, very disorganized, my husband says.
-So we have to organize you.
-That would be good.
-Sloppy.
-When I get stressed, I have a headache.
It's coming about the 7th thoracal on the back to occiput.
-How frequently you get this headache?
-Not so frequently as in the winter time but it's really much because I work a lot
and every time I get stressed, I got this headache.
-It was after exertion?
-Yes and I'm much more tired in the evening. I told that I wanted to take a nap about 1.30
but that I don't do so much anymore and I'm tired at 6.30 in the evening.
-Stiffness in the ankles that you have mentioned last time?
-Yes, that's got more because I got some cramps.
-About the stiffness I want to know first.
-Yes, in the ankles but all up to here.
-Is it stiffness or cramps?
-The stiffness is in the ankles but I feel as if the cramp could come.
-Itching on your nose?
-Not so much anymore but I can have it from time to time.
-This is perhaps the time where you can take your next remedy.
-I hope so because this warm is really killing me.
-And it will be Sulphur 200, a dose of Sulphur 200.
-I like to be well, so it doesn't matter what remedy.
-The problem with Sulphur is that maybe your eruptions which have started,
the itching and eruptions may become more and that will be a good reaction, don't stop it.
-Yes sure.