I have promised that I will see Dr Bennis from Germany, he is a very good homeopath,
excellent homeopath and he has sent a case which he was treating,
it is in your hands now.
A case of a young male 31 years old, married with two daughters,
who first went for consultation..
I had a look and the first look I have seems that the case is incurable,
as far as Homeopathy is concerned. We can not do almost anything with this case.
But since I did not have a good look, we are going to look together
and see if we can make a better prescription than the prescription
that was given which was Alumina, Phosphorus and then Alumina phosphorica.
It is a case of diabetes, treated with fixed amount of insulin since 1994
and then he had a hemorrhage into the corpus vitreum of both eyes, first left,
then right since September 1996.
One and a half year before detachment of retina.
So he had detachment of retina and then he had hemorrhage in the eyes
which developed in the 9th of 1996.
Visual aptitude reduced a lot since September 96. Now left nearly blind and 16 to 24...
I don't understand what it is.
-Per cent.
-Are you sure? 16 to 24,6 %?
-Yes it is per cent.
-The man is almost blind.
-Not at all.
-16 % you can see with one eye?
-It's working.
From the clinical examination one would have to say this man is practically blind,
the objective examination says this, but subjectively the man says, I can see quite well.
-It's still working, so yes he can see and function.
-A boy who has lost both his eyes and works for the Ministry of Transportation
doesn't mean anything.
-But he can see still, he can see both his daughters for instance and he can work
and function with it. He is going to work every day.
-What do you mean "can see"? He can see shapes or just barely can differentiate
whether this is one daughter or the other?
That's what you mean. All right. We said almost blind, we didn't say blind.
All answers come out only very difficult, very tenacious, slow moving,
even the easiest question is answered with great difficulty.
So here we have a mental symptom, which we can find in the Repertory.
Now you go to the Repertory, you look hemorrhages in the eyes, which is the pathology.
Then diabetes. Diabetes and hemorrhages are close to a remedy,
which is called Phosphoric acid. We said yesterday on Phosphoric acid, we have diabetes.
We can see the repertorization here. Answers slowly, so by these two  things that we see,
diabetes and slow answering, here we see Phosphoric acid is the remedy
that we have to be thinking.
As we said Phosphoric acid produces diabetes and produces also this slowness, mental slowness,
difficult thinking. What is the symptom here?
Always answers come out very difficulty, very tenacious, even easy questions are answered
with great difficulty, the more the pressure, the more difficult it gets for him to answer.
He says, I know the answer, some keywords but I can't remember the sentences,
so forgets the words as in Phosphoric acid.
Go to the Repertory and find 'forgets words'. Phosphoric acid capital.
So you are learning Phosphoric acid.
You remember when I described Phosphoric acid, I said he tries to remember the word,
he wants to say the word "glasses" and he looks at the glasses and he can't remember.
He says, 'you wear glasses' finally but it takes a long time to think
and to bring back the words. So actually here it says some keywords that can not remember.
No feeling gets to the surface in an obvious way.
Anger, wants to hit somebody and what comes out in the end is a quiet talk.
How you will look for that symptom? No feeling comes to the surface.
That means feelings do not surface, do not come out and the man looks quiet.
Find the rubric quiet. He is very quiet on the outside.
Look at this rubric. Did you see the rubric? What you see again?
You see that Phosphoric acid is again very strong.
If I had given you this case for examination...
You know what happens if you don't answer correctly.
I don't know how he missed this because the first remedy...
For everything he needs time and preparation, then he can work a lot and well.
If he is surprised or should react spontaneously, he breaks off and stops.
He does not find the words, again.
Nothing comes out of him. That's why he plans everything.
He says, I never get up and just think - let's see what happens.
It says that he has to plan carefully what he does, otherwise he can not perform.
That means his mind is very slow, his feelings are not existent.
There is a kind of slowness of the mind, slowness of the feelings.
He can not remember words, he says, I can't, I try to say a word and I can not find the word.
-The patient together with Dr Bennis, this is what Dr Bennis has sent me.
It is not true that he is got no feelings, he's got very, very strong feelings
but he can't get them out. He is so angry, he could kill somebody,
it's very strong feelings that he has.
But when he tries to bring those feelings out, on the way
while he is trying to bring them out, then he ends up with this quiet talk.
-Exactly and that is why we say to be quiet is not pathology.
To be calm and quiet is nice and it is not pathology. Pathology is when you are not quiet
and you are forced by the disease to be quiet. Then it is pathology.
Correct? Understood? This is what he says. He can not express any feelings.
It is the same thing. It doesn't matter, deep down we know.
Pronounced lack of self-confidence. Look lack of self-confidence.
Phosphoric acid is not appearing, fears, dependence, fear of being depending,
that something happens to his children or wife, darkness and spiders.
Are these fears strong or mild?
-The depending is very strong; the other fear that is very pronounced is that the fear
that something will happen to his wife or children.
For instance if he sees his children running out into the garden, he will immediately connect
that with an accident, that some accident will happen to them. He gets the vision of that.
-Put anxiety about others and lack of self-confidence, twice both.
Fear of dependence we don't have it as a symptom but here is not a symptom, it is a fact.
He has a fear that he will depend on someone who will take him to lead him
because he can not see.
-But he had that before also, before getting so sick and soft of depending,
he has already had that symptom.
-There is no symptom in the Materia Medica but I say in such serious cases,
this is a juvenile diabetes, they know the future.
The future is very bleak, very bad and put fear of darkness underlined once.
She says it is not so strong.
Anxiety about others, twice. He could not pee in front of a lot of people.
Whatever he does has to be perfect. Building a toy for the children has to look as if bought.
Car clean, obstinate, has a difficulty to not follow his plan.
Desires bread with cheese and sausage without butter, prefers cold food.
Prefers cold food, put it twice. Bread with cheese we don't have it as a symptom.
We have bread and we have cheese but not bread with cheese.
Headache above left eye after straining the eyes.
Put headache above left eye.
Worse in the morning, has to sit on the bed for quite a while before he starts seeing something.
Worse after sleep, also you put it underlined twice.
Head pain forehead, that's more correct.
I'm just doing this to show you that most probably even if you put all symptoms in the case,
once you have put the strong symptoms with underlining them properly,
the repertorization will insist on Phosphoric acid and will say the remedy is Phosphoric acid.
12 symptoms they are put already. Show me the columns.
Nux vomica, Phosphoric acid, show me Phosp. acid.
She did not underline properly, answers slowly is very strong, it has to be 3 times,
just put it 3 times. Forget words it's so strong, at least 3 times.
Quiet disposition also this so strong, 3 times, show me now the analysis.
Not only it says Phosphoric acid but there is no other way that you can analyze this case,
you can not give another remedy. The remedy is Phos. acid,
it doesn't matter that it does not cover all the symptoms,
it covers the main symptoms and the main symptoms are strong and this is the remedy.
So here in this case, you have a good example of Phos. acid with a difference,
that the pathology underlying such a case is so strong that it is doubtful
how much you can help such a case.
And because the pathology is sensitive here, you have to be careful of the potency.
In this case you really have to be careful of the potency
and what could be the best potency for him? What potency you would suggest for him?
Very low like 6X or 6C, medium like 30? How much insulin he needs?
-40.
-It's quite a lot.
-What about LN potencies?
-I have not been convinced that LN potencies can handle a situation of that type.
I don't know, I haven't got the experience, I have given it a few times only.
I know the potencies how they work in the centesimal, 1 over 100,
so I would suggest in this case 6C, 1/100 6.
-Blood sugar all his life long was really difficult to handle
and after receiving Alumina for the first time in his life he could manage his blood sugar.
-What does that mean? You said blood sugar was unstable, going up and down,
is that correct?
-Yes.
-And after Alumina it steadied to a level,
is that correct?
-Yes.
-The level to which it stayed what it is? Now it's 40 units, before what it was?
It was 50, 60 and then 20?
-The blood sugar levels in the blood would differ between 350 and 60.
So 350 is far too much and 60 is too little.
So before, even though they were giving insulin, it was changeable, very changeable.
-Wait a moment. With the same amount of insulin, the readings on the blood
would be different, is that what he is saying?
-I'm trying to say this. Until 1994 he had a fixed amount of insulin
that he was getting to try to control his blood sugar but it was never possible.
Then after 1994 he got flexible amounts ...
-No, first consultation in 1996, is this incorrect?
-No, three lines underneath, just read.
-Since 1994 flexible treatment with frequent controls of blood sugar.
That means from time to time he would go up to 60 units
and then come down to 20 units of insulin.
Flexible treatment means changing the amount of insulin needed at the moment,
according to the blood reading.
In any case chronologically this does not correspond with the homeopathic treatment.
Chronologically it says until 1994... and then flexible treatment with frequent...
-George, if you look in the follow ups you will see that before he had either rigid
or flexible amounts of insulin but the blood sugar was never able to be controlled.
Then after getting Alumina for the first time in his life
the blood sugar was never more than 200.
It was always between 150 and 250 but it never really shot up anymore.
So her question is, what does that mean concerning Alumina?
-Before I can answer what I want to know is when the treatment was flexible,
it was coming from 20 units of insulin to 100 units of insulin or what?
This is what I'm asking in order to be able to make an assessment.
-What happened was that the amount of insulin actually he could not reduce at all,
whether he did it rigidly, with a fixed amount of insulin or whether he did it
in the way of flexible amounts of insulin.
The only advantage when he put flexible amount of insulin was that he
could control his blood sugar a little bit better, so that the peaks of blood sugar
would not be so high anymore. So the amount did not differ.
-How is that possible that the amount does not differ if the treatment is flexible?
How is that possible? It's not possible for me to comprehend that.
Flexible treatment means either you take every second day,
either you take different amounts of insulin every day, this is flexible treatment.
-So basically he gets three different types of insulin.
One is the old insulin, the long acting insulin, this is the basic treatment
and he gets it all the time.
Then to cut the peaks of insulin, he takes some sort acting insulin
and this differs from day to day.
-Anyhow, she was asking whether this steadying it means a better situation.
I'm not sure, it may mean a worse situation. In order to decide whether it is better
or worse it depends on the amount of insulin needed now than before.
If now he needs more amounts of insulin, that whole situation got worse
and became steady yes, but before the organism was trying.
Sometimes bringing down, burning the sugar. And the sugar was going down.
Now it does not burn the sugar, so you can not say it is better unless you know
that before he needed 100 units and after the homeopathic treatment, he needs 40 units.
Then we cay say yes it is better, it had an effect on the diabetes.
I don't know if it had an effect on his mental-emotional.
In any case, seeing the case, since you want an advice, I would say without question
I would start this case with Phosphoric acid, I would go to low potency of Phosphoric acid
and give repeatedly three times the day and then this Phosphoric acid,
I would raise it every week one potency.
First week 6C, second week 7C, third week 8C and you go like this
and by the end of three months maybe you can find out
whether the treatment is giving some positive effect.
So three times daily, 6C, 7C, 8C, 9C, 10C...
But my question is why I say this? Most probably it is an incurable case.
Because it is a juvenile diabetes and when we have a juvenile diabetes,
the treatment is very difficult to have an effect.
The pathology is very deep, the pancreas, the islets of Langerhans are totally destroyed,
they do not produce any insulin, so how can we improve this situation?
I'm not sure we can do it.
Interesting enough, you remember in Phosphoric acid, just put back Phosphoric acid...
Diabetes in its progress state gives symptoms of Phosphoric acid.
It is a typical pathology of diabetes because it affects the circulation,
the vascular system. You see there? Diabetes.
We have the elements, the apathetic, the indifference and the weakness
and the emotional progressing to the physical and mental planes.
The weakness on the emotional level which affects the mental level
and which affects also the physical level. How it affects?
It affects in this way exactly, as he describes in this case.
So it was a good case for learning live something about Phosphoric acid.
You remember I described to you how difficult it is to find words.
He says, I can't find words. He says it so clearly as if he is talking on Materia Medica,
Phosphoric acid Materia Medica is this what he is talking.
-How do you explain the anger which can not come out? He is very angry.
-Be in that state and you will see how..
-I have the same question for apathetic. That means for me
that there is nothing in and nothing comes out, here there is a lot of emotions inside
but do not come out. It's a big problem.
-Yes, here in cases of grief we see really this total flatness of emotions.
Grief takes away the emotions.
We have a pathology here, we don't have grief, we have a pathology which brings about,
but the total result is the same. He can not express any emotion. His mind is very slow.
He cannot find the word, he cannot answer. You go to the repertorization
and you see all these symptoms very strongly on Phosphoric acid.
But still now Phosphoric acid will not cure this case.
-How can I recognize which potency I have to take?
-Here we go low because of the possibility of hemorrhage.
A little bit stimulation on the vascular system, on circulation, may produce some hemorrhage.
So we have to stimulate as little as possible and slowly.
It's like pushing somebody very nicely.
Maybe it can be pushed, it's not sure at all because once an organ is finished,
then you can not replace it. Never mind how much you push.
Something which is dead will never start working, it will stay there dead.
If there is any possibility of regeneration of the pancreas, maybe there is,
I don't know, God knows only.
I'm not in a position to know, but experience shows,
because I have tried several cases of juvenile diabetes, little effect.
-George, what are the other major remedies that you might be thinking of for diabetes?
-Best remedy for diabetes is Natrum Sulphuricum and remedies
which have strong desire for sweet things and at the same time they have strong thirst.
They can be like Sulphur, Argentum nitricum, Lycopodium. These are remedies for diabetes.
-Uranium nitricum.
-Uranium nitricum yes, when the sugar comes mostly out in the urine.
When you have urine loaded with sugar there is a possibility.
I have tried the Uranium nitricum several times, I have not seen the effect.
Maybe we don't have enough information to prescribe more accurately the remedy.
It is true, it is written like this.
-What about (?) It's often suggested.
-I don't know.
-I don't also know.
-But I have seen simple cases of diabetes, when diabetes starts at the age of 40, 45, 50
and they come early, the best remedy is Natrum sulphuricum in the beginning,
Sulphur is a second remedy, Argen. nitricum is another remedy, Lycopodium is another remedy
and Phosphoric acid once the effects of diabetes have gone into the vascular system
and they produce a similar state like this. This is too strong.
If you can imagine the effort of this man to survive, the will power
that he exercises every day. His mind is totally empty, can not receive and react.
You can understand.
He says, I know the answers... for everything he needs time and preparation.
Then he can work a lot and well. If he is surprised or should be react, forget it.
He breaks off and stops short. He does not find the words. Nothing comes out of him.
Never mind these remarks, I described to you how the person tries to say a word,
even he sees the object and he can not bring the word to his mind.
I look at the telephone and the word is totally gone on my mind.
And they try..... telephone. It takes so long. They look at it..... Glasses.
You see how slow it is?
It is described here, it's very beautiful, Phosphoric acid in Materia Medica.
It can not be better, I could not have described it better.
Here you write first hand and then what he says, quiet, I come out and I'm quiet!
Many times I have said what is quiet? It's not good to have quiet?
It's good but when it's pathology, because of pathology you are quiet, then that is a symptom,
this is the symptom, this is the situation.
I have become very quiet, because of pathology, it's not my type.
And then it's a change, then it's pathology.
In spite of the fact this is considered to be a healthy quality.
If somebody is calm inside and because of this calmness he feels quiet and never gets mad,
it's very fine, it's very good, this level is very healthy.
He says, I'm quiet because I can not do otherwise and perceives deep down inside some anger,
whatever it might be, feelings etc.