-Please can you see to come? Can you come here? Please help her.
So you see the eye, just zoom the eye, she can not open it.
There is a swelling on the upper lid quite severe,
there is an inflammation on the margin of the lids
and the swelling seems to be quite edematous and the pain...
The swelling is coming up all the time, most probably it will reach quite...
Do you feel your eye is OK? I will open a little bit just to see.
Is it painful as I touch it?
The eye is OK, the sting is on the eyelid and do you have pain?
-Yes and in my eye. More on the lid.
-There is a lot of water running.
If the eye was red and the lacrimation was burning, the remedy would have been Euphrasia.
But the eye is not affected in this way, it is not red, it is painful,
she is very sensitive to touch, there is a tremendous swelling,
there is the stinging pain and therefore with some kind of confidence, not completely,
we can prescribe a dose of Apis.
-I was stung by wasp three weeks ago at home under the sole of my foot,
I had stepped on it and at first I took Apis and it got worse and then I took Ledum
and also bathed my foot in Ledum and it was good after one hour.
-Very good. Wait a moment.
-I feel worse enough already, I don't want it to aggravate in any way.
-Yes sure but what I want, did she develop a reaction to this wasp?
She was really bad, the foot became swelled up or a thing like that?
-The foot was this swollen and the pain was so strong that I could not walk anymore.
-That means she has an allergic reaction towards the sting,
so we have to be more on the alert for what might happen.
Since she has a remedy which has helped her before in a similar situation,
we first have to try that remedy, not Apis.
-In the Repertory in Generals we have wounds, bites, wasps which is Mezereum
and again Mezereum is aggravated by touch second degree
and we have wounds, painful, burning which is again Mezereum.
-You have to be careful when you read things like that. You have to be careful.
This is a case in which after a sting, a wound develops.
It inflames and then it opens and it develops into a wound.
Then you may be needing one of the remedies which is Mezereum
but at that stage where there is this allergy and because the lids are involved,
maybe still Apis may work.
But we can not give Apis at this moment since she tells us that in a previous situation
with a wasp she was treated with Ledum.
The remedy that has to be tried first is Ledum.
You should not go away from that remedy before we have tried this remedy.
If it does not work, we'll see what we will do, we'll see in the afternoon.
Whenever you give a remedy that has worked and there is a relapse of such a situation,
you try again the same remedy, this is the rule. So find Ledum here.
-What treatment did she get before? People were around giving her something, what was it?
-She said she got Apis and then Ledum.
-Three weeks ago, she wanted to know what about now, before when the wasp first stung.
-I don't know, it is something like mixture of certain flowers.
-Bach flowers, rescue remedy.
-Well what potency you have taken before?
-30.
-OK, give her 200 now.
-I would like to know how can we judge that Apis was not the remedy
because the first reaction was that it got worse and we know that if it is the right remedy,
it gets worse.
-That's correct.
-How can we know now if Ledum... perhaps Ledum didn't have any reaction.
-Yes sure. I will tell you.
The answer is like this. If the patient says a story, you have to believe the story.
What you say is absolutely correct, that means it might have been that Apis aggravating
and then eventually curing.
Now we are going to have the proof because she says no I don't want to be aggravated.
The fact that she will take Apis and she will be aggravated again,
we may have the same problem.
So therefore we have for different reasons, for psychological reasons also
and for reasons that if what she tells is objective, we have to start with Ledum.
Because if she says, as soon as I took Ledum, I felt better.
So that means that what she says, it might be correct, we shall find out how Ledum will act.
In the afternoon we shall see.
Peter take her back where she lives.
-One question. There is a specific remedy which is made of wasp...
Can we try this remedy as well?
-I don't know.
If this was just a wasp, as usual, you just forget about it but if she has a sensitivity
forget about these little measures.
Then you have really to go deeper and do something correct.
So her eye will open by tomorrow evening.
I'm not sure that Ledum is acting but the pain goes away in such cases once the swelling is full.
Once the swelling is full, that means it's not anymore swelling up, then the pain stops
and starts reducing.
By tomorrow evening her eye will be open, whether because of the remedy or natural I'm not sure.
This is the natural, if you left it without any remedy, still you will have the same process.
It will be impressive of course if we give the remedy
and by now the swelling will be almost gone.
That we could say is because of the remedy definitely but now as we saw the swelling
became bigger and bigger and bigger, reached a point where the organism does not react anymore,
then the pain stops and then starts the reverse order. By tomorrow night...
Still you will see some swelling, not completely gone.
What would happen if she had taken Apis, we do not know.
Do not think that Apis would be better, no. We don't know.