「死への恐怖とパニック」 途方もないパニックです。
そして「死が近づいているという感覚」、死が目前に迫っている。本には「死の時刻を予言する」と書いてあります。
これは急性状態におけるものです。慢性状態では「１０時に死ぬだろう」などとは言わず、別の状態になります。
その人に全ての症状が出るわけではありません。ある人には「死への恐怖」「めまい」「「失神する恐怖」「強烈な？」などが出ます。
他の人には「ふるえ」「発汗」「片側のしびれ」例えば顔の半分のしびれ、などが出ます。
また他の人は心因性の呼吸困難が出るでしょう。
深呼吸しなくてはなりません。
もしくは身体全体や顔が「熱で紅潮」するかもしれません。
全般的に悪化する時間帯があり、多くは夜です。
特に真夜中から４amです。そして一般的に「暑さで悪化」します。
しかし「寒さから悪化」も時々見られます。例えば８０％は「暑さで悪化」、２０％が「寒さで悪化」です。
(?) by heat, when they are heated up in a very warm room.
(?) individual with intense fear (?) a big syndrome.
When the Christ's come then that is the violence, the intensity, then there is the panic, there is the fear, all these are very intense.
When you converse to him, when he describes to you, he will not describe it with this intensity but he will say (?)
So these patients are very sympathetic as we said. They need company and also they express their feelings easily.
This sympathetic element leads to a state of anxiety about others. They are concerned very much about their relatives, their friends
and they react out of proportion (?)
What happened to you? Oh my God. The reaction is out of proportion to an event.
Because of that element they do not like to hear bad news.
You see they are setting rubrics in the Repertory that we do not see them in the patient, (?) on bad news, we do not see that.
You will have to see it at all fashions. I mean a crisis comes so many times, intense, the fear of death, perspiration, tachycardia etc.
Then they go out, they are sympathetic. It's the whole picture that will make a person Aconite.
Anxiety about other people. You have anxiety about others? Yes. You see it's an information which is useless.
What we're interested is to get the personality, the essence. Is that Aconite case?
And that is why we need the Materia Medica (?)
In Greece for instance, are you sympathetic? Yes very sympathetic. All Greeks are sympathetic.
OK this is not a symptom because it is (?)
Sympathetic is a symptom when the person is really suffering because of the suffering of the others.
And he can not control himself. (?)
The sympathetic is you want to put is as a symptom has to be really suffering because of others and can not help it.
I mean if a woman has a child, she is always sympathetic but a Phosphorus woman or the Aconite woman or the Sulphur woman will react completely different.
The Aconite in the Repertory says, anxiety about others. What happened, oh my God, what shall we do?
It's an intense thing, the anxiety about others. The Phosphorus has completely different (?)
Is people OK? He shows all the affection, all the concern, he is interested about you. The Sulphur will not show it, the anxiety.
The Sulphur will say, the child is very (?) They stay awake, they can not sleep.
12.20 (?) does he have an accident? And they get up from bed and they walk up and down, going in the veranda, watching the child coming.
Once they see the child coming, they will go back in sleep.
The Phosphorus do not take this so much imagination. When he feels something which is very (?) then he becomes very sympathetic.
If we see the sympathy in a different way, the Arsenicum also has anxiety about others. Anxiety about others in Arsenicum is inner anxiety.
Whom others? Those that he is connected and he feels a kind of security with them, the father, the mother, the brother. What happened to my brother?
Because he holds on him and so he wants him to be well in order to help him.
It is an anxiety on a reflex where he wants the support from others and he wants others to be well to support him.
It's a different thing in attitude, in personality. (?) anxiety about others it's underlined 3 times.
It doesn't say anything. It is not (?)
So this we are interested to understand.
We said the fear of death, that he is going to die now within half an hour, 1,2 hours whatever it is.
But in chronic states the fear of death that is imminent is within a time, let's say in 3, 5 months, in 1 year, they say my heart is going to give in and I'm going to die.
They are actually sure that they are going to die and they make preparation.
They make their will and then they tell you that through the symptoms they are absolutely sure that my heart will stop and I'll die.
Therefore I have to arrange everything that after my death everything will be taken care.
I mean this thought is not somebody (?) You say he is a prudent man about his death.
Here we take into consideration everything which is pathological. It's not natural, it's not healthy for one to think that in 3, 5 months I'm going to die.
This is pathology and we take it in consideration.
Except from the fear of death Aconite is also claustrophobia, fear of dark and especially fear of clouds.
Many times he will not sleep without the light on.
And he will not go through (?) if he knows that the (?) is going through (?) he prefers to get up.
Also you will not get an Aconite going into demonstration, when too many people are in the streets.
And they have also a fear of accident. So much so that many times an Aconite will not drive by himself. In order to drive they need somebody else to accompany.
Also Aconite has many times fear of disease and has to be added, it's not in the Repertory.
And also fear that his heart will stop beating.
It appears that those fears are gone and there is the least provocation, and then they come up.
In some cases there is an aggravation which reminds you of Lachesis.
And that is when they go to bed and they sleep for 10-15 minutes, then suddenly they wake up with tremendous fears, they jump up.
Now the difference is that with Lachesis the fear is not a fear of death; it's a fear of suffocation when they're falling asleep.
By the time they go into sleep. Aconite is a fear of death, is a type which comes 10-15 minutes after sleep.
You see the difference? It looks alike, you may confuse it but it's not the same.
It is 10-15 minutes, that means the person has gone into sleep and the moment that the logic mind has gone away, the fears that have been staying inside, they (?) and they (?) suddenly.
And in such an intensity that the person jumps up and he feels he is going to die.
Also there is an aggravation from heat. He may explain it that he is getting warm in bed (?)
That heat aggravates him and brings the crisis of (?)
Sometimes these fears instead of making the person to wake up, they appear as nightmares.
So they go through tremendous nightmares.
And another fear that can come about is a kind of "mora". You know what is a "mora"? No. I will describe to you.
When they try to wake up or they wake up without being able to move their limb.
What's called this? This can happen with Aconite. They wake up, they can not move their limbs and they go into a state of fright and panic.
Anyhow what we observe in general is that the fears that have been (?) they surface very easily the Aconite people and they bring out these states of panic and fear.
The Aconite is also the number 1 remedy that is affected by earthquakes.
And it is an analogous state inside, like an earthquake happening. Inside the circulatory system is in such a turmoil as if an earthquake is taking place inside.
Sometimes the feeling of the earthquake inside is so strong that they wake up and they feel that the sea may (?) They have the impression that there is actually an earthquake.
It's a tremendous commotion inside and then this (?)
a state of Aconite which is terrifying.
One of the aggravations of Aconite is this time, the twilight. And I've seen a case of Aconite in a state of agony
coming every night when the twilight comes, where the person will go into tremendous fear in a such a way that (?)
Terrified, full of fear, not being able to express anything at the moment.
It was terrible experience once that a doctor had. He took the patient inside and while he was in the consulting room, it was about this time
the person started the interview and then suddenly that syndrome came and it was so intense that the doctor terrified.
He said, come in I can not handle the situation. With this syndrome they would call usually the ambulance and give her injection, valium.
It was terrible, the fear. (?)
With one dose of Aconite not only that crisis went away. It went away the whole. I mean this woman she was getting very frequently this attack.
So Aconite states can start from a million places like tachycardias, (?) and then we see the fear, fear of death, panic
tremendous panic and then these terrific fears which come indescribable, they can not say what happens to them and most probably they feel the death is imminent.
That they are going to die and they take them to the ambulance.
The claustrophobia also. I remember another case where the claustrophobia was so much that if in the house they were 6 or 7 persons, they would feel claustrophobia.
And she could not stay in that room. She had to leave. Therefore they say, I can not invite my relatives in the house. With 6-7 people she felt claustrophobia.
So you understand the intensity of the claustrophobia.
Also there is a fear of suffocation. (?)
And sometimes you will get a fear of open spaces. It's the opposite, exactly.
They can not drive into the autobahn. They can drive in the city, they can go anywhere. As soon as they come in the autobahn where the space is open, they go into a panic, into a fear.
They paralyze, they can not drive anymore.
They can not say why this is happening. They go into panic and they can not explain why.
We did some characteristics of the different systems.
In general we can say there are tormenting sensations on the head.
Tormenting headaches and vertigo. There is convulsion often and (?) often accompanied by great heat.
There is a very characteristic sensation, void inside the head.
There are headaches which can come about after 5 or after exposure to cold, dry winds.
This is characteristic to Aconite. The headaches are located mostly in (?)
One sided numbness of the face, as we said before and these headaches usually are accompanied by some kind of fear, fear of death.
Most probably Aconite will be (?)
When the (?) is very hard, the headache is very strong.
When we have severe cases of encephalitis and encephalomyelitis.
In the beginning of such cases we do not have frequently the possibility to treat such cases unfortunately but from my experience
I've seen that Homeopathy definitely can work and ensure better. We do not have the statistics yet that it can work better.
-Have you seen many doctors with good results?
-Yes.
The problem we can not see many cases to have such statistics. We see cases of the child of my sister or the doctors who are in the center, their children.
The children are connected very much with Homeopathy and their parents know very well about Homeopathy.
This is the only time where you can take such responsibility. Also I don't suggest to take such cases especially when we are not medical doctors.
You don't know what to do if the remedy has failed. You may have a difficult situation.
(?) after cold wind, exposure to cold wind.
An inflammation becomes (?) the eyes become very sensitive to light and there is photophobia.
To sunlight and artificial light. Also Aconite may be have sudden loss of sight. If you have sudden loss of sight, it is the beginning of Aconite.
In the stomach you can have gastritis inflammation which will come about if somebody is over heated and drinks very cold water suddenly.
Then comes this burning in the stomach and the gastritis starts. Then Aconite is (?)
Also they have great thirst. Especially in waking in the morning.
In the abdomen you will find characteristic pains in the abdomen which extend to the chest.
Also (?) retention of urine. The Aconite is very much used in case of (?) because of the (?) that comes.
If the urine is retained then Aconite is one of the main remedies.
Sudden bronchitis. Sudden inflammation of (?) in cases of suppressed menses.
But all these symptoms are very well described in Kent and this is one of the remedies which (?) in all these details.
But I would say we are using Aconite say 80% in chronic cases and 20% in acute.
We have hundreds of cases treated with Aconite for 5 years, 10 years, chronic cases.
Especially of indescribable suffering. Before we knew this remedy we would give Lachesis, Kali Arsenicum, Belladonna, all other kinds of remedies
that were not acting. And when we came out with the Aconite picture, then we had a great friend in all situations.
Tachycardia, the vertigo, the headaches, the fainting they are not functional.
-I had a case where this lady she would wake up at night paralyzed. She couldn't move, she couldn't touch her husband to wake him up.
-Waking up in the fright of the night?
-Yes and also waking up in the morning just being paralyzed. She couldn't move.
-You mean from "mora", what I said that they can not move their limbs?
-Yes.
-Lachesis, Sulphur.
-In all these cases the crisis is coming and going? They are not constant.
-Yes they are not constant situations. They come and go, every 2, 3 days, every day, once, twice the day.
They are not regular crisis but when they come they are intolerable.
This is the idea. It seems that the fright took place. That fright they have it in the subconscious but not too deep and with the least provocation, with some sleep, it comes up.
With some thought that something may happen, it comes up. With too much heat, the crisis comes up.
They are going to the wood, they are driving the car, they are in a traffic jam, suddenly they look behind, they get into a panic.
-Can they suppress the crisis?
-They can not, no. You mean suppress it by logic? No.
It is too strong, they can not. They say, yes I know but when the crisis comes they say, it's impossible to control myself.
-Do you find that the fear of panic is always a fear of death?
-Most of them they will describe it as fear of death, most of them.
It's not only the fear of death because in some cases you will get the fainting, you will get the perspiration.
-In Kent's Repertory there is a rubric which says effects of shock or shock in the mental. (?) you would put Aconite into that.
-Yes sure.
-What other remedies would you put in?
-I would put Opium, Gelsemium, Stramonium.
-Arnica?
-When we say shock we don't mean physical.
-You talk about mental?
-Yes.
-A crisis.
-When I give you this idea it's not that I'm covering the whole, because all remedies can have (?) There is no remedy that can be left out of this.
I'm giving you the most prominent.
(?)
-I can not say for what reason a person has a shock. Because he was too sympathetic to the other? Because he felt sudden (?)
Because of different reason? Here the fright is not just a fright. The fright involves most of the time the possibility of death.
This is what I found out. (?) this idea is behind the Aconite causative factor.
In Homeopathy I found out that there is no, always. If you say always, you can forget it. Most of the times, yes but always?
Because you will get sometimes the Calcarea Carbonica who is warm, the Pulsatilla who is cold, the Arsenicum who is also warm, you will get
the Nux Vomica, warm, the Argentum Nitricum who is cold.
You will say but Argentum is suffering from heat, this person is suffering from cold.
How do you get at it? Because the whole picture indicates, it's strong for Argentum Nitricum.
Therefore you have to ignore the fact that this Argentum Nitricum is worse cold.
Another thing that you have to remember is that Arsenicum is very cold in his body but hot in his head, OK?
Sometimes the heat is there and what they say, I'm suffering from heat where the headache is quite warm.
I remember in a hospital in Calcutta, where we had weekends sitting there for watch and the nurse came down, I was with another doctor.
The patient had tremendous pains, he was shouting. So (?) that patient, in India, very warm.
That patient was covered with four blankets, she was holding (?)
And then she was on her top with a fan and fanning her head.
When we went inside we saw this patient, water, water and we give him water and she was (?) in the bottle where she was trembling like that and the face was absolutely hot.
The picture is so intense and so clear.
When I saw the blankets, 4,5 blankets. So sometimes the person will give you the impression that is hot (?)
There was a case actually by an American doctor who wrote the case and said, this person was warm and I gave Arsenicum.
And he was very angry by the teachers teaching that Arsenicum is a cold remedy.
Anyhow this is not a case where we will say definitely is an Arsenicum case, we still have to see whether it was Arsenicum and secondly whether it was only the head that was warm and not the body
but it is a fact that in Homeopathy I found there is not "always".