Who of you are working in hospitals or research centers?
Ok, it doesn’t matter.
I’ll give you an idea that you may become very famous for the rest of your life.
The idea is in order to make a diagnosis without taking blood or anything.
I say this but I’ll put it on the Internet so some people may put it in practice.
The idea comes from my dog.
My dog has a passion if anybody throws a stone anywhere he will go and find the stone and bring it back.
Whoever throws this stone in the forest he is going to find the stone and bring it back.
You saw this dog. It’s crazy like me!
So the idea I thought about the diagnosis of a case is like this;
An experiment which will take place in several countries; Russia, England, Israel, Romania.
For 10 years a big portion of the population in each country is attended and they give information from the odors of the body.
The odors of each patient are registered through machine and the odors we need is the odor of the mouth,
the odor of perspiration, the odor of the urine and the odor of the stool.
This 4 odors being digitalized create the profile of that person.
This person attended 5-10 years and each person develops several chronic conditions.
We establish the difference in the odor and in this way we have the profile throught the odors of a person who is going to develop Lupus eryth., cancer of the bladder, M.S.
and these results can be compared from nation to nation and in this way we will not know only know that a person may have cancer of the bladder but we can predict that
if he has the combination of this kind of odors he is going to develop in 3-4 years cancer of the bladder.
This is an idea which I think today is possible to be put into practice because there are devices that can register the odor of a person.
It’s fantastic idea, crazy, coming from my dog but I have been thinking of this for very long time. I said let me say this.
Maybe some people will start investigating.
In this way you are going you are going to investigate also people who are healthy,
people who are in the process and people who are having already the specific disease.
So, a profile of the person together with the profile of the odors of his body… You see I’m an old doctor.
I treat patients since 1960, 48 years.
By that time I had heard talking with pathologists that there were some doctors who could recognize, make a diagnosis entering the room of a patient by smell.
They have realized if I enter and this is the smell that’s the problem.
So if we can make now this in a scientific way and very correct we can have a tool for diagnosing and prognosing what is going to come which is much more important.
I talked to you in the morning about the proteinogram.
It’s a very gross way of knowing more or less the state of the immune system.
You have anemia but this anemic person is going to develop a very serious condition later on.
The other person with anemia is going to be cured very soon. Anemia… Everybody has anemia.
What is the good of it? The good of it it’s to know whether this person can be treated and can be cured.
The other person maybe is going to be very difficult to treat and cure.
Especially this will be very useful for homeopathic doctors because you could always check the change in the process.
I’ll tell you a few other things that led me to this idea.
One thing is… I don’t know if you have experienced the odor the stool of a constitutional Sulphur.
I remember in a Greek Congress.
One of my students had been in the toilet which was upstairs and he came down and the whole hall smelled very bad.
I said to him; you stick your feet out, yes, you need at 11 a.m. to eat
something, yes, and you have a headache on the top of your head, he said yes.
You better take Sulphur because your stool smells so bad!
By doing that you prevent because definitely in decomposing the flora of the intestine in such speed
and such aggressive way the food it means that most probable within a few years
the person will develop something which is quite serious.
Not only that but you give a remedy and there is a reaction and the reaction is excessive perspiration
and when the perspiration becomes offensive you say that the remedy was absolutely correct.
The toxins are coming out through the perspiration.
Another example; I have many times treated with kidney problems and especially when they have stones in the kidneys.
In many of these people I found out when I was investigating that when they were young they were using borax which would stop the feet perspiration
that was very offensive and they were very embarrassed to be in a social gathering.
The toxins that were not allowed to go out through the perspiration were causing after 10-50 years kidney stones.
All these and other observations have brought me to the realization that we can have a diagnosis
and prognosis if we combine not one smell, you know the Mercury smell, not only the smell of the mouth,
not only the perspiration, not only the urine but also combination of all these odors.
So I give it to you as an idea to promote it and see what happens.
Thank you!