This is the main page of the e-learning platform.
You can navigate, and get more information about using the main menu, or the other options provided.
The two year course e-learning program is an academic online program, based on the highest educational standards
according to the principles of Samuel Hahnemann.
You can find more information about the program the curriculum, the conditions and the fees
by clicking on the corresponding sub-menu items.
Here you can see the available 2-year course, e-learning versions.
By clicking the view button you can get more information such as the course language, the total videos and the provided facilities.
You can also get a 10-day free trial by clicking the "Get Free Trial"  button.
For more information about the free trial, please visit the corresponding link on the main page.
Now let's register for a free trial.
We are redirected to the registration page, we enter our personal data.
You should also read the instructions underneath each box.
The 2-year course is selected as default, in this drop-down list.
Now we must select language, from the available options.
Selecting language is actually for a later use,
when you have purchased the course, you are registered to the corresponding course
and the provided content is in the language you have chosen in this step.
We continue with the registration.
And now we click the "Create new account"  button to finish.
The registration process has finished.
An e-mail has been sent to the e-mail account we have entered.
You should open this e-mail and click on the link provided, to confirm your registration.
A new free trial group begins every Friday, and you will be notified by e-mail from the Academy.
Now let's see how to register for a post-graduate course.
From this menu item we can see the post-graduate courses of the Academy.
In this page we can see the available post-graduate courses.
In the same way, we can get more information by clicking the view button.
If you already have an account on the e-learning platform, and want to register to a post-graduate course,
just send and e-mail to the Academy, that you want to register to this specific course.
If you don't have an account yet click the "Register now" button.
We are redirected to the registration page.
We enter our personal data as we showed before, and select the post-graduate levels of health course and language from the available options.
We continue with the form, and click the "Create new account" button.
Open the e-mail to confirm your registration and another e-mail will be sent to you from the academy to process with the payment.
Once the payment is complete you will have access to the course.