In this video we will see how to enter course.We click on the e-learning platform menu item.
If you are not logged in you will be redirected to the log in form.
We enter our data and click the login button.
The list with the courses you are registered to is displayed.
To enter a course just click on it.
This is the main page of the course, and these are the available features of the course.
Online tests and excersises, announcements about the course, assignments, online notebook, and the course content.
We click on this icon to access the videos.
From the list on the left you can select the content you want to view.
The main types of content are the videos, the pdf notes, and self assessment questions for the corresponding video.
The green ticks on the right of the title means that you have visited this link but not necessarily seen the content.
Now we click on the play button to start the video.
These are the options we have for the video.
We can move the playbar to the minute we want.
And from here can choose the quality of the video.
For slow internet connections, it is better to choose the lower quality.
By clicking this button, we can switch the subtitles to another language or disable them.
We can also edit the sound and set video on fullscreen mode.
Please make sure that you are using the pause button, which is excactly below the video player together with another resume button
instead of the pause button at the bottom left of the video player.
Here we can keep notes for the video.
Click the "Save my notes" button to save them before leaving the page.
Depending on the module, theory or materia medica, you can find more information or references below the player.
For example the other books, that you need to study along side with the video.
Below each video link there are notes in pdf format.
You can either download them on your device by clicking this button,
or print them by clicking this button
If you can't view the pdf notes, please make sure you have a pdf reader installed on your device.
The self assessment questions are questions about the corresponding video and help you assess if your have understood the content.
Read the question and try to answer it then click the show answer link to confirm your answer.
We click the "Course home" link to go back to courses main page.
Here is another way to keep notes for the course.
As you can see here are the notes we kept for the video.
We can edit or export them to pdf format.
We can also create new notes by clicking here.
In the next video you will see how to enter an online test, and how to submit your assignments and tests.