In this video, we will see how to take the e-learning tests and the purpose of the assignments provided.
We click on the test icon to access the available tests, in module 1 theory A.
This is the first page of the tests.
On the left of the table, you can see the titles of the available tests.
And on the right you can see whether you have attempted the test and the score.
Now we click on the first test to enter it.
In the first page of the test we can see the title of the test, a brief description and instructions of how to proceed.
And a table with information, about our previous attempts of the test.
Those tags shows whether a test has been corrected by the moderator, or not.
By clicking the show button of an attempt, we can see our answers and the moderator's marks and comments.
This message informs us that we can not take this test as we have reached the maximum of two attempts.
We click the test's link to go back to the list of the available tests.
We click on the "Start test" button to open the test.
This is the main structure of a test.
By clicking here you can expand the description text of the test.
Enter your answer in the text area, below each question.
The tests can be partialy filled in and saved, since they might take a long time and require study.
Click the "Save unfinished test" button, and all the answers you have filled in will be saved.
So the next time we open the test, we can proceed with the unfinished test.
The moderator will not see your partialy answered tests, they will only be available for correction and grading after you have made the final submission.
We click the "Proceed with the test" button to open the unfinished test.
When we have answered all the questions and we want to submit the test , so that it can be corrected by the moderator,
we click the "End test" button.
Our test have been submitted.
Here we can see the questions and the answers, we have given.
Now we will see the assignments and their purpose in the course.
We click on the "Assignments" icon to enter.
This is the first page of the assignments, on the left we can see the titles of the available assignments.
We click on one of them to enter.
On the left we can see the titles of the available assignments.
The purpose of these documents, is for students to assess their understanding of the licence and practice with questions,
similar to the ones that they will come accross during the final exams.
Both question and answer documents are included and they don't need to be sent back to the moderator.
We click the "Save" button to download the document.
Now we select the save file option, to save the file on our computer.
This is the end of the video of how to take the online tests, and the purpose of the assignments provided.