In this video we will see how to access the forums, create a new topic, reply to a post
and getting email notfications for new posts.
We click the forum icon on the main page of the e-learning platform, to access the forum.
Here we can see the available forums divided in categories, based on the content.
In this column we see the title and a brief description of a specific forum,
in the next column there is the total number of the forum's topics, and next to it the total posts.
In the last column on the right, there are information about the last post of the forum,
it's title, creator's name and creation date.
This is how the topics of the forum are presented.
On top of the list there are the sticky posts, that only the administrators of the platform can create.
In the first column there is the title of the topic, the name of it's creator and the creation date.
In the second column we can see the number of replies of the topic
and again in the last column there are information about the last post and it's creator.
Now let's create a new topic.
We click the new topic button.
A new page opens, in this field we enter the subject of the new topic.
Try to create short and comprehensive subjects, so it's easy for someone to understand.
Avoid using subjects like "Help" or "I have a question", instead
use the subject of the new topic to describe the contents of the post.
For example, help with video on children remedies.
In the text area you can be more specific and describe your question.
Now we click the save button.
As you can see our new topic is presented in the list.
Now we are going to see how to reply on an existing topic.
We select the topic and click on it.
Again you do not have to reply something to everything.
We have two options, we can either reply to a specific post of the topic,
or reply to the initial topic post.
For the first option we should click this button, and for the second we just fill out this form .
In this example we are going to reply to a post.
Entering a subject is optional, we add our answer and click the save button.
Again you do not have to reply something to everything.
Getting email notifications for new posts on topics your are interested in
is one the best features provided to keep us up-to-date.
Inside each topic we see this block where we can select to be notified for new posts for this topic,
or for this forum in general.
Another way to select the forums we want to be notified for new posts, is to go to the user account page.
Select the forum notifications tab.
Select the forums tab.
Select the forums that you are intersted the most and click save.
This was the video about the e-learning forums.