Before we go further I would like to analyze more systematically
what took place in this case and to show you how I thought.
When the practitioner took the follow up, if you observed, she came
and said certain things have happened but I'm confused. Did you hear her saying that?
Many times we are in a similar situation.
So in order to avoid that, to say I'm confused, I don't know what to do,
we have to know certain principles, certain laws that exist and to apply them every time.
There were several questions concerning the follow up of this case.
The first question is whether your remedy has acted, yes or no?
The second question is if it has acted, did it move the case correctly or wrongly?
That means it was a close remedy or it was the exact remedy,
the remedy that really the person needed?
You have to answer these questions clearly in your mind.
There is a difference here, I don't do it on purpose.
The practitioner said I'm confused, I said you are doing very well. I was pleased.
What is the difference that made me being pleased
and the practitioner saying I'm confused? The difference is on facts.
I evaluate the facts in a different way perhaps than the practitioner.
What I hear is first of all she took the remedy and then she fall asleep
and she felt she slept deeply.
This for me is almost an infallible symptom showing that the remedy has acted curatively.
Then this person sleeps for 10-15 days, gathers a little bit more energy for one week,
then on the following...
There are two months between the remedy and the follow up.
The follow up is taken middle of July and the remedy was given middle of May.
This is a two month follow up that we are observing.
The person says I slept and it was very good.
Then I had perhaps a little more energy because in the evening I was socializing,
before I could not do it, now I'm doing it.
Very good.
Then I hear the practitioner and herself saying she is lately on the depressive side.
I also hear the patient saying certain things happened with her eyes, squinting the eyes
and then she developed these impulses...
And I have to put all these into a logical sequence and understanding of what has happened.
Otherwise I'm going to make a mistake.
What did I say to myself is that the remedy acted because of the reaction.
Also it took away some of the desires, pickles and also aversion to sweet
that eventually had and brought about a change in the general temperature of the person.
Where she was rather cold person, she became so warm that she could not cool down.
These drastic changes together with the fact that she slept so deeply,
together with the fact that for some time the energy was better,
it shows that the remedy acted.
But now she comes and says I have impulsive tendency to commit suicide,
I'm on the depressive side, my energy is not better, it might be even worse.
You hear me saying, you are doing well. Why she is doing well?
Because she felt better for one week? No. Because of what I know.
Now what she presents to me is a case of Argentum nitricum.
What has happened is that Graphites acted and took away the first layer
and another layer is coming up, quite clearly which is represented
by a clear picture of Argentum nitricum.
That is why now I can be sure that in this case, which is deep pathology, we have hope.
The reaction was very good from the first remedy presented, did whatever it could.
If you let this patient go on without Argentum nitricum, she would go on suffering
and suffering. You will not see the real effect of a cure. Why?
Because she needed the second remedy to complete the action of the first.
If you make a mistake and you give another remedy, instead of Argentum nitricum,
you may have eventually a confused case and finally you will not see
what we want to see with Homeopathy after a period of time that the health of the person
really gets better and better and better.
The idea with Homeopathy is that we don't have the elimination of the symptoms immediately.
The idea is that according to the pathology of the person we prescribe correctly.
So year after year the person's health is improving, we are regenerating the health.
Don't forget we don't eliminate the symptoms. Not that we don't bother by symptoms,
not that we say never mind you suffer.
We are guided by the symptoms but how? In a very scientific, precise way.
We like Homeopathy to be very precise.
Don't miss anything. You have to take into consideration all the information
that is coming and evaluate it properly, correctly and with care.
It's not that you don't care about whether she is suffering.
It's not that I don't care when I say you're doing very well, when she says I'm exhausted,
I'm tired. It's not that I don't care but what I see in my mind it's coming out beautifully,
its' so clear, great, it's going to act.
Now she is going to find out how she is going to be better and better.
That's why I'm saying in the interview, now you are going to see the follow ups
and see whether I was right saying in the interview you are doing great.
Where the great is? The great is not there, where she wants to commit suicide,
she has tiredness. This is not great.
But in my I can't retain my joy because I have seen what takes place.
And what I have seen is very clear.
Graphites acted and then what it means a picture of another remedy.
It means symptomatology. What kind of symptomatology?
It might be as well symptomatology on mental-emotional level.
How is this symptomatology is better than the other one? We don't exactly know.
Because we don't know really the main symptom which is lack of enjoyment in life.
To be alive means to enjoy, that measure is difficult for us to pin out a person.
A person does not enjoy life, it may be just indifferent and you give a remedy
and he becomes very aggressive and still you say he is better now
because before he didn't enjoy at all, he didn't care.
His house was put on fire and said I don't care really.
And now you just say a few words and he fights with anger and you say he is better.
Wait and you will see the result.
In this case Argentum nitricum was prescribed on middle of July...
-...1939.
-OK. Let us see now October 86, that means three months later after Argentum nitricum how she is.
-She took Argentum nitricum on the 14th of July, she took it in 200
and has had no prescription since then.
-How she is?
-Very good, excellent, stunning.
-She had Graphites initially?
-Yes.
-We have seen this case for the first time after Argentum nitricum?
-Yes this is the first time that she had her prescriptions for two months.
-I have not seen her.
-I spoke to her on the telephone, I've seen her occasionally in between,
she brings me patients and she looks better for the last couple of months
but I haven't prescribed.
But I do that her symptoms are changing and the emphasis is on different things now.
She looks very concerned about her cold fingers. Two things she is concerned now.
Tremendous sweating and cold fingers that she wakes up and also her hearing aid is back.
-Make her take out her hearing aid this time
-Yes this time.
-Just take it out. Can you hear?
-No, I have to do it by lip reading.
-Just turn to the other side. Can you hear what I'm saying now?
-No.
-Last time that we were talking she had a hearing aid?
-Yes.
This is a very crude test of course. It's not the test that the otolaryngologist will do
but this is the most convenient test and I'm going to do this test again
and perhaps you will see the difference and you will see what Homeopathy can do.
-How are you now?
-I'm much better in energy and I have not that inner tiredness that I've had for so long.
I just get it very occasionally.
There was a point that I didn't know what it was like and I realized what it was like
and almost after that it started to get back again.
Tremendous sweat. If I get very hot, then suddenly I get tremendous sweat.
In the morning I wake up in a sweat. It's really very unpleasant.
You see what you have to be aware here in this case that she says she is sweating a lot.
She had tuberculosis originally, I don't know if it was mentioned in the original case
but getting sweat, you have a possibility of going back into that state perhaps.
What do you feel about the sweat? What it is?
Because of her age, she is on a menopausal age, she has the possibility
of getting tuberculosis and be on a tubercular state
you have to examine and make sure that this is not a state where tuberculosis starts coming.
Because of her age and most probably her answer indicates
that this is a menopausal kind of sweating.
It is what they call the woman flushes of heat, it's not a tubercular state.
Always you have to be aware of different possibilities that exist with Homeopathy
and be aware of the pathology underlined and don't escape it.
The fact that you are treating the patient, it doesn't mean
that you are automatically protecting the person from different things that they may come.
-Do you have a particular time when you feel that the sweating comes,
like early in the morning or...?
-It comes early in the morning and I wake up in this sweat.
A tremendous thirst all the time.
-For cold or it doesn't matter?
-At night more but in the day time it turns...
I could drink cold water all the time, it doesn't matter really. It's a tremendous thirst.
-You are having your menses normally?
-They stopped.
-Because these are climacteric symptoms now.
-Probably. This time I had it once in a three months.
-What other symptoms are bothering you now?
-I have a lot of very thick sputum and...
-From the left ear? Did you have an X-ray?
-...
-When?
-All over the years and I had particularly...
-But you are bringing out sputum now?
-Yes, very thick, frothy, creamy, occasionally it's cream.
I have dripping. I have constant nasal discharge.
-Like water with no other reason?
-No.
-Do you have this perhaps when you go to the toilet for stool?
-As well yes.
Which is this remedy which has dripping of the nose on having stool?
-Thuja.
-Do you see the next remedy coming?
What she says is that the deep tiredness is gone, she doesn't feel deep tiredness
and you remember from this case of Graphites, we learned a few things.
One is this deep tiredness, as she described it, that type of tiredness,
connected with the lung problems.
Desire for pickles, which is not mentioned in the Repertory.
The excessive thirst for cold water, which can be as excessive or as cold as Phosphorus.
It was not very much in your mind concerning Graphites.
Now she says still she has the tiredness, she has the sweats
which alternate with coldness,
she has the coldness in the hands.
Can you see a remedy?
What was her comment concerning how she felt in general?
-She felt better.
-She says she didn't know how this better was for years,
she has not experienced this feeling of being better.
Let's see a little bit more if you can tell me what is the next remedy.
-Now my hands get numbed, the circulation I think it stops.
This morning three fingers were dead and all the hand went white.
It's much worse, I need to push my circulation, I often have to get up to get it going.
Then it's hard to hear.
-They went away for a period?
-Yes, everything was...
I think for four weeks after the remedy, this was marvelous.
Now it has come back.
Did you hear what she says? The first four weeks she felt marvelous and the swelling
of the glands went away. Now the swelling of the glands is coming back.
Tiredness also but not this deep tiredness.
Now you are going to make a mistake here, I'm sure. So far it was very easy this case.
-I had a tremendous heat, they still get numbed, now my chest was still producing sputum
that's going on but now the noises in the head is much better.
-The noises in the head is better.
-They came back as they were before?
-Not as bad but it is a hot feeling here and I have a tremendous discharge from my ears.
-You have a lot of discharge after the remedy?
-Yes.
-What kind of discharge?
-It was pale, creamy yellow.
Again another point. You give Graphites which affects the ears.
Graphites increases a little bit the discharge initially, then it takes it away.
Then you come to Argentum nitricum. That's another level altogether
but still pushes further that point as well, discharges from the ear even more
and discharges from the lungs.
She says purulent discharge quite a lot, she felt it from the lung coming out quite a lot.
This is very good reaction together with the feeling of the well-being that she was having,
together with the tiredness going away.
-Do you feel any improvement in the hearing?
-It is not this last month but... the noise from the head has gone this time.
-And the hearing remained deteriorated?
-No it remained, it came up and remained.
-Anything else?
-A few weeks ago I had tremendous dryness, not on my eyes, skin reaction.
-For how long?
-It lasted for five days.
Inner burning underneath the skin, when I touched it. it was hard and thick... from getting cold...
always it has been a pattern.
-Last week was as severe as you expected or it was less?
-It was slightly different... I didn't feel congested after it.
-Any reaction?
-I get coughing,  spasms of coughing.
Varicose veins comes up in my right leg now, it's a mild thing.
At night I get this increasing urination and I have to get out of bed.
-After you go to bed, then you have to get up?
-Yes I just have to go to pee.
-How many times you may have to wake up?
-Sometimes six times or more.
-Because the water that you are drinking is too much.
-Yes I still drink a fair amount and most probably is that that makes me wake at night.
-You could drink gallops of water.
-I could drink.
-Also you said in the beginning that your feet could go cold and numbed.
-Yes now they became numbed and very cold.
-It used to go numbed?
-Not my feet, my hands. But they get this cold all the time.
That's it, the interview. What are you going to do?
This is your biggest chance for mistake.
-Tuberculinum.
-Nothing
-Sac lac [placebo]
-Why sac lac?
-But she seems to be going into a kind of relapse. What about that?
-It's not clear enough.
-Very good.
-What if you repeat Argentum nitricum?
-You have a very good possibility to spoil the case.
The symptomatology on which we prescribed Argentum nitricum
were the impulses, were the heat, the desire for sweets.
If this symptomatology was back, we were justified to prescribe or to repeat Argentum nitricum.
But this symptomatology is not there at all.
She is feeling very well. Actually she says for the first time I felt so well in my life,
I don't remember how it was to be well.
Now the glands are getting swollen, there is an excessive perspiration
and those two symptoms together with the tuberculosis of the past
indicate a possibility of Tuberculinum.
But do we have enough symptomatology to prescribe Tuberculinum at this stage?
Not according to this interview.
Therefore what we have to do now is to wait.
This is three months after the second remedy. Still we have to wait.
To see if another picture really develops and then we can prescribe.
Because during that time, now we can spoil this case.
I promise you, if you start prescribing in this case, a few months later, six months later,
you will not recognize the case.
But leave it alone and see what happens.
You prescribed Graphites in the beginning, could it be anything else? No, it was correct.
Especially because it was confirmed by this last keynote
and then it did whatever it could and produced a clear picture of Argentum nitricum.
Beautiful. You gave it, you had a good reaction.
Now here you don't have enough information to change your remedy, repeat your remedy,
prescribe a higher potency, no.
So hands up, don't worry, she is going to be well.
Let's see the next. This case again last February and then a few days ago,
so I show you the two follow ups, so you have a complete picture of a year treatment.
See also the pathology how deep it is. It is not a simple case, it is complicated.
The hearing since childhood is impaired, the lungs from many, many years.
She has been eating up a lot of antibiotics, injections, treatments.
The circulation, the vascular system is in a very precarious condition.
So it is very deep pathology.
You see bronchiectasis, impaired hearing, Raynaud's syndrome,
all this is a complex, which does not make the case easy.
-This is case MAH, date of birth 20 of 9th 1939.
I saw her again on December the 4th 1986 and her glands have been up again,
her hearing had been better for some time but it was relapsing again, she was tired again
and she'd been having some nights sweats.
She felt some times that she was in a daze and she still had some impulses
to jump under trains but finally they were coming less and less.
She'd lost a lot of weight and she had been passing a lot of urine but that had improved.
She said her appetite was enormous and she was hungry for anything
but not particularly sweets anymore.
Her eyes were getting worse, she was having tears in her glasses more often,
her numbness in her fingers was getting worse again, that fluctuates all the time.
She was always complaining about her cold hands.
She felt that the deep fatigue of the past was not there
but she still feels a tremendous weariness and she consistently complains about this.
Basically her thirst was more normal and she has no particular craving for anything,
she is just very hungry.
She was very insistent that she had something, so I gave her some sac lac.
She felt better afterwards and again she came back in February the 5th
about one week ago and she is complaining of a different sort of tiredness.
She says she doesn't have the deep fatigue, I questioned her very deeply on this.
She said she needs tremendous amount of sleep, she will complain to you
about the fact that she is feeling tired all the time, she can't concentrate on her work.
I feel there is some new things coming through from her.
She has this very deep inner frustration, which she talked about
and it's always a desire that she has to get on and she is using these words,
every time she comes to see me, "I really want to get on,
I'm fed up being ill, I feel that I must..."
She's got some fight in her now where before she had no fight.
And she is lonely, it's coming through very strong that she doesn't want to be on her own.
We talked about sometimes to have a relationship, so her energy is so much better
that she is actually thinking about having a relationship.
I agree that she has been ill for so long, she is beginning
to have some feelings about the situation.
-Did she have the possibility of meeting somebody?
-She has some boyfriend who is been lingering around, but he is obviously very vague,
he was not consistent and she wants more commitment than he is willing to give.
She stressed very strongly to me that damp aggravates her, she says that
whenever she is in damp condition she loses all her energy.
So if she goes to the west coast of England she feels like she used to feel
when she had tuberculosis. It's very strongly stressed.
Her chest is being getting worse again, there is more expectoration,
this bronchiectasis Cause, although the expectoration is no longer green.
-She had a lot of expectoration the last time I saw her?
-Yes. The hot flushes are better, there are no night sweats since the beginning of January,
her glands and throat had gone up and down and she hasn't had period since August.
Her hearing cleared up tremendously from after the treatment but it's relapsed again now.
-You mean she was able to hear without hearing aid?
-No, you ask her because she is never clear to me. She says it was better
and now it's gone back and I say with or without the hearing aid
but she says I need the hearing aid...
So I'm not entirely clear about that.
She gets me into more involved... she keeps talking about this tiredness
and she wants to get on and I feel she is a lot better
and I begin to see that there are some new things creeping in and that's all I want to say.
But she stressed to me the suffering by the sea and the dampness
and how much she relapses, so she can't even think to go away on holidays
because if she goes away to the west coast, she is ill.
-But it's very cold in there?
-It's not, it's the dampness and the cold. She says I suffer by the sea.
-And she had only one dose of Argentum nitricum 200 in July 1986?
-Yes one dose, you said nothing else. She thinks she has but it's only...
-What is your impression, she will need a remedy?
-Yes.
-Most probably yes. What will be the remedy?
-Tuberculinum.
-Why? Because she is worse by the sea side? Lose weight, history of tuberculosis?
All right, let's see.
-You have some notes?
-I've made some notes yes.
-Very good. What I want before the notes, I want you to give me a general idea of...
Last time we met it was October. During that period of time generally
how you were considering the initial kind of problems that you came with?
It was this deep tiredness mostly and all this psychological state.
So how you are in general from that point of view?
-The tiredness is changed, it's not that...
It's more now I'm tired and I want to sleep but I haven't got that inner tiredness.
And from the psychological side I didn't get faint easily, I got more fight.
My hearing suddenly became very clear. For five days, I was walking around,
hearing sounds I haven't heard for years and then it's gone.
-When it was that from the improvement?
-After about...
-Last month or December or November?
-The same month with the remedy, it suddenly cleared, it was really clear,
it was like a fog going away.
-But you were still wearing your hearing aid?
-Yes I did but I could cut it, I certainly heard sounds that I haven't heard before
even with the hearing aid on.
-But she has the hearing aid now.
-I have it now. But now I just got this impatience. I want to get on.
-You are very impatient.
-Because I have enough of being... and I do want to keep on accepting things
but I feel that I got the energy and just it has been cut.
I can feel progress. I can see a lot of progress, I feel calmer though I got the fight
and in healthier state generally. It was chaos...
Now it's coming and going.
It's very interesting how she describes the effect of the treatment, where it was chaos,
entropy, it is coming to an organization where our remedy is doing,
it's organizing the different levels but remember we have to give it time.
Give it time, don't rush into conclusions.
You see when I rushed into giving a remedy after two months,
I had my strong reasons for doing that.
Don't rush.
Did the practitioner gave you the impression that this woman should get a remedy?
What is your impression from hearing this case? Should you give a remedy?
You see the subjectiveness of evaluation...
Two people look at the same case and one says, no wait and the other one says,
why not, try this. This is our biggest weakness in Homeopathy.
Try this, why not? It looks like so much.
Try this and then the mistake and then the big sighs, Ignatia state.
Oh god I made it again.
In these cases you don't have many...
The organism is not in a powerful state to resist your remedies.
Your remedies are going to affect this, if they are the wrong ones.
You have to be very careful whether you will prescribe or not.
I don't say don't prescribe now but try to tell me if you will prescribe.
-Perspiration?
-The night sweats have stopped. Last night it was very hot generally and I seemed sweaty.
I haven't got the control yet.
If I get cold, I get cold easily, if I get hot, I get hot easily
but still I haven't got what we call more balance. But my night sweat is gone.
-But if the weather is damp, then it's...?
-Damp and really hot damp it's OK. If it's cold damp or in between like the English spring
and autumn or when it keeps changing, I have no energy then.
If I go away to the country, I just end up tired and I don't sleep a lot.
But if it's hot and humid, then that's fine. I have a lot of energy.
-In United States? In Hawaii, in Florida?
-Yes, just north of that, near Charleston where it's hot I had bags of energy then.
-No problem. God, it's terrible climate!
Another point. The practitioner said she is wasting away and she gives an impression
that she is losing weight.
Do you see this?
-No.
-Normal.
-It's not only normal, she looks much better than originally.
You will see her face and everything looks fine.
It's not a person who is in a tuberculosis state who is wasting away, nothing of that type.
Her color is very good, her appearance is good.
-The sunshine.
-Maybe you feel more the cold now, you are more sensitive to cold.
-Yes I'm very sensitive to cold but this last winter I haven't got cold badly.
I only liked, I didn't enjoy it.
-But it's not as bad as it was.
-It may have been half as bad, I think I have to put more clothes but it hasn't mentally got me.
-The expectoration from the chest?
-That's variable. Sometimes it's not at all, I have more pain the last two months.
-Do you smoke?
-No. I never have done.
-The sputum?
-Now it's creamy white. In the mornings it's obviously thicker.
Sometimes in the mornings it doesn't come out. At the end of the day,
in the evening then it's very thick.
-I see.
-You had also noises in the ears?
-That has gone completely.
The last 2-3 weeks it's slightly there when I'm tired in the evenings perhaps
but nothing like it was.
-Also you had some nodules in the throat that they were swollen and they were down
and then they came up again?
-It's slightly hard here. This side is better but then it comes up.
-Hard and painful?
-Yes I can feel pain compared to that side. But that to me is all part of
when the ears eventually will get better, I'm sure this goes together.
I do get sore throat occasionally, not as I was getting sore throat, quite a lot.
What I have is a sensation of a hair in my throat for about six weeks but that it's now gone.
-You had these chest infections with discharge from the ears.
Now you don't get anything of that?
-From my left ear I get occasionally brownish discharge.
The right ear it did get more but some of it is maybe condensation from my hearing aid.
It's more clear, slight yellow.
-How do you feel now considering your social life?
-I feel a battle all the time because I have to paste things. I'm thinking of being too tired,
not able to keep up.
-What about your sexual energy? Has it changed, has it come up more?
-Nothing has changed, it's very constant.
-You remember you had a fear of disease, do you remember that?
-Yes, I don't have a fear of disease. I have cricking hips every time I get up my hips crick.
I hate that or my knees are not coming up straight.
-I want to say that her mother had two operations for arthritis,
so you have been worried about it.
-Your mother at what age?
-At her 60's but she was familiar with it.
What is your next proposition?
-Placebo.
-You are more careful now.
You can't give another remedy. You must not give another remedy.
You do not have the right to give another remedy. Why?
Because there are not enough symptoms to guide you to a prescription.
It is much better to wait. Now she may not get fast enough better, as you might have liked.
She is getting so much better that you don't realize it perhaps
that she is getting so much better considering what she had.
The fact also that the color of the sputum and the quality of the sputum changes,
it will show the different stages she has been through.
That means the defenses are working and bringing as fast as she can do it,
her defense mechanism can do it by bringing order. That's what she has said.
There is some order coming in me. Then you just watch it.
This is not going to any kind of danger, she is not having any really severe problem,
she says I would like to have more energy.
If I ask the whole class here, tell me one that says I have enough energy, I don't want anymore.
There is no such thing, especially under the pollution situation in which we live,
under the stresses, under all this who does not complain for lack of energy? Tell me one.
You have to wait until the pathology takes its time, sort it out
and then the energy will start be coming.
And then you may have this case after 2, 3, 5 years better, better, better...
These are the cases that will bring the other cases also.
They will say I'm benefited after a year, still I'm not well but what a difference.
Let's see the last interview a few days ago.
-She was diagnosed with bronchiectasis, I'd like to have seen these old X-rays
compared with the now.
-The main thing she is complaining about now, she has some new symptoms.
Her joints are very swollen and may definitely be, sometimes she comes
and I see her arms are very swollen.
Ankles feel swollen sometimes and they feel quite painful
and she continues the complaints about her hips cricking
and because her mother is now arthritic and she had two operations, she is very anxious now
that she doesn't become arthritic like her mother but it's definitely something
which started to develop, she can't put her rings on.
And you said that something will start to develop and it has.
She has no hot flushes for the last 3 or 4 weeks.
The only thing that she changes in her food is the desire for cheese,
she said she was craving cheese the last time I saw her.
-Not anymore?
-She is craving cheese but sweet desire has gone and she desires sour, three underlines.
Cheese and sour. Sometimes her glands come up and go down still.
Everything is basically better but there are some new symptoms.
-I would like you to give me an overall impression of your health,
what is your overall impression? How are you doing?
-I really feel much better, I began to see some energy there.
Do you see now? We prescribed in October and it's May and it's the first time she says
I feel a lot better, it's the first time she said it clearly. Because you waited enough,
because you haven't prescribed.
If you had prescribed, you would not hear that. I'm absolutely sure.
Unless we do understand this aspect of Homeopathy, unless we do perceive the deepness
and what we do, how deep we affect the organism and until we appreciate this deep action upon,
it's like a surgery, it goes very deep and corrects.
Then you wait, take your hands off and you wait to see what is happening.
Things fall into place. I will test her hearing now to see how her hearing is.
-I collapse but I can easily get up and then easily get down.
On the other hand I got more spark and it can last. I can laugh more easily.
-It's good.
-I got other things coming up like some swellings.
-Where the swellings are now?
-In my joints.
-All the joints have started swelling?
-My hands particularly in the mornings.
Some mornings I can hardly move my fingers and my feet particularly in the mornings
I can't put certain shoes on and then they get better and I can't put rings on them in the morning.
-Later on you can?
-Yes. It's not as it used to be.
-But the joints seem to be swollen and stay swollen or they go up and down?
-They stay all day but it's worse when I wake up. This thing particularly has been moving.
When I wake in the morning with pain, that goes all day. I have tremendous cricking hips,
every time I get to move my hips crick. It doesn't hurt but I hate the feeling.
-It's cricking, it's not bones that come together.
The cricking is air, which goes inside the sacks, which are around the joint
and this is what makes the noise. It's just air like little sacks, if you squeeze them.
Don't imagine it's the joints which are hitting each other.
-Is this from the antibiotics?
Because when I used to get antibiotics I got rashes always with every antibiotic
and I didn't really bother about them but the actual consultant said that they are worried
that it might affect my joints.
-There is some kind of infection, we can actually do some laboratory tests
for rheumatoid arthritis and see the rate. Just these two factors.
Also what I would like to know is... You have been treated for bronchiectasis, right?
-Yes.
-You have been treated in a hospital, which hospital?
-I have all my original X-rays, my bronchograms.
-What I would like is to have now, not today, if it is possible within the next week
to have an X-ray and compare this X-ray with the old ones and have a report from the radiologist.
Have him to evaluate the situation and give us a report.
-My chest hasn't been so good, the last three months, I'm aware of it.
I feel a smell from it but I'm aware of it.
-But you have to check it up.
-Yes but it's better, it's not concentrated.
-We have to do the check-up and after a year to have another check up
to have an objective confirmation of what we are doing.
Which was the last hospital that you were?
-I was in the London hospital with my TB...
-How many years ago?
-In the 60's. They have put them in the museum.
-So you are in the museum.
That's a good case, for the museum also.
To go after 20 years to show that the lungs are in a better state.
You see all the symptoms of Tuberculinum have gone without any remedy.
Why did I ask for a RA test, rheumatoid arthritis test?
Because in this case because of the severity of the pathology, the level of pathology
it may change into a rheumatoid arthritis state.
You see clearly the direction of the pathology now is going towards the joints,
which indicates a very good direction but still it can be severe, it may be severe.
What is the severe arthritic condition that we may have? It's rheumatoid arthritis.
That's why I checked it immediately after I had the first indications.
So they will not say he has been treating and she had rheumatoid arthritis.
Let's see a little bit more.
-Does he know that you are doing homeopathic treatment?
-Yes.
-Does he object to that?
-No, he says do what you like.
In fact he has asked me to do some work with him for diabetes.
A friend of mine, I still have friends in the hospital, he can't believe how well I look and he
comes to see if the improvement still holds. He is amazed and he is very interested.
-We aroused some curiosity at least.
-I think we aroused it and it's nice.
-Is the rheumatoid test that you can have also? What I would like to see is the radiologist
report, if it is possible within the next week. The other test you can have within this month.
What other things you have to note?
-I had enormous appetite and then that leveled out but now it's more...
-You tried to restrain it?
-No I couldn't restrain it and at night I felt hungry sometimes but I tried sensible food.
-Try to eat as healthy as possible, eat yogurt and fruits and salads.
-My teeth are causing me trouble. They had tremendous sensitivity
but in fact that is much better now. Now it's more one or two teeth that are sensitive.
I now have a lot more desire for cheese.
-Strong cheese or any kind of cheese?
-Basically creamy cheeses. I do like so much meat. I'm not bothered by meat.
-You don't eat it?
-I do eat it.
-You eat it but you don't desire it.
-I used to have a steak but not now. I'm still thirsty but not as thirsty
and I wake up at night thirsty, but that's better.
You see here the symptomatology how fluctuates and eventually takes a shape?
You have to wait until it takes a shape before you can prescribe.
You let it fluctuate, thirst and no thirst, desires cheese...
You don't rush into prescribing for no substantial reason. This is the idea.
Because you may find excuses for prescribing every time, there is no question about that.
What do you think has happened with her hearing?
Let's see.
-Even that it's getting better.
Another thing it may come at night is to urinate, it drives me crazy.
-You have big quantities or little?
-Quite a lot.
-And it is only during the night?
-Yes and in the day and I have stopped drinking about certain clock at night,
I don't drink anything and still I wake up.
-Do you have special time when you wake up?
-Not that I'm aware of.
-It can be 2-3 times?
-Yes sometimes 2-3 times, sometimes 6 times.
-It can be as many as six times?
-It can be, yes.
-What is your reaction to weather?
-I don't like the cold and particularly the cold and damp but today it's sunny and I'm fine,
I'm warm because it's sunny.
-But you don't like the cold?
-No, I don't like the cold days.
-Tell me something else and then I ask you a few things.
-I got noises that buzz in my head all day now. I used to have it but now it's there.
Sometimes it's very bad.
-What is this buzzing?
-It's like a hamming.
-In both ears?
-I'm not aware if it is in my ears, it seems to be in my head.
-What about your hearing?
-I think it's better.
-You are having your hearing aid?
-I do have it but I can carry on a conversation.
-Can you switch it off for me?
-Yes.
-Can you hear what I say now?
-Can you hear what I say?
-But you read the lips.
-Can you hear what I say now?
-Can you hear what I say?
-Can you hear?
-He said something else.
-What is your name?
-No. That was...
-Where do you stay? Where do you stay?
-Where are you staying?
-I think it is improved.
-I think it's better.
The last time I was taking without the hearing aid, she could not hear at all
and she can hear quite a lot now and there is a possibility still of an improvement
as she goes on with the general improvement.
I'm afraid I tired you a little bit with the case but I wanted to show you in a long follow up,
is you don't rush to prescribe and yet you rush to prescribe when the time is right.
This is what it exemplifies this case and also it exemplifies the second difficulty,
we said what is happening to the case? Is she getting better,
is she getting worse after Graphites?
Also I would like you to understand that the cases I'm showing you
they are not a kind of selected cases.
In these seminars, where I have done mostly in America and London,
I have asked every case to come back.
And from those cases, I have seen almost 100 % of these cases back, I'm presenting to you.
It's not a selected case.
Of course here I brought a case that has a relative value concerning the problems
that I wanted to talk to you about but do not get the impression that these are selected cases.
No. My students have the possibility to check me in every case
and always they like to try to catch me being wrong sometimes.
Somebody put a question outside.
Dr Ross, I would like you to ask this question again in the class.
-I asked when you give the right remedy and we have to wait.
I think we wait too long...just  give the right remedy in the good potency
and I asked you what was the result if you repeat the remedy untimely?
-The question was, if you repeat the remedy, for instance after three months,
that's the right remedy Argentum nitricum, the right potency 200 and you repeat it again,
what is going to happen after three months?
The answer is that most probably you will have unwanted reaction because don't forget
that the remedy is not indicated anymore.
Once it has started the changes within the body it's not indicated anymore.
So if you repeat it, it's like repeating a remedy that it's not indicated but it's close enough.
Therefore what you are doing, if you repeat the remedy untimely without being indicated,
you are giving a remedy that is not exactly indicated but it might be close.
Still the condition of the organism might be close to Argentum nitricum.
So therefore Argentum nitricum repeated untimely is going to stir up matters
not in a curative manner but rather in a disturbing manner.
So you will definitely get some disturbance. Whether it is big or small the disturbance,
it will depend on the strength of the constitution of the patient.
If it is a strong constitution, no problem.
A weak constitution, you can have a lot of disturbances.
Somebody else asked me whether I prescribed Tuberculinum in this case.
I didn't give this impression, I did not prescribe Tuberculinum, I did not.
The person received only Graphites and Argentum nitricum.
But we can say that in the future we may expect the possibility of Tuberculinum in this case.
But we have to wait and see that the picture of Tuberculinum is established now
and the person is really suffering and then you are justified to give Tuberculinum.
But if you give it untimely again, you may have some side effects or some unwanted effects.
Unfortunately there was... the impression has been in Homeopathy, give anything,
give any remedy. It doesn't matter, it is without side effect.
That is true but at the same time if you keep on doing these things,
you will never see on the long run real cures. Because you will be mixing up the cases.
It is not that you are going to bring a side effect like in allopathic remedy
but you will change the symptomatology picture to the extent
that you will not recognize it ever to give the right remedy some time.
And I have told you this many times.
In this case you heard the practitioner said I gave Hepar Sulphur, she did somewhat well,
I gave Mercury, she did somewhat well, I gave Psorinum, she did somewhat well etc.
Let's do the graph of that person so far.
Graphites was the first remedy and underneath this remedy
was the symptomatology of Argentum nitricum, which appeared.
Therefore we had there all the time a constitution of Graphites, Argentum nitricum
and a possibility of a third prescription, which is Tuberculinum.
This is the constitution of the person on which we are acting.
Let us say now this person develops a sciatica.
Is the sciatica going to be of the Graphites type? Very doubtful.
Most probably her sciatica will be Kali bichromicum, it develops on top of this here.
So you prescribe Kali bichromicum and she does very well for her sciatica.
The sciatica goes away and she develops a bronchitis and in her bronchitis
she needs Bryonia and you give Bryonia and you treat.
You may treat a case year after year without ever touching the Graphites,
Argentum nitricum basis underneath.
This is what we have been doing many times before we realize what is going on.
Finally the patient is not really improving after years of treatment
though the treatment appears to be successful. Because she came with a cold
and Allium cepa did so well. Immediately it disappeared.
She came with a bronchitis and Bryonia and Rhus tox took away the bronchitis beautifully,
this sciatica etc.
You treat upon a layer, what we call we treat always upon a layer, not the layer itself.
So maybe also you try to treat this layer and you give Hepar Sulphur instead of Graphites.
Because Hepar Sulphur is close, it creates some sort of disturbances or changes
and she says I'm a little better, close to the placebo effect.
This is not placebo effect, this is worse because the placebo effect we don't care.
If this person had come and say I feel a bit better, without deep changes,
constitutional changes, temperature changes and all these dramatic changes,
I would not take into consideration whether she was saying feeling better.
What it means feeling better? It doesn't mean anything.
What I want to see are changes and in depth. Then I know my remedy is acting.
When a person comes and says, how are your headaches? Well I think I'm better.
Placebo, go. And next month he comes again, I have my headaches.
Natrum muriaticum, OK Sepia. Then how are you? I think now I'm really better.
This kind of thing, you can prescribe close to the case, not exact
and you may have some effect and you say better and better and worse and better
and not really touching the case where you see the rejuvenation,
the new situation that will take place.
You see with Homeopathy we have that possibility, there is no question about that.
And we have to exploit it. The problem is to apply it properly and it's not difficult.
But it has to be applied properly. It is the most exact science that exists so far on Earth.
I'm telling you, you have to be very exact, you cannot make mistakes here and there.
You cannot be loose about your way because you will not get these deep reactions.
You have the possibility to get them.
Also in this way you are learning because what you learned about Graphites today,
you will never learn it in any book, it's not written in the books.
You learned this kind of tiredness, this kind of combination, this pathology of the case,
the Raynaud pathology together with the lungs, together with the ear...
You get a complex pathology and you say Graphites.
No questions?
-I have a question.
-She was asking, she has the impression that the patient was acting differently
to the practitioner and to me, that she was giving different information.
Another thing that this question implies is that the practitioner every time she tried
to persuade me to give a remedy, so she will not be bothered by the case.
Fix her quickly so I cannot be bothered, she complains about not having energy
and she gave her impatience about the case but facts are facts.
This is a great talent I can tell you, this is perhaps the greatest difficulty in Homeopathy.
Taking information which is real, the person does not mislead you.
The patient usually wants quick cure, he must be treated fast,
he must be treated immediately, if it is possible tomorrow he must be all right.
And you have to deal with that situation. You have to deal with the anxiety of the patient
to become well completely.
Therefore she says I don't have enough energy, give me energy
and in the meantime you see the sputum is changing colors. What it means?
For those that they have worked in hospitals, you will see the sputum how it smells
and when we have a microorganism which is severe like the bacillus pyocyaneus,
the sputum becomes very offensive.
When it's staphylococcus it's not so smelly.
The discharges which are purulent become transparent eventually,
it's a much better state of affairs, don't touch it, the organism is improving.
Because she says I have no energy. It doesn't matter in this case.
In another case it may matter.