-Did you put a bottle?
-I put a bottle to get my feet warm. I can't bear them too hot either.
-Then you push them out of the bed?
-No my feet are in.
You see in spite of the fact I have a rejected Calcarea carbonica,
she is putting a hot water bottle and then she says I can't bear them too hot.
Because I know in Calcarea carbonica the circulatory system is not easily regulated.
Slow to send the blood and keeps the cold, once it starts sending the blood,
then it becomes too hot and then Calcarea carbonica has to stick her feet out of covers.
That's why Calc carbonica also sticks her feet out of covers.
Now I turn to Calcarea carbonica and I enquire, do you stick your feet out? She said no.
If you are careful enough, the questions and the answers are coming to confirm
or disconfirm the right remedy, as long as you let yourself being open and don't judge.
Don't jump into conclusions because anybody could have jump into conclusions long time ago
and say this is Calcarea.
Fear of mice, worse cold, cold feet. Finished, take Calcarea carbonica. Nothing.
She would be very disappointed.
-With your work you are very fastidious?
-Yes.
-Cleaning the house?
-Yes I like to clean the bathroom and kitchen has to be clean.
For the sake of the students she says she is so tired, she feels so tired
because this is Arsenicum case and she is thirsty, she drinks cold drinks, she is tired.
This is Arsenicum case. So I enquire are you fastidious? How much this, how much that?
For the sake of differential diagnosis to find out that she is not fastidious,
she is not the Arsenicum type.
-Do you like things in order, put them straight?
-Not very much of it. I wouldn't have anything dusty.
-Do you have salivation during sleep?
-Not now, I used to have in the autumn.
When I sweat it's not that awful smell.
-It used to be offensive?
-Yes very.
-What kind?
-To me it was ahorrible smell. Now when I get hot... I get suddenly very hot.
-Your energy is more than when you go to...
-Yes, I'm depressed and frustrated now because I realize I can get better
and I'm upset I want to get my hearing, I know it's there and I can hear beautifully.
-Can you hear sometimes?
-Yes I have 1/3 of my hearing.
-But it's gone?
-It's not very clear and then in the hospital put it...  and then my hearing is back.
Is anybody who wants to ask a question? Are you thinking about a specific remedy,
so you would like to ask a specific question?
I don't ask yet specific question, I could have made it more clear.
Once you hear my question, you will understand the remedy.
-Metallic taste?
-No, she does not have.
-Does she have a small limit where she could be warm or cold?
-No.
-Polypus anywhere?
-Warts?
-No.
Now it's very difficult, I know but I will give you a few hints.
You will look a little bit in your Repertory and you will tell me the remedy
but don't think that the remedy is clear. Do you agree that the remedy is not clear?
Is it clear the remedy?
Anybody who says that it is clear remedy, can anybody says that in the class? No.
Don't tell me afterwards it's clear. It's not clear. The remedy is not clear.
There are some indications about the remedy.
Ask yourself now what is the remedy that has affections of the chest
and the ear primarily? The hearing?
Which has an aversion to salt and also an aversion to sweets that the practitioner
has mentioned in the very beginning.
Go in your Repertory and tell me if you can give me an indication of
what is the remedy that has aversion to salt, aversion to sweets and then tell me
if there is a remedy involved there, which affects both the lungs and the hearing?
Cold as well.
It may be a thirsty remedy also. Look extreme thirst to see if this remedy is there.
Look desires cold drinks to see if this remedy is there.
The remedy that you have thought by these hints...
Did you look aversion to salt, aversion to sweets, a cold remedy that affects the ears,
affects the lungs, has thirst for cold drinks and has worse cold?
Did you look and you did not find the remedy?
What is the remedy? Say all together those who are feeling sure about the remedy,
say it all together.
-Graphites.
-Very good, very good. You are excellent homeopaths now.
If you were thinking Graphites but you are not sure because we selected certain of the symptoms
of the patient and put them together. We are not absolutely sure.
We like to be sure. What is the question that you would like to ask?
-If the practitioner was right, she would say desire fish.
-That is one question that I asked and she did not confirm it already.
When I tried to confirm desire for fish, she didn't really seemed to have a desire for fish.
-Does she have an eczema?
-Whether she has an eczema. The whole thing started after skin eruption.
Suppressed skin eruption it can give problem with Graphites, that is correct.
-Her reaction to music?
-Whether she likes music or whether she cries when she hears music?
It's not a reaction to music.
Graphites feels melancholy when they hear music and it brings on crying.
-Is she constipated?
-Constipation is not a keynote. You would like to hear a keynote of Graphites?
-Does she have cracks?
-She hears better when it is noisy?
-See that in your Repertory, find this hearing better and tell me if this is a keynote of Graphites.
Page 323, did you see it? It's not intuition.
Like when you play chess, you have one possibility with the best.
You have one move which is the best, if you don't make it, you lost.
This is Homeopathy. We have one move to make and it has to be the correct.
Because the hearing is impaired in this case and because you know
that the keynote of Graphites is hearing better when there is noise,
the hearing becomes better, you will have to ask this question the patient.
And if she says yes in this case, this case becomes Graphites, not Phosphorus, not...
But it is not clear, do you agree? Don't tell me now it is a clear cut case. No.
There are indications about Graphites.
-Is it both ears the same or worse the right side?
-Worse right side. Yes, I think...
-When she was three she had a mastoid infection, she didn't have antibiotics then.
Swelling...
-That's why I lost hearing but I wasn't aware of being deaf then.
So therefore this is not a loquacious patient. If this was a Lachesis case,
she would not have stopped. I look in the Repertory or I pretend I don't look there.
A Lachesis person will not stop talking. Never mind whether you listen or you don't listen,
Lachesis has to talk, therefore she is not loquacious.
And I remember I asked her specifically, she said sometimes I can be loquacious,
sometimes I'm not. And the interview does not bring out loquacity.
Some of you noticed loquacity in the beginning; it appeared to be a little bit loquacious but no.
Loquacity always is when the person talks almost without caring whether anybody is hearing
and also talking in different subjects.
Then it becomes loquacity, an urge to talk.
She is not volunteering any answers.
I give her the chance to talk if something comes to her mind.
Sometimes it is very interesting and very important when after a pause,
the person himself comes out with an answer without a direct question.
-From high places you have vertigo?
-No, I get noise in the ears. But when I'm occupied, I forget.
-Is there any other condition when the hearing is better?
-When I'm very relaxed. It'd been better the last few months.
If I'm relaxed I can hear well but I can hear very well in the noise.
You see first I go around the ears, I brought her attention around the ears.
I would like for the sake of the students, this is why I' m doing all that...
So if there is something peculiar, she will come out and tell without me asking because
always the students accuse me, you ask so direct questions.
I try my best, as you see, to be a good student of yours.
So I bring the attention and then she says yes and then I stop and I wait.
I wait with the hope that she may come and say, you know something?
I'm hearing better with the noise.
It doesn't come out, so what shall I do?
Then I ask, is there any condition in which you are hearing better?
I put not a direct question.
Then she comes up, she misunderstands my answer.
I don't want still to put the direct question and eventually because the symptom exists,
it is strong and she knows it, eventually she brings it out.
The thing is that if I had done that without explaining to you what I'm doing,
I'm sure I would come to the class, I let you see the case
and you prescribe most of you Calcarea carbonica, from Calc carbo to Sepia,
all the range outside of Graphites.
Why? Because you didn't pay attention.
Why I have arrived at this? In spite of the fact she would tell me in the beginning desire fish,
while I know Graphites has rather aversion to fish.
She misguided from the beginning.
When I came back in the middle of the interview, I enquire about fish,
she didn't give me the impression that she desires fish, on the contrary.
Fish, I can eat it maybe sometimes. Then I said all right.
Then I go to salt. Definitely aversion to salt, I don't want salt.
Then I remember the practitioner has said aversion to sweets.
I don't want the students to know, I don't want to go to the class and everybody says Graphites,
as you understand.
I want first to make aware the student that unless he is very careful,
unless he puts things together, unless he does certain mental exercises,
he will not come down with the right remedy.
First I gave the impression you don't know at all which is the right remedy.
But who could have known?
In between the symptomatology there is something which pops out, as long as you can dig it out.
So it is not Mercury, it is not... It is a Graphites case.
Let us see now what happened when we gave Graphites in this case.
Can you go to the first follow up?
Graphites was given on April 86, about 13 months ago. Graphites 200.
-She was very positive in desire fruits and it's not there.
-That's why I said, don't rely completely to the Repertory
because Graphites may have desire fruits and it's not recorded.
-Only in this case or generally Graphites likes fruits?
-I don't know, I can't tell you.
-In 86 she was prescribed Graphites 200.
-After the remedy, she took the remedy on 16th of May and I saw her at 23rd.
The first week...
-What was the main complaint?
-The main complaint was bronchiectasis and hearing problem, she had very poor hearing.
The first week she was very tired from sleeping 10 hours every night.
She was very heavy sleep, she felt tremendously tired in the afternoon.
-She slept more hours than usual?
-She said she slept deeper than usual, also she was thirstless one week after the remedy.
She's been out socializing a lot, she has a mouth ulcer two weeks after the remedy
and she felt she was starting a cold two weeks after the remedy.
She still feels very exhausted this is four weeks after the remedy,
she was considering her period didn't come this month, she said it's becoming menopausal.
She is been in the last couple of weeks a bit depressed. Weariness coming in the afternoon...
The ears are not discharging so much, she says she feels a bit calmer about the future
and the desire for pickles has gone. This is the only change.
Her stomach problems she seems much better at the moment.
She is still tremendously complaining about this weariness
she said she had lots of energy for a week and then she relapses, she can't cope with anything,
she can't be sleeping.
-What did she say now?
-She had this after the remedy, she felt she was going out during the day,
she could go out at night. She stopped working for the time being, she was on holidays.
But she is always complaining about fatigue and weariness.
Last night she said she slept well.
I find it difficult to analyze this case.
-Do you have any other observations?
-The discharge from the ear was not so strong smelling.
-The amount of the discharge is less or the same?
-She said it is less.
-Yellow-white, offensive and sometimes brownish?
-Yes.
-The noises in the ear?
-The noises in the ear are slightly better but they change all the time.
-Two weeks after the remedy...
One week after the remedy I became thirstless which is not usual.
I felt very tired, I'm extremely tired for the first four weeks, I needed 10 hours of sleep.
-Usually how many hours do you sleep?
-Usually 7,5 to 8 hours.
-And you slept for 10 hours?
-Yes, it was beautiful sleep. Three weeks after the remedy I had great menses pain
and particularly on urination...
...and pains on my joints.
Four weeks after the remedy I found I could not remember a name in a conversation.
-Do you remember names of people?
-Not people but a place, a flower... and I found that scaring.
My desire for sour things is gone... My teeth have become very sensitive.
The sputum in my chest has become a lot worse.
-It doubled the amount or three times the amount?
-It's the same but now it's thick. It's somehow creamy and greenish...
-Did you notice any change in the sputum?
-It was much less. For the first four weeks it was better and then it became back again.
And then after six weeks after the remedy again...But it hasn't really gone much...
When I'm tired I really get... I wear glasses, I put on my contact lenses when I'm tired.
Now I haven't slept at all and I get very, very tired and I don't feel well.
I feel better today because I had got a good night sleep last night.
-How was your energy level in this period in general?
-Not tremendously better at all.
-It was better than before the remedy or the same than before the remedy?
-The same or worse.
-The whole period or there was a period when it was worse and then the same and then better?
-It's the same initially and now the last month it's been worse, very draggy and I have found
that time I'm hot, every time I can't be cool.
-You are chilly.
-I can't be cool.
-You can't be cool.
-I have to be indoors and I'm hot and clammy the whole time
and I put on my thermometer to see what is going on and I'm very hot the whole time.
-Do you have any salivation, any metallic taste in your mouth?
-No, no. I cannot get cool. It's unusual for me.
-Because you were very chilly as you reported.
- If I get cold my hands get white.
-Even now?
-...The sweat when I was in hospital was very cold, feeling cold winter.
-You had streptomycin?
-Twice.
-And after the streptomycin you got cold?
-I'm not absolutely sure how much I had... I was in hospital for six months.
-During the time of the hospital, you got the same?
-Yes, so I just wonder...
It's interesting the feeling, I was wanting air.
-Do you cry easily now?
-Not very easily.
-Your food except of the change in pickles, is there any other change?
-I'm not very hungry, I haven't got great appetite that I had before.
-You did actually cry when we were talking last time,
she has been a little bit weepy with me sometimes.
-Have you given any Tuberculinum?
-Only Hepar Sulphur and Mercury.
-...
-What about the fright, do you imagine jumping?
-...with that impulsive side.
I notified I'm very much shy in a way, I hold back in a situation, I don't join in.
-But you look to me quite open and happy.
-Yes I'm open and happy, I just long to get strength and energy.
I get a tired feeling in the head, my head feels tired and I feel frustrated.
-Do you need a lot of sugar?
-More than used to.
-You are doing very well actually and with the next remedy...
Does she know the remedy she was taking?
-No.
-Do you have any other aversion?
-Can you look so I can talk to you to see your hearing? Can you hear me now?
-Yes I can hear you. When I'm going in stressed situation, I will turn my hearing aid off.
-Turn it up. Can you hear me now?
-Yes you are very clear.
-What is your name?
-Very well. Most probably your hearing has improved.
-I think but this weekend and I had a tremendous trouble because I needed selective hearing
and I couldn't.
-What is your name?
-What is your name? You see?
-It changes.
What do you think? She is doing well? You think she is going to commit suicide?
Fall into the train?
She has now impulses when the train comes but she is doing very well.
What is happening here? The practitioner didn't mentioned it here
but when she met me she said I don't know what is happening, her eyes are squinting,
she has impulses to commit suicide and to fall under the train,
she has all kinds of strange phenomenon happening; so she mentioned some of these
during the interview. The most interesting is this impulse to jump from a higher place,
when the train comes to jump into the train and she retreats back,
the impulse is there and then she retreats back and she is very hot
and the desire for sweets has increased.
What you have to do here is to pass judgment whether your remedy has acted.
Whether the remedy has acted there is no question about that.
Why? Because it has produced certain changes.
First of all she has slept 10 hours the day, which is a good reaction to have immediately
after a remedy a lot of sleep. It's a good reaction in generally
but in her case I did not bring about any real change in the tiredness.
She says the tiredness is the same or perhaps worse.
Also the hearing is affected, it's a bit better
but what is interesting is now coming in the tube where the noise is usually
and she could hear better, now she could not hear better in the tube.
That means that peculiarity of Graphites is gone, that means Graphites
as a remedy has done whatever it could.
There are certain other symptoms to indicate that Graphites did  whatever it could
and another layer has come up, another remedy has come up.
So Graphites has acted, it has not cured the case, the case has now some mental pathology,
the tiredness is the same, the hearing is better.
You see desire pickles is not mentioned in the Repertory for Graphites,
yet Graphites cures this symptom.
That means she has the desire and the possibility to cure the symptom.
So if you like, you can add desire for pickles but it's not important.
I did not base my prescription desire for pickles or desire for food.
I based my prescription in aversion to sweets, aversion to salt,
hearing impaired and the keynote.
Therefore what is the remedy which is worse from heat?
She cannot cool down, worse from heat.
Desire for sweets becomes important in this case because she had aversion to sweets.
Now she desires sweets, it becomes strong.
An impulse to jump from a high place, she says my god what I'm going to do?
What is the remedy?
-Argentum nitricum.
-You see now two months after the initial prescription of Graphites,
we have the action of the Graphites finished and another remedy coming into action,
which is Argentum nitricum.
This case for me is very clear, it's Argentum nitricum, there is no question about that.
I will prescribe Argentum nitricum and I will show you what happened in the follow up,
in a year time and show you what happened after the Argentum nitricum.