We come back to this case now. What potency?
The remedy is clear or not first of all? Yes it's clear.
For me it's not clear because this kind of case can hide things behind.
To the best of our understanding and ability we've put things together
and we said Nat. carbonicum covers best the case.
But it's not a very clear cut case.
I would like you to see the pictures.
She said that she would wake up in the night and she would call her son, Marcus!
Then Marcus will not come because he knows that his mother is going to wake up
and kept on sleeping peacefully. He never came to her room
but she would still call him and then after a few minutes she will calm down
and go back to sleep.
That was the syndrome.
Do you see that the toes are crooked?
Zoom down on the toes.
-During the last two years the hair have grown.
-OK. Tell me something else, how do you feel sexually? You have desire?
-Yes.
-Always you had desire?
-Not the time with my husband. Not at all.
-When you were with your husband did you have desire for other men?
-No.
-Not at all?
-Are you sure?
-Yes, I lived many years without having any contact.
-Then what happened with your husband, how did you have a son, if you didn't have a contact?
-It was one time when I felt good with my skin after the treatment in the clinic.
I had a very good skin and I felt better than the years before and I decided to have a child.
At that time I never had a plan to leave my husband and that was...
-It was your decision actually?
-It was my decision and it was really the first time it happened.
-And the next day you didn't have anymore?
-No.
-Just one time and then you didn't want anymore?
-It was the first time in your life and it was a pleasure or it was unpleasure?
-I drunk a bottle of wine.
-Your son has any skin problem?
-Yes he has acne.
-Severe acne?
-Yes, his back, breast and face.
-Do you have anxiety about your health?
-Yes since two years.
-What are you afraid? You are afraid of heart attack or that you will get cancer,
that you will die from a disease?
-I often feel so weak and then I think, I can't call a situation.
-This on the face, on the nose and on the cheeks always was like that?
-It's new, since I took Pulsatilla.
Before that I had nothing in the face and I was very happy about that and after Pulsatilla
it came in the face and since that time it is in the face.
And when I was very young I had it in the face too, in the front only, not here.
Why do I ask about this distribution?
-For Sepia?
-I don't ask for Sepia.
What I'm asking myself in this case is how seriously, how deeply is affected?
We have cases of psoriasis in so different degrees, we have severe cases,
very severe cases and milder cases and very mild cases. Very mild cases of psoriasis mean nothing.
Very severe cases of psoriasis have a lot of problems and psoriasis can go inside
and create a lot of disturbances.
Is this a severe case of psoriasis?
It is a very severe case of psoriasis because what we see on the legs,
now with the psoriasis being inside has been transformed into duodenal ulcer,
into headaches and into psoriatic arthritis.
When do we see psoriatic arthritis? In severe cases of psoriasis.
When the psoriasis will become from psoriatic arthritis is depending on the time,
after a year, after two years, after 20 years. Then the stronger is the case.
The more severe is the case.
If the psoriasis starts and after six months you have psoriatic arthritis,
you have a very serious case at hand.
Don't expect, don't tell them I'm going to cure you.
Even with the right remedy it's going to take very long time before you bring around such cases.
This case is one of those very severe cases, why?
Because she had the psoriasis from very young age, under a shock her grandmother died
and then it went to another level the psoriasis and then it went into another level.
Headaches, pains, exhaustion, psoriasis and arthritic pains.
There is a distribution of the disease now and you see it in different levels.
Once the disease is going to concentrate in one level the most external,
it's going to be quite severe. She is going to go through a severe aggravation of the arthritis.
There is no way out. First of all we have to know that and to prepare.
To say do you want this? We try. Usually we say what we will do during the crisis.
Will you take away my psoriasis? You say, no I don't take it, it's going to stay.
For how long? I don't know.
In this case you don't say it will stay one year or two or three years.
You don't know really but what is more important from a pathology point of view
in this case that you have to be aware.
Can anybody tell me what is going to take place from a pathology point of view,
if you give the right remedy?
There is a possibility that something will take place.
What is this something? Can anybody tell me?
The whole class knows that; I'm asking something deeper than that.
It will go back to three years ago? No, I don't mean that.
-What will take place in her mind?
-Yes and what will take in her physical body? Worse yes. Where?
Duodenal ulcer. No.
Mainly the duodenal ulcer is going to be aggravated, though it is the last thing that happened,
so it should not be very aggravated. The headaches may be aggravated the first 2-3 days,
the duodenal ulcer may be aggravated within the next week or two.
The sensitivity to the sun may go away after 3-4 months.
There is a sequence of events that will take place and within that sequence
we have to expect something which may alarm you. That's why I'm mentioning it.
-A growth.
-Very good.
Do you remember that this woman mentioned a fibroma in the uterus?
Why a fibroma in the uterus? This woman has a lot of upset in her hormonal system situation.
The hormonal upset we see first by suppressing sexual desire almost completely
to the extend that she does not have any sexual desire.
He was exactly to the month what she meant. They are born the same month.
She was in the same age. One year up and down, this is what I meant.
It happened but it was exactly How I came to that conclusion? It's not reading the mind.
I will analyze it now.
-She had first the husband who was a marriage convenience, he accepted her disease
and married him and then she could not have sex with him for different reasons.
Then she has a love affair with an older man by whom she likes.
Because then she was devastated when he left her.
That means she was attached to this man and she was having satisfaction,
most probably sexual satisfaction as well, in spite of the fact that he was an older man.
But after the shock what happened? The woman goes through that shock,
then the hormonal system shrinks again, the desire that was motivated,
that was let loose during the second or third, with this doctor,
the hormonal system is functioning, trusting and at a certain moment distrust.
I made a mistake, I let myself open, I should not have done this.
This is how I imagine, the hormonal system draws back desire, you should not have desire.
Then in order to do that a woman develops unbalance in her hormonal balance.
More female hormones and less male and then through effort male hormones will be more
and female hormones will be less because emotionally she thinks it should be this way.
I must not have desire, so there is an imbalance in the hormonal system
which reduces the desire for sex.
But once she has felt the desire, she cannot reduce it completely.
Therefore there is a growth in hair growth pointing out to the possibility
of male hormones having increased but at the same time she has the desire,
it is not lost completely.
But who can stimulate the desire?
Only somebody who is...  she needs a strong sexual partner to reactivate
what has been reduced through the shock. So it is a kind of mathematics.
All these things are going on in my mind and then I ask is he the same age?
This is my thinking. Am I thinking correctly for this case?
It is a kind of check-up.
Did you remember the point? She says yes, I was surprised he is exactly the same age.
I can't believe it. I don't read the mind.
You will say why do you need all that? You don't need all that, you can give Natrum carbo
because she has aversion to milk.
Some keynote prescribers say aversion to milk? Nat carbo and by chance
they don't give one of the other 60 remedies, by chance you give Nat carbo
and the case is beautiful.
You can do that and you can do a more thorough analysis and a more thorough understanding
of what is going on in this case. It depends on what depth.
The more you understand the case, the more you learn to understand...
This is a process, what I'm teaching you is a process, which in my life time
I found it more rewarding.
You can be a keynote prescriber, I do not object with that, I will not accuse you
but I will say this is a way of prescribing. You want it? It's a bit hard,
it needs a lot of application, a lot of study but it's a much more rewarding situation.
After three years with keynote prescribing this woman will be exactly the same,
if not worse.
With this kind of prescribing after three years, she is going to be better.
How much better? I don't know, maybe 30% better, 50% better.
After three years 50% better it's nothing. That's all we can do.
We cannot do more, the case is too deep.
When she will open up emotionally, with Nat carbo, she will open up emotionally,
the hormonal system will vibrate and in the meantime she has a partner
and the memory I must not let myself, then the uterus will swell up.
The impact will be taken on this level; that's why I predict
that we are going to have a big fibroma in the uterus. And then you get scared.
Shall we operate? All these conditions come into questioning then.
I will give you a rule for operating or not operating which I follow.
If the fibroma does not give problems and the person does not have constant bleedings
or other discomforts or pains or whatever, leave it alone.
Fibromas in one part is like skin, like mucus membranes.
They take the impact, they grow but if there is bleeding, you have to take measures.
One of the measures of course is to operate, this is not the best thing you can do
but you may have to do it.
-From the beginning it seemed like her organism was very sensitive to grief.
The grandmother died she developed myomas.
From the beginning of the case I was looking for a remedy that had much grief in it,
that had myomas after grief. In the beginning she got the psoriasis
and then she had headaches after grief, she was devastated when her lover left
and I was wondering, I don't have it in my notes, that Nat carbo
but it has so much of a grief and I just wanted to enquire about that.
-We may say that all the Natrums have ailments from grief with the following sequence.
The most is Natrum muriaticum. The next is Natrum carbonicum,
the third is Natrum sulphuricum and the fourth is Natrum phosphoricum.
In this sequence you will perceive Natrums as having ailments from grief.
I would say because of the phosphorus element in the Natrum phosphoricum,
you do not get really the deep grief though you get another thing.
I have not spoken ever about Natrum phosphoricum but it is a subtle situation
which we may have to discuss one day but this is the sequence.
Nat carbo is one of the most sensitive Natrums and that's why their solar plexus,
the stomach which takes the emotions a lot, which is dealing with emotions is so much affected.
Nat carbo is very much affected in the stomach and it is a dyspeptic remedy.
It is a remedy that suffers a lot with discomfort, dyspepsia and also Nat carbo
is a remedy that alternates between the headaches and stomach pains.
There are periods where the stomach pains are much and the headaches less and vice versa.
They are periods, six months, nine months etc.
But I would say that in this case we might expect within three years
the appearance of the fibroma, it will become much greater than what we see
and we have at this moment.
We expect before that, that the psoriasis is going to be quite strongly manifested
and also psoriatic pains.
I don't believe that we can ever stop the psoriatic pains and the psoriasis.
If you expect that the psoriasis will go away, you will make a big mistake.
The psoriasis can reach a point that it will be a little less than what we see
but she will not have the headaches and she will not have pains and also from time to time
she will have arthritic pains.
There is no way, I believe maybe I'm wrong but I'm giving you my experience,
there is no way that you can cure completely this case.
-Not all cases. I would say many fibromas. I would see a connection between
hormonal disturbances either conscious or unconscious of a woman and I would see also
that this is a good place to appear.
It is still on the periphery, it is not too deep, to appear the manifestation of the disturbance.
-Nux moschata?
-No, nux moschata will be in a dizzy state, completely absent minded.
This woman is not absent minded, she is a woman who has suffered a lot.
You see the story. That kind of suffering of a woman is terrible and still she is on the point
when she answers.
We do not see the hesitations, the kind of absent mindness and the kind of inner state of Nux.
-What potency?
-Therefore the potency should be...
I would suggest is a medium potency, Nat carbo 200 and with serious observation
of what takes place, we wait and wait and wait.
Not just wait when there is no reaction, no information.
Wait when there is reaction, there is information but be sensitive to perceive the information.
People are saying I'm the same and 80% better and still say I'm the same.
If you don't understand that, then you are tending to give another remedy.
And it can be 80% better and say still I have my headaches and you press them,
you get some Arsenicums and some Natrum muriaticums and some Aurums,
they will not say I'm better.
They will just not say it, until everything is cleared up, they don't believe
that something will happen.
Until everything is cleared up, until this clearing is for a long time and then you lose them,
you don't see them again, they don't come and tell you it was very nice,
they don't want to have this kind of exchange of energy.
It is too much for a Natrum to owe something, for an Aurum to owe something, for an Arsenicum.
It is too much for their psyche to admit that I owe you my life, let's take it to extreme.
You get other remedies that are very grateful and they will come and thank you and all that.
And we need that, homeopaths absolutely need to hear that because it strengthens them.
Because you have one success and five failures, so at least tell me that I have one success.
We need that.
-Can you see a remedy that perhaps is following?
-That's a good question. I can't really in this case.
If you take the symptomatology somebody suggested Borax.
It is a possibility but I don't see Borax as a picture. She has quite a lot of symptoms
that is Borax, it is correct.
I think what may also need at certain point is a high dose of Ignatia.
Nat carbo and then Ignatia at a certain point.
The organism is such a strange complicated thing.
You see the grief and the grief is so deep that instead of Ignatia being the first, it is Nat carbo.
And after Nat carbo the grief comes to the surface and she starts crying and  suffering,
remembering the past, that is the time for Ignatia.
When if Ignatia was given in the beginning it may not have an effect,
she may come to an Ignatia state because this is so much grief, she may come into Nat mur state,
if she starts eating salt this woman.
I would immediately go and give Nat mur. If this woman comes and tells me
I have a great desire for salt, I don't need anything else, Nat carbo did a lot,
did what it should, now Nat mur. Then after Nat mur we will see the real effect.
The patient will say now I'm better but unless you start in the right sequence of events, forget it.
I had my secretary which I had a few years ago. She had tremendous bleedings,
I was giving Nat mur, Pulsatilla, Sepia etc. no effect.
Then I sit down and take the case Millefolium I give Millefolium and she comes I'm the same,
still bleeding, a lot of bleeding.
I said wait and then I observe that she had become spiteful. She is very spiteful with me.
Whatever it is, I feel...
I said to her do you have a boyfriend? She said yes but lately I have problems.
What problems? I don't want to sleep with him.
I said before the remedy you were sleeping? Yes there was no problem.
Spiteful with aversion to sex after Millefolium Sepia, beautiful
But I've given Sepia before, why it did not act?
Because it needed Millefolium to bring the picture of Sepia out clearly
and then you give it and then you see the effect.
Unless these things are understood, we are going to have problems, problems.
It is a nice thing when the students come and give me the feedback
and say you are right because this is the case I had, this is what happened to me, same things.
Then I have an objective feedback from other people who have same experiences.
-I'm sorry, I still don't see where you dropped Nat mur?
-First of all because Nat mur was not, when I asked about salt, she said no.
Then the aversion to milk was too strong. You may say Nat mur has also aversion to milk
but it is too strong.
Thirdly the way she described that she wants to be under shade.
Natrum muriaticum can tolerate some amount of sun. It does not really to wear a hat all the time,
all the time to be under shade. It is Nat carbo that cannot tolerate at all the sun,
it has to be all the time under shade.
Not only that but she says I'm more open lately.
Nat mur would have been even more closed than what you have seen.
She would not have said, if she had been to a Nat mur state, she would have said
the last two years I'm more closed. I think I closed more.
What she said is that the last years, I'm more open and you remember I said,
do you consider yourself an open person? She said yes, considering to how closed I was,
that's what she meant.
So before she might have been a Nat mur, we may expect a Nat mur appearing
but now we have to give Nat carbo.
-She said that she is much more open the last two years and the sensitivity to the sun
is also the last two years.
-Because if it is a proving, the proving does not last.
The symptom of a proving will last 1,2,3 months and it will go away.
Also a proving of a remedy, the symptoms of the remedy does not really changes planes.
If you have a close remedy, it can make you a suppression but a proving
it won't change levels on health.
A proving will be that she was having after Nat mur headaches between 10 to 2 o'clock.
That headache will last 1,2 months, 1,2 weeks, 3 months the most.
Then they will disappear, they cannot stay.
What happened in her it is the shock that changes level and brings out a new state of things.
What is this new state? We take into consideration everything
and we see that Nat carbo covers the case mostly.
-How do you explain Pulsatilla?
-Partial action, it can aggravate a portion, whatever it might be,
without starting a real process from inside outwards.
Let us say I will give in this case Sulphur, you will see a tremendous aggravation
in the skin without an amelioration inside. How this comes? We don't understand it.
It is like aggravating a symptom, a level and all the organism remains the same
and at a certain point you just aggravate that point. You make disturbances from that point.
You will see it in your practice many times, what I'm talking it's not imagination,
it's facts that you will see it again and again.
The most difficult of these cases was Causticum. Why? Because it was not a strong Causticum.
The other Causticum that was strong, you say yes Causticum.
This Causticum was not strong. It hesitated and when he came back in the first interview,
that's where most of you went wrong.
The words that he was using were the same as before but the words do not mean anything.
It is facts, how she feels about me. The fact, not what she says.
We have to be perceptive for that, we have to be attentive.
We will see in the following days, I will show you cases from the beginning with long follow ups
and you will see what I mean and you will tell me what is happening.
I promised you also to show you a case where I made mistakes. I prescribed wrongly constantly.
You like that? You will enjoy this case mostly.
You will go away and you will remember only that case.
This is a very interesting case that I want to show you.
Some of you have seen some of it, not all the follow up.
You will see a very interesting case that for me it was a teaching case also.
-Why it is not Nat carbo in the rubric?
-He asks why Nat carbo...?
Because it has not been recorded, it does not mean that it is not there.
But Nat carbo has not as strong ailments from grief as the other Natrum, the Nat mur.
This also we know. Also I said it might be Nat carbo first and Nat mur second.
The grief may appear more in that woman after Nat carbo.
You may have more grief appearing consciously because she is not conscious of all things
that are happening. The impact has been taken upon the body.
-What about Staphysagria? Is it completely out?
-No it is not completely out but we do not have enough information to make a prescription,
where Nat carbo we have a lot. If we repertorize, we will see Nat carbo quiet frequently.
-She can continue the light therapy?
-She can continue the light therapy.