This is a 124 kilos woman, 270 pounds.
She is a Ph.A. in anesthesiology.
She has obesity and she has problems with her menses. She is 28.
Until 23 years old the menses were normal, every 28 days.
She had some emotional problems with her family
that as an effect had the delay of menses to the extent that she has menses
every 40 days now and reaches up to 2 months.
That was the case until two years ago when she got into fight with a friend of hers
while at the same time she was taking Terolak. It must be some hormone.
Then she had a metrorrhagia and she took estrogen for that.
There was a delay of 4 months and then kept on coming late, 2-3 months.
The last time she saw her menses is in January 81 and she had come to us in January 82.
One year now with no menses.
Sorry, October 81 she had again menses with great amount of blood and clots.
In order to stop it she took the preventing hormones, the birth control pills.
In 30 days normal menses and pain with much blood and the membrane
of the uterus was coming out.
She took again birth control pills for two months.
Three years ago she had become pregnant but she did voluntary abortion.
Three years ago.
Since she was 16 years old, she started putting on weight very rapidly
after the separation of her parents.
Many times she had tried different fasts but as soon as she stopped the fast, she'd retake the kilos.
She would take up to 7 kilos the week.
She went to a homeopath who was in the Center for some time
and he is working by himself now
and he gave her Natrum Muriaticum and some Kalium.
This is her doctor who stayed in the Center for six months.
He gave her about 3-4 remedies trying to find the right one.
Anyhow that was his assessment.
When she used to get normal menses, she had 4 days of blood.
The first two days a lot of blood and then the last two days less.
The last day had a lot of blood and during the night also.
That was worse movement and better lying down, the pain was better then.
The last period with menses was quite a lot of blood with clots and
she had a lot of metrorrhagia during night and that was worse by movement
and better lying down.
The blood was coming out more when she was walking and if she lies down
the blood would come out less.
The last menses is the last menses. When I hear that it doesn't register...
The last menses what? Is it a big keynote what she is talking about?
But you don't have it as a constant thing coming all your life which you take...
You are about to laugh easily and what I wanted to tell you is
when I was taking the case she was telling me about the other doctors and how
they ridicule her. Don't laugh.
We should be at the corner when one of these patients goes to them and tells about that.
When we laugh with the mistakes of somebody else, that's better at that time to think
of our own mistakes and then we feel better.
Pain on the right foot, on the anterior side of the thigh, starting from knee going upwards.
This pain started 20 days after taking the birth control pills.
She says she is taking a lot of X-Ray because she is working on that department.
She has pain in the back in the lumbar region in the center, worse motion, underlined twice.
And she explained that my weight is so much that I feel this is from my overweight
that I have that pain.
Better lying down on the back, better when she sits bending forward underlined once.
Wakes up with pain in the back in the morning, as if I have not rested at all.
Pain on the cervical region and between the shoulder blade.
Worse with exertion, the pain on the cervical and worse towards the end of her work.
This pain is better by movement and worse by keeping it immovable.
This pain in the cervical is better by movement, underlined twice.
So the pain in the back is worse motion twice and the pain in the cervical
better with movement, underlined twice.
Her hair is very greasy and in two days she must wash again.
Diarrhea twice. All kinds of fat brings diarrhea, underlined twice.
If I eat soft boiled egg, I will start having diarrhea within two hours.
Many times I have an intense desire to eat green things
because by eating green things the diarrhea stops.
That's peculiar. Usually the diarrhea...
The diarrhea starts about 1,30 hour after eating and she has pain,
especially if she eats something fat. Worse anxiety and worse fasting.
The pain and the diarrhea.
When I am tired and psychologically tired I just want to eat.
She goes there and eats all the time.
She says I want to eat because the eating anesthetizes me.
Often tachycardia, sleeps on the abdomen, all the time she changes position.
When I wake up I feel stiffness but when I go into the bathroom
and I have a bath, I feel better.
I keep my feet inside, I have nightmares.
Until 23 years old, she had dreams of flying.
Feet perspire all the time in winter and the summer.
Very warm extremities.
Warm water in the spine makes me feel much better, underlined 3 times.
Can anyone see the remedy?
Better warm water 3 times, better motion, pain here.
Calc. phos. is the best until now.
When I'm not feeling well I just lie down and I don't want to see anybody.
The only thing that makes me feel better this time is music.
She is a singer, she sings very nicely, music touches her very much and
brings about something that is better than the indifference in which she is inside.
She is worse with cloudy weather, one underline.
When it's cloudy weather I don't want to sleep, I feel an empty feeling in the stomach
and I'm just bored from everything.
She is an open character, she talks for her problems,
Anxiety in her work, I'm concerned to see people sick, which is underlined twice.
She talks and laughs a lot, the doctor says constantly she asked what are you writing?
Desires company, underlined 3 times.
Thirsty for cold twice, desires spinach, lemon and fizzy drinks twice.
Aversion to sweets, no underline and aversion to salt, no underline.
In the morning I sleep always better - don't change the remedy because the remedy
is not so difficult...
Likes warm weather, neither she is feeling too cold nor too hot.
When I go out in the summer suddenly the sun brings me a kind of unwell feeling.
Likes the sea underline twice, much cold if I walk outside, it bothers me.
She has some fears of thunderstorms, no underline.
She likes dancing, she likes actually very much dancing she says later.
I cannot tolerate tight clothes,
fear earthquakes,
fear of dead, fear cemeteries, fear of ghosts,
fear that somebody might do some harm to her, all this not underlined.
She says I need affection, she is generally an open person and very joyful,
when she is in company.
That's the case.
What about that?
Pulsatilla only ameliorates in the sea but because it is cold.
She is ameliorated in taking a cold bath.
It might be aggravated but mostly the basic description of that would be
a Pulsatilla which is ameliorated by cold.
General amelioration by a cold bathing and local amelioration by a cold bathing.
But you may see an arthritic condition of Pulsatilla, they go inside the sea
and they get better.
-Give her Medorrhinum.
-No it's not. You have to differentiate between local amelioration and general amelioration,
which is a different thing.
Ledum is the same thing. It goes into cold and it's ameliorated.
Ledum needs very cold. Pulsatilla with just cool water could be OK.
Ledum must be ice cold. You go to Guaiacum.
It's the same thing. Not ice cold but cold.
Cold ameliorates but now Pulsatilla has worse from the pains on the knee mostly & Guaicum has worse pains on the wrists.
So we have two symptoms; ameliorated by cold and we have arthritic pains...
Where are the arthritic pains? Whether they are here or whether they are there,
they determine what we give.
But it's not that Pulsatilla cannot have pains on the wrists, it has pains all over.
Guaiacum prefers in most of the cases, it develops an inflammation on the wrists
and Pulsatilla prefers to develop an inflammation on the knees.
Actually except of the worse with fat, except of that, which is a keynote for Pulsatilla,
what are the remedies?
-Nat muriaticum.
-China.
-Carbo vegetabilis.
-Carbo vegetabilis is a remedy that is aggravated and we don't usually think about.
Also another remedy, a small remedy starting with C...
-Cyclamen.
-Cyclamen yes.
Except of that do we have another keynote, another strong symptom for Pulsatilla?
-Sun aggravates.
-Sun aggravates. How much is that?
-Three.
-Neither too cold nor very hot.
I don't see it. Is it underlined 3 times?
She feels neither of the extremes but somewhere she says she says a little bit towards the cold
-Worse is too cold outside.
-This will make you be careful about Pulsatilla, this information.
Pulsatilla is quite strong.
Another thing you must remember about remedies.
You say Arsenicum always is cold and Pulsatilla always is hot
and that is true with some exception.
Just have in mind these exceptions but use exception on the right time.
OK the person sometimes is cold but you have to have strong evidence
that in spite of being cold, that is a Pulsatilla case. Strong evidence.
Do not forget this main characteristic of remedies, don't put it aside just like that
because you want to say it is a case of Arsenicum.
And you say it's not ameliorated by heat but I can feel the Arsenicum.
No, you have to have strong reasons for that; otherwise most probably it's another remedy.
You tend to do a lot of that. I understand why perhaps.
Because you are in practice before you have enough knowledge,
enough information and you want to give something, you must give a remedy
within a limit of time and that's where you make the mistake.
We got a situation with the supervised clinic where you just give your idea
and then somebody else...
She is afraid of thunderstorms without any underline.
I want to ask you about that symptom.
Would you use it for a reference on another case of Graphites or you would not use it?
Should this symptom, the fear of thunderstorm no underlined...
Are you going to take it out as a feature of Graphites? No. Yes?
-I wouldn't highlight it.
-If you are doing work of adding symptomatology on the Repertory systematically,
that means having a book in which it is A, B, C, and you have your remedies...
You know a book with A five pages, B five pages, this kind of book.
You find a remedy first that you have, how you do this systematically?
You put Graphites there and you put down
fear of thunderstorms because it was cured.
Now you get another case. You don't remember that a year ago you put that to
Graphites fear thunderstorm, you see again there cured,
take it and insert it in your additions.
In this case if you have a symptom and it is cured and it went away,
that means something was there, the feeling was there and now it's not...
Even that you don't get it strongly and that the symptom went away.
Never mind how it was not intense the fear, the fear was there and now it is not.
So you really have a symptom.
You can use that work for adding symptoms, you can use it.
-Provided...
-It might be that the person has given it on a low key when it was perhaps stronger.
But now it knows the difference. What else is there?
-Desire for soft boiled eggs.
-What else did we say she has? There is a desire for soft boiled eggs.
What else Calcarea has concerning eggs?
-Aversion.
-When we spoke about Calcarea, if you remember it feels better eating eggs.
If you remember, we have spoken about Calcarea better eating eggs.
That means you may find a case of cholecystitis or cholelithiasis from the gallbladder
and being better by eating eggs and that's very peculiar because in the pathology
that can be a Calcarea carbonica case. Better by eating eggs.
But worse eating eggs is not a symptom of Calcarea.
You have to differentiate the information.
The Nat Carbo would be much more closed person, a more sensitive person.
She is outgoing quite a lot, when she is bored out, I don't want to see anybody.
That is another type of that type we have described in Natrum Carbonicum but
they are concerned about others, they have certain aversion to certain people.
That is the attitude of Natrum Carbonicum.
Here we don't see that sensitivity, it's an outgoing person. This is a real extrovert.
When she is out there, she is a real extrovert, she enjoys, she laughs.
That also makes the case with a good prognosis.
A person who tells everything, it doesn't keep to himself.
It's bound to have more diseases than the one who is an extrovert, the one who interacts.
A person who is impulsive is bound to have much less to suffer
than a person who is an introvert. What happens in the two cases?
They are destructing forces.
There are destructing forces acting all the way.
The extrovert lets these forces to interact with others outside of him.
The introvert allows these forces to act within him, so he keeps them to himself.
So the extrovert destroys the others and the introvert destroys himself.
The extrovert is a person who will bring out anything, enjoys himself and he gets it out,
what happens to the other person, he doesn't care.
But the introvert allows these forces to interact inside and become destructive.
You saw that case how she allowed this argument to sink inside?
I could see how destructive could have been and it was, not to speak out at that moment to the other girl,
that she just let her and she didn't know what to do, she was humiliated.
And it went deep inside. She did not interact.
She did not do the right thing at the right moment.
And all the forces remained inside and destroyed her.
So what is the best?
-The "golden rule".
-The ancients used to say the "golden mean" is the best if you can strike a path
which is always walk on a tight rope.
Now there is an uprising trend in the consciousness of people.
When you up rise your consciousness for the first time, and you have seen how
all children started to be extrovert.
They, themselves is the most important in the world and everybody else at that age.
So they started extrovert, do that and do that. They started as extrovert.
We are children as far as spiritually also.
In a way we are concerned about ourselves quite a lot.
As humanity progresses towards a higher state of evolution,
people become aware more and more of the destruction they can have,
their saying, their words, their acts.
The force that this world can have upon others.
Suddenly they realize that and then they become introvert.
Now in this process of consciousness as they go from extrovert to introvert,
diseases are coming up.
You will see, most of you have been involved in spiritual things,
what you have found is that at a certain stage you become quite a fanatic
on what you believe to be the truth.
Now you are going to act on that and what you will do?
For 5 years in my life  I didn't eat meat, I will eat rice every day and vegetables.
The result was that I lost quite a lot of my energy because I was not paying attention to what I was eating.
In my effort to evolve myself, I destroyed quite a lot of myself but I did not only do that.
I did other things. Sex out. You know how you do these things.
For 10 years a young man who is quite normal decides no sex. Strange.
And I realized quickly enough that that might not be the right path to follow and I have to find a way to compromise.
All this resulted in all this preparation of mine from another point of view.
When I put my mind on something immediately I was there.
Smoking never. Drugs out of question really. Of course that gave me all the possibilities to be able
to concentrate and do what I had to do. To find out what was lacking in Homeopathy.
It allowed me to put quickly my mind and concentrate my mind immediately on the issue
but to the expense of my health.
And everybody who is doing some harm within himself...
because he does not allow forces to express.
So if we see a case like that, who is an extrovert
we may induce that she is not going to go and to (?)
To have hormonal disturbances at the moment.
And if we decide the right remedy and the right remedy should be quite easy to find
in such cases also.
These patients is easy to find, easy to see the remedy, the extrovert are easy to
find the remedy.
You saw the people that we saw in video, the introvert, difficult to decide.
In the next video you will see what I mean.
Ignatia can be an extrovert or Staphysagria or Nat Muriaticum can be an extrovert?
Can be an extrovert Nat Muriaticum?
In the way I'm speaking now, you may have an extrovert who doesn't show
the mental-emotional affected and you will see from a physical level the problem.
Whilst the Nat Muriaticum on a physical level has raised his consciousness,
then the disease started to come inside. The forces destroy his emotional side.
Then eventually he learns not to talk, he goes into a room and cries by him/herself.
Instead of talking and solving the situation on the spot.
That is going to bring problem in mental-emotional level.
A Nat Muriaticum can be an extrovert as long as it's not affected in mental-emotional.
So when they are affected (?) not expect that everyone who is Nat Mur will have it.
When you see a Nat Mur affected in his physical health,
you will see mostly keynote symptoms.
You will see the desire for salt. Salt, I like it.
Sun no, I don't want it.
What time? 10 o'clock.
How can I give him Nat Mur? Of course you can give Nat Mur, you have everything there.
The mental-emotional is quite in order because he is a successful manager,
he is a successful  businessman.
He doesn't care what it's going to happen, if he makes a bad deal with you,
He does not care, he is a businessman.
When the disease is coming upwards, then he starts thinking about others.
There are two different things which are happening.
In order to remain healthy, you have to  be nasty with the society and do whatever you like.
But from another point of view if you have the totality and the real thing,
then you say no.
You know the American millionaire who destroyed his mind?
And they will do anything to get (?) their responses, they are having a severe condition.
If she came in contact with a spiritual guru, how she could see differently the world,
he was very vital, going with all women. That woman and that woman.
You see vital force very strong, very high (?) are there.
You see everything showing that he has a good vitality.
But from a spiritual point of view, that's not a healthy thing.
Destroying the whole society because of his personal winning.
So I came down with the wisdom that the happy man was the one that he could strike a path
that whatever you were doing it was good for himself, for his own interest, his own evolution
but his action will have an equal good effect in the society in general.
So I'm healthy if what I do has a good effect on you and on me.
If it has only on me, I'm unhealthy. If it has only on you, I'm unhealthy.
Do you understand that? It goes to other things.
That's an unhealthy state. You look after yourself also.
That's the golden mean.
-You are saying that is in spiritual world, one goes to certain exercises or changes
and that there are therefore diseases which come along with spiritual growth?
-I won't say it that way. I would say that there are possibilities of disturbances that
they may arise as you go on.
On mental-emotional.
Usually when you have a person going from the outside world to the inside world,
he was an extrovert and now introvert, from acting in the world, acting within himself
what you observe usually is that...I have colitis, I have this, that...
Unless this is happening really under homeopathic treatment,
which I understand it can happen that, most probably this is the arising of the concentration
on the level of the disease, diffusion of the disease on a different level.
-So you are saying that disease is the process of dispersion?
-Diseases are outward manifestation of whatever negative forces are working within us
in all levels.
The expression of this negativity is within us.
Life tends to repair and to bring life in.
Disease tends to destroy and to bring death.
The Natrum Carbonicum is not this type we discussed here and we analyzed
this mental-emotional situation that this person is in.
Therefore that is the obesity, the whole (?) of that girl, how she is vital
and that should give as an essence the patient of the Graphites, than anything else.
Also Calcarea Carbonica...
Because of the better heat, Calcarea Carbonica is so much better by warm water,
by warm application.
So Calcarea Carbonica or Calcarea Phosphorica, the element of Phosphorus which is there,
it gives much more burning in the body.
They don't reach to such huge proportions.
That is the context between Graphites and Calcarea Carbonica
and you don't really know which one of the two.
-(?)
-It doesn't tell. With the Graphites and the Calcarea Carbonica yes.
You see if you have Graphites symptoms or Calcarea Carbonica symptoms.
You don't have (?) either Calcarea or Graphites.
Then you can go on to Capsicum or can go on to Ferrum or to Kali Bichromicum,
Natrum Carbonicum, Opium.
Opium is because of the thyroid dysfunction, it becomes quite huge.
-(?)
-I don't know that. That's a new symptom and we have to find out to which
remedy it belongs.
It is a symptom of our modern society, it did not exist by the time.
This is a syndrome which has developed in our contemporary society.
And it is a symptom which comes along with particular psychological make up
and we have eventually to find out.
We don't have so many cases in Greece of that type. Here you have a lot but in Greece we don't have
so I was not able to establish what are the remedies that are connected with that syndrome?
I don't know. When I look at a case, I may have an idea.
I have seen that case quite a lot because I like observing and I see quite a lot.
Yesterday I was taking a case of bronchitis.
A woman was sitting on the other side (?)
nobody was there but one woman who had a book and she was reading,
she must have been staying there from the time...
It was one hour and still she was sitting...
That's what I felt. Now that is a syndrome, introvert completely.
Everything in her world was that book. I was observing her from time to time
to see if she was sensitive enough to look. That syndrome.
-It was a romantic novel from the library?
-I don't know that. What I know is she enjoyed it.
Over eating also comes from the lack of affection.
Usually these people are not steady enough with the emotions
and they are replacing with something that brings pleasure and this is eating.
So usually it is lack of affection, not appreciated.
How do we go with over eating? I'm not sure yet.
Bring back the balance.
-Maybe we should do a study.
-We have some cases and they are some successes.
-What are you eating? That's a coarse thing to do. Are you hungry all the time?
You get the information from the figure I saw in the waiting room, the secretary.
How joyful she was there. She was so joyful that the second time she came,
my wife...She spoke with much love, with affection, strong emotions.
That is what I mean coarse.
Because after all she likes music, she is a singer, she has a job which she makes quite a lot of.
It's interesting from here that she is so much better in colitis by green vegetables.
That's the first time I met that syndrome. I just make a note if I meet it again
that's very important to see that.
Colitis usually is aggravated by that in 99% of the cases. It's a rare exception.
We have to take into consideration that.
She is aggravated by fat. Graphites has that?
Graphites is not written.
Here we have it strongly and with everything fat.
You make a note. You don't have to add everything.
So we have the disturbances with menses, we have all kind of arthritic rheumatic condition,
which is ameliorated by warm, the person who is aggravated by cold rather than by heat,
the person who has aversion to salt and aversion to sweet,
who is so fat and eats and yet does not like sweets and that's has to become
a symptom for healthy, aversion to sweet.
We have to take that into consideration.
And say what is there?
Desires company is not in the book. You have it in mind, you put it in.
There is a lot of things which are not put in the Repertory.
-I was saying yesterday I never thought I shall be teaching, I never thought to systematise that.
-She is young, she is 28 and she is not stressed psychologically so much.
To suspect that the blood pressure is high, I have to have the inter-stress that is always there.
With her it's easy going.
She misses to fall in love...
She does not have a partner and always it's going to be some trouble.
The second time she came, she said I'm happy.
The last 5-6 days, she had some kind of nausea in the morning.
She said continuously I was in a happy mood.
That started after the third dose.
On the last day of the treatment, she had some menses that were very short.
Last menses was in November and we see her in January.
In spite of the fact she had a stressful situation with her mother she said,
I did not feel the stress this time.
She said in another situation if I was not feeling so well,
I would feel rotten if I had that conflict.
The pain on the back continued, the pain on the cervical is gone.
-George, is there any suffering from lumbar pains...
-Not myself and I don't think in the Repertory.
-There is a rubric which says it is secondary...
-I would rather tend to think that the over weight is really pressing somewhere between the vertebrae.
That's why actually she said that this pain has gone, this pain has remained.
The greasiness on the head is much less.
You go to the Repertory, hair greasy and you see there Bryonia, Phosphoric Acid
and Thuja perhaps and Natrum Muriaticum.
You see here how strong is that symptom in Graphites?
Graphites has that kind of reaction on the skin.
So we can comfortably insert Graphites in greasy.
That is a rubric which has very little. Sulphur also should be there with the greasy hair.
She says that there were days that she did not need to eat.
She said that she had that on the 1st of April and the interview is on 14th of January.
She said that she had regular menses for 5 days, lost a few kilos.
She took up another job.
And of course she gets tired because she doesn't sleep enough.
About the psychological state, she says that I have ups and down and changes in mood.
She had some hoarseness in voice, she thinks that she gets quite tired with this second job,
going the whole night until 2-3 o'clock, then she has to get up at 7 o'clock to go to the other work
and she got quite tired from that.
During the last 15 days, she got an influenza for which she took antibiotics.
The doctors saw her and they said take that. For 4 days she took antibiotics.
What are we going to do?
-Wait.
-She took antibiotics, (?) and we try to evaluate what is happening with the body.
You have to wait and see what happens, the body goes up and down and then it goes up.
She was able to throw out the effect of the antibiotics and go up again and that is what has happened.
She needs somebody to talk and tell the story because from now on we just
give placebo to the case.
I just want to show you an aspect of Graphites together with new symptomatology
which may arise and how we may evaluate and use it.
-How much weight she is losing?
-It doesn't seem that the doctors had asked her.
She hadn't lose too many, otherwise I would have seen it.
She lost some from the third visit and lost during the menses two kilos.
Eventually she said the whole story to the doctor, how the father used to hit her mother
and used to hit her and how she had lack of affection.
-Did it seem at the time of her parents separation...?
-No, the parents had been separated quite early, at the age of 3.
It was quite a stress for her to see them, the father was a drunkard.
He hit the mother and he hit the child. She gave the whole story later.
She became intimate with the doctor and gave that information of what happened
in her previous years.
It's a matter of information.
-George I'm just wondering in your experience...
-I have not seen dramatic changes taking place in these obese children.
Sometimes you will see quite a good response but not dramatic.
What I have seen now that within a limit of time in 3-4 years,
they are able to do a diet and stick with a diet and eventually lose weight.
But I have not seen that dramatic change happening with the remedy.
-You mean you don't see it immediately but you see it in a long run?
-You see it in a long run, they have to go with a kind of fast, of diet to lose it
and then they lose it more easily.
Sometimes they will say I used to do this diet and not lose anything and now I lose.
-How about the attitude that somebody is having a  treatment and they are doing very well
and then they develop a weight problem? That's very common in my practice.
That means they had a weight problem in the past. Do you find that in your experience?
-That seems that there are several categories.
The ones who had weight problem always. Calcarea carbonica.
Then secondly it's when they come with a lot of stress and excitement
and there is a situation that makes the person burning a lot.
And you bring it back to the normal and he is calm, he copes better with a situation.
Now that is the time where he has to be aware.
The amount of food that he has learned that he can eat without any effect,
it has to be lessened now.
-The Calcarea would you say that (?)
-It can do that. Usually what happens is that within 2 months, they may put on weight.
What I feel is that our society is structured in such a way, as to push food in us.
I'm used to that.
It's another situation that you give in.
It's not the remedy or the treatment. It's the situation which we call ourselves.
When there is advertisement for food on a bucket, you don't have to do anything.
Cooked already, ready for the oven, just put it there and eat it with saucages inside and green things.
That's why we develop more and more food diseases.
Stop. This has to be understood.
Diseases now they come from over eating.