You remember? Sulphur, possibility of Medorrhinum, then Lycopodium.
Because of different reasons until he said that he is much worse in the cold, wet weather.
And if it is cold, wet weather, forget about Sulphur.
-I like to exercise and sweat.
-You feel better then?
-I used to, not any longer. Running or walking.
-Now you cannot do it?
-Now I feel the heartbeat, this feeling of my heart in the body.
Now I feel depressed and I cry very often. I can't control it.
I feel that that medicine that they had given me, I can't take it because then I feel my heart
and my body were stronger.
-The crying comes because of suffering, of pain or it comes for different reasons?
-I believe it's a mix because sometimes I feel sorry for myself and I feel sorry for my son.
-And some other times you can be crying because you see a film in the TV?
-Yes, all my life has been like that.
But that's very controlled, at home I know I can do it but never officially, never outside.
Sometimes in movies I may have difficulties but then I think of something else.
I felt it was that. Today I can talk about that, even to my students.
I don't try to stop myself when I'm crying because I feel it's safe.
-You really feel better after the crying?
-Yes.
What symptom we are looking in the Repertory now?
Here we have a good symptom of a man who cries and feels better after crying.
So this how you find it? Weeping ameliorates. Which remedies are?
Page 93. Anacardium, Colchicum, Cyclamen, Graphites, Phosphorus...
-That has changed. Normally I've been drinking a lot.
Now when I was sweating that has changed. Now I drink mostly in the evening,
1 1/2 lit in the evening.
-Just water?
-Yes.
Thirsty in the evening. Look.
Cyclamen is a remedy that looks like Pulsatilla.
Can this person be Pulsatilla?
Because of the crying could he be Pulsatilla?
-He is so cold.
-Yes, he is very cold to be Pulsatilla and we don't have any other symptom to support
Pulsatilla description, apart from crying. So because somebody is crying is not Pulsatilla.
-(?) Mixed with water.
-Have you been feeling good inside the sea and sea baths?.
Have you noticed some amelioration of your condition if you are in the sea?
-No.
-Do you like to bath here?
-No, it's too cold.
-Even in Mediterranean?
-Yes it's too cold but in the Indian Ocean, in Kenya it was OK but even there it wasn't warm enough.
You see how cold he is? He cannot be Pulsatilla.
Pulsatilla would say I enjoy going into cold sea. It is exactly the opposite.
Why did I ask again whether there is amelioration in the sea?
Because I saw Medorrhinum has amelioration from weeping. And Lycopodium also.
-Are you a restless person or you can sit for some time in a chair?
-I used to be restless but now I can sit and be.
I asked this question thinking of Rhus tox, maybe this is a Rhus tox case
or an Arsenicum case with so much coldness.
But he is not a restless person, he is sitting there quite quietly but I put this question in
case he tries to hold himself back and say I'm very restless but I now I try to sit quietly.
-I don't like to go out, I like to be at home.
-Do you like to eat something? There is a special desire?
-It used to be (?) or meat but now I've started to eat fruits. It has changed.
Not very much.
-Would you like some meat with some fat?
-Yes I love that.
Now I reduce that because of the diet but I love it.
Yes, my wife too but she loves fat as well.
-What about eggs? You like eggs?
-Not very much, scrambled eggs I think I can bear because I don't like eggs.
I think I don't like them because my wife used to make them every morning.
-Salt do you like?
-Yes, I used to take a lot of salt but I've learned that it doesn't help,
so I don't use very much now.
-When you wake up in the morning are you refreshed from sleep or unrefreshed?
-I'm tired, always I shoul like to sleep two hours more.
-When you wake up you are in a position to have conversation or you like to have
half an hour, one hour before you feel in condition to talk?
-I don't think so. I'm not very... When my son is getting up at the same time,
it's nice to talk to him but I'm not very deep talker in the morning I can say.
Can he be Magnesia muriatica?
-No.
-The more you put a question, then it comes the answer.
Can he be Lycopodium?
-Yes.
-He can be Lycopodium because he said I want another two hours to keep on sleeping.
So he can be Lycopodium.
-I hate to wake in a different house with other people. I prefer to take a taxi home.
What he said is very important because now you understand what he is in the morning.
When he says if I'm a guest in a house and I wake up in the morning and I have to talk
with other people... but he said in the beginning (?)
When he wakes up in the morning, he can talk with his son but nobody else.
He said I would prefer to take a taxi and go back to my house.
Then I take a taxi from the house where I woke up and go in my house.
Why did I ask this question?
Why I asked for Silica? What I have seen before? He is very cold and what else?
I don't ask him for Silica, I ask him for another remedy.
-Not at all.
-Do your feet perspire enough?
-Yes and my feet are cold.
-Is it offensive perspiration? Do you have to wash your feet?
-No. Now I go from six this morning and they don't smell very much. Do they?
But I like leather shoes, all my shoes are leather shoes.
-Otherwise the perspiration is more?
-I don't know. When I walk I feel...
-When you wake up in the morning do you have to drink a glass of water?
-No.
But I'm not hungry either. I don't feel hungry.
-What is the best time for you?
-In the evening and at 8 o'clock I like to have dinner.
-Just once, you have breakfast and then dinner?
-When I'm back at home from school at 2.30.
And during the night, sometimes I have to eat three times during the night.
-You wake up and eat?
-Yes, that I have done as long as I can remember.
-You wake up and you go to eat?
-Yes.
The symptom that he describes is characteristic of Sulphur, Psorinum, China and
Lycopodium. Sometimes Phosphorus, as well.
Can anybody tell me what is the remedy I have been thinking?
-Nitric acid?
-Nitric acid yes, very good. I have been thinking of Nitric acid because of the coldness,
the worse wet, because of the great anxiety that seems to prevail all his life,
great anxiety about his health and mostly because of the desire of fat which is very strong.
Desire for fat is characteristic of Nitric acid and Nitric acid also does not like eggs,
as we said before.
He wakes up in the morning and he does not want to talk to others, as we said also.
Nitric acid is a remedy that has primarily anxiety about health.
But is it Nitric acid?
He gives now another symptom how during night he wakes up with hunger.
This indicates the possibility of Lycopodium, it has the right from left, it has difficulty to wake up in the morning,
it has anxiety about health, sleeps on the right side as he used to sleep
but there is one point that we don't like and this is?
-Desire for fat and salt.
-Desire for fat and salt. Salt is strong for him, desire for sweets is strong for Lycopodium.
If he would say that he wants fat but he cannot ignore fat, the combination of fat and salt
and aversion to eggs, where Lycopodium would have desire for sweets and very little
about salt or fat.
I'm trying to confirm now Nitric acid.
Actually the Nitric acid idea came when he said he likes eating fat.
Immediately by that time eating fat with the anxiety about health,
the main remedy that I think is Nitric acid now.
-I'm very heavy smoker. Normally I get two cups of coffee and two cigarettes and then it goes like an explosion.
-But only once, explosive.
-What time in the day?
-In the morning, at 7.30 or 8 o'clock.
-That's the time you wake up?
-I wake up at 7 or I get up at 7.
-And then after an hour?
-Yes.
-But now that I stopped smoking...it is regularly.
-Is it still explosive?
-Yes.
-You have a lot of gas?
-And eructations?
-No.
-The gas is very offensive?
-Now it is different.
Why did I ask about eructations? There is a differential diagnosis between
Lycopodium and Nitric acid.
He said that he has some flatus but not eructation.
Lycopodium would have been quite a lot of gas, which comes up all the time.
And it's ameliorated by bringing up air.
-Would you say that you have a kind of anxiety about your health?
-Yes I have and I believe I've been hypochondriac.
-So you feel hypochondriac, you cannot find anything wrong and then you still feel bad
and you wonder what is going on?
-Yes.
-Do you suspect that you have cancer or something serious?
-Sometimes I'm thinking of this.
-What it can be? Mostly cancer or heart?
-Not heart.
-The idea of cancer comes mostly?
-Yes. I've always believed that it was the rheumatism but sometimes when it's aching,
then I think it must be something serious.
-Then you are thinking of cancer?
-Yes.
You see when he says that the pains are arthritic pains or rheumatic pains, he feels it is too much,
it must be cancer.
That is a case of either Nitric acid or Agaricus or sometimes Arsenicum or Phosphorus.
-Do you have any skin eruption?
-No.
-Any warts?
-I used to have one here.
Nitric acid has warts. What kind of warts? What is the peculiarity?
-They are bleeding?
-Yes, they are big and bleeding.
Look Nitric acid, Causticum and Thuja for bleeding warts.
You are looking skin warts bleeding, page 13-39. But warts of Nitric acid are bleeding.
So if I'm thinking of Nitric acid, I would like to see if he has warts that are bleeding.
Of course he says he does not have warts now, he used to have.
-I used to have one here and I took it away. Now it has started something here.
I had that one for a couple of years.
-This wart here was big?
-Yes.
-You went yourself to the doctor and say what is this and he takes it out?
-Every time it was bleeding this one?
-Yes.
He says if I touch it, it goes bleeding. This is characteristic of Nitric acid, warts , sometimes,
sometimes Thuja I have not seen so much but in Nitric acid it is characteristic.
-Are you especially fastidious? You want absolute order?
-Yes.
You see now in my mind Nitric acid is the indicated remedy and then again some Lycopodium.
Why did I put this question, fastidious?
You see the possibility of what remedy?
Of Arsenicum, because of the coldness and the desire for fat.
Restlessness is not there, I asked him before. Now I only want to confirm that this is not
an Arsenicum case, the fastidiousness is tremendous.
I will start rethinking the whole case.
-It changed.
-I think so, I'm not very clever myself.
-Is this Arsenicum?
-No.
-Is it something peculiar in your symptoms that you didn't tell me and you would like to add?
-No. You asked me if I have an argument if I take things(?) but it's a statement,
I truly think I can even take a plate but I never touch any, I can't control it.
That's when I don't get through verbally,
when I'm not able to explain verbally, then I take a plate.
-You desire but you never took it.
-Well I do take a plate.
-Was any tuberculosis in the family?
-No. It must be 10 years ago, then I got prostate.
Why did I ask that?
-Because Tuberculinum wants (?)
-And desire for fat is there always with Tuberculinum and desire for what kind of meat?
Smoked meat but mostly pork.
-Which kind of meat you say you would like mostly?
You see immediately I examine that possibility, is there a strong desire for meat
and I would like to know is it pork?
-I believe that lamb meat as well.
Tuberculinum would say certainly pork
but Tuberculinum does not have great anxiety about health.
You see the problem now? I will explain to you later.
-I do like fish, if I had to say 7 days fish or 7 days meat, I would say fish.
There is a problem here.
Why there is a problem? Because mostly Phosphorus likes very much the fish and
Phosphorus sleeps on the right side, Phosphorus has desire for fat and anxiety...
-What about sausages and fish, what you would prefer?
-I would prefer fish. I don't like sausages.
-Now you don't like but you used to?
-I like meat but not sausages, it's mixed. I don't like it when it's mixed.
I would like pure meat.
-I thought you said you like sausages?
-Yes but dry sausage meat.
-Between dry sausage meat and fish?
-I prefer dry sausage meat.
You see the Nitric acid likes salt and meat with fat and likes dry sausage meat.
It is in favor of Nitric acid and not of Phosphorus.
-When you say you are thirsty in the evening, what hours do you mean?
-8 o'clock, 7,30.
-Onwards?
-Yes.
-So it is towards the night, 8 onwards, it's not the evening.
-Do you think there is any cure? Especially for the sleep?
I feel that if I was able to sleep during the night, life would be much better.
Because I'm aching and I'm quite emotional when I'm tired.
-I believe that (?)
(?)
-I'm using that now. Do you think it's wrong to use or can I continue?
-When we start this treatment I would like you to discontinue that because then we will know how to proceed.
Otherwise we do not know what changes have come because of this or that therapy.
For that reason I would like you to discontinue.
-Thank you very much. I'm glad I was able to come here, it's a long journey.
Thank you very much.
One journey between different remedies and how you really go and finally conclude about
one remedy or another.
You see now why Nitric acid? It has most points from any other remedy.
Phosphorus I almost excluded from the beginning, why?
Because usually Phosphorus sleeps well.
Phosphorus is very seldom when you see, as the main problem, sleeplessness.
Phosphorus not only sleeps easily but they sleep well and they are very much refreshed
from good sleep.
I sleep well and I'm very much refreshed and sleep is my medicine.
Here this is not the case, it is exactly the opposite.
That's why the Phosphorus possibility is very minute but I examine in the end what he says...
What information he gave that it was Phosphorus?
The desire for fish. Desire for fish is a characteristic of Phosphorus element
because fish contains a lot of Phosphorus most probably.
Phosphorus cases or Natrum Phosphoricum cases and perhaps Calcarea Phosphorica cases
and Natrum Muriaticum also desire fish quite a lot.
But not Nitric Acid, it's not interested.
In this case we went through Sulphur, possibility of Medorrhinum, then Lycopodium,
back to Sulphur, back to Lycopodium, Nitric acid, Tuberculinum,
Arsenicum and Phosphorus very remote.
Therefore I feel some of you are looking at me as if I'm from another planet. That's OK.
It's not easy always. Some others I can see they understand the process much more.
In this case, after we studied the case, is that first remedy we give is Nitric acid 1M.
Then we have the possibility of Lycopodium. There is a strong argument for Lycopodium
but not entirely confirmed.
Nitric acid is much more confirmed and what is strange in this case is that Norwegian kind of character,
where I had to underline the anxiety about health.
If we start from the beginning he tells about anxiety, when I'm asking about anxiety,
he says yes, yes, yes I have anxiety.
This is a yes of a person who knows what he is talking about, he is quite sincere.
I believe that he talks the truth and he did not try to hide any information
but in another person the anxiety would have come out much more intense than what it appeared with him.
He said how hypochondriac person... That means for me he has gone and complained and
he was not understood and then he thought most probably that the doctors don't understand.
I know that  I am seriously sick and they go to see.
He said that when I had the pains, I felt that this was too much, going too far
and most probably this is cancer, pains in the joints.
But mostly if I would base my prescription on anxiety because I asked him
and he said yes, that is wrong.
The anxiety for me is mostly because of other things he said and the way he said.
The way he looked, he wanted to give all information that was possible.
He did not try to withhold information.
He gave all the information, even that information which was not very nice for his ego.
He gave information because he wanted to be seen, to appear that something wrong really is with him.
That is a Nitric acid case.
-I also saw a possibility for Mercury because he said he has salivation during sleep for a long time
and he told me this summer when he went to Spain, he was very tired.
He didn't like hot weather so much.
-No, he didn't say he didn't like hot weather. He said in hot weather this time
I was not better in my pain. That's another thing.
-Mercury no.
-I believe that the diagnosis maybe right but still we have multiple sclerosis in the beginning,
in spite of the fact that he had 10 years ago the first symptoms.
The intensity of the disease is quite low, it's not high intensity.
And therefore I consider it to be in the beginning.
So I don't care if this is a multiple sclerosis or it is something else neuromuscular.
Still I believe this case can be helped with Homeopathy because it is the beginning.
If if the remedy is not right it is not right, that's another story.
Worse from cold, worse from heat also. It is like Magnesia Muriatica.
They feel the cold but also they like to go out and have fresh air.
For Lycopodium is strong, they say I don't want to get up from bed. This is strong for
Lycopodium.
For Lycopodium is strong the fact that he mentioned always from right to left.
This is strong for Lycopodium.
Lycopodium is also when he used to sleep in previous years on the right side.
This is strong for Lycopodium. In Lycopodium is also strong the anxiety about health.
It is as strong as almost in Nitric acid. Nitric acid is much stronger and Nitric acid
makes less noise concerning his anxiety. He tells you the symptoms, he tries to evaluate and
then he goes away without telling much about his anxiety but goes to another doctor and
tries to confirm what one doctor said against the other.
So Nitric acid will not tell you straight forward about their anxieties because they believe
that what they know it is better than you.
You don't understand, I have cancer. This is the idea behind Nitric Acid.
Always the idea of cancer.
With Phosphorus we have symptoms that are against and symptoms that are in favor.
The fact that he likes wine, he used to drink wine because he gave that information...
What he said? I used to drink wine because of the  moment. Everybody was drinking and I was drinking.
But when I came here, I stopped. Now he has stopped drinking or he drinks very little.
He has stopped smoking. That again is an anxiety element which is towards Nitric acid.
Phosphorus will not do it. He has anxiety about his health but he likes his smoking,
his drinking, he is excited. He will not give it up so easily.
It has to be a person who is concerned about his health. To give up smoking, to give up salt.
He is concerned about his health. Phosphorus will not do very much.
Phosphorus likes to go to the doctor and say I have my heart or I have cancer and the
doctor tells him that he has not and he is happy, he goes away for certain period of time
enjoying his cigarettes until next time. It's another personality all together.
This personality mostly is the Nitric Acid personality,
though he did not come fully as Nitric Acid anxiety. It can be much stronger in Nitric Acid the anxiety.
The fact that he is not better in the sea, he does not want to go to the sea at all...
This kind of anxiety you will not see it very much in Medorrhinum.
The sleeplessness and the time of aggravation is not Medorrhinum.
Medorrhinum usually suffers during sleep, he suffers during the night.
He has said I feel better in the evening when he goes home and he has a glass of beer
or a glass of wine and is at home and he likes home.
This is the idea why he says better in the evening.
Better in the evening here is not a start symptom that he gave.
If it was for Lycopodium, then you may say better in the evening.
But it's not a strong symptom that you take it.
He is not a high liver. What we see here is an anxiety about health,
it is disturbance in the nervous system, the sleep is disturbed
and a person who likes to be at home, he likes to be with his family, not very much an extrovert.
He will not go out with friends and other women etc.
He does not have points for Medorrhinum, where the Nitric Acid is so strong.
You cannot ignore a strong remedy and go to another. It can be anything.
Because he has numbness in his gums, it can be Aconitum.
But the remedy that you have to give, the remedy that is covering the case, is Nitric Acid.
Why not Sulphur or Causticum because anxiety, fat etc.?
When you try to find the remedy, you try to find what really covers mostly the case.
This is strong point for Lycopodium, the appetite in the night.
That's why I gave it as a second possibility.
First Nitric Acid, then in case it does nothing, Lycopodium as a second possibility.
Then we may be going to Tuberculinum, Medorrhinum, Phosphorus, Mercury...
All these are possibilities but they are weak possibilities. The strongest is Nitric acid.