I want to present to you now another case of our contemporary disease...
-AIDS
-What else? A case of AIDS.
-In February 1951, the consultation was on 24th of March 1987,
he is diagnosed as having HIV and was infected three years ago;
he had only known it for three months when he came for the first consultation.
She noticed that the eyes were very red, his face was very pale.
He had never had any venereal disease but possible he had hepatitis B
about two years beforehand, without any symptoms.
He had the flu twice four years previously and he had taken penicillin.
He had swelling of the glands in the anus in which he was given antibiotics.
The reaction to the HIV diagnosis was over-activity; he felt very much in a hurry
and everything had to be done right now.
-When this happened?
-The diagnosis was three months before March this year and when he got the diagnosis
he felt he had to do everything now, he has to see all his friends, he has to rush
and do things. He says he feels very restraint because of the diagnosis.
He has never had any high ambitions, he said he is an messy type.
-He feels he is restraint because they have told him he has AIDS and he cannot...
-I'm not sure what that means.
I have to explain to you this practitioner is reading the report of the doctor
from another country, this is in London because the doctor has not come
and reads the report of the doctor who attended the case first, in another country.
So she is not the direct practitioner.
-He has irregularly eating and living habits and lives a very hectic life style.
Desires salt one underline, alcohol one underline, oranges two underlines and dry food,
thirst one underline he has a glass of water on his bedroom table.
People see him as being gross and uncompromising one underline, egotistic.
He gets very angry when he hears about unfairness, he calls himself a moralist
which means he is against conservatism and conventional morals,
he is not fastidious, he is rather untidy, he is very seldom cold
but lately his feet have  been cold, he always had to sleep in a cold room before
but recently he is been leaving a heater at night and he put the cover around himself.
He works in a restaurant and in a local radio station at night,
he likes to see the things been done, he is very good at his work,
fear of water two underlines, he learned to swim two years ago but he had to force himself
to overcome that fear,
he can have some sticking stomach pain and sticking pain from the back,
he had swelling of the glands under both ears and in the back of the neck when he went in March
and he had some flashes of heat during the night before he had the diagnosis.
He was given Nux vomica 200 and 1M.
He telephoned on the 4th of April about a week later and said that after the Nux vomica
he slept for 10 hours, then he was up for 5 hours and then he slept for another 10 hours
and he felt more calm and that the pain in his shoulder and neck had gone.
After the Nux vomica he developed pain in the tendons of the right heel,
which he feels when standing on the foot and he felt an increased desire for fresh air.
He came again a month after the Nux vomica and she reported that he looked much better
and the redness had gone from around the eyes and the swelling under the ears
had also cleared up but he was getting more pains in the glands of the neck
and a new symptom that he developed was headache in the occiput, coming and going.
He reported that he had two warts on the right first finger which he hadn't notice before,
I don't know if they are knew and also some spots on the finger nails.
He hates to get up in the morning and the pain which came after Nux vomica remains.
That's the case.
-Did he have examinations from the hospital?
-He didn't send them.
This case is under the supervision of the hospital of the country, which is dealing with AIDS cases.
-Who diagnosed it?
-This is the Health Authorities of Oslo.
-Do you know what kind of examinations they did?
-Blood tests and they found antibodies.
They haven't found the virus but they found the antibodies.
-What about the lymphocytes?
-Yes that was on the examination, they found some irregularities.
They found some nodes here and I had read, I was very concerned about this disease
and I thought that maybe this is the HIV virus, so I went to the examination and it was.
But that was the only symptoms.
-In the blood test they examined the T-lymphocytes, have they given you any information
of how they are?
-The only thing I know is that they found the antibodies, that they cannot find
any irregularities in my blood, that's all I know. But I have the papers from the laboratories.
What does he think?
His look what it tells you?
His look in the eyes?
-Doubting.
-Critical and challenging.
-Fear.
-The most is fear.
Fear about the disease, it's natural you will say but it is depicted in his face the fear.
There is an intensity, a fear and an intensity what is going to happen and on a second level
there is doubt, suspicion, what you said is correct but the first is fear.
What we call severe anxiety about health, it's natural.
It doesn't matter whether it's natural or not, we see it.
Because he has AIDS it means that naturally he will have anxiety about health?
Do you think that someone because he has AIDS automatically he has anxiety about health?
-No.
-No. You can see AIDS people where they don't care.
He is a homosexual, as you understood. Who understood he is a homosexual?
All the women. He has no signs.
-These are not good photocopies. They are not good.
You don't have good photocopy machine in Norway?
-They don't have much money because of political situations.
Do you hear that? I said they are not good copies, I could hardly read them,
I could not understand and what is his comment?
They don't have enough money, this country does not have enough money.
It is one of the richest countries but what he says is because of political reasons...
That means they don't want to spend money on people.
You get the impression? You see his attitude?
This bloody government does not want to spend money on people.
People are dying, they are very sick and still they are afraid to spend a little money
on photocopies. You got it? He had to say that. He has to make a comment.
It is not accidental that he makes a comment. It is the type.
Lachesis would respond in that way, Stramonium in another way, Belladonna in another way.
He has to make a comment.
Do you think that this is a Nat mur case?
-No.
-Why not? He looks like Nat mur, he is very sensitive, why not?
-He makes that comment.
-Because he makes this comment, a Nat mur will be very difficult to make that comment
and to make these grimaces in front. He has to be somebody who is rather open and communicative.
Nat mur, Ignatia, Staphysagria they will not. Phosphoric acid is too tired to talk, Stannum also.
Do you see the differential diagnosis?
-I'm here because I've been given money to have this trip covered but I have to make a report
of what is going on here. So since they are so many microphones, may I put on my microphone
for this conversation is also taped? I don't have to take notes?
-Usually we don't allow this but you can do it.
Do you see? Did you understand?
This is not to play game. It says either you cure me or I will report it to the government.
He has given money by the government to come to London and to be treated by me.
So what he says is you better be serious about it, I don't play around.
You got it? he says. It's a mild threat. I represent to him the conservatism.
I'm the authority to him, so he threatens but very mildly because he knows how much
he depends on me at the same time. I may show him the door out.
-You can do it.
-Thank you.
All this is very important for me. For you maybe it would just pass unnoticed but I perceive
everything. I see his anxiety, his fear, his intensity, the kind of comment he made.
What he says now, how he says it.
At a certain moment, as soon as he became aware of the camera, he was a little bit...
but then he came back, it doesn't matter, I'm in front of the camera but it doesn't matter.
All this it is registered because I'm aware, I have to find the remedy.
Unfortunately in Homeopathy don't expect that it's going to be a routine.
Routine you can forget. It is every day, every time a challenge.
What is now this case? What is the remedy? That is the fascination about Homeopathy.
It will never let you sleep peacefully. You always think what about that case?
Is it going to go well? And you always have some cases at stake.
-By whom you have been given the money?
-By a gay organization in Oslo, which has charity concert going on,
collecting money for the HIV positive and I've been given the trip to London from that fund.
-Can I keep this?
-Of course, it's for you.
-You said that the medical report is by Oslo health...
-It's the Community Health Department of Oslo.
-The official?
-Yes, it's not the country but the Oslo.
-The patient first consulted us on 04-1984 complaining for other discomfort
and pains like fatigue and fever.
Clinical findings; swollen lymph glands approximately one by 0,5 cm in the anus left side...
of minor glands in both armpits.
Colonoscopy showed injected mucus membranes with pus treated as gonorrhoic proctitis.
Antibodies positive on hepatitis B, negative on antigens, no history related to hepatitis,
no other serious illness. Back in January 87 for HIV antibody test have noticed
swollen lymph glands on the left side of neck and slight soreness of throat,
clinical findings pea-sized gland left side of neck below ear,
laboratory test showed HIV antibody test positive, on the second test at the 6th of February 87,
all other lab findings within normal ranges, retrospective testing of frozen plasma
from 1984 shows slight positive reaction of HIV antibodies.
He was probably infected before December 84. He is clinically in good health
and coping well with this situation.
You see because the report was coming to me it was written clinically he is doing well.
-What I would like you to tell me first is how many times you have been treated in your
life and for what?
-I've never been seriously ill. So it depends on what range...
-Here it writes that you have been treated for gonorrhoic proctitis.
-Oh yes this is the Journal from the Health Department of venereal diseases in Oslo.
-For how long you took antibiotics?
-Yes I have taken antibiotics for this in anus, whatever it was.
This is the first mentioned, so it is not in the Journal, this disappeared
after I used the antibiotic, which I don't remember the name of.
-How long you used the antibiotics?
-It was one. Tablets.
-For how many days?
-I don't remember, it was just given, I took it and then it disappeared.
-I don't remember, sorry.
-It was the first time that you took antibiotics?
-I have taken antibiotics before.
-For what reason?
-For swollen throat, living in Paris.
I took twice one winter and what happened in my childhood I'm not able to say
but I was often an ill child with often colds.
I remember one serious illness from my point of view was when I had a headache.
-Frontal sinusitis?
-Yes which I tried to cure with medicine, it didn't help and I went to homeopath at that time
and it didn't help either but it just disappeared.
So maybe it was the homeopathy, I know now.
-You are now 30?
-36.
-You are homosexual?
-Yes.
-At what age you became active?
-About the age of 22-23.
-You have been very active sexually?
-I don't know what you learned but compared to what they write about 10 the night,
not at all, definitely not very active.
-Did you have a lot of partners?
-No.
-How many?
-A year? Maybe between 5-10.
Different persons.
I'm not morally concerned about this. If I had thousands, I would say.
So that's no problem. But that was so strange because they say people are infected
by this virus by people who are over active and that's why there are so many in America.
-From your partners was anybody outside of Norway?
-Yes. I think a lot about work and my final answer now is that when I was in Paris
I had sex relationships with people I didn't know, in the same period in which
I was using the antibiotics for the throat.
-For how long you were using the antibiotics for the throat?
-It was twice the winter, so it was like I was buying tablets for...
-Almost constantly.
-Two weeks each, maybe.
-Did you feel that because you were taking antibiotics you were protected from infections?
-No, I didn't think that way.
-Just be honest. You didn't think now I'm taking the antibiotics,
therefore I do not have anything, it was not like that?
-No it's not like that. Now afterwards I've been thinking I might have been too weak
at that time because I was taking the antibiotics, after having read your book for instance.
Maybe I was in a weak situation that the virus would attack me.
Why I ask this question? What reason do I have to ask this question?
-To find out how long really he is taking the antibiotics trying to protect himself from the gonorrhoea.
-But what reason do I have to doubt what he is saying?
Isn't strange that he remembers that he was having sex in France five years ago
during the period he was taking the antibiotics? Isn't strange?
Usually you say antibiotics, when did I take it? I can't remember but now he remembers
that he took antibios during the period he was having sex in France.
What is the explanation? He gave a reason to himself to take antibiotics,
I have a sore throat, so he had a reason for taking antibios and at the same time
he thinks I better take antibiotics because I'm having some sex with people I don't know.
This is the real story behind, according to me.
Of course he denies it but the way he denies somewhere in his subconscious
there is the same story, I do not want to push him too much but we have to be like detectives
and use our logic mind.
I have asked thousands of people when did you take antibiotics?
Nobody ever told me the time. They say it was a year, what year, not the month.
Now he remembers he took it during that period.
How this has remained to his mind? Because he had connect it, that's all.
-He tries to find out.
-If he had not connected it in his mind, he would not remember it.
The fact that he remembers it, is the fact that gives me... and also his reaction,
he says no, no. First he says yes and then words say no. It's not important.
What is important is for you to observe and understand what I'm trying to say,
don't just let things go away like that and then you will know many things about the people.
You will know how they think, when they doubt, when they believe, when they are angry,
when they are going to sue you...
They are coming into the office and say here I am and you say oh my god,
he is going to sue me in America. You don't have it in Europe so much.
-Maybe I was in a weak situation that the virus would attack me easily,
that's what I'm thinking now.
-What year it was?
-This was three years ago.
-84? 83?
He doesn't even remember the year, you see? He does not remember the year
but he remembers that he was taking antibiotics during the time he was having sex.
It's the same story exactly.
-Why did you go to Paris?
-I'm in a trip.
-Somebody likes to sail, somebody motor bikes, somebody goes for adventures?
-These too of course are always part of the game but still I travel a lot
because I like other cultures. Paris is not another culture exactly but I had a friend there,
I wanted to learn French, I went to school to learn French.
-So you had a boyfriend in Norway or in France, he invited you to France?
-This is a long story. I had a friend in Paris, I had no boyfriend in Norway.
I went to Paris because I wanted to do something else. I didn't have a steady job,
so why not to go to Paris, I had money and of course I was sexually active too.
Going to Paris I had gone to many places with the friend in Paris, we went to Asia
because I met him there.
I'll ask you something else. I do not have a confirmation of what I'm asking you
on the video but just for the sake to see your observation.
What does he think about himself, about his appearance?
Can anybody tell me, is it obvious to you or you don't know?
-He likes himself.
-Haughty.
-Self-confident.
-Considerate.
-Women are very critical.
-He had done mistakes and he thinks about them now.
-I said how he thinks about his appearance?
-Content with himself.
-You see men are not responding. Women are responding but no one has told me
exactly how he feels.
-He is sexually attracted to you.
-To me? I never thought about it.
I never understand such implications, whether it's a woman or ...
It's a point which I would like to see if anybody can see.
If you were observant, you would have understood.
-Smiling like an actor.
-Yes, this remedy likes to act.
-Insecure.
-He wants to give a good picture of himself.
-What does he think about himself as an appearance?
-I think he is very good looking but he does not know whether he is good looking.
-I will give you now my observation.
This is a man who has a very good idea about his appearance.
He says I'm good looking except of one part. Which is that part?
Somebody says I'm good looking but I have a bad nose, I'm good looking
but I have bad eyebrows, I' m good looking but I would like to have a correction on that area.
Everyone has some idea, what is his problem?
-Mouth.
-The problem is his mouth.
He feels that he is good looking but his mouth is not good enough. Why?
Because you will see how many times he hides it.
If you have a part which you want to hide... if we put backwards the video,
I will show you how many times he bites his mouth and I don't remember if he will do it further.
Most probably he will do it because he is very conscious about his mouth.
Very conscious that his mouth is not perfect, everything else is perfect, he is content.
And further can you tell me what it says this kind of mouth?
Is it a strong mouth?
-No.
-Babyhood, immaturity. This is my observation.
I could not ask such questions but it would be interesting if you could take an intimate answer
from him to confirm these things.
I'm just telling these things to show you the sensitivity with which I'm observing.
I do not look at a picture, I look on a live thing and I understand different levels
which are existing.
A human being thinks that he is closed and nobody can understand anything and
somebody else comes and reads everything and says, I will tell you your life.
You have done this, this and that's your life more or less.
Everybody understands these.
The only thing is that we don't say, we don't say it to ourselves,
we don't say it to others but everybody...
If I really press you and say, look and tell me, look and tell me,
you tell me finally the whole story.
Don't project, don't put your mind into explaining anything,
just look and tell me and you will see everything without prejudice. Just look.