-He was in the hospital.
-Does he ask for water?
-No and he refuses it while I put a straw in his mouth.
-But he does not want to drink.
-Not really. Sometimes he is eager but very seldom.
-What changes have you observed in his character, in the way he contacts others?
He was a very lively child or he always was like that?
-It's a confusing question because he is not just one way all the time.
Sometimes he is very lively and very excited about everything and then other times
he is very mobby, when he is upset about something he doesn't want to talk about it
and goes away.
-He was always able to answer his own questions, which is unusual for a child.
Here I know the remedy. You will see the remedy later on.
What is my analysis now in this case? What do I observe?
I observe a child that is too serious for his age.
Either he is suffering too much, has some kind of pains that he has not.
He does not complain of pains but he is too serious, too sad, depressed
and the child for me, as I observe, he has a depression.
What I ask the mother is to see whether my observation tallies with her observation.
That's not the picture of a child, right?
So the mother gives me the answer. What did she say, do you remember?
The mother says this confuses me because sometimes the child is elated,
sometimes it is depressed.
-Is he afraid of anything?
-Yes.
-Very much?
-What is he afraid of?
-Maybe being by himself, being abandoned, being left alone.
-So he wants somebody next to him.
-Yes.
-All the time.
You see it is very misleading.
The mother says that the child is afraid. There is the hydration and there is fear,
the child can not stay alone. It wants the mother next to him.
What's the remedy?
Phosphorus.
-To hold his hand?
-No.
I'm moving around in the room and then I sit down and maybe I hold his hand and
massaging his body.
-And she likes that?
-Yes that seems to bringing him out.
Another symptom of Phosphorus, massaging his body. Phosphorus he likes it.
I'd like to see more the interpretation. How you can go one way or another
and how the differential diagnosis becomes unless you go to the heart of the matter.
What the mother said for my mind in order to differentiate...
She says something which is contrary to Phosphorus.
I said, does he want you to hold his hand?
She said, no actually I can be just around in the room and then eventually I can go and hold him.
That's not exactly typical of Phosphorus.
The Phosphorus would like the contact, would like the security of the mother all the time.
Phosphorus in such a state.
-He sits like that, he doesn't respond very much, he sits very quiet.
Is that usual?
-Yes.
-That's not his character, he didn't use to be so quiet like an angel.
Jacob, how old are you, do you know?
-Six and a half.
-Can you lift him up to see how he responds?
-I will lift you up. Maybe sit up. Can you help me?
Can you sit by yourself?
-Do you feel tired Jacob? Do you want to lie down?
Just put him around and let him sit or take him in your lap sitting.
Did you try to test his strength?
-Yes. Oh, he is strong.
-He is making jerking movements all over.
-Give me your hand, give me the other hand.
Was anything happening in your house that he might have been in grief?
You see what is the characteristic of this child in general? It is sorrow, it is sadness.
That becomes the main characteristic of the child. The sorrow of that child.
Can you see his face? This is the face of a child?
That's the face of somebody who is really suffering, he is in deep depression.
So when I see that I want to know why he is in that state.
Is that because of the disease? Is it characteristic of the disease to be on that state?
What has happened? I would like to know.
Why I would like to know about this particular aspect in this case?
Because I see it very prominent. The main characteristic of the child is grief, sadness.
Something must have happened?
What can happen in the life of a child of such age?
Do you have to be magician to find that?
-Parents.
-A conflict.
-The parents most probably are divorced. That is the first idea.
Things are going on in my mind, I start thinking. Is that a case of Phosphorus?
It doesn't look like because he is too depressed.
Then she is giving me symptoms of Phosphorus but the child is too depressed to be Phosphorus
What has happened?
This is the side effect of chicken pox? Is this mental state because of the chicken pox? No.
What has happened? Most probably the parents are separated and he is very sad
because of that fact.
The idea that comes to my mind is what is happening with the child is that the child
must have felt tremendously insecure by losing one of them and that has brought about
a tremendous grief of the child.
The grief must have brought a state in which the child got the epidemic, the chicken pox.
The chicken pox found an organism that was under grief, very low and progressed to
the cerebellum.
And then he goes to the hospital and they said it is an inflammation of the cerebellum
after chicken pox. What can you do? We can do nothing. Just take your child.
They just wanted to get rid of the child and said we don't know.
Maybe he will come back again, maybe he will stay for the rest of his life
in semi-paralytic state but most probably something will stay with him for life.
Listen the story, it is very interesting.
-Did he watch you or your husband fighting in front of him?
-I think there is lots of talk, that's what I'm sensing, that Jacob overhears this talk
between his father and the house I'm in and the people that are in the house
and the little girl that stays there. She is difficult to be with, so there is lots of talk.
-Do you want to lie down sweet heart?
-What do you feel Jacob?
As the mother talks, I observe the child. Have you observed?
Do you see as she talks about that subject, how the grief in the child becomes
deeper and deeper and deeper? And then she can't stand it anymore.
He will become aggressive. I want to see the reaction, so I don't allow him to lie down,
because he feels better lying down. I want to continue and to observe what is happening.
I want to find out, otherwise you can't help the child.
Causticum was given and Carbo Vegetabilis, the whole of Materia Medica can be given
without any effect. Do you think it has an effect? No.
It says I'm a little bit better, a little bit better, the child can go on for months
and for years a little bit better but still on a paralytic state.
What he says? Do you want to lie down?
-Yes.
-Why Jacob? What do you feel?
-I feel bad.
-What? You feel nausea? You want to vomit?
-No.
-Why you want to lie down?
-It feels good...
-If you lie down...
-Jacob were you upset about something?
You remember if you had something that made you upset last week?
-No.
-Are you telling the truth? Why don't you look at me?
-I don't want to.
-You don't want why? If you are saying the truth why you don't look at me?
-But why you are so sad? Something made you very sad.
Do you understand my question? What made you so sad?
-Nothing.
-I think to answer to your question his father and I aren't together as man and wife
and I sense that that has upset Jacob and I opened that up to his father
in the last couple of days because he has been so much in the space...
-You were very upset during that period, last month or two?
-Yes.
-Especially upset?
-Yes and when it declared, his father and I had ...
Why do I enquire about the last period of two months?
When he fell ill with the chicken pox...
The child seems to have a problem because the parents are in not good terms,
they don't stay together etc.
But what I feel is that two months ago, just before falling sick with the chicken pox,
the child must have had another shock to bring down his system.
This condition can not come just like that.
-His father and I had to define our relationship so that it would be clear for me
and then for Jacob so we can live our lives according to some truth,
rather than being fuzzy out of our lives and we function as a couple a lot of times
but there is so much unset between us that lives everything unresolved all the time.
And I'm aware that I want it resolved, I want it change and he doesn't like it. There it is.
-What you say is already a known thing for Jacob, he knows already?
-I think so, yes.
-And you are very connected? He is attached to you?
-Yes and he is very attached to his father. We are both very close to him, very special to him
and he to us and we are operating in terms of "we" except not all the time
and it is confusing to me.
-I see.
Was Jacob's mood before changing quite a lot? It was very changeable his mood?
-Yes when something was disturbing him and also I've been assisted by a welfare program
for the last, since a year after he was born.
And I quit work just after he was born and I made it out to be with him
for at least 3 years and finally I'm going back to work.
-When?
-A month ago.
-Wait a moment? When did he fall sick?
-Maybe two weeks.
-That is already 14 days and one month ago you decided to go to work and you left him?
-I didn't leave him.
-Did you discuss it?
-Yes.
-You told him that you are going to go to work?
-Yes and that I was going to do it gradually and he would be staying with Jo
and he goes to school for those 2 days anyway and he lives at Jo and then Wednesday and
Friday he would be staying at school, during school and then till evening
and Jo would pick him up and I was going to be busy, I was going to work
so I can make my own living and that 's a big thing.
-You discussed it?
-I told him, not that we had a discussion.
-When you told him that this is going to happen, he never reacted, never said anything,
he never complained?
-Right.
Do you hear the story?
One month ago the mother tells the child, now I'm going to leave you, I'm going to work,
you are a grown up, you are going to stay sometimes with your father, sometimes with me,
we are going to discuss now as grown ups and all this American way of putting things,
business like...
But the child is in a state, he is not well and what happens is that the child gets a shock,
gets a grief and the grief is a silent grief, he hears the mother but he does not respond.
That is what has happened?
-He was not been able to sleep in the night or something like that?
-Just a couple of weeks I would say.
-Did he have a good appetite before?
-There was some fluctuation with his appetite and I would say it was a big issue at 3 years old,
not knowing what to give him, giving the wrong thing, vomiting...
-What does he like? Does he ask for something?
-I think he asked for cereals?
-Can anybody tell me what information I'm looking for now?
My main drive is whether the child eats fruits or not?
That is going to become very important. Why?
Because so far information I have is that the child is in grief but it is silent grief.
If you look in your Repertory you will see the remedy, that the child's mood is changeable.
Changeable mood, silent grief and what she says is that he has convulsions if he is sitting.
Look in your Repertory convulsions sitting, can anybody tell me what are the remedies there?
-Ignatia, Nat. muriaticum, Pulsatilla.
-Where did you see convulsion in generalities or in extremities, when sitting?
Extremities, convulsions, generalities? Not sitting, it's not there.
Ignatia has this kind of situation where you try to sit, there is this kind of convulsions
or choreic movements, involuntary movements while sitting, Ignatia and Cuprum
are the main remedies for this kind of state of affairs.
-Chorea after grief.
-Chorea after grief, Ignatia.
-Chorea lying on the back ameliorates while sitting is aggravating. Very good.
You see the child how he likes to lie down?
Give a little bit more information.
-I think he asks for cheerios.
-What else?
-This morning he said what is peanut butter and later he goes what about peanut butter?
Can I eat peanut butter?
-Did he use to eat a lot of fruits before?
-Not a lot.
-Does he like fruits in general?
-Not really, I haven't been able to eat much fruit.
Did you see aversion to fruit? Ignatia is one of the main remedies?
You see the child how it stays in a silent grief? That is in our books silent grief.
What you see there that is silent grief.
When I try to describe I say words, now this is what it happens.
The child did not react, silent, he took the grief inside, he did not react.
This is the way that Ignatia and Nat muriaticum children will react
but why don't we go to Pulsatilla?
Because the Ignatia has exactly that symptom that the child has. Wants to lie down,
sitting has an aggravation and Ignatia together with Cuprum, there are two remedies only
that have this condition. Not only that but that face in the child...
If the child was Pulsatilla, what he would do? He would cry.
The same thing sad but ....
He would hold his mother but what he does now, he stays like that, immovable
with all this grief inside him. So much grief, so much grief, is it not impressive?
-Can you say that there is a period where he stopped eating fruits from that period on?
Can you define such a period?
-Sometimes when we moved into this house that we are in.
-That new house that you are living now?
-Yes.
-That means from that moment you didn't not live together in the same house...
Do you see what happened? The child was taken by the mother in another house
where they are staying now and as soon as it was taking in the house,
the child stopped eating fruits. It's not stopped eating fruits, it went into an Ignatia state.
The child is in an Ignatia state since one and a half year. That is now the diagnosis.
The diagnosis for this child is Ignatia 10M. That is what he needs.
You will say in a case of inflammation of the cerebellum? Yes, it doesn't matter
what it is the picture. That picture is Ignatia. I don't care about the diagnosis.
They gave Causticum, they will give Cuprum, they will give all kind of local remedies
trying to cure the child. The child will never be cured by these remedies.
It is one remedy only and that is Ignatia, you can't replace that.
Causticum also is worse grief, why not Causticum and also Causticum has the paralysis,
has the pathology and does nothing for the child.
I took the case, I went inside to the class, now I analyze in front of you and you see Ignatia.
I went inside the class and they argued, nobody thought of Ignatia.
But anyhow the child was given Ignatia and I asked to see the child two days later.
This child is not eating. You can't just wait. How long you are going to wait?
He can not keep anything inside. The first thing you have to see in that child
is that he starts eating, you can not wait anymore.
He is dehydrated, he is not eating, he does not keep liquids, he has to be hospitalized
just to give him some saline.
That's why I asked to see the child 48 hours later.
-How he is?
-Eating.
-He is much better?
-Oh, much better.
-Did he start eating the same amount?
-Yes, a little bit. We started slow.
-His appetite returned?
-Yes.
You see in video they will never give you the real story.
The real story is that the  practitioner who was giving the case
I telephoned to tell me how the child is.
I was worried, Ignatia, Ignatia but you want to see the result before you see the Ignatia.
So the first thing I would expect in such a case is that immediately
the child would start eating. He took the remedy, within one hour the child must start eating.
So I asked the practitioner, I said you telephone in the night to see what happened.
The mother said his appetite is so great that we can not... I'm afraid to give him,
he is asking for everything.
She says we started him slowly, I'm afraid he was not eating for so many days and
suddenly asks for everything, shall I give him everything?
He may be upset in his stomach but his appetite is immediately better and his mother
is trying to monitor his diet.
This organism he knows what he wants, whether he can keep food inside,
his mother is not going to tell him whether he can keep food or not,
neither before his mother could make him eat anything.
-That was on Saturday.
Friday he took the remedy.
-How he went?
-I'm worried. Saturday he eats all day.
-The food didn't vomit at all?
-No and no upset stomach and he was pleased, very pleased.
He was talking about spaghetti and meat balls. I said not yet.
-When did he get up and started walking?
-On Saturday he wanted to move into the wheel chair, so we put him in the wheel chair
and then he started moving the wheel chair around, so he started having
good sense of control with that and then in that evening
he wanted to get out of the wheel chair into his bed
and then he would crawl out the wheel chair himself.
-That is 24 hours later.
-Yes.
The next interview is about 2-3 weeks later.
It is a pity that we did not have the follow up with the Anthracinum.
Here where the diagnosis was based, what I wanted to tell you, if my observation was not there,
it would be definite either Phosphorus or Cuprum because he had the spasms or the paralysis
or any other remedy except of Ignatia.
What brought out the Ignatia state was the observation.
What I have learned to look is to look on the person. I do not hear words,
I also observe who is in front of me, what he is doing, that is very important.
And that what I'm trying to give in the lectures. But it is so difficult to describe
with words what I see. Can you forget this state of grief that this child was?
-And he walked a bit?
-He walked with help. He stood up and feeling I can stand up.
-How do you feel Jacob?
-Good.
-You are happy now?
-Yes.
-Do you remember how you were before?
-How? Can you describe?
-Sad.
-Do you know now why you were sad? You don't know.
Now you have a good appetite?
-Yes.
-What you would like to eat now?
-Everything.
-What about ice cream?
-Yes.
-What about sweets?
-What about fruits? Do you like fruits now?
-Protein in yogurt.
-Has he been able to run at all so far?
-Yes.
He runs to the kitchen. Like a little person would run.
There is a little friend of him who is one year old. With her he started to walk.
-Tell me something Jacob. Do you remember seeing any dream?
-Yes.
-Do you remember the dream?
-It's about that tooth that came out.
-Did he go out to play at all or he stayed in the house so far?
-He wanted to play where his father lives in the country.
I don't know did you go out and play?
-Yes, near the manor.
-There is a big house and there is a big eucalyptus tree.
-Do you like salty things? Sweets you like.
What about meat, fish? You like.
How is your thirst? Are you thirsty? You drink a lot?
-No.
-He doesn't want to drink anything.
-Let me see your tongue Jacob.
How is his mood?
-Sweet, precious.
-He was not so sweet before? Before he fell ill I mean.
-Just before he get the chicken pox he was irritable.
-Otherwise before he had the same sweetness?
-Sweet and then moody.
-How is now these 4 days, he is moody still or he seems to be...?
-He seems getting tired very quickly and he will be high spirited and then
he just gets very tired. It seems that he has an association with my niece,
he is doing something new with his hands and then he get tired.
-These 4 days also you noticed this pattern?
-Yes.
-Is he perspiring at all?
-No.
-In bed he is not perspiring?
-Is any time that you noticed he feels worse or he feels better?
-It seems he is doing great in the morning when he wakes up but he has always been like that.
What I was trying to do is to see whether any remedy is coming up?
Not that I would give the remedy but just to advice the practitioner in case
that the child needed a complementary.
As you see I was trying to differentiate between Nat muriaticum or Calcarea or Sepia
or whatever it might be the next remedy.
15 days later I saw the child, the child was so happy and so well that there was no question
of any remedy more.
Still here you may still see because this is the 4th day after the remedy,
you may still see some kind of sadness.
In the next follow up sadness has completely gone, he has never been so happy
and you see a happy child, a very healthy child. Thank you very much.