This was a difficult case.
I remember I had a problem with the class explaining, I don't know who has the notes,
that I'm going to give a remedy which I cannot very well justify.
As you remember I read several possibilities also in the class
but yet I did not really like any of them.
There was a point which was quite strong and that was aggravation from heat,
amelioration from cold blowing air.
This man also appears to me to be older than he really is and also he was complaining
at a later stage about his skin which makes wrinkles.
-How old is he?
-He is 46 but the idea is that he gives you an impression of being old, no power,
no stamina.
So the remedy I prescribed was...
...Secale cornutum.
I think there are several follow ups.
Next time I saw him...
-It was during the seminar in 87 next year.
-Do you have any follow ups here?
-Can you give the reasoning more for Secale?
-We do not have at all information about the psychology of Secale.
It's never given, never written but what I know from previous cases
that I have seen on Secale, I have not seen exactly that syndrome.
What I have seen is a weakening of the mental powers.
A kind of stagnation of the circulation, as if the circulatory system becomes stagnant
without power to force the circulation.
As a result of that stagnation I have seen for instance a kind of varicose vein situation,
where the legs may become extremely warm, they are swelling and they are painful,
especially having a pain which is round, like a strip around the arm or around the leg.
But the main thing is that they are ameliorated by cold air and they are much worse by heat.
This stagnation produces a state of confusion in the mind
and that confusion can be expressed as this man is expressing it in this case
or it can be expressed...
That means you perceive the confusion but the person is not able to describe
that actually I have a confusion, as if living inside a kind of cloud.
As if they do not have a direct perception of reality.
In general as if the circulation had stagnated in the brain.
How one could feel, you can imagine as if the circulation is stopped.
The circulation gives life to the brain and stops, still keeps it alive without life.
Just being alive.
It was a very difficult decision for me because I could not show to the students through the books.
I was leaving all the other remedies which appeared to be better
and still I didn't choose them and why.
-What about this difference...
-Most probably.
This formication and tinkling in the eyes, the stips were there, the pains around the arms and legs.
-Unreal, that the world appears unreal to him.
Whether this is a Secale symptom? What do you want to ask?
How is that goes with Secale?
We do not know, that is what I'm saying.
We do not have the symptomatology on Secale on mental-emotional level.
What I have perceived is circulatory stagnation, which may explain...
it's a slowed up circulation, it's very difficult to explain in a physiological manner,
the action of the remedy.
Because we do not have enough information and this is building up
some information about the remedy.
Onosmodium is very close and Selenium also because there is definitely a sexual neurasthenia,
a sexual preoccupation.
Is he sexually preoccupied? Everybody can see that.
Preoccupied almost all the time with his sexual behavior.
I have seen this kind of masturbation which starts from the very young age
to an age of 45-46, I have seen it with Staphysagria...
Staphysagria can produce a kind of this type.
It produces a feeling as if the brain is like wood, that feeling is in the occiput.
Staphysagria was given to him without any effect
and Staphysagria is not such a warm remedy and what impressed me is that kind of stagnation
which I have noticed in other cases of Secale.
Secale has no symptoms at all, we don't know the Secale symptoms...
Secale has a special action upon the genitalia, ergotamine.
It was a remedy that was given to produce an abortion.
-How is going to affect the male?
-We don't know.
Did you find any follow up?
-We have the analysis.
-It is quite an ordeal. He went through different phases.
This man came with a lot of crying, at a certain period of time we thought Secale
was not working and we gave Mercurialis perennis.
He said afterwards although it was Secale, I became worse, without knowing exactly
that we changed the remedy.
And we went back to Secale but during that period it is very interesting to see
that he go to a state where he cannot eat, he cannot swallow anything, he cries all the time,
he cries a lot.
There is a crying like a child almost, a self-pity and tremendous concern about himself,
about the sexuality and all the things we have been talking about.
Much more accentuated, so finally do you remember when you gave last time Secale?
I think you gave once more Secale, you don't remember Peter.
I will see the correspondence but very seldom I make mistakes in remembering.
How high was the Secale? 200.
After Mercurialis he did not do well and either you repeated or I repeated in Alonissos.
Definitely he got one more dose of Secale later.
-In higher potencies is not justifiable?
-It is yes but it has been given later on, he was given Lycopodium again,
he asked himself and he was given by the practitioner and if you remember he said,
it sent him into an aggravation where he lost the reality.
For weeks he was not feeling real, the world was unreal after Lycopodium.
Simply what he meant is he took two doses of Lycopodium and went into that state.
Once you got that information you are very careful to prescribe Lycopodium again.
-One of the argument for the Picric acid might be that after Lycopodium
he had these sustained erections, that Lycopodium brought out this state of Picric acid.
Picric acid has suppressed sexual desire, as well as masturbation,
which gives the sexual picture reasonably well because we don't know the mentals...
It can make an argument for Lycopodium...
-That is the problem we are having because we are trying to find
the best possible prescription for him and I read to you several possibilities
and you agreed that all the possibilities were feasible and still I was not satisfied.
In this case I do not expect that you will find Secale.
It is because I have some knowledge with Secale cases and Selenium
and I was able to differentiate actually without being able to point out the symptomatology,
what was that which made me decide for Secale.
I think I said the same thing two years ago when I first took his case.
But what is this that makes me not decide on that remedy or that remedy?
I do not feel a Picric acid.
A Picric acid is mostly affected in his mental but you can talk with him for five minutes
and it's perfect, the sixth minute is tired and from then on he will not understand
what you are talking about.
That means it has to have the element of exertion, mental exertion to go for Picric acid
and it has to be strong, it cannot sustain any kind of effort.
What we see here is a complex which is much deeper, we have emotional,
mental and physical problems.
In general all these are in a weak state, the whole organism is in a weak state
and what happens with the brain.
It seems that there is a kind of stagnation; this is how I perceived it anyhow.
It's a poetic expression I'm using but I can't give you more information of what I know.
This man is quite ill, he is a mental case but it's not only a mental case, he is mental,
emotional and physical because he does not have energy to run and to go and to do things.
What I know is it's going to take long time before we can really bring about results
in such a case and we have to wait quite a long time.
-If he did not have Lycopodium before should you give it?
-No, my mind went to remedies such  as I read to you. I did not read Secale, it doesn't matter
but these are the remedies that my mind went.
Knowing the Materia Medica my mind will go to such remedies.
What I perceive in this man is this deep disturbance in him and I would expect
when he is saying I'm better...
This is a man who is out of work from 79 to 86, for 7 years.
He cannot work, he is exhausted.
What I want to see is that the whole organism is coming back, the stamina is coming back
and he will start working again.
This is the test whether he will be better or not.
He is complaining in the whole interview, the complaint was tremendous, he was crying,
I cannot eat, I want to die, there is a time where he cannot swallow.
Eat, I can't swallow, it doesn't go down he says.
Now the last interview.
-He was emotionally after 6 months he gets this I cannot understand why he got a second remedy.
-Because there was a time where he was complaining very much.
I thought that maybe I had evaluated wrongly the situation and I gave another remedy.
-The first consultation you have seen was during the Alonissos seminar in 86.
Then another practitioner attended the case, as you might have seen.
He was a teacher in a school and he was treated by another practitioner at that time.
These two practitioners were teaching in the same school, so for decided to give Gelsemium
and after this patient, one of the participants here a few months later,
he experienced that he didn't get the remedy that George gave him, which was the Secale.
Then at that time he was given the Secale 200 and I must be clear about it,
he experienced dramatic amelioration of energy and psychologically.
Then 6 months later during the Alonissos seminar of the Norwegians he came to visit George
and then there was this pitiful, emotional state in which there was decided
to give the Mercurialis perenis 200, which didn't have real effect I think.
Afterwards, because he stayed to Alonissos,
George gave him the Mercurialis perennis 6X during 2-3 weeks.
Now I took off the case during the International Seminar in September last year
and he had in my practice during the last year.
In November in one of the consultations he was crying continuously almost
and being in a kind of Pulsatilla state and I phoned George at that time.
I said these and these are the symptoms and he was crying very strongly,
he was warm blooded too and there was a possibility of Pulsatilla
but because he was longing for the Secale so much, like for the Lycopodium,
he was asking for his second shot of energy with the Secale,
we decided to give him sac lac and call it Secale.
Then after this Secale he got better for 1-2 days in energy and then he explained
that he got worse again because he inhaled some eucalyptus fumes.
This happened a few times and I thought the remedy was antidoted by circumstances.
To my experience the Secale and the Mercurialis to my understanding didn't have much effect
but in theory you might have the conjecture that the Mercurialis had done the job.
After the Mercurialis I could not see much or any improvement at all.
So this was the story, he did have Secale after the Mercurialis.
-Mercurialis did nothing, from the reports I was getting there was any effect.
From the Mercurialis he went into an aggravation and he was asking for Secale again and again
and I was under the impression and still am that he got a second dose of Secale.
But if Peter did not give it, this is a problem of international communications
and misunderstandings.
What is interesting also is that after Secale he gave reports where his energy
was much stronger and you will see now in last week what he said.
This is the last follow up that we have.
About one and a half year since the first Secale.
-I have something I have done myself, maybe I should give it to you first.
-Read me first your overall impression of how you are doing with your health in general.
Just give me a general impression.
-I think generally I'm much better than last year.
My arms was about because next to Homeopathy I'm doing some other things.
-What are you doing?
-I call it meditation. I sit in my chair and...
-And you try with your mind?
-There are two things. One is that I say all kind of positive things like you are going to be well
and let everything old in the past go away of you, you are full of energy today
and today is the best day of your life, these kind of things saying to myself.
-And it's helping?
-Yes.
-Very good.
Again the same story, all this happens after the homeopathic remedy, that's a coincidence.
Do you think he is really doing better because he is saying that?
What he implies is I don't know about the remedy but I'm doing this and I feel
that this is why I'm better. What do you think? You are afraid to say now?
Let's say that many of you think that maybe.
Let us see if it actually happens.
-Apart from that are you working?
Just go back a little bit.
-I'm not working but I started a kind of voluntary job last September,
so I work now for two days the week.
-What is this job?
-We collect old tools, repair them and are going to Africa, middle South America.
-Very good. Do you like this job, do you enjoy it?
-I started because I thought I had to do something, not to sit.
So I started to like it, I started to like people that work there
that I have said to myself I will do this for one year and then I will see what I will do next.
So to go to find myself a normal job, a paid job because this voluntarily job
is too voluntarily, whether I come in 9 or 10 o'clock it doesn't matter.
I don't care for the payment because I have good allowance but they can tell me
you have to be there at 9 and do this, do that.
-Whether you will be able to do that.
-Yes to test it.
-Very good idea.
-I think I can stand it now.
You see the difference? Forget about in and out, the brain, all that is past.
Now what he wants is to stop playing and get a proper job.
And as he said he had been doing a voluntarily job that was light and easy
but the fact that he says I'm planning now to go to a proper job, this is the sign
that we have finally reached the state where we should be approaching a good health.
Let us hear him a bit more.
-You look very much better.
-I feel very much better, that is true.
-Tell me now the other aspect of your life, the emotional aspect, how is that?
What is happening in that aspect?
-I think on the physical plane that is where I'm much better but emotionally I don't know exactly.
Three months ago I broke up with my girlfriend, that is what happened.
-Three months ago he broke with his girlfriend and he says emotionally I don't know where I am.
What do you think?
Emotionally is worse?
-Better.
-Nobody says worse?
-Much better.
-He finally after one year he found the courage to break the relationship.
Emotionally he says I do not know, let us hear.
-That is what happened emotionally.
-Three months ago. This girlfriend is the same that you had two years ago?
-Yes it's the same.
-Did you break several times with her?
-She broke several times with me, now I broke once.
-You decided this time.
-Yes, more or less yes.
It is not so simple. I decided to tell her the truth about what was going on between us
and during that conversation I decided that...
-You wanted to leave.
-I wanted to leave because she had definite plans with her life
and the plans were she wanted to get married and have a child and I was not up to that.
I was not ready for that and I think there was not enough love. So this time I said we stop.
-In the meantime you had found another girl that you like?
-Not yet.
-Tell me the truth.
-No, not yet.
-But you have something in mind?
-No I haven't. I have no girl in mind.
This is an encouraging sign because in spite of the fact he does not have another crutch
he decides I had enough, we cannot continue.
That shows that the strength is returning to him and he can handle situations.
-These three months now that you are without a girlfriend how do you cope with the situation?
It is too painful for you or it is all right?
-The first few weeks were a kind of relief, a burden was falling of me and then there are weeks
when I missed the things we were doing with her, she was a very good friend.
We liked the same things going to museums or opera or dancing, going bicycling
and I said to myself where do I find a girl like that, that likes to sleep in a little tent
and go bicycling 100 kilometers.
You see during the time of the course that he was complaining, he was taking the bus
for Holland to France bicycling. I said who can do these things?
Not someone who is almost paralyzed the way he appeared in the beginning?
-...and go bicycling for 100 km, it's not easy to get but I think it has been a good decision.
It wouldn't work out.
-How old are you now?
-I'm 48.
-How is your energy level now?
-I think it's much better but it is still going up and down.
Only the going down is every time a little bit less deep than the time before.
That's the idea I have about it.
Sometimes there are days that I feel so good and so strong like in March that I was going skiing.
I was skiing with youngsters who were 25 years old and I could just keep up with them
and that surprised me very much.
But still is the meditation. I don't whether he meditates while he is skiing, maybe.
-These days I haven't been so strong but generally the energy is like waves but upward trend.
-How long you sleep?
-Most of the times I sleep quite normally. I go to bed, fall asleep, hardly wake up.
-So you are refreshed in the morning?
-I'm normally refreshed.
Because of meditation?
-I feel a little bit tired but not such a problem. Only one thing that the times
I felt very good I had a definite sleeping position.
-What position?
-It was on my side and one hand under the right pillow and when I felt worse
I was lying on my abdomen and that's how I sleep now though I feel much better.
-You sleep on abdomen mostly with the hand under the head?
-Yes.
-How is your appetite?
-The last time I couldn't eat was on last December.
There was one morning I couldn't eat at all and then that lasted until March,
until the winter sports that I had problems with eating in the morning.
But now there is no problem with eating at all.
-You have a good appetite, you eat a fair amount?
-I eat a fair amount yes.
-Do you want to put more weight?
-No, I want to lose weight.
-Do you remember when crying and asking me whether you will be able to eat again?
Now you want to lose weight. It's terrible, now that you want to lose weight,
I will not let you to lose weight.
-I have to stop the coca-cola then or the beers.
-You drink beer a lot?
-Not a lot. I never was able to drink a lot but I drink five beers.
-Five bottles of beer?
-These glasses that you drink in Holland about a quarter of lit but it's not much.
I know they drink 50 or 60 or 70 glasses of beer and I don't drink them every day of course
and when I have five glasses I can feel it.
-How is your relationship with other people, with friends? How is that aspect?
-I think I have some very good friends, only most of them are girlfriends
and that hasn't changed very much that time and they like me and I like them.
That's all I can say about it.
You see the way he describes? The whole thing he forgot, he does not remember.
He only say I feel better but if he could decide he would say I'm still the same.
You can hear these things, the difference can be so much
and still the patient will say I'm the same.
-When I came to Greece I went sailing 14 days before going to Aidipsos
and they were nine people on board and a skipper, me and another male and six girls.
Then I always am afraid that being the eldest of course I'm not accepted but I'm always accepted.
There never has been a problem, they always accept me, the strange thing is
that I always worry about that.
-What would you say at this moment is the problem that you want to improve
concerning your health?
What is the point in your health that you would say I'd like to improve more that point.
-I think the problems that I came with are not totally solved yet. They are still weakness.
-That means you want to feel more energy, correct?
-Yes.
He compares with a man 25 years old skier and he wants more energy, that's nice.
If I can give him that, I would get it myself.
So we can go on teaching indefinitely, we don't have to stop now. Why?
-What else? You feel you have enough energy now but you feel still you can go more.
-I think I'm not on my normal level.
-Yes but how many years you have been sick?
-I've been sick from 84, when I started Homeopathy in 84
but that was just for my psoriasis I think but the real problems were at 85,86.
I know I can have more energy because there are those days where I feel like my normal self.
I don't know what to do.
-Anything else?
Emotionally do you feel balanced? Do you feel at ease with yourself?
-That is difficult to say. I think I have never been emotionally balanced enough.
-Yes but comparing with the things you had in the past, you remember all these blockages
and everything which was happening. Do you remember?
-I remember the second time when I saw you I was crying and crying.
-The first time also you were crying.
-I don't remember.
-In Alonissos, it was two years ago.
I don't remember whether he was crying in the consultation but this man was after me
every day and he was asking me different things and then he was crying and I'm better...
You see I've taken his case but every day in Alonissos he gives me a follow up.
I couldn't remember whether he was crying in the interview or...
-Then I wasn't even so bad than what it occurred to me later on.
-You have forgotten how you were. I will show you one day the details to remind you.
-Yes but I know that 3-4 months later it was worse for me than when I saw you in Alonissos.
What took place after Gelsemium the situation was very much aggravated
and he developed a difficulty to swallow. By that time he would cry constantly.
In the whole interview he was crying and crying.
-You remember that?
-Yes but I was sitting in my chair, even breathing costed too much energy then.
Do you see the expression, breathing costed much energy, how tired he was.
He goes skiing, walks for hours... due to meditation.
-I think Secale was the problem. I didn't have Secale then in September, if you remember.
-I'm very happy with the condition in which you are. It is quite balanced, not totally
balanced, still we have some work to do but I'm very happy that you are doing quite well.
-So am I.
-Finally we can say that we are happy both of us, me more than you,
I don't know how much happy you are but I'm more happy than you.
The main thing now is you go back to your normal life now, if you get a job
and you see that you can cope, to have a new girlfriend, to fix your life.
As long as coffees and take strong medicines and all that.
Don't believe that anybody on earth has perfect health. Don't go for perfect health.
See how much you can improve, this is our goal
but what you said that comparing with youngsters you were skiing, it's not anybody
who is almost 50 can compare with people who are 25.
-That is true but...
-And don't want to be all the time in that form.
-No, I don't have to, I know that but something is telling me...
-That you can still improve.
-Yes, I know it.
-I'm glad that you improved and I will tell Peter how to continue,
I hope next year to see you with much more strength.
-I'll be there, wherever. Thank you.
-Thank you.
-I just want to ask a question about the progress I make, is it the Secale
or is it the other things I'm doing?
-Both. Later on also your job is going to play a part in your health.
When you have a job you feel that you are doing something constructive, creative.
It's going to be a positive factor in your health. When you have a relationship
is going to be a positive factor for your health. All these things go together.
It's not only the remedy, it's what happens around the person and if you have a positive attitude,
this is what you want.
-The last 14 days sailing I was rather good and this week I went down,
I noticed, the skin became wrinkled. Now it is normal here.
The last two days I say these things to myself, I love my life and that's
why tonight I feel better...
-The last two days he was doing the meditation and that's why he is better. I see.