-I shall give you the case of a girl 29 years old with fears and tachycardia.
She says since one year after the earthquakes, we had some earthquakes in Athens,
started strong palpitations.
She comes to us on 1st of February 82. The earthquakes are in February 81.
Strong palpitations, numbness of the left side of the body, chills and fears
and fear that she will collapse, she will faint.
She took different psychotropic drugs which did not help.
She also took the Inderal, no result.
During summer the whole situation was worse
and she is worse in the night when she goes and lies down, that's underlined three times.
Worse also when she eats, dinnertime, underlined twice and worse
when she does not go to sleep early.
If she goes 2-3 o'clock in the morning to sleep, the next day the whole thing will be worse.
When tachycardia starts, these palpitations start, the phobias become very strong
and she is afraid now it's going to have and earthquake again,
that the ceiling will fall down.
Worse also lying down for siesta.
Again some other times this crisis can come a quarter of an hour
after falling asleep and wakes her up.
She has frequent urination when the crisis comes.
Bloatedness of the stomach and nausea during crisis.
Until June she was working in a factory with great stress.
She used to eat very lightly and always with anguish.
When she started to eat more and better food, the palpitations became worse.
Summer was her worst time. It was terrible, she said.
Desires and aversion from desires, desire for sweets underlined twice and egg,
oranges not underlined, aversion to milk not underlined.
Thirsty one underlined, drinks cold water one underlined.
Likes the sea, likes changes of weather, she likes the sun,
I'm afraid of going on a great speed in a car and she has great claustrophobia in an airplane.
That has been all along, it's not something that she developed last.
This is underlined three times. She said if I had to go somewhere
and I had to go all by airplane, I prefer not to go, I will not go.
She is a very vital person and quick in what she is doing.
She said she likes to sleep on the abdomen but because she has palpitation,
she avoids that and sleeps on the right side.
She does not take feet out of covers and sleeps from 11 to 6.30.
She said I need quite a lot of sleep in order to work the next day.
Fear of earthquakes three times, airplane three times, death three times,
fear of heart attack, fear of the future, fear of going to the cemetery, fear of dead people.
Feet are cold even during summer.
She is a nervous person, she shouts and she expresses herself during irritability.
Desires company underlined twice, discuss about the problem,
she doesn't want any kind of consolation, she is easily insulted
and sex is higher than normal, a little bit higher, it's not underlined once.
Earthquakes and planes and death are underlined three times, the other fears,
fear of the heart is underlined once, fear of the future, on cemetery
and dead people not underlined.
Cold feet.
-Was the earthquake a very severe earthquake?
-Yes it was, great shock for many. During that time to this earthquake
we had to treat quite a lot of people that they got a shock and could not get over it.
And we treated quite a lot.
Has anyone of you been in an earthquake?
-Yes.
-In a big earthquake?
-No.
-For claustrophobia which rubric do you look?
You look in the additions? Who does not have the addition?
Everybody has my additions?
-We have them.
-Claustrophobia where do you look in Kent's Repertory?
-Fear of narrow places.
-It is two types of claustrophobia, the one is when the airplane closes doors
and then there is no way of going back. The airplane has no way of going back,
no way of stopping and getting out and they go into tremendous panic. This is the idea.
And there is another one which is fear for any closed place but there they know
they can go away, they can stop and open the door. They can tolerate it.
With elevator you can stop it.
It depends because if there is an executive director of a big firm that he has to travel
with the airplane and he never gets into the airplane and it's his life,
that's a severe form.
I have a case like that.
So you prescribe Lachesis? No.
What you prescribe? Causticum? Argentum nitricum?
-Yes.
-So the remedy starts with A.
-Arsenicum.
-Gelsemium.
-Argentum nitricum.
-Arnica.
-Aconite.
-So let us see Argentum nitricum, how many? 21.
Causticum? Nobody.
Lachesis? Nobody.
What other remedies we said? Aconite. Who is Aconite? 9.
Gelsemium? 3.
Other remedies?
-Arnica.
-Who is in favor of Arnica? 2.
-Kali Arsenicum.
-Phosphorus. Any other remedy?
-Ambra grisea.
-Sophisticated.
You were thinking of Argentum nitricum also? Yes.
It is strange that I would not think of Argentum nitricum in that case at all.
-I failed.
-Yes but it's interesting.
It's interesting to see how you are thinking because it helps me also to help you.
The previous case I told you Calcarea was my thinking also.
Here I did not think of Argentum nitricum.
What I would like in this case, to make it an Argentum nitricum case,
I would like to have stressed some more keynotes.
Arg. nitricum has definitely claustrophobia and fear of the dead and desires company.
The worse heat is a very strong characteristic of Argentum nitricum
and the desire for sweets, usually I expect to see a very strong desire
when it is an Argentum nitricum.
The desire is strong and they will express it, they cannot even control it.
I expect also some desire for salt to be there, they have strong desire for sweets
and salt, quite strong.
Gelsemium, what we don't like in this case to make it look like Gelsemium?
-Too vital.
-We have to have a vital remedy. This element is quite stressed in that case.
It can be Belladonna, it can be Strontium carbonicum.
They are vital people and which of these remedies is the most vital?
The most violent in its reactions?
When we have a reaction it is quite strong the reaction and everything is intense?
-Aconite.
-Who thinks that the remedy which has the greatest violence in reactions?
Who thinks of Aconite?
This is what we call the essence. You must not lose sight of that violence.
You see little things now will come to tally or not to tally but we must not lose sight of that.
Aconite has claustrophobia.
Is it fear in narrow places?
-Yes.
-Is it after fright?
-Sure.
-The primary remedy that you will think after an accident, after big fright...
it will be a different situation when there is...
Gelsemium was indicated after earthquakes quite frequently.
That trembling, it's an exhaustion, there is a cowardice state. This does not appear here.
Palpitations from these, oh I'm going to faint and then fear of death, fear of dying
and then the claustrophobia running right through.
When this person was hit by the stimulus of the earthquake was an Aconite case before.
With the fear of entering...? If he was coming for claustrophobia to be able to travel,
we would not perhaps have given Aconitum but after this stimulation
which it takes from the earthquake, the whole picture of Aconitum develops.
Aconitum can help such cases; it can help a case which is 5 years, 10 years suffering.
We are thinking of Aconitum on a short acting basis, where here this person
must have been an Aconitum person all along.
We hit the chronic state together with the acute state, if you say acute
because it is not an acute here.
It is this layer that was the fear of airplanes and on this same level
some other Aconite symptoms were added. So it makes a full picture of Aconite.
So I prescribed Aconite. What potency?
-10M, high.
-What potency did I prescribe?
-CM.
-I prescribed 50M. When I prescribe in these cases Aconitum,
I do not prescribe lower than 10M.
When I see a case, which I feel it is Aconitum, I better go high
and usually is 10M, 50M or CM.
-What's the reason for that?
-I have found out that it's a high frequency remedy, I cannot explain it.
Low potencies may not work at all or they may work for a short period of time.
Also if you prescribe Arnica in a case that you do have a real picture of Arnica,
you prescribe very high, you go 50M.
When you need Arnica after a shock, you go high and you will have
much more impressive results than you have with the 30's or 200.
We are not first aid prescribers. I consider you as constitutional prescribers.
If I was talking to first aid prescriber, I would say the highest you prescribe is Arnica 30.
But I tell you with the idea that you understand an Arnica case and you prescribe.
-Physical pathology in an Aconitum case?
-I don't think that it can exist such a situation.
When Aconitum is needed, I've never seen a physical pathology.
When the physical pathology has come, the Aconitum case has gone into Sulphur
or it has gone into a deeper remedy already. But the time it is Aconitum,
it can go into deep pathology.
You will not find a deep pathology in Aconitum, they don't go together.
When I say deep pathology, I mean deep pathology,
I don't mean pathology on a superficial level.
-I would like to know what is against the Argentum nitricum?
-Not much. I said already what it is. The lack of heat in the Argentum nitricum,
there is a lot of heat, it's a person who is very much aggravated by heat,
it cannot tolerate heat, which is not the case with that case.
Then there is strong desires for sweet and salty things, we do not see that in this case.
Then Argentum nitricum has fear of heights but I've told you not in an airplane,
it's not the case.
You will see fear of heights but if it's a little bit narrow
and there is no things to hold, it's impossible to go through it, the Argentum nitricum.
But you put him in an airplane and close the door, he feels secure that he can rest,
no problem looking down.
It's the fear coupled with the idea that he cannot hold and maybe he will lose his gait
and will fall. There is such fear which goes on inside.
If it is an impulsive person and builds the fear more and more, he goes at a certain moment
and stand in the middle of the pont.
I cannot go, somebody has to hold him and he will pass.
That is the Argentum nitricum situation which I would expect to find here.
These are automatic thinking of course.
Because there are some symptoms of Lachesis as well here, all the night aggravation
and when she enters into sleep but nobody has mentioned of course.
Also worse summer is a strong symptom for Lachesis. Do you remember it?
You could have taken it.
This person you want to know what she said when he came back? Yes.
She came on 17th of March 82, it means in a month time about.
The first thing she says is that generally I did very well, especially the last days.
The first few days there was no change and then for 4-5 days a tremendous tachycardia,
palpitations which I had to lie down and since that time I feel quite well.
No palpitations at all, no numbness.
The fears are just a shadow of fear, it goes away immediately. Sleep much better.
As soon as I lie down, I fall asleep, I wake up in the morning, no problem.
And there is a curious symptom, which has come up, very interesting for the psychology.
She says she has a nightmare now, every second night, that she is in an airplane
which is falling down. Why that is interesting?
See says I'm very calm and she says an expression, which sometimes we hear it
when we have hit the right remedy, she says my husband I changed so much
that he does not recognize me, I'm another person.
With Aconitum, you hit as a chronic case and I would like the psychologist to tell me
his opinion about that nightmare. What it shows? Or anybody who wants to comment on that?
There is a nightmare, every second night she said, that she is in an airplane that falls.
-The dreams is maybe the fears coming out. She is resolving it.
-Yes she is getting over this.
-The same idea everybody has, also I feel the same. She is now able to confront the fear,
she is able in an unconscious level still to really come into contact with that fear
and sort it out. We don't have further information because she has not come anymore.
Maybe after a few years she will come back and we will enquire about that fear.
I believe that within a few months perhaps she is travelling to the United States.
She is entering an airplane.
That I do not know. That's another explanation.
Aconite is listed on a nightmare falling from a high place.
In this case it's a confirmation that the remedy is correct
but also the other explanation can hold true.
You see how beautiful these things occurred.
I feel that really it's mathematics.
The fear of entering in the airplane and the strength of the reaction is part of it.