-Tell me what happened?
-I have an acute lumbago.
-You had it before?
-No, it's started in the noon break. I had little tension and pain since the morning
but in the forenoon break, I bowed down to get something from the floor
and it was like a strong shooting pain.
-Where exactly?
-In the right side of the lumbar sacral region.
-Can you exactly show me where is the pain?
-Here.
-You showed a little bit higher than the sacro-iliac junction.
Is this the pain?
-No, it's a little bit higher.
-Does it extend to the right foot?
-No, not at all.
-It's only on a point?
-It's an area but the most pain is to a point, I can localize the pain to a point but
the whole area is. Tonight I didn't sleep out of two reasons.
One was that I have a strange thing, when I get tired in the evening, I have about 15 min.
to go to bed. If I don't do it, it may happen that I don't sleep.
And that happened yesterday.
-Due to the pain?
-No, there was no pain.
-You just did not sleep immediately and therefore you stayed for the whole night.
-Yes, I slept with my wife yesterday and that's why, I overdid it.
-And you were excited and you could not sleep?
-Yes I was excited for another reason. Yesterday evening my wife told me that a man here
had fallen in love with her and I don't know, it bothered me a little bit
because I was thinking what shall I do with this situation?
My wife is very stable with these things, I don't really worry but he went so far as to ask her
to kiss him, so I'm not sure that this is connected but it was strange that
I didn't have this before.
My wife she just said that she is confused by the whole thing and a lot of thoughts run through
her mind and I was worried how to help her, how to help him because he is in a bad situation also.
-And you can not walk now?
-I can walk very carefully.
-You can not straighten your body?
-When I rise up like this it hurts and when I go forwards like this it starts hurting also.
To the left I can go all the way.
-And movement, like keep on walking, makes it worse?
-I think it makes it better because in the break I lied down for some time and then getting up
was a bit heavy. It was about 10 min. until I went to the toilet and I had to be quite careful
how to get up. After a while it was easier but still not very good.
-Do you have to turn while you lie?
-No, I better not. Just lie flat...
-It is the most comfortable?
-Yes.
-Rising from bed is very heavy?
-Very heavy.
I haven't really found out the way to do it because just a very small movement will bring
a strong shooting pain again and I really don't know which movement to do,
I haven't found out yet.
-Do you feel any hot or cold applications will help?
-I don't think so. The only thing that I felt comfortable was when I put my feast and
put pressure on the point here.
-Do you usually take a lot of salt?
-No.
-On the contrary you don't like salt?
-I can eat salt but when I cook I don't use any salt because I don't need it but I have
no problem eating salty things.
-Your organism does not need salt.
-No.
-Are you thirsty person?
-I can forget to drink the whole day and it doesn't bother me.
When I'm working, like also here, I have a bottle and I drink all the time.
-Sips?
-Not just sips.
-So when you work you need liquid.
-I like it. I don't really need it, I can stay all day without drinking also.
-You are a cold person, a hot person, you are bothered by heat, by cold, by exposure to the sun?
-I'm bothered more by the heat, I'm more hot than cold. I can stand cold quite well I think.
-Sun?
-I get a sun stroke very easily so I have to wear a cap in the summer always.
-Do you drink milk?
-No, I don't like milk.
I eat muesli in the morning with fermented milk, a little bit sour milk but no more milk.
-Never? Never in your life?
-I don't like it.
-Do you know why? They gave you too much?
-No, I get the connection with the cow. It's disgusting.
-There are some people sometimes you don't like?
You have an aversion?
-I don't think so.
-Which remedy I'm thinking?
-I'm a beginner.
-I want to know if you control the interrogation.
-I am in homeopathic treatment.
-What remedies you have taken?
-I don't know the remedy that I'm given since 4 years.
-Do you suffer with hemorrhoids?
-Very seldom I have a little bit of blood.
-What remedies you have taken so far?
-Right now I'm in treatment since 1995 and I don't know the remedy.
I receive one dose about every 5 months but I don't know the remedy.
-Are you German?
-Austrian.
Before I was in treatment with the same doctor and he gave me for a long time Pulsatilla,
which helped.
He gave me one time in the beginning Tuberculinum but then I don't know what
other remedy. I tried Pulsatilla myself once in 1994 and I took it too often
and a autoimmunity disease came out.
-What?
-Lichen sclerosus e atrophicus.
It's the mucus membrane either oral or genital gets sclerosis and atrophy and shrinks
and I have this since 1995. That's why I'm in treatment.
-How is that now?
-It's in a standstill and it's not bothering me as much as it did.
I have it in my glands in me penic, it's underneath and it's shrinking so much that in the intercourse
was very painful and the mucus membrane would split up and was very painful.
It has been progressing even during the treatment but there was always aggravation.
It would become very hard like a cartilage and then it would become soft again
and I would have no pain.
Right now it's in a standstill and I can live with it.
-Do you consider yourself as closed, open person?
-Closed.
-Very close?
-With people that are intimate to me, good friends I'm open but the second reason that
I'm in treatment is a kind of social phobia .
Every time that are more than 2-3 people I get cranked up and I have lodged big problems
with that and it's getting a little bit better by the treatment but it's not really satisfactory.
-Do you feel fear or you don't know exactly why you have cramps?
-I don't know, it's more like a state that comes over me.
-It's like timidity.
-I was timid since I was a child but then I was 13 this thing started and I begun to shake
in front of the class, my neck begun to cramp whenever people's attention was on me.
I don't know, maybe this is a long story, I don't know if I should explain this.
This is an acute case.
-It's an acute case which if it's correct, it's going to cure you.
You never took Nat. muriat?
-No, except the last remedies I don't know what my doctor has been giving me.
-Ignatia you took ever?
-No.
-Do you like fruits?
-I like fruits.
-Sweets?
-Yes, I eat them, I don't need them.
-It's not important.
-Milk I can drink but I wouldn't go myself to the fridge and take milk.
-But if you have to drink it, will you drink it?
-Yes, I'll be polite and drink it.
-What did you study? Are you medical doctor?
-Yes.
-You have a speciality?
-I practice as general practitioner since 2 years and in my practice I do only Homeopathy
and I work night shifts.
-Are you still used to work a lot?
-Yes, I think so.
-Is it possible to urinate in front of other people?
-No, that's something that has come up since 1996. It started in Germany, I was in a course
and it started there and since then I haven't really tried it.
-You haven't tried ever again. It was embarrassing for you?
-Yes.
-Do you ever get cracks in your lips?
-No.
-Do you get herpes? Blisters?
-When you say easy sun stroke, you mean real sun stroke or some dizziness from the sun
and you get headache?
-I get dizzy first, then I get nauseous and maybe a headache also.
But mostly dizziness and nausea.
-After how long staying under the sun?
-Without cap maybe half an hour under strong sun.
-OK.
-That was a quick case for finding his constitutional remedy.
The fact that the first thing he says is, when I put my fist I feel released, I put this
hard pressure on the point it is either Rhus tox or Nat. mur.
These two remedies should come to your mind.
Then the sensitivity to the sun takes you straight to Nat. mur.
Then further the closeness of the person it is more Nat. mur. and I don't know if he is given already
Nat. mur., in which case we have to give a very high potency of Nat. mur. in order to cover up
in case he is given already Nat. mur. he needs Nat. mur.
Plus the fact that he was under some stress, some grief because of the incident with his wife.
So all this together makes a case of Nat. mur. 50M. Thank you.
-No problem that he needs no salt?
-No problem.
Nat. mur. can even have aversion salt. If the organism absorbs a lot of salt,
then there is aversion, they don't like salt because they take salt from every food.
Or on the other side if they can assimilate salt, they need salt all the time.
Whatever you have taken, what you need at this moment is this remedy.
So after this remedy, you may need another one maybe but this remedy you need at this moment.
And it will help you not only with the back but it will help you in general.
-Half an hour ago, between 20-25 min. you received a dose of Nat. mur. 50M
and you felt quite a difference.
-Yes, a little bit pain left but I can move quite well.
-Very good, it was quick prescription and quick reaction also.