-The last thing that appeared was a spasm in the calves in the night.
- Cramps in calves. In bed?
-Night and in bed only.
Also the fingers of the feet she has to jump from bed and
stay straight on the floor, push on the floor, so it won't hurt.
At the beginning it started every two months, every month, now it's every two weeks.
Once in two weeks. The same strength of spasm she has also in the heart region.
-She feels as a cramp?
-And this minute when it happens, she can not breathe. It takes only a few seconds.
-But how long she has this spasm on the left side of the chest.
She is talking about the left side of the chest.
-The heart region.
-Heart region but it's not the heart.
-She feels inside. It's like pressure.
-Like squeeze the heart?
-It's something burning, not squeezing.
-And you understand intercostal neuralgia?
-No, I have not intercostal and I have not [...] my heart because I checked my heart.
-Have you been examined by some colleagues of yours?
-Yes, of course. There is a block in the right artery which is for the last 30 years,
since she was a kid, she knew about it after she gave birth to her daughter she found out
about it, that she has a block in the right artery.
-Did she have another pregnancy after this?
-No.
-The cardiologist said you can not have it?
-They didn't tell anything like this but the father had the same thing, congenital.
-How long is  these cramps on the left side chest? One year, two years, five years?
-One year.
-How frequently?
-Once the month.
-With some stress? When you have some kind of grief or stress?
-The first time, a few times was when she was stressed but lately it comes at night when
she is not stressed, not connected with stress.
-Connected to exertion also?
-Not connected to exertion, it's when she is asleep.
-Has she ever tried to use dilator, vessel dilator like trinitrin to see if it is an angina?
-The only thing she took was Cactus in 7C which gave a relief, a little bit.
-During the pain?
-Yes.
-No other remedies she used?
-6-7 years ago she took Lilium Tigrinum because of pain in the low back which used to return,
this back pain, every month or twice the month.
Then she took Lilium Tigrinum.
-Only Lil. tig. or she took other remedies and Lil. tig.?
-No, only this. She had a very strong aggravation after the Lil. tig.
-I couldn't move and couldn't go out of bed for one week because of the back pain.
-Then the pain vanished and never came back?
-It came back two years ago after four years, it came once.
-And she took again Lil. tig.?
-No.
-She took nothing?
-She was here when it happened, we did cream Rhus tox and acupuncture.
About two years ago, when she came back from here, she took Mercurius because she
felt starting a little bit depressed and she couldn't concentrate, she would start
stammering while she was talking.
And she started staying at home most of the time.
-Because of the fear?
-Fear of people.
-Was any reason, somebody threatened you?
-They were a few things which pilled up. Twelve years ago she got divorced
and the husband married the best friend, two years later she opened a medical center
and when it went up to the peak and it was beautifully operating, her partner stole money
and made her bankrupt and two years afterwards her daughter married against her will,
she didn't even know, she was told just before the wedding that she is getting married.
-She has only one child?
-Yes and two years ago her father got very sick with cancer and she took care of him for
about a year or two years and he just died last February.
And now the mother is under her responsibility and she is also sick and everything
is under her responsibility and it's heavy for her.
She pushes herself to more and more work and she can't stand it anymore
because she came to her limits actually. She took on herself more and more work.
-At the point where she has been exhausted?
-She works from 7.30 in the morning till 4 o'clock as a medical doctor and from this time
till about 11-11.30 at night as a homeopath.
That's every day including holidays and weekends.
In the beginning she really loved it, it gave a good feeling, she loved it.
She loved Homeopathy and she enjoyed it, it was giving her really good feeling back
because of the feedback, because of the patients becoming healthy.
Lately she can't stand this.
-She feels exhausted and she can not stand anymore a telephone, if someone telephones
she says oh my god one more telephone.
-A year and a half ago she still used to wake up at 3.45 in the morning, exercise,
doing everything, studying until she goes to the patients and now she can't do it.
Now she is asleep sitting down.
-As soon as she sits down she falls asleep?
-Sometimes but she gets tired, her concentration is very bad and she even forget names
of remedies and medicines that she works every day with.
Lately she has a very strong burning pain in the heart, in this area.
-In the chest?
-Not in the chest, from left side and it goes up.
-In the esophagus?
-It's burning but it's a pain. It's for few minutes and it goes. She smokes too much.
2-3 boxes the day. She tries to stop but it makes her very irritated.
-Trembling?
-Not trembling, irritated, nervous. She loves people, she wants to be near them but she can't.
It's fear and a feeling that makes her tired.
-So therefore she feels better when she is alone.
-In the beginning. The feeling is that she feels that she can't cope,
she can't be friendly enough.
-She does not have the energy?
-No, because she is depressed she doesn't want to affect others.
She doesn't feel at ease that maybe she will say something which is not correct
or something like that.
-At this moment she wants to give up work, to give up everything?
-Except work. She can leave everything but not work, she wouldn't like to leave work.
If she could concentrate only in work, on the things that she love, she would be happy
but she has so many other destructions around like the mother ...
-Originally she came from Russia?
-No, Romania. She took two years ago our room and she had a very funny reaction.
After one week she had shivering with cold in the middle of the summer, she put
four blankets but she was still shivering for one night and the next morning
she woke up fine.
-Was any effect from Aurum? Psychologically she felt better?
-Not really. It happened the week after the Aurum, for one night and she doesn't
have any other answer why it was like this and no other effect either.
-Is she a cold person?
-Normally she used to suffer from cold but the last year or the last summer,
she is very hot and the feet are burning. The soles in the night in bed.
-She takes them out.
-She takes off all the covers anyway.
-She is in climacteric now?
-When she was 38, when she got divorced her period stopped completely at once.
-And she never had again?
-Never.
-From last summer it is constant heat or it is flashes?
-Only in the night in bed. Only burning soles and cramps and in the night
and day was in the heart.
-But has she checked whether she has hiatus hernia?
-No, I haven't.
-This burning that you talked about, it comes through the esophagus or you don't know?
-It's something like spasm.
-And it's for few seconds.
-She has it here also two times.
She had pain yesterday and then it went down to the arm.
-Pain here for one hour.
Do you make fever when you are sick? You have high fever or you never have fever?
-I had fever maybe 4 times all my life but I'm never sick usually.
-You never get influenza?
-6 years old she had tuberculosis pre-infection. They saw a mark on her right lung.
-Since then she had an X-ray in the lungs?
-There is nothing except nicotine. 3-4 times she had pneumonia in her life.
7 days with antibiotics and it was gone.
-When it was the last time she had pneumonia?
-3-4 years ago in the winter, with very high fever and coughing.
-Does she ever perspire in bed?
-Not especially. Not every day.
-Which place mostly?
-Only under the arms but not much.
-Except of the fear of people does she have any other fear?
-She wouldn't stand up to her duty.
-Fear that she will not fulfill her duties.
-She had very strong feeling that she is not lucky, she doesn't have luck.
She is afraid to go closed to people, not to ruin her relationship with them.
-Especially with the relations is this or with everything?
-Everything. Every place she puts her hand, it's ruined.
-Any other fear? Fear of poverty, fear of dark? Thunderstorms?
-Snakes and she has some funny thing with dogs and cats.
They always like her, they come to her, they sit next to her but she has something
against them, she is not afraid of them.
-She does not like them. You don't like dogs? You don't like cats?
-I like them but far. The funny thing is that they always come to her.
-She attracts them.
-Yes.
Even the dog here comes to sit next to her, they are 150 people and he comes next to her.
-I'll bring Rocky to check it. Fear of high places, looking down?
-Yes.
-Do you even get fear that others may observe what you feel?
-That's why she put an appearance for people wouldn't see what actually is going on.
That's why you said she looks very good, she looks healthy.
-What about likes, dislikes in food?
-She took the Lil. tig. because she loves meat, she used to love it, she still
likes it but after Lilium is less.
-What else?
-I don't like so much sweets.
-If they offer you you will take?
-Some but I put a lot of salt.
-Desire for salt.
Sweets if they offer you in a house, you will eat it or you will say no thank you.
-I eat it. Because I'm polite.
-But not because perhaps she doesn't want to put on weight, because sweets put on weight.
-No I cook meat with sweet and whenever she touches it, she throws it, she can't stand it.
-But chocolate?
-Only cream she likes.
-How much she will use?
-A lot.
-Did she ever take Nat. mur.?
-A year ago she took Nat. mur.
-Was any effect?
-No.
-Did she ever take Calc. carb.?
-A year ago. Calc. carb. 200.
-No effect?
-No.
When she is in stress at work because she works too much, she takes Nux vomica.
She never took more than 30C and it gives her a relief for a while.
It does work for 3-4 days.
-What about her sleep? Her sleep is good?
-Not continuously but OK.
She wakes up at night because she has to stand up because of those cramps.
-She wakes up because of cramps, not otherwise.
-No.
-Has she ever taken Sepia?
-Yes, two years ago 6C for one week.
-No effect?
-I don't know.
-She is working non stop all the time, she can't see if something changed.
-The nails are strong. Very strong.
-She can't cut them.
-She is somebody who would care very much about others, has anxiety about others
being very sympathetic?
-She said, if she wouldn't be like this, she wouldn't be a homeopath and she wouldn't
work so hard, she has sympathy to all the patients and the feedback that she gets,
holds her to continue working.
-Except of names her memory is weak? For instance, she wants to do something and
she goes to the other room to take something.
As soon as she arrives at the room, she can not remember why she came to the room?
-It happens but not very intensive but other thing that bothers her a lot, if she reads
something, she can't remember it, unless she writes it down. That's lately.
The nails are hard but the hair is very weak. It's very soft and fine hair.
-How she would describe her emotional side. She is depressed or indifferent?
-More to the depression side and the feeling that she is alone and she wants to be with
people but she is afraid she will ruin the relationship, if she goes near, closer.
-Did she take Ignatia?
-After her father died last February she took Ignatia 200.
-At night in sleep does she have any salivation?
-Lately she found out that she has salivation at night.
-She said, she is stammering but I can not hear stammering.
-If she excited and tired she says again the same word.
She can't say the word, she forgets the word.
-This is different than stammering. Stammering is...
-This and she forgets the words.
She thinks that inside her there is dissatisfaction from herself, from the world, from life.
There is some kind of dissatisfaction. She feels something like she is not good enough
and she didn't stand in the standard of expectations.
There is a dream that comes all the time and makes her jump and waked her up at night.
Sometimes the dream wakes her up and sometimes the cramps wakes her up.
-What is the dream?
-That she is inside a swamp and she tries to get out of the swamp and as much as
she tries to get up, it takes her in more and more and then she wakes up.
It' s a dream that returns all the time.
-Did she ever have suicidal disposition?
-When she was a kid, when they sent her for three months to the sanatorium because
of the tuberculosis, she was missing home, she tried to commit suicide, to hang herself with
the belt of the dress.
-But never again?
-They sent her twice, so it happened twice, year after year.
-Does she grind her teeth in sleep?
-No, never.
-Nobody told her?
-I went to seminars with her, I don't remember her grinding and I don't remember her
snoring either. Her daughter told her that she snores.
-Does actually not like any animal or only cats and dogs?
-She is afraid of them.
-Of animals in general? Like a cow...
-Not so hysterical and extreme but she prefers to be far away.
-From birds?
-From everything, even from the little flies, the insects.
-If she likes meat, she likes special meat like pork or ham or smoked?
-She likes pork, she likes ham, smoked more and she likes all the grills, the open fire.
She had mononucleosis two years ago and the doctors said that this tiredness,
this weakness is a fatigue from the mononucleosis.
It was an epidemic of mononucleosis in Israel, every third person had it.
-Even the children?
-Yes.
-And you got it.
-Not strong. Only in the blood test she found out that she had it.
-How is now the blood test?
-OK.
-I don't think you made any, you just say OK.
-Everything is fine.
-Did you take Carcinosin, Tuberculinum?
-No, no nosodes. She doesn't take nosodes.
-How is her thirst?
-Medium.
-Thunderstorms?
-She is not afraid but it makes her more depressed.
-She has any problems with digestion, constipation, colitis, bloatedness?
-All the years that she remembers, she has pain in the left side in the spleen area but
it's something that I have all the time.
-Do you have a time of aggravation where you feel better or worse, when you wake up in
the morning, after that, you feel better in the evening, better in the morning?
-In the morning she feels the worse until she wakes up, in the evening her concentration
is much better.
-How long it takes in the morning to come back?
-One hour, from 6-7 is unrefreshed. The worse she feels after eating, whenever she eats
she feels very tired afterwards. She wants to sleep, she lies down and she sleeps.
-Thank you.
A lot of grief, that's one fact, really a lot of grief, long time grief.
It has to be taken into consideration.
I would like to hear the opinion of the cardiologists here, what do you think?
It reminds you of some syndrome or any possibility involving the heart?
-It is known that there exist cases of angina pectoris although the coronary results
of examinations are perfectly normal, the cause is the spasm of coronary arteries,
the stress tests show no results at all. There are cases which you find a disturbed
metabolism of the myocardium.
These patients produce more lactate than usual and it is suspected that, that maybe
the cause of the pains.
It's not a seldom symptom, you see it quite frequently and in the cardiologic literature
is described it as syndrome X.
-In that form it comes sudden, it is acute and it goes away so fast? It can be?
-Yes it can be.
-She is afraid to go and have a check up but she smokes 60 cigarettes. My god!
-What we don't know exactly is what she exactly has on her coronary arteries,
which she has from birth. All we know is she has something wrong with the right
coronary artery and something not normal at the coronary artery can at a certain time
of life lead to symptoms similar to this.
-You always had this weight or you put on weight lately?
-She put on weight the last 4-5 years. Before she did a lot of sports.
-She still eats a lot of meat.
-She likes it very much but she tries not to eat that much.
-Fear of people, let's see which are the remedies which have fear of people.
-Hyoscyamus, Nat. carb., Rhus tox. Where is Lycopodium?
-Yes it's there.
-Let's see what the Expert System says.
Causticum with Calc. carb. Causticum is quite ahead with a possibility of Carcinosin,
let's see why Causticum.
Causticum has 13 out of 25. Let's see cramps in legs and calves.
It's very strong for Causticum, cramps in calves in the night in bed, Calcarea and Causticum
are very strong together with Calc. carb.
You remember, she said I don't like sweets? And I insisted to find out.
The reason is because we have to differentiate between Calc. and Causticum.
She feels unfortunate. This is something also interesting. Show me this rubric.
If we put desire for smoked meat of course then Causticum will be pushed very much.
It will go too high.
Therefore when you use this System it is good if you don't use some strong keynote for
one remedy and see whether the remedy is coming up even without the keynote.
Then you are more sure that even without the keynote, the remedy is coming up with
the repertorization. This is a strong indication that the remedy most probably is correct.
Delusions, she is unfortunate, we see Bryonia, Causticum, China Staphysagria, Cub. Graphites,
Hura, Ipecacuanha, Lycopodium, Sepia and Ver. album.
-I took Staphysagria.
-The struggle in this case should be not with remedies like Nat. mur. in spite of the salt
desire for salt.
You see the difference? Nat. mur., Ignatia and Aurum they will do nothing.
Desire for salt which is for Nat. mur. but this is not a Nat. mur. situation.
It's a long grief that brings out what? Cramps in the calves or cramps in the toes.
Causticum. Because if we say long grief, one of the main remedies for long grief
if you open Kent's Materia Medica, it says cases of long grief.
12 years ago she started one after another grief, grief, grief which ends up with some
symptomatology now which is mental, she is sympathetic, she does not want to harm others
but also the physical symptomatology is going towards Causticum.
Therefore we can not ignore this remedy and we don't have a better possibility.
Let's see which remedy covers most of her symptoms on flat repertorisation.
Let's see on flat repertorisation, which is the remedy that covers mostly her symptoms.
Causticum must be quite high, Lycop. more symptoms, Arsen., Calcar., Sulphur and then
Caust. Lycop. forget it, Arsen. you don't like it, Calc. carb. yes there was a possibility,
Sulphur forget, so therefore Caust. even from the flat repertorization is quite a
correct decision.
Now the problem with this case is what potency shall we use?
Shall we use high potency, low potency, medium potency? Let me see your feelings on
this case after the analysis. Who will CM? 50M? 10M? Six. 1M? Ten. 200? 86.
30? Four. 12? One.
200 daily, three times the day! In the beginning I thought this is a case of Calc. carb.
because what she said is, I got tired. I'm tired, I don't want... The Calc. carb. we said it
in the Materia Medica and it's very characteristic, once they get tired, they just want to
get away from everything, they want to leave their business, every obligation which they have.
The way she described it was like a Calc. carb. Not only that but when I asked her
do you think others can see what is happening inside you, a characteristic of Calc. carb.
she said yes, that's why I'm putting now a face.
You should have investigated this question because it was very important, what does
she really mean.
If this is a fear that others will observe how weak I am, how the mind does not work,
fear that may others observe, this is characteristic of Calc. carb.
but she did not say exactly that.
She said I'm putting up a face so that others don't pity me perhaps.
You see the difference? I didn't want to differentiate because I didn't want to give you
the possibility of understanding what I was thinking very much because you have to think
for yourself but this is the question that you should have put up during that answer.
Because it was not clear that it was a fear others may observe my inside. She most
probably did not want others to see that she is in a bad condition,
why should I bother others, that is different. So what is actually the answer in what I say?
-What potency she will get?
-Given the fact that she smokes so much, given the fact that this symptomatology may indicate
some problems with the arteries, I would go very low, just to be careful, I would go to 12
and I will give it 3 times the day, 12 C. Anyhow, even is she takes it once the day
if she keeps on taking it for a period of time like one month, she may start feeling after
the month, a little bit better and then you can raise the potency, you can ask the pharmacy
or raise it yourself to the next potency, number 13.
Even better 10 days, 12 and then 13 and then 14 and then 15. That will be even better.
And if you will find out after a month that you start getting less cramps and less pains
I hope you reduce smoking and I hope that you modify a little bit your diet as well with
the fat in the meat and the meat. So actually if we are treating, she is a medical doctor
she knows everything but if you are treating somebody and you have to give ...
you have to say, you have to stop smoking and you have to say it's good if for a period
for six months you become a vegetarian.
And then give the medicine and then the result of your medication will be much augmented
by a better diet and non smoking situation.
-She says she knew it's a slow suicide what she is doing.
-Exactly and she did not care, that's why I said this.
Once you have a patient, it doesn't matter you are a medical doctor I can speak openly,
once you have a patient like that most probably if they don't see results immediately,
you prescribe a dose of 200 Aurum 1M and no immediate results, he gives up,
he says forget it, I drink coffee, I drin kthis, nothing happens.
Because the long grief has taken away the joy of life.
Therefore she does not care on a level.
On another level she does but on a level they don't care.
Let me enjoy, smoke, whatever happens, happens. Is this correct?
-Very correct.