-In last May I came to you and I said that I had some problems.
-No you said that you felt very bad, you had taken the remedy which I gave you.
-The last one was Ignatia 200 and I didn't sleep at all after Ignatia and then I came to you.
-And you said that you have been sleepless all these nights and that you feel very bad
and then you started telling me this story.
-Before I came here I had some problems with my parents who wanted me and pressured me
to divorce from my husband.
On the other side was my husband which I loved him and I was somewhere between them.
I had some suicidal thoughts.
-You must say also that you are very close to your parents, you were brought up in an
environment very autocratic and very strict, your parents were supportive but at the same
time they were suppressive.
-Yes and they wanted to support them in the same way...
-That they supported you.
-Yes and they didn't want to accept that I'm married and I work.
-And they were pressurizing you in different ways to divorce.
-Yes.
-By saying what? Your husband is a medical doctor?
-Yes he is a medical doctor, he is practicing Homeopathy but another kind of Homeopathy,
not to give one remedy, to give many remedies.
At that time I couldn't understand why they pressure me so much to divorce but
after I came home I started to understand some things, so I didn't take Aurum that evening
I let to take it when I will arrive at home.
-After telling me the story I said to you, you must take Aurum 200. Very good.
Which you did not take.
-I let it to take it at home. When I arrived at home everything was OK, my husband was kind,
gentle and then he said he has some work to do and let me to rest and then I have
a shock because I saw that all these things from the house are gone, the clothes,
the books, everything and I said OK I must take Aurum now and I took it.
Then I wait for him and he said, OK I move because I want from you some things that
I cannot obtain if I stay with you.
So he said till you will give me some money about 3000$ something like that,
he said I own to him these money, he will not go to sleep with me anymore and he will not
live with me anymore. And I had a second shock.
I said it's not possible, you are joking. He said, no I'm very serious and he was serious.
He left the house with everything and we have no relation till now.
-You live separately.
-Yes and little by little I started to discover all kind of fixed ideas, fears that he has and
he started to make around me, he talks with somebody he says something wrong about me
and then he comes and prepares me that that man will come and tell you...
I wasn't sure if I'm right or he is right, I wasn't sure about my judgment, I was so...
I don't know for a period of time I wasn't sure for my judgment.
I said I'm insane and he is healthy.
And one evening we had a quarrel and I decided to finish with the life because there is no use.
So I want to kill myself, I couldn't support me anymore.
It was too much for me but I couldn't find any medicine in the house, he has all the remedies,
so in the next morning very upset I said to him, you know last night I wanted to kill myself
and his answer was yes, why you didn't do it.
And I took another dose of Aurum in the 1st of July and then I tried to speak with my parents
and to understand what is happening because I must know and I found out that they saw his real
face before me and they tried to tell me but I loved him too much to see the reality.
Another thing happened, when I was here, the office was opened and he took all my patients.
I don't know what he told them, he spoiled all my treatments because he gets a lot of remedies
and then he said, OK you can go and practice.
I can have 1,2,3 new patients but at the end of the week or he was at the office and that patient
had an aggravation, he called him and treat him and I lose that patient again.
And he says it's not true, they just come at me because they love me.
So I was in a situation that I couldn't earn money and he wouldn't give any money at the house,
not at all and the financial problems are mine.
-You practice in the same house where you live?
-No in a different house. So I'm moving in another town and I'm going to open there an office
because there I have now a lot of patients.
So I just closed in my town my office because it's no use.
-But your office was the same with his office?
-Yes we work in the same building.
-And now you closed it. That means he stayed in that apartment?
-No we do not live there, neither me or him.
-He opened another office?
-No, he stayed in my office but now I closed and he remained with anything because
I closed and I said, I will not let you do any treatment anymore, I close it.
-This is your personal apartment?
-Yes, it's my private apartment and it's my private office. He treats because I'm his wife.
I let him.
So in the middle of July an old friend of mine met me and saw that I was very changed
and he said what happened to you, you are like a dead person, what happened?
-Then I couldn't stop, I start crying and saying all things and from that moment
he started doing like psychotherapy with me and to show me that my judgment was right
and he is an ill person and day by day I just started to see what is good and what is wrong.
In August I had another problem, my mother had to be operated by uterus carcinoma,
I didn't want to have operation, I wanted to treat her but this was her decision
so I stayed with her 2 days and 2 nights, I had a lot of fears, if she will be OK,
if she will live and then it appeared another idea which still goes on,
3 of my grand parents died from cancer, my grand mother had uterus cancer and my mother
had cancer of the breast 8 years ago and I started thinking if I can have something like that because
I stop the sexual life and this will be quite a problem.
After Aurum my menses stopped and I was quite worried about it and I told to my husband,
I said, look my mother is with that, we stopped having sex for a long time, I have no period.
So this is your problem not my problem, he said. I think he has somebody else, I'm not sure.
-You still live together?
-No, he lives separately, he comes at home only to eat once the day.
-In your house with your parents?
-No my parents stay apart, in another house. He comes to eat, I can be at home or not
but it's not very important to be at home when he comes. I was very terrified because
2-3 times he said he will kill me and 2-3 times he said he will beat me.
-He said he will beat you or he beat you?
-No, once he was near but somebody came and he stopped. At that moment I take the
decision to divorce because I can not live in such a manner.
-When did you take the decision?
-In the beginning of September when I had a terrible quarrel and in the middle of this quarrel
I felt that my menses started and I had another problem after the menses, in the period
of ovulation I had great pains in the night.
-Where?
-Ovary, uterus, something like that, I was very excited, I couldn't sleep, I was turning
around and finally I go and take a cold shower to recover, that was 2 nights, one after another
and I told him we need to have a life together and he said, we can find somebody else,
he will not disturb me but he will not divorce from me. I want you to be with me
and you will die near me.
I don't know if it will be like that because we already made the file for the divorce
and when I come back I don't know how he will react but in the last month I changed myself.
I became stronger and I can answer him without being afraid that he will beat me or kill me,
I said, if you want, do it.
And he considered that the fact that we are not living together is not enough to start a divorce.
-He said?
-Yes. He doesn't want children now, maybe next year, maybe we'll see, we wait.
Now in the last moment he will do everything...
-Are you sure you were not pregnant?
-No. I haven't slept with him until the end of April, so it's 5 months.
He became jealous he didn't want to let me come here, he said that I have here a boyfriend
and that I came from here pregnant and now that I have no menses...
-He said you are pregnant with another man?
-Yes. So that's it.
-But after all you look good. I don't know how.
-That friend of mine helped me very much with talking.
-Is he a medical doctor?
-No, just a friend and we talk daily and when I am little depressed and in something I'm not sure,
I call him, I meet him, we fix the problem and everything is OK.
I have a spot and it's much easier.
I have also migraines before the menses, strong headaches 2-3 days.
-2-3 days before menses you have a headache?
-Yes.
-Where is the headache?
-In the beginning I feel that the head will explode and then it's like in a circle
which is very tight in occipital and in front and when the menses start, the migraine disappears.
If I have normal life, I will not have migraine.
-Psychologically how you feel now? If you measure the last month, the last 15 days
can you describe your psychological state and say my main problem is this.
-I feel good in general. I have little fear that it is possible to remain alone.
I don't like to be alone, I need to have somebody near me, I need to have friends
and all this period I haven't. He took care and he threw away all my friends.
-In order to be with him?
-Yes and to listen only to what he said, not another opinion. I don't like to be alone,
I think this is the most important fear that I have. It's not very strong but it comes.
At the same time I think what kind of life I will have, if I remain with him, so I think
I took the right decision.
I will open an office in another town and go there and start practice have other patients and
after a while I will open again in my town.
-I think the only problem is when such cases, as you say, if he is not balanced this man
maybe he will trouble you for certain period of time.
-I think so but it's another thing that is unusual for me. I told him if he will bother me or
he will do something not to divorce and give me troubles, I will revenge.
I'm not revengeful but I feel that I can revenge on him and I told him that I can destroy him
that he will not be able ever to get up again. I can and he knows. He asked me once,
you can revenge for me and I said yes I can. You are joking?
No, I'm not joking and I really believe that Ican do it. I never do it but now it's new,
this revenge appear. And I will use the blackmail to let me in peace, I have no other choice.
I told him to take a remedy and to be well and he doesn't want because he is a healthy person!
-If he threatens that he will kill you or beat you and you have some proof of that, then you
can always go to the police and report him. It's not something light.
-Yes I know.
-It's good that you stand up and you show strength.
-When I'm near him, sometimes I feel I'm paralyzed, I cannot do anything, I cannot
react and I must recover myself and put together and then to react. This is a great effort.
After that I'm finished and he is amazed, why am I reacting like that?
Because I must be like a Staphysagria, to be quiet, to say what he likes to hear
and everything will be OK not to hear what I want to say.
Like physical problem I have only 2. Since yesterday morning I have great pain on my spine,
it's like it is inflamed.
I can not have a position without pain, I don't know why, it's because of the trouble I don't know.
It's terrible. In the night I wake up and turn to one side or another to find a position, I can not.
-In the whole of the spine or the dorsal region?
-It's the whole spine.
-Do you feel pain like burning, stitching?
-No, it's like it is inflamed, like you have a joint twisted, something like that.
And I have a bad taste in the mouth, like metal and at the same time I think I have a bad smell.
-You mean offensive breath?
-Yes.
-Do you have problems with your teeth?
-I made a stomatological treatment just before I come here and I wasn't sure that Aurum will act.
I wanted to repeat but then I said, no it's better to come here than to repeat Aurum.
I think Aurum helped me very much.
-Do you have the written report which you sent me?
-No, I just called you in the telephone, I didn't send any fax.
-Do you have any salivation during night?
-No, the pain is so strong that I have the feeling that I will faint any moment.
I must lie down on something hard.
-There is any change in your desires, aversions, desire for salt more, for sweets?
-No. I think everything is normal, thirst 1-2 lit the day. Now I'm in a diet because
I want to lose weight.
-Do you need more heat or you can not tolerate the heat?
-No, normal.
-When you lie in bed the pain does not start immediately, it starts after some time?
-Yes or it starts when I sit.
-How long you have to lie before it starts 1 or 5 hours?
-No about half an hour, 1 hour something like that.
-And then it starts and then you have to change position all the time?
-Yes, one side or another with the knees on the chest, it's the best position not to have
pain but I like to sleep on the abdomen, it's the best position for the sleep but now I can not.
On the back it's impossible, I can not stay on the back in bed.
-Do you sigh?
-I sigh all summer but now it stops and I was crying all summer. I think I cried for all my life.
-After Aurum you were able to sleep immediately I think.
-Yes I sleep immediately.
-You felt quite good and you reported that you were handling the situation.
-Yes because at that time I wasn't sure what ...
-What was happening?
-Yes.
-So until the time you found out what was happening, your report was that you were fine
you were controlled.
-Yes because I thought that he was right, I was wrong, so I believed him and everything
was OK till I met that friend of mine who said, no it's not OK. Wake up. It's not OK.
You can not live like a slave, you must have your dignity, you must have your practice.
-Do you have a time where you feel better or worse? Your best and your worse time?
-Yes, my best time is in the afternoon and evening. The worse in the morning.
Now I must make and effort to get out of bed and to wake up and everything.
-How is your sexual desire?
-It's quite high.
-Do you have a lot of amalgam fillings in your teeth?
-Not amalgam, I think I have one tooth with another metal, I think silver and gold.
-Do you feel that you need special company or just anybody or you need companion?
You need a close friend?
-I need a close friend, I need somebody to be near me all the time but now I haven't
because the time was too short. I want to have people around me and a lot of friends.
-So now actually you want to be social, you like people around, you are not closed to yourself?
-No, I want to be somebody. I can open my feelings to somebody, not to keep in me.
But mostly I need somebody to be all the time with me.
-The back pain is better when she lies on something hard but do you have to put your
feast on a certain point and lie on your feast?
-No just lie and with the knees up or to put both hands in the lumbago region.
If I put the hands in the lumbago region, then I can stay down.
-Motion ameliorates?
-No, she has to move all the time but you are relieved for a few seconds if you move?
-If I move it's OK but if I sit or lie down or I stay long time in the same place,
in the first 5 minutes, the pain starts.
-And if you move it's OK. In the beginning of motion it's more and then ameliorates?
-No, it's less, less and then disappears.
-Then motion ameliorates put 3 times.
Do you have any bloatedness, some gas?
-Yes, if I'm fasting I have a lot of gas.
-Fasting you mean?
Not to eat at all.
-And can you fast or you feel difficult?
-I can fast 2-3 o'clock in the afternoon till morning and then I must eat something.
I can not keep all the day.
-You can not keep all the day or day after day?
-No.
-In general, at this moment, the cold or the heat suits you best or you don't care?
-No, it's the same.
-If there is a draft you don't mind?
-No.
-Do you have the tendency to cry?
-Not now, in the last month no.
-The menses have come back?
-In September.
-Normal or the blood was more?
-No, it was normal.
-Your sexual desire has anything to do with before or after menses?
-No.
-Do you eat onions at all?
-I like onions. No problem.
-The amount of sweets that you take, would you say normal?
-Normal, I have no special desire for sweets.
-Bloatedness?
-From time to time and if I fast I have it.
You remember the case from last seminar where she had several days that she could
not sleep and she was going down and down and we prescribed Ignatia and the last day
of the seminar she came inside and she said, I don't feel better at all, I'm still not sleeping
and she broke out crying and telling me the story about the conflict between her parents
and the husband and her parents forcing her to divorce and she did not want to divorce
and she was in between that situation and she was in a terrible depression with suicidal disposition.
This story did not come out during the interview, it came out in the office and
I said to her take Aurum 200. She took Aurum 200 and because I worried about her,
I asked my secretary to telephone her after a few days to see what was happening
because I knew the depression was quite serious.
And Lona telephoned and you can say what was the conversation. Can you remember exactly?
-Yes, I asked her how she was feeling and after she took the Aurum she said, she felt
very much better. That was about all.
-Well, anyhow I got the message that she was well and I said OK. Then eventually she
discovered what was happening and then most probably she needed another dose of
Aurum which she took. I did not advice for that, she took it herself.
What is impressive for me is when I look at her, how well she looks.
After all this I would expect to see somebody totally destroyed etc. and I think she is back
to life and therefore we are going now to search for the next remedy to see
if we can help her further.
We took the case and we took these symptoms, you can show these symptoms and tell
me if you would like to take another symptom or you want to change one.
Family history of cancer, menses...
-It doesn't count, zero.
-What do you mean zero?
-It's on the list but not in the evaluation.
-Ailments from mortification, sighing, even sighing you can take it out, now there is no sighing.
-No.
-Not sighing really but you can leave it.
-She has menses now.
-That's why we don't take into consideration the symptom, it's zero.
-Sorry.
-The head pain which she described, which is exploding, a head pain before menses is
a Belladonna headache.
The Belladonna woman before menses have headaches, instead of being depressed or irritable,
they develop headaches.
Bursting before menses, constriction before menses, beginning of menses ameliorates
revengeful, taste metallic, odor offensive, pain on back on something hard ameliorates...
This pain also is a pain different that what she describes. This pain which is described in
the Repertory is a pain which you have to put at the point of pain, pressure and then you
lie on it and then slowly there is amelioration. What she described lying on something hard
is a position of the spine which makes her feel better. It's not the hardness, it seems
that the position of the spine had to be flat to be best, so this symptom actually is not correct,
you can take it out.
Drawing up limbs ameliorates, desire for company.
-That symptom wasn't in back, I only found something in extremities, so if anybody finds back,
drawing up limbs ameliorates... I couldn't find it.
-Has anybody found this symptom?
-So I took extremities instead of back.
-Bending forward?
-No, it's in bed drawing up the legs.
-Yes, the back has to be flat.
-What is the analysis of these symptoms?
The analysis says Lycopodium, Lachesis, Nat. mur., Pulsatilla...
Motion ameliorates is very strong. Show me the symptom, motion ameliorates in pain in the back,
it's a very clear symptom. Motion not pressure.
-She said pressure.
-Not pressure. Dulcamara, Rhus tox and Lycopodium, Ammonium muriat.
You see the Rhus tox first has to have more pain in the movement. So therefore it's not
a case of Rhus tox and for different reasons, she doesn't feel the cold, she doesn't need
the heat to support her pains.
With the metallic taste and the offensive breath you think of Mercury, not confirmed.
You need the third symptom, salivation during night, you say this is a Mercury case and
therefore Lycopodium is the best possibility. The question is shall we give it, yes or no?
-No.
-Shall we give it, yes or no?
-Who says no?
-Who says yes? 2 courageous men.
-I think that the entire process is now going down to the physical plane because she has more strength
and she made a decision for herself, so I would really say, let's wait.
-That's exactly the situation, I'm afraid that when sometimes grief affects the whole of the back
and especially with Ignatia we have a cramp that goes from the cervical right to the sacral region
and the whole area is cramped and this can stay for years after grief which is the somatisation of
a psychological problem.
Now in her case she says, as if there is inflammation, this is better than the cramps
because the inflammation can be controlled easier, in case it stays.
I agree with the decision, we have to wait at this moment because of the good condition
of the mental emotional in spite of so much upheaval, which she could not control before.
You remember she was in a state of great stress before with this conflict and she lost totally
her sleep, that means leading her to a depression that was quite deep, since Aurum has acted,
the depression was really serious.
Therefore looking how well she is psychological, we have to wait in spite of the fact
the repertorization will show a remedy, most probably indicated and we just have it in mind.