-And there during the course I received Nat. mur.
because I was running from one catastrophe into the next.
I fell and bruised in hands and knees and feet.
-Where, in which course?
-Here in Alonissos in May.
-You're talking about last May?
-But her mother died last week. One week before she came in May.
-After falling and bruising myself I got a sun stroke and went to the water
and it was hard to get out anymore, one thing after the other happened.
-She got a stroke?
-A sun stroke.
-And she could not get out of the water?
-Yes.
I came out of the water and the Cuban guy assisted me and afterwards I got Nat. mur.
and after I took this remedy a lot of hatred came up.
I hated my father all my life like anything and my mother was only living for him.
My mother had her first stroke 5 years ago and the remaining 5 years until she died
I somehow subordinated under my father and cared for my mother.
And I always tried to help her out with what I had. She was paralyzed...
-Is she a medical doctor?
-Practitioner.
Whatever I did was under the intention to help her.
Every time I turned against my father, he let it out on her.
If you want to bring somebody who is paralyzed into some nursing home,
you have to pay between 5-6.000 DM per month.
Today I understand that my father, who had been self-employed all his life,
was afraid from starting paying money for something like that
because what he had was what he saved all his life and he was afraid to spend it.
And what caused all this now was, after I came to the island this time,
meaning now I saved this dog, you saw me outside with a young dog, the Alaskan dog.
He was tight down behind a house, he was beginning to get ill
and the reason why I did this and slowly I drew the dog close to me was that I had understood
that my father lost his motivation for life.
I know he is going to leave life soon until he finds a new motivation to return to life again
and so I had figured that if I bring him this dog, I might give him new motivation, to continue living.
-How old is her father?
-85.
Since my mother died, he was water in his lungs, one of his heart valves doesn't function anymore
and you can just watch him ...
-But does she still hate him?
-No, I've been working so much with this subject and I really left it.
-Left the hate she means.
-Yes and this morning I received a fax that he sold the house
and now on my way coming to the Academy this afternoon, after having cried all morning
and all noon I suddenly realized what my point is in this whole thing.
Everything I ever earned or saved for myself, I lost repeatedly or had to give away
and I somehow secretly had hoped that he would leave at least something for me
and now he also sold the house; so it's really this financial point that I'm working right now.
That's one of the points and it's a point that really runs through the family since generations.
For example his sister who used to live in East Germany had his OK in general
to care take of his possessions there but without him knowing it, she sold his house
which he was owning there and he almost went crazy when he heard of it.
This is an issue which has been running through my entire life constantly.
Always the issue of loss and him, feeling responsible that he had not taken well enough care
of his heritage.
And he constantly feels responsible for anyone in the family who is at weak point
to somehow support this person and so now he wants to buy the house of his mother.
All his life he had said, whenever I leave the house, I live in now.
The only way I'm going to leave it is with my feet being carried out first.
-Which he changed it now because he sold it or did he sell it with the idea that he keeps it
until his death?
-I don't know exactly but when he bought it, it was his intention to live there until death.
My physical feeling right now is everything is gone. My mind says,
it's nonsense but my entire body goes to pieces.
It's like a part of me I have no control of it.
-Is she trembling?
-Yes.
-How did she feel before this information came in?
-I was so happy, so incredibly happy, ever since I took Calcarea phosphorica.
So maybe if you want to know about my remedies, the last remedy I took was Calc. phos.
-When?
-I prescribed for myself 5 weeks ago. I took a C12 which lasted for one week,
I took it 4 times all together and a C30 one week ago.
-She had some other problems when she took Calc. phos.?
-Yes, I took it because I can't really study. I was studying all my life
but I always have the feeling I can't memorize things, I can not keep it in my head,
as other people can.
There is always a barrier, the moment I need it, nothing comes out
and when I'm really relaxed things just pouring out of me, one after the other.
But I have to be in a certain state of joy and then suddenly I know things,
I don't even know where I got them from.
There is so much there, just it's a certain combination in my head
which makes things come out suddenly, quickly and come one after the other
and I even pass them, even though I was so way behind before.
-And Calc. phos. helped her to have a state of mind which is clear.
On what symptoms she took Calc. phos.?
-I had started eating bacon like some crazy person every day and that I could not study.
Due to these two symptoms, I took it.
Before that just after the death of my mother it was Nat. mur.
I go through the remedies backwards now.
The Nat. mur. was 1M twice all together and before it was Ignatia 1M.
-That's all?
-No, I once had pyelonephritis, 3 years ago, first I treated with Sarsaparilla
but I stopped taking it I had strong cramps in my right leg and then I received a remedy
which I don't know which one.
I also once had Naja C200, I had Lycopodium all the way up to 10M
and Lycopodium didn't exactly help me
but it assisted me in getting a very deep understanding of communication with others.
Before that I did a remedy proving on my own. I took Mercury for almost half a year.
-On purpose, she took it to have a proving?
-It was a mixture, on the one side I was very curious about this remedy
and on the other side I had holes in my rectum which closed and healed with this remedy
and I believe without the assistance of Mercury I would not have been able
to take care of my mother at this time.
-She has fistula in the rectum?
-The rectal situation was she had fissures of the anus, she had fistulas,
she had strong itching and right behind the anus inside
there were two big holes through the mucosa in the rectum.
These holes she had had since her first menstruation and it all disappeared with Mercury
and some of the hemorrhoids disappeared but not all.
Eight years ago I received Arsenicum 1M on three following days
because at that time I had a sensation as if my entire body was burning,
I was overwhelmed with everything that was happening around me.
For 3/4 of a year I had told nobody about that state I was in, I was running through the streets
of the town every night and the condition I was in was so terrible.
The entire body was burning like fire inside.
And when I closed my eyes, it was as if all pictures had been cut into pieces
and for 3/4 of the year I did not sleep one night
and then finally somebody gave me Arsenicum 1M three doses and within three days,
this state had vanished.
After that there was so much I had to deal with, my father, my mother, my practice a job on the side,
earn my living, my partner, there was so much going on
and so I prescribed for myself Arsenicum 10M and immediately after taking the 10M
I knew now the whole problem is down to the physical level.
Within a few days first I had the cystitis and then a pyelonephritis.
And after that I skipped one remedy, that was after the pyelonephritis.
I prescribed Silica for myself and that was beautiful.
I took it for one year and it helped me so much.
-Silica what potency?
-Up to 10M.
-For 1 year every day Silica helped her? But never closed this fissure?
-Starting with C12, the itching, the fissures and the hemorrhoids now were healed with Calc. phos.
and Silica helped me to really straighten my life, to go through things to find my goal,
to set myself straight and manage everything, new stuff, computers the course here,
my practice, whatever.
Before it used to be so that once I was in something I could work like a machine
but until I really started there were a lot of fears and insecurities.
With Silica it went really beautiful. I just straighten out and did whatever I wanted to do
and managed very well.
-Which of these remedies she consider it acted best?
-It was a development and concerning my feeling for life it was Calc. phos.
The feeling that came back was like a feeling I've known before 6 weeks vacation in Greece
and this feeling I did not have in the last 25 years.
-For 25 years?
-I have not had this feeling.
-Not even under Silica?
-No.
-The reason why I didn't have this feeling for the last 25 years has to do with my life partner,
whom I met 25 years ago.
Before I met him I was a wild person.
I did whatever I felt like doing, I lived in different countries all around the world
and always did what I felt was best for me.
Once I got to know him I did exactly what my mother had done.
I subordinated, I assimilated into his life system and even though I was defending myself
and trying to go against it, I had to suffer for 25 years.
Then 10 years ago actually we officially separated but we always kept playing pretending
we would still belong together and half a day we still work together.
What he never forgave me was that even though I left his life, I stayed in the shop.
And so from then on he said, whatever we earned, whatever we built up together is mine.
And so I told him I couldn't care less and I just set my own practice
and he keeps telling me what you did in formal times it was just jumping on to wave
and going along with the wave and your practitioner stuff now
you just jump on to some wave, although he really supports it in the meantime.
That's one of my basic structures I always fight against my father, just to prove to him
that I can accomplish something too.
-How is her thirst?
-Last time not so much, if I don't remind myself to drink, I don't feel any thirst at all.
-But she came with the bottle here.
-Because I was shaking so much but it was more a mind thing and after Calc. phos.
I developed a lot of thirst, I drunk enormous amounts.
-And still drinks?
-Yes but I feel that it's reducing and I can also feel that the effect of Calc. phos. ended
when I received the fax from my father today.
-Does she drink milk?
-No, I decided to stop drinking milk 6 years ago because I had a blood test
and this test showed that I'm highly allergic to milk, which showed itself that
for example my entire head fell as if it was burning and I reacted to all kinds of milk products
milk, cheese and so on; also to nuts and green peppers and things like that.
This burning in my head and also a burning sensation in my shoulders alongside
with the feeling that everything is contracting, I can feel now again
and I can feel that Calc. phos. is still working a little bit
because there is still some clarity in my mind which allows me to think in spite of this.
-But she has this stiffness here?
-It's starting again like that.
It was really massive at the time when I took the Arsenicum 10M;
at that time everything felt like it was just one burning nodded area
which was working back and forth and side and I could hardly move anymore.
I also had a whiplash syndrome 20 years ago on this area on the left here.
The effect of the whiplash syndrome eased with the Silica, almost completely.
-Now at this moment does she feel anything on this area?
-Just beginning to burn again.
-Is sensitive this area to cold, to drafts?
-I used to be very cold at the times of Silica;
if my feet were cold up to the half of my lower limbs, I would get ill immediately.
Now my feet are cold but it's not as bad, I'm not that cold, I don't get ill.
In former times it would always happen that my feet were cold and my lower limbs were cold.
What I could do for years is scrape off the pus of my tonsils
and the chill the coldness was on my back, going down to my buttocks,
then into the legs and I was ill.
-And then she was ill?
-Yes.
-Does now she want to eat bacon again?
-16 years ago she was a vegetarian for 4 years but she stopped being a vegetarian
and now she has the feeling she could eat bacon but she wouldn't do it.
She was eating bacon a couple of months ago but now she doesn't eat it because
she just feels eating bacon is a strange thing. She wouldn't do it anymore.
-But that means she does not want, she has no desire.
-I have the desire, I could eat it, the desire is there but the mind says,
eating bacon is somehow wired, I won't do it.
-Still I do not get an answer when I ask about these burning feelings here.
Is she affected by any coldness?
-Not specifically this area, in general I'm sensitive to cold and to draft.
If my kidney area gets cold and I feel the draft there, I panic immediately.
-If she feels a draft in the kidney area.
Does she have any predominant fear at the moment?
-The first thing it came to my mind now was everything is gone again.
-But this is a financial insecurity?
-One part is financial and the other is emotional.
-But the emotional what has to do with losing the house?
She was emotionally connected with the house, that's what she means?
-No, my mother was my home and since my mother died I tried to make my father
and the house into my home.
-Does she have the feeling that she is unfortunate?
-No, my basic feeling is that I'm a lucky person and whatever I start, I will manage somehow.
And I worked so much in these last years, it would be equivalent of three people's work.
-But the fact that she lost repeatedly, does it give you the feeling that you are unfortunate?
-No, it's more like something that just belongs to me. My grand parents lost everything repeatedly,
my father lost everything repeatedly, I also have lost repeatedly.
It's something more like a back pack, I'm carrying it around all the time.
-How many times she had a sun stroke? Only one?
-As children we were in the sun for long hours but it never really did good.
It was more or less just being together with others.
-Does she avoid sun now?
-No, I don't avoid it but I can not sit under it for hours.
And if I was in the sun, afterwards anxiety feeling arises and my entire system is affected.
Maybe this information is important to understand better my sensitivity to the sun.
18 years ago I had a meningitis and this meningitis I developed because my partner
and his mother were planning to travel to the USA.
3 weeks before I had really intensely hoped that I would come down with something
that would keep them from going and 3 weeks later I was in the hospital with meningitis.
So they canceled their trip, stayed with me until I was healthy and then
they dragged me on to a ship here to Greece and since then I actually don't like sun anymore.
-She has a regular stool or she is constipated?
-At the moment when I'm traveling at the beginning I'm always constipated.
After a couple of days I have normal stool. With Silica I developed normal stool
before Silica I had diarrhea constantly.
And every time I'm excited or there is something ahead of me which I will manage
but at the moment I think I will not be able to manage, I have quick urge to go to the toilet
and I have a stool once quickly.
-But not a diarrhea?
-No.
-What is the first rubric that you have to take in this case?
-Ailment from grief?
-Ailments from sun?
-Ailments because of bad news.
-Ailments from bad news, sudden news and she was overwhelmed and this is the rubric,
show me the rubric. Which are the remedies?
Gelsemium is the main remedy and Calcarea. Does somebody has the original Kent?
-Yes.
-Show me the remedies that original Kent has?
It just raised Gelsemium.
This is the same.
-More or less.
-Almost exact. This is the first. What are you going to do?
Is this a case of Gelsemium trembling in the beginning?
And now she is still crying outside of course.
But in the beginning she was affected very much. The organism was affected.
I don't think she has any control of what is going on inside. It's too much.
The bad news are overwhelming. But this is the rubric you have to be looking first.
And then show the other rubrics that you have taken and now I' ll tell you.
Ailments from bad news, difficult studying, ulceration in the rectum, fissure, fistula,
itching, thirst less, pain burning, cervical region, bacon desire, draft of air aggravates...
No, this is not correct but anyhow leave it there, it doesn't matter.
Exposure to the sun, excitement, inner trembling...
Show me the analysis.
With these symptoms we see the first remedy comes is Gelsemium. You changed it?
-When you take the bad news in the 4th degree, Gelsemium take it to the 3rd degree it's Calcarea.
-OK, Calcarea, Phosphorus, Gelsemium.
-I drive with her every day and have some contact with her and she complains
that she constantly has a sour taste.
She just now said my entire body is sour and so she says my entire body
and my taste is sour and besides the craving for bacon, she always have a craving for pork.
And when she received the news this morning, we were standing together, she was not trembling,
she cried immediately and broke down.
-Concerning this physical feeling I'd like to add something,
it is as if a system in me is broken down.
It was the same feeling when my mother died and now I have the feeling
that my father is going to leave.
-You mean he is going to die.
What time she received the news?
-After breakfast about 8 o'clock.
-Did you ever take Calcarea carb.? No.
Do you perspire during sleep here?
-I used to never perspire a lot, since I took Cal. phos.
I perspire in the night on my back and on my chest and it's more towards morning around 5 a.m.
And also 3 days before my menses come, I perspire so that the entire bed is wet.
-Perspiration before menses, can you try?
Calcarea comes quite strongly.
The question that we have to ask at this moment is this.
She was doing very well with Cal. phos.
Also this is a case where you will see the layers. She needed several remedies, which were correct.
She took Arsenicum, it was the correct remedy at this moment.
She was for 9 months going on and could continue that state of Arsenicum for 5-10 years.
She needed Arsenicum.
And also Silica acted curatively. So she needed Silica and finally she needed Calc. phos.
She was fortunate or her organism is strong enough to give out clear pictures.
This craving bacon you see how strongly she describes and saved her life.
What we have here? A case that goes like that.
Arsenicum, Silica, Calc. phos. which are not mixed so much and underneath Calc. phos.
is possible that there is Cal.car.
This is the question and while she is doing very well here and this layer is gone
and she is going to develop this layer of Cal. carb., she receives a shock here.
She has not received yet Calc. car., she received a shock on these layers.
Maybe underneath there is Natrum carb. even.
The shock has different possibilities. Either to bring back the previous state,
one possibility, second possibility to create a new state this is Nat. mur. or Ignatia
or Staphysagria, whatever. Third possibility is to make this level more prominent.
This is what we have to solve and to decide upon.
What is going to decide? What is the deciding factor?
-This insecurity is since the separation lasting for 10 years now.
My mother was, as I would described it today, delusion religious.
She never understood why we didn't marry and every Christmas she wrote a letter to me and said,
my greatest wish for Christmas would be marriage.
That's why I remained in this relationship.
-Her greatest wish was to remain this marriage, is that the idea?
-The mother's greatest wish was that her daughter would marry the partner.
They have been together for years and years but they did not want to marry
but because it was the greatest wish of the mother, our patient decided
to remain in the relationship although it was very difficult.
Due to this about 12 years ago I blackmailed him more or less and said,
either we marry or I leave. But it was not my wish, it was her wish.
-You see also it is too early to decide whether a remedy like Calc. carb.
which is quite a deep remedy is really manifesting its picture;
it's too early to decide whether it will need this sensitivity to coldness,
perhaps more than she described, we need the desire for eggs or sweets,
we need the perspiration.
-I have had this craving for eggs and I had times where I ate up to three soft boiled eggs per day.
And when this bacon thing came up, I really broke through a barrier, at that time,
when I started to eat bacon because usually at home I never eat meat
because my partner is vegetarian.
And now I'm at the point which after Silica I can really live my own things again.
-Is it true that, one of the doctors remarked, you said you feel you're going crazy?
There is this fear, you may lose your mind?
-Before Calc. phos. this was true and with Arsenicum it was there for years.
-Did it cross your mind at all?
-It is interrupted by this burning and the constriction in my neck and my shoulders and
in the head; everything closes down and I can not feel anymore.
-Thank you.
What's the remedy?
-Phosphorus?
-You want Phosphorus but you have no thirst?
-At the moment I'd have half bottle of the water.
-No, no.
It is the teaching that we had in the morning, when I said, when there is a relapse
what do we mean by relapse?
We mean that we may have back the symptomatology or the keynotes
on which we have prescribed the previous remedy, which has acted well.
The previous remedy that has acted well was Calc. phos.
Now she says, one keynote is that she really wants bacon, desire is there.
The other keynote is, Calc. phos. has a critical point on the cervical region,
where they feel constricted and this constriction makes the thoughts not possible,
the reflection goes. It is as if they are living in a limbo, neither positive, nor negative.
No thoughts, no feelings, they are clogged here; both thoughts and feelings for Calc. phos.
seem that something holds them there and they can not flow.
Feelings can not flow, thoughts can not flow.
And Cal. phos. is one of the main remedies for bad news.
Bad news affect, bring a state of Calc. phos.
She had very good reaction from Calc. phos. We have back 2 keynotes from Calc. phos.
together with a new situation, which again fits with Calc. phos.
So the remedy that she has to take at this moment is Calc. phos. 200.
What she described here, she says this thing here makes me having no feelings and no thoughts,
I can not think, I'm crazy because I have no thoughts, this is typical of Calc. phos. situation.
You can not go away, you have to take a dose of 200 and come down to earth again.
-If it's interesting for you I could describe what else has happened when taking Cal.phos.
because it was really the theme of my life when I took the C12.
I took a C12 every week, it actually lasted for one week each time
and what came back was this Phosphorus part in me.
I was almost like I used to be when I was young.
Almost careless, light, joyful, laughing and after 4 weeks about this Calcarea part,
finally struck, for the time in my life I got the feeling that I have ground beneath my feet again.
It was a feeling as if my body changed from before being almost immaterial
and invisible down to becoming very material.
And in the mornings when I woke I was almost angry about this feeling
because it was as if I had lost one aspect of my life and after about one week
these two elements started to combine with each other and so I had flexibility together
with stability and that really made me incredibly happy.
-Therefore I would suggest actually, looking at her, because she cried quite a lot
and this crying you can't say it was releasing the tension inside and I can see her laughing now.
I would suggest that she will not take the remedy today, you wait until tomorrow.
See if do not by themselves come to balance and if they don't or become worse
you can not sleep etc. and it becomes worse, then it is better...
Because it is too early to know, maybe the previous situation, the previous remedy
can still be acting, not being antidoted.
So you just wait, don't be in a hurry to take the remedy
but the remedy most probably is Calc. phos.
You are blessed with a good constitution, it's very important.
The remedies that you produce like this makes...clear remedies produce clear pictures
shows a good constitution.
-The complains were mainly on the mental-emotional level and they were very intense,
very severe, so I would have tend to give at least 1M or higher.
-It seems that her organism is reacting so well in lower potencies that going a jump
from 30 to 200 is already a big jump.
I was thinking whether we should stay still on 30 and maybe we'll do that
before we'll go to 200; because her organism reacted so well in 12C.
That means the remedy was dead right, the organism was on Calc. phos. exactly.
-I would like us to hear what happened with the case yesterday when we said
that she must wait before taking the remedy to see how she is today and then we will decide.
So I will ask her how she is today.
-I cried a lot yesterday, still and then I went for a long walk with Adam.
We went down and we both had huge portion of ice-cream and after that I already felt better
and then tonight I slept very well and the feeling this morning is...
Yesterday when I got the message, I felt as if somebody had bitten me over the head
with a frying pan and this morning 3/4 of the frying pan are gone.
-Also laughing and she is quite happy actually.
-And you know this feeling of soreness in my body and the sour taste in my mouth
which occurred after I had received the message, it's got relieved a lot through the crying.
And usually if I drink black tea in the morning, I then have the feeling as if all minerals
have left my body for the day.
Now I feel balanced, the minerals are there and they are in my body.
-Very good, so can you imagine if we gave the remedy, she would report this and
we would say, ah the remedy did very well.
Or if you have given the wrong remedy, maybe you had some kind of a proving.
This is quite a good state, very happy.
This is what we call placebo effect, you don't even have to call it placebo effect
because the moment that a person is under such a shock, it's natural to react
and it will be much worse if she had kept everything inside and presented herself
in front of you with a face still and unexpressive, without showing her emotions.
It would be much worse and you will have to fear that she will develop eventually
quite a symptomatology.
The fact that she cried, it's a natural reaction to such a disaster
and the organism gets over due to the fact her organism was functioning well,
due to the Cal. phos. she has taken before.