-Now yesterday she came and she complained that she has started
with the diarrheas again and today the diarrhea continued.
So she came with her doctor friend who said to me something very remarkable.
She said yesterday when... you tell the story.
-Yesterday evening we went out for dinner and we went in a restaurant
and he drove me home and we came to our flat and she had closed the door,
suddenly she turns around, runs back to the car and checks
if she had really locked the door.
Since I observed it for the first time, nevertheless even though I know her for a long time,
I asked her if she does that several times, if she had been doing that before
and that she can tell you herself.
-I've done that before and sometimes I run back several times to double check
if I switched off the lights and if I put on the brakes.
-If she switches off the stove also?
-Yes, in the kitchen.
-And immediately something connected and I asked her, the next question
that we put to her it was... This was outside.
The next question I asked her was whether she was sympathetic and the doctor friend, she said...
-She is extremely sensitive with our animals or with our friends or when I'm sick
just for a day, she would run over and ask me how my headaches are and she gets scared.
-But what you said actually was very, very, very sympathetic. Right?
After that answer and that little conversation, I said we missed important information.
That information is important and then the little girl said that she did not think
of speaking about these matters, especially double checking because her father is doing that
also all the time. Is that correct?
-Yes, that's true.
-Then the next question that we put to her is whether she is losing urine
while coughing and she replied...
-When I laugh. In former times it has been much more but still nowadays, a little bit.
-And then I asked her about sweets, whether she likes sweets. What was the answer?
-I do like sweets but I don't take them because my symptomatology aggravates.
-Two days after the remedy she developed some herpes on the tip of the nose
but she said she already had some of the side on the tip of the nose,
when she came to Alonissos.
-And thank you very much. You are lucky.
In your computers do you have the case? What did you get?
-Now Causticum.
-Who got Causticum? Everybody.
Very good.
I think we spoke about Causticum and this is my mistake that I did not investigate further
when she said, I get an eruption on the tip of the nose.
That should be enough to investigate more properly the possibility of Causticum.
But I'm tired and my mind is half working.
She says the fourth day starts with diarrhea. What is this?
You can not say anything but the eruption comes in the tip of the nose.
That means the remedy just pushes us and gives us a sign. Causticum, this is the idea.
It's Causticum and then if you don't have your real mind, you lose the case.
Many times it happens like that.
You give the wrong remedy and push the right symptom, out.
That means you are a good/bad prescribed. You are close. That means I'm getting there.
I'm becoming good.
So what shall we do in this case? Forget Gelsemium. The fourth day? Yes the fourth day.
It does not matter. We give Causticum, she will take Causticum.
She will start with Causticum again with the same idea, 200 every day and see what happens.
Every day you have to watch. Where is the doctor?
You watch her in case she has a reaction, whatever.
That was a good demonstration of a bad omission.
I wanted to see this case because according to the reactions she is having,
we can decide to regulate from now on the cortisone enema.
It has to be noted also that since 10 days, she has stopped taking the cortisone orally
and I think it was recorded that she started having diarrhea
in the fifth or sixth day I think.
-She normally started to have diarrhea again when the cortisone went down to 5 mg.
-She started already by the time.
-And enema she took every day always.
-Now how many days she is taking the remedy?
-Since Thursday. it's a week.
-Can she tell us what happened after Causticum?
-The diarrhea stopped already the next day. It was gone completely
and I got an eczema in my face, especially in the morning and the evening
and it looks a little bit like very slight urticaria.
-In the face?
-The whole face, the forehead, the cheeks.
-Now she has a normal stool, formed?
-Yes.
-And how does she feel otherwise?
-Not changed, very normal all together.
-Because she was tired when we took her case, she says I'm always very tired.
How she feels now in this?
-That didn't change. I'm still tired.
-Is she taking Causticum every day?
-Yes three times.
-And also enema every day?
-Yes.
-And she is having the kind of the stool that she had before with the cortisone
or it is more formed,
less formed?
-The same.
-How many mg of cortisone is in the enema?
-It should be written on the box, so we can find out.
-OK, she can start reducing the enema, from half and every day a little bit more,
until in 10 days she will have no enemas and then we can observe while at the same time
she continues to take the Causticum.
In case there is a relapse while she is taking the Causticum, then you go to 1M
and you give every day for more than 10 days, depending on the reaction.
Psychologically she doesn't feel any different?
She is still checking all the time?
-Yes.
-And she had an eruption on the tip of the nose and that was gone after Causticum?
-OK, thank you.