-Tell us last time you were here for main problems. Tell us the main problems.
-I used to have cramps mainly in the night in the calves and pain in the chest
which rises up from the stomach going upwards.
-And in the heart she said.
-Yes in the left side in the heart. I couldn't fall asleep at night because
I had to get up because of the pain in the calf, I needed to walk a little bit.
I began in September with Causticum 7CH and I didn't feel no difference
but my friends around reflected that I seem to be much more relaxed.
I went to 8CH and then I began to feel very tired that I need to sleep all the time.
Because of that I missed a few lectures in the last seminar in Alonissos.
At that time I felt a lot of relief from the death of my father and I even could dance
although I was very tired in the party in the seminar, something which I couldn't believe
I would be able to feel because I have much grief.
After two weeks I went up to the 12CH and then I began to feel very agitated
and nervous about injustice, political, social injustice, in the work, everything
looked to me injustice.
Therefore she sent the (?) at the Academy and for some reason it was not included
in the marks and she sent you a fax very angry, she was very frustrated about it.
In her fax she expressed her injustice about it. It was very bitter.
-She was not included in the marks which she sent, not included?
-I was here in turn 3 and at turn 4 my father died and I couldn't come, so I sent the (?)
with my friend and when I came again at turn 5 I saw that I received no mark
and I said to myself I'm coming here just for studying and I didn't allow it to come up
but when I went back to Israel, then an explosion came up and I couldn't sleep at night,
I was so frustrated and angry, I couldn't sleep.
-By that time she was on 12CH?
-Yes she continued with 12CH. At that time also I belonged to the Union of doctors
in Israel and at that time I began to speak at every meeting and to express my anger
about the injustice because one of the doctors there were doing terrible things.
And until all the problems were resolved I didn't dare to come down here again.
At that time, when I used to drive or walk in the morning, listening to the news
on the radio, I got so angry about Benjamin Netanyahu the ex-Prime Minister,
I was so angry, I used to vibrate, to shiver all over the body.
Then I began to feel that lids in the eyes get itchy and then they became swollen
and then I saw the development of eczema on the eyelids and then I stopped the 12CH.
I saw doctor (?) in Israel and I told him all the symptoms which rise up,
she belongs to a working group in Israel with doctor (?) and while she saw him there
in this group and showed him the symptoms that rise up after the Causticum 12CH
and he told her to take placebo for some time and to write to you the symptoms
and ask your opinion.
So she is asking, if it's so good the reaction, why she feels so bad?
After a few days I took for four days 30CH Causticum and then gradually the cramps
in the calf began to reduce and I could sleep much better and it was even difficult
to rise up in the morning, I slept very deep.
Also gradually the pain in the heart in the left side began to reduce.
After I felt I need to sleep much more than usual and the sleep was very deep
and I need to sleep also during day time. At that time I used to be involved with my
patients, especially the patients who come with a complaint that somebody abuses them
and then I used to shout, don't let them abuse you.
I was surprised for some of them was very useful. They felt much better.
-This is Homeopathy, sympathy.
-After some time, after much long time of carrying many duties and working lots of hours
with patients, I felt that I will collapse because of so much of things that I have to carry
for long time and I couldn't bare it anymore, I felt that I will collapse
and I can't take anymore the stress which comes from different areas of life,
especially the stress that comes from duties and family relations.
So I took Nux vomica one time.
I thought it will fill me with more energy and it helped only for one week,
after one week I was much more going to relapse or stress or lack of energy.
-But she actually did a lot in her work, in her family?
-This is the time when she sent you the fax because she didn't know whether to continue
with the Causticum or not.
I felt most of the time withdrawn from social relations more and more.
Then I received from you a fax to take again the 30CH Causticum and I took only one dose
because I was afraid.
Then after the one dose of Causticum I developed acute flu with very high fever
and this is after two years without any flu or anything.
I had to go to home to rest because of the high fever and for my surprise after 48 hours
I came once more to my energy and I recovered very quickly and after two years I could
go once more to usual activities.
One week after the flu I felt a feeling as if I used to carry a very heavy bag on my back
and then suddenly the feeling was as if the bag is taken out of my bag.
Suddenly I feel so good and so light, I don't know how this feeling feels like and I walk
bend like this because the muscle of the bend did not how to feel free.
Seven years ago I used to have frequently very severe back pain which it came to a condition
that the doctor suggested operation. Then I took a dose of Lil. tigr. and since
then the back pain didn't come until this experience.
And after this experience of the very severe back pain, doctor gave me two weeks of vacation
from the work but for my surprise after three days I recovered spontaneously and could go
to work with good energy, with the help of physiotherapy.
-I didn't follow very well what she said. She said after Causticum, she developed an acute
high fever for two days, after that she felt very good, the energy was good
and then she felt as if a weight was lifted and was out of her back.
-Suddenly, a week after the flu. I was in the evening very weak and I couldn't walk and
I went to lie in bed and after bed one night I woke up and I couldn't go out of bed,
I had to crawl and I go to the orthopedist.
He said me that it's a collapse of the muscle of the back.
All my muscles are not working.
-When it was that?
-One week after the acute. And the doctor gave me twelve days off to treat it.
-She is talking about now or in the past?
-After the severe acute that she recovered very good, one week after that she has
experienced of very severe pain and collapse of the muscles in the back.
-Now, not in the past.
-Now in March.
-And the doctor who saw here gave her 12 days vacation. But in 3 days she recovered.
-This pain was in the past, every year I have for 2 weeks, I have to lie down and year
after year until I was very sick and the orthopedist told me that I have to operate.
-This was his diagnosis before?
-Seven years before.
-She said that after this recovery she felt very free as if a heavy load was lifted,
is that correct?
-Yes. I feel about five days after the flu, I feel very good and my feeling was that
somebody had all the time something very heavy on the back and they put it on and
I can't do what I want. And I felt after the acute that I feel very light, a heavy load was
lifted; then I planned to do many things but then the back...
-Then it came the collapse?
-Yes.
-Now it's clear. Then she recovers from this collapse in the back, she came back
after the collapse...
-In the past it took her two weeks to recover, right now it took her three days to recover.
In April I felt very good feeling and I felt a lot of love to myself and I felt like changing
the hair style, need to buy for myself new things.
All the people around me at work told me that I look so different, that I look so good
and over here at the seminar also everybody is telling me that I look so different
and I look so new and good that even me, myself begin to believe in it.
Right now what is remaining is a pain on the left side at the spleen area.
This pain used to be when I was a medical student and the pain has no pattern.
It comes suddenly and I have to bend like this forward.
-Did she mention this pain last time?
-No.
-This pain when it was there last time? After Causticum she had this pain but I said
before the Causticum, when the pain was?
-When I was a medical student and I was 20 years old. The pain began when I was 20 and
continued for 20 years and it finished a few years ago but I don't remember exactly when.
-Now the pain is back and it's still there at this moment, correct?
-Yes. When I speak or when I'm excited I have itching in my throat and I can't speak.
After Causticum, I used to suffer from cold weather, right now I feel more warm.
In this kind of weather like now I used to wear a jacket, right now I don't need it.
-I would like about the memory.
She had mentioned about the memory that she was forgetting words.
-I tend to forget dates and words and when I speak about the past I don't recall
if it was in last Wednesday or last Tuesday.
When I was young, medical student, I used to be very shy, very timid and for a long time
I used to be alone because of that and right now once more I feel shy and I want to get
close to people, right now I do feel the need to get close to people but I feel shy again.
But before it didn't bother me, right now it is bothering me.
While taking the Causticum, the concentration of the mind is to a less degree.
Right now as well I need to do much effort to usual to concentrate.
-In her work?
-Everything which I'm doing, working or reading or even speaking with people.
I had it in the past but right now it's coming more strongly that while I'm speaking to someone,
suddenly I forget the word and I know the word but the word doesn't come up.
-This is what she has said. (?)
Another thing is, she was mentioning fear of people, how is that?
-In the past I suffered emotionally from people a lot, I was hurt from people a lot
and right now when I want to open up and to get close to somebody, I feel immediately the pain
and I withdraw back. I fear to be hurt and with this as well I feel loneliness and right now
it's much more bothering me than in the past.
-What about the injustice? How is this injustice feeling now, still there or it's reduced?
-Many things make me angry but since it's the past that was gone away, I feel good.
But I don't outburst.
-Cramps, how are they?
-In the last six months I had only two attacks from cramps where I had to wake up in the night
and walk for twenty minutes and the pain was much worse than the past attacks
but it was only two in the last six months.
Before Causticum I used to wake up almost every night because of the cramp and the pain.
-Also she has said that she has fear of animals. She didn't notice if this continues.
-When I see a dog I have to go around to cross the street, even for a small dog.
-This cough which she had just now how long she has this?
-Before the Causticum because of the cigarettes I used to have every once for a while
coughing attack but after the Causticum, I don't remember in which potency it began,
it's quite a lot the coughing all the time, each day and not in a special situation.
Only if I speak or I'm excited.
-Also I don't remember we have noticed here stammering speech,
I don't notice now stammering.
-If I was excited or shy I used to repeat one word many times because I couldn't remember the word.
-And now she has this?
-No but I speak much less with people so I can't know.
-The finger nails also she said they are very strong.
-Yes, very strong.
-Still strong?
-Even the scissors are breaking because of the nails.
-And the sweets still she does not like them?
-Not very much.
-Salt?
-More. I didn't notice but other people noticed that I put a lot of salt and without this
large amount of salt I feel as if the food has no taste.
-So much?
-Yes, she needs to put much salt.
-Emotionally how she is now?
-My energy is very high and I want to get closer to people.
-But she has a lot of emotions? That means the emotions have started coming strong?
-In the beginning all this emotional channeled to my daughter and I was angry expressing
a lot of anger towards her but right now I even brought her with me here in Greece and
I have very good relationship now.
-She is a pediatrician. She sees only children or she sees cases?
-She is a family doctor and a homeopath, she has two clinics.
One as usual family doctor in the government hospital and one private clinic as homeopath.
-But she sees grown-ups or only children?
-In the morning only children, in the afternoon as a family doctor all kinds of people and
in the evening as homeopath in my home place.
-She works too much.
-I enjoy it.
-You enjoy it? Do you feel more close to children or in your patients?
-To children. I can help more easily.
-How is this sympathetic element?
-I feel my patients, not all of them but I feel them and sometimes I'm asking questions
to my patients and even me I'm amazed that I know much more than they say.
-Does she have any time to take a nap in between? I want to know how she feels if she
takes a nap in the afternoon. How she wakes up.
-I feel very bad if I sleep in the daytime taking a nap and my body intends to collect
electrical static, especially in my hair. If I touch my hair, the hair will stand.
I changed my haircut because otherwise they will stand because I feel my body has electricity
and I can't touch... When I examine children the child will jump because of the electricity.
-What she says about the hair happens if she has a nap in the afternoon?
-If I take a nap in the afternoon I feel very bad as if I'm not in the situation, it takes me
a long time to come back to myself and I feel generally bad.
-How many children she has?
-One and two grand children.
-Her husband, she is divorced?
-She didn't get along with his wife that's where she got divorced.
He got married with her best girlfriend.
-Can she now tell us if she suppressed her anger from time to time?
-Yes. I have to because if I explode on my work it's not good. The main issue that I'm
afraid to explode and to express my anger is the relationship with my mother.
She used to make a lot and very painful and bad things to me and right now I'm taking care of her
and it's something which is very difficult for me to stop the anger which is all the time.
My mother has somebody to take care of her which I'm paying for this and she does not
do nothing at all to support that thing.
-And that makes her very angry but she withholds herself. She does not say anything.
She lives with her mother?
-I took care of my father when he died and then I took my mother to my place because
of my mother I couldn't give children anymore, in the past.
After the first child while I was a student in the medical school, I got pregnant again
and my mother began to shout at me.
You don't need a child anymore, don't bring a child, you don't need it right now and
she called her doctor, the doctor lived in Romania and she called the doctor to her house
and the mother told her that she just wants to give her a shot just to calm her down and
the shot was anesthetic shot to make her do the abortion without she knowing about this.
And the abortion was on the kitchen table in her house.
The mother asked the doctor to twist the uterus so she wont' be able to get pregnant once more
and only when she took care of the father and the father died only then she discovered that thing.
When I came to Israel I did all sorts of things to get pregnant but I couldn't and I think this
is one of the reason why I divorced my husband.
Because I couldn't bear children anymore and I was very angry and I came to my mother
to ask her, why you did this to me, why you didn't tell my, why you killed my child.
I told her you are a killer, you are amurderer, why did you do it? And the mother replied,
I did it because if you have less children you'll have more time to treat me and this is what
is going on right now.
Right now she is taking care of the mother and because of this she has a lot of anger.
After taking the Causticum 3-4 times I decided to send my mother once more to Romania
to elder house where people will take care of her but my consciousness doesn't allow me
to do it, I can't do it although she never really helped me to grow up, my grand mother
grew me but my mother never involved in my growth. This is part of my life.
The thing that I see her every day and I have to treat her and see her every day rise up in
me so much anger and emotions that I think I have to take every month the Causticum.
-We'll take care of the anger. Reduce it. She will have a relapse if she stays like that.
-After taking the Causticum 30C, I felt to do things for myself and I didn't feel anymore
guilty to do things for myself and not to take care of my mother.
Always I had some kind of guilt, why do you take care of yourself, why don't you take
care of your mother?
And now I feel good with it. In my mind always there is the thinking that I want to kill her
and only because of this thought I'm afraid so much that I take care of her more and more.
Shall I tell you a secret, yes or no, I'm thinking? I'll tell you my experience,
it's an observation which happens with this type of Homeopathy, where you prescribe after
studying the case.
There is a certain phenomenon that takes place that things seem to have a kind of a harmony
of another dimension, a kind of order which happens with the prescription of the remedies.
That means the person comes and gives you a story and gives you in information
and you prescribe correctly.
Next time he comes and gives you similar story but something deeper, something which reveals
to you the deeper level and how things are unraveling and unblocking and lifted the heaviness,
as she described.
If she had given this story from the very beginning, what should we do?
And it was very interesting in the end I turn around and I say to Margaret, show me what
you have been putting and I would like to show you. It's very interesting.
The two remedies that stand out very prominently Causticum and Staphysagria.
So what shall we do in such a case?
Is now the time for Staphysagria or do we have to wait or do we have to give a higher Causticum?
There are some Causticum symptoms like aversion to sweets, desire salt.
What is the right thing to do in such a case? Where you have symptoms of the previous
remedy still but you have some symptoms of another remedy which is complementary to
the previous one.
In order to decide let's take a hypothetical situation where we let...
we say wait a few months, see what happens. We let this organism under this stress of
anger which is suppressed, where is it going to go?
Most probably is she going to have a relapse?
Most probably she is going to have a relapse and the relapse will be back in Causticum.
The cramps will start, the closeness.
What was the most dangerous symptom for her, if you remember, you got some person
who didn't care to live or die. Life was going away. Now she starts coming back to life
and the fact that she has so strong feelings against the mother are now strong feelings
but dangerous, dangerous to the point where they can bring about a relapse.
Therefore if we have enough symptoms for Staphysagria, we have to prescribe Staphysagria
and most probably there is going to be another round which we will need again Causticum
and perhaps higher.
So this is the case where we say, Causticum and Staphysagria are complementary
and they may come around.
Causticum and Staphysagria a few times before she is unloaded with this experience which is
a terrifying experience of course.
Because I never had parents, so I felt so independent all the time and these things I hear
are beyond my comprehension, I don't understand because I don't understand the connection,
how a mother can have such an influence upon a child or do this or has the authority upon the child.
My mind can't follow because I don't have the experience.
I don't have the connection. I don't know, you have the connection? Your mother can do
such things to you, I don't know.
It's beyond logic and she said I did it in order that you take care of me in the old age,
calculating in such a way!
Making a murder and now she is in a position now where she will feel bad even if she sends her
to the house of the aged.
-I would like to make an observation that perhaps because the nature of the relapse that
another remedy of similar action perhaps being introduced and I'm thinking in terms of Nat. mur.
Because the hatred, the anger, there is similar action to Causticum.
There is this tremendous fear of dogs and all the ailments from the anger and the indignation,
the same as Staphysagria but now she also wants the company which not that it comes out in
first level but still comes out desire for company, aggravation for being alone, the need for salt
and this hate, the estrangement from family members, the aversion to certain persons and so on.
-Nat. mur. will not do anything, almost anything for this case because is we say what is
the main problem at this moment with this organism, is the suppression of anger.
So you have to take suppression of anger underline it 4 times and then take it into
consideration and then see what happens. Also she says, if I sleep in the afternoon
I get up very bad state, also another Staphysagria and you don't need further symptomatology
to go along and prescribe the complementary of Causticum which is
Staphysagria. Staphysagria has to be given to reduce the anger, she will get Staphysagria,
not that she will forget but this type of anger which reaches almost the limits because she says,
I feel I could kill her.
This is the limit because you stay sane and you don't kill her. This is a limit situation
so we have to reduce this anger by Staphysagria. The problem is what potency?
Very high, medium or low?
-High.
-Low.
-Let me see your opinion. 30? 200? 1M? 10M? 50M? CM? We leave it for later.
High, yes. 10M I think it's enough.
It is very interesting also to observe how diseases are produced through these very deep traumas.
It was very interesting also for me the reaction she had to Causticum.
It is unusual. What is unusual? She takes the remedy and she has this acute, then she feels
extremely well, then the muscle collapse. So all the problem of the organism which
leaves the emotional, goes to the body and paralyses the body and then fortunately
she will recover quickly.
You see also the confirmation of these observations which I have made all along
these years, every case almost will have to go through this type of confirmation before
you can say they change level.
Change level is a big thing in Homeopathy, between I feel better
and my symptoms are better and between I have this evolution.
Thank you very much.