Case study 003
Thank you! Thank you for your warm welcome
and I would also like to welcome you
all and wish you a period that may be
significant for the rest of your life.
As I have been informed a lot of you are coming from
the first time in Homeopathy and you have been already
medical doctors for years, practicing conventional medicine,
you may find it difficult to adapt in the beginning.
I want to know from which countries
you are coming from so I will ask
from the furthest part which is the
United States. How many people?
And is anybody coming from South America? Europe,
Germany? England? Not in this course. Australia? Is
anybody who is coming from another country? Romania?
This is a Romanian course! Very good. From? Russia!
Who else is from Russia? Only one. All Russians are gone.
Last seminar we had the invasion of Greece by Israelis.
They were the majority in the class. This time the
Romanians are coming. Very good. I see some changes.
I could not recognize you. What happened to you? You
became a rabbi? Of high order? You didn’t do anything?
It just grew. I agree with your beard. I don’t think
your wife will agree. Usually wives don’t like it.
That’s why I don’t have a beard. I never had a
beard. What shall I say, it’s very difficult
because some people here are, for instance Steve
is attending the full course for the third time,
I don’t know why but anyhow, there are some people,
Romanian also that are very knowledgeable and there
are some absolute newcomers. So I want to know who
the newcomers to Homeopathy are. Raise your hand.
I have to adapt my teaching. I have
to say a few things for the medical
doctors who are coming for the first time.
I will just give you an example.
A periarthritis, if it is on the left side,
the remedies that may cure such a condition
are different from the ones indicated if
the periarthritis is on the right side.
This already makes the individualization of the case,
makes Homeopathy a bit difficult. Because every time
you will have to decide on the indicated remedy according
to the totality of the symptoms that a person has.
When I say the totality I do not mean the
physical symptoms on the physical body, I
also mean conditions and situations referring
to the mental or emotional side of us.
In every case we have to take into consideration
whether together with the periarthritis there is
an anxiety state, an irritable organism who is
very easily irritated and immediately explodes,
we have to take into consideration whether there are some digestive disorders,
we have to take into consideration whether this person has constipation
or diarrhea alternating, whether with this periarthritis there is also a
colitis,there is anger kept inside, whether there is grief kept inside.
Because we understand that a human organism is a
living being who has be subjected along his life
from the moment he was born to the point where he
comes to you as a patient, to a lot of stresses.
His organism was able to deal with these stresses
so far, either in good, positive way where
he got rid of the effect of the stress or if the
stress has left its marks upon this organism.
For those that may know theoretically what a
stress is, Cellier, a Canadian doctor, I think
was the first one who spoke about stress in
general and the effect of it upon the human body.
So it is now accepted in Medicine that stress of
whatever kind especially if the stress is on mental or
emotional level can create a situation in the body
where it starts compromising its possibility to react.
A stress within the organism, if it stays for a long
time, eventually will create a pathology which we
may recognize as arthritis, colitis, ulcerative
colitis, autoimmune disease, neuromuscular disease etc.
but there is always a time where the disturbance
starts and from there on the organism is
compromised, his immune system is compromised.
It’s not going to deal well with this stress.
The stress can be mental, emotional, you lost
your job, you lost your child, you lost your
beloved one and anyhow it is mostly connected
with some kind of loss of something you loved.
And this stress will have an effect and the immediate
effect of the loss is… we cry. If we cry this
is a defense of the organism that by crying we
allow the organism slowly to come back to normal.
If we don’t cry, if we keep it inside, most probably there
is going to be a problem and the problem will manifest
after a year or two or three etc. That’s why the homeopath
will take into consideration all these phenomena.
Maybe I will shock you a little bit saying this;
the fact that we give to the children today a
whole lot series of vaccinations which are
addressing themselves exactly to the immune system,
the idea is preparing the immune system
so that it will be able to deal with
the specific epidemic disease, that
is the theory behind the vaccination.
We create antibodies and therefore the organism
will be able to deal with that, but if you give 10
vaccinations together you create confusion in the immune
system which does not know anymore what to do first.
As a result we have studies that showed
that after immunization we have severe
conditions many times quite severe like autism
or we may have neuromuscular disorders.
The French have done a research concerning the vaccination
for Hepatitis B in which it was found out that there were
quite a lot of cases of Guillain–Barré syndrome which
creates a kind of paralysis which may or may not be cured.
In view of this introduction which is quite theoretical
and some of you may agree or not I thought
I will present to you a case of a child which
I had seen back in 1983 in the United States.
I will give an introduction so you may
understand what happened with the child.
I was teaching, I had a class like you in Berkley and
suddenly one of the students said I have a case of a child
in the hospital who had chickenpox (varicella) and he’s
in the hospital diagnosed with varicella cerebellitis,
it’s a complication of varicella that inflames the cerebellum
and there is a paralysis. And this little boy, 6 years
old, was in the hospital supported by saline intravenously
because he could not eat, swallow, neither water nor food,
he was exhausted, he was about for 15 days in that
condition, they asked me whether I would agree
to take the child from the hospital and bring it
to me to see the child in front of the students.
I agreed and see what I can do.
The child was brought and
I will just show you the
condition in which the child is.
The time is 11 o’clock Friday morning and they brought
it straight from the hospital and the child because
it was treated by some of my students had received
several remedies already, which had no effect.
So the child is really in a bad condition and I will just
show you how he was when he came. The child has lost
a lot of weight these 15 days. He sits quietly all the
time like this? – Yes. He’s been more animated today.
– He likes company? He likes somebody next to him?
– …Although he will pull away. - He will pull
away if somebody goes near? – Not all the time…
- How are you? – Good. - He can hardly speak.
This is the situation and it is a case in which the
doctors that they have attended they have given me all
the remedies they have given so far. The remedies that
were given were targeted towards general paralysis.
So we have certain remedies that are active in paralysis.
These remedies had been given but with no effect.
So when they bring the child the first thing I see is
that his inner state is one of exhaustion on one hand,
and at the same time of sadness; there is a
deep sadness in this little boy which is
impressive for me. I said to myself
immediately how come that this boy is so sad?
When I asked the doctor who was attending she said it is because
he realizes he cannot walk and therefore he is sad. I didn’t buy
that. Because a boy, it doesn’t matter whether he can walk or not,
his inner state can be joyful and still he may not walk at all.
You realize the importance of the paralysis. So
I had to investigate what had happened to the
boy and came to that state. Because the information
is he had varicella and then complication.
Varicella went deeper, created and inflammation of the
cerebellum. The question that we always ask is how and
why an organism can accept something which is usual as
an epidemic disease and can deal with that quite easily
why he accepts to give up his defense and accept
to have such an inflammation on a much deeper
level. So after that all my investigation is
to understand what has happened to the boy.
What I have found out is that the boy is
living with his mother because she had
separated with the father and this is something
which is not realized by the mother,
that maybe this separation has anything to do with the condition
of the child, she is not aware of that at all, so she
does not pay attention, so when I ask and I say to her did
the boy watch some discord between you and your husband
she mumbled something I could not understand, I insisted to
understand what had happened in order to, finally, tell me after
much provocation that she and her husband are living in a state
in which I explain to Jacob and Jacob had understood the state.
What is the state exactly? They were living in
another house. Jacob had left the house of the
father, she has a boyfriend and she has taken Jacob
to live in the same house with her boyfriend.
Usually, in the U.S. there is no something peculiar.
What is peculiar is that here we have a child
who is sensitive and who receives this information.
She says “I spoke to Jacob and he understands”.
What he understands probably is not known to the mother.
Jacob understands some things which he does not say
to the mother. I investigated the situation further and
I found out that this epidemic happened 15 days ago
and the mother had to
go on a seminar like
you, I hope you didn’t
leave your little one,
and she said to Jacob who was with varicella and
fever, “Jacob it’s ok, I am going for 3 days,
don’t worry, everything is going to be alright…”
and she leaves the boy to go to the seminar.
Then I investigate further and I
find out that the boy had been
vaccinated a few months ago and there
was no reaction to the vaccination.
The information which comes to me
and I evaluate is that this boy
has been already in a state of grief
because of what has happened,
when the mother left the house with the boy to live with
her boyfriend and it’s very interesting, you will not
understand this point but I will tell you, asked “does
Jacob eat fruits?”. She said no he doesn’t like fruits.
I said do you remember since when he stopped eating fruits? She said
from the moment we changed house, from we moment I took Jacob to
that particular house where Jacob found himself instead of having
his mother and father he was having the mother with her boyfriend.
From that moment Jacob stopped eating fruits. Now, what
is interesting for us is that if an organism stops
eating fruits, it’s a signal that some changes have
taken place which are due, most probably, to grief.
You may ask why grief should make an
organism not wanting fruits? We don’t know.
We don’t know the physiology of that but it is a fact
that if you have been in grief yourself you may remember
the same phenomenon but it is a very well-known phenomenon
that grief if it goes towards a particular direction
which we call ‘silent grief’ that means a grief
during which you cannot express your emotions
at all. You keep everything inside. If this happens
then the remedy which is needed is Ignatia.
The remedy for me was Ignatia but then I had to confirm
it, the aversion to fruits is not enough to give Ignatia.
Ignatia must have some other conditions, as well, one
of which is chorea, where the body moves automatically…
if a person who has chorea needs Ignatia
then he is better lying down, as soon as he
sits he starts moving. That is characteristic
of Ignatia as well. This was confirmed.
Later on I asked the mother to lift the
child and make the child sit on her lap and
after a while the child started feeling
uncomfortable. I asked what do you want, Jacob.
He said I want to lie down because he was
feeling much better when he was lying
down. The aggravation on sitting is
another symptom that confirmed Ignatia.
So we had this boy that one and a half year
ago he entered a state of grief which we
call silent grief because he was not able to
express grief to the mother or to anybody,
this boy staying with the boyfriend without
telling anything to anybody, already
his immune system started compromising,
started becoming weaker and weaker.
An immune system which after grief cries with deep
cries, sighs it can release eventually itself. If
this is kept inside, it shows an immune system that
is compromised already, cannot express the grief.
That was going on for one and a half year, already. Then
comes the varicella and after a few days because the
remedy was not found, the remedies given were outside of
the range of this disease, because of this condition,
this boy’s immune system allowed the inflammation to
go to the cerebellum. Quite a serious condition. So it
is Friday 11 o’clock as I said, the boy could not eat
or drink, so I go to the class, I analyze the case,
I decide the remedy is Ignatia 1M, high potency
of Ignatia and then we have the evening session
and by 8 o’clock in the night, I remember, I
asked the doctor who had brought the boy,
I said please call the mother and ask her whether the boy
can now eat, swallow. She calls and she says that the boy
is eating, drinking and asking for food all the time, from
11 o’clock in the morning till 8 o’clock in the evening.
I said ok because if the boy continued not
eating and outside from saline he would
be in tremendous danger, unless the remedy
has immediately acted, we could not wait,
we would have to take him back to the hospital
because the boy had to be supported by intravenous
saline otherwise he would be totally dehydrated,
not being able to eat or drink anything.
Therefore I was very anxious what had happened,
if the remedy has acted. Fortunately the remedy
was correct. It was a weekend, we did not have
a class and I wanted to see the boy on Monday.
So you will see the boy on Monday morning and you
will see what happened. How is he? – You can see,
yeah? –He is much better. – Shortly after we left
here, on Friday he felt better. – That’s interesting.
Because she is a mother, she does not know Homeopathy,
just brought the child to Homeopathy, shortly after
receiving the remedy the child felt better, so this
is something that you will experience a lot of times.
Here is a case which is acute and in acute cases you will
experience this much more. Immediately after the remedy
there is a sense of being better. In computers you make
a reset of it and the computer comes back into balance.
This is the feeling that you will have and you
will be described by the patient in case you are
giving the correct remedy. The child had received
6 wrong remedies before without any effect.
This is the problem and that’s why I said in
the beginning it may be a little bit difficult
this but once you investigate, once you
understood the global situation of the boy,
where you did not have to take into consideration
only the fact that he was paralyzed
and he could not swallow, but you take into
consideration his mental-emotional state,
then you will be able to see the remedy
because Ignatia is a remedy that is
almost a specific for grief which is
kept inside. Secret. They cannot cry.
If you ask them they will say I cannot cry and what
happens, another characteristic is that they feel a
constriction in the throat that cannot be overcome and it
is almost painful. It’s like a tightness in the throat.
You know you may have felt it, all of you, when you had some kind of
emotional trauma or you wanted to cry and you do not allow yourself to
cry, then you feel a tightness around the thyroid and this tightness is
constriction after grief which is a characteristic of Ignatia, as well.
That’s why, when you have cases of
thyroid swelling, of whatever type,
if it comes after grief one of the
remedy you may be using is Ignatia.
Another is Natrum muriaticum which is a
complementary to Ignatia and you may need two or
three remedies even, later on. It’s Monday
and the boy is still not walking properly.
He is wambling a little bit still and he is
not steady. What else you can still notice
is that is his eyes there is still the idea
of sadness. It’s not a happy boy, yet.
If Ignatia acts it will act in such a way that will
bring back the joy to the child. On Monday we will see
what he says. – When did his appetite return? – Next
day, pretty much. – And that was Saturday, right? – Yes.
– And how it went? His appetite just returned
to normal? – More than normal. He wanted to
eat constantly. On Saturday he ate all day…
- You see his eye. The grief is still there.
What is interesting is when I asked the doctor to call
the mother the same evening she said the child is asking
constantly for food but I am afraid to give it because
the child had much time to eat and the mother was afraid
that she will give all the food that the child
is asking maybe it will damage him,then she
said, the next day, pretty much. But actually
the child was asking for food the same evening.
The child was able to eat but she said
to the doctor I am careful not to give
him as much food as he is asking. But
the child had a very good appetite.
What is interesting I want you to observe the eyes
because the treatment here is not that the child gets
over the possibility of having a damage more permanent.
The idea is that the child may get out of the grief.
And that is the most important issue with Homeopathy, a
reset, the organism will come back to its normal state as
long as the organism has the possibility but let’s see a
little bit more. -…And he was very pleased. Let me try!
And then I told Vicky he was talking about pizza, spaghetti,
meatballs… -When did he get up and started walking? – On
Saturday he wanted to move the wheelchair, we put him in the
wheelchair and then he started moving the wheelchair around.
And he got a good sense of control with that. And then
shortly, I think that evening, he wanted to crawl out of the
wheelchair to his bed, and then he would crawl into the
wheelchair himself. –It was Saturday evening, already.
When did he stand on his legs? It was it on yesterday
or today? -Sunday. – And he walked a little bit or…? –
He walked with help. Then he strained standing on his
own in the afternoon and just standing testing it out.
This feels good, I can stand up! Is that right, Jacob?
– How do you feel, Jacob? – Good! – You are happy
now? Yes? Do you remember how you were before? How?
Can you describe? –Sad. – This is very important.
Because the child can say now, I was sad. That means he
was really realizing how he was in comparison to what he
is now. How you feel? Good! He is not good, yet. You will
see later on when he is really good how he will behave.
Still there is that background of sadness. You
don’t know. Now you have a good appetite? Yes.
What would you like to eat now? - Everything. –
What about ice cream? Yes. Sweets? –Sort of.
- What about fruits? Do you like fruits?
He likes fruits. – We have been giving him lots of protein
shakes, blended protein powder, fruit juice and yoghurt.
– Has he been able to run at all? – Yeah. He ran across
the kitchen. He made a goal for himself to the wall,
then he ran to the wall. Like a little person would
run if he was trained to. In fact his little friend
Kellen who just turned 1 year old she, with her mother's
help, showed Jacob how she was learning to walk,
so that’s how he started to walk.
Cause we noticed how
she kept her balance. – You
understand what happened?
An one-year-old girl came and taught him how to stand, she
showed how she was standing one year old and then he was
testing it the same he was able to stand up. It is very
interesting. – Jacob, do you remember seeing any dream?
Yes? You saw a dream? Do you remember the dream? –It’s about
that tooth came out. –That’s a very interesting point. I
don’t know why I asked him. I can’t remember now. It’s about
35 years ago. But he said about that tooth that came out.
That means something of his own that he lost. For me the explanation
was the deeper acceptance of the boy losing his father. Losing
something belonging to him, he has accepted in a subconscious level,
this fact which the mother was trying to persuade him long time ago.
Jacob, it will be alright if we go there… He said ok. It was
not ok, he would not speak. Now, as the organism comes back,
I don’t know by what mechanism, is on the subconscious level,
that he sees a dream that he lost something of his own.
Part of him. I explain it as the acceptance of the loss
of his father. – And did he go out to play at all or he
has stayed in the house so far? – He went out to stay
where his father lives in the country so I don’t know,
did you go out and play? – Yes… - What did he say? –
Near the manor, there is this big huge estate house
and there is a very big eucalyptus tree, so he played
under the tree. – Do you like salty things? No.
Sweets you like? Sort of, he said. But
what about meat? Fish? You like. Are you
thirsty? You drink a lot? Not really.
– He doesn’t want to drink anything…
- What I am trying to do here is find out
whether there are some indications for the next
remedy because I am afraid that if there is a
relapse maybe the same remedy will not do,
we may need to give a deeper remedy and I am trying to
find out through this questioning whether there are any
indication that the next remedy will be this or that. I am
investigating Phosphorus, Natrum muriaticum possibilities.
I could not find any possibility and then I
asked to see the child 20 days later. So what
you are going to see now is about 20 days
later. Here is the mother with the boyfriend.
You will see how the child reacts in spite of the fact
that the boyfriend of the mother is present. The boy has
come back to normal which is the normal state of children,
when they are healthy, is to be happy no matter what.
Even they have one hand less or one leg less
whatever the natural state of child is to be happy.
So you will see how happy this child is in front
of the mother’s boyfriend. He is playing.
He enjoys, he does not know he is being filmed.
Also you will see he looks to the boyfriend with
no reaction. He provokes the mother to play with
him. I ask him the time and, see, he answers.
I try to show whether mentally the child is ok,
emotionally you can see, it is obvious, the child has
come back to the state of being happy again, but whether
mentally he has been affected, it’s not at all,
but I will ask him some mathematics later on. – I have
some mathematical questions. What class are you now?
First grade or second grade? First grade. Can you add
for me 4 plus 4? -4 plus for, it’s easy. It’s 8.
100 plus 100, 200! – Can you add 1000 and 3000? – 4000.
– You are very good in mathematics! Are you happy now?
Ok. I wonder really, children with psychotherapy… how
long would it take to bring that state. This is 21 days.
The child is in normal state. And this
kind of therapy, so effective, so
precise, so natural, yet is fought
against, viciously for many years.
You are aware that something is going on but this kind of
Homeopathy which is precise, because there is Homeopathy
which is easy… Which Homeopathy is easy? For instance, you
have paralysis, which are the remedies for paralysis?
It’s Causticum, Plumbum, Cocculus etc. You
take all of them, you give them and you
have some effect. It just doesn’t work.
It will work for some cases, sometimes,
but this kind of effect
where you have a real reset
of the organism will never
come with easy Homeopathy.
You will be learning all this science and I
hope you will be successful in your prescribing
by applying what you are learning but do not
expect to have immediately impressive results.
Sometimes you will but not in all cases because most
of the cases today are difficult to treat because they
have gone deeper into the human organism. What we call
autoimmune diseases, neuromuscular diseases, cancer etc.
All these deep chronic diseases need a long time of
treatment and very correct treatment in every stage.
I would like you now for some minutes to ask questions
that you may already have by listening so far.
Who is translating Romanian? Who can understand my
English? Who cannot understand my English? So why do
you raise your hands since you cannot understand my
English? You understand a little bit! Only 3 people.
Ask them, the Romanians that do not understand
my English. No Romanian is raising his hand.
That means… 3! Only 3. Romanians are preparing
themselves entering the European Union.
Wait and see what happens if you enter the E.U. More
or less, you are like Greece, most of the people know
some English but… we will see. I would like to hear your
comments, your questions, whatever you like to ask.
Don’t be shy. – My question is when you gave the
potency, 1M, was it because it was the mental
level that had to be rectified first before
physical? – Yes. I realized that the whole problem…
it was a problem that mental and
emotional level was involved.
The mental and emotional side
of the child was involved.
If you see the whole case you will see that child was
lying there for 1 hour or more, totally silent and if you
look at his eyes you will see that they were looking
beyond, not to me or anybody, were looking the eternity.
It was the look of a child in deep depression. Not
interested to talk, I provoked him, how do you
feel, good, leave me alone. I said sit down. What
do you want? I want to lie down, that’s all.
Lie down, don’t talk, like all the deep depressive cases that
they want to just lie down, close the windows, be in a dark
place, stay by themselves, looking inside not being able to
face the world, because the immune system is compromised.
Does not have energy, does not have power to react.
When somebody is reacting even violently he is much
better for us because we see there is energy, this is
much better than somebody who cannot react at all.
– Can you explain me why you did not give
Phosphoric acid to him? Is it because the child had
difficulty of swallowing or…? – I’ll tell you the
difference between Ignatia and Phosphoric acid.
Phosphoric acid is also a remedy that has deep
depression but the difference is that Phosphoric acid
desires fruits. One of the main symptoms of Phosphoric
acid is that wants to eat fruits and juice fruits.
So the child had aversion to fruits. So the mind cannot go to
Phosphoric acid anymore. I understand that there is a grief and
Phosphoric acid is one of the remedies that you are thinking in
depression but the organism needs in order to survive fruit juices.
– As I understood the child had a specific sensitivity
to this kind of stress, did Ignatia make him less
sensitive to this kind of stress even though the
situation in the family remains the same? Is it true?
– As long as I understood, she asks if
the constitutionally the child after
the remedy remained as sensitive as
before or less. – Less sensitive.
The fact that the grief was so deep for the boy, the
boy felt I lose my father now, because they take the
child put him on another house with a boyfriend,
what is this situation? It’s a shock for this child.
The child goes into that state which is very
sensitive state. The remedy will bring back to his
normal, healthy, state. When he is under the grief,
it’s a very sensitive boy because the mother…
I also forgot to tell you the mother told him that listen,
all these years, I had taken the decision to be with
you and not go to work for 3 years. So she told him here
I am for almost 6 years and I have to go now to work.
That was one thing she said to the boy. The other was while
he was having fever the mother said now I have to go to a
seminar, this is ok. The boy said it is ok but it was in a
state of Ignatia, the organism was in a sensitive state.
If now the mother says to him I will go to a seminar,
there is no problem. Unless it is a very big stress
again to bring back a relapse the boy can withstand
any kind of reaction like a healthy human being.
I will also give you another information about the
boy, because I called about 18 or 20 years later, I
spoke with the doctor who brought the boy, I asked how
is Jacob and she said I never gave another remedy.
Jacob remained well. That means a good constitution,
if you want to know. We come to the conclusion that
his constitution was good and that is why he presented
such a clear picture for me and for any homeopath
because the stronger a constitution is the
clearer the indications for the remedy
are. They give out clear signals. It’s
like saying give me Calcarea carbonica.
The little ones they cry out, how do they say give
me Calcarea carbonica? Because the mother says
he is asking me for soft-boiled eggs all the
time. Soft-boiled eggs contain a lot of calcium.
So the organism says give me soft-boiled eggs and there
is another peculiarity; when calcium is disturbed
there, usually, is a perspiration which is around the
neck, on the upper body. And there are cold extremities.
The whole body becomes cold. All these are
signals that say I need Calcarea carbonica.
– Regarding the pathology, do you think it
was really encephalitis or cerebellitis due
to the virus or it was more a kind of
cataleptic state induced by repeated shocks?
– It is known that varicella can create
an inflammation of the cerebellum.
So I believe it was really a viral
infection which brought the state.
Of course, if we want to examine it from a theoretical
point of view we know that i.e. Ignatia brings about a
state of paralysis but it is usually hysterical. In this
case it is not hysterical because the boy is with fever,
has varicella, is diagnosed and then he goes to
cerebellitis. The moment he stops being able to swallow and
the extremities are paralyzed you know that the case
is going towards an inflammation of the cerebellum.
So in this case really it was unusual that one would
think of Ignatia. What I was lucky to see it was that
the boy was in a state of sadness. Deep sadness. I
immediately realized it by the way the boy was looking.
It’s not natural for a
boy to look so sad. Not
outside but in the inside.
I was impressed…