-Tell me what happened? Did she have an accident? Did she fall down?
-I have no idea what happened? I had no accident, nothing of that kind, I could
imagine it might have been a draft or something but actually there is nothing.
-So she just woke up like this morning or is it from yesterday?
-It's since Friday evening.
-Where does she feel the pain?
-It's mainly on the right side on the sacral region. Yesterday it moved a bit to the middle
but then it went back to the right side and today I feel the entire bone structure on the
right side, I feel the pain.
-And she can not walk? She walks very difficult?
-Yes, it's difficult to put weight on my right leg. It's painful and I also have the fear that
the leg might collapse under me.
-She had this incident before in her life?
-Yes, it's many years back so I don't have exact memory of how it was precisely but
I remember also it was very difficult for me and once I had injection for it.
Once it happened after I had a treatment with a dentist, which lasted for hours and
I was in such a tension that after the treatment finished, I also had this.
Maybe that also has to do that I have quite a severe scoliosis.
-What are the modalities of the pain?
-It gets worse towards the end of the night. This morning I woke at 3 o'clock with strong
pain and I could hardly turn anymore. I can not lie on my left side, I can not lie on my
back; if I lie on the right side, it gets a bit better.
And it's really bad in the mornings when I have to get up, I can hardly leave my bed and
in the morning hours the pain is very severe.
And yesterday I was so exhausted that I slept at home at 2-2,30 and from 3,30 p.m. on
it got worse, all by itself without me having done anything.
And on Saturday I had a phase that I felt so much better that I dared to go swimming.
Swimming did not aggravate and also walking back to the beach did not aggravate also
not taking a shower afterwards but after all that was over, it's started getting worse again
and that also was around 3,30-4 o' clock but I'm not sure it was because that was the
aggravation time or due to swimming. I can't tell you.
-As I see, she can not go to the bathroom by herself, she has to be supported.
-Yes, since Saturday afternoon it really got bad. I need help.
-By one person or by two persons.
-I guess I would have managed with one person but they are just so caring souls
around me that I had two.
-Movement aggravates.
-Yes, if I have to raise myself. Sometimes it gets better after walking for a long period
of time and concerning your question about turning in bed, it's extremely difficult
hardly possible and I really have to support myself with the hand, all the time, if I turn.
I have to use my hands to turn my leg with me, when I turn in bed, very difficult.
-While she is sitting now, she has pain?
-Sitting is one of the best possibilities. If I sit very quietly, I only have a remaining
sensation of soreness but hardly any pain.
-Any kind of movement is much worse?
-Yes.
And any motion aggravates, even coughing aggravates.
-Sneezing, laughing?
-I didn't laugh very much either.
-You are afraid to laugh.
There is any special desire or aversion or thirst?
-Right now, since it's happened, my thirst is not so large
and I hardly have any appetite at all, it's almost impossible to eat anything.
Yesterday, I felt hungry some time during the day because I have not eaten anything
during the entire day and then Hannah prepared some food for me.
Even though I had been hungry, I couldn't eat anything.
When I saw the food, the hunger disappeared.
-Not when she smells.
-I hardly have any sense of smell in general. They once did a test on me
and found out that I do have some remaining smell but these every day smells
I do not realize I can not smell them.
-Was ever suffering with hemorrhoids?
The cold or heat does affect her?
-At the moment I feel more hot in general and I perspire a lot and I was told that
the perspiration stings.
My toes are cold and if I put a hot water bottle in the area of the pain, that ameliorates.
-Any pressure there?
-I feel no pressure, the feeling is more a feeling of soreness and if I apply pressure it aggravates.
2-3 times I had a kind of chill.
-Any constipation?
-Only yesterday.
The days before, the stool in the beginning was harder than usual and then turned soft.
My stool situation always has to do with the amount of drink.
Yesterday I did not drink much, I slept most of the day and that's why I probable had problems;
the less I drink, the more I'm constipated and that finally turns into headache in general.
-Is there any dryness in the mouth?
-Yes and also a very bad taste along with it.
-Does she need to water her mouth all the time?
-Yes, that's the reason I'm drinking right now, not because I'm thirsty
but because I want to get rid of the bad taste and the dryness in my mouth.
-I'd like to add that psychologically spoken, I'm much better now.
-Sure.
What shall we do? This is an inflammation of the sacro-iliac junction and of course the fact
that she has not done something to aggravate, either she lifter
or she had an accident or she fell, this is not a good sign.
It is a severe inflammation on this junction which came by itself and there is a possibility
that we have quite a severe condition here.
It's not a simple inflammation, so we may not expect quick results.
-No wonders.
-Especially if it is something which I'm thinking about, is somebody here rheumatologist?
The severity of this case indicates that it might be a collagen disease
which is called inflammation of the sacro-iliac junction. I don't know the English word.
It is not a simple inflammation, it is severe. We don't have a rheumatologist here.
There is a kind of an epidemic going on at the moment, not here in the class,
it is a real epidemic. There are several cases, I've heard from the Centre in Athens, severe.
One of these such cases was so severe that she had to take pain killers
and anti inflammatory drugs and god knows what else. Not responding to homeopathic treatment.
When the inflammation is so severe and so constant, we don't like it.
We hope it is not this case, we will see from the remedy.
The remedy is not clear either and never mind how much you may try.
Give me the repertorization, so I can show you something in the repertorization.
The remedy does not come up.
She started twice in the afternoon after 3, also 3 a.m. ...
Pain while working, sacral region worse during motion, right sacro-iliac,
extremities coldness in toes, back pain, warm application ameliorates, odor offensive afternoon,
taste bad, coughing aggravates, any kind of motion.
You can take this symptom but it is natural that with this kind of inflammation
any kind of movement, coughing moves the whole area, with sneezing, coughing,
laughing she will have the pain, so we go to Tellurium.
-There is no symptom for Tellurium.
-There is but not to give a lot of emphasis into this symptom.
So I will tell you the remedy.
The remedy I would like to give at this moment is Lycopodium. Why?
Because I see it is on the right side first, I see lying on the right side is the best side.
I see the aggravation in the afternoon, after 3 o'clock she starts being aggravated,
in the afternoon and in the morning.
I have told you Lycopodium is worse 3-4 o'clock in the morning and 3-4 o'clock in the afternoon,
it starts getting aggravated.
It is worse in the morning, worse motion and likes warm but still
she will like fresh air as well, most probably.
Anyhow, Lycopodium is the remedy and we'll give her a dose of Lycopodium quite high
because we like to have quick results.
Very quick, it can not be the same result as his case, it can not be though
if the remedy is correct it may give a few hours,
maybe a kind of amelioration of the order of 10-20%.
Where is Lycopodium? What position?
She had also the better lying on right side as well, she has the right sidedness
which is not recorded of course. And that's why you can not see the remedy.
-You have an acute condition.
-Yesterday I got a note from home that my mother is very sick.
She is in intensive care in the hospital and yesterday for quite some time they weren't sure
if she will survive.
And before she was quite fit, it was totally unexpected.
And I was crying all the evening and all night, I couldn't think clear, I really...
-I saw her this morning, red eyes crying all night.
-That was nothing this morning, it was much worse tonight.
There was really panic this morning. I think there is so many things not yet settled
not yet cleared concerning the relationship with the mother...
-So she is attached to her mother?
-It had been difficult the last years because I had been abused in my childhood
and I'm quite sure that she knew about it, I'm not totally sure
but my feeling says that she knew about this and she didn't protect me.
And I always wished the time to be right to talk about this because we now have more or less
a superficial relationship and she and me, both sides, we suffered from this.
Now I got panic with the idea that she might go without me being able to show her
that it might be OK for me one time just to forgive her.
Up to now I had not been able to forgive her, so it wasn't possible to let her know.
-How does she feel now? If I asked her to describe her state, her state is
anxiety, panic, depression, remorse?
-It's confusion and a lot of fear.
-Fear for what?
-A lot of fear that she might go and I won't be able to see her again
and that she would just be gone.
-Was she able to eat last night?
-This morning I tried to eat a little bit because I was so weak that I hardly could stand.
But I can't really tolerate it, I feel nauseated.
-What about water? She can drink water?
-Yes.
-But the solid food would not go down even?
-It's difficult. What I tried was muesli and yogurt because that was easier to shallow.
A friend of mine that has been holding me a long time yesterday evening,
she told me this morning that I had a very bad smell of my body yesterday night.
She couldn't really described it but she just remarked it.
-She did not sleep at all last night? She saw any dream?
-Yes, some hours. Only very rarely I can recall a dream. Nearly never.
-When it was the last time she contacted her brother to give her some news?
-This morning.
-And your mother was in intensive care?
-Yes.
-But she vomited blood?
-They told me it looks like coffee what she vomited.
-That's bleeding of the stomach. But why they said she is almost dying?
-Yesterday the doctors in the hospital told my brother that for half an hour they weren't sure
that she will survive, it was very critical and in the evening they said
she is not yet over the climax, she is not yet through the crisis.
She had an arrest of breathing and she had an extreme fall of the blood pressure
so that her kidneys wouldn't function anymore.
-Otherwise how she was doing just before she had that?
-After Lycopodium I felt great, wonderful, I was even able to rent rooms for my new office,
for my new practices but then my energy went down a little bit and then in February
I got an acute with a high fever over several days.
-She took a remedy?
-I smelled twice on the Lycopodium bottle of 50M and there was a reaction
and during this time when I was so sick, that disappointment too
because the man with whom I'm  together for some years already, he didn't care all together
for me being so sick.
I would reproach him and since then I hardly ever saw him again.
I saw him maybe 3 times within 3 months and I was very disappointed.
-This disappointment affected her health?
-Yes, I had the impression for 3 months that I was in a stagnation on the same level
nothing would move anymore and too about 3 weeks ago I got pains in my right breast
and they were so severe that I went to have a check and they were nodes
and the doctor found out it's a swelling of the glands and he took a sample
and he found out that this is cyst.
Since Monday again I'm having these pains.
-Last time she was here she was with a severe lumbago, this went away?
-Yes, I repeated at home 2 weeks later, the 50M and now is practically gone.
Every now and then I would feel it a little bit but nothing really bothers me.
-Lately she has found out perhaps she is taking more salt?
-A little bit yes.
-Sweets?
-Rather aversion.
Every now and then I will be able to eat a little bit of sweet but not really.
-Now she is here she is bathing in the sea?
-Not up to now but I'm very busy studying but I think if I really wanted to,
if it would have such an importance to me, I would have gone for a bath.
-Would she stay under the sun? She does not like it?
-No, I can't endure it, if it's so hot I have to go...
-After this disappointment she had with this boyfriend, she felt more closed towards men?
-Yes but it's been like this already before, I'm not that open to men.
Only to somebody who is very close to me, very known.
-I don't follow.
-Already before this disappointment it's already been the case that
I've been rather closed towards men.
I only could open up towards men that I was very confidential with, known for a long time,
that I was already very close.
-But this boyfriend was one of those people, close.
-Yes, we were for about 20 years, I nearly daily worked together with him.
-For 20 years they know each other?
-18 years. But maybe I have to mention that he is married which might explain a little bit
his position towards me, his reaction towards me.
-Do you eat meat?
-Little but it should be spicy and smoked.
-Smoked meat she likes?
-The main point is spicy.
-What about the fat in the meat?
-Not so much.
After I had the acute, I had an expressive aversion against it but now it got less again.
But I don't need to have it.
-The fat?
-Yes, the fat.
-Her perspiration, which she says is offensive, she herself has any idea
what type of offensiveness?
-I don't have any sense of smell.
I can't even recall if I ever had one but maybe this is
an idea since I have this acute, I have every morning bad taste in my mouth.
Sometimes my saliva was even blood stained, rarely only 3-4 times.
-Was any salivation during sleep?
-Yes.
-The gums are bleeding when she brushes?
-No.
-The taste is ever metallic?
-When she perspires she feels good, she feels bad or she feels indifferent?
-It does not much of a difference, only I can't control and I'm afraid I might smell badly.
-In general she feels more towards cold or more heat?
-I need a lot of fresh air and I stick out my feet under the covers.
-She had reported coldness of toes.
-I don't have that anymore, very rarely, in rare exceptions.
-Would she say she is more warm than before?
-It didn't change that much I would say. Nevertheless I can very well tolerate local heat,
like if I have some problems with my back I can tolerate local heat in my back.
-She sleeps on a particular position?
-As I have strong scoliosis I'm trying to lie on my left side
but I'm quite well lying on my back.
Another thing I remark recently is that my memory got very bad again.
For example I recently had a handful of cherries and I washed them and afterwards
I didn't know what I did with them, did I eat them? Where did they disappear to?
I couldn't tell anymore and there lots of examples.
-If she has taken a decision, she can make a decision?
-Not as good as I'd like to be able to make a decision but it's possible.
-Her self-confidence has improved since the beginning of treatment?
-It had already been better and I think superficially seen that' OK
but when you get into the depth, it's wanting.
For example at home I would wake up with a terrible mood and always started at that moment
when I was opening up my eyes and because it was so bad,
I used to start with 10 min. of auto training before I open up my eyes and that is the way
how I realized I have no laugh for myself but I only realized when I really go into myself
on a deeper level.
On every day basis I can easily go over it.
Recently I found out that I feel disgusted for certain things and it's a sort of disgusted
that I can't really understand. For example I feel disgusted for giving myself to somebody
I find really nice and whom I like very much and nevertheless I feel disgusted to shake hands.
-To a man usually or even to a woman?
-Maybe everybody.
-How is her sexual desire?
-Not people that I feel not sympathetic, it's maybe anybody.
It's mainly if somebody is close to me that decides this I feel sexual desire
but it's very difficult for me to let go.
-Do you have any leucorrhea?
-Every now and then and then I feel marvelous.
Just a little bit of leucorrhea and I feel great.
-This nice woman I saw in the morning and she was absolutely crying and my mother...
She was acting like a Baryta carb. I'm protected, I lose my mother.
Then I said what's the problem with your mother?
She said, my mother vomited blood and I said OK, if she vomited blood she will not die,
they can save her very easily.
If she had a heart attack, if she had a brain stroke, it's different
but vomiting blood is not somebody who dies. You don't agree?
-Lots of people die.
-With what? By hemorrhage?
-By hemorrhage from the stomach, it' s a major cause of death.
Thousands of people die from taking aspirin.
-Anyhow it's not my experience, I haven't been living in a hospital
but anyhow when I told her that, her mood changed. Due to the information which I gave,
which I believe according to my understanding it is true and she is much better.
Now the problem is what shall we do in order to help her.
Are we going to give Ignatia? She does not have symptoms of Ignatia.
You can see she is not sighing. The first thing we will see in such a case is sighing.
So there is some deeper problem than Ignatia and as she explained the relationship
with her mother has been quite a stressful one and she is afraid the mother may go
and this will not straighten up. The relationship will not be cleared.
So it is a deep grief and there is a grief also which preceded that grief
with her boyfriend and the disappointment.
So we have a love disappointment and we have also this grief.
We propose a dose of Nat. mur. in case you go into depression because of your mother.
But let us say your mother is well. Tonight you hear she is better, what you will say?
How you will feel? Very happy.
-I think I will be back into the confused state that I had been in before.
The feeling that still something has to be cleared and to be straightened out
but I think too it will be a push to really get the things started.
Another thing I want to mention is that I think I sighed and during the last weeks
I had a sort of pressure on my breast, that I couldn't breathe really deeply,
in case this might be important.
-But what I would suggest at this moment is, wait until you hear about your mother.
I believe she will be all right and then see how you feel and then we talk again.
Are you going to leave tonight to go to your mother?
You phone first and then you decide what you have to do but you have in mind
if things are going bad, you take a dose of Nat. mur. even higher 1M.
-I want to add in these circumstances that I would really have disliked being alone
that it would really be very difficult for me to stay alone yesterday night.
I even let the door to my balcony open tonight to feel more connected.
-She sighed 2-3 times.
-Pulsatilla is better.
-And she lies on the back, also Pulsatilla very strong.
-I would rather give her Pulsatilla because there is also leucorrhea ameliorates
one of these 4 symptoms, 1 is Pulsatilla, she doesn't like fat meat,
she put the feet out of bed at night and she is warm and she doesn't like the sun.
-Pulsatilla is, yes.
-And she likes fresh air.
-OK, we'll change, take Pulsatilla, in case something happens with your mother, 1M.