-So last time you took Aurum 200, actually we spoke after you have given the case,
not here because here I have written wait. I told you to take Aurum or... ?
-No, in September you told me to repeat Aurum and I was repeated 3rd time already
till December when I had the divorce, I repeated another 2 times.
In December I had the divorce and my divorce was in a break, in a Course,
I go and sign the paper and then I go back to the Course.
So I haven't realized what was happening because I had another week of Course and...
-You were busy.
-Yes but in January I had a depression and I sent you a fax and you told me
to take Aurum 50M.
I haven't had that potency, I couldn't find in the country.
I speak with one of the colleagues in Germany and she said, OK I send you the potency
and I said OK until I receive the potency let's solve some stomatological problems
and it happened something strange.
That machine which makes a hole in the teeth suddenly makes a noise
and that thing burning in 90 degrees and cut my tongue.
I couldn't explain what has happened and I didn't realize what happened.
In one moment I felt all my mouth full of blood and in that moment I had panic,
I stop the hemorrhage and then I looked and I saw a cut of 3 cm quite deep.
It was inside of the tongue, not on the surface and after one week
I should have a Course and I couldn't speak.
So I took Symphytum 30 for 1 week every day and I could speak after 10 days and now when
I talk too much without break I feel a numbness in that place on the tongue.
So I finished with the tongue and I said OK let's see if I have something else.
My dentist said that I had fistula in one of my teeth and I feel it and there are
only 2 solutions, to take it off but I must (?) to treat homeopathically or
to make an operation.
I didn't want to take antibiotics because I'm allergic, she didn't want to take me off,
homeopathically I didn't know what to do, so it's still there.
In this period I have 4-5 biliary colics, very severe. It keeps me 2-3 days one colic,
very painful.
-How is the pain?
-To the back and here is like a heaviness and like a knife, it's extreme.
In the first day it's extreme.
-You had an X-ray?
-No, I made once a sonograph and they said that it's dyskinesia without stones.
Since October I can not recover, I am very tired. I wake up in the morning and I'm already tired.
-Unrefreshed from sleep.
-Yes. I have desire to sleep, I want to sleep but I can not.
In the afternoon I have no time to sleep but in the night I can not fall asleep before 12-1 o'clock.
-Why? You are very awake?
-Yes but I'm very tired at the same time.
I can not sleep, I can not fall asleep because I'm too tired.
-But still you are very awake, your mind is clear?
-Yes my mind is clear but I'm very tired. I have less energy.
I have nightmares very frequent.
-What kind?
-Someone wants to kill me or I'm in a funeral or I see somebody makes a crime.
Last night it was a snake which was following me and after every nightmare I scream
and I wake up screaming.
This happened about 3-4 o'clock in the morning and I can not fall asleep again because
when I try to go to sleep again, the dream reappear and I come in the dream again
and I wake up again.
-So every night you have a nightmare?
-Yes, I'm here and I had 5 nightmares and mostly they want to kill me or to push me into
the dark, or I see a crime or I'm in a cemetery and last night it was that snake.
And I realized about 2 months ago that I have fear of snakes, it's strange because
in my town there are no snakes in the city but when I enter in the house, especially when
I come in the evening I search the house to see that there are no snakes.
Also I have from time to time erotic dreams.
I have also very strong migraines that keeps me 3-4 days, sometimes they are connected with
the menses, sometimes not.
My menses are irregular. In March I had 1 full month of menses, 30 days with a lot of blood.
From time to time when I wake up I see the pillow is wet and I suppose it's because of saliva.
I have constipation, it's every day and the stool is very hard, I have also hemorrhoids
and when they start bleeding, the bleed for 2-3 days. I also have a painful coition and
after it's bleeding. It's bleeding between 5-10 days after, it's not menses.
-But is this bleeding because of irritation of the mucus membranes of the vagina?
-I don't know. It's very painful and after it starts bleeding. I don't know why.
-Can you wear something around your neck?
-Usually not, I must be naked here.
-Around the abdomen?
-It's not a problem here, I can.
-How much salt do you take?
-Usual.
-Pepper? You like a special pepper?
-No, in every food I put a little.
-Black pepper?
-No red.
-In every food you put red pepper?
-Yes not too much. When I cook.
-Not in your fried potatoes?
-No.
-You are warmer than before?
-I think now I'm normal.
-The position you sleep?
-On the abdomen only.
-There is no perspiration during sleep?
-No.
-But you said the salivation is because of the position most probably?
-I don't know.
-This salivation was not there before?
-No. A couple of months.
-In the tooth where you say there is a fistula, do you have problems, pain?
-No but I must evacuate twice the week.
-The fistula?
-Yes.
It is accumulated in a bag and then I must pressure it to take it out.
-And there is no pain?
-No.
I desire company all the time. I must be with somebody, I can not stand to be alone.
-And you feel better with company?
-Better. Now in the last week, from Monday I'm alone and I can not stand.
I feel day by day...
-Would you say that you have fear in the night of being alone or is it not real fear?
-It's not but I sleep better if it is somebody in the house with me.
-Your appetite for sweets is bigger, smaller?
-I think it's a little bigger.
-There is any abdominal distention or gas?
-No.
-This fear for snakes and nightmares also about snakes is?
-Yes nightmares, last night it was a terror because that snake was following me everywhere
and it was deformed and I woke up screaming. I heard myself screaming.
-Would you say that you have developed jealousy?
-I don't know, I don't think so but I'm very possessive in a relationship.
I don't think I'm jealous but I want to be only mine.
If I will see with another person, it's no problem if I trust him, no problem but my feeling
is he must be mine.
-When you go to bed how long it takes you after you are in bed to fall asleep and how
you feel that period of time?
You go to bed 11 o'clock and until 12 o'clock you can not fall asleep or you go to bed
12 o'clock and at 12.45 you fall asleep?
-Usually I go to bed between 10 and 11 and I open the TV and I put it for 2 hours and
usually I fall asleep at 12.30-1 o'clock because when I'm not totally asleep I hear it finished.
-But during this time it is difficult for you, you battle to sleep, you have an aggravation
at that time?
-Usually I try to sleep but it appears a fear when I'm alone. It can be fear of dark
and it can be fear of somebody entering the house, it's something I can not say exactly
what it's happening but it's a fear. I'm more secure when I'm not alone.
When I'm not alone I can go to bed at 10 o'clock and sleep until 3-4 in the morning.
-When you have company you go to bed and you sleep.
-Yes, usually.
-Salt how much you like?
-Normal.
-Sweet is more?
-Yes but not too much.
-Sweet is only once, desire for company 3 times.
If you are in a high place and you look down, you have problem?
-Yes I do not approach too much in the border, I stay... because I have a fear that I may fall.
-The fear of snakes you develop how long ago?
-I think 2-3 months ago.
-If you see on television snakes, you will close the television?
-I saw one night, it was Hitskok movie with a lot of snakes and I was curious how it will
end but in that night I didn't sleep at all because I closed the eyes and I saw the snakes.
Open, close I saw the snakes.
-But after that you develop the fear?
-No it was before. It was before.
-But how it was before the fear and you kept on looking at the movie?
-Because I can not see when it is on TV, on animal planet, I have a fear and since I'm
here it's very strong.
Sometimes at home I can go to bed and before make the bed, I search, maybe a snake is there.
It's not very often but it happens.
-OK, you will take a dose of Lac Caninum 200. We're thinking of Lachesis, Argen. nitr.
Lycopodium but I prefer Lac can. because Lac can. is strong desire for company
and their fear is quite peculiar.