-George the last time you saw me I was in Berlin, it was in February of 1999.
At that time, I was taking Phosphorus C200 every day after the last attack
and felt quite well with it.
On the 20th of June, she developed new problems.
The cortisone dose had been reduced, up to that point down to 10 mg every day
and then the problems reappeared again.
But her blood examination was fine, nevertheless she had watery and bloody stool
about 4 times every night and twice during the day. Her energy went down,
she was living on her own by then already and told me that
she had more double checks than before.
-Again?
-And also her menstruation had become normal again since the beginning of the year.
Her cycle was 30 days, the menses lasted for 5 days every time,
it was completely without any problems, no pain, no nothing accompanying.
She was also doing fine at school, so actually she didn't know what could be the cause
of this new attack again. Where did it come from?
-Let me remind me something. When I first saw her, there was a stoppage for menses.
For how long?
-At least one year.
Due to the fact that diarrhea was mainly coming after midnight,
you prescribed Arsenicum album C6.
Besides that she was very chilly and had very low energy.
Two days later we raised the potency to C12 because C6 did not act.
In the meantime she also developed fever during the night, up to 40 degrees Celsius,
always after midnight.
And the main problem at that time was the menses pains she had when she had
the urge for stool. Strong pain.
-Strong pain in the abdomen?
-Especially on the left side, she was always pointing.
-This pain was there before, she can remember?
-I had it before but not that severe.
-When she had it before?
-Every time I had an attack, every time I had the urge to stool, this pain.
-The urge or the pain?
-Every time when the urge for stool came, she developed the pain.
-Every day or during a crisis?
-During every crisis.
-Every crisis since the beginning? She had that pain?
That particular pain in the same place?
-Yes but this time it was extremely pronounced and she focused on it again and again.
On the 12th of October we started the C12 and on the 17th of October the fever subsided
but the stool problems remained also mainly during the night.
It actually wasn't real stool anymore at that time, only pieces of mucus and blood
and the main problem I underlined twice at that time was these severe pains.
She described it in the following way.
The pain begins and then immediately she has to bend double and immediately
she has to rush to the toilet but she does not have stool every time,
it's mainly this intensive urge.
Then she also reported that since two days, the stomach fluids were rising
every time she had this urge and that she always feels she is one step from vomiting
but she never vomits.
The modality we had at that time was that it was always bad after sleeping
even if it was only a short nap.
-The pain?
-Yes.
The pain is ameliorated either by lying on the left side or by bending double.
Then she had salivation on her pillow, the trembling of the fingers,
she perspired a lot at that time and all complains were worse after sleep.
Then we tickled out two facts in her emotional sphere.
One is that she can not say no to anybody.
If somebody wants something from her, he will get it.
Even in this bad state she was in, she still pulls leg to go out of the way for other people.
And on the other hand she can easily react aggressively, especially within the family,
with her mother and her father.
At that time she already received injections of vitamins and iron.
All together one can say that this attack, this crisis lasted a lot longer than the ones before
but it was never as severe as the ones before had been.
During the entire time she could continue going to school while in former times
she was at home after four days and two weeks later she always was in the hospital.
-During that crisis did you use Colocynthis at all?
-No. In this phase they were I think it was about 10 days where we could not reach you.
And so during this time we went up with the cortisone, I think 2,30 mg with mg every day
but I have discussed this with you and on October 29th 1999 after I have sent you the fax
we both talked on the telephone. Then you asked me the deciding question if I like fat.
And if I never ever ate anything that only looked like that maybe could contain fat,
then you prescribed Pulsatilla C200 and so with Pulsatilla C200 it went better, day by day.
It took about another week for her to really get out of the crisis completely
but ever since she has been taking Pulsatilla and she is doing fine.
So the Pulsatilla was on October 29th 1999.
-She continues with how many mg of cortisone now?
-5 mg.
-For how long is on 5 mg now? Since November?
-She reduced gradually and the amount of 5 mg is now for about two weeks.
And she is doing well in spite of the fact that right now she is undergoing
the final exams at school and it is quite a stressful situation.
-She is in high school now, she is finishing high school, the last class?
-The last class, 13th grade yes.
-What can we say? We can not change the remedy.
-What is also important is that I frequently had a cold in the past times
and I also developed herpes again on my nose.
-Where?
-She had it before the colitis started, just very shortly before.
-And this time was as bad as the original one?
-Yes.
-Sure?
-Yes and I had it twice another time right down here.
-And you didn't do anything to suppress it?
-Nothing.
-You say that you are under stress but why you are under stress?
Just because you take examinations or because you haven't studied enough?
-Just because the exams are now.
-But she has studied, she feels she knows.
-Yes, up to now yes.
-After Pulsatilla do you feel more cold in general or still you are in the hot side?
-I feel colder.
-Very cold?
-No, it's OK.
-Is she bothered at all with drafts?
-I wouldn't say so, no.
-Stool now is normal, it is formed?
-Completely normal, formed.
-The nails are good, strong?
-In the moment they are quite OK, relatively normal, not completely strong but OK.
-We have to continue with the same remedy until we see there is a possibility
that she may go to Silica after. She may or she may not, we don't give it.
-How quickly would you advise to reduce the cortisone in this situation?
-It's two weeks now that she is taking 5 mg. Can she regulate it to 1 mg less?
-No, only 1,25. She can only divide it into quarters.
-Into two quarters which means 1,25 she could reduce it.
One more week that means 20 days she can reduce one more quarter.
One more week, that means 20 days from the last moment she reduced,
she can reduce again one quarter.
Does she pay any attention to her diet?
-No due to the school stress that's impossible.
-But does she eat junk food also?
-Every now and then yes.
-She is a bit of an anarchist.
-The only times when she ever paid a bit attention to her diet
were in the absolute crisis times. Otherwise she just loves eating sweets.
-I see. OK Eva you are free for the time being.
For instance talking about Eva and you remember the 12 levels. We have the 12 levels.
12, 11, 10 etc. Which level Eva is?
-Nine.
-Eva is somewhere around here.
That means whenever you see that there is a frequent change of remedy picture
and the pathology is deep, that means the person is in danger,
the person is close to malignancy
in which you will have to change your remedies frequently.
Here according to the original idea, how many remedies we said
we will need to bring up patience?
You remember the analysis of this? We said here only one remedy, we start two remedies
for these levels, three remedies for these levels, 4,5,6,7,12,20 remedies
for down here to bring up, if we are ever able to bring up this.
You will see for instance with Eva, when she will come up, she is already I believe
somewhere here between 6 and 7 level at this moment.
After a year or two, you will see Eva getting frequent acutes.
That is the time you feel OK, the danger is away now.
-The question concerns cases like the one of Eva where we are forced to use
very strong acting orthodox medication like cortisone, like anti-epileptic medicines
and so on and these medications change the chemistry of the organism in a massive way.
And in these situations I always come into conflict, due to the influence of the medication,
patients often develop clear remedy pictures but they have to do with the influence
of this medication and then I always am in conflict do I prescribe
on the actual momentary symptoms which are strongly influenced by the orthodox medicine
or do I take a remedy which represents the state the patient was in before all this started?
-When we treat severe pathology under allopathic drugs, let us say a rule ideally.
If we say this case is curable, ideally we should be able to bring back health
by cutting the drugs, reducing the drugs and never again coming back to the conventional drugs.
If ideally we knew so well Homeopathy as to prescribe at the right time, the right moment,
the right medicine, the right potency and sometimes in such cases
you may have to change in one day, to change the remedy.
So therefore your question is, yes when you have severe pathology and you have a picture
you prescribe it, in spite of the fact that that picture has been created by allopathic drug.
Ideally if this case is curable, why do we need to resort to conventional medicine
at the moment? Because we can not have the control of the case through Homeopathy
and especially these cases are more difficult for me because I'm not present.
They try to find me on the telephone or send me a fax but a fax, a telephone
is not at all the same as when you have the patient in front of you
and you can realize the severity, you can see the picture,
maybe the person is exaggerating or whatever.
So therefore not that I try to find excuses for myself but I say that
if we knew what we are doing ideally, we were perfect, we should be able to carry these cases
from 9 level to level 5 or 3 or 4. Ideally, without intervention of allopathic drugs.
This is not all possible and you have to resort again and again, in epileptic cases etc.
Otherwise you may have problems, you may have a status epilepticus and then the case is finished.
She will stay for ever damaged, you can not just cut epileptic drugs especially
when you have mental disorders complicated with epilepsy.
In such cases you don't withdraw the drugs, you have to be very careful
because when the whole force of the disease comes with the right remedy,
you have to know what to do next.
-I would like to ask another question concerning Eva's case.
It has to do with the dosage.
If I understood correctly, she is taking Pulsatilla C200 every day,
meaning she is doing that since approximately four months.
-If somebody is under allopathic drugs, especially heavy drugs,
in order to counteract the effect of the drugs, you have to repeat the remedy.
You have to repeat it and frequently.
If it is 200 or 30 you have to repeat it once the day, if you prescribe under this,
that means 8,12,6 you have to repeat it 3, 4 times the day to counteract
the effect of the drug, until you are able to withdraw the drug totally.
For me I would be very happy if you understand how to evaluate a situation.
You know the Theory so well in your mind that you understand every time,
now it is wrong, now it is correct.
You know when you have prescribed wrong, you know when you have prescribed correct.
That is a great thing, a great knowledge that a homeopath could have.
-I understand your first prognosis that you said it's going to take about 5 years for her
to be cured because her colitis is complicated, for example with the compulsive neurosis.
And they were some factors making the whole thing more difficult for one that
the entire treatment was mainly done through fax and telephone and so for me
I have the impression that some remedies she received in the mean time
before she got Pulsatilla, some of them helped her but some of them didn't help that much.
The main reason why you decided for Pulsatilla was her strong aversion against fat.
-Not the only reason.
-Yes, since she has always had that strong aversion to fat, couldn't it be possible
that if she had received Pulsatilla from the very beginning, that this whole healing process
could have been speed up much more?
Also mentally she is having quite an amelioration which we can see due to the fact
that she has a boyfriend now, even though she has had a severe disappointment in the past.
How much it would have been right or appropriate to have hope that her case
could be cured quicker than the initial prognosis said?
-That's a good question. I'm very happy that you are making such a correct observation.
In this case perhaps you missed the fact or she did not mention it that Pulsatilla
was given before to her without much effect.
In the process of giving several remedies, by the time she was calling me etc.
I had prescribed Pulsatilla again.
That is the first where we know that now Pulsatilla is indicated.
That leads us to understand that there is a time for each remedy that has to be given
and as we peel off layer after layer, remedy after remedy, then we come more and more close
to the healing remedy, I would say, that will have the best effect.
But without the previous peeling off, this will not be possible.
And this is always, it's not only this case.
It's many cases in which we have prescribed the remedy, no effect.
You prescribe another one and another one and you come back to the original
and then the original acts. Which shows that there is a time...
If you remember or you will see it later on that I have explained the different layers.
You will remember this, saying that the second layer brings 1,2,3 possible symptoms
from the underlined layer and there is another layer which has a symptom going right through.
And in spite of being clear symptom, it will not show an effect until you reach...
You take out these 2 layers and then that symptom becomes indicative of this layer.
You most probably if you have not seen that lecture, you will see it.
-My other question, whether this last follow up we saw now, doesn't it give us hope
that the prognosis can be better now than it was initially?
-Yes. But this moment the prognosis is, let us say, 30% better than the initial prognosis.
That means we arrived at a point where some real hope has arrived.