-OK, that is the third follow up and you have taken originally Sepia
and then you took Arsenicum and the last follow up you took nothing.
So can you tell me what was happening?
-After September when I came back home I start to have some troubles at my work and
those troubles become more and more and in April, when I find out that there is
the possibility that I can't come here because of the job, I had two days of depression
and it was quite bad.
Not so intense as in the past but it appeared quite bad.
-Why they did not allow you to come?
-After I came back the boss changed and another one came and he didn't agree to practice
something else but to practice only allopathic medicine, not homeopathic not acupuncture,
not any kind of alternative.
And I stopped but he was not satisfied but he continued making me all kind of problems and
now I understood that he will not let me to work there anymore, I don't know.
When I come back at home it is possible that I find out that I can not work anymore.
In April that was very bad news for me and I suffered.
Now it's OK, he can do whatever he likes.
-That's better.
-In that two days of depression I cried a lot and that's not usual for me. This is not usual.
And also in December when I was very pressed with all kind of problems, I had a pain here.
In one point it was like a knife and I had this pain until 1-2 weeks ago,
when it became a little diffused but it was very acute.
I couldn't move, if I was going to make any move, it was like a knife.
-Internal.
-Yes, in one point it was like a knife.
-In December I had my wedding.
-Ah you got married. This is the first thing you should tell, my god. Congratulations.
-Thank you. After I start my sexual life it appeared some pains and I go to the gynecologist
and he said that I have condylomata.
Now it's OK but one month it was very painful.
In January I made a cystitis for 1 month, it was very bad.
For the first week I said OK, I let it pass without doing anything but then I tried
to take some remedies in low potency but without any effect.
So after 1 month I couldn't spot anymore and I took 4 pills of antibiotics.
One of them was the slightest antibiotic I could find.
-But why didn't you phone? Did you take Cantharis?
-Yes, it was good for 2 days.
-Good for 2 days but it started again. But you needed higher potency.
-I was afraid to take higher potency.
-If you had told me, I would immediately tell you the remedy but anyhow.
-In this winter I had 4 times a flu and this is new.
-Very good.
-But one of them I had high fever, 40 degrees, and this happened to me for the first time.
It never happened.
-But I'm sure when you were a baby you had also but you don't remember.
-And I was scared because such temperature I never had and I told to my husband
you know I never had such a big fever and he said, all right let's try to make it less.
-And you took aspirin?
-No, he tried to make something like a massage with vinegar and after 1 min. or less
I had such a feeling of suffocation, I couldn't breathe anymore and I let the head
to have enough air.
I go to the window and I start coughing, so strongly and then I was breathing and
between coughing I had apnea and I had a feeling that in the next minute I will die.
So all this kept for 10 min. It was awful. I couldn't stand it.
Finally I went into the shower and I took all the vinegar from the body and I stopped coughing
and I started breathing.
After 2-3 days I tried to open a bottle with vinegar to see what's happened and
I started coughing immediately, so vinegar for me is finished.
-Very interesting.
-I had this allergy I think, with strong odors, it was awful.
-But you never before experienced this with vinegar.
-No.
Then 2 weeks before I come here, I cut one of my legs by accident and I go to the surgeon
to put stitches and he makes me local anesthesia with Xyline.
It was about 10 min. and when I get up I feel dizziness.
I had the good idea to say, let's go to another room and lie down for a while
but when I arrived there I start breathing very shortly and very frequent and immediately
cramps appeared in all the muscles and I just jumped from bed so strong with cramps.
My lips and my tongue was numbed and I don't understand why because it was a local anesthesia
and I think...
-It was xylocaine?
-Xyline which stomatologist use and I had anesthesia with xyline before
but it never happened like this time.
I ask myself what will happen if I need real operation.
-No problem, I'll tell you.
-Then I have spontaneous ecchymosis, they appeared suddenly without any touch and
they are quite big and persistent for a long time.
-Did you have a blood examination?
-No. I don't like to make tests.
I observed that it appeared a crack on my tongue.
-At one point?
-No, it's all cracked.
-Can I see it? Very small.
-It appeared pain in the...
-...Joints.
-Yes, only at the hands and it reappeared fear of elevator.
It's not very strong but when I come to elevator, I have a fear and it doesn't disappear,
it is not quite strong, it is to be alone in the night at home.
I still have that fear that somebody can come in.
-Robber?
-Not to steel but that they can do something, they can kill me or something like that.
-Yes, to do some harm.
-I still have edema under the eyes in the morning.
-Did you drink coffee also?
-I drink only 3 times because I was very tired and another thing is that I can not recover
myself very easy when I'm tired and this is unusual. I need too much time to recover.
Usually in 1-2 days I was recovering and now I need 10 days and this is too much.
I'm all the time tired and it reappeared the cramp in the legs at night.
-Especially with a stretching like you said last time?
-Yes and now I wake up with the cramp.
-How is the leucorrhea you said last time?
-I have it and it's quite a lot.
-It's the same, this sweet odor?
-Yes.
-The desire for coffee is still there?
-No, only if I'm very tired.
-You need something.
-Yes, because I have a lot of work.
-Sensitivity to noise that you have mentioned last time?
-Yes, to the clock. I took the clock from bedroom, I put it in another room and then I can sleep.
-Also you had numbness of the toes when you walk.
-No.
-You mention now only during the cramps.
How are your menses now? Clotted?
-The same but a little shorter. It's not 10 days, it's only 7 days.
-How is your sexual desire? It's OK?
-It's OK now.
-And the coldness at the foot at night is still there?
-Yes.
-Do you also perspire in the feet easily?
-When I had emotions even if it's hot outside, me feet are cold and with cold perspiration.
-In the night when you sleep, do you get perspiration in the upper part of your body?
-No.
-The desire for sweets, how is that?
-I haven't.
-Your weight?
-It's much more. I put very easily weight.
-You have to watch what you eat?
-Yes but I can not keep a diet because I'm hungry. I can not do diet but I don't eat too much.
-How is your sleep? You sleep right through?
-I sleep very good but in the morning I wake up a little unrefreshed.
I wake up difficult, I need more sleep and it's very difficult.
-Did you check yourself from a high place looking down, if you have problem now?
-I have a little fear but if I do, I have a little dizziness.
I can go near but I have little fear which I can control, I can go near
and look without any problem.
-The stitching pain here has gone totally now or it is there?
-It is there.
-How much per cent is there?
-30%.
-The pains in the joints since where they disappeared?
-Since November, December something like that.
-How is your reaction to weather?
-No problem.
-That means you feel the heat very much, you feel the cold more?
-No, it's normal.
-Also you have mentioned last time, you were forgetting what you wanted to say.
-It's OK now.
-The need for salt how much is it?
-Normal. I need more lemon, sour, a little bit not too much.
In this case we see again this idea coming from the second group, from 3rd to the 2d.
This was quite a deep depression originally and immediately coming to this group,
she starts having the flu.
It took her 1 year before she started having the acutes and then she gets the cystitis and then
even more she gets a very high fever.
She said, she never had before which happens with certain remedies, they don't get a high fever.
For instance if you are in the state of Arsenicum, in a depression of Arsenicum,
you will almost never experience fever.
So people who will say I never develop fever, many times they need Arsenicum, we have said this
in the Materia Medica I think.
Why the cystitis?
We have spoken about Cantharis I think.
We said that when a woman gets married for the first time and especially if it's a person
who really controls herself, not a person who goes every night or every second night with another man,
especially those women who control themselves and then they go into a marriage where they
feel free to have sex then the excitement gives an easy inflammation of the vagina.
There is a lot of blood concentrating in this area and they can develop severe cystitis,
which is usually of the type of Cantharis.
Because the pain is there, yet the desire to continue is there and that irritates more and more
and then they go into really bloody cystitis, where the burning is so much and the irritation of the
mucus membranes, of the vagina so big that it will almost have blood, vaginitis or cystitis.
That's why I mentioned when she told me the Cantharis that she took most probably Cantharis 6, Cantharis 5.
This was not enough to control. She needed 200 every day 2-3 times the day before you can control that.
Now the question that we have is... She took antibitiotics, the coffee, the local anesthesia.
Does she have a relapse?
She took Sepia originally and then Arsenicum. Then we have that type of situation.
Now she is on another level, here, let us say Calc. carb.
She comes now with this level then underneath maybe Sulphur I don't know but she comes
with this level and there is a stimulation of this level, now the possibility is that either
the organism resists the relapse or the relapse will go back to Arsenicum.
You see what we have said?
So the judgment is, is she going back to Arsenicum or still is on that level?
The organism is still resisting to stay in this uppermost level now.
If now there is no relapse and we don't see the Arsenicum picture strongly and if this picture
is not clear, what we have to do?
-Wait.
-Wait OK. Do you remember in the last follow up in September we prescribed nothing.
Now I would like to show you the repertorization of the last time.
The last time we argued, if you remember,
whether we should give a remedy, yes or no and we decided not to give a remedy.
So it is about a year since she has not taken a remedy, correct?
-One year.
-Now she comes after a year and we still talk about waiting. You see how Homeopathy works?
That's the way Homeopathy works.
Is this the last time? Show me the symptoms.
Calc. carb. was the most prominent possibility for her and we decided not to give it.
Was it the right decision, yes or no?
-Yes.
-No.
Because if she still is on Calc. carb. that means we lost some time.
We should have speeded up, we were able to prescribe it and she would be much better
already and not with this kind of sensitivities, which she mentioned.
This is the previous one.
She was still having some sighing, ecchymosis, desire for cold drinks, forgetful, sensitive to noise, toes...
What was missing last time that she mentioned it this time?
-She puts on weight.
-She says, I'm putting on weight. That is another point for Calc. carb. What is missing?
The desire for sweets. What about eggs? Normal. You don't eat eggs?
-I can eat eggs. It's normal but usually I prefer eggs soft boiled but I have no problem.
-Another point for Calcarea are the cramps in the legs at night.
-She had it from the previous time already. This is very interesting.
I have noticed that Calc. carb. is very sensitive to certain chemicals. Aspirin also.
If they take aspirin, they have a big allergic reaction but the reaction is interesting that comes
to the pathology of the Calc. carb.
Which pathology? Cramping.
When we say, I don't want to go into the cystitis because we didn't go into details of cystitis.
So if you take the case you will ask the details. When the pain is?
During, before after urination, no urination etc. How strong is very important.
If the cystitis in that case is very strong, it's burning, she is shouting every time she goes to urinate,
this type of cystitis, then it's Cantharis.
But I did not go into the details of cystitis. I just asked her, did you take Cantharis?
She says, yes but the amelioration was only for 2 days, then most probably if she would have said
that on the telephone, I would say take a higher potency to save the antibiotics.
-George look at her sensitivity in Calcarea in her reaction on vinegar, it was very strong.
Perhaps it's the same direction and I think we have given last time the problem with the loss memory,
it's very quite better with that argument for Calcarea.
-The vinegar reaction I have not seen with Calcarea.
It's very interesting but I have not seen it, but we have it in mind, if we see it again.
-A general question. If you could influence the remedy with your mind or with your wish?
For instance she said, not her but generally when we say, I tried not to eat this or I tried to eat fruit,
if then I can avoid to get in an Ignatia state with my will power, if I can influence this.
-If you can influence the reaction or the remedy or if you can influence your organism?
Your organism you can influence with your mind anytime. That means you can suppress emotions,
you can suppress pain, you can do a lot of things with your mind, sure, there is no question,
nobody will argue about that.
We know it very well because that is how the Nat. mur. state...
I will answer your question.
I take it logically, so you understand what I will say.
The Nat. mur. will influence, I must not cry, I must not cry and they do not cry.
That influences the organism and they don't cry and the get cystitis or gastritis, whatever.
So that means when they take the remedy, the organism is strengthened and still if the individual
is very powerful in their minds, they can still influence the organism not to express in the way
the organism wants to express because the organism wants to cry.
If you don't allow the organism to cry, like she said, I cried for the first time in my life I cried
under this stress which I had. If she did not allow it because she feels, I'm ridiculous I'm crying,
I'm this, then she would have some other form of depression or whatever she may develop.
Under the influence of the remedy you can still do it but not so easy.
The organism is more powerful and wants his own way of expression.
So you can really with very strong individuals but I told you the case of a man who came
he was a secret agent from CIA, he came very tough man who resisted the remedy actually.
He said, I have been to the biggest doctors, I was 25 in a little apartment in Athens in 1970,
as he was relating to me afterwards.
He comes the first month, how are you? The same. He comes second month, how are you? The same.
I didn't change the remedy of course. He comes the third month and he brought I remember,
a ring with diamond for my wife and he says, I couldn't believe it.
I have all this addiction with Valium, he was living on Valium and that I could be able to free myself,
I would be able to travel wherever I like, anyhow. You can influence but not so easily
as when you are sick.
And the more sick you are, the more you can interfere with the functions of the body,
you have to remember that.
If you interfere with the functions, they are going to have a repercussion because the organism knows
how to rearrange the things inside.
That does not mean of course that every time you get crossed you just throw a cup of hot tea
in the face of the person.
-I want to say something. After aspirin and pain killers I have dizziness and after any kind
of antibiotic, I have dizziness.
I feel like I'm fainting, something like that and I want to put that question
if I need anesthesia, what will happen?
-After Calcarea you will have no problem.
Show me the last repertorization.
So definitely the repertorization goes towards the Calc. carb. the whole picture is Calc. carb.
then we can give it. What potency? Very high.
Who says 30? 200? 1M? 10M? 50M? CM?
I would like to give only 200, the reason is that there is missing still some sweet
and the sensitivity to cold.
These two little things which are missing I would like to be on the safe side.
-But she has cold feet.
-Yes, cold feet are there but sensitivity to cold in general. Cal. carb. is cold remedy.
The perspiration in the back is missing. So therefore we go with 200, maybe later on
if she goes with more clear picture and after all her problems now are on the physical level.
Her problems are not mental problems. It's not mental depression we have to treat where
we have to go really very high.
One time.
-This extreme tiredness for which she needs 10 days to recover, is that also Calcarea?
-Another point of Calc. carb. yes. Worse exertion. If you put this also in repertorization
that will also make it stronger, that's exactly, that's the idea.
So the organism needs the absorption of calcium, she needs to absorb and
she needs to utilize calcium much better than she does. Very good observation.
-In this case now that you said that this organism needs calcium, would you also suggest
diet changes, so that there will be more calcium?
-No. Dietary changes will do very little. It will ameliorate a little bit the situation but will not
correct the problem in a deeper level. Calc. carb. definitely will.
-After a week that I took Calc. carb. I had a terrible quarrel with my boss and I think I
antidoted because we shouted each other for half an hour and I was very nervous and I came home
and I was so nervous that I couldn't cry.
It was something incredible, I was so angry and I think I antidoted because I don't feel anything.
After 2 weeks I decided to repeat Calcarea and after 2 weeks I had another quarrel with my boss
in the same manner.
-It's very good when you want to have a quarrel, you just take a dose of Calcarea.
-So since then I live every day in a stress.
-He is pressurizing you?
-Yes very much.
He wants me to throw out and I didn't want to and the idea was that I leave when I want,
not when he wants.
He does anything he can to make me very nervous and angry.
-He is a director in the hospital?
-No, he is a director at the factory and I'm a doctor there and now he is my boss.
-I see and he creates problems.
-Many problems.
-Every day?
-Every day.
-And how you react? You react again in the same manner like the first time?
-When I am at work I was calm and I didn't show any reaction or emotion or anger but
when I come home I'm very upset and angry and furious.
-But the first time you said you quarrel with him, that means you shouted him also.
-I shouted to him and he shouted to me, at the same time.
-And when you went home you felt you did not say enough or what?
-I don't know, I was too angry and trembling.
-And the second time the same thing happened?
-Yes.
-You shouted, he shouted.
-Yes, it's for the first time that I can shout to somebody who is superior, this is for the first time.
-This is very good, it's healthy.
-So I don't know how much...
-We will find out. You want to say something else that has happened?
-Yes, in this period I have edema at the ankles very big edema, especially when I sit for a long time
or when I travel. They go for 2-3 weeks, so it's a long period with edema.
-If the edema comes, then it stays for 2-3 weeks before it goes away?
-Yes and it's so big that I feel the skin cracks.
-You did not have this before? You had it less?
-I had it but it was for a short time, 2-3 days but now it stays for long time.
-And this time the edema is bigger?
-Always it is bigger but for long time.
-With pain?
-No.
I developed great desire for fresh cream with sugar and bread. I eat kilos.
-You never did this before?
-Never.
I couldn't support fresh cream but now I eat kilos of this.
-What about milk?
-No. 1 kilo in 1 year is enough for me and also desire for fish, I can eat every day fish.
Strong desire for fish and also coffee.
-Did you have coffee? 2-3 times? How many times you said?
-Coffee I had before I came here.
-But now did you drink?
-No, only when I came here on the road.
-So 2 or 3 times, I want to know if I'm correct in my perception.
-2 bottles of 250, let's say half a kilo but only one spoon, so two spoons.
-So twice.
-Also I have ecchymosis which appears spontaneously and this summer
I had all the analysis and it was OK.
-How many platelets?
-I don't know but it was normal. They appear spontaneously.
-Without knocking?
-Without.
I have an allergy to wasps, I have constipation which is quite serious.
For about 1 year I have a sensation of rawness or some pain in the throat, it's almost permanent,
it's like a wound. At the beginning I said it's nothing but now...
-Now you see it stays for 1 year.
-Yes. Sometimes I have, you know in my family history it is a lot of cancer and for a while
I think too much about this problem.
I don't if it is good or bad but sometimes I say, it is too much cancer in my family and it's not a fear,
I'm just thinking about it.
And that's it.
-I want to ask some questions. You said, you quarrel with your boss, what about your husband?
-No, it's OK.
-The relationship is good?
-Yes, he supports me all the time and he said, I can not imagine how you can resist in such a stress.
He supports me a lot.
-Something else. Do you have a child or do you want to become pregnant,
do you take precautions?
-No, I don't take anything.
-In general the temperature of your body has remained the same as before?
-It's a little warmer. I didn't realize myself but the others observed that I'm warmer.
-Did you have occasions where the warmth even bothered you?
-I didn't understand.
-For instance here or when you were in Romania, did you have occasions where the weather
was warm, that this bothered you?
-No, I can stay under the sun with no problem.
-And the warm does not aggravate you.
-Yes.
-Do you take butter?
-No occasionally and cheese also, only fresh cream with sugar but I have no desire for sweets,
only for this kind.
-Ice-cream?
-Yes occasionally.
-Not something special. Here I have noted before that vinegar aggravated you very much
this still stays?
-Yes and it's strong.
-And the ecchymosis was before, it's more now or it's less?
-No, it's the same.
-You have reported some finger, in the joints of your finger, it's not there?
-No.
-Also fear of being alone in the night you have reported.
-I don't know now because I'm not alone.
-Also you have reported swelling in the eyes, especially in the morning.
-No.
-Feet cold in bed you have reported.
-Sometimes but it's not so cold.
-The leucorrhea you have reported.
-Yes it is and it is a lot.
-It is more?
-Yes it is more.
-What is its consistence?
-It is yellow and thick.
-I want to ask you now how is your sexual desire?
-It's great. I don't want to change.
-OK. Also you had reported fear in narrow places.
-Yes I have it. I observe that I can not go into elevator; in some I enter but in others no.
It depends.
-Also you have reported fear from high places, it might still be there?
-Yes.
-And stitching pain in sternum.
-No this has gone.
-Also cramps in legs with stretching.
-Yes these are still there and especially in the night and they are more painful.
I observed last week these cramps in the day when I walk, when I stay, it doesn't matter.
They are not only in the night, now they are in the day also.
-After exertion?
-No, just walk or stay and they appear.
-Desire for salt has increased at all?
-No. I can say it appeared but not very strong, the desire for spicy food.
-Your nails are strong?
-No.
-They break easily?
-No but they are soft.
What shall we do in this case?
-Wait.
-Shall we give Apis? Swelling of ankles?
-No.
-Medorrhinum? Swelling of ankles?
-Pulsatilla?
-No.
-Maybe.
-Very good, you are learning. Let's see the repertorization. If you go to the repertorization you
will see something which is interesting.
-Ah...
-Still Calc. carb. is on the top, shall we repeat Calc. carb.?
She says, I don't know if it's antidoted, maybe it is antidoted. Shall we repeat Calc. yes or no?
Who says yes, he will justify it, who says no, he will also justify it. Who says no?
I also have the impression that there is still a lot of movement in the case, especially on
the mental and emotional level.
I think it's a great development that she has the courage to withstand her boss in such a clear,
straight and direct manner.
-You talk Causticum. Hit him, kill him!
Any other wants to justify why she should not take Calcarea carb.?
-I think if she had antidoted with the coffee, we have to wait for relapse
and now there is no relapse.
-The main reason is very practical, very down-to-earth. Because she is getting warmer.
The fact that she is getting warmer and her feet are getting warmer forbids you
from repeating Calc. carb.
All other things, even if there is something in process, you still may repeat,
in case she was cold, feet cold, perspiring, you could have repeat it.
The fact that she has become warmer, the feet especially, they are not as cold as before
that is an indication that you must not give Calcarea and all the other symptoms
are not enough to give us a clear picture of another remedy.
-I think too the discharges are going worse, it's a sign of no remedy, leucorrhea and swelling.
-Exactly, also the fact that it is discharging with leucorrhea quite a lot,
you allow it to happen as much as possible.