-I start from the beginning. After two weeks all the physical problems reappeared.
-What was the prescription in May?
-It was Arsenicum.
-What potency?
-200 and after two weeks the migraine appeared which keeps for 2-3 days and
it is very strong and I start to sigh very often and very deep
and appeared some cramps.
When I try to stretch especially in the night or if I'm not attentive there is a cramp.
-Mostly where?
-It depends on the moving.
-In the extremities?
-In the extremities and here in the leg, this is the most strong.
The first time keeps me 3 days, it's very strong and very painful,
not I'm very attentive to every move because ifI stretch too much,
it appears immediately.
-Find in the Repertory cramps after stretching in the extremities.
-Then it appears a back pain which is still now.
-Lumbar region?
-Yes lumbar region.
-Is it constant?
-Yes it's constant like blow, like after a blow.
Especially when I stand too much in the same place without moving,
the pain appears.
-And it is better when?
-It is better when I lie down.
Also it appeared some ecchymosis but without to blow myself, just appeared.
-They go away after a while?
-After 7-8 days they disappear.
-Did you check your blood? Platelets?-No.
-Then?
-Then it appeared when I start talking in the middle of the phrase I forget
what I want to say and I can not remember and this is ...
When I talk with a patient and I want to put a question and disappears,
I must find something else or I know the word, I have it in my mind but I can not express it.
It keeps 20-30 seconds and then I can say the word.
-Forgets what she wants to say.
-I have very great desire for coffee. For 5 years I didn't drink coffee, not at all
but if I startto drink, I can not stop. I drink 6 coffees, 7, 10, I can not stop.
-Lately did you drink?
-Lately no. For 4 years I didn't drink and I try to stop myself from drinking
but I have a great desire to drink coffee.
-Desire yes but what I ask is, did the last week drunk some coffee?
-Yes, a little one. I try not to drink much.
-Yes but I want to know how much.
-Half of a cup.
-How many times the day?
-Just once because I said to myself that I must not drink coffee.
-But you drunk only half a cup how many times?
-6 times, 10 times.
-Not a big crime.
-And it appeared a sensitivity in the noises, I cannot hear the clock in the room,
it disturbs me, it makes me nervous or hear somebody who is eating something croquant.
And the last physical thing is when I walk I feel in the toes numbness, it's like the toes
are not there. It disappears when I walk.
And the most important thing that happened was 3 weeks ago when a man
who was looking for me for 5 years called me and I accepted to see him and
after the first date I make love and we will marry in November.
-Congratulations. I think I predicted that. Very good.
-Yes, I opened myself incredible and just I can not believe that it is true, it's like a dream.
-You remember the previous state of course. Nothing else to report spontaneously?
-No.
-I want to ask you concerning the sighing? When did you notice that you are sighing so much?
How long after Arsenicum?
-Two weeks after Arsenicum.
-And the sighing continues. I saw you sighing when you started.
Now you are more calmp erhaps and this sighing continues even after this?
-It's a bit rare, it's not so often.
-After the last relationship?-Yes
.
-Let me ask you something else.
During this period from May until now did you have a specific desire for fruits or
in the contrary you remember not eating so much fruits?
-No. I have a desire for fruits but not very strong. It is more than before.
-And has anything changed in diet? That means you desire something now that you did
not desired before? More salt or more pepper, more meat or fat?
-No, I don't like to eat too much meat now but nothing special.
-What about salami, smoked meat?
-I prefer not to eat them.
-Is it because of diet reasons?
-No, I don't like them. I prefer not to eat them.
-Concerning the temperature of your body has anything changed after Arsenicum?
You became more warm, more cold?
-I' m a little cold than before and in the night I wake up trembling, I feel very cold.
-In general?-In general and internal cold.
-In bed do you have to wear socks in bed at night?
-No but the feet are cold.
-The feet are especially cold, more cold than before?
-I can say like before the first remedy. They are cold and they warm very slowly.
-Very difficult to warm up.
-Yes and the insomnia appeared.
-What time do you have insomnia?
-3 a.m. I wake up and I can not sleep anymore.
-And you go until morning or after 2 hours you sleep again?
-No, until morning and I go to sleep late. At 12 or 1 o'clock.
-But this sleep is enough for you?
-It's not enough, I'm very tired and in the morning I'm very tired.
-The last two weeks when you started, you sleep better?
-No, I sleep worse.
-And that is something which you would explain somewhat?
-Yes I explain it but the sleeplessness was before.
-From May until this you had been sleeping, it was not a big deal your sleep.
-After 3 weeks I think, this insomnia appeared and at 3 o'clock in the morning I wake up
and in the morning I'm tired, I start working and I go to sleep at 12-1 o'clock and...
-Why do you go so late to sleep?
-Because I have a lot of work to do?
-So much work? What are you doing?
-Translating the book and I have two jobs, I work in a private office also and I have
patients and I must repertorize.
-Do you enjoy the work?
-Yes, very much. I do it with pleasure.
-Tell me something. Do you cry more easily now?
-No, I can not cry.
-And you have not been crying even the last few weeks with this affair?
-No. I can not.
-Do you allow yourself to feel happy with this affair?
-I'm very happy.
-That's very good. In sleep do you perspire?
-No. I perspire only when I have strong emotions.
-Like excitement?
-Yes and it's cold perspiration. Cold and clammy.
-Do you find yourself being more sloppy now than before?
I mean you don't make your room or you don't have time or you continue to be very orderly?
-Yes, very.
-Your nails do you bite them or do you cut them?
-No.
-And do they break easily?
-Now not.
-Before?-Before yes. When I'm cold they become blue black.
-When it was the last time that you had that?
-I think last week because in my country now it's very cold.
-Already.
-Yes.
-What about sweets? How much?
-I don't. I prefer ice-cream, chocolate but not too much.
-In your weight you lost some weight?
-Yes, I lost 6 kilos.
-Your thirst is normal or has increased?
-My thirst has decreased. I didn't drink in the night as I used to and the day is normal.
-How are your fears?
-I still have strong fear of robbers. I lock all the doors and I stay with the fear
but if there is somebody in the house with me it's OK, I sleep well and no problem.
-What about fear from high places? Have you noticed any fear developing for high places?
-No.
-Thunderstorms?
-No other fear? Fear of dark?
-No.
-Do you have regular motion? Do you have any constipation?
-No, it's normal. In the last month it's soft stool, 2-3 times the day but not diarrhea.
-Diet has changed drastically?
-No, I eat less than before because of the program. I don't have time. I eat in foot and go.
-The urination has no problem.
-No problem.
-No special desire for urine?
-No. What I notified also was the menses are from 7-10 days, they are shorter now.
-With less blood also?
-No, the same amount but the days are shorter but it reappeared the leucorrhea
which is quite strong.
-How is your desire for sex?
-I have desire for sex but I'm afraid, I have not the courage, not yet.
-To let it go. But you had sex already?
-No, I haven't sex already.
-Oh I see.
-And I'm afraid. Everything has happened so quickly in such a short time, I cannot.
-You are not able to relax. But the desire you say is strong?
-It's quite strong.
-Very good, the hormonal system needs to work again after all.
Do you have any other change in the modalities of your menses?
That means before menses you become more irritable or anything like that?
-No, in the first month I had headaches, migraine before and two days
after the beginning of the menses and it was quite strong but now it's OK.
-It's normal. The menses are coming before you know even?
Do they come perhaps only in the day time?
-They came 3-4 days before the normal and they are with many clots.
-Very dark?
-Very dark and they are many and I'm feeling better when I have clots than when I
haven't.
-But how many times you had the headache?
-Just one month after the Arsenicum.
-The leucorrhea is white, yellowish?
-Yellow, white and it's all the time.
-During that period did you see any constant increase or in the contrary it increased
until July and then decreased?
-No, it's constant.
-That means from when it started it is the same, no increase, no decrease.
-No. And it has a sweet smell.
-OK thank you.
-Thank you very much.
Let's see the symptoms. Cramps on stretching out the foot.
This, put it in third degree.
It has to be put in third degree.
This is what we have been saying.
When she says, with the least stretching I have to be aware this is a clear symptom,
clear, strong, intense 3 times. This is the idea. Who put it 3 times?
Can you please rise your hands?
8 only. That is no good for the class.
Immediately the idea of Calcarea comes to the picture. You got the right rubric.
You see the intensity, immediately Calc. carbonica comes.
You say maybe Cal. carb. but she said she was sighing very much. Show me sighing.
How many remedies we have capital in sighing? Strong sighing appears.
Therefore you go to the Repertory and you see how many remedies really sigh.
One is the Ignatia, the other is Calc. phosh., the other is Cimicifuga
and the other is Bryonia, not so much. Ign, Calc.phos. and Cimic. are the remedies
which sigh very strongly.
Now you remember in this case, when we discussed this case because of the grief
we might have gone and give Ignatia, because of the grief.
We did not give Ignatia. Now she has sighing. The thinking should be like this.
We have Sepia layer first and then we had some symptoms of Arsenicum which were
underneath and now she has some symptoms of Ignatia with big sighing.
Was she sighing in the beginning? For those who remember, did you write sighing? No.
Why now she is sighing?
Now the organism can tolerate the pain of the grief, on a more conscious level.
Before the organism could not handle the grief and went into a deeper level, Sepia.
Sepia, more dizzy, not clear, no sighing.
And then you take away the Sepia first layer and then there is another layer of Arsenicum
with fears etc. and what we have decided in the analysis.
And now sighing, sighing, sighing all the time which shows that the grief is now taken up
by the organism and what is interested is, we asked how is the sighing the last 3 weeks?
She says, better. The sighing is better.
That means already the relationship takes care of that level in a way.
We don't know how far, how much.
What is interesting is, you must ask, if this is an Ignatia layer, shouldn't we have
another symptom, a few symptoms to confirm the Ignatia layer
and we investigate in this direction.
Do we have really an Ignatia layer or in our thinking we are making a mistake in the analysis?
You understand what I mean? Fruits? Do you need more fruits? Less fruits?
No big change there, there is no an aversion to fruit to indicate that definitely
we have a layer of Ignatia.
Then we go to the pathology. We look the pathology which is the  cramps mostly,
no Ignatia there.
Then the thinking should go, sighing a lot and Calc. appears in the cramps,
what then should we be thinking about?
We should think of Calc. phosporica. We have to investigate the possibility of Calc.
phosp. All these lumbar cramping, there is a cramp here which affects the sciatic nerves
and the organism now has done what? It has taken the grief that was deep inside into the
emotional level and brought it down as cramping on the physical level.
This is the explanation from the pathology point of view and from understanding that we
have of the human being.
The organism therefore has become strong and now the grief is these cramps appearing
in the lumbar region and in the legs. It's beautiful.
But maybe she comes like this and then cramps and the toes are numbed.
Then what shall we do? Here is the point where most of the mistakes are made.
At this junction. You make a mistake and you will see very interesting developments.
So a lot of thinking has to be done in analyzing that state now in which she is
because what we are looking for, we are looking for a clear picture, the third layer.
So is this a case of Calc. carb., of Calc. phos., of Ignatia, of Cimicifuga, of Phos. acid?
The memory is affected quite strongly, in the middle of a sentence I forget
what I want to say.
-Desire coffee is a symptom?
-Yes, you can put it as a symptom strong, 3 times.
She could spoil the treatment if she goes into coffee, you must know that.
What is it going to happen if she drinks coffee now at that stage?
We have to discuss this also. What is going to happen to her?
-Falling back.
-Falling back to what?
-To Sepia. You remember we have discussed this. I said, you take this out.
If you take out the second layer, then antidote the second layer,
then the first layer will come up.
She will not go all the way through to the original because of the coffee.
You remember the original case, how she was feeling emotional and all that.
She will not go to that original state by drinking coffee.
By drinking coffee, she will fall back into the original Sepia, what happened after Sepia.
You remember she described this after May.
Then if she keeps drinking coffee, then eventually she will fall back into
the original state but maybe not entirely.
-Is it possible that she could fall back into the Sepia state even though Arsenicum
has already unfolded its efficiency or has worked through completely?
-Sure. Sepia on a different level. We treat Sepia on a mental level and then another
remedy is needed, Arsenicum.
And then the Sepia picture may reappear on a purely physical level, leucorrhea and cramps.
So we have cycles of remedies but if your prescription is correct, then the disease
will come down, the disturbance will come down from mental, emotional to physical.
It is the observation of these old masters like Kent. Kent also said, sometimes you have
cases that come in cycle, Sulphur, Calcarea, Lycopodium.
You may repeat 3 times this cycle before the patient is correct.
Therefore the possibility of Sepia is coming again now as on physical level.
-Numbness she said during walking.
-Numbness on foot, Phos. acid is there, Causticum, Aconitum and Cyclamen.
Cramps on legs, on calves was Sepia there, yes or no? Who says no?
Cramps in calves on stretching. There was Sepia. Nobody knows.
I lead you to Calc. carb. Somebody says, wait, with this leucorrhea it might be again Sepia.
Yes it might be Sepia and you see it from the leucorrhea and from this tendency of Sepia
to produce the cramps on the calves.
Desire for coffee we see it in Angustura vera. Are all these the remedies?
-Yes, only two are missing here.
-Some additions. The Calcar. phos. is there, the Sepia is not there.
So she desires a stimulant there is no question. She desires a stimulant because she is tired,
because she is not sleeping so well and therefore she does not have some energy
and the organism is craving.
So the desire for coffee is a symptom which you just put a question mark whether
it is a real symptom or something that she knows she can get energy from.
When I feel very tired, I drink coffee to my detriment.
I will die 10 years earlier because of that.
-I saw in few of the symptoms also Nux vomica and she said she is very irritated and
she doesn't sleep and there is a lot of things of Nux vomica that also come up.
-Put sleeplessness after 3.
That's it. Magnesia carbon., Arsen., Sepia, Nux vom. is only on a second place.
Actually this particular it is very much like Sepia, Magnes. carb. and Sulphur.
Thuja and Tubercul. I don't know why they are so strong here.
Arsenicum I don't know it is so strong. Sepia, Magn. carb. and Sulphur I know to have that
type of sleeplessness.
Mostly now the problem is the cramps, the pains in the bag, the legs and the memory.
These are the problems. What shall we give?
We have a possibility for Sepia, Calcarea Calc. phoshp.
She says, she has cold and clammy perspiration. What reminds you this perspiration?
Which remedy? Calc. carbon.
The first remedy that you have to think when a patient says
I have cold and clammy perspiration is Calc. carb.
Now is she in a Calc. carb.? She desires ice cream.
The way she said it, is it really desire? Very doubtful.
Desire is for coffee but coffee is needed to have more energy.
So therefore Angustura, I would not go to that extend.
What is important in her case for those who remember the first interview.
Can you see the difference in inner relaxation? The soul has been relaxed.
It is impressive for me because I feel the patient, I feel the inner state and to see that
state and that state, for me is day and night. It was a state of total cramp inside.
A soul that was cramped inside. Now it is only cramped in the physical body and the
inner self has relaxed. This is how far Homeopathy can go. It is not a miracle working.
It is a very systematic methodology and that's why we discuss very carefully now,
not to make a mistake.
So we have another possibility, Ars, Sepia, Cal, Cal. phos and Ignatia.
We have 5 possibilities to choose among. Who is in favor of repeating Arsenicum? 11.
Who is in favor of Sepia? 11. Who is favor of Calc. carb? 11.
That is a super natural phenomena. Who is in favor of Calc. phos? 9
Ignatia? 4. Most of the class remained silent and did not want to make a decision.
Who wants to wait? 36. It's 36. We can count them. This is the easiest, the more safe but
she may find herself in pain and what it may happen, she may go into a state of lumbago very strong.
What is she going to do?
So if you are a good doctor, you have to foresee what is going to happen to give some direction
because by the time she will fall, she will take anything.
So by the time that she will have the lumbago, if she can not contact you who is the doctor
and she is already becoming homeopath, she will have to search between these two remedies,
most probably the remedy is either Sepia or Calc. carbonica.
I can not say at this moment whether it will be Sepia again or Calc. carbon. but
she is sensitive to both these remedies.
So if the wrong one will be prescribed, it will affect the case but it will not push the case forward.
It will confuse it.
So by the time she will have a severe lumbago, she will have to think about these two remedies
but maybe a third one will appear, if you have a specific symptom that points
to another remedy. Show me fear of robbers.
But fear of robbers is not in the same intensity as it was in May. Here we have Ignatia
which is a possibility, as we said, Arsenicum of course.
-We left off the symptom perspiration emotions after and that has 3 remedies,
the one of them is Sepia.
-Cold perspiration after emotions.
-That was a very interesting observation. Where did you find it?
-Perspiration emotions after, page 1495 in the perspiration.
-Yes 3 remedies Physostigma , Rhus tox and Sepia.
You remember when I said in the beginning how you underline?
If this was a reliable symptom, it is added by somebody whom I don't know, I don't know
how reliable it is but let us that symptom is reliable.
Then it happens, when I said that a symptom is told by the patient but we just forget
about it, we don't pay attention to that and maybe that is a clue
because of that peculiar symptom.
So if the rubric was cold, clammy perspiration after emotions, then it is exactly and
maybe we have to pay attention, as long as the recording is reliable.
As I told you from Kneer's Repertory which comes from Herring's symptoms,
you know the 10 volumes Herring's?
You have a Repertory called Kneer's Repertory where he records the symptoms of
the Materia Medica and many times I have seen the exact words of the patient
found in one remedy only. Magnesia phos. has that particular symptom, you give it
and it doesn't work and many many times - that's why in the morning I told you
forget about this, you don't pay attention.
What you pay attention is on the main structure of the remedy because these symptoms
are not so reliable.
Who is PK? Phatak? Phatak means comes from Herring's Materia Medica, it means from
Kneer's Repertory, that's what we have been talking about because Phatak uses a lot of
information from Herring's Materia Medica.
These are good as indications but not to go and say yes that's it.
Because if this information is absolutely reliable then Sepia is most indicated again for her.
-It says that in the cases of menses where there are both clots and it comes earlier,
Calc. carb. is indicated much more than Sepia.
-Put menses with clots.
-And also menses frequent to earlier.
-Where is Calcarea? Sabina, Crocus, Belladonna, we don't have Sepia, Calc. carb.
Arsenicum.
Calc. phos. also is there, Camomilla...
This symptom here, dark clotted, how many times you can underline that symptom.
The way she says it, she says I have many times menses clotted and I feel good.
Some other times they are not clotted and I don't feel so good.
How you underline that symptom? You underline 1,2 or 3 times?
Who underlines once? Who underlines twice? Who underlines 3 times? Very lonely.
So most of the class will underline it twice, this is correct. You underline, it is quite strong
but not absolutely in frequency, it's clear, it's strong but not in frequency absolutely.
So you go a little bit down on the third. Take another symptom.
For instance desires coffee, who has underline it in your paper 3 times? OK.
Who has underlined it twice? And who has underlined it once?
Most people is 3 times, very close to those with 2 times.
The way you hear it is between 2-3 times, that's correct but when you think the way I thought
or I explained it, I may not take it into consideration at all or I put it one time.
Just not because she did not say it strongly but if there is something that gives you energy
and you are used to take.
You are used to take coffee 4 years ago?
-Yes.
-So you know the effect of the coffee, you remember. So this is what she said, for 4 years
I did not drink coffee but I have the need for coffee. She remembers the energy that
coffee can give her, she does not sleep, of course, then it calms down.
Why at the same time the symptom perspiration from emotions, how much you underline?
Who has underlined it once? Who has underlined it twice and who 3 times?
This symptom is between 2 and 3 times because it is strange, we have only a few
symptoms, and she has said it quite clearly. Because it is strange, because it has been
described clearly in a few remedies, that we take into consideration very seriously.
Next symptom. Forgets the words while speaking. Who has underlined it once?
Who has underlined it twice? Who has underlined 3 times?
This symptom the way she said it, you can underline it 3 times.
We have Baryta carb. and Helleborus, Phos. acid is lower, Sepia is not there, Calc.
carb. is not there, Cal. phos. is not there, Arsenicum is not there.
-Which of the two we take?
-Both. There is another rubric also which you can use also...
Ecchymosis, how many times you underlined? Who underlined once? Twice? 3 times?
Once.
-We didn't mention her sensitivity to noises.
-We didn't mention sensitivity to noises. Slight noise or any noise?
-Clock.
-Low noise and repeated sound but you said something about paper.
-Not paper, when somebody is eating something an apple or chips I can't stand.
Or I leave or I say stop or I start to eat myself.
-This is the best.
-There is exactly the rubric sensitive to noises when others eating apples.
-What is the remedy?
-Lyssinum. When somebody is eating apples, which is what she says.
This is what I say, in this little information, you don't go and give Lyssinum in this case
but sometimes it will happen that you need this information.
This is very strange. The Uva I never added Uva in this. There are a lot of things.
Uva is the shell of the egg, Asarum is very strong of course and I have added this,
this is true, I don't believe is Kent who said it but I said this to be upgraded,
Coffea and Theridion.
So Sepia is t here which was added by Gala Barden.
After you have analyzed all this case very carefully then you come to the decision that
she will have to take Platina.
The right decision at this moment is that we don't prescribe a remedy. We wait to see
whether she will develop into Sepia state or Calc. carb. state or to Platina or whatever.
-One more point for Calc. phos. The offensive leucorrhea with the sweetish smell
is rather peculiar symptom and there are only two remedies and one is Calc. phos.
-The other one?
-Mercurius corrosivus.
-Yes that is true. Another peculiar symptom is the sweetish smell of leucorrhea which
we did not pay attention.
Actually I had decided long ago that this case will go without a remedy of course
but you don't decide you go without remedy because you like it.
Because you feel it's not Calc. it's not Cal. phos., it's not Sepia, it's not Arsenicum, wait.
And then you expect one of these remedies to develop. What will be the remedy?
We don't know, maybe she comes next May and a beautiful picture of Calc. phos. and
then the whole class says, Calc. phos.
You have to be patient and you don't have to cure the patient, the way the patient likes
because she likes of course to get rid of the leucorrhea and not to be cramped
but you don't like it. You wait, you give placebo.
The matter remains that we can not at this moment decide that this is a case of Calc.
carb. Do you like eggs? I didn't want to ask the key question. Do you like eggs?
You like. Very much? What type of eggs? Soft boiled. That is another point for Calc. carb.
Still I would be careful not to give Calc. carb. I still will be careful but I will say watch out.
Most probably you are going to develop Calc. carb. with the lumbago, with the cramps.
She is developing but we want to improve the health, we don't want to be in a hurry and
spoil the case.
Sweets? She says, I'm not interested. That point alone...
I ask do you perspire in bed during sleep, she says not at all.
OK, these two keynotes I don't have for confirming Calc. carb.
If it was a first time case I say OK we have to prescribe Calc. but now the way that
develops the case with all these changes, I better be careful.
So she is going towards the Calc. carbon., we will see in May perhaps what is happening.
-But she is looking to a very happy life now, could it be that with all these happy events
the body can recover totally by itself?
-Yes, of course, we wait, we'll see. Because the body is at a process of recovering.
At the same time it has a positive shock. Already the sighing is reduced, the cramps are not
reduced and also the leucorrhea is not reduced.
Do you remember I asked, the leucorrhea is diminishing?
These are important questions to evaluate whether we should give a remedy or not.
Is the leucorrhea much more? That could take us towards the Sepia.
If the leucorrhea was increasing constantly, that would take us towards Sepia again.
The cold and clammy sweat take us directly to Calc. carb. but perspiration from emotions
confuse you again because it takes you back to some other remedies which is not Calc.
Therefore we better wait with the possibility that this case will go either to Calc. or Sepia.
Thank you