-Give us a resume of your case.
You came here in September 1999 for the first time with asthmatic bronchitis
and what else?
I prescribed Guaiacum and in case this does not work you should take Aconitum
and in case this does not work, Stramonium.
So tell us what you did.
-Guaiacum didn't show any effect, the cough was exactly the same, energy too.
I didn't take Aconite because there was no more panic attacks.
-I prescribed Guaiacum because of these panic attacks.
-There has been this accident before and after this accident, I had a lot of fears
and these panic attacks ceased, I didn't have them anymore and then I took Stramonium...
-And panic attacks came back?
-No.
The cough went away, I had fist slow aggravation and the energy slowly went better
and only then I realized how low it had been. It quickly increased the energy.
But emotionally for one week I was feeling very much worse,
this feeling of being deserted, left alone, loneliness was much worse.
-After Stramonium?
-Yes, then this got better but emotionally I didn't feel well.
I fell back to my love sickness.
-What she means by love sickness? She means love, nostalgia?
-I terminated a relationship in June 1999 and then there was this accident and afterwards
I fell back into my sadness, my love sickness concerning this man and then
on Christmas I sent you fax listing my symptoms and you faxed back that I should take Ignatia 1M.
After taking Ignatia a lot of things happened.
I think I mentioned when I was first giving the history here, this feeling of guilt,
I feel as if I have done something wrong and feel guilty but I wouldn't know what it was.
Then it got clear to me and I could remember a sexual abuse in my childhood.
-After Ignatia?
-Yes.
And I think it was something that this man told me then that I had done
something really evil and nobody should know about this.
I think then as a child I was very lonely because I could go nowhere with this
and I closed it up within myself and that only got clear to me now
that I thought when this kept on my shoulders, I can't really become happy.
I think this has something to do with my spells of desperation,
all of my life I had periods and spells of real desperation
and I never knew where it was coming from and I think that was related to this experience too.
There was always a feeling that I'm not allowed to be happy, that this is not for me
and since now I didn't understand what this is all about, the desperation is not as deep
as it has been and it got clear to me that it is not my guilt
but that I have been carrying the guilt of another person. So that happened.
-No asthma now?
-No but still it left a sort of a nervous cough.
-From time to time, in certain hours or in the night?
-Every now and then and it always happens when I remember these things.
But it's only for short time, it wouldn't last.
-There is no breaking out in the skin?
-After Ignatia it was rush coming out around my breast, red spots and it was itching
but it wouldn't last for long, it came several times and it was going very quickly.
-What about the leucorrhea?
-This gradually got better but now after the last menstruation I had leucorrhea again
for 3 days which was quite strong but then it went away.
-By September last year she said she had no menses. That means menses started again.
-I was still in Alonissos when I was having a relation and 14 days later the menstruation started.
-How long she did not have menstruation?
-From August to October.
-And the shock took place in June-July?
-The accident was in August.
And afterwards the menses stopped.
-But first was the separation in June-July?
-The menstruation ceased in August after the accident.
-How is the fear of the dark? She had so strong fear of the dark.
-It is still there but it's not so strong as it used to be.
-The fear of accidents?
-That is still there.
-Quite strong? Because here we had put it on 4th degree.
-Not as strong as it was, it is in latent state.
-The fear of death?
-Still there in latent phase but not as pronounced as it used to be.
-She complained also of a weakness on the heart area, you remember?
-That is still there and I often have a stumbling, this is a very forceful beat of my heart
and palpitations. This is quite frequent.
-There was a sensation of tiredness in the eyes.
-That is better.
-Also if she remembers, she has said that the air outside aggravates her.
It was the asthma or it was a general aggravation, whether she is still aggravated by open air.
-The aggravation, as far as I remember was due to cold air.
-Cold air then the cough aggravated, that was one.
But then I have here on the notes that a general aggravation from open air, as well.
-That is there no more.
-She drunk any milk?
-I have a strong aversion for milk, for the time being.
-Still it's there. What about the restlessness in bed, she was very restless.
-That is still there and I have a hard time falling asleep and when I'm sleepless
I'm very restless and turning around.
-How much salt she takes?
-Completely normal.
-The desire for sweets is still there?
-That is as strong as it has been.
-What about ice cream?
-Not that much.
-Fruit?
-I like it.
Abdominal pains and I think is due to my anger.
Psychologically I'm in a state where I feel a lot of anger.
-She feels the anger? She expresses the anger?
-No, I can't do this.
I feel the anger is there but I'm not able to express and then the abdominal pain starts.
I think this is related to this man too who was sexually abusing me and I fantasy of violence.
-Killing him?
-To hit him and to stab him with a knife.
-She knows the man?
-He was a neighbor.
-So she knows.
-I wouldn't know now where he lives now.
-So there is anger towards him specifically or anger towards her boyfriend for instance.
-Yes, this is generally. The thing is that this happened over and over again in my life,
like this man was using me sexually.
-Who, the original man?
-In my childhood, this man was using me sexually and my soul didn't matter to him.
He didn't mind and that happened to me over and over again that men wanted to sleep with me
but my soul just didn't matter anything to them. And that makes me really angry.
-How she feels towards the last man, after Ignatia she forgot him or he is still there.
-I haven't forgotten him.
-She has another affair at the moment?
-I'm fleeing at the moment when a man is approaching me.
-She doesn't trust.
-Another physical complaint, here around my eye, there is growing a tight thing.
A sort of a wart.
-Anything else? How is her sleep in the night, is it constant?
-That differs a lot.
It may happen that I sleep well but it may also happen that I don't sleep very well.
I'm easily excited.
If something happens, I'm easily excited and if I'm excited I can't really sleep well.
-During day in the noon time, does she take a nap?
-Every now and then but very rarely and mostly I can't fall asleep.
I have difficulties in falling asleep.
-If she does fall asleep, that sleep makes her feel good, she wakes up well?
-It does well. But it's rare that I fall asleep.
-I had headaches and that was coming up more frequently that two times
I had headaches by the sun and that was completely new
but maybe I was staying in the sun for too long.
-Generally she feels very warm, very cold?
-In the winter very cold but now it's summer so it's OK but I'm rather on the cold side.
-How is her sexual desire?
-This is normally very high but I'm not able to sleep and have sex with a man
and I don't have feelings for him and I won't just be able to sleep with him
if I don't feel for him. But there are lots of erotic thoughts.
I don't remember if I had analyzed this case last time. Who has notes? Why I gave Guaiacum...
Did I tell you? You have your notes?
-In my notes I read that you prescribed Guaiacum because of the shock she had, the fright.
-This is what I wanted to say, whether I had mentioned this
because I want to again comment on the Guaiacum.
Guaiacum is a remedy which has after effects of fright and you may have asthma,
you may have rheumatoid arthritis, you may have headaches
and because it lives within the sub-conscious mind a kind of a state
which is a state similar to Aconite or Stramonium but I prefer to start with Guaiacum.
In this case most probably I had some other reasons,
I don't remember and Guaiacum took away, she said, the panic attacks.
Guaiacum took away the panic attack but did not affect the cough,
which means that Guaiacum acted partially.
And normally because it did not act curatively, it should have aggravated even perhaps
the other conditions, like the asthma or whatever.
Stramonium was the correct remedy and then what happened.
The organism started dealing more with the grief.
There is the separation, there is the accident, there is this big fright that comes
after the accident, that stops the menses, brings out this condition and the fear
and all that which is taken away by Stramonium and then the organism wants
to deal with the grief of the separation from the boyfriend and she starts having these problems
and she writes the fax.
In the fax most probably she wrote some symptoms of Ignatia,
that's why I prescribed Ignatia.
And I was ready to say, wait. Then she mentioned the anger
and the repercussion of the anger in the abdomen.
Which symptoms you have used? You have used nervous cough.
On this I have to comment, nervous cough is a very characteristic symptom of Ignatia.
Nervous cough is a hysterical kind of a cough which they cough, cough, cough,
they can not even breathe and then it goes away and then comes next day, after 2-3 days.
Hysterical kind of coughing, repeated coughing which goes away as sudden
as it has come and it comes because of grief usually.
In such cases the causative factor of this cough is grief. Now she says, she never coughs.
Then ailments of emotional excitement, fear of accidents not so much, fear of dark not so much,
weakness heart, about the heart palpitation, aversion milk, tossing about in in bed  restlessness,
chocolate desire, fruit desire, suppressed ailments from anger, violent, disappointed love,
suspicious, sexual desire increased.
Sexual thoughts, maybe you can take away sexual desire increased,
I'm not sure that this is correct.
Show me now what is the Expert System says? Staphysagria and second Ignatia.
Staphysagria shot up. Why Staphysagria? Show me why, explain why?
Because she has 9 symptoms, palpitation of the heart, milk aversion, tossing about,
chocolate, fruit, anger suppressed, love disappointed, suspicious etc.
And we have to think about Staphysagria because everybody most probably was thinking
of Staphysagria, yes or no? That is the question. Here the repertorisation says yes.
-You can add...  which is growing. I think it is in Staphysagria, it's not added,
it's very strong point.
-Where can I find it in the Repertory? Did you find it?
-Yes. Growth in the face of what?
-Tumor.
-Tumor is very strong.
Now what I think is, let me give you the analysis, my evaluation of the case.
We have given remedies like Stramonium and Ignatia to deal with her shocks
and the organism is dealing with this quite all right but still she says, my anger is there.
Now what we have to do is to say, shall we help this organism to take away anger?
To counteract the anger by giving a dose of Staphysagria or should we still wait
to see this organism how will develop. Why?
Because if we give Staphysagria and Staphysagria is not correct, is going to interfere
because it's very close.
It's going to interfere with the case. Now the case is doing quite well,
in spite of this anger being there.
I want to see if this organism lead by itself with the remedy she had already, whether
she will deal with this anger in a more conscious way.
She does not like the idea, she wants to take Staphysagria
but why I said that is I tell you a little detail which I don't like.
A typical Staphysagria, if she sleeps in the afternoon wakes up in a terrible state.
If she would have told me, I wake up in a terrible state, I would say OK
but she was not able to confirm that important keynote of Staphysagria.
Therefore I will wait either to see that this keynote will come, where I will have the seal,
yes Staphysagria is there, or what I will see is that the organism by itself will sort out the anger.
The fact also, she has sexual thoughts is in favor of Staphysagria also.
Staphysagria does not like, as I have said in the Materia Medica,
does not like to have sex, they like to have first contact and then sex.
And I have said that is why Staphysagria many times will resort to masturbation.
They prefer to have that instead of having...
They can not have sex without the emotional attachment, without the emotional synchronicity.
They are too sensitive, they feel vulnerable so they will not go to bed
without having this emotional connection.
And what she is saying, she is actually saying that and yet I would like to have further confirmation,
before I give it.
Because she is doing well and I don't want to improve matters too fast to spoil the case
and then when she comes back here, she comes back in a confused state
and we don't know what to do.
Therefore you have only 10 minutes of interval and we go for the next case.
You would like to say something?
-What would you do, if the symptom you are waiting for, does not appear and the state remains,
as it is, unchanged, what would you do then?
-Let's say it remains for 6 months, I will give it. I will give it.
-This decision is confusing me a bit because we always learn with every keynote
or every symptom can be there but it's not a must that the patient has to have all the keynotes
before you can give the remedy.
-I explain. This case is doing well. This is different than if she was saying,
I'm suffering I have this, I have that. Then I would have given it.
But at this moment I say, wait to see whether the organism by itself will clear up this internal anger.
Because she is aware now. She says, I know what has happened to me,
so that means the logical mind is in control of the situation.
The organism may find a way to readjust itself and settle down the anger
because it's not urgent that I should give this.
So I have now time to wait and see what happens until I have more confirmation.