-OK, we start and she must remind us what was the problem.
She got Calc. phos.?
-I took Calc. phos. C12 for quite some time and till Christmas I went up to C200,
that means I took once C30 and once C200 and twice I smelled it.
-So what was the reaction?
-In the midst of December I was psychologically really doing very well.
I only took the remedy when here, right on my back in the middle part,
it was like my spine was closing up.
Then I felt terrible fear, my head has no more blood circulation
and always in moment like this I took the remedy and it quickly helped.
-When she started taking the remedy?
-I was here in September but in June I started taking the remedy a C12 once the week.
-And then she came here on September ...
-And then you said that I don't need the remedy at all, what I need is just a very deep crying
because it was always connecting with the death of my mother and my father.
-But I suggested Calc. phos. 30 or 200?
-You didn't suggest anything, you told me that I should know when to take it.
-From September now to December she took it several times?
-Yes, I took C30 and C200 and I smelled in addition twice the C200.
And during that time in the beginning of December I was feeling that I get a heart attack
and I get a stroke and my system was totally upset but it was just on the physical plane.
It took me two months up to December to find out that Calc. phos.
has something to do with discontent.
Getting this idea I was trying to find out and look up all the discontentment in my life.
And I found out that all my life I have been really basically discontented
and it was just by very strong religious education that I had covered this up all the time.
I didn't even realize it, perceive it anymore.
And this with Calc. phos. really got to my awareness.
I had a little flu and like always with me I didn't have any fever
and that was when this changing between Calcarea and phosphorica started to come up.
After these three days of being all alone at home, I was not even able to go out on the street
and meet other people because all the impulses would directly go through me.
It was really like everything, advertising, forms and colors would really like fall into me.
-When it was that?
-That was around the beginning of December.
Then I was told that my father had sold the house without letting me know
and now the tears come.
-The house belonged to him or to her mother?
-Belonged to him but after the death of my mother, I tried to project my feeling
of being at home to this house.
That was like an intermediate step for me to get along with my father again.
And then gradually I cleaned and cleared the house, just piece after piece,
I took out all the belongings of my mother and I always had the feeling and I asked myself,
I really wondered, am I going mad now because I had the impression that what I did
I had to save these things for my father.
This is just what I wanted to stress that even at this time when I had to clear the house,
taking everything out, I already had the feeling I had to save things for my father.
At the end of April the house had to be totally clean
and my brother made the moving of the things.
My brother would throw away everything that any respect could be of any value for my father.
So family situation before had been like such.
I had practically no contact to my brother, very difficult contact to my father
and a very good relationship to my mother.
And since my mother died, my father and me were both like little kids, like little children
and my brother just whatever he thinks of, he just does what he wants.
He just decides what is going to happen with all these things and both of us,
my father and me were standing there hopelessly.
My father meanwhile had been to the hospital and I was always driving to
and from and physically I was completely rag.
She lives in Berlin and her father in Munich, as far as I understood.
So every week was 100 km by car. Then my hands started burning, I got slight inflammation
of my tendons in the lower arm.
-She is driving with the car herself or she goes by train?
-By car.
-That means she drives for 12 hours?
-6 hours each way.
-Still I have not understood whether she likes her father?
Why she goes every weekend in the moment she does not like him.
-It completely changed after the death of my mother.
-So she feels connected?
-And I have the feeling that I have to help him.
-He is now in the hospital?
-Now he is at home.
-What was the problem with her father?
-He had a pulse of 33 bits per minute, both cardio valves weren't functioning well anymore.
He had ulcers on his legs, edemas on his legs, so going up to the heart.
And she said before I now feel towards my father like I've been feeling before for 6 years
for my mother. Like she is helpless and I have to support her.
-Where does she attribute these pains? To a lot of driving, to over exertion?
-Driving a car I quickly learned even to repertorize, while I'm driving.
I was imagining the patients, had a piece of paper next to me and then let it pass through
my inner eye  and just make notes and I had better ideas than when I was sitting at my desk.
At home I would do the repertorization again and mostly it was fine.
At that time I was working 3 days in Berlin and 4 days per week I was staying in Munich,
so I had really to be very busy within these 3 days because I had to do the work of 5 days
and I was working like paragraph 291 and worked and examined on every patient,
on the physical plane, like I would feel all the muscles, I really over exerted my tendons
and had these pains.
And all these impulses I got from the patients, they fell right into me.
It was like all electrical impulses falling into me and one day there were two spots
on my right breast and within hours they were heating up like Berberis and I had the feeling like,
as if within hours, they were developing hot spots, hot nodules.
On that week I went to see a participant of the course
and she gave me Phosphorus LM 6 three times
and one week later I would take a Q12 and everything was gone.
And another thing that comes up when I'm so over exerted is that when I overdo myself
I feel these burning meninges, which is due to a meningitis which I had years ago.
And this feeling of the meningitis like it had been at that time came again now about 4 weeks ago.
And it's still there, in between intermediate, I have the feeling that
I only can have my neck pulled back and everything is stiff going downwards.
This is now the state of affairs which after Phosphorus is somehow balanced.
-So if ask what are the symptoms at the moment, what she would say?
-For the time being I recovered quite well except from the last 3 days
and today my meninges are just like fire.
-Because she over worked? Because of the examination?
-Because it is excitement too and exertion, it is exhausting the exam.
-Headaches of school girls is called this.
-Then the first anniversary of my mother death came, that was on the 5th of April
and I forgot the date but not my body.
I completely freaked out, I was feeling so full of hatred, I was shouting at people,
insulting them and then I really flit into my office, into my practices
and I was sitting there for some minutes and then I thought
this is exactly like Nat. muriaticum state I was in after the death of my mother.
And then, like a year ago I took Nat. mur. 10M.
The effect was that within one hour I was out of this state
but after this everything was very narrow in my brain, in my head
and I know this from former times, too.
What I haven't had so far was an understanding for people in grief and now I have it.
What brought the week following were icy cold feet,
it was one week after the 5th of April, icy cold feet they were like a big clumb.
One day I ate an egg salad made of 10 eggs, which usually I wouldn't do...
-10 eggs!
-Yes, obviously the Calcarea state would come up and during the night my neck was wet,
not in the back but in the front.
Some days later I had burning feet, they were so hot, I couldn't wear any shoes
and for about 25 years for the first time I had the feeling I'm really absolutely lazy.
-After Calc. carbonica?
-Not carbonica, I didn't take it.
-But the last remedy she had so far was Nat. muriaticum 10M
and then after the Nat. mur. was the cold feet and the desire for eggs
and then the sweating and then the hot feet.
Until now?
-It was changing then but now here in the warmth outside, I'm having warm feet.
And what was changing too with the Nat. mur. is that about 3 years ago,
I had a kidney inflammation and nephritis and when I was getting the Nat. mur. 10X,
after the grief for my mother, immediately the kidney got warm and this time too.
With the state of Nat. mur. obviously my buttocks are very cold and the kidneys too
and then all the energy is gone and it flows out of my head and my tonsils are swollen.
Every time I'm greedy, I'm punishing myself for it afterwards.
This is really very strong.
Concerning my senses I'm a very lively personality and always when I get the feeling
that I'm crossing a border I sort of punish myself. What is there?
Since my first menstruation, the fissures between my toes are so deep
I have to peel off the skin that is above the fissures,
otherwise they will tear even further down.
Cones on my toes. I have 3 of them. On the little toe and in between.
As a child I had warts on my soles, once they had been burned of
and then they reappeared and when I was about 30, I was speaking to them
and then they disappeared.
Water is real problem for me, when I go into the water, I don't warm up afterwards.
That is really a problem for me.
I had a fear of dogs, that was so pronounced that my hands would grip with water
when I only would meet a dog.
I mentioned it last time. I got Arsenicum and then later on Causticum
and after Causticum it disappeared for about a 3-4 years. It was gone.
2 years ago I had a very severe influenza with fever, first time in my life
and then I took Causticum 1M and after this the fear of dog was gone
and in nowadays I can touch every dog.
Concerning my menstruation, before menstruation I'm irritable up to really picking fights.
When my menstruation starts I have to lie down for 2 hours. If I don't do this,
I don't come up to my energy level for about a week.
During this time I have very deep fissures in my anus, itching and really very swollen abdomen.
-Because of flatus?
-The whole tissue is like swollen, then I have a very swollen abdomen.
-As if she has a lot of fat in there? Flabbiness.
-Then I feel nauseous and I have to belch like an automatic machine gun.
I once made a proving of Argentum nitricum up to the C200 and this symptom occurred
after this proving and for the time being is getting worse and worse.
I'm sleeping on my abdomen, one knee is caught against the body and one is stretched
and I'm turning a lot and this changed since I'm here on Alonissos.
And yesterday I had a massage because my third vertebrae had been dislocated
and she really must have done a good job because all changed into really severe lumbago afterwards.
And I hardly can lie on my back, it's really pretty bad.
This too started about 3-4 weeks ago, while I was doing some yoga exercises,
where you have to breathe onto the pelvis and then breathe out onto the vertebrae spine.
I did it at maximum 3 times the day and that was enough that the whole plate
was getting inflamed and it was a feeling as if the flash would go off the bones.
-So painful?
-And the same would arise around here.
-How she feels with drafts?
-Not in my neck but in my back.
-What about cold? She is cold, hot, where she stands now?
-I got warmer but my tolerance between cold and heat is very small.
-How is her head? How is the mental condition? She has more clear head?
-It got clearer now due to the fact that this part is open now but I'm still having headaches
on different locations.
-How is her thirst?
-I don't feel thirsty but when I drink, I will drink half a liter at the time.
-She had perspiration after excitement, now she mentions nausea after excitement.
-My hands are completely wet and to my axillae.
-What about eggs now?
-I eat at least 3 the day, for the time being.
-Sweets?
-Not so much, I do eat some.
-What about salt?
-I like salty things but not as much as I used to. This went down after taking Nat. muriaticum.
-The irritability before menses is very great? It's more than before?
-No, it stays the same.
-The fissure stays the same, as before?
-They are always there, they are like before but the itching is nearly unbearable
during the time of menses.
It's itching all the time but during the menses it's nearly unbearable
and there are all different kinds of hemorrhoids but during the time of menses they are swollen.
-What about perspiration before menses?
-3 nights before menses, during the night I'm all wet around the breast area.
It's so much perspiration that the bed would be wet.
-Still there is? More than before?
-No, it stayed the same.
-What about bacon, pork she likes this time? Smoked meat?
-Up to the time of the C200 of Calc. phoshorica was acting, I would unpack the sausages
and eat them right in the shop.
-Now not anymore?
-If it's a real good salami, I will still eat it; otherwise not.
-But she still has it now this desire?
-It's got much less.
-The desire for eggs it was there underlined once, now is more the way she says it.
-I've never in my life eaten so many eggs.
-So it has increased.
-The desire eggs got much stronger.
-What about vertigo high places?
-When I was a child my father carried me down from a mountain tour
because I couldn't descend anymore.
-And her feet at this moment with this heat in bed, they are warm, cold, normal?
-In bed normal but I wouldn't be able to sleep without wearing trousers
because I can't sleep without my knees being covered.
-Because she feels cold in her knees especially?
-At night.
-OK, take a dose of Calcarea carbonica 200.