-It' another case we have to see. What is your main problem?
-Now I can say that is the fact that I can not make normal relationship with a man
because I'm afraid and I don't feel anything. It's like an object for me.
-A man is like an object? It doesn't bring out some emotions?
-No.
-No emotions at all.
-Even if he touches me or he kisses me, no feeling.
-But would you say it's almost an aversion or it is neutral?
-It's neutral, I want to be kind, to open to him but I can't.
-You can not. When this happened?
-This happened about 4 years ago.
-So what happened 4 years ago?
-I fall in love with someone at the first sight and totally and we were together
about 1 year and we talked about marriage and the future.
He showed me very much affection he was very kind with me and one day before Christmas
in the evening he was OK he came to my parents, talked to them.
-To arrange the marriage?
-For the engagement and the next day when we usually meet, he said we must separate
because I do not love you so much as I wanted to and I want to finish.
-How much older was this man?
-About 38-40.
-You were 20?
-I was 32 and he was 38.
-And he was married before?
-No and he is not now.
-So he felt great responsibility from one day to the other and
he flew away from the responsibility.
So we would give him Lycopodium if we had him now but we don't have him,
he made the damage.
After that how you felt, can you described to me?
-That night I wished to be dead and at home I couldn't say anything
because my mother was in treatment at him, he was stomatological doctor
and if I would say something maybe my mother would not finish and I went home
very happy and I didn't say anything for 3 weeks.
-You don't speak to anybody, you just cry or you didn't cry?
-Yes I cried a lot.
-But you cried by yourself.
-Yes on the way to the office and coming back and in the night.
-When nobody could see you. That was the idea.
-Yes. Actually at that time I don't know how I lived because for me
I was walking to the office because I couldn't take a bus and I just couldn't see
people or cars.
It doesn't matter, I cross the street and I didn't know if a car comes or not.
It was like in a dream.
-And when you were back home?
-I was happy.
-You ate whatever and then you went to your room and you locked your room?
-No because if I lock my room, my mother would come and say what happened.
No, no. I expect the night.
-And you could sleep or you had to think, think, think?
-No, I just think, think, think and I had insomnia for 3-4 months.
-You could not sleep. And all these nights you were crying and you were suffering?
-Only 3 weeks and every night I said tomorrow I will not be weak anymore,
tomorrow I will stop, he does not deserve it.
And I said to myself that never in my life I will be in love with someone.
-It was a deep hurt.
-Yes, in the office if a man opened the door, I just cry.
It starts without wanting.
And I couldn't be touched for about 4 months by anybody, woman or man.
-And now you can be touched by someone?
-Yes but I don't feel anything.
-Yes but if another woman touches you it doesn't matter.
-Yes it's OK, it doesn't matter.
-But if a man touches you also, it's indifferent.
-Yes.
-Do you have a desire to have a relationship?
-Sexually do you have some phantasies?
-No, no.
-Not at all. Now you can sleep?
-It's a problem because a year and a half ago I started a treatment to a homeopath.
-What remedies you took?
-A lot. Anacardium, Agaricus, Ignatia, Sulphur, Berberis, Lac can., a lot. Maybe 30.
When I go for the first time to the homeopath, I think it was the shortest visit.
In two words I said everything it was a problem with my eyes and that's all.
No fears, no problems, no grief, anything and he probably didn't know what to give me
and I don't know, I can't remember what he gave me but after that
I had 5 months of insomnia and I took all kind of remedies for this insomnia.
-But you did not know the first remedy what it was?
-No, I can't remember. I think it was China but I'm not sure.
-You never had Nat. mur.?
-I think I had once 30, one dose of 30.
-Sepia?
-Sepia no.
-Tell me do you like salt?
-No, normal.
-Sweets?
-Yes a lot.
-Your menses had been affected at all?
-Yes they became irregular and they stopped.
-Instead of menses do you have leucorrhea, some discharge?
-Yes and it appears migraine, headaches.
-Which are mostly where?
-They begin to occipital and then they come forward over the eyes and
it's about 2-3 days I have a headache. I wake up in the morning with a headache.
-And they last how long?
-2-3 days. And in this period all other symptoms and pains are gone.
-For instance what other pains?
-Pains from the back.
-So you are suffering with back pains as well which come when?
-They are permanent. After the homeopathic treatment they became permanent.
Before they were only in winter.
-Mostly right or left, can you say where the headaches are mostly?
-No, it's the whole head. And it becomes like an explosion, I feel like the head will explode.
-That means you had China most probably. China has these headaches.
-(?)
-Sometimes yes, not always.
-Now for how long your menses have stopped? For 1 year, 2 years?
-No, for 1 month.
-And the discharge leucorrhea since when is appearing?
-It is almost permanent.
-It is quite a lot, what color?
-It is a lot and it is yellow.
-It's good you did not take the Nat. mur.
-She took.
-It doesn't matter. Can you tell me if you like to sleep in a certain position?
-On the left side. Because I have pains if I sleep on back or in any other position.
Only on the left.
-Before that incident your emotions were strong? You had strong emotions?
-Yes and no.
-Your emotions were equal?
-I would say I could have real relationship with a man.
-During that year when you had the relationship, did you have sexual intercourse?
-No because he didn't want.
-But you wanted? You had the desire?
-Yes. It was the only time that I had desire.
-Before that you did not have and after that also you did not have.
-I see.
-Do you have any peculiar symptoms in your back pains?
Would you say I have that peculiar symptom?
-I have a pain like blow which is permanent on the lower back.
-But is it better by lying down, worse by lying down, something very clear?
-No, it is permanent.
-Do you have any fears?
-A lot.
-What is your biggest fear?
-Now it's death.
-Fear of death. Next to this?
-To be lonely, to remain alone.
-And the fear of death comes together with some fear of cancer, fear of heart disease
or you will die soon, anything of that type?
-No, I just think that death scares me very much. I was many times in front of death.
-In the hospital?
-No, myself. Several times I was almost drowned.
-By accident?
-Yes, I don't know how to swim and I go further than I could and somebody took me out.
Then I was near to an accident car when I was driving and since then I can't drive.
I was too scared. And earthquakes.
-You fear earthquakes?
-Yes.
-Any other fear?
-Of robbers.
-Is it strong?
-Really strong because several times they tried to break into my house
and to cut my bed and so on.
-Just put it once. You have thirst? What do you need?
-I need cold water also in winter I drink cold water.
-Ice cold?
-In summer ice cold but in winter cold by the refrigerator.
-And you have aversion to milk? Or you can take some?
-Yes, I can drink but I don't like it much.
And it is something from my past. When I was 16 I suddenly became ill, nobody knows
what it is, it was after an operation of appendix and after 3 months where nobody could
tell me what it is, some doctor prescribed me tuberculostatic drugs.
-For tuberculosis?
-Yes.
-Did you check yourself to see what it was?
-Yes but it was negative.
-And still he gave you the antitubercular drug?
-Yes they said that perhaps it was in genital.
-When you sneeze or you cough do you have loss of urine?
-Sometimes.
And maybe it is important to say that in my family it was a lot of cancer.
-Your parents died from cancer?
-My grand parents, 3 of them died from cancer and my mother had cancer.
She was operated.
-Would you say are you very timid?
-Yes.
-And also you have low self confidence?
-Very much?
-Yes, very.
-But I see here in your hobbies you like dancing. Is this something that
you enjoy very much?
-Yes I love music and it gives me some quietness and peace.
-Loud music?
-Very loud.
-Loud and rhythmic?
-Not rhythmic, meditation music.
-Here dancing is underlined 3 times. It's really so strong?
-Yes.
-And you feel better in the afternoon?
-Yes I can work better in the afternoon, evening.
-Do you feel very much in a hurry inside you?
-Yes. I'm in a great hurry.
-But you sit there very quiet, you don't look in a hurry at all.
-Yes but I want to do everything very quickly.
-And do you want to do 3 jobs at the same time?
-Yes, if it is possible.
-And do you want others to do things quickly?
-Yes.
-If they are slow, then you become angry?
-Yes, yes.
-Do you have aggression inside? Do you keep inside you, you feel you have kept
aggression, you are angry? You are a person who would fight easily?
-Yes, for anybody else yes, for me no.
-But you would fight for your friends or mother, father?
-Yes, it doesn't matter, who wants to be helped.
-When I say fight, I mean real fight, you go and kick them.
-No, no physically.
-But you would use bad words, you attack somebody by words or you just go
and help somebody only?
-To help.
-Not to fight, real fight?
-No.
-What would you answer to my question whether you feel aggression inside?
What is your answer to that?
-I don't know. Sometimes this is very rare, once the year perhaps, I become very angry
and I do not want anybody near me or if I'm at work, everybody must do the right thing
because if they don't, I'm very, very angry and I use bad words.
-By that time?
-Yes, it's like I try to get out from me to relieve but it's once the year.
-In your bed when you are sleeping, you are very restless or you stay in one position?
-No, I'm restless because I have pains.
-Otherwise you won't be restless according to you or you don't know?
-I don't know.
-What I ask you, everybody around you must hurry is very strong for you?
-Yes, I have a problem with time because I want to do everything very fast.
-Even if you have enough time, if you have 1 hour, you want to do it in 5 minutes?
-Yes.
-Is that what you say?
-And you want the others to do their job fast? If you see them doing it slowly...
-I get angry.
-And you say you have clairvoyant dreams?
-Yes.
-Are you clairvoyant?
-I don't know.
-The leucorrhea which you have, it is since 11 years old when the menses started.
It started again with leucorrhea almost immediately?
-Yes.
-During the time when you felt the desire for sex do you remember you still had the
leucorrhea or during that time the leucorrhea was reduced?
-I can't remember.
-It was more, it was less?
-No.
-In general you feel cold, warm?
-Cold.
-And you suffer from cold?
-Yes but not much. Before the remedies I was very cold.
-But after so many remedies at least this is cured. What about your nails? Are strong?
-No.
-They break easily?
-They are soft?
-Soft yes.
And when I have an acute disease, I do not make fever of perspiration.
-You never have fever?
-No.
-When you have an acute disease, you don't have fever.
-You have taken Arsenicum in the past?
-Yes.
-I took only low potencies.
-You have a lot of warts?
-Yes they appear on the head, in the hands.
-Can you show me these warts? What do you mean wart?
These black spots you call warts? These are not warts.
-No, this appeared last time about half a year. These black nodes.
-No, it's not a wart.
How are your feelings towards your parents?
-They have a lot of affection to me.
-They have not changed this affection after this incident?
-No.
-It became more?
-I can say yes.
-This hurried feeling do you remember how long you have it?
-It is...
-It is with you all the time as much long as you remember?
Even as a child you were so much in a hurry?
-Yes, yes.
-Do you do physical exercises?
-No because I have pains.
-But before the pains, as a young woman, 13,14,15?
-No.
-Did you like running?
-Not physical exercise. Do you like to read?
-To read or to make something else but not that.
-Do you like to walk?
-Walk only if I'm upset.
-Then you go to walk fast or slowly?
-Fast.
-And then slowly you calm down?
-No I calm down also fast.
-Walking fast ameliorates?
-Yes.
-Now you weep, you cry easily now?
-No.
-Even if you want, you can not?
-Even if I want, I can not.
-Even if you are alone at home?
-No.
-You can not cry. And you like to be with company or you like to be alone?
-I like company. I'm afraid to be alone.
-Do you like fruits?
-Yes.
-A lot?
-No.
-Would you say that your memory is not so good?
-No, I have no problem.
-The general energy how is it? Of your body?
-Normal.
-Would you say you have more energy than normal?
-Maybe, I don't know.
-How many hours you sleep now?
-4-5 hours only.
-And this is enough for you to carry on?
-Sometimes yes but sometimes no, I wake up tired.
But in these 4 months of insomnia, I was not tired, I was fresh all the time
and I didn't sleep 1 week not at all.
And then 1,2 hours but OK.
-OK.
-You always sleep on the left side?
-Yes, if I have pains yes.
I like to sleep on the abdomen.
-OK, let's see.
This is a very instructive case from another point of view.
This is a case where everybody could give Nat. mur. and with good reasons, as I said,
in these case I gave you. I could have given you this case actually saying all this.
You remember when we analyzed the case here, when I write, I said this is a case of
typical Nat. mur.
Yet when we took the case more thoroughly and with the knowledge of the different remedies,
we saw the possibility of another remedy which is Sepia.
Sepia is a remedy which can be indicated after grief that stops sexual desire.
Sexual desire is finished, is gone and an aversion to sex starts.
The case showed that it was going towards Sepia until the time she gave out certain symptoms
of Tarentula.
The symptoms of Tarentula where this inner hurriedness which is so strong in her
and it's quite deep, it goes back as far as she could remember.
What brought us to the idea of Tarentula? Can anybody tell me?
-Dancing.
-Everybody must hurry.
-Everybody must hurry is characteristic of Tarentula, also liking of the loud music and
also liking of dancing but Sepia also like dancing.
Sepia likes dancing with the idea of exercise that does good to Sepia.
So here we have to decide between Nat. mur., Sepia and Tarentula and what
is going to be our first choice?
She was actually already given Nat. mur. by the fact I said this is typical Nat. mur.
So we can ask her now to see when did you take the remedy?
-3 days ago.
-Do you see any change?
-No.
-What potency?
-10M.
So in this particular case we have the proof already that most probably Nat. mur.
is not going to do anything and therefore we left with the two choices of Tarentula or Sepia.
What is the first remedy to start with?
-Sepia.
You see now even if I did not remember she had taken and I said, it's good
you did not take Nat. mur.
I don't remember in the analysis where I have said, the desire for salt is missing but
it was so typical with the information it was given, so typical of Nat. mur.
We make the mistake but since she has taken already 30 medicines, now she has taken 31.
It's not very important.
The remedy with which we should start is Sepia high potency and perhaps she will need for
a few days because an organism who has taken a lot of wrong remedies the body does not
react anymore to one dose.
You have to touch the organism 3-4 times before you can create a reaction.
Slow acting remedy, not only Nat. mur., every remedy can be slow acting but you have
some indications from the beginning whether the remedy is going to act or not and
these indications are not here.
The question is, I have heard that Nat. mur. is a slow acting remedy.
Can it be a slow acting remedy so the Nat. mur. will...?
And I say yes remedies can be slow acting, you can wait if you like but in this particular case
actually nothing will happen and if Nat. mur. is indicated at all, it will be after Sepia.
First you have to give Sepia. Why? Because of the whole case as it appeared but most
particularly about the leucorrhea which is strong feature in this case.
So leucorrhea with aversion to sex, leucorrhea in girls especially, shows that the remedy
you should start with is Sepia.
Maybe after Sepia if she develops desire for salt and sensitivity to sun, these two things
maybe she will need a dose of Nat. mur. before going into Tarentula.
If the hurried feeling, which belongs also to different other remedies, between them is the Nat. mur.,
if the hurried feeling does not go away, then you have to chose between Nat. mur. and Tarentula.
What I really believe it will happen, first she will take Sepia.
Then I believe she will feel better psychologically where maybe the back ache will become
even worse maybe, the headaches will be reduced, the back ache worse.
For a certain period of time the leucorrhea maybe even worse, a lot of leucorrhea
then the leucorrhea will start going down, then the pains will be more.
Then she most probably will develop some taste for salt and that is the time where Nat. mur.
should be repeated.
And if these two remedies, first Sepia and then Nat.mur. do not complete the cure,
maybe the possibility of Tarentula is there and we can have it as a possibility
and we can use it later on.
-We know that Tarentula has very big desire for sex. This is not something which speaks
against Tarentula?
-Yes, that's why we don't give Tarentula.
-We must know change the desire for sex to give Tarentula?
-At this moment we don't give Tarentula. One of the reasons that we don't give is because
Tarentula has a lot of sex but later on maybe that changes and the desire starts
and its' quite bothering and also the insomnia remains and the hurriedness.
So this combination will take us there but before we go to Tarentula, we have to deal with
the emotional side, which at this moment is pointing to Sepia.
-I'm curious what lead you into the line of leucorrhea about the hurrying?
It was just the history of the dancing or did you see something that seemed that she was hurrying?
-No, I did not see Tarentula in her but the history of dancing together with better with
music, amelioration from music and dancing, this combination gives you
the idea of Tarentula already.
Now she said another symptom, a third symptom of Tarentula which is everybody must hurry.
I repeated 3 times this question if you remember. To make sure that the symptom
was really there and still I go along with the main symptomatology where she said
my feelings towards the other sex have been totally deadened and this is
particularly Sepia and not Tarentula.
So maybe after Sepia, Tarentula will be indicated but I said before
Tarentula we have to try again Nat. mur.
Because for the feelings to come back I think we need some time, they don't come back so easily.