We had agreed that you start immediately with the beginning of a new crisis
but the remedy was not prepared yet so you waited for a week before you started it.
During that week the albumin was quite ... - Low, it was reduced very fast and when gets
The albumin which comes out... - It’s just albumin I’m leaking.
The globulins and all the proteins are not leaking. – How fast was the leaking?
In the first week it was quite high. – Before, I was leaking a little bit. It was a mild situation.
I didn’t take any medication and during this week I was waiting for the remedy.
I ran new lab tests and my albumin ran down really fast from 40 to 28
and then it was under 20 and then I started having the edemas.
I gained about 10 kilos during that week. When I was waking up in the morning
the edema was concentrated in the face, underneath the eyes and then it went down under
my belly and when I walked it was down in the ankles. I had to do something about it
because my homeopath was in touch with you and we agreed to distinguish
the medical situation, so I went to the hospital and had
an injection of SENDOXAN (Cyclophosphamide). They usually use it for cancer cases.
I took it intravenously and this is very strong medication they give me, but just for one day.
Then it took about a week for the protein to gradually stop leaking.
And then the albumin level started to raise, we took new tests, then I urinated very much
and I lost the weight very fast. I went down those 10 kg.
After a period I gradually got more energy and I am not so tired anymore.
We took new tests after a period of time and they said that my hemoglobin was always
too low but it started to raise. It used to be 17 and now it is more than 18.
My orthostatic blood pressure has been a bad situation for me.
It still goes down but in general it is higher and I am very happy about that.
Except from that I can notice that I urinate more frequently during the night.
When I go to bed at 11 p.m. I usually wake up at 1 and 3 a.m. and I urinate very much.
Also at 6 a.m. At least 3 times a night. – What I notice very much is that you
don’t feel so sleepy anymore.  – I feel more energy, definitely.  – And you stay more awake,
you attend almost the whole class now. – As far as the heat is concerned,
very hot makes me feel very weak and tired.  – You don’t like the heat here?
– If I stay long time in the sun I feel very tired and weak. As far as the cold weather
is concerned, if it is too cold and humid I am freezing very fast. I tolerate heat as long as
it is not too hot. – Any other change? – Another thing I have noticed is that
the loose stool and the diarrhea that used to be very frequent , now my stool is better
except for certain food I am sensitive to. I am sensitive to white flour,
red meat and special food. Except from that I am pretty good concerning the stool.
– The stool is more formed? – Yes. Before it was loose all the time and it changed
from loose to diarrhea. Now I have little diarrhea and loose stool when I eat milky products,
flour and certain times the red meat. Except from that my bowel movement
is ok and the stool is formed. That’s better.
Because from having this diarrhea and loose stool all the time I was very much exhausted.
I took new lab tests now just before I came to you and they have never been
as good as they are now. My albumin level was 38
and my hemoglobin has been raised a little bit. My kidney function is very good.
The creatinine is perfect, no sedimentation rate is about 20. A little high.
– The first it was 20 and the second hour? – They have different measurements for that
in Norway but it states that the normal should be 4-12 if you are completely balanced.
But my sedimentation had been up to 40 and now is 20 so it’s a good reduction rate.
I know medical specialists very good; they are also patients of mine so every time
I go to the hospital they talk about their own problem too!
Another thing I had was a problem with the chest, pain in the chest and down to
the left arm. I went to the hospital and the ECG under pressure was normal.
I know I had a very bad scoliosis in the thorax and when I get a little stress
my second thoracic gets very fixed, I can feel that right away.
I notice that in my family too when I take x-rays all my family they have the same scoliosis
in that part. There are different symptoms but we have tendency to the same problems.
I eliminated that I didn’t have a coronary disease. But when I get this fixed,
correct it, manipulate it, it usually takes care of it. Let me think if can think
about anything else which is different... - Since June you had this crisis, now it is September,
4 months... - The only I have been taking is this herb and that’s why I get these lab tests.
But the concentration in the blood is very very low and I like to get rid of that.
– How frequently you have these peaks? – I am not sure. If I get off this herb then it usually
has lasted 1 or 2 weeks then I start leaking a little bit. What I do then is take 100
in the morning and 100 in the evening. I double it for about a week and then I stabilize.
They gave me a choice and I didn’t like the cortisone. They say there are no side effects
with that little dose but what I am concerned about is my kidney function
which continues to be as good as now which is functional. They say the only side-effects
for that one is that you get more hairy. I don’t know but I want to get rid of it.
Except from that every 4-5 month I get a little relapse. This is can get rid of right away;
I have little concentration of that cyclosporine.
– When the edemas come where they appear first, the feet or the face?
– It always starts in the face, when I wake up in the morning.
It depends how I am laying, if I am laying on the head then it comes in the body,
but when I am lying on the one side, then when I am looking in the mirror
that one side is bigger than the other. Usually I can see. Now even though I am not leaking ,
when I wake up in the morning there is little underneath the eyes.
I don’t know if that’s normal... it goes down later. If I don’t stop it I am feeling like
I am floating when I walk, I hate that feeling because I usually exercise every day,
I take a walk every day and in my clinic I have a training sector so I make exercise for
half an hour or 40 minutes. Just easy exercises. That’s good for me.
– Is there anything else that you feel that has changed? You need more water
or you are more thirsty or you eat something different? – I feel I can eat more of different
food now than before without getting the loose stool. I also don’t have so much gas
in the stomach. It’s much better. But as far as drinking is concerned I drink regularly
during the day but I am not extremely thirsty, I drink normally.
I don’t drink anything else than water, no alcohol, no smoking.
When I am sitting and then I start to walk and getting up I got so dry in the mouth,
extremely dry, no saliva at all. It’s like I am under some kind of a stress situation.
I feel the blood coming down and I really have to concentrate not to faint.
But still I get over that phase faster than before. When I am lying,
I sit a bit on the bed and then I stand up and start to walk. This system seems to work out.
– I would like you to continue with the Acetanilidum C12 once a day.
You continue for 1 month, then we’ll see how things are and then after a month
they will prepare one potency higher, if they can; C13. And then C14 etc...
Every month you go one potency higher. They can prepare in one of the laboratories.
Now, you can start once a day with C12 and then every month you go one higher.
For 2-3 months we go this way then we get the feedback on how you feel and then
I will tell you how you continue further. Once we see the organism is better and steady,
not leaking then you start reducing this by ¼ , ½ and by ¾. – I am not leaking now,
I start to reduce it? – Yes once you start with this you can start to reduce it by ¼.
– Now I get 100 in the morning and 100 in the evening
so I will get 100 in the morning and 50 in the evening. – For one month.
– And then I go to 50 – 50 and then I’ll try to reduce it this way. That’s the way I will do it.
If I get a relapse during that time...? – If you get a relapse you will have to raise the potency,
that means first of all raise the potency like 15C immediately, 16C,
every day a potency higher but 3-4 times a day, not once. You take 3-4 times a day
and every second day raise the potency. When you go back you order to prepare 13C
up to 20C. One pharmacy will raise it for you and you have it.
– I take one potency for a whole month. – But if you start leaking make it much faster.