So, it’s about 11 months since you started the treatment.
Can you first tell me what is the situation at the moment and then I will ask you other questions?
– My condition has been improving since I started with the remedy in June.
I’m not so anemic anymore, my whole blood chemistry is better.
My hemoglobin has increased about 80% and that’s good.
My pupillary reflexes are better; I can stand the light better than I did before.
As far as my bladder control is concerned, I don’t have to press so hard my abdomen to get empty my bladder and get the urine out.
This is also positive. As far as my orthostatic blood pressure is concerned, that has also improved.
Of course I still have the dropping of the blood pressure from sitting to standing position but the fall is not so great anymore.
Let’s say, my blood pressure is normal when I am sitting about 100/80 mm Hg which drops down to 80/60 mm Hg.
– Do you still have to be very careful when you get up, or you are getting up freely now?
– I can get up more freely than before. Not entirely.
But I can notice that I don’t have to go so slow.
Of course, I still have some mild relapses of proteinuria but not like before.
The relapse regulates itself after about 14 days.
I am testing my urine every day with the stick and in a scale from 1 to 4,
when I get this proteinuria it’s about +1 and then it stays there for about 14 days and then it stops by itself.
Before it was just increasing, it didn’t stop until I had to go to the hospital and start with the chemotherapy.
Right now so far, it has been regulated and it takes about 14 days.
– Since you started the treatment, did you go to hospital?
– No, I have been going just for check-ups and control and I’m checking my blood chemistry all the time.
Used to do that once a month to check my kidney function and still my creatinine and my function of the kidneys is good
and the whole blood chemistry has been improving a little bit.
Everything has been increasing. Before my values were really low.
I have noticed that when I get these relapses, these mild relapses,
it always starts with losing stool and it increases the diarrhea and diarrhea stays
there for about 3 days and then I notice on the stick that it gets a very light color,
a little slight proteinuria and then it goes up to +1.
Now, I have been having proteinuria for the past 17 days but it has been just +1 on the scale.
3 days ago it increased to +2 and I got your advice and you told me that I should dissolve the remedy in water and I did.
I started yesterday taking little sips 4 times a day.
And I checked the urine today and it’s not down to +1 but it’s getting down.
It’s still 17 days now.
I don’t have the edemas like I did before.
Still I am not leaking so much and my albumin level is not so low, so I don’t get the edemas and that has been my worst problem.
They are connecting, when I get too many edemas like I had before, with lung edema and of course there is a danger with that.
– Another very prominent symptom you had it was the sleepiness.
Great sleepiness. How is that?
– Generally it has been much better.
Of course, when I am leaking I’m tired and I need a lot of sleep and I feel I never get refreshed.
I am still sleepy and feel that I need more sleep.
Even though I can get early to bed… But in that period I am gluten free then I feel ok,
my energy is much better and still with the leaking my energy is better.
– What about the gymnastics? Do you do more gymnastics?
– Yes, I still have problem.
I used to do a little bit of jogging and running, playing tennis but I still have problem with running.
I can walk in a good speed and do the bicycling.
– How the going upstairs?
– It’s a problem. I still have to take it very slowly.
But still there is an improvement I can walk faster upstairs and uphill than I did before.
I am exercising a little bit every day.
I have my own training section in the clinic and there is a program I do and I try to take a walk of at least 30 minutes every day just to get the circulation going,
I think that’s good.
As far as food is concerned I’m trying to eat a little bit of everything but I’m trying to avoid red meat.
– But you take some time red meat?
– I can take it once in a while but it’s a little strange sometimes I react upon the red meat.
It seems there are certain food I can tolerate, all the time I get loose stools and diarrhea.
There are certain food I know I am reacting upon.
I have to be careful with sweets, white flour, sugar and certain milk products.
I can tolerate cream but I have to be careful with milk.
Then I get loose stools and diarrhea.
– In all this period of the 11 months, did you ever have any stool with blood?
– No, I try to check that. The color of my stool has been ok, but I know that I have a little hemorrhoid.
So, I look at it and it’s not dark.
– Tell me something else. When you initially had this colitis, did you have pains?
– No. I didn’t have any pain.
– You never had any pain. – No.
– Neither now? – No. I don’t have any pain.
– Is the diarrhea always a forerunner of leaking or is it of late that you noticed that more clearly?
Of the last 5-6 months.
– It’s always a forerunner for the leak.
It usually takes about 3 days.
If I could find something which could stop this and keep my stomach ok it would be fine.
– That’s what we’ll try to do today.
In the meantime I want you to tell us how you take the remedy from the beginning.
So the class can hear it.
– I started with potency 30C for a couple of days and then we tried 200C for 1 day.
I didn’t see any change after that, then we went down to 12C…
- But when you started… Because I remember you sent a fax saying there is no effect in the beginning.
Did you have to take chemotherapy immediately after starting or you went back?
– I had to, because it took some time before I got the remedy.
I had to wait and I got in touch with you because it was gradually increasing my proteinuria and
my edema got massive and then I had to go to the hospital and got one injection to stop it.
– That was last June.
– Yes. When I got home. Then I got the remedy.
– You took 30C for 3 days?
– Yes, I think it was 3 days.
Then it still kept going up and then we tried 200C once.
But it still did not stop it.
Then we agreed I had to do something drastic to stop it and I went to
the hospital and then I got that Sendoxan IV and it took care of it.
Then I started with 12C.
– You started 2 or 3 times a day?
– I started once a day 12C.
We kept on doing that.
Of course then I was protein free and we kept on going with this potency for 1 month.
And then we went up to 13C and I stayed on 13C for some time, probably 1 month.
Then we agreed on increasing the potency by 1C every month.
In that period when I got these mild relapses, I tried to increase the
dose and take 1 in the morning and 1 in the evening, twice a day.
It took about 14 days before I could see a change.
– But so far, from July until today, on the scale from 1 to 4, it never went up more than 1.
– Yes.
– Except of this time which went a little bit over and I told you to take it 4 times yesterday and you can already see …
- I can see a little change.
It’s not down to 1 yet but I can see the change, it has the tendency to go down.
I’m excited for tomorrow to see… I am testing every day.
That’s important for me to always check my albumin level because if it gets under 20, I get the edemas.
So I try to avoid that.
But so far I don’t have any edema.
The only thing when I am leaking a little bit now, when I wake up in the
morning I can see I have a little edema under my eyes and also my eyelids.
It’s hard to notice for someone who doesn’t know me but I can see it.
Except of that I don’t have any other symptoms.
I get more tired in that period but except of that there is nothing else.
And of course my energy level is a little lower.
– I want to ask something else. During all this period did you ever get any inflammation of the lungs?
– No, I haven’t had it and usually when I get a cold it goes down to my bronchi.
This time I hadn’t have any of this bronchitis.
– But did you get any cold on your nose?
– It just got started a little bit, but I have been taking some vitamin C and in the next day it was all gone.
So then I got a high dose of vitamin C, about 1000mg.
Except of that I haven’t been taking anything else.
– Can you tell me if there are any symptoms which have appeared?
Do you perspire now more or how is your sensitivity to cold?
– I’m not freezing that much, I think that it is a little better.
I still have the problem with the saliva.
My mouth is always dry and I have to drink a lot of water.
That’s the only thing I am drinking.
– Do you drink some alcohol?
– Once in a while a little bit wine with the food and a beer once in a while but I’d rather take water.
I enjoy water too.
– Can you give me an idea of what you are eating?
– In the morning I eat some eggs, I eat a good breakfast.
I take some oatmeal, a couple of pieces of bread and about 3-4 eggs.
I like to eat a little protein in the morning because if I don’t I get hungry very fast.
And I feel to get my thyroxin production, my metabolism going by eating some protein in the morning.
In the middle of the day I eat some fruits.
– Lunchtime?
– I could take cottage cheese with some fruits, half chicken or I can get some pieces of bread with cheese.
In dinner I eat some fish or some white meat, it could be of any kind but the best meat I can eat is turkey.
Because I read it contains enzymes which are very good for my digestion.
And there is very little fat, nearly no fat at all.
Before I go to bed if I am hungry I can eat some scrambled eggs, salmon, shrimps, and some light food.
– Vegetables?
– I also eat vegetables and salad usually in my dinner.
I enjoy tomatoes.
– What brings diarrhea to you except of milk? What other food?
– The worst thing I can eat is chocolate and white flour, like in sweet cakes. I can’t tolerate that.
– What will it happen?
– I start with some gas in the stomach and then pretty fast, I start to get loose stool and diarrhea.
And then I have to get it out to feel better.
– So, white flour… bread?
– White bread is not so good for me neither.
I eat a darker type of bread, rye bread.
I noticed that all food that contains white flour is no good for me.
Oatmeal is good. I eat that in the morning.
– What about butter? You take butter?
– Yes. No problem. I eat bread with butter because I think it’s very good to get vitamin A.
I try to avoid the other sources, the artificial ones.
– What about meat that has meat that fat in it? If you eat the skin of the turkey?
Does it affect your stool if you take a little bit fat with meat?
– I know if I eat pork, it will affect me. Then I get loose stool.
Sometimes I can tolerate certain food one day…
- But you haven’t connected it with something else?
– I have been trying to do that but.
But if I eat some food in connection with other food, that could affect me.
So, I have been trying to test and find out if I am allergic to certain food and I have one physician in Oslo,
who is running some allergic tests to find the reactions to certain food and sends the results to the States.
I didn’t react too much. The only thing she mentioned was broccoli.
– Do you like the broccoli yourself?
– Not especially. I can eat it but it’s not like I enjoy it so much.
– How much sweets you would like?
– I don’t really have hunger for sweets, I would take a fruit.
– What about the salt? Are you careful with it?
– Yes, I don’t use very much salt. I add some in my oatmeal but nothing special. I like bananas.
– Can you eat 10-20 bananas?
– During the day I can eat 4-5 bananas in between when I feel a little hungry.
– Every day you take bananas?
– Yes. But my idea is that I should take at least one banana every day to get my potassium.
Except of that I think that banana is ok.
– But do you like bananas?
– I like them yes. I also like all fruits.
Banana is one fruit I can eat without getting too much gas in the stomach.
If I eat an apple or a pear or something like that I can
get a little gas, but banana is pretty safe so I do that.
If I take cottage cheese it’s a actually a milk product I don’t react
upon that because I take a little banana in it and that might help me.
– Do you know if you grind your teeth during sleep?
– No, my wife never told me about that. I sleep generally very well.
When I get to bed I can sleep in 10 minutes.
– In your family was any member from your mother or father side suffering of tuberculosis?
– No.
– Do you have brother or sister?
– I have 2 brothers.
– Anybody having kidney problems?
– No. I am the only one.
– And when you went to the USA you were totally healthy.
– Yes. But I was a bit worn out.
I have been working very hard with a lot of patients, a lot of stress and my immune system was very low.
That’s why I thought that I got something in the food when I was there, we were in that orchestra and we ate at the coffee shops
but they couldn’t find anything out of there.
I took the biopsy of my left kidney but there was very slight inflammation, nearly not noticeable.
– When you drink water is it because you feel thirsty, because you have to drink or because your mouth is dry?
– My mouth is extremely dry. Like now, if I have been talking 5-10 minutes it gets dry like sandpaper.
I have to drink all the time in the clinic too if I am talking, I depend on having water all the time.
– Are you organized in your things, your room?
– I am pretty organized. I like to have order.
– But you like it very much? Does everything have to be in its place and you are aggravated if it is not?
– Not particularly, but I like to have some order both in the clinic and at home.
I don’t need to have everything in line, I like to have an order.
– Did you notice any change in your mood? Are you less or more irritable?
Or is your psychological mood the same?
– I think it’s about the same as before.
I am enjoying life but when I am leaking I am thinking all the time…
Anxiety and I am thinking of what I can do.
I am trying to think about what is aggravating it and causing it.
Now I am very concerned about why I get these loose stools and diarrhea.
What did I eat… And I have to find out that.
– When you are in high places and look down…
- I don’t like that.
– If somebody else is near the balcony and it is very high you don’t like it either and you say come in or this does not affect you?
– That doesn’t affect me that much but myself I have to stay a little bit behind, I don’t like that.
I am feeling that somebody is pulling me across.
That’s the only thing I have a little fear about; heights.
– Do you perspire at all during sleep?
– That’s another thing; I don’t perspire at all.
I have very little perspiration.
What I should tell you is when I get these loose stools and diarrhea it has a bad smell.
It’s a very sharp odor.
– Does it remind you something?
– Yes. It’s a bad odor and if you were in the room you would probably say that it’s a Sulphur case.
But it is very sharp smell and it stays in the room for a long time.
Today my stool was ok.
The last couple of days has been loose, it changed a little bit and from today it is ok.
New color and no smell.
– You are ready now to go to the next potency which will be 16C?
– Yes, I am on 15C now. I finished it.
– Now you go to 16C.
– Yes. I think I will get it from Belgium, it’s going to be ready for me.
– You are going to take it 3 times a day.
– You want to me dissolve it in water or take it directly?
– Take it directly.
– I do that.
– Your nails… Are they brittle, they break easily?
– No it’s strong and my hair grows fast and my nails grow. I have to cut them too frequently.
– Ok, we go inside and we talk about the analysis of your case and then we continue.
Now with his case we still have to do a lot of work.
As you already heard I continued with the same medication because the whole picture has not really changed.
If you see the symptomatology is less but still is there.
The anemia is only 80% better; we still have to go.
The blood pressure is still 100 still has to go up.
The kidney is still leaking. There are no essential changes to indicate the next remedy.
There are some symptoms which belong to an underlying remedy, for instance the
symptom which he has, vertigo high places, belongs to the underlying remedy.
These are very good indications but Acetalinidum will never take care of this fear.
This fear will be taken care of, most probably when Calcarea carbonica or Sulphur, either of the 2 remedies,
will pop up in the next stage.
And then in the next stage his colitis will be a little bit stronger than it is today and it may also reappear
with some blood, in which case if we have given the remedy and we have that reaction you’ll say very well.
You brought it back to the original state from which the whole thing started, from ulcerative colitis.
And then this will go away in a little while and then you will have a steady cure.
The kidneys have gone back to the normal condition.
Another thing we have been talking about and I want to stress again
is this idea; this upper layer Acetanilidum and he gets Acetanilidum…
And the underlying layer is Calcarea carbonica.
This is vertigo high places which appears here also.
If this organism gets a big stress will come back to Acetanilidum that’s why Acetanilidum is indicated.
That means that every day he has a relapse and the relapse is Acetanilidum.
Once Acetanilidum has finished its action then it will not
act anymore and you give Calcarea carbonica and it acts.
Then the relapse in case he gets a stress here again will be Calcarea carbonica not Acetanilidum.
Perhaps you are not aware.
This information is given for first time.
For the first time I give this information from A to Z.
This means all the knowledge I have.
It’s a historic class!
I give portions of information in this and that seminar but here systematically I try to give
all the information that you are needing as a practitioner to practice Homeopathy properly.
– Nobody who doesn’t know this remedy could have solved this case because I didn’t find it once in the repertory.
– That is true and that is what I said about the strategy.
I said where you will find the remedy that has the essential features of the case.
This remedy had the essential features of his case.
Of course you have to know and that is why I wanted to make a repertory which can give information about that case also.
I would like to make a new repertory but never mind… this is another story.
– What I did not quite understand; you said when the relapse will be Calcarea carbonica is it because it is very basic remedy?
Why are you so sure it cannot be something else?
– Underneath it can be anything. We don’t know yet.
It can be Arsenicum, Calcarea carbonica, Sulphur.
I said let us suppose the next remedy is Calcarea carbonica and you give it and
it acts then after this after this organism gets a shock then he has a relapse.
But what will the relapse be?
Not anymore Acetanilidum but Calcarea carbonica.
– My question is when I was observing the patient during the interview the impression that this person has really anxiety about his health
and at the same time as a neighbor I could tell definitely this gentleman is very fastidious and he takes care of how is looking and so on.
For me it would be a big temptation to fall down to Arsenicum.
But then when I started to think that probably that is something like in your book the Essence of Homeopathy I have
read that some intellectual patients can bring information about broccoli, contents of proteins of different products,
medical tests, is it this kind of case?
– Yes. Let me comment on what you are saying.
What you can rely on… The information he gave about eating.
On what information you can rely on.
There was one symptom on which you can rely.
What was this symptom? Banana, eggs, no!
There is only one symptom you can rely on and this is diarrhea from milk. That is for sure.
The rest is the eggs he takes to replace the protein etc. And he has his reasons.
The bananas for the potassium etc. He has his reasons because he has studied this kind of medicine, then he is careful and he says forget it.
Then we go to the question about the anxiety about health.
Yes, but if you had the same problem tell me if you would have anxiety or not, whether you would be careful or not.
Of course if you are Sulphur you may not even take care.
You would say forget it give me some wine… Let’s live today, die tomorrow.
– I noticed he is battling a lot with tiredness and fatigue and weakness.
Where do I find weakness and fatigue in the layers you have showed us?
– You mean in the hierarchy?
– Yes.
– The tiredness is connected with the kidneys, so you will be looking at the kidneys level.
Another tiredness will be connected with liver; you will be looking at the liver level.
Another tiredness will be connected with lungs. Asthmatic tiredness; you will be looking at the lungs.
And the fatigue, the tiredness, the sleepiness?
– She said when can I find in the hierarchy scale weakness.
I said you don’t find it, you find it in the heart; weakness because of a heart problem.
Weakness because of kidney problem; you find it in kidneys. Alright?
– Yes, but also I am talking about the sleepiness.
He is so tired. He falls asleep here.
Where can I find that?
– Sleepiness is not just by itself, it is a secondary effect of some problems within the organism, which is on the physical level.
Where the seat of anatomical problem is, there is the sleepiness.
For instance you give a remedy and after the remedy the patient says I am sleeping and I can’t wake up.
I sleep 12-14 hours a day.
And we say this is a very good reaction.
So the sleepiness by itself is not put in the hierarchy, it is to what it is connected pathologically.
What is the pathology which brings about the sleepiness?
Sleepiness can come because of lack of oxygenation of the brain…
The old people are arteriosclerosed sleep all the time, because of it. It is different.
Sleepiness can come from conflict. People get grief and they go to sleep for 12 – 15 hours to get over the grief.
So sleepiness is not by itself.
– Concerning the mental emotional level we haven’t heard very much about this and you may say in
Homeopathy, if there are no symptoms of mental emotional level, no remedy is needed for that.
But still, some questions about dreams, about times of sadness, about mood, I haven’t heard anything.
Maybe I haven’t seen the whole interview before but what about this?
– In this particular case. You can see, I ask do you have fears.
You want to "make" fear, "make" anxiety about health.
You ask the patient and he says yes, I have a fear.
I fear high places. That’s it. You have fears? He thinks and says no, I don’t.
– But he have said it.
– He said yes, I have one fear. I look from a high place down and this is my only fear.
And sadness and dreams… Ok. You can ask about dreams if you want but the idea is not to go away from the essentials.
Here is the periphery. You see little symptoms. You lose this and you say here is a circle.
No. The essentials! They gave him several remedies, they gave him Nat-m., Ign., Ars. …
He has taken all these remedies, no effect.
There is not going to be any effect from these remedies.
– I want to say something about his diet. He said that his body doesn’t tolerate milk.
I think there is some sensitivity towards milk, this might affect his kidneys as well.
And then he said he is very thirsty, so to me it is quite natural because he eats so much protein all day and this is natural,
that you get very thirsty. And then about his sleepiness.
When you eat so many proteins, this makes him tired as well because the body has to work so much.
– If we had a dietician here he would contradict everything you said and he would tear you into pieces.
Protein diets give so much energy.
Not only does not give tiredness, they give a lot of calories, a lot of energy.
People go to such diets to have energy.
You can say whatever you like, the problem is that he has kidneys which aren’t working.
Of course he is going to feel very tired.
Of course he needs to relax to get back some energy and never mind how much protein he takes, it’s
not because of the protein that he has weakness, it’s because of the kidneys that are not working.
She disagrees.
– I have one more question concerning the future treatment of the patient.
Is it so that he will keep taking Acetanilidum until he has his old
colitis again and then receives another remedy or how will you proceed?
– Well, this is very difficult to predict but I say what most probably will happen is this, but
I am not sure if it will happen with Acetanilidum, but it may happen with the next remedy.
The next remedy may be Sulph., may be Calc., may be Ars.There are points for Sulph.
and Calc. at this moment and I suspect that rather Calc. is the underlying remedy.
Until he gives me signs of Calc. … What are the signs of Calc.?
The cold feet, the sweatiness, the perspiration in the night etc.
All these will take me to Calc. and then I prescribe.
Then I said most probably, I am not a prophet, after the Calc. he will go to the original
state from which the whole thing started.
And that was ulcerative colitis.
The ulcerative colitis will take place for 1 -2 weeks and then the
organism will stabilize itself and the kidneys will be out of danger.
We still have to understand that we have to do a lot of work with his case before he is really cured.
It’s not like you just give Acetanilidum and he will be well. No.
I perceive that under Acetanilidum he will need Calc.
– And why did you ask for the bronchitis? Is this something you would expect to reappear now?
– The bronchitis came during the state of depression. His organism was depressed.
So the bronchitis actually is a side effect of the kidney and the digestion problems.
We have a series like this; digestive problem, colon affected, kidneys affected, lungs affected.
So, lungs have to be strengthened first as the result of a general weakness of the organism because of the kidneys.
The kidneys get better so the organism reacts better to bronchitis for instance.
Then the organism goes backwards and is going to reach the place where it started.
It will reach the place of ulcerative colitis.
His kidneys are going down, his blood is not clean, he has toxicity; because of toxicity he has sleepiness etc.
What you will see is that the side effects of the kidney problems which are bronchitis, sleepiness etc.
are reduced until the time the whole organism will go back to the original state which was the colitis.
You are like children, I feel I have to say it again and again… These things are essential that you have to understand.
For me it’s so obvious and then I have to transfer this knowledge and I see your eyes, what is he saying?
Did he really mean this or that?
And each one thinks about himself is this guy crazy?
I was joking but I perceive that.