This is the remedy which I take every time I finish a seminar.
After the seminar I have to take a dose of Stann.
So you don't need anymore information,
it's just pure and total exhaustion.
This is the idea with Stann.  especially if the exhaustion is connected with some respiratory and bronchial, lung problems.
It has a tuberculinic background. Tuberculinic people you know how they look, white and rather yellowish-white.
And always with problems with the respiratory. And then when they come to the point of having dyspnea or asthma
the asthma is really exhausting.
They can hardly move and they go out of breath.
They can only lie down, not moving at all in order to survive. They move a little bit and then the dyspnea comes.
This is the number one remedy for
this and the number two remedy is Bry.
Number 1 is Stann. for asthma worse with any kind of effort.
But this remedy also has a tremendous weakness it's out of proportion, when he talks.
When they try to talk, they are exhausted and the voice goes down and down. And they say, forget it I'll stop.
The fact of talking makes the Stann.
extremely exhausted.
If you are in that state of exhaustion,
who has been in that state?
Do you like to have company?
You don't like to see anybody. This is the idea. 'Leave me alone'.
But you see how difficult will be to differentiate this remedy from Bry.?
Both Stann. and Bry. do not want in their suffering to see people, to communicate, to give out energy.
Communicating means giving out energy. If I sit there and I just talk like robot, I can go on for years.
But if I give energy to what I say, I can do so much.
Communicating means energy and Stann. does not have it and you can see it in all respect.
In asthma also it is possible that you may
get a dry cough, exhausting dry cough.
And at another stage you get thick expectoration and sometimes by coughing there are pieces which are flying
out of the mouth. Pieces of mucus, like a jet.
I have never prescribed Stann. without exhaustion.
Most probably Stann. might be indicated in some other condition but I have never prescribed it without the exhaustion.
Or if I have tried to, it didn't work.
Concerning the digestive system and there we see the emptiness, the empty feeling in the stomach
with a nausea that comes from smells, especially cooking.
You may see prolapse of the uterus but this you will never prescribe in prolapse of the uterus Stann.
unless you have the general picture of exhaustion.
There are some remedies which react different when they are exhausted.
Sepia will be what?
When exhausted, Sepia will become irritable.
For instance get Nux-v. down, exhausted and the moment you say one more word, explodes.
That means there is left inside some energy
and there is a protection from the organism.
It says don't give me anymore stress.
With this remedy, there is nothing left. And
when you push, the Stann. just wants to cry.
There is no reaction, there is no protection anymore. It is a remedy which is unprotected.
It's finished, no energy to protect anymore.
I just want to give you the intensity.
Because by comparing the remedies and comparing the intensity you can only come down to the right state.
So with Stann. you have to have weakness during talking, it's a keynote.
Weakness on doing anything.
The woman has to cook and she has to get up and go to the kitchen. By the time she goes to the kitchen, she is already tired.
And in the asthma conditions, it's a remedy that will not straight away cure asthma. You will give this remedy
as a first remedy, then it picks up the energy, then eventually you will get another remedy and perhaps a third one.
That means heavy asthmatic conditions, not simple.
And when you see the vitality of the person
looks good, you will not think it needs Stann.
In Stann. you see that exhaustion. It's there, you see it.
-May I ask one more question concerning the weakness? Mur-ac. also has such an extreme weakness.
-Yes it has but Mur-ac. usually the weakness you will meet under fever. Under conditions which have inflammations.
One more thing that I forgot to mention here in Stann.  it is the position in which they sleep. I will show you the position.
It's very strange. They try to bring down the foot.
They bring the knee on top. This is a very awkward position.
There are some remedies which sleep like that.
I have mentioned already Nux-v. I think.
-I sleep like this and my two daughters.
-Podo. sleeps like this. You take out the foot and they cannot go to sleep. This is a very awkward position.
That's the only position they can sleep, Stann.
They lie on the back but then they may turn. Once they turn it changes but lying on back always they bring
the one foot, usually the right foot they bring it over.
-How does one recognize a tubercular diathesis?
-You will recognize the sensitivity on the lungs. The sputum which comes out profuse eventually
you will recognize it from the look. Why do we have connected it?
We have connected Stann. with tuberculus diathesis because we have seen in the past of such people
either themselves having tuberculosis or their parents. And that's why we have connected it.
You see in tuberculosis after years, the exhaustion continues, it reaches that state or during or after tuberculosis
or when the parents had tuberculosis, the children get all these infections and eventually they end up in asthma.
You ask the father he says, yes I had tuberculosis. You see the exhaustion, OK.
Pic-ac. is another exhausted remedy.
Have we done Ph-ac.?
What is the difference between Pic-ac.
and Stann. and Ph-ac.?
Exhaustion here in the head, in the brain is Pic-ac. mostly. Exhaustion here in the heart, Ph-ac.
Exhaustion in the physical body, Stann.
That means when you have an exhaustion and the seat of complain is on mental, I cannot think, my mind has stopped.
This is a Pic-ac. exhaustion.
An exhaustion which comes suddenly which is many times met in students, good students who study
study and they are approaching the examinations and suddenly a curtain falls.
It is unbelievable. It is a curtain, they go into paralytic state. They say, I will not go for examinations
because they have studied and one day they try to pick up something, they read, nothing goes inside.
Total mental exhaustion. The brain does not function at all and this is a terrifying situation for the students.
And you give Pic-ac. and in few hours he picks up the book and can read again. It's fantastic.
Otherwise there is no way that they can go and take the examinations.
So the exhaustion has some seat of action for these 3 remedies and the Pic-ac. will be exhausted
physically, exhausted also in her emotions but primarily on the brain. Primarily on mental level.
Where the Ph-ac.
will be exhausted here as well.
Ph-ac. you go to the Repertory you see, forgets words, forgets what he is going to do, forgets names.
The memory of Ph-ac. is terrible.
But the main exhaustion is on feelings.
Feelings are finished, I have no feelings.
And then the state in which they go it's apathy. I don't care.
Your house got fire, it doesn't mean anything. Your child is on fire, he doesn't move.
The feelings are not there.
When you don't have brain waves here, you have Pic-ac. When you don't have heart waves, not physical heart, feelings.
No feelings, it's electric line. And that is Stann. on the physical level.
-What's the difference between Pic-ac. and Kali-p.?
-Kali-p. is not near this state. Kali-p. is
a remedy that you will give after exertion.
You see sleeplessness, the sleep does
not recover, wake up during the night.
They continue the effort and this comes slowly. Kali-p. will develop over a period of 5 years.
This, Pic-ac. will develop over a period of 5 days.
It's sudden. You will never see this picture in Kali-p., what I describe.
The problem is of course that in the books we have the same expression for different things.
But if you take the whole picture, it's totally different. What we talk here is the characteristic.
Maybe you will get a Pic-ac. who has fear of thunderstorms, we are not talking of this. We're talking about
the very characteristics of the remedy so you know where your mind should go at the first place.
You get this information, your mind should go there. Pic-ac. will look also very much like Gels.
At certain points you cannot differentiate Gels. with Pic-ac.
The reason is that both they give up,
they don't want any mental challenge.
Another characteristic is this burning along the spine. This is also a beautiful symptom for Pic-ac.
burning feeling all along the spine.
In the books they say, progressing from fatigue on motion to complete paralysis. Are you going to give in M.S., Pic-ac.?
Almost never.
So it's a paralysis of the central
nervous system and not the peripheral.
When it comes to that, you will not recognize
it. Unless you have the mental weakness.
They will be aggravated by the heat, by the motion all these 3 remedies are aggravated by exertion.
Pic-ac. also will be aggravated by heat, by exertion. And what is the worse exertion?
It's mental, yes.
What is the worst exertion you can have in the shortest time?
Sexual intercourse, they are aggravated by sexual intercourse.
You are grown ups now. Even this little one who was here in the beginning, she has grown up.
So we can talk seriously about matters.
Pic-ac. can come from worries of the mind. Somebody worries, where shall I find the money, where shall I invest money?
And the mind becomes overworked but usually we see it when under stress and pressure you have to exercise
the power of the mind.
That is the time where the mind collapses. If you give Pic-ac. before that...the person says, 'I'm exhausted'.
And you ask, 'can you read?', 'Yes I can still
read' and you give it, it will do nothing.
You have to have this curtain, it's like a curtain that goes down and nothing allows to come in.
-Do you remember we gave Pic-ac. to the Norwegian girl we had? I was not here to know if Pic-ac. helped.
I would like to know.
-There is a follow up.
-Can you give it if the exhaustion is already very long time?
-Yes, once you have that state. Because Pic-ac. may stay, once it comes, it may stay. It's not that it will come
for two days and then it will go away.
Pic-ac. will come suddenly and it will stay.
That's another remedy which is similar to Stann. because it's a remedy that has sensitivities on the respiratory
with aggravation from exhaustion. It's a very exhausted remedy. It's a remedy that you will need
in a flu situation, influenzas with fever, exhaustion, coughing, a deep cough.
It's like a saw.
This heavy cough.
Many times you have a combination of respiratory problems together with heart.
They have an aggravation from cold and
an amelioration from warmth in general.
Unlike other remedies which usually like to be up, the Spongia can lie almost flat in her back.
-Can I say something about Spongia? I had a patient who came to me with heart problems and coughing
and many symptoms and I did not know what to give him. I was completely lost and then he said,
'I have terrible pains in my legs'. 'What kind of pain?' He said, 'it's like a sponge'
and I gave Spongia 30 and all the symptoms ameliorated very much.
-You see in the books it says, when they breathe they feel they breathe through a sponge for instance.
In the book you will see that.
I have not heard that really but it's a good thing to know and this is something even more extreme. The pain is like a sponge
I don't understand even what they say but what they feel and they say maybe it's something of value.
These remedies you will not perceive them easily in chronic cases, in chronic conditions and the only thing you see
as I said, is the type of cough, the respiratory being affected and at the same time the heart being involved.
This combination brings the mind to Spongia.
So Petr. is a remedy which primarily has dryness. It's a dry remedy on the surface.
What is the difference with Alum.? On the inside is lose. Petr. you will use it for strong diarrheas and persistent
with dryness of the skin. Alum. you will use it for persistent constipation with dryness of the skin.
The dryness here on this remedy is much stronger and the idea is that it is so dry the skin, it looks like leather.
And cracks. Cracks are important for Petr. You will not get a case of Petr. with dryness of the skin simply.
You have to have some cracks from a few cracks to a lot of cracks.
Painful cracks and that is the time when you think of Petr.
Also in a stage of exhaustion, especially with constant diarrheas and by that time they feel they are going to die
and they have to make their will.
In the same way as what?
Which is the remedy which they feel they are going to die and they have to make their will?
-Arsenicum?
-No.
-Aconitum.
The imminence of dying makes
them feel that I have to do something.
Here is a sudden idea, I'm going to die, without reason. They don't have cancer in the last stage. They have just diarrhea.
In the same way that Acon. is not really in danger of his life but the feeling and the fear is tremendous.
Irritable after coition, it is because of the exhaustion.
This is again the feeling of either he, himself is double or somebody else is lying in bed, is a symptom
which really exists and I have seen it a few times.
Another strong element of Petr. is the easy upset of the stomach. The digestive system easily gets upset
and especially the stomach in movements. Whether he is travelling in a car where there are turns
and he is sitting on the back seat, he has to vomit or whether he comes with the flying dolphin or the boat.
They have to vomit, it's very strong. The sea sickness is very strong.
Another keynote is while they are having diarrheas at the same time they have excessive hunger.
They want to eat.
And they will remark it themselves. These are good keynotes to remember because once you will hear it
you pick it up immediately.
Who has seen a skin eruption of Petr.?
-It's not that the skin eruption appears at the level of the mucus membranes going over onto the skin.
It's they come really on the skin and they are extremely dry and the skin has cracks and it's coming up in winter.
And the patient says that in winter the skin gets extremely dry.
And it's not like Graph. The skin is getting very thick.
-What you have to remember also it is that in many cases the psoriasis, for instance, which is with great cracks
you're treating a case of psoriasis with great cracks and you will see in summertime totally disappearing,
this is characteristic of all psoriasis,
but in Petr. is more characteristic.
In the summer it will disappear. In the winter it starts blown up and it starts September-October-November.
By December it's full blown up and then
it goes up to May and then it starts reducing.
Petr. of course is one of the main remedies for psoriasis with cracks.
And generally ailments which come in winter especially.
If people say, I suffer with diarrheas
but in winter, that is a keynote for Petr.
I suffer with skin eruptions but in winter
immediately your mind should go there.
Aggravation in winter.
-Can you differentiate the travel
sickness of Petr. and Cocc. and Tab.?
-You will not be able by the symptom of sea sickness, all these three remedies have strong sea sickness.
You will not be able to differentiate them. I've not known different sea sickness for different people.
All these remedies together with Sepia, Cocc., Tab., Petr. and Sep. they have strong nausea in the sea.
But also I have seen strong nausea which has never gone away with the remedy.
You give several remedies over the years and you see this sensitivity of the person to the sea sickness remains.
-I want to relate something. I had a gallbladder operation when I was 40 years old and after this operation
diarrhea started and I had sometimes, 10 times watery stool, per day. It was totally painless, it was totally
without odour and it was not exhausting.
And a very strong aversion against fat.
And they gave me Petr. C200 I had aggravation for 24 hours and after this it totally stopped.
-The aversion to fat also is strong symptom that you can notice together with Nat-m., Puls. and China.
-I had never had any dryness of skin, nothing.
-It was a superficial Petr. just on the surface.
But the diarrheas of Petr. can really be exhausting. It is constantly running water.
The diarrhea doesn't have a specific pain but it is profuse and exhausting.
And most probably you will see some dryness in the skin.
-I wanted to say something as an answer for Richard's question about sea sickness.
The last term we had finished here and
we travelled together in the flying dolphin.
And I remember that I asked you which remedy should I take because I know myself I'm very sensitive
and you said, try one of them, I don't know if it will work.
And I had 3 from Ip., Cocc. and Tab., from each of them 3.
I tried first Ip. and it worked for half-one hour. And then I had to take Cocc., it also worked and after this Tab.
they all 3 worked but I still remain sensitive to sea sickness.
-This is a good example.
-24 years back I came to Greece and I had to take the ship very far, from Athens to Mykonos.
And I start getting a bit strange in my stomach and we were with many Greek women and they all took out
the plastic bag for themselves and they started vomiting. I got on deck with fresh air and it stopped suddenly.
I did not have to vomit and I thought it is better with fresh air and I thought it is even a mental case.
The idea that we now are in sea, we have to vomit.
-No, no, it's not exactly like that. All people they need fresh air, when they feel nauseous, the fresh air is good.
Also if you have some natural perfume,
like lemon and you smell, it may act.
But the moment the sea goes over up, forget the lemon, forget the breathing, forget the fresh air, the whole boat is down.
I also had the experience one time, I resist, lemon, things like that and the sea was really rough
and the plates were coming down and then finally I was also down there.
And I could see a patient of mine with their daughter.  They were sitting nicely chatting.
And I was dying because you feel like your soul is coming out, now it's going to come out.
The sea was 10 Beaufort, very rough sea.
I was in Skyros and I didn't like it and I wanted to come back to Alonissos and I tried to get into the boat
but the boat was full of cars of the army
and I persuaded somebody, I don't remember how I did it
I persuaded somebody to let me go in,  and then I had it.
We were 4 people, my wife immediately fell down, I resisted and the other 2 people, our friends
out of the whole boat, they said, I have no problem.
So it is a matter of degrees, who is more sensitive.
You are less sensitive, you can manage, you go upstairs, you stay.
But the moment the sea becomes really rough, you are also going to come down.
We go out with a boat to fish and the sea is rough and I have seen local people in little rough sea
especially when the boat is standing,
they get dizzy and they want to vomit.
-I know Petr. from only skin diseases and diarrheas but in which conditions would you see that delusion coming up?
Are they so sick in diarrhea that confusion is coming up?
-Usually during fevers.
It will say 'who is lying next to me?'
and you will get the indication.