We shall be talking about Agaricus this afternoon.
So Agaricus has been famous for twitchings,
tremblings, quivering, paralysis, jerkings
and therefore it will be indicated in cases of neuro-muscular disorders,
multiple sclerosis and convulsive disorders, facial paralysis etc.
This is the note of action of Agaricus and
mostly frequently you use it in sciaticas
and lumbagos and also in hay fever.
And there is another aspect of Agaricus for
which I would like to talk mostly tonight
and it is the psychological make-up of the
remedy, which is not described in our books.
There is some predominant symptomatology on that level.
What we see is a kind of retardation in the development of the mind and body,
retardation of the development.
We notice that from very young age when
children and babies are very late to walk
but also to talk.
I noticed also that Agaricus switched later on personalities that are weak,
with a weak will, we may say or a dependent character.
They need help, they will ask for help and they will ask it in such a way
that it will be given and then they will learn to have assistance, to have help.
They are people who from the early age will seek guidance from others and help.
And this tendency
develops from a kind of
unwillingness to take up
responsibility themselves.
You will see immediately the element of slow development, a kind of immaturity
that happens also in other remedies like
Sequata, like Baryta carbonica and Anacardium.
You will see it also in
Natrum muriaticum the
late development and
especially in the children.
But what you will see it is most prominent
is a lack of grip, a lack of will power.
Therefore there will be
people that will give
a lot of love and affection
to their parents,
to their teachers with the
idea behind that they
will in return get some
guidance and protection.
But in this kind of development where we really find a problem in life,
they will try to find an escape.
Because you told me to do so, it's your mistake.
They don't want to take responsibility.
You see that element of retardation, of retarded maturity.
For instance if you talk badly to an Agaricus
child it's easy to go to convulsions
because they cannot take that reprimand, that you punish them.
And they go to convulsions, twitchings etc.
A lack of development, a lack also of
coordination between the mind and the body.
The mind gives an order to the hand to go
and take these flowers and put them down.
If it's here and wants to catch these
flowers, their hand will go like that first.
Instead of directing straight...
There is a lack of coordination.
So while they are eating,
they try to take
something from the table
and push bottles down,
plates upside down and then they try to hold...
It's not a grip, it's no coordination. Clumsiness.
You see in the Materia Medicas mostly and in the Repertory in particular,
we have flat symptoms, clumsiness, the person is not coordinating.
But now and we synthesize and we put together all the elements
that constitute an Agaricus case in order to be able to recognize that case,
when we see it in front of us.
So it's not a simple clumsiness, that kind of individual who gives affection,
who is very sentimental, who listens to his teacher...
Because he cannot take it and then the twitchings start.
The nervous system is forced in a way that immediately you will see twitchings.
Force it more, press it more, you will see
more twichings, then you will see tremblings,
then press it more you will see chorea like symptoms.
They start moving, they make big movements and especially facial movements.
You see the nervous system is very peculiar.
In Agaricus you will see the nervous system is affected
and the reactions in the movements are like that...
but inside the psychology of the person is mild.
You see the facial expressions, they may show a kind of aggressiveness
but it seems that the aggressiveness on
the subconscious level has been imprinted
upon the peripheral nervous system, which produces these twitchings and motions
and the psychology of the person has remained mild.
You see almost a serenity
in the emotional level
once the emotional
level is not affected.
Because as the pathology progresses we have
affections on the mental-emotional level
on the type that I shall be describing later.
Take now that constitutional type of person with the weakness,
with the desire to live a secured, a protected kind of life
that the child has managed to establish because
he reacts nicely with his teachers etc.
and the teachers are protecting him and that
child is not prepared to take up a shock.
The child is not prepared
to take up a shock and
the shock is going to
come sometime or another.
Its biggest weakness, Agaricus biggest weakness it is a shock which is connected
with some kind of death, either from heart or from cancer or from brain stroke.
Once they are faced with an event of that type...
In front of them somebody dies, whether their parents die or their relatives...
Someone who is close to them that they never
thought that they are going to be faced
with such a shock, then immediately we have the development of a psychology
which is logical now to develop such a psychology.
He does not want to see the reality, it's almost living in an intoxicated state,
living in a state of nice surroundings and environment.
The moment that he is faced with a shock then there is death.
That means death can make and then we have the development of an anxiety state
that is overtaken the whole of the person.
Death, death, death... I will die, everybody will die.
The idea of decay and
suddenly the idea of death
with all its paraphernalia
comes into the mind.
Death, decay and then the child or the grown- up start thinking about death
and how death may come about.
There comes some pain.
There is a little pain, which is not going to go away immediately,
the mind will go to the possibility of having cancer.
Immediately there is an overwhelming fear that this is cancer.
If that state is left to progress and now we
have a peculiar psychology with these cases
where the Agaricus cases they seem to attract information concerning death
or you may say in another way, whenever death is concerned they cannot forget.
So when they come to you
to the consultation
room and they will tell
about their sciaticas,
their pains, they will relate to you all kinds of death.
As you discuss you understand that there is an anxiety about health
and you say do you have an anxiety about health, you are afraid of cancer?
They say yes, how can I not be afraid?
Yesterday I had a friend and his friend
went to the hospital where they cut his leg
because he had cancer.
They tell you a tremendous story about cancer and how he died from cancer.
One week ago I had another case where my mother has a relative and this relative
had a friend... Again cancer and then they tell you all these stories of cancer.
Where am I living? Because
she relates all these
stories of cancer which
are impressing her,
she relates whatever she hears about death,
the picture is impressed upon her mind
and she develops the anxiety more and more.
Most probably everybody has cancer, everybody...
and then it starts the real pathology on this level of Agaricus,
where the fear of cancer, the anxiety will grow bigger and bigger.
It will completely overwhelm them and sometimes they will reach the point
where they will say either I will lose my mind tomorrow...
There is no further fear to go to withstand, I cannot withstand further fear,
I'm going to lose my mind because of the fear of cancer.
In such cases with tremendous anxieties, you
will be prescribing mostly remedies like?
-Nitric acid?
-Nitric acid, then?
-Arsenicum.
-Kali arsenicum?
-Kali Arsenicum, then?
-Phosphorus?
-Phosphorus, then Lycopodium, Argentum nitricum etc.
Before I was able to recognize that picture of Agaricus,
I was prescribing all these remedies with very little effect.
Cancer will be better, maybe nothing, maybe
this or that but not with the real freedom
that brings about the correct remedy.
In overwhelming anxiety about health, we have Agaricus in capital there,
where in the Repertory I think it's said it's ordinary...
Anxiety about health is there? No?
Hypochondriac and anxiety?
You can add Agaricus in anxiety about health.
Hypochondriac and anxiety also.
These cases, if you don't recognize it from the beginning,
they will overwhelm you because the anxiety builts up so strongly that even
talking on the telephone, they will break out crying on the telephone
because the anxiety is so great. They don't say the anxiety story.
This state now comes because of some little reasons.
For instance they might have a pain in the course of the sciatic nerve...
I want to move, I'm Rhus tox.
And sometimes Agaricus will have a pain on a
point, which is there all the time almost.
That is what they feel at least and they will
press it and press it and here it is again,
it's not gone.
By pressing that point,
they will irritate that
point and they will
keep the pain is there.
That pain, there is something there, this
is what triggers the tremendous anxiety.
A woman will come with her breast and you
will search and search to find out something
which is maybe, which hardly exists.
Here in the (?) region they will search and
search, they say there is a nod there.
There is a gland swell, you try to find and you cannot find anything.
Their imagination is so big that they will imagine that it's really cancer.
If every half an hour the woman searches
and presses, she will aggravate the glands
and maybe sometimes there will be some gland swelled up but you can see nothing.
But the anxiety of that nothing is so tremendous that you cannot believe.
You say I can see nothing, it doesn't help.
Whether they will go to
10 different doctors to
confirm that there is
nothing in the mammography,
there will be 1 or 2
days maybe they will not
search and the third day
they will start again.
They say here it is, the doctor most probably made a mistake.
There they come to you and they will not say I have anxiety about health.
They will sit here and you will say what about that pain?
They will say nothing, nothing.
Then why are you crying? She says I don't know.
She is pressing so much to find whether the pain is strong or not.
What is there? The crying is not because of the pain.
It's because of the tremendous anxiety behind that this pain might be cancer.
That crying, asking for help but immediately
because it is cancer, you don't understand.
This is cancer and I have been to 2-3
different doctors and they say it's nothing
but it is cancer.
This is behind her mind, she won't talk, they are words that are not spoken
but what you perceive, what you feel is that idea of overwhelming anxiety
and then you dare to understand that maybe it's a case of Agaricus.
Because the pain is not really...
Do you really afraid of cancer?
Of course I'm afraid of cancer, what do you think?...
And then you will hear the story and you say
my god there are so many cases around you?
And then another story and
another story, another
person and another person
and then you go crazy.
They all go to that particular person and everybody hears about such cases
but we don't pay attention so much. To the
Agaricus case this is a tremendous event.
You talk to them, you are
very nice, most probably
this time you take
Arsenicum or Nitric acid.
The strange thing with Agaricus will be that once real pains come,
when the real sciatica pains come, the anxiety will reduce to 10%.
It's very strange because now she has come with tremendous lumbago,
where she can hardly move or the leg...
You see real pain and the anxiety she has forgot it. This state is not there.
The psychological state is not anymore there.
We see this changing over from physical symptoms to great anxiety.
I remember a case, with
these sciatic pains, I've
given the wrong remedy
and supress the pain.
Then I gave different remedies and for 1,5
year I was trying to cure that anxiety
that had come after the sciatica, which I had suppressed with the wrong remedy.
Nothing, nothing would help.
Agaricus took away the case and brought back the sciatica.
So you will see the exchanging of one to the other.
These people where many times will be obsessed with suffering around them.
It is peculiar that though they are afraid so
much of cancer etc. once it is not cancer,
they will go and help
cases where somebody else
would not even think
of going and helping.
They hear of an old lady of 95 years old, living absolutely alone, dirty,
she doesn't have to eat, she is very sick...the
Agaricus they will go and help that case.
They will go right into the meat of the disease.
Of what somebody else would be terrified.
They seem to be attracted in hearing all these stories or looking after people
with such severe kind of diseases and illnesses.
Naturally you would think that these persons would avoid going sick persons,
like Arsenicum, when they hear hospital, far from it, as far as they can be.
Phosphorus also, they don't like hospitals.
And Nitric acid... I have to go there? No...
Agaricus will rush into situations with suffering.
Do you see the difference?
There is a kind of immaturity
I would say, there
is a kind of later
development of the mind
and late development of the system in coordination, twichings, chorea,
they cannot take an imprimand. If you talk to them...
A grown up, they can take so much and you say how is it that they don't react?
If you challenge, nothing to retaliate and
to hold back, no, they don't have that.
And they will go into twitchingsBut within that the voice is quite cold.
There is no the reaction that you expected.
Why you are doing the stupid thing 5 times the day, why?
And they say I'm stupid, this kind of reaction.
And the more you shout to them, the more the twitchings...
It seems that it doesn't penetrate their emotional level.
Emotionally actually they are quite nice
people and usually everybody likes them.
Because of that quality most probably that
they don't have the will power to go out
and tell what they think.
It is the mental part that overtakes that fear.
The idea that they may get fear overwhelms them completely
and then they will go into depression, a kind of.
Perhaps in the books you will see the expression as if drunk, as if intoxicated.
You will not see drunk, you will not see intoxicated.
When you see a drunk person, you do not take it seriously.
It doesn't matter, it's OK I'm a fool. This is the idea behind.
They are not aggressive, they do not have spikes, their emotions are nice.
It's an animal that has only...
Never mind what you say like the Lilium tigrinum, you feel the spike, needles...
This is what the animal has. You feel...
Nevermind what you say to the Lilium tigrinum case, the answer will be...
Nux vomica a lot, Natrum muriaticum a lot of spikes.
Agaricus, nothing. They are sweet in that level.
Tell me what shall I do? Am I right? Should I go there?
The idea of non-development, the non-timely maturity.
They mature more slowly than others.
Another characteristic that you may see in their psychology is that
once this overwhelming fear, anxiety keeps standing a depressed state.
This is the only thing that gives them depression but it is very strong,
so it overwhelms their life.
They say I have a nice life, my husband is nice, my children are nice
and I cannot enjoy, nothing. Why? Because all the time that pain is there.
She comes with sciatica and she can hardly
move and she says yes I enjoy life now.
It is not logical. The moment they tell you,
they try to persuade you that it is logical
that I have this anxiety because the pain
is constant, therefore it means cancer.
And therefore they live in a state of constant agony, depression.
It's almost impossible to describe to you the
intensity of the anxiety of that remedy.
I have seen it in a medical doctor and he would telephone all the time.
He is in the hospital and he sees another case and another case.
Are you sure that this case of mine is not...? I had diarrhea yesterday.
I say yes but you know, you are a medical doctor,
you know that one diarrhea doesn't mean anything.
Yes, yes but I'm afraid that this diarrhea of mine is a special diarrhea.
They try to make a point and you say no, no
please, don't be afraid and they go away.
And then two days later it's another case, now I have a pain in the chest.
With that pain, this is the history he took
from the patient who had pain in the chest
and now they have cancer on the lungs.
And I have coughing... Lately I have noticed that I have coughing.
How many? How many? I don't know maybe 3 months I'm coughing now.
You are coughing 3 months and you never told me?
Yes I haven't notice but now I look back and I was coughing.
And you are still coughing? Yes I'm coughing.
How many times the day? One, twice.
So you have cancer? Yes.
But you are a medical doctor and you know that cancer is not coming like that.
With cancer you have to have also the exhaustion or other symptoms.
Yes but lately I'm feeling exhausted.
When we say exhausted, we mean really exhausted.
And then developing and developing and thinking and thinking what is the remedy?
He comes to the office in a crazy state of mind...
I'm destroyed. Why you are destroyed? What happened?
This idea of cancer is overwhelming.
That is the state of Agaricus. It's not I have anxiety about health.
Like a Norwegian! Perhaps a Norwegian Agaricus could do that.
I have cancer, maybe?
Never mind how much I describe, when you see the case it's a different thing.
To see the case in different stage of development also
because you do not see only always in that
last stage I described to you with the doctor.
You will see it in lower forms also.
You will see it when the anxiety...
Another point that you
must remember is that
they are concerned so
much with the relatives.
The woman about the husband, the husband
about the woman, they don't tell anymore...
I'm terrible all the time, so I cannot tell him.
Did you discuss the problem with your husband? She says no.
For the last 3-5 years I have destroyed him.
During morning, noon and
night are constantly
talking about this, so I
don't talk it anymore
but I can't live anymore with that fear. That's the idea.
They are concerned that they have said so much, they have complained so much...
They feel that it is too much.
Themselves they understand but yet they will say I cannot get over it.
So you see their inner
struggle feeling that they
are tormenting everybody
with their complains,
yet they are not able to keep inside the complain.
And suddenly you may see in such cases this
state to go completely away from the person
and another state, which is a very peculiar state...
we try to describe it to you, where the person
feels suddenly a tremendous energy arising
from inside them, a kind of joyfulness, a kind of exhilaration,
a kind of almost ecstasy in which they go into it.
So there is a tremendous energy, exhilaration, joyfulness but again it's so much
that back in their minds
they say this is not
natural, it is not
something that is natural.
It's going to burn me up, it's going to destroy me.
So the Agaricus stage can be alternating
and changing from one state to the other.
The difference is that
the state of anxiety and
the state of tremendous
fear is much bigger
but in length of time than the stage of exhilaration and joyfulness and ecstasy.
Then in the book it says he will go into poetry, they make poets...
It seems that the mind becomes so clear, so
easy to perceive ideas, they live intense,
in the book it says he makes verses.
It's not makes verses, it's not makes poetry.
Sometimes I have found an Agaricus case that makes poetry
but what they do is they talk in an exhilarated state of mind.
They are talking in a state where they are more perceptive
but yet they will tell you that the energy, which is coming is too much.
Once you see in the
history of a patient, you
see these ideas of
anxiety, anxiety, anxiety
and then suddenly to go into stage of exhilaration, loquacity etc.,
then you must remember Agaricus.
It is also strange that they seem to provoke out of the body experiences.
How many people have had out of the body experiences?
Half of the class doesn't know what it is.
It is a state where they feel that they are out of their bodies
and they experience different things.
That can happen to a stage of mediumcy. When
you go to a medium to tell you your fortune,
it is somebody that hypnotise himself and tells the future.
This kind of experience.
These Agaricus patients go out of their body easily.
They have experiences where the aetheric body jerks out easily.
In such a state you would have expected that
the person would usually goes into panic
and this is a state with what remedy?
-Canabis indica.
-Canabis indica would be terrified with this feeling.
Agaricus cases have that feeling and they almost enjoy it.
They will lie in bed and try to have this feeling because they feel better.
They will tell you that after these experiences they feel better.
So if you have a patient who is overwhelmed with fear of death by cancer
and they are desperate and they say they want to die.
Nobody of Agaricus wants to die really but
they say my life has become such a suffering,
I don't want to live anymore.
You say you want to die?
No I don't want to die,
I want to live but not
under this condition.
This is the idea. So when they go into bed and they go out of their body,
they feel rejuvenated.
It is a state of escaping from their tremendous anxiety.
Agaricus we may see in latest stages of development of its pathology,
that they go crazy, they go out of their mind and you may see them
in a state of constant
loquacity, whistling in
stage where they are in
very serious condition,
out of contact.
They will go into rages, into shouting and shrinking and in this stage
you may see that they will talk about prophesies, about catastrophes,
about things that are going to happen in the future.
A stage within this fear of action of Agaricus is that they become religious,
they have religious
affections and these
affections usually show
great simpleness or piety.
They are very sweet, very good... this type of religious affection.
From a general point of view we see convulsive stage
which alternates consciousness and unconsciousness.
They can into unconscious stage and then they come out.
Another sphere of action is hysterical kind of convulsions or fainting.
Especially when these convulsions or fainting
are precipitated by sexual intercourse.
In their sexual sphere, they are quite excitable persons.
They can be very excitable
and very amorous
because the imagination
is quite active with them
but they have maybe a lack of enjoyment during orgasm.
That means the orgasm is not analogous to the excitement.
And many times after sexual intercourse, they may have different problems.
Sexual intercourse aggravates the Agaricus case.
In case there are convulsions, they will be aggravated after sexual intercourse,
In case there are headaches, they will be aggravated after sexual intercourse.
We have periodicity especially with convulsions that are coming once every week.
If you see vomiting ameliorates the convulsions, that means convulsions
end up in vomiting and vomiting ameliorates the convulsions, then it's Agaricus.
Chorea, when they move or the whole body moves and dances...
that is aggravated again by sexual intercourse.
Whenever you see headaches, which are accompanied by twitchings of the face,
grimaces, this kind, that kind of twitchings, both eyes...
Headaches together with this kind of twitchings, you think of Agaricus.
As we said headaches aggravated by sexual intercourse
and also aggravated by spiritual liqueurs, by alcohol.
Quivering in the eyelids or twitchings in the eyelids...
And if these quiverings or twitchings happen before a thunderstorm,
then it becomes a case of Agaricus.
If you get little symptoms like that, they are peculiar symptoms
that you would like to have and indicate the remedy.
Also there is a lot of itching in the eyes,
which starts from the eyes but it extends in the upper respiratory track
and you may have itching inside the throat and inside the ears.
If this itching is aggravated during menses
in women, then it becomes characteristic.
The hay fever also is characterized by intense itching like another remedy...
-Wyethia?
-Wyethia.
In the face we have the twitchings, in the
stomach we have increased appetite usually
but the appetite is lost after coition again.
You see the general aggravation of the symptoms
after coition, after sexual intercourse.
Another symptom that you may get is...
You may see especially in women a type of hysterical reaction after coition.
They start crying hysterically, without
knowing why and they have spells of fainting.
They seem to pass away, to fade away.
Another symptom you may meet with Agaricus and that you have to connect
with the weak will of Agaricus, in the sexual sphere, especially with men...
The sexual desire is quite strong, they get very easily excited
and they end up in pornography, looking at magazines with nude women
and get excited and go into masturbation.
Then we have the characteristics of Agaricus
in lumbagos, pain in the lumbar region,
pain in the sciatic nerves ameliorated by lying down.
Great amelioration from lying down, the pain is excruciating, they cannot walk,
they cannot make a movement, they lie in bed and it is as if they have nothing.
The amelioration is great with Agaricus.
Aggravated by rising from a sitting position.
While stooping, bending forward.
There is stiffness in the cervical region,
which is aggravated by leaning forward.
You may have also twitchings in the back area.
We have also trembling
in the extremities after
coition and twitchings
in the extremities.
Coldness, generally they are cold and especially coldness in spots,
there is a whole small area, which is cold.
Aggravated by cold.
I will just give you a brief summary of what are the main symptoms.
Tremendous fear of cancer, depressing states alternating with ecstatic states.
The manic depressive kind but not the pure type.
Then twitchings, (?) convulsive disorders, twitchings especially in the eyelids
and especially in thunderstorms.
Facial grimaces, aggrevation after coition,
lumbago and sciatica better lying down.
Diagonal pains, the elbow left and the right knee.
It is the right shoulder joint and the left knee joint, diagonally.
Hay fever with deep itching that extends
to the upper respiratory truck and ears.
Coldness in spots and coldness in general.
That is -you can say- is more or less the idea of Agaricus.
In studying a case, you may go to the books and see thousands of symptoms
but you don't know where to start and where to finish.
What I'm giving you is the essence of the symptomatology.
This you can stick into your mind and you
can relate because always in your cases
you will have to find these kind of
peculiarities to say this is an Agaricus case.
It is seldom that you will find just flat symptoms that will indicate Agaricus.
As you know, there are different ways of repertorising a case.
One of them is the mechanical way, taking all the symptoms, go to the Repertory,
find all the remedies that are there and then you see which remedy goes through.
This is very seldom that you will have it.
Sometimes you will have it but it is seldom.