I'd like to speak today on Cann-i.
and the era of Cann-i. that the western civilization went through and I believe we're still going through.
I'd like to speak a little bit in depth on this very important drug, especially of the young people.
And to see and find out what Cann-i. can do for the human race and what we can do to erase the effects of Cann-i. on the race.
It was a big question for me why the younger people of the previous and the present generation, they were so much in favor of using Cann-i.
What was the reason behind?
I have understood that the exciting causes for diseases were of 3 different types.
The first was a frustration on the survival instinct. When a man does not have the means to survive physically, he wants to support his physical body.
And he has to have a job, he has to have food and the lack of these basic things bring about a frustration on the physical body and we have a frustration on the survival instinct.
That can be the exciting cause for diseases which can be either chronic or acute.
Another reason for frustration is on another level and that is on emotional level. Frustration on an emotional level which also covers the sexual sphere.
I have noticed that it is very frequently another exciting cause for bringing up, manifesting acute or chronic diseases.
And here we have what orthodox Medicine also recognizes as psychosomatic diseases and the type of psychosomatic diseases.
And the third reason for chronic diseases is the frustration on a spiritual level.
And I consider this area very important for our contemporary society.
What happened was that the generation that started going in Cann-i. had actually solved the problem of survival.
They felt quite secure that they could survive even if they did very little work or not at all.
The society was ready to support, the parents, the society, the different security forms that existed in the society. So that instinct was satisfied.
Also the so-called freedom on the emotional and sexual level presented an abundance in this area.
And therefore left the young people over-satisfied with food and sex finally.
And the next step that had to be satisfied was a spiritual need, a need to know the truth.
I believe that this was the reason why so many young people went into drugs in general.
As they felt that material needs were so easily satisfied, they felt also that they had the right or the possibility to taste a spiritual kind of
understanding or to come into contact with what they felt it is the truth.
States of enlightenment that have been described in different spiritual books by different spiritual teachers became then the object of the young people.
But they were unprepared to really rise up to the situation.
And Cann-i. provided a very easy way of coming into contact with something that they felt was inside all the time.
A state of being that was inside but it was unattainable through sheer efforts.
I feel this is mostly the reason why the young generation went into this kind of exploration.
I said before that this generation was unprepared to face spiritual truth.
I believe that the seeking out on a spiritual level is a natural kind of drive within the human beings
once they have satisfied the lower levels of survival, instinct and also sexual instinct which are very powerful.
But there has to be an effort, you see in spiritual things you're dealing with truth. Therefore you cannot bluff anybody.
In material things we can bluff each other, we can rationalize, we can say I deserve also to have money in spite of not working because
I did not ask to be born my parents brought me here because they wanted to have pleasure and so I was born and therefore it is their responsibility to feed me.
That's an immature attitude that we can take and we can have, we can feed ourselves.
We can feed it with material food bluffing our way.
Then the material body feeds on material food and oxygen.
There is another body within us, the emotional body, the emotional structure which feeds on what?
Can anybody tell me? What is the food? Emotions are not the food.
Impressions, we receive impressions and impressions generate feelings. The food on the emotional level is impressions.
We can have that because impressions are not difficult to get.
And we can stimulate our emotions with different kinds of impressions.
The problem was that this generation that went into drugs, into Cann-i., again misused impressions.
They found again very easy excitement of the emotions and they wanted more and more and more excitement. Nothing was then satisfying them.
There was a kind of immaturity also on that level; I want adventure.
They wanted relationships for the pleasure only.
And this seeking of impressions lead to a dead end.
Because young people of 20, 23,25 felt already very old, that they knew already everything.
There is a balance in the body. Let's take an extreme example.
You lie down and you open your mouth and somebody is feeding you all the time. Lying down, feeding you with chocolates, sweets, fatty food and you lie down and you just eat.
This is the situation. What is going to happen to the physical body?
It's going to get sick. The same thing happens with the emotions.
Without any kind of effort, without any respect to that portion of the human body the young generations asked more and more pleasures and pleasurable impressions.
As a result the body got unbalanced, the emotional level got unbalanced.
There was a kind of saturation. And then came the need for spiritual truth and understanding.
And then the spiritual feeds with what?
What is the food of the spiritual part?
Do you think that a man can stay alive spiritually if he pursues simple knowledge?
Learning only some, will he stay alive? Pursuing some knowledge, crapping his memory with knowledge?
What the spiritual part needs to be alive?
What is a good food that will keep it alive?
The spiritual feeds on ideas.
The physical feeds from a lower part of evolution. What is physical in us feeds from the animal, the vegetable, the mineral kingdom.
The physical part of us feeds on what is lower than us.
The spiritual part in us feeds on what is higher than us. Do you see the difference?
You need a book of new ideas to understand and to feel that you are alive spiritually.
Somebody who is higher than you will give some ideas and these ideas will make you feel more free, more in contact with the truth.
So therefore the spiritual part in us cannot be bluffed because we are on a certain level.
We cannot play with ourselves and bluff ourselves. We need real ideas, ideas coming  from the truth in order to feel the kind of nourishment that we need spiritually.
That is what the people were seeking through Cann-i.
They were trying to bluff because to be fed from a higher source spiritually, you have to make an effort, to lift yourself to that source.
There has to be a kind of homogeneity that will communicate. Nobody can give spiritual truth, understanding, enlightment etc.
if you just lie down in the sun and you are half dozed, unconscious.
The super conscious in men has to be awaken. Now Cann-i. what it did, gave a delusion of truth.
It gave an appearance as if the person was having the state of truth.
What was the payment for that?
The payment was a miasm that was engrafted upon many many people and we call the Cann-i. miasm or proving.
It is interesting also that to see who are the people who are taking Cann-i. It used to be in the past a few people that used to take Cann-i.
They were basic people seeking pleasure.
Not spiritual questioning or seeking, just sheer pleasure, they were the people who went for narcotics in the past.
They were seeking pleasure on a completely material level.
Today the use of Cann-i. is mostly from people seeking spiritual understanding.
Out of those people who take this drug, I have seen 3 kinds of reactions.
The first are people who had mixed experiences with Cann-i., some pleasurable experiences and some very unpleasurable.
After going for a while in the drug culture, they gave up. And these are the lucky people and they came out with a conviction that Cann-i. is not the solution.
There is another type of those people with weak will mostly that were caught on this pleasure.
They followed this path and they  became addicts.
The first group does not need treatment. The second group does it need treatment and what can we do about them?
The second group is the group that likes the pleasure, they are convinced that it is good for them, they are convinced drug addicts.
And we are going to try to take them away from the drugs. What Cann-i. can do in a potentized form? What other drugs can do?
What do you think?
Can we save these people? Do they want to be saved?
If you give them a Cann-i. on high potency, even without knowing, is it going to have an effect? What kind of effect?
Do you have experience in treating such people?
There is really very little hope for the people who are really caught in the drugs.
Out of these drug addicts we may be able to help a 20%.
The confirmed drug addicts that say, 'I like it'.
I don't talk about people who say, 'I don't like it, I try, I cannot get out of it but I want to try'. This is another group of people.
This is the third group of people that understand the effect upon them which can be two-fold.
Either an effect because of the long use of the drug or an effect because they have a great sensitivity towards that drug.
And these people usually have experiences which are not at all pleasurable.
They have very frightening experiences usually. These people can have an engraftment on their system of the Cann-i. state by just using once or twice Cann-i.
Once they go a little bit bigger in their dose, the mind is engrafted and from that point onwards there is going to be a symptomatology that we shall be talking about.
So from this third group is that we really get our information about the proving of the drug.
When you have the pleasurable state, you do not have the proving of the drug.
People will not come to you to be treated because of the Cann-i. state which is pleasurable.
We shall see what is the real pathological state of Cann-i.
Before going into pathology of the Cann-i. state, I would like to give you an idea of what I think is happening when somebody takes the drug in general.
And according to this idea the pathology will be around this idea.
Let us say symbolically that there are 3 kinds of levels. The physical level, the physical world
another world which is the dream world or they call it the astral world and above that is the spiritual world.
A human being living in this physical world cannot come in touch with the pure spiritual world because this world is guarded somewhat by the astral.
The astral level is what we live in our dreams. Sometimes we live a bad experience, sometimes we live a very nice experience in our dream.
Now in order to live in this dream state, there is a kind of detachment between the physical body and the ethereal body which is within us.
A kind of detachment that we leave the physical body during sleep and we live in this level that we call astral or whatever you want to call it.
What Cann-i. does actually and most of the drugs is to bring about a forceful detachment of the astral body and make the person live into the world of dreams, into the world of delusions.
But now this process is the same process as the one that is used by the yogis, the saints, the spiritual people when they have out of the body experiences
and when they try to come out of their body and approach that spiritual world which is the world of light, enlightenment.
They try to do it after an effort of many years with very systematic work. Cann-i. will do the same thing for the individual, will detach the body forcefully.
But in order this astral part in us will go on a higher kind of level approaching the spiritual, it has to be what?
-Pure.
-It has to be pure.
That's why the experiences which the young people have, because the young people are pure, many times have spiritual taste.
Because of their purity the body is just jerked out, the intensity is for spiritual experiences and they pass through this after world
and they come up on a higher level of this astral level where experiences are kind of spiritual.
But if there is a fear within the experimental, if there is a bad situation or bad vibrations in the environment, if there is guilt inside, fear, guilt, negative emotions, whatever
by coming out of the body, going to this realm, it will be caught on the lower levels of the astral world and there the experiences are terrifying.
That's why many people will take this drug and they will have a terrifying experience. They go through hell.
If somebody, his constitution is such that is easily detachable, the astral part from the physical part, then this person is prone, is predisposed to have Cann-i. symptomatology.
What will happen now as far as pathology?
There are 3 different stages that the pathology can follow.
The first stage is a kind of excitement. An intensive excitement which makes the person become very loquacious.
He will talk, make fun, tease people, being in a state of excitement, you see the person and you say this is not a natural state.
Too much excitement, loquacity, ideas, talking of different things.
And during that stage he may relate to you a few delusions here and there that may be happening to him.
And while there is that kind of excitement and mental stimulation especially, there are times when the mind seems scattered and becomes completely absent minded.
So great absent mindedness will alternate with states of stimulation of the intellect and loquacity and then as a result we have laughing, immoderate laughing.
You see this person who is excitable, how easily is to break out into laughing now.
And with the least provocation, will make him laugh in a way that will show you that this person is not balanced.
In that state they may have a kind of clairvoyant ability, not that they can use this clairvoyance willingly. It just comes.
From time to time with open eyes, they may visualize things.
And because of that excitement in this stage we see many times trembling and especially shaking of the head. The trembling is on the head or on the hands.
And some other times you will see suddenly to bring out an anger that you do not expect. It is sudden and it is very strong.
During that state also you will see that these people they have a tendency to try and find out in an intellectual manner truth, what is happening, making all kinds of theories and ideas.
What is the net result of that, you will see an over stimulation that is on the brink of something breaking down. An over stimulation of the intellect.
You do not have to have theories like Einstein theory and this theory and that theory and the philosophical theories, no, no.
They may be theorizing about little things. Why this book is blue and white and why the man who produced that has made it and they can bring a whole story
about how this book was conceived, what the man thought, what is the symbolism of blue and white. Then they go to another subject, to another subject.
At this stage they will not almost consult you. It is the other people around them that feel that something is wrong with that guy.
They, themselves do not feel yet the need; all the symptomatology is in the first stage that does not yet provoke suffering on the path of the person.
In the books of Cann-i. will say ecstatic state etc.
Even Kent will say that. I have not seen this state.
That means without taking the drug some person to have ecstatic state which bothers him and will come to you for consultation.
Cannabis produces these states but you will not see them in treating cases.
What you will see it will be that stimulation, that trembling, the stimulation, the thirst is increased, the urine is excreted quite a lot.
There is a stimulation definately and there is also a hunger which is greater than usual which again predisposes the person, or gives you the idea of diabetes.
Then the second stage comes which is the painful state and which is exactly what we described, the disconnection between the astral body and the physical body on a permanent basis almost.
What these people feel now is that they have something that there is something in them which is out of their control.
As the excitement state breaks down, then what happens is the astral body or part of the astral body seems to go out.
They have a very real sense that the arm is raising up.
The arm is there but the feeling has gone away and that feeling is now that produces what we see in the books 'fear of insanity' in Cann-i.
Fear of insanity in Cann-i. you will seldom hear it like that.
The person to come and tell you, you know something I have fear of insanity, I'm afraid I'm going to lose my mind. Very seldom.
They will tell different stories, they will tell these experiences, the leg comes up, the head is as if opens and closes.
The hand goes up and then it goes down. It can happen to any part of the body, especially the head and the extremities.
They go out and back again and that feeling brings about a tremendous fear with panic that they may lose control.
The fear in Cann-i. is fear of losing control on any level, not only losing control of the hand.
Neither they will say 'I'm afraid of losing control of my mind'. They will say 'I have to have control'.
What do you mean by that? That means I'm travelling and have to have a kind of security that I know who is driving, whether he is a good driver etc.
I have to have control. He goes with another driver who do not trust, immediately fears and panics develop.
Another example is, you're going to give me a remedy, I have to know what it is.
Why? Because in this way I have a  control. I know that you're giving me Sulphur.
And I have a control. If you give me something which I don't know, I don't have a control, then I'm going to panic, panicky states.
Fear of losing control so much so that it goes into panic states, so much so that when they drive with a car they fear that they may lose control.
And they may just pass out, faint. You know these things will happen.
The hand makes them almost impossible to keep on doing the daily tasks, especially driving with a car. They may just give up driving.
In these stages these people will get hallucinations, delusions. What kind of delusions?
If you look in the Materia Medica or in the Repertory, the Cann-i. is full of delusions, anything imaginable can be produced by Cann-i.
But what is interesting for you to remember in order to recognize Cann-i. in a case is that these delusions will have the idea of going out of the body and travelling out of the body.
So delusion that they're riding on a horse, that will fly away and start wandering amongst the stars, that is flying or dancing around the sun.
This kind of ethereal delusions which are not pleasant. Do not imagine that they have these ideas or delusions and they feel pleasant.
They feel they lost control completely and before they break down which is the third stage, they go into panicky states.
During that state the face looks burned out and exhausted.
The eyes usually will have a glistening, kind of bright glistening and later on will become dull.
Detachment of the body and the mind, this is the idea which gives the idea of paralysis which may happen with Cann-i.
With Cann-i. we may have stages of complete paralysis for a certain time, a certain period.
The people feel paralyzed completely and then they may come back. It's a hysterical kind of paralysis.
Delusions which are inside the head like delusions of hearing but inside the head.
As if somebody singing within them, especially the moment which they try to fall asleep.
This is a difficult time for Cann-i. because this is the time where the body is separating actually and can cause a lot of problems.
And a lot of jerkings also, severe jerkings that will wake up the person.
But what you're interested to remember is this intellectual stimulation in the beginning.
Theories, loquacity, laughing and then these panicky states where all this happens on a level where the person feels
if I tell now that I fear insanity, then the other person may believe that I'm insane and then I lost control.
They feel that there is a tiny bind that if it breaks, then they will go off and then they will become insane.
And that tiny break they try to keep and try not to tell that they really feel fear of insanity.
So in Cann-i. you will not get the patient telling fear of insanity.
Which is the remedy that will say it quite easily?
Calcarea, Pulsatilla also and Mancinella. For different reasons but they will express it.
Cann-i. is capital letters on the Repertory together with Calcarea, Mancinella, Pulsatilla but it will not say, 'I have fear of insanity'. I have never heard it from Cann-i. persons.
I have seen that urge to have control of every situation possible you can imagine. Never mind what is the situation, they have to have a control. A logical control.
And if they feel they are losing that, they are going into panic and it will appear then as if they have tremendous what?
What is the Repertory symptom that you may be mislead to be looking at?
As I was describing this state and you have to imagine I'm trying to make you imagine having the patient, talking to you, saying different things.
And how you will differentiate.
So he will tell you about all these panicky things and he will call you on the telephone because it's not easy to get Cann-i. from the beginning.
You will give other remedies before you reach the conclusion that this is a Cann-i. case.
So Cann-i. will appear to have great anxiety about health. It will appear to have tremendous anxiety because they will call you and tell you again and again their symptomatology.
'George I don't feel well, I don't know what's wrong with me'. What do you have? I have tried again and again whether they will tell fear of insanity. No.
So they get the idea that they fear about their health. 'But what do you fear about your health?'. 'No, I don't fear about my health, I don't have an anxiety'. 'What do you feel?'.
Fear of losing control. The most they can reach to tell you, fear of losing control.
It is not an anxiety but it will definitely appear to you as an anxiety for certain period of time before you come down to the idea.
These stages are usually accompanied by great prostration, great weakness of the body.
The first stage is exaltation and a lot of activity of the mind, of the body also. A lot of drinking, thirst.
I remember a case of Cann-i. I don't think it's mentioned in the Repertory as great thirst but I remember one of my first cases where I've never seen such a thirst in a Cann-i. case.
Great thirst, great appetite, a lot of energy. Second stage, out of the body experiences, ethereal experiences.
The head opens as if it's lift, they feel the head is lift and then it closes.
You understand the panic that can accompany such experiences.
And then prostration leading up to paralysis, tremendous weakness leading up to paralysis.
And then hallucinations of that type, travelling around and flying away from their body.
Clairvoyant experiences the first stage and the second stage. Absent minded very much in the first stage with periods of distraction.
The mind feels no complete, not there, not total, not able to do, to perform a special duty.
Trembling of hands and the head.
How do they behave now sexually?
Before we go sexually I will describe to you the third stage.
The third stage is a kind of complete breakdown where you can see the person really becoming old, his eyes from bright glistening that was before, become dull.
A sense of paralysis and paralysis comes to the intellect. The intellect and the power of concentration is broken down completely.
They try to concentrate and it's impossible. They try to focus their eyes and it's impossible, it brings dizziness and a state of weariness and tiredness.
They lose urine, they just go away.
The energy is so little that they have to lie down all the time and recuperate in order to get up and do very little things for very little time. They will have to lie back again.
In that state there is no fear anymore, there is no panic.
There is something beyond the fear and beyond the panic where people have lost complete control, they cannot control the urine
they cannot control the bowel movement, voluntary movements of any organ almost.
So in this way we have a picture of what Cann-i. can do. It can first stimulate and start breaking down the individual.
Eventually continues the stimulation so they cannot control the astral body, the ethereal body, delusion starts, fear, tremendous panic.
This panic is one of the worst. Only Aconite during the crisis that they get, they get from time to time the Aconite crisis, can match the fear of that. That's why you will give Aconite many times in cases of Cann-i.
You will give Kali arsenicum or Nitric acid because you will confuse it with tremendous anxiety that you feel that they have
where the underlying cause is loss of control. When you have that, you have a very good symptom for Cann-i.
Phosphoric acid has also this ethereal kind of disconnectedness but you will not get the extreme panic that accompanies Cann-i. symptomatology.
Not all people that they will have these kind of experiences will go into such panic.
When you see that then you have the idea of Cann-i.
Now how it behaves in their sexual life? Because Cann-i. affects primarily the mind and the sexual sphere.
On the first stage what it will do?
Stimulate the sexual energies and you will have a kind of person that you may be thinking of Platina.
They need a lot of sex and the woman for instance can have successive orgasms and the more they get an orgasm, the more they seek.
They will say, I need a deeper and deeper orgasm.
And you may say that this is happening usually. No.
In Cann-i. cases it is very strong. They are never satisfied with one or two orgasms. They need to keep on, so the more the pleasure, the more they seek.
In this stage Cann-i. seeks out pleasure.
In this first stage also you will see the individual but it will not give it to you as a symptom, just taking the case
watching the case, getting information about the case, then you will perceive these things.
He will say that I'm doing meditation and in meditation sometimes I feel very well. They have a kind of serenity, beauty, a sense of great beauty which comes upon them.
You will see a person for instance that has such sexual energy and they seek for meditation and it has that beauty kind of experiences.
And they are quite basic in their attitude and contact with the other sex. The instinct is quite stimulated.
Actually it's a hormonal almost stimulation and they know what they seek, they seek pleasure in sex and they try to have it.
This is the first stage.
The second stage where the person, especially when you find these ideas of theorizing, all kinds of theories;
it seems that the intellect interferes with the sexual center and makes a mess out of it.
And while they still need sex, they intellectualize so much in a kind of relationship, they will say and do things that is like interfering with that function
which is usually straightforward and normal, they will interfere. If they describe to you a Cann-i. case, the other person, will tell how confused the person looks upon these subjects.
They will not say, let's have sex. They will theorize, they will bring on cases after cases, they will say this and that.
And the other person most probably will disconnect but Cann-i., as they imagine things, they get involved into situations
where in spite of the other person - I mean in a relationship it has to be two persons that they agree on this.
The Cann-i. is so much involved intellectually, he wants sex but the other person disconnects, the Cann-i. person intellectualizes, does not see the reality it and makes advances to the other person.
The other person withdraws more and more and they can get into terrible states of crying, laughing, hysterical stage.
In the end the other person will say, what's happening, you are not well, why don't you go to a doctor?
You see now the theorizing, the intellectualization how it interferes?
The sexual instinct is at a certain level where other people will say, 'I want sex' and they do sex, nothing more.
And the third stage of sexuality where the sexual potency, the sexual power is completely lost, it's a kind of paralysis.
What is left there is an anamnesis, a memory of the sexual desire.
If you say, do you have sexual desire? Mentally they will say no but I remember it was pleasure.
It has been completely gone, paralyzed, not that they have an aversion to sex.
The anamnesis of sex is pleasurable, they do not have the power or the real drive, the real desire.
The second stage also after the panicky state, they go into periods of anguish, indescribable anguish.
They don't know what is happening, what they want and eventually into states of depression.
These states of depression will lead them to try anything. You tell them try this, try that, meditation techniques, hatha yoga, everything; they will try to get away from this state.
Many times they will say meditation helps me but it is a point where I feel my arm is going out and I get scared.
Sometimes they reach a point where they feel the death is near. Death is after a month or two or three more or less.
It's not like Agnus castus that they predict the time of death, they will say after 12 days I will
die, but the feeling that death is approaching.
You see this coming out of their body is a process of dying. This is how we die.
That experience is so real for them that they don't know what's happening; they feel that death is near.
Concerning a few things on the head. Apart from that feeling of opening and closing the upper part of the head and the trembling of the head
many times there are shocks like electric shocks through the brain.
And then they complain of a dull heavy headache, especially on the right side.
They have dreams that are clairvoyant dreams.
Nightmares in the first part of the sleep.
The hearing can be very acute.
An intense thirst and many times you may see in Cann-i. grinding of the teeth.
Great weakness, I said they want to lie down all the time and palpitations especially on waking.
Cann-i. will be indicated in impotency, in functional disorders, in phobic neurosis, in diabetes, in hysterical paralysis.
You immediately go and give Cann-i.? No, that's the whole thing. The delusions have to have this kind that we described.
Otherwise maybe another remedy may be indicated. Also you would expect, for instance, to feel a Cann-i. as a delusion that the mind and the body are separated.
It has to be in the nature of the remedy to really act. So in case of senility what remedies we expect to act more?
Baryta Carbonica.
Conium.
Alumina. Plumbum also.
-Can Cann-i. have suicidal tendencies?
-I've not seen it myself in the cases. I've seen so much fear and panic that they may die that I doubt whether it will really have suicidal tendencies.
They may say 'this is not a life, I can't live that life, this is the end, I can't take anymore, things like that'. But real suicidal tendencies I've not seen.
-What proportion of Cannabis cases have you seen as secondary to the person taking the drug and would you say there is a Cann-i. miasm?
-How many in numbers? You ask me a difficult question because I'm dealing with Homeopathy for 25 years so to actually give you numbers is very difficult.
But they are not very many. In proportion how many cases have not taken Cann-i. and they had the state of Cann-i.?
And how many they had taken? That proportion is 80 % to 20%. 80% they had taken Cann-i., developed the state.
20% they never touched Cann-i. and they developed a state of Cann-i. of the cases that I have seen.
-Do you regard the use of LSD as part of the Cann-i. picture or do you find there is strong differentiation?
-I feel that each drug has its own picture. So in general it may appear similar but unless you have for instance the panic in Cann-i., in these stages, it's not going to act.
Where LSD may not have the panic. They may have the out of the body experiences without the panic. In Cann-i. we have to have this fear of loss of control to be effective.
What I wanted to show you the other time was the physical, the astral and the spiritual and what is happening here is the physical body and within it it's the emotional and the mental.
Now the emotional and the mental part they jerk out in experiences and they enter here, still they are connected.
They may reach these areas here or here or here or may come as close as this area here but they will never enter the real spiritual realm.
There is nobody who is living on the earth who can be as pure as that and be able to really transcend.
They are grades of experiences and that's certain.
Here up to a certain point you start having spiritual kind of experiences and as you approach the spiritual area, the experiences become more and more powerful.
More and more real and more and more instructive but nobody ever lived in the spiritual realm.
This is a delusion for my understanding and I have done quite a lot of research, meeting a lot of spiritual people and discussing with them
and having my own experiences, their own experiences.
Here in order to pass through these areas, the areas of fear, darkness, guilt; whilst in the mental emotional part of you there is fear or guilt
all these emotions, as soon as you come out here, you are caught in this area.
You cannot go further up. It's like in your dream, you say I don't like the place where I am but you cannot get out.
So you are graded in whatever emotions you have at the moment. That's why if you want to have spiritual experiences, you have to purify that portion, mostly the astral.
Because that astral portion, that emotional part of us, the psychic part of us carries the spiritual part and that has to be purified.
And that is purified through a lot of work that one has to do upon himself and Cann-i. will not do the trick.
If you do it once or twice it's OK. Just give up because you are going to pay by breaking down the mind.
Cann-i. definitely has broken down the mind of the people that take it and it has left them with less intellectual powers.
I know that you don't like always to hear.
It's a pity because I believe we have reached a point that we are enough degenerated that through the action upon our bodies
of these drugs, whether it's LSD, cannabis, cocaine, heroin, morphine, amphetamines or Valium, Tavor etc.
we can degenerate further and lose completely the possibility of any kind of evolvement.
If we go spiritually, we say if you go through this area eventually then you may be drawn from the spiritual realm, higher.
If you don't manage to reach this area you will be drawn down here. Down here what exists? Death, decomposition, distraction, nothing will be left.
Your hand will be taken away and the other unless you keep it as a whole here.
To keep it as a whole here you have to work while you are in this earth, not with Cann-i.