You see capricious. The word capricious should be more, exaggerated.
You have the keys in your hands? They want the keys.
OK, take them. They take the keys and throw them away. That type is the Cina.
You remember the difference between Calc-p. and Cina?
'I want the cream'. It takes the cream, throws it away.
Why? Because most probably there is an irritation on the nervous system which does not allow them a minute of peace.
They are grinding the teeth in the night.
They are boring the finger into the nose and itching in the rectum because of the worms.
The worms are eating them up. Can you imagine an organism full of worms?
You can't get rid of them.
This state, the state of Cina if you can imagine. Because it is the remedy par excellence for worms. Pin worms.
The little worms that they eat you up and
their nervous system is so irritated with all this
and in the night irritation and what we say, capriciousness. They don't know what happens to them.
You will get this in the children so exaggerated. But you will get the same condition in the grown up
this capriciousness irritation, they don't want this and that.
You give this, they are not satisfied, you give that, they are not satisfied.
- Will they grind their teeth during the day?
During the day also. But especially during the night, during sleep.
They do not understand the situation. I have seen such cases in India. They don't realize that the child is under this condition
and they go into convulsions finally.
If this state is allowed to continue, they go into real convulsions and they stay convulsed.
Of course we have to use words but for every case, we have to get the essence, what we tell, that particularity of the case.
You say, this is Aur., this is Calc-p., this is Cham., this is Cina.
- Is it possible to heal pin worms just by giving Cina and in what potency?
-It is possible to get out the pinworms yes.
-What potency then?
-What was the question?
-What potency shall we give if it is for killing worms?
-From 200 upwards, 1M, 10M, 50M, CM if it is a child.
We shall be talking tomorrow a little bit more theory and maybe we reach the point where eventually
will give you some measurements or parameters for using potencies.
Cramps on all levels.
Cramped emotions, cramped thinking.
Cramps so severe, you get in the night persons who will make a movement in their legs, simple movement
to turn in bed and put the feet and that moment the cramp starts and it keeps on increasing until you shout.
That kind of cramps because other remedies like Caust. has also cramps in the night, in bed.  Calc. has also cramps in bed
but now in this remedy we're talking that the main symptom, the main theme that you will see is cramps.
It's a person who is cramped.
The emotions have been cramped and no release.
They are passionate people with extreme sexuality.
This can terrify them.
A woman who wakes up in this sexuality and suddenly she thinks it's so terrible, I have to do something.
Then the fear is such from the feelings that she takes it back and then after that, we see total frigidity.
Therefore the person remains in a cramped state.
And every now and then, you see this.
Cramps are starting in the extremities and eventually they end up around the solar plexus.
Then tremendous cramps, the same crying, deep crying of the emotions.
And they cramp emotionally, cramps all the time and then automatic cramps. Cramps in the stomach.
Cramping pain in the stomach you see, suffering for years.
Convulsions of course. And convulsions are ending with extreme flow of urine.
Also if skin eruptions are not left to express themselves, that means cortisone and whatever allopathic remedies
are used and after this you have epileptic fits, convulsions of any kind, cramps of any kind, after suppressed eruption
usually the remedy is Cuprum.
If you don't have only convulsions but you have mostly twichings and also restlessness, is Zinc.
You suppress any discharge. You suppress the monthly period, convulsions. You suppress the perspiration, convulsions.
So whenever you have discharges or eruptions which are suppressed and there is a result, you see convulsions of any kind.
It can be epileptic or any other convulsions. Or cramps. A pattern that starts with cramps, this is Cuprum.
- Are the cramps that you are telling us about reaction of the body, of the organism to some great need
or some trying to do or to feel something which is not allowed?
-Yes correct. You are not allowed to feel this. You put it well, you understood exactly the meaning. You are not allowed to feel this.
And then cramps, convulsions. But you understand the intensity of the feeling and the intensity of the suppression.
Intense feeling, intense suppression it ends up into convulsions.
You have to get to the idea of the remedies and then you become fantastic prescribers.
-In cancer patients very often before they die there is this uncontrolled cramping all over the body?
-Yes, yes you can relieve them, not save them but you can relieve them.
Of course Cuprum is one of the main remedies for epilepsy.
The first signs are the clenching of the thumb. There is a tendency in the beginning to clench.
This positions is characteristic of convulsions. But in the beginning is the tendency.
The nervous system makes this thumb go inside and you see they walk like this.
Also this indicates a shyness, not being able to show your inner feelings.
The Cuprum people are cramped and they cannot show their inner feelings.
They have a color which is like copper.
It's a peculiar color which is grey copper if you can imagine. You have to imagine.
Once you have seen it, you will not forget it.
Like earth but towards the copper.
There is some unhealthy, greyish, earth and copper put them together.
Also you get some involuntary grimaces (faces). Like Agaricus.
The grimaces in Cuprum are much more.
Agaricus is less. It's twitching.
You feel all the muscles in tension.
You will feel they try to hide something which they don't know themselves what it is.
These people they have psychoanalyzed themselves, they have done quite a lot to be able to release this pressure. Nothing.
I have seen the most disturbing
for 5 minutes and then released. And then again after an hour. With the least emotions which are stimulated.
These are not cramps, I don't know how to say it. When the cramps come are very painful.
Not always painful.
When the cramps come on the extremities, very painful. These cramps here may not be painful but
you have a gastritis and you say, what do you feel? They feel cramping pain. Very clearly they will describe it.
-I have a question also. Is Cuprum a case on hyperventilation?
-Sure it can be in any case as long as you have the cramps or the cramping, the grimaces, the cramped emotions.
Because people will hold back. You know a syndrome which is called Tourette?
It's called Gilles de la Tourette.
This is a terrible and difficult for us to cure also. It belongs to the ticks. It's the worst from all the ticks with this kind of grimaces.
This syndrome comes also together with the need to speak out bad words.
When you battle with such cases then you get some experience, you know what I mean.
-Should it be cramps always or it can be tensed?
-I want to say that always when I speak, I speak on an exaggerated level.
I speak to give you the clear picture. Before you reach that clear picture there are steps.
If you get the essence of the whole thing, then you can understand the steps. Because it's not possible for me
to describe all the different steps. So it is true that you don't need to have this, there is a tension,
a tension which can bring stammering.
The speech is cramped.
In Stramonium where the subconscious is so much in aggravated state, the stammering is ....
You look at the person and you say 'God! Just say one word'. There is aggression, suffering.
And it's different stammering as I said, Caust. stammering yes but if they are excited, then they cannot speak.
And then you get the Mercury stammering which is a sweet stammering.
-What is the difference with the cramps of Nux-v.?
-The pains of Nux-v. are not cramping pains; sometimes they are but the main pains in Nux-v. are burning.
Heartburns. It is burning and comes up there.
No in the legs we have Caust. and Calc.
I was saying that Merc. has a stammering that you hardly understand
you don't feel any pressure behind and therefore you are sympathetic towards that.
You don't even mind but the other remedies like the Stramonium.... oh God!
Because it is a violent remedy the expressions are violent in Stramonium.
Very good remedy when you give final examinations. When you come in front of giving the final examinations
you better take a little bit of Gels. because you'll be a little bit trembling.
What is he going to ask me? Shall I answer?
The idea of weakness and trembling together. Weakness in psychic, in the mind and in the body and trembling.
So somebody who is weak and trembling we call it, there is a word 'coward'.
In the Repertory it says coward.
If you open the Repertory you will see Lyc. and Gels., the two main remedies for cowardness
but Gels. is totally different than Lyc.
Gels. is a person who is totally afraid.
What am I doing here myself, I cannot be Gels., it's impossible. Gels. to appear in front of people talking
forget it!
If she has to do it she has written everything down and she has to do it tomorrow, she will not sleep the whole night.
Next day she will be trembling. She may do it if she has to do it. Sometimes they do it but they swear to God
I'll never do it again. So much is the ordeal in appearing for an examination.
That's why it's very good for the students who are going to give an examination to a Professor who is really like a shark.
You know there are some professors you think they want to swallow you.
Then you take Gels. and you appear.
The mind becomes strong.
In a state of Gels., not only physically you
are trembling, you are trembling psychically.
You are really afraid of how they will judge me.
What they will say about me? It's very important what others will say about me.
I remember one of the old cases. I was treating for duodenal ulcer. I was treating him for years.
He was an electrical engineer studied in Germany and he was Greek, suffering with duodenal ulcer.
And I gave different remedies.
And he was doing better and then back again and then I was exasperated.
One night his wife comes and says to me. 'You have to do something for my husband'. I said 'why?'
'Because tomorrow he has to be in the school
of the children', they had their children.
And they had the parents meeting of the class. All the parents of this particular class they had to meet
and he had to say a few things to this meeting.
His wife says, 'it is impossible for him to go'. Huge man, educated, I couldn't believe it!
And then suddenly I said to myself, this is a Gels. case.
I gave him Gels. and since then, 20 years ago, I lost him as a patient. He never came back again. He is very good friend
and he supports Homeopathy, he goes to meetings, he discusses.
The last time we had a meeting of the friends
of Homeopathy, he was there, speaking up.
It is unbelievable, I treated him for 2 years, giving one remedy after another.
Calc. and Graph. and Lyc. and then back to Graph., back to this, to that, relapse, relapse, relapse.
And just this symptom which I had not taken in the initial report or the follow ups came up so clearly
and then I put things together. And I said, oh my God yes that is Gels. Take Gels. 10M, 50M.
Finished the duodenal ulcer plus all the others.
Also there are people who are weak people in their minds and the danger is when they are standing in front
of some height. They are confused in their mind, there is a kind of vertigo and confusion at the same time
and then the tendency to jump. The tendency to jump from a high place, almost like
Aur. or Arg-n. but they have their own specialty. The confusion, the weakness, the trembling.
They look quite old, they look as if the organism has become old and weak and trembling.
Sometimes you see this in the face of the person.
The face of a person who is 35 and looks 50. Who is 50 and looks 70.
I saw a case of anorexia nervosa, 35. She was looking 80. Anorexia nervosa is a terrible state.
So we have this remedy, we say ailments from anticipation. Anticipates to go to appear.
And then we have frequent urination, trembling, diarrhea, all kinds of upsets in the stomach.
Another characteristic is severe headaches, maddening headache. They really feel they are going crazy
and then during the headache the eyelids feel so heavy that they cannot open them. Whatever is the condition.
If you have somebody who has, even without headache, heavy eyelids and trembling of legs is one remedy: Gels.
Heaviness of they eyelids and sometimes because of the trembling, they arrive at paralysis stage
it's a remedy which will be indicated in the multiple sclerosis cases.
Where we have weakness, trembling, paralysis and also if they have diplopia. Double vision.
Of course the multiple sclerosis many times starts with double vision.
But if you have the Gels. case you will have the double vision and then you will have the trembling
and then you will have the paralysis and then you will have the weakness and then you will have the drooping of the eyelids.
Almost the eyelids paralyze.
Therefore it will be a remedy that will be indicated also in another disease which is called myasthenia or myopathy.
Where we have drooping of lids.
Another characteristic which has to do with the heart is, the heart feels weak in general and sometimes
the impression is that their heart has stopped. And they have to move, to make some movement
to see that their heart is beating again.
The idea is the heart stops and they will describe it to you very clearly. They will say, 'I feel many times my heart stops.'
'And what you have to do?', 'I have to jump up and move in order to make it start again'. That's characteristic.
Also chilliness, chills that go up and down the spine.
Also they have a feeling in the heart as if they expect to hear bad news.
And if they hear really bad news or what they feel is bad news, they have a great reaction, much too greater
in proportion to the information that came in.
'They are going to catch me. The police is coming'.
They imagine, they exaggerate the fear and the bad news have a big effect on them.
We say 'bad effect from hearing bad news'. The idea is this losing of heart, this is the idea behind.
That's why in the Repertory says, big reactions from hearing bad news.