Very sympathetic people who are really affected by the environment and what takes place socially in the environment.
What takes socially in the environment, is of great concern to them.
If somebody is treating unjustly or they think somebody is treating unjustly somebody else,
they are the first to interfere and immediately react. They say, 'Hey, what are you doing there?'
So they have a nervous system which is in an excitable state and therefore in a precarious state.
They are very excitable people, very aware, looking. The nervous system is really in a great excitement.
So therefore it can easily break down. In Caust. we see that the nervous system breaks down and eventually paralysis comes.
First there is excitement, the nervous system is weak, not strong, they cannot stand in injustice.
They cannot stand see things suffering.
With them it's mostly suffering socially, which affects them. Physical suffering affects mostly the Phos. case.
If somebody has pains and Phos. is there, Phos. will be very concerned.
Caust. is sympathetic towards the social suffering of others.
Also physical suffering but mostly social. Especially suppressing others.
Especially think that somebody is treated unjustly, they cannot tolerate. They have to shout, they have to fight.
Caust. can really fight in the street because of the injustice and Caust. will join parties that are concerned with social justice.
'I must do something'. They cannot just leave it alone.
This is the idea behind Caust. and that is why the sympathetic element is so strong.
But I remember for instance a case, when I was in India, there was the labor ward in India there are no doors.
They had just a curtain and then there are others lying there and they can hear the woman suffering.
So there was another man who was sick and he would close his ears.
Everybody could see he was suffering very much while the woman was giving birth to a child.
I remember by this time, in the School I was in Calcutta, students were studying and also teachers and
they did not know the difference between sympathetic of Phos. and sympathetic of Caust.
So they gave this person, everyone said, give Caust.. Of course nothing happened.
By that time they would not use in the School, they did not know even the Repertory.
They would just read from some Materia Medicas but the comparative value of each remedy was not known.
They give Caust. because in the keynotes Caust. is very sympathetic. It did nothing.
I said no, this is a Phos. case. You give it Phos..
Once he took Phos., he calmed down and he stopped complaining. He said, I can't hear.
Phos. cannot hear somebody suffering physically. Caust. cannot hear somebody suffering socially.
Primarily. Because both they have concern, they are affected by pain, suffering etc. But primarily it is sympathetic on a social level.
They rebel against authority. Sometimes they will come, they join anarchistic groups and they bring justice
by throwing a bomb which is actually a kind of madness. You don't kill somebody to bring justice.
But for Caust. and for Arg-n also, they can throw bombs. Arg-n also they like some justice but not as much as this one.
Mercurius they feel inside them that they want to do some violence; they have some impulse to do things.
Impulse to kill, impulse to throw things. Impulse which they try to control and sometimes it may happen
also this kind social reaction but mostly is with a home situation.
They like to throw things in their immediate environment, to the wife.
Nux vomica no.
Of course, if you see injustice, everyone is affected but we see injustice and we don't jump and start
punching the person who does the injustice. The Caust. cannot but do something.
He will see something happening in the streets, somebody who is attacked; he will jump into the situation. We don't do it.
For Caust. is very important, he cannot help it.
The most characteristic is the paralysis of single parts. Paralysis of vocal chords.
You see the voice is lost and they talk like this suddenly.
There is a paralysis which comes after a cold. They get a cold, they got paralysis.
Bell's palsy. They are paralyzed on one side of the face.
The urethra is one special point, especially with women, which is not functioning properly. It's almost paralyzed.
That means they have to run very fast, otherwise they will lose urine. And if it happens that there is a pressure from the diaphragm
a pressure down in the abdomen and the urinary bladder is pressed, a little bit of urine always goes out.
So whether they are laughing, sneezing, coughing, they lose a little bit of urine.
Of course there are other remedies which they have that but for this remedy is very characteristic.
Another characteristic is that the excitement which they have, makes them unable to speak out their emotions easily.
The more the excitement, the more the stammering. They start stammering once they get a little bit excited.
If they get more excited, more stammering. If they get very excited, they cannot speak.
While other times when they are calm, they can speak. You don't even notice that they have that kind of stammering.
This is similar with Mercury.
Another characteristic of the pains. The pains are felt as if the flesh is raw. That means the skin is off.
All the pains wherever they may be they feel raw, the pains are raw. As if the flesh has lost its protection.
No protection you see? So outside influence aggravates them.
So you understood the idea. I have no protection that means I receive the outside impressions as if I have no skin.
The pain feels as if they have no skin, the skin is gone and even the air can make this painful.
All the pains feeling as if raw.
Constipation. It is an interesting point, stool passes better when it is standing.
This is very unnatural because the stool passes better when you sit; the deepest you sit, the better.
Here is a very strange symptom.
The aggravation in Caust. is from dry weather. It is very strange because usually people are affected by wet cold weather.
Here they are affected by dry weather.
And they feel good in wet weather. How is that ? We cannot explain.
Desire for smoked meat. Which is the other remedy that desires smoked meat? Calc-p.
What is the weather that aggravates Calc-p?
Cold, wet. This is aggravated by cold, dry.
Another thing that we usually find in Caust. is they don't like sweets. Sweets? No, I'm not interested.
Either they have an aversion or no interest for sweets.
The desire for sweets is something you don't take it as a symptom unless it is too extreme.
Somebody says, I live on sweets, this is a symptom. But because everybody likes sweets, who likes sweets?
Who does not like sweets? Fewer persons do not like sweets.
Those who do not like sweets usually are thin persons. They have a better combustion.
They take the glucose and they use it, so they don't need extra glucose because they have enough
from the farinaceous food which they take.
That means the combustion is better, so usually the aversion to sweets is together with lean people.
Sugar, chocolate, whatever is a sweet taste these people do not like.
They have no specific desire or aversion for fruits, we don't know. What we know is that they have aversion to sweets.
There are people also who suffer because of grieves. The Caust., as I said, is an impressionable person.
They are going through different grieves in life, one and another one and another one.
They are not the people who will complain, go around, find friends.
On the contrary they are people who collect the suffering of the others.
Collect the suffering, finally they come to the point where themselves develop a disease.
They are usually people who are closed. What happens to you? This, that and he is involved.
But to come himself to tell you that I have this problem, I have a child, it has done this to me
I have a wife or my husband has done that, no. The healthy people exchange this information easily.
Healthy people will talk about their problems, their friends, they need that exchange.
Once the disease starts coming, then there is if I tell, I'll be humiliated. If I tell, they laugh. If I tell, they are not interested.
If I tell, I will give them a burden, I will give them some responsibility which after all they don't deserve.
If I tell, I will make myself a fool. All these thoughts are thoughts from a mind which is not healthy.
Because the natural is, if you have a problem to discuss the problem with the society.
Homeopathy bases its power, in the power of confession.
Why I say that?
You will see that with Homeopathy you don't do anything else but make the organism, confess.
You force the organism to confess, to bring out, if it is possible to the skin, everything which is inside and it is diseased.
You give the homeopathic remedy and then the organism starts bringing out to the light, to the skin, the darkness which is inside.
The guilt, the sins, the whatever is inside as disease now, you bring it out with the correct remedy.
So either he wants or he does not want, you make the person confess.
As I said, symptoms are expressions of a diseased organism.
And you go there behind the organism and you push it more, out. You say, out.
Christ when he was saying, take the demons out.
The idea is before you reach that point where you have the problem of Caust., it would have been much better
to have talked over with your friends, mother, father, wife, children, whoever is near you.
And can give some support, even just as a release, even if they cannot give you some good advice
or give you the money which you owe, you just discuss.
In our societies we're getting sick because we hide, we keep secrets. Each one of us we're full of secrets.
I had a very interesting case in the previous seminar.
A little girl of 11-12, an Italian girl changed completely her character, why?
Because she did something and the brother said to her, well you have to do now this, this, this and that for me;
otherwise I will tell my mother and father what you did.
So she became from a very free, open girl, very secretive, very fearful, obeying totally her brother.
She started obeying totally her mother; her mother said what is wrong? Now she obeys everything I say.
She will go and do it and the child started to have delusions. She would see, with open eyes
she would see pictures, people coming to kill her. And they say this was because of a fall.
In the class we tried to analyze the case and it came out that this little child
she kissed a little boy in the country and the brother saw her kissing this other little boy.
He said, now I'm going to tell. She was so scared, she kept it inside and she was twisted so much that most probably
the spine came to a position, where she would have constantly a pain in the left ovary.
A pain in the left ovary, limping, changing her character and she was totally afraid that she has made a big sin.
I said God, the power of the guilt!
She could have grown up and become invalid, she could be crazy because of such secret, the fear that she would be exposed.
Fortunately we found the remedy, I'll show the video later on, in later years we'll see the video. It was very interesting.
What I want to say is that these people come and they lose their father, nothing they keep it inside.
They lose their child, they lose their job and then paralysis.
And then they lose the voice or paralysis.
In labor we may have a delayed labor.
- What was the question?
- Which are the symptoms of Caust. in labour?
What I would look for?
I would say that if this is a Caust. case,
you may find that there is a delayed labor.
There is not enough contractions, a paralyzed uterus.
Was anybody in the seminar in Aedipsos?
You remember the birth of twins by one of my students in Athens? A lady doctor who was in her pregnancy
the last month and she gave birth in a little house, there was no hospital. She didn't go to the hospital.
In 10.30 there was a dilatation of the uterus quite strong.
We expected to deliver in 2 hours at the most.
10.30 in the morning and 12.30 nothing, 1.30 nothing. In the meantime one of the students of the class
who was a gynecologist or something like that, she went and prescribed for her.
On a very peculiar thing, she said I saw something in the leg and she gave Sepia, without me knowing.
And the labor was delayed and we reached 9.30 in the evening and the uterus has remained paralyzed like this.
Because Sepia collapses the uterus. So at that critical moment, the uterus was paralyzed and would not contract.
At 9.30 I said, we have to do something. I took her symptoms by that time.
Fortunately Pulsatilla was apparent and I said, thank God in 1 hour she will deliver.
I gave Pulsatilla and in 10.30 exactly in 1 hour, she started delivering.
But what I want to say is the power of the remedies and how they act.
Sepia totally paralyses the uterus and we know the uterus prolapses in Sepia.  It's paralyzed, it collapses.
Sometimes you will see the uterus on the vagina coming out.
In cases, in old women or in typical Sepia who have stayed for many, many years.
A similar situation you may see in Caust.
Not prolapse, paralysis.
If the uterus is paralyzed, Caust. may help.
It was a terrible experience because one of the twins came out and the other was coming in a breech presentation.
And we did not have anything; it was just a room, we had no surgery in there. It was 11 o'clock in the night
no helicopter, nothing, no surgery and the child would not come out.
We sweat, the story is too dramatic. Traumatic!
But fortunately there was a German gynecologist who did the manipulation. He had learned the manipulation
because he had worked in Africa. He had learned to manipulate and slowly, slowly but in the meantime
we thought the child was dead, after half an hour, he says it's not possible. The child is finished.
In the meantime I was giving remedies because she was fainting from pain, the woman was fainting from pain
and I would give medicine to bring her back. Because he said, she must push, it cannot come out. Stay alive, don't faint.
Give the remedy, sweat, the other one was trying to get it out and I was reporting to the class the whole incident.
Terrible but I never felt I was failed by the remedies. I was not let down !
One way or another, whenever I found myself to such a very difficult situation. This was very close because
he said to me, we have to cut the child, we have to cut it to bring it out in pieces.
Because if the child is dead inside, the uterus cannot bring it out. Forget it, it will not come out.
And I was thinking all the time while I was holding her, giving remedies, thinking what shall we do in case this is a fact.
The child was blue when it came out and we gave several remedies. We gave Laurocerasus
we gave to her Cuprum, Carbo vegetabilis again Cuprum, Carbo animalis.
Because the moment she was trying to push, she had cramps in the legs, screaming I have cramps
Cuprum to release the cramps. She was fainting, bring Carb-v, it was terrible.
Really an experience.
With the gynecologist we became friends forever after this. We felt very close.
He said, let's go for some wine. And the woman, once it was finished, she didn't understand anything.
She would say 'Oh my girl, I don't want to lose my girl'.
And I knew the girl was gone, what about her? Whether we would save her.
Once she was delivered and she was alright, she said bring me some wine, bring me some food, ate very happily.
Because it was premature, I said, 'you have to go back next day'. 'No, no problem, we stay here, you give us some remedies'.
She stayed, finished the course and then she went back to Athens.
She had by that time 8 children.
And since then, she has another 5. She has 13.
Crazy, I mean 13 children! She was screaming, my girl, my girl, she didn't want to lose this one; she would kill us.
She never understood, I never told her what happened through me, what was inside me.
And this stupid practitioner to give Sepia at this moment, for no reason. That is why I'm so severe;
when it comes to Homeopathy you better do it correctly.
Because I know what it can do and what it can spoil. And it's a pity.
You will say, you never made a mistake? Of course I make mistakes but I'm careful at least that the mistakes
will be the least possible and will do the least possible harm.
You don't have to remember very much of Chel. Chel. is a difficult remedy; we don't know the mental picture.
As far as I have see in Chel. cases, the mental picture is one of a powerful individual, who
wants his opinion to be implemented.
An individual who will tell you what to do, how to do, the mothers.
There is an expression which says, has a gall bladder. That means is a strong person, is it correct?
-It has gall, it's different from having guts, it's a bit stronger.
-How do you spell it? Gall, you see it's the same, I'm telling you, it comes from gall bladder.
It comes from gall bladder, that person is strong, is ruthless, is powerful.
And somebody who wants to dominate others.
But this is not something on which you can really rely. What is the Chel. is a remedy that you will find in
affections of the gallbladder when the pains are extending on the back. And especially on the lower angle of right scapula.
This is very characteristic. The lower angle of the scapula.
It has some characteristic with another remedy we will see later on Lycopodium, which is desire for warm drinks.
Bry., Chel. and Lyc. desire warm drinks. They don't like cold drinks.
Aversion to cheese and sometimes the opposite, extreme desire for cheese.
People who cannot tolerate cheese, even the cheese in some mixture. They cannot tolerate.
They cannot tolerate to have cheese in the table. The smell. They have great aversion for cheese.
Right sided, like the Lyc. complains.
Neuralgias right sided, trigeminal neuralgia or headache that affects the teeth.
They get a headache and the teeth are painful. Like Kreosotum.
Constipation.
You have the dryness of the mucus membranes of the colon and a constipation which is similar with this
of Nux vomica. Little round balls.
- This constipation is with tenesmus like Nux-v?
- Not very much, like Nux Vomica.
It is dryness of the colon and the stool is dry and in small balls but difficult to come out. Not the  tenesmus of Nux-v.
I like the sea, I should be there fishing.
You can say that China officinalis is a touchy person. You understand this expression, touchy?
They are in a state of erethism, the nervous system is in a state of irritation.
And they will react badly with the least offense.
Very touchy. It is interesting that China is aggravated by touch.
They have a headache and you touch the pain, they need hard pressure, then it is better.
But with the touch, no. The same thing on the level of the emotions. A kind of irritation, a kind of excitability, nervous.
People who are debilitated because they have lost fluids in general from the body.
They have lost blood, a person who feels exhausted and at the same time irritable. And excited.
People who will have great distention of the abdomen, very bloated like Lyc., Colch., like Carb-v.
But if the wind (gas) comes out, there is no relief. The same bloatness, the same irritability stays.
And the characteristic for these people is that they lie in bed in the night and they develop a great imagination.
They build castles in the air, as they call it.
They imagine, this nice feeling where they imagine themselves giving a lecture in a big hall and everybody
is listening and they give the lecture. They are orators, great orators and they live so much this
as if it is reality and people are applauding. They become the heros.
And then they go with another story in the night and then they go to sleep in the morning and they come to reality.
And the reality is totally different. They have to go at work from 8-2 o'clock.
You say something to them, just a little bit, they are totally offended, they go into pieces.
What other remedies are like this?
Natrum muriaticum or Nux vomica, very easily offended.
They exhibit also many times a great fear for animals. Which are the other remedies which they have fear for animals?
Stramonium yes, Tuberculinum, Belladonna. Hyoscyamus, no.
Out of the 3 remedies which are Hyoscyamus, Belladonna and Stramonium, Hyoscyamus is not afraid of animals;
Stramonium and Belladonna, these two.
China is afraid of all animals; a cow, it will run. A sheep.
But Tuberculinum is afraid particularly of cats.
If you see fear of cats, that is most probably Tuberculinum. Tuberculinum has fear and aversion to cats.
Don't touch cats. They feel the hair.
Before the cat is there, the hair is here. They never touch but the hair is there.
They feel the hair. It's aversion and fear also.
Fear that they get the disease, they will eat the hair, they feel the hair is in their mouth already.
Cats and dogs, Stramonium has fear of dogs.
Also Tuberculinum of course is afraid of cats and dogs.
It is unbelievable. I had a secretary back in 1970. She came to my house and I had a little puppy inside a little box in the apartment.
We're staying in an apartment. It was a little puppy like this in one box, staying there. My secretary comes
she had the key of my house, she opens the house and I hear her screaming. I came out and said, what is it?
'It's a dog!'.
But the dog cannot walk.
She says, it doesn't matter. It does not walk, in order to bite you at least it has to walk.
The fear is irrational. Because some people they say, 'are you afraid of dogs?'. 'Yes' and you examine and they say
'if there is a big shepherd and I go through and suddenly he comes up to me, I'm afraid'.
Of course, who is not afraid of that? This is not fear of dogs. You don't take it as a symptom.
But cats are not known to attack but dogs can attack. Very seldom if a cat is of a special breed, they may scratch.
But in the Tuberculinum does not matter. The cat is coming near, forget it they will run.
Fear of insects like wasps, Abelmoschus and Hepar Sulphur esp. wasps.
If there is somebody who is really terrified from the wasp, that is most probably a Hep. case.
The sting, they are terrified.
China is afraid of all animals. Calc-s is one of the remedies afraid of birds, Ignatia also.
It's strange that somebody will be afraid of little bird.
-I don't really understand the irritability, how do they react, they are crying or do they get mad?
-Who, China?
-Yes.
-China they will not have the possibility to cry. They just run away from any animal.
-No, like when you offend them, you hurt their feelings, their irritability?
-Irritability, not crying.
-If you speak of Tuberculinum of having so much fear of dogs, how many percentage of the cases?
-Fear of cats or fear of dogs?
-10%, 15%?
-No, much more 40% my experience.
More perhaps 50, 60 I cannot say exactly. But it's quite a lot, not only 10%.
-Hepar is not in the Repertory by the rubric 'fear of insects'. Shall we add it?
-It's not? Fear of wasps, that means something that can sting them, bees, wasps or insects that can sting, they are terrified.
I have seen a man, 30 years old, he came to my house. He had AIDS and they had come from Europe to be treated by me.
My house is in the woods, in a wild place inside  there and of course the bees and the wasps were there.
So as we were talking, the bees came and then suddenly he started running but I did not understand what he was doing.
Going out of the house, I lost him finally. What happened? He said, the wasps. That kind of reaction. I said, Hepar sulphur.
This is a case of AIDS and I believe is 10 years now since I saw the boy and he is still alive.
By running away because of the wasps. I heard all the symptoms but I could not be sure. The moment I saw this reaction
I was thinking of Hepar sulphur of course, but this confirmed it. These are the points where you really confirm.
You have this beautiful fear of animals. What animal? Dogs. It's not China.
It might be but if she tells you, 'all animals' most probably is China.
Little tricks and then after these tricks what you do? You start getting feedback and you learn, you observe,
what kind of a person she was. What changes? That's how you learn more and more and you go deeper into the case.
But what I'm teaching you are the basics which will make you good prescribers. After that you can learn more and more by feedback.
-I would like to ask whether Hepar Sulphur is afraid of injections?
-Yes sure, very much. Fear of injections Hepar sulphur, anything that will sting.