Platina, we could say, what is the essence of Platina?
It 's a remedy which has an inflated ego.
Inflated ego which takes two turns, either this or that. Either mentally inflated, that means the patient shows
great arrogance, great pride great haughtiness, to the extend that it may become quite pathological
and then it can really become a severe mental case where the woman or the man feels it's the Great Napoleon
or the woman says I'm the Queen of England etc.
So this is one side of the remedy and in such a case, you may not see the inflation of the enlargement of the sexual sphere.
If the sexual sphere takes this impact, then there is no proud, there is no haughtiness.
But the sexual sphere is exaggerated to the extend that we have what we call in medical parlance, nymphomania.
So in Platina either you will have the nymphomania without proud without haughtiness or if this is suppressed
especially if a woman, for instance, realizes in the young age that has too much energy in sexual sphere
and she does not like it and she wants to suppress it and close it and stop it then eventually
she may go into a kind of pride, "I am bigger than others, I am superior".
And this delusion may eventually reach the stage, where they feel bigger, bigger than they really are
bigger than others, others are small.
It's something that, of course, is difficult for us to understand
but for them as if they are sitting on a high place and looking down upon small people.
You see this exaggeration of the ego in Platina and the tremendous exaggeration of the sexual need, on the other hand.
-Can it stop in the middle between both?
-Yes it can.
So you will have some of these and some of that, but take the two polarities and you will understand
more or less where a patient stands.
Of course in Platina you will get the woman who has a lot of experience, sexual experience.
Because when Platina is acting on the sexual sphere, is uncontrollable. She cannot control it.
The reason why she cannot control it most probably is that she does not have a total orgasm.
She does not have a total release, a total relaxation so she can feel satisfied. There are small orgasms
which do not stop, she wants more and more and more.
A Platina woman they may say that I can go with 20 men, one after another.
In a case which I had with cancer on the breast, with metastasis in the brain and in the bones, I suspected Platina in this case.
So I asked her how she was feeling sexually.
She was in that terrible state with the bone eaten up, the joint was eaten up she was in pain, with brain metastasis.
I thought most probably she cannot have a relationship. Most probably she masturbates;
so I asked her whether she was masturbating and how many times.
She said 40 times the day!
I see a lot of Platinas here, they are not surprised.
40 times the day, I mean she was not doing anything else.
I was taking this case with Alexandra, the lady who taught the taking of a case, OK Platina 10M.
She took Platina. This was one of these cases that you don't believe that Homeopathy can do something.
Metastasis in 8 places in the brain and several places in the bones. With pain killers trying to keep down the pains.
She entered with crutches, she came on a wheel chair. It's very interesting because it's very instructive this case.
She had telephoned through a clinic in London that she wanted to see me. So somebody from the clinic telephoned
and I said, no forget it I cannot take such a case.
We can do nothing, metastasis in the brain already and in the bones, forget it.
She insisted and they telephoned again. They said please she is so insisting that you must see her. I said, no forget it.
They telephoned 3rd time, the woman was telephoning from London said, she will pay you 10.000 pounds for 1 visit.
I said, 1million pounds no way, forget it. I cannot do anything.
Then, one month passed, 20 days passed and somebody who is my friend, a Greek friend of mine  who supported
Homeopathy all alone he telephones, he says George please can you see a friend of a friend from London?
I did not connect. She had cancer, no other information. I said, OK tell her to come.
Then she comes and she tells me the story. I said, you are the one? I told you I cannot do anything for you.
She said, 'no you are going to cure me'. I said, 'please I cannot do anything'.
I tried to tell her to go away. I tried again and again to persuade her.
She said to me something very strange of course. She said, I know you are going to cure me. Why?
She said, because I have spoken with God twice. One time and she related the time and another time
I spoke with God and God told me that you go to George Vithoulkas.
I said, never mind God I tell you that there is no way, can you understand this? No.
And then we were forced to take the case and the case developed in such a way as to become Platina case.
And I asked the final question. I said, how many times do you masturbate. She said, 40! Thank you very much.
What is going to happen now?
Very interesting this woman was from Australia and she hated her mother and her mother hated her and cursed her.
The mother cursed this woman that she dies. And this patient cursed her mother and such tremendous hatred
I've never seen in my life. As a result, the explosion of the cancer.
It is very interesting because her mother was very rich really but she did not have much money.
Yet, she was living on borrowed money in London on the idea that her mother will die and then she will get the inheritance
and she will pay them back. And she was moving on this high society of London. She knew Murdoch the paper man.
Because she said maybe you would like to write something, I know him. She made it all blown up.
And the man who telephoned actually is the man on the aristocracy in Athens, in London, in these circles.
And of course I did not connect all that together at the moment I was taking the case but I just saw some symptoms
that led me to the idea of Platina, asked her about and confirmed that she was a Platina case
because of so much need for reliease on the sexual level.
She had pain killers and was monitored by a hospital in London. So I said 'OK I can give you a remedy
but if you are taking all these medicines that you take for pain killers, the medicine is not going to act'.
She said, 'don't worry I leave the medicine'. I said, 'you cannot leave the medicine because you will scream from pain.
You have metastasis'. The bone pain in cancer is terrible, for those who know.
I said, 'you cannot leave it'. 'No, no I leave it'. I said, 'it's your responsibility. OK, take the remedy'.
She takes the remedy, stops the pain killers.
She telephones after a week or something and says, 'I'm very well'. I said, 'you do not have pains?'. 'No'.
She telephones after a month, 'no pains I'm very well'. 'No pains?'. 'No'. This is very strange.
And then she telephoned one day after two months, very early in the morning, 4 o'clock in the morning.
I wake up and she was screaming. She said, 'I broke a bone'. 'How did you break a bone?'. 'I just moved and broke a bone'.
It was a terrific pain. I said, it's not possible. I know that people who have such pains think that they broke their rib
this is the impression. What to do now? Take a dose of 10M, Platina 10M. She takes Platina 10M.
She calls me tomorrow, 'I'm better. No pain'. Very strange. She throws the crutches after a few months
she goes to the hospital and she performs in front of the doctors, she was dancing.
She said, you could nothing. Now I'm taking Homeopathy and she started dancing.
I said my God, they will kill me.
And then one day she telephones after 8-9 months, she says my eye is coming out.
Because the tumor was pushing out the eye. I said, OK you take Platina 50M.
Platina 50M, the eye went back.
And then she called me with some tremendous pains in the abdomen and then I changed the remedy.
I gave another 2-3 remedies until she became quite well and she did not call me anymore.
A year or 2 years passed and I did not hear from her. Then I'm in London and I call the woman who had originally telephoned me.
I said, 'what happened with this case? It's a long time she has not phoned'. She said it's a very sad story.
Her mother died but before dying her mother gave all her money to a foundation so nothing will be left for her daughter.
She received the news, mother died, no money left. But she was borrowing the money, thousands and thousands.
So what she did? She went into a restaurant, she ordered a very nice food, she took poison and committed suicide.
This story is very interesting because it shows apart from the intensity with which the sexual sphere was functioning
it shows also the grandeur. Underneath this story you can see the grandeur story. One visit 10.000 pounds.
And then borrowed money; how she was performing; everybody was thinking she was having real money.
The hatred that was inside which I believe created all the problem, the conflict with the mother
which had created the problem.I believe if her mother had taken Homeopathy, she would be still alive.
Platina 10M. I said OK, take 10M it doesn't matter, you are going to die after a month or two.
Whether you die under 10M or 50M.
I think I repeated a few times the 10M but the most incredible thing for me was that Platina stopped
entirely the pains the next day, immediately.
-Could I say that I just had a cancer patient with cancer spreading into the bones and brain and he was very old, about 70.
And I gave him Aconite D6 because he was run down and it was starting with prostate and he did not have any pains
he should have been dead 5 months ago and he is still alive, he is still walking, he can still go to the toilet.
He has a stricture but he still can go to the toilet on himself. I mean that is really ridiculous.
-How old is he?
-73 maybe. And it's a disabled person but he can tell you when he has pain or not.
So he should have been dead at least half a year ago. And he is still alive.
-Was he taking any pain killers before?
-He had a lot of. I was the doctor who had to prescribe this person and I asked the persons who took care of him
if I could give him this because I thought it might help. And it was very successful on this case.
-And he stopped the pain killers?
-No but he had Novalgin every two months and I'm a doctor and tell you, usually you need this  much more.
Very often, every day 3 times 20 drops I would say, this is the average that you would have to give.
So this one didn't have to have this for long time.
-With Aconite 6X.
-Yes.
-3 times the day?
-No, just once the day.
He had no pain at all.
-How long?
- He should have been dead by Christmas already.
He himself said, I will not live until Christmas. And then we have 6 months later now.
-So you started the treatment in Christmas?
-In November I think.
-It was with metastasis?
-Yes it was already in the bones. Starting from the prostate.
-But with metastasis on the bone. Very interesting. Especially the fact with Aconite and very low potency.
Did he have a kind of a shock before on which you prescribed Aconite?
-He was a disabled person. I was treating him; I gave Aconite because he had so much fear of dying
and because he had a very strange relationship with the people around him.
He was in fear that he would not be able to go to visit his relatives in Christmas.
So I didn't have to change the remedy but all I knew I wouldn't have known what else to give him.
-Very interesting. These are a few of the cases in which we have success. It does not mean that we can cure cancer.
I don't want to give you the impression that I can cure cancer.
This woman especially, forget it. Once cancer has metastazed. Forget the cure. Maybe you prolong a little bit the life.
-If you consider cancer with metastasis a kind of desperate balance that the organism reaches at that time
maybe the remedy has to stabilize this desperate balance and so it could not advance but what about the pain?
Is it natural morphine? It is very mysterious. Anyway stabilize the desperate balance that was reached.
-Most probably, I don't the physiology. Most probably the inflammation on the areas of the bones
where the pain is produced, the inflammation goes down. And at the same time the brain produces
more opiates to cover up the pain.
Maybe all together these are happening. I don't know the physiology. I cannot understand. I could not believe
that you take today Platina and the same day you don't have the pain.
I could not believe it myself. I'm just giving you the experience.
But the Platina is really a remedy for cancer especially cancer on ovaries, uterus and prostate.
In Platina also we have a kind of hysteria. Hysterical reaction.
That is why you will see that anger alternates with burst of laughing and ends in weeping.
It has tremendous fear of dying. Platina was one of the main remedies for fear of dying. The fear is overwhelming
and especially when the Platina produces certain symptoms.
Especially a numbness around the mouth, a numbness around the forehead that goes from forehead down.
All these sensations bring on the idea that I'm going to get cancer and I'm going to die.
I have tried sometimes to treat such cases with anxiety remedies like Phos., Ars., Agar., Nit-ac, no effect.
And Platina calmed down this tremendous anxiety which is connected always with some kind of numbness.
They say, 'I have a numbness here' and they make such a big fuss. And I say 'OK, it's a little numbness don't take care'.
'Oh no but I feel it'. 'Don't bother'. And then they telephone, 'Shall I take something to tranquilize myself?
To calm down myself?'. Why? Because of that numbness, that numbness is still there.
I say, 'don't bother it's nothing'. Next day, 'shall I take Valium?'
And then you try to give different remedies, then you give Platina and things calm down.
It's very interesting also that Platina many times, especially with women, they dress in an impressive way.
A woman will come into your consulting room dressed meticulously with black glasses, painted beautiful
wearing a robe, enters your room; she sits there and they have an air of exposure.
They are huge, something special, 'I'm destined for something which is special'. They have special mission.
They come from families which are aristocratic and all these can be delusions really. But in their mind, this is projected as such.
And there is another symptom which you will see with Platina, it's very interesting.
They are women who are practical, they are not romantic.
It's not romance which interests them; it is sexual urge.
And that sexual urge has to be satisfied. The sexual urge has to be satisfied.
So whether it is little girls, they will start masturbating at the age of 5- 6 years old.
And the woman also. They are practical. OK do it and go. They are not interested to have a romantic affair.
They are interested to release the sexual energy.
Now given this fact, they do not have a good idea about the world. I mean, see the life of such a woman
going with a lot of men, some of them treating them badly, she treats them badly etc.
Their ideas about the world is very bad and therefore as a result of this, they don't want to have children.
They say, no children, not for me, thank you very much. Children are no good for this world.
Yet, they have a dependency upon their husband many times and they're fixed upon their husband.
If they go away, they feel my husband is not going to come back. He is going to be killed,
he is going to have an accident, something is going to happen to him. The husband, they are fixed to the husband.
It says here, fear something will happen to the husband and may not return home; may be killed or abandon her.
You see the connection with the other sex? It is very strong and she would be afraid, she would be terrified to lose this connection.
Anxiety, fear of being strangled or hanged. Anxiety about her salvation.
If this symptom develops after a lot of experiences which are not satisfying experiences.
You see to be in love and to have love is nice.
But Platina is not interested in that.
Platina is interested, the man or the woman, they are interested on the sexual act, forget anything else.
-From your Platina wife...
-I don't have a Platina wife!
-Platina wife I wish I had.
-The potency?
- 10.000.
- Why?
-To shake her, high potency is powerful.
-George could I just to ask one more thing about the Platina case because you said you used the 10M.
But last time you said if it's a very ill person, you should not give more than D6 or very small remedies.
So what made you give 10M?
-It made me give a high potency because the remedy appeared to be very clear. So I thought if the remedy is clear
maybe there is a possibility of a cure.
If the remedy is really clear, I can give high potency.
But we will talk about these cases. In cases which are severely ill and complicated, you will not get a clear picture.
And it is better to go low and give repeatedly.
-I have given one lung cancer patient which was 75 years old, a very clear remedy also and I gave 1.000.
And she felt very good for 2 days and the third she died.
-Very good, she was going to die.
-I think she was. She knew it and she was very convinced she would but still this was too soon for me;
so I think I might have killed her and I think I did with this remedy. Could it be that I gave it too high?
-No, you did not give too high. You did very well.
You see the problem is that everybody dies under allopathic treatment.
1million people every day they die under allopathic treatment on all the planet.
If one dies under homeopathic treatment, then we have a problem as if everybody is eternal, nobody is going to die.
-Can you imagine that you can aggravate a Platina constitution in a female patient?
That you can aggravate it so much that she gets nymphomania from it? By applying Platina in the teeth or these things?
-With Platina can we aggravate the sexuality of a woman so she will be become nymphomaniac after Platina?
-In teeth?
-No, I don't believe it. If we can aggravate and make a patient nymphomaniac because as dentist we place Platina
in the fillings of their teeth? My answer is no.
-If the person is sensitive?
-Well I would think that if a person is really Platina case and you do the fillings, if there is anything at all
it's going to be a cure.
Actually I remember one case which has come for headaches and all that, she was doing very well.
The 6th month she said, 'I don't know what's happening'. I said 'what?'
She said, 'I do not enjoy sex so much. It has to do anything with the remedy?'. I said 'of course not'.
The children enjoy doing this and also the grown ups also enjoy having a lot of sex.
The problem is that all the organism is disturbed and they don't realize it. This is an outlet for the disturbance.
The same way an outlet for the disturbance for Tarentula is the restlessness.
She has the energy that becomes restless or Veratrum album the energy is spent in restlessness.
-You said there are two kinds. One that the sexual desire was suppressed and then she became haughty.
Is it possible that one like this, that was suppressed and was haughty come for treatment
for haughty and then her sex desire goes up and the other way around?
-What can happen is, for the time being. If you give the right remedy, the whole organism comes eventually to balance.
But for a period of time, when you say there is an aggravation period, maybe the sexual sphere is really activated
and then it comes back into balance.
- You said, if someone is suppressed and you give him Platina and then it starts acting out what does one do in those cases?
Cause I feel responsible, there is a nice married woman and I'm, you know.
-If you have a case and it's Platina and it starts having great desire for sex, if they are not married, there is no problem.
If they are married, they make their husband a little bit suffering.
And of course, they can resist. I mean under Platina it's not going to be something like madness
because this type of constant need for outlet, it is a kind of perversion.
And Platina is supposed to be the remedy for perversions. I don't know what kind of perversions;
for instance it has been a remedy for sodomy. But it is not sodomy, it is that the excitement is so great
that they can do anything. The idea behind is not sodomy or not sodomy.
The excitement is so much that they can go on and do anything which can give them a release, a final release.
And the final release does not come. The final release that means the woman in order to have a satisfying orgasm
she has to be relaxed, she has to be involved emotionally, she has to have conditions.
Now, Platina does not ask these conditions.
The local stimulation is so much that she need only a stimulation on the clitoris. That's all, it's enough.
Of course not that she cannot be in love. She may be madly in love of course, you can understand.
Because a woman going from one man to another, sometimes she gets a man and says, that's it.
And then the man had it. Forget it, he will change countries !
I have seen cases where really the man could not tolerate and he had to leave because the passion becomes
so much and the attachment becomes so much the fixing is there, that the man had to leave.
-Can it ever be that she'll repress it again  and go back into a Platina state?
-Yes she can.
-How do you get them out of it?
-By Platina. A Platina can repress sex and become haughty and become megalomaniac.
And then if this megalomaniac finds a partner on which she concentrates on sex, then she can be cured from megalomania.
By having a lot of sex. But in any case both are extremes and both are border lines in such cases.
-Can you say  that going from sex into haughty state is aggravation?
-It's aggravation. It's better to stay with the sex urge than going to the other state. It's border line.
A woman can still function in the society but of course it will come depression. Because sex, sex, sex is not 24h.
Sex is for a few minutes and then depression. And then fear, and then anxiety.
It's an organism which is upside down.
-I was interested if you saw a Platina man?
-Yes, you see Platina men and it is the same thing. A lot of sexual urge with a lot of masturbation.
A man will have sex and then his wife or his girlfriend turns around and sleeps.
Then he goes to masturbate to be able to release the energy.
It's a lot of energy which goes to this area and cannot be released really.
You will see egotistical, if you see in the Repertory, you see Platina is there. Of course one of the main remedies.
It's the ego, I must get satisfaction, I am so big, I am, I need satisfaction. Me, me, me !
I am beautiful, I am this and that. These ideas are there.
-Are some features that Platina and Lachesis I think have in common according to your description.
Can you tell us something about the most important distinctions between those two?
- Some similarities are when they are thinking about next world and salvation. Shall I be saved?
The egotism on Lachesis is different.
It's an appearance to the others,
Platina is what she thinks about herself.
Lachesis appears to others egotistical because talks a lot, it's very extrovert, it appears to be.
Platina thinks I am a special person. This is a difference. Lachesis does not have that feeling.
But about salvation, what is going to happen in the other world Platina and Lachesis have the same problem there.
-How about the need to have sexual contact to get their energy away?
-The need is not comparable. It's much less for Lachesis. Lachesis also cannot go so easily changing partners.
Lachesis will find somebody and that's it. It will be very passionate but it will be with one person.
In Platina it will happen once in her lifetime after she has been with 100-200 people, she may get one
whom she likes very much and then she gets this attachment. Lachesis is always attached.
-I was wondering if the arrogance and the sexual desire if they are correlated with the fear of death
in terms of do they occur at the same time or is there some type of progression?
-Fear of death and anxiety will come rather to the cases of sexual intensity.
-Not the suppression?
-Not the suppression.
In the suppressed state where she feels all these delusions, she may run into delusions, then
the fear of death is of secondary importance.
-And will that alternate?
-Alternating stages are also there when she will have physical symptoms and then she will get mental symptoms.
And the mental symptoms go away and physical symptoms are appearing.
We have this alternating state. I tried to give you general lines of thinking.
You see Phosphorus, you get the main issues. Phosphoric acid, you get the main issues.
Platina, what are the main issues, you will see this enlargement. Maybe the enlargement of the ovaries also is there.
With Plumbum you will get this idea of the people who like good life but they get the trembling, the arteriosclerosis, the sluggishness.
-Could you say something about Lycopodium and Platina? Because Lycopodium also can be arrogant.
-It's interesting what you say because Lycopodium has this tendency to change partners
and to have superficial sex, we call it.
Lycopodium is interested to have sex but it is not a powerful sexually remedy.
Lycopodium it is from normal to less sex, to impotence. Lycopodium is the remedy that goes and have affairs
but soon becomes impotent because of lack of interest.
So Lycopodium will lose interest, will find another one, will lose interest, will find another partner etc.
And by the age of 35 they are impotent, by the age of 40, impotent.
Because they have affairs which they did not involve, like Platina, the emotional side.
Lycopodium is not so much haughty as it is dictatorial.
In the environment in the house act like little dictators.
Outside where they don't feel so secure they become very subdued and obedient.
But it is interesting that Lycopodium wants to show off. It's like an inflated with air, ego with air.
That means somebody who does not really have substance. Somebody who wants to show off.
Lycopodium comes and you have a nice secretary. You don't have an affair with her.
He comes and because she is good looking immediately he tries to make a date with her.
Then your secretary tells you and you say thank you for the information.
Lycopodium will show off, this is its tendency to show off.
I am a great man, I can have any girl  I like. They are easy in contact, not Platina. Platina is hard.
You know that with the exhaust gases and all that we inhale a lot of Plumbum?
We inhale a lot of Plumbum which can be detected in the organism actually.
And Plumbum is a remedy par excellence of arteriosclerotic people, arteriosclerosis which comes after good life.
Somebody has good living, enjoying, enjoy life.
That means having very good food, fatty food. It means having sauces, sausages whatever, having all these pleasures of life
with eating, without any discretion and then arteriosclerosis develops.
And then we have the effect on the arteries mostly where they get hardened and the effect on the tendons Dupuytren.
You know this syndrome, where tendons are sclerosed? These are typical conditions with Plumbum.
Plumbum is a very difficult remedy to detect because people will not give you much information.
It's a very tricky remedy.
They will accept for instance that their mind does not work as fast as it's used to be.
And they will accept also that the memory is becoming weaker and weaker.
And especially they forget words they forget recent things which are happening.
High livers!
Of course when it says apathetic these are end stages of arteriosclerosis where you see one of the main problems
is the trembling. Trembling from arteriosclerosis, this remedy is one of the main remedies.
I remember a dentist who started with this trembling and he said
I have to resign because once the hand is not steady, forget it.
But it is very difficult because I remember in 1976 when he came in Athens and Paschero
was there and Ortega was there and Chand from India. And we saw a few cases together and each one decided
on the remedy. So when we saw this case, the other three decided that it was Lycopodium case.
Why? Because Paschero said or Ortega, I can't remember and the other two agreed.
And I said, no I don't agree but you take Lycopodium first. He took Lycopodium, he waited for 3 months, no effect.
Then he took Plumbum.
During the congress I was observing how he behaved. And by observing him I recognized that he was trembling
and I saw him, he was trying to seduce several women. He tried one, he tried another.
You know the man who has this tendency.
Dancing with one woman and dancing with another, excited.
And then I said to him, 'open your hand'. This finger could not be straighten, it was like this.
I didn't say anything to the others. OK you take the case, we all take the case.
And of course the observation is necessary. Really a homeopath has to be very cool observer, very cool observer.
Not passionate. Because if you don't like somebody, forget it. If you like, forget it.
If you like very much somebody, you cannot observe. If you don't like somebody, you cannot observe.
You have to be neutral always in observation to see really what is happening there.
Homeopaths have to develop that quality of neutral observation.
You see the sadness, you see immediately the anger. But you don't say, 'you are angry'.
If you want to ask, you ask in a nice manner. But still you need to be very precise.
For instance nobody can understand anything about your characters while you are sitting there.
Because you are calm, you don't show your qualities. But once you are in a social environment
where feelings can be expressed, then the real character starts to come out.
And that is the time where others, people around, will give you information about a situation which you don't know.
I have seen serious people sitting there, very serious, high judge. And you ask about his behavior
and then you find out that he is quite naughty.
You understand naughty? There is a German word or no German is naughty?
And you go totally wrong in your observation, in your decision if you make a decision while somebody
is sitting there and tells you what he wants to tell you.
And of course, these arteriosclerotic people they get eventually trembling and suspicious that others may want to poison them.
It's also a peculiar symptom, if you get the keynote, which is very strong for Plumbum, a sense
as if there is a string which pulls this to the back. It pulls the stomach to the back.
A pain as if the stomach is pulled back by a string.
The idea of retraction.
It may mean this,  that when he knows that if he eats fat things, this will make himself harm.
He is arteriosclerotic. You have to eat a good diet. They cannot. Their will power is not strong. They have used in nice living.
It's very strange that you enjoy life and you live less.
Also this is one of the remedies that has severe constipation, similar to Nux-v, with a sheep dung stool.
Stool with little balls.
Also it may happen sometimes that they will feel better in their trembling with alcohol.
They drink alcohol and they can be more steady.
-So you can use this in alcoholics? Because if they don't drink, they are trembling and if they drink, they are better.
-Yes you can use it but for alcoholics this is pathognomonic symptom.
I don't mean alcoholic people. I mean in people who don't drink or they drink usual, not alcoholics.
Most probably the alcohol promotes the circulation and these people are arteriosclerosed. The circulation is not good
alcohol promotes a little bit the circulation for the time being and then they become more steady.
They are people who are not fat people, they burn material. They are not obese.
They are rather thin and a color which shows good living.
Who has this color?
The skin has some texture which is thick and juicy.
-The President of Germany.
-No, no.
Anyhow the color is not white. It becomes chocolate like as if they are sun burnt or maybe the sun burns the color.
It's a specific type. I cannot describe it to you. If we have a case of Plumbum I will show you.
Is anybody Plumbum here?
-George I want to know if it's so common remedy because in the country, where there is a lot of hunting
the bullet from the gun will stay in the soil.
You get the lead by the vegetables and things like that, eventually you get lead poisoning.
Can you treat lead poisoning with that?
-Yes, you can treat of course but the problem is that all the population because of the pollution, we get a lot of lead
and we're going to use more and more. But the action of this remedy is very insidious and very slow.
That means you may recognize a case of Plumbum after you treated for 5 years.
You don't recognize and then it starts trembling and then your mind will go there to Plumbum.
-The remedy also acts very slow?
-Not very slow.
The interesting thing is Dupuytren's which nothing can fix this, Plumbum can really fix the tendons.
-Is typical keynote?
-Yes, you can say it's a keynote.