It's exactly the opposite of Cocc. Both are worse from sleeplessness but the one becomes oversensitive
to external impressions and the impressions travel very fast, The other one becomes slow and signals are
travelling very slow, Cocc. very slow, Coff. very fast.
That is why the Coff. is a remedy for over excited people, that they get over excited very easily.
Over excitement with the least cause to such an extent that will bring tears.
The excitement brings tears even if it's a good excitement, a joyful excitement, then they break out into crying.
Coff. hightens the senses so they are over smelling, over tasting, over hearing, over seeing.
It is the remedy which is the fastest in mind. A lot of thinking, a lot of ideas go on through the mind and the Coff. people
can stay awake from an activity of the mind. So you get over excited, over active, sleepless and at the same time
hearing very acutely, smelling very acutely, seeing very acutely.
Then of course the headaches start and it says from mental exertion. It is not only from mental exertion
because once they are becoming a habit, they are coming due to this over excitement of the mind.
One sided headaches usually as if a nail is driven but this is not only.
It can have any type of headache, not only a headache as if a nail is driven.
Which is the remedy which looks like Coff.?
Nux-v., very good. Nux-v. looks very similar but Coff. lacks the aggressiveness of Nux-v. Nux-v. is aggressive.
Many times is almost hard, malicious.
It says ecstasy. You see the joyful over-excitement, it can reach a very high state.
So these are the individuals who need Coff.
It says aggravation from noise, why? Because the hearing is so acute, it's not a kind of fear from noise.
Fear from noise which the remedy that has?
Borax. For different reasons.
In this, the aggravation from noise is like another remedy which we have not spoken about, Ther. and Asar.
This remedy is worse also from loss of sleep; they cannot sleep. Sleeplessness with headaches come
and couple with over excitement, these three essentials make a case for Coff.
Coloc. is a remedy that affects the colon. It's a remedy that inflames the colon, a remedy for spastic colitis
with severe pains which are better when the patient draws up the legs and keep and press them in the abdomen.
And presses hard in the abdomen, then it can retain a little bit the pain. Otherwise the pain is unbearable.
It's a remedy that belongs to people who are angry. There is a lot of anger inside the Coloc. which is expressed
actually in every day life. That's why it says, 'become angry when questioned'.
This is an idea, it gives you the idea of an
angry person that says, 'leave me alone'.
And people who have gone through some bad experiences and they did not express at the moment all the anger
because it's very difficult to express the anger in many cases.
Especially in northern people, the Israelis don't have so much problem. You just do something to them...
It's a spasmodic remedy in different parts of the body. Also it is a remedy which will be useful many times in lumbago
but especially sciaticas. Severe cramping pains which are alternating with numbness. Numbness and pain together
or alternating of severe pains and then numbness starts.
Of course these colic pains that we get in the children.
If they are severe and the baby does this movement, then this remedy is indicated.
If the baby has colic pains and you turn him around and put him to sleep against his abdomen, then it is Bell.
Illicium also is a remedy for baby colic. It's a herb actually which the mothers used to give to the babies, in the old times.
Shooting pains, worse on the left side.
-Some Homeopaths say that Coloc. is similar to Staph. in some way and it is a remedy for ailments for humiliation.
-Humiliation yes. I would say if anger is kept inside, then it's Coloc. If humiliation is kept inside
the main idea is 'I'm humiliated', then it's Staph.
The remedies sometimes, Caust., Staph. and Coloc., are indicated in one case.
As we saw that case with Nat-m. and then we go to Nit-ac. And then the other case Nat-m. and then Phos.
And then the other case Calc-p. and then Phos.
In this way these 3 remedies are in a rotation. That means symptoms change in such a way, because you say
Caust. is a revolutionist, he does not suppress himself. Staph. suppresses himself, how is that possible
that they complement each other? In spite of that fact it happens that they complement each other.
Not only that but you may see a case where you start with Caust., you go to Staph. or you start with Staph.,
you go to Caust., then you go to Coloc.
You may see these 3 remedies in a rotation and sometimes in serious conditions where the organism is really undermined
then you have this peculiar phenomenon. Where you try a series of remedies and then
you start again on higher potency, the same cycle. And then there is a better push.
This happens in serious cases. When I say serious cases you have not to think of death. Who is near death, serious.