The idea with Con. is not so much the idea of paralysis. Paralysis is there as a final action but the idea with Con.
is that it produces areas in the body which are sclerosed, become hard. Which are usually the glands.
The glands become swollen and hard but also it produces areas of sclerosis, of calluses in the brain.
It seems that it is a remedy that is very set of certain ideas to the extent that it becomes, we say, superstitious.
They cannot get away from an idea that comes to their mind.
It is also a remedy in which, the body will function well as long as there is a release on the sexual level.
Release, that means normal sex, regular times. Regular times they have to have the release of the hormones.
They have to be released to feel in balance. Otherwise the balance is lost.
Therefore Con. you will see it many times being indicated in women who have separated and they are not having a new affair.
There are a lot of women once they are used to this regular, sexual activity and the husband dies, the woman
does not easily will have a new affair.
Because of this non-release of the hormones, then start problems which can be from vertigo, which is the first to appear
until she may develop even cancer. Especially cancer of the breast.
Of course she has tumors, the idea of having hard tumors it may not be only in glands, it can be anywhere but mostly in glands.
That's why Con. is the main remedy for a gland that is affected by sexual activity in men, what is it?
The prostate gland. The prostate gland in Con. men is the first to be affected. If there is a suppression of sexual urge
it can cause in a Con. case cancer of the prostate gland.
So swelling of the prostate gland, it's very interesting we say practical people.
I found out really these people, Con. people are similar types with Platina but not as oversexed.
The practical side. 'I need sex', this is the idea and the release of the orgasm, that brings the orgasm.
This is what they need and their body can go on and function. Once this stops is interrupted suddenly then
there is this kind of dizziness. They complain constantly. He says, my head is never clear. This is dizziness.
And the worst is Meniere's syndrome where things are really turning. In Meniere's syndrome things are turning around
and especially when they lie in bed and they try to change side. Once they try to turn...whether left or right, it doesn't matter.
Also with sudden motion, they move just to look somebody behind, there is turning.
But the head, they complain about the head situation. It is that complain which is indescribable.
They use words, they do not say vertigo. They use words which they describe a state of mind which goes vzzz..
And it's a noise inside and it is buzzing and dizziness.
Con. is one of the main remedies for what we call superstition, why?
Superstition is a fixed, wrong idea that comes to the mind and they cannot get it out. It's like a callus in the brain
in a particular area of the brain. Otherwise they function very well, they function in society. But there is an area
in which they get a fixed idea and they cannot get away from that.
In the same way they are fixed on their sexual partners.
They are not the people who are over sexed and therefore will make it easy.
Once they take a decision and they have one partner, they continue until the partner dies.
You say, all Con. partners die? No, but these are the cases that we get.
And then they complain, the glands are swollen, the head is not clear and they are headaches.
Sometimes very severe headaches, non-describable. A headache together with vertigo.
They will say, sometimes is headache, sometimes is dizziness, sometimes is both.
And then you don't know, you give different remedies until they tell you suddenly they lost the partner and since 5,6,7 years, no sex.
Some organism can handle this. Con. organism cannot handle it. She will have problems.
In a keynote is the 'interrupted urination'.
People with prostate or Con. symptoms they will urinate and the urination stops.
They wait, then it starts again. Then they wait. It starts again, it stops. 3,4,5 times before emptying the urinary cyst.
So interrupted urination becomes a keynote symptom for this remedy that produces this sclerosis,
hardening of the glands and hardening of the thoughts.
-What would it be if there is hypertrophy of the urethra of the penis?
-Hypertrophy of part of urethra? Or stricture?
-Yes.
-Stricture you have to think of Thuj., Med. It is a kind of a local inflammation which eventually has become
has made a kind of tissues that have become hardened.
A stricture is not easy to cure but sometimes you see some release. And then the urination becomes more easy.
We cannot cure everything in Homeopathy. We have to know our limits also.
It's not possible. Sometimes it's amazing what we can do but at the same time we think that we can cure everything?
When you have a combination of affections of rheumatic type, rheumatic or arthritic type affections
and at the same time you have an individual who is suffering with skin problems this will bring you to the idea of Dulc.
In such a case you have to have a severe aggravation from cold and wet weather.
When it is cold and wet, Dulc. is suffering a lot.
Actually in older times when there were no electrical refrigerators they produced ice cubes that were in big boxes.
And the people who handled this, open the door, getting these big ice cubes,  put them there, deliver them, they could suffer.
This is the best condition for Dulc. to get sick. And then Dulc. symptoms may develop.
They don't like ice, they don't like cold, they don't like cold and wet especially.
Another interesting thing is that it has paralysis of single parts.
And this paralysis may have its origin in the exposure of the people to the cold and wet.
So exposure to cold and wet and then paralysis of single parts, Dulc.
Exposure to cold and dry and paralysis of single parts, Causticum.
The difference is in the cold and dry weather, that means in the night of a spring time you get a motorbike and you go fast
and the cold wind of the night but it is summer and it is dry, hits you on the face and then you come down
with paralysis of the face, of one sided paralysis of the face. Then the remedy is either Acon. or Caust., it's not Dulc.
But if you drive in cold and wet situation in winter, then most probably the remedy will be Dulc.
Cases of Guillain Barre, paralysis that starts after exposure to cold and wet in winter, may need Dulc.
Another remedy of course they may need, is Calc-c. Because Dulc. and Calc-c.  are both worse in cold wet.
But if this patient says that at the same time, I have been suffering with skin eruptions, skin eruptions
paralysis of single part, under this condition, Dulc.
About a month ago, a girl was sent to the Athens center, by the hospital in Thessaloniki.
She was in the hospital with Guillain Barre
and the only symptom that we could find was that she has been exposed to cold and wet near the sea.
She was living near the sea. In the night they went out or they forced her to go out something like that
I can't remember, and the next day she came up with Guillain Barre. The remedy was Calc.
She is doing, as I hear, much better to the amazement also of the people of the hospital who thought
only cortisone or whatever they give that could save that child. Otherwise the child blah, blah, blah you know.
I have seen a lot of cases of Dulc. with people who are, especially women, who are very loving.
But loving with much possession.
That means they take of others but in a manner which is quite authoritative.
'You do this, you do that. You have to do that'.
A kind of dictatorial, it's not exactly dictatorial because it's a concern. You married the wrong girl, the wrong woman
so I have to protect you from this woman who is a bad woman!
So you do this and that. I mean they will try to protect in a possessive way.
So all women who are possessive, give Dulc.
It says here: confusion, cannot find the right word, cannot concentrate.
Restless, cannot keep still; this reminds a little bit of Rhus-t. You will confuse it, many times you will give Rhus-t. instead of Dulc.
So these remedies are exchangeable because both they have skin eruptions and at the same time
rheumatic and arthritic conditions. But the tendency for paralysis is more accentuated in Dulc.
If you can get this information alone you cannot imagine how many of your cases will be solved just like that.
Because this is after all an experiment. Here it's the first year we're doing this experiment. We'll see the result.
We'll see if the information I'm giving you is enough, it's not misunderstood. And if you really go and study and repeat
I don't know if you go home and you ever look back in your notes. That's a big issue.
You say, we finished, no more obligation. But something will remind you, I'm sure something will remind you
George said something about this D, d, d..., you look at your notes in 'D' and you find Dulc. This is how it works.
Later on we go more into details on the mental-emotional.
Then the information is going to be so much. I don't want that you overload at this moment with details.
You have to grasp the structure of the remedy first. Once you grasp the structure then the rest can stick.
Aggravation sudden weather changes, cold and wet and suppressed discharges. That is true.
If you suppress a skin eruption and then you get headaches, you get rheumatic conditions or you get paralysis
one of the remedies you will have to think is Dulc., in case the person is aggravated in cold and wet.
This is key issue, cold and wet. Like it is a key issue for Calc. or for Rhus-t.
Thick, brown crusts. Chill between 7-9 a.m. perceived by great thirst with great soreness and aching of bones.
This is a case of influenza where the chill comes between 7-9 in the morning and then the fever rises
and there is great thirst but if it is 9 o'clock, after 9,10 with great thirst it becomes what remedy?
Bryonia.
You see? Little changes and it changes the idea of the remedy. Bry. is worse from cold and wet?
No, she is worse from cold and dry.
Do you see how you differentiate?
You don't need too much information because anything you want you go and find it in the Repertory.
What you need is these essential features. That's all you need. But grasp them well, keep them.
You have to remember two things, heat and explosion.
You will have very strong aggravation from heat, from the sun, sunstrokes, from fire, from sitting in a warm room
in an explosive nature of headaches. Headaches which are exploding.
Waves of bursting, pounding headache.
You feel the head is going to explode.
When the patient says, 'My head will explode, I feel it'. Explosion, explosion, Glon..
You see how sensitive this remedy is to the heat? You see sunstroke immediately. Of course you don't have it so much in the north.
Here we have it quite a lot with the heat waves, a lot of people go to the hospital with sunstroke.
Most of them belong to two remedies, one is Glon. and the other is Nat-c.
But when we say sunstroke it does not mean only during the acute phase. It means also that after the sunstroke
you may have developed headaches, you may have developed depression, loss of memory.
Actually this remedy loses its direction very easily. They don't know which street it is.
They are in a street, they look at the street and say, 'now where am I?'. And it is a street in which they go every day.
They go with the car every day and he says, 'now where the hell am I?'
Ambra to less degree.
This is the beginning of arteriosclerosis, because of pressure.
Because this is a high blood pressure remedy. High blood pressure remedies are the remedies especially which
are affected by heat and heat makes them feel worse and makes them having headaches. Which are these remedies?
Bell., Lach., Glon., Nat-c., Nat-m.
They are affected by the sun, affected by the heat and then the heat produces headaches.
That means the vascular system is already in a sensitive condition.
The headaches of such a remedy will be aggravated by anything that stimulates the circulation.
So what stimulates the circulation? Alcohol, coffee also.
And alcohol also they cannot tolerate. They will have strong headaches.
Better in cold air of course. And better in shade.
Under a cool place, they need to be in a cool, dark place.
Even the light, the strong light, the artificial light can make the headache worse.
So you have to remember the explosive nature of this remedy.
Of course they are explosive people. People that they will explode suddenly.
If they do like this and they explode, they are temperamental.
Because there is a lot of energy inside. If they explode they save themselves from having headaches.
For instance I shout a lot, everybody knows, and that's why I can still teach.
High blood pressure, OK we said about that. Burning hot on vertex and back of neck. Heat and flushes of heat of course.
And the heat goes towards the upper part and here it ends. In the vertex.
Which is another remedy that has heat on the vertex?
Sulphur, very good. He is a good student.
Sulphur has heat here but also where else? On the soles. Not this one. This one the heat goes up towards the head.
The head becomes very hot. The head is a sensitive part, then there is heat there, there are flushes
then there are explosive headaches.
The sun is terrible.
Glon. and Nat-c. people will go to the sea at about 7 o'clock in the morning.
That is the time they enjoy mostly going into the sea.
Of course most of the Germans are Nat-m. and also they go early in the morning.
It's very strange. One of my students, I will not tell names, he gives about 80% of his cases, Nat-m.
And he claims he has results.
This is a fact. By giving everybody Nat-m. actually because everybody has some grief
which is kept inside, will be some effect.
The idea is that you have to separate when to give Nat-m. or Nat-p. or Nat-c. or Nux-v. or Glon.
It's better than just patching up little things.
There are others of course who do something else. They say, while we have the miasms all together
why don't we make a mixture? A nice mixture of Syph., Med., Tub. and Carc. and give it?
And there is some miasm which is going to respond to this mixture and they give a name and say
this is drainage therapy or whatever.
Somebody was telling me the other day another name. What name did you say?
"Protective", this is protective therapy !
So if you do things like that, of course you can give to everybody Med., especially the Greeks can get a lot of Med.
and you can see some effect. But it is not Classical Homeopathy.
You will never have the satisfying results that Homeopathy can give you.
You can do these things, they have been doing all along but what is there? It's so much difficult to learn this? It's not.
That is all the knowledge I have and I'm able to discriminate between one remedy and the other.
-One question to Glon. Geukens says from his experience that a Glon. patient who has headache and does like
and he's sighing or moaning this is a typical posture of a Glon. case. Is it true? Have you observed it also?
-I cannot say that because in my experience I have not seen this position.
Hyper. is another remedy that we use when the causative factor is injuries, especially on peripheral nerves.
Injuries on peripheral nerves which have as a sequence whatever, depression, headaches, epilepsy
they may require this interesting remedy.
The pain that causes is really bringing on fainting. It's so much pain that brings fainting.
Depression of course. Depression can be after injuries of the head.
It is very interesting one of the doctors in the center in Athens, he was carrying a big television to show one video case.
And as he was climbing up the stairs, he fell down and he tried to save the T.V. and the TV. hit  his fingers against the floor.
And he managed to just bring the T.V. a little bit more steps and then he fell down. He was totally white.
When they called me, I go and see he was totally white. What happened? He said, I fell down with the TV. and I hit here.
He was just ready to go away, he was trying to hold the pain.
Bring Hyper., you give Hyper., in 3 minutes Peter was standing up.
I said, are you all right? Yes. Are you going to come to the lecture? He said, yes.
This is the action of the remedy when it's indicated. Fantastic.
But not only for the acute state but it can neutralize long effects of injuries.
Many times you get in the dentist. The dentist hurts by doing some extraction or whatever they manipulate
they hurt some nerves, nerve endings and then you may have the development of a trigeminal neuralgia.
Or a severe pain which the dentist says, I cannot see where it is. They make X-ray, they cannot find anything.
Yet the person says, the moment I try to eat, forget it, the pain is tremendous. They cannot find it.
It is a matter of trauma on the nerve endings. Then Hyper. will end this problem.
Pain shooting upwards along the nerves.
Asthma amelioration by expectoration. This is a common thing. I mean once you expectorate, it's not a peculiar thing.
When the coccyx is traumatized by a concussion, then the main remedies that you have to be thinking is
Sil., Kali-bi. and of course Hyper.
Especially if the pain has stayed in the coccyx. Sometimes a trauma in the coccyx, it may produce a lot of symptoms
along the spine and many times headaches.
Sensitive to cold, worse cold and lying quietly ameliorates. Desire for warm drinks, not important.
Motion, touch, pressure aggravate.
It says prevents lockjaw or convulsions. The idea is that if you have an injury and the injury brings on a lockjaw
then you may be thinking of Hyper.
Which are the other remedies which have a counter effect on injuries on the head?
Nat-s. Nat-s after head injuries mostly develops what?
Depression.
After injury depression with suicidal disposition, especially if the suicide is with shooting
then the first remedy we are thinking is not Hyper., it is Nat-s.
But Hyper. also. Hyper. is the remedy we are thinking when there are nerve pains after injury. Shooting along the nerve.
Amputation also yes. Also All-c. that we have been talking, phantom pains.
They have amputated and the pain continues.
It's terrible pain, it's unbelievable pain which is not easy to manage and Hyper., also All-c. are remedies
that can counteract that situation.
- Is it always a precondition to have these pains, shooting up along the nerves?
Because I had a friend, and as she fell from her bicycle she fell on her mouth and injured two teeth
and her dentist told her that the nerves of these teeth have been injured. Then I looked it up in the Repertory
and in the Repertory I found Hyper. But then people told me, no that's wrong you made a mistake because
she did not have those typical pains. Anyway the woman could preserve her teeth but I'm not sure if that was due to my action
giving Hyper. or whether it would have happen anyway? The question behind the story is, is it wise to administer Hyper.
if the dentist tells you that the nerves are injured or destroyed or not?
-Yes it is. This is exactly what I said. Sometimes teeth, actually the around situation from teeth, are affected by the dentist
by an accident etc. In such cases Hyper. is indicated. 200, 1M, 10M.