So we have another case who is afraid of snakes. Fear of snakes here is the primary symptom.
Lac-c. has fear of snakes. Most probably the dogs are afraid of snakes too much.
Fear of snakes here is a pathology. Who is afraid of snakes? All the others are not?
I'm going to bring a snake tomorrow and see what happens.
Everybody is afraid of snakes but we don't imagine that a snake might be here. A Lac-c. will come in here
and will think maybe the snake is underneath. Or the snake is in the bed.
I remember when I was in India with Krishnamurti, he was talking about fear. He was analyzing fear.
It was a children's class and I remember one boy was in the class, hearing about fear. So he asks for a question.
He says, 'Sir what are you doing if you feel everywhere there are snakes?'
He told me 'this is a case for you. Can you do something?' I said, 'yes we can do something'.
This kind of fear, the boy was terrified, 'I see everywhere snakes. In my imagination, in the bed'.
Fear of snakes. Lach. also has dreams of snakes, fear of snakes but not to that degree.
And the other great symptom of Lac-c. is when you see symptoms going from left to right, you think it's Lach.
But then it comes back to left. Then it's Lac-c. Or it is from right to left, you think it's Lyc. but then
it goes back to the right, then it's Lac-c.
You get a tumor on the right breast and then it goes to the left; either operated or even subsides on the right side
and it appears on the left. You are thinking of Lyc., right to left.
Then in no time this is back. The same with headaches. Headache that starts on the right side, then the next day
is on the left side. Then 2 days is back on the right side.
That is very characteristic of Lac-c.
You will get a tonsillitis left. Then right, then back to left. That's the time you think of Lac-c.
Also glazed surfaces of mucus membranes, diphtheria like.
We have not cases of diphtheria. Actually I have not seen any case of real diphtheria but I have seen cases
quite severe that they look like diphtheria. With high fever and then they are covered with some membranes.
You see the white and then of course it comes back and forth.
Lac-c. has the opposite of Lach. It's rather low blood pressure with a feeling as if it's not touching the ground.
There is a kind of a vertigo which the person feels as if I'm floating and then I'm going to faint.
And fear of fainting can develop very strongly and they get fear of dying and fear of fainting.
Fear of going out of their body. It is similar to Cann-i., similar to Agar. also.
The best cures you will do is when you will find a person who desires very much salt, strong desire for salt
but even stronger desire for pepper.
And when I say desire for pepper, you know the red chillis? If you touch them, unless if you are Indian
if you touch them and just make a little bite like that. I was in India and I did not know that trick. I died by touching it.
You get the Lac-c. cases and they say, give that to me.
I say, 'no you cannot do it'. It was a woman, I challenged her. She said, 'give it to me' and she ate the whole thing.
I couldn't believe it. I said now I know your remedy.
She came to be treated my me, I'm talking about 1970, and she was in a terrible state. I saw her and I said
'are you taking drugs?', 'Yes'. She was taking different drugs and she was in that terrible state.
I said, forget it I cannot treat you. She stopped the medication and she came back. And I treated her for years.
Actually this was a case of Lac-c. which I have missed it for many many years. And it was when she bite this pepper
I said my God this is a case of Lac-c. I gave her and beautiful.
But the original symptoms were treated with Phos., Sep., from time to time I would give different remedies
and I kept her satisfied.
Desires salt and desires pepper. Red pepper.
-You are talking about chili pepper?
-Yes chili, not the pepper which is not hot. It has to be hot, burning.
Rheumatism begins and ascends.
The pains are going upwards, from down. This is the extension of the pain.
You have a pain that starts in the ankle and then extents to the knee. That most probably is a Ledum case.
A Ledum case also is a case where the pains are shooting upwards. Ice cold applications.
Though the part can be cold, ice cold application makes it feel better.
Though the patient himself may not be a warm patient.
Also eczema is better with cold application, cold water, cold air.
Eczema which is worse by heat and better with cold.
Wounds become cold puffy.
Pains worse at night by warmth of bed covering and better by sticking feet in ice water.
You get a joint which is very painful where the pain from here shoots upwards; you put it in ice and it feels better. That is Ledum.
You get a pain here which needs cool, not very cold, just cool.
Then it's another remedy Guaj.
General aggravation from heat but some of the cases feel the cold very much.
So you don't always have to have a hot individual in Ledum.
Nodosities in the joints.
Ledum is specific for uric acid arthritis, gout.
Where the big toe is swollen and red and
painful and the pains shoot from the toe, up.
They will tell you they need to put the feet on cold, ice-cold.
Once I had a case, the man was suffering 16 years and he had not to wear a shoe. The shoe was pressing
and it was very painful. So he had to cut, either the shoe was open or to wear something like a slipper, on top of the slipper.
He used to have exposed the toe. So in1967 I came back from India and I was working with this architect before
we were working together. I saw his foot and I said 'what is this?'. 'I suffer many years and now it has become much worse.
What are you doing?'. 'I'm doing Homeopathy'. 'Can you do something for my foot?' I said 'yes I can do'.
I left his office by 1956 his office where I was working for him, building. He said, 'OK you give me a remedy'.
I said, 'no I will not give you a remedy'. By this time I was not charging anybody but a few rich people.
He was very rich and he had become rich because of me actually, because I've been working like 3 people you know.
I said, now you are going to pay back everything that you owe me. I said, 'we'll make a deal. If I cure you
you will give me so much, a huge amount'. He said, 'OK'. He didn't believe it of course.
So I started treating him. From time to time I would go to the office and say, 'how are you?' For a long period of time
I did not go. Then I go one day and I see he is wearing shoes.
First I look at the shoes. I said, 'well you are wearing shoes?'
He says, 'I will tell you something. Unbelievable actually'.
I said, 'what?', 'I was in Switzerland and somebody suggested Vichy water  a mineral water,
and after drinking this water by miracle this thing was cured'. I couldn't believe it!
I said, 'I see. Next time that you have a relapse, drink Vichy water, bye, bye'. He said, 'wait a moment'.
He pressed the button and comes the accountant and said 'pay him the money'.
It was Ledum one of the remedies which I had given him.
By this time I was Robin Hood. We were treating all people free but some rich people had to pay for everybody else.
And he was one of them. He was really rich but he tried immediately to play a trick.
He didn't want to pay. Same thing others tried to do like this.
I said OK you don't need me. You take whatever because everyone finds things, a reason why he is now better.
I mean OK, when you have a relapse drink some coffee also, it will do you good. Coffee is very good for you.
I felt I had this task. I had to bring Homeopathy to this world, to establish it. The tricks they played, the fight
and what I had to fight, unbelievable. I said, yes still I will do it.
You just have to remember a few things like that and the miracle is coming, I tell you.
-Do you use Ledum in injuries in sports where people are putting ice?
-If the ice is really very effective, then most probably you need Ledum. Also you need Ledum in punctured wounds
like cut, there is laceration and then pains are shooting pains.
You know here there are a lot of goats, especially 20 years ago. I hurt my foot where a rusty nail went inside.
The nail went inside quite a lot.
Everybody was saying, take antitetanus vaccine. I said, forget it and everybody was waiting 24 hours, 48 hours.
Secretly I took one dose, I thought maybe.
And I remember I had some stinging pains coming and shooting from here where I was hurt.
Nothing happened of course. I don't know if Ledum affected the whole thing but I was not sick.