Concerning now Mag-c.
I have not much discovered on the mental-emotional side of Mag-c.
I will give you my impressions. Mag-c. cases will look quite sick, quite broken down and if you can imagine the pre-state of tuberculosis.
How a person who is maybe going into tuberculosis is, with a broken down constitution, with a general weakness, with a face which is quite earthy.
And of course in Mag-c. we have the liver again affected and also we see quite a lot of neuralgias, especially on the left side.
Especially facial neuralgias which are called trigeminal neuralgias of the left side, which are aggravated very much by any kind of draft. This is a peculiarity. And ameliorated by warm.
The people that will need Mag-c. usually are, like Mag-m, peaceful, quiet people. They are not making a lot of noise.
It seems that the Magnesias because the liver is affected, I don't know why, the element of aggression is quite minimized.
And the element of wanting peace and being quiet as people is very prominent. You will see these people are quite placid. They are not aggressive.
As I'm talking about remedies, what I want to give you is main impressions that you will have when you see your patient.
I mean you have to discuss with your patient and you have to find out how he behaves, how he reacts, sometimes you have to stimulate your patients or to aggravate them to see how they react, the children also.
You have to be like an artist because you are in a journey of discovering when you see a case.
Unless you get the inside of the case, what you see is the periphery. Especially in the northern countries where people are very reserved and sit there and say, I have headaches.
'Yes, what else?', 'Nothing else'. You will say this is a peaceful remedy but you put certain questions and you see the passion inside, the nature which is quite different, eventually through inquiring into such a case.
You have, at least I have to be very observant, very careful to understand people of the North. Because people of the South are more extrovert and will give you much more easy their symptomatology.
And their symptomatology also is not so much depressed, repressed, suppressed. What you do in your character here is to discipline which is very nice.
For us this discipline, order etc. is very nice to see that. But it has its price because by suppressing your instinctive reactions, you suppress also your automatic defenses.
So when you give a case, when your body reacts and produces symptoms, the symptoms are under a discipline. And the way that you will present the symptom, will be different.
A discipline presentation usually. Unless it's a mental case, then there is no control. You will see full blown the remedy.
I will give you a few points of a remedy by an example. As you know I came from Norway, I had a seminar there for a week and one of the students presented a case.
This was a man with psoriasis on the whole body but also mentally very disturbed.
He had all kinds of fears and all kind of mental symptomatology. He has been given about 30 remedies so far. He was very kinetic; he was given also Zinc, very hyperactive.
But it was interesting that at a certain point, I said to him, how you would react in a case of anger?
He says, 'do you want me to show you?' In the meantime he was trembling like that. I said, let me see your pulse.
You could feel all the tissues. I know that state in a remedy. Then he says, 'you want me to show you?'
Do you know the broom, he says to me. He says, I take the broom and put it down and break it.
And you would see in his reactions, the increase of energy during the angry state, during the crisis.
Tremendous and then at a certain moment he says, you want me to show you again?
So he stops for a while, he gathers all his energy and he hits the table with such force that I thought the table will go into pieces.
The increase of energy, I said my god, what's next?
The whole class was like that. What is going to happen now?
I said, 'what about music? Do you like music?' He said, 'I'll tell you what I do. I put this rock and roll music and I have two huge loud speakers in my room and I put full speed.
And this is not enough because I want to feel the music inside. So what I do? I put my ear into the loud speaker so I can feel the music.
the vibrations in the room are so great that the doors are opening and closing'. Do you mean the doors? He says, 'no the ward doors'.
If you go to the Repertory and you look 'insanity', I made this man perform and bring out the Tarentula state but the students still they could not put together all these things.
The amelioration from music, this 'I want to feel the music inside me to really get the pleasure of music'.
If you see in your Repertory, open in chapter 'insanity, increase of energy during insanity'.
'Strength increased'. What page? Page 57. I said, did you see that? This is a tremendous increase of energy. Nobody could find it in the Repertory.
Because in the Repertory is mentioned in the mentally disordered people and the chapter insanity, we see that increase of energy which Tarentula is the number 1 remedy.
We see the tremendous increase during the crisis, they want to break, to tear things and mostly what they want to tear is their own clothes during the crisis.
So in this case I didn't inquire anything about his sexual life of course because Tarentula has tremendous sexual urge.
It was not necessary for me, I could see this was Tarentula case. But a lady from the group said, you didn't inquire about his sexual life.
So immediately he jumped on the occasion and said, 'do you want to know about my sexual life?'
And he started telling about his sexual life and the same lady later on said...
he did not want to show his eruption, his psoriasis. I did not ask to show his eruption and the patient asked me 'do you want to see my ulcer?' I said, 'no it's not necessary'.
The same lady said, let's see it. So immediately he says, do you want to see my body?
You could see the energy was so much he was ready to....he had not enough time to unbutton.
The whole thing, the whole performance was a Tarentula case. I mean when you see that, 5 or 6 homeopaths had taken his case and nobody had seen Tarentula.
Psoriasis, hyperkinetic, this and that but the essence is that. And he had beautiful Tarentula symptoms because I put the symptoms on the board and I say, OK repertorize. Only Tarentula.
And then try to see 'strength increased'. When I pointed out I found it. And then amelioration from music is so great, how he said, what else do you want?
If I like music? Yes and he described how much he likes music and Tarentula likes exactly that, strong music.
Very strong music ameliorates and it is a very known fact that Tarentula is a spider that lives in South America.
Now if somebody is bitten by Tarentula, in older times what they used to do in order to cure this because it would fall down into spasms so immediately they would run and bring the band of the village with the drums.
The band would play while the man was convulsing in the ground and by playing strong music next to him, the man would calm down and eventually recover.
That is the amelioration. It's very strong amelioration from music in Tarentula. You have to remember that.
This person is Tarentula. He goes and search his liver, never mind his liver this is Mag-c.
He cannot be Mag-c. why? Because Mag-c. they don't have the energy to do these things.
They are so tired. There is an unquiety inside and a sense all the time something wrong is going to happen, something wrong is going to happen and an anxiety.
And then a tiredness, something wrong is going to happen and that feeling goes away when they go to bed, opposite to Mag-m. When they go to bed the Mag-c. they are ameliorated from their anxiety.
Especially from that unquiety, that fear, something is going to happen. In the night they become quite calm.
Also what we see in Mag-c. again that suffering that has been going on for years and again the same idea of sour temperament, these people that are suffering and suffering, sour.
And then we see that sour idea, we see it in perspiration, we see it in vomiting, in smelling the whole body sour, all discharges smell sour. Sour smelling becomes a keynote for Mag-c.
And they are quite depressed and indisposed to talk, they don't want to talk, they don't want to interfere very much.
And therefore again we have this pacifistic attitude of Magnesia which they don't want to have noise, quarells etc.
So you get another person all together, another personality.
We may have anxiety with trembling. But the trembling is fine and it is quiet trembling. It is not an aggressive trembling. It's trembling from weakness.
It is like Gels. trembling. And especially this anxiety comes, this is a keynote, the anxiety, the trembling, the weakness comes with warm food.  If they eat very warm food, the anxiety comes. This is a keynote.
Sometimes also they get very tired and sleepy the whole day. They go to bed and they cannot sleep. They become sleepless.
This symptom is characteristic for what other remedy?
Of Staphysagria, very good.
For another reason. I do not want to go there. Anyhow it is sleepy during the day, the whole day and they go to bed and they cannot sleep.
Mag-c. also has an aggravation time which is similar to Kali-c, between 3 and 4.
Their pains, colics, discomfort they come between 3 and 4 in the morning and their sleeplessness also may come from 3 to 4 to 5.
Again in Mag-c. we have, as I described it in Mag-m., the great tiredness and unrefreshed after sleep in the morning.
Very characteristic, very strong. Unrefreshed in the morning. They cannot move, they feel heavy, they feel tired, indisposed to talk, they don't want to talk.
They are slow in digestion and usually constipated. And when the liver is very much affected, then we have again the whitish chalky stool with yellowish which shows obstruction of the bile duct.
Mag-c. will be found, indicated in children that do not thrive do not really get well.
We have sometimes children that the liver is affected, they are small, weak, very weak in keeping their head up, very slow in walking.
Not thriving, not building up. Usually it is found in the laboratory that the liver is quite disturbed and the children cannot grow.
Then Mag-c. will be the number 1 remedy to think about such children.
Also during dentition when children start with the teeth and then there is vomiting, sour smelling and aversion to milk or if they take milk there is immediate diarrhea.
A characteristic of Mag-c. with a woman is that during the period of menses, they suffer a lot. And a lot of symptomatology comes during the menses period.
A peculiarity is that menses will flow only in bed, when lying in bed, in the night. They get up and walk and the menses stop.
There is a periodicity that comes every 3 weeks.
And we have lumbago during pregnancy but it is worse sitting or lying in bed. They have to get up and walk and also they have to keep very warm the back.
During the menstrual period woman can get colds. A whole cold can start every time the menses come. There is a time of very weak period for woman at the time of menses in Mag-c.
From the desires you can see desire for meat which is quite strong and also another keynote aversion to vegetables.
Aversion to vegetables is a keynote for Mag-c.
We see the dryness of the skin, the oldish looking and also the idea that they are getting old, they are getting weak.
It is interesting that some remedies produce a lot of energy and some remedies take away the energy.
The Magnesias are from these people that are always tired, always making an effort to continue.
There is no time where they will feel the energy is quite strong.
You have to understand also that sensitive state where the nerves are affected and are very painful. While the body is not strong, it's rather flabby.
You see a flabbiness which is unhealthy. You see in Calcarea carbonica  there is flabbiness but it is quite healthy and they are agile in spite of being flabby.
In Mag-c. you will see the flabbiness, the withering. They have been obese and now the obesity goes away, the flabbiness stays. The muscles are very flabby and the nerves seem they become very sensitive.
With Mag-c. you have tremendous neuralgias. It is one of the main remedies for facial neuralgias whether it's on the right or the left, especially on the left.
Mag-p.  is mostly on the right side. Magn-p. is one of the main remedies for neuralgic pains, severe pains which are ameliorated by warm application.
When you get a stomach pain that she will take something very warm and put it there. I will give you an example of that warm.
A man who was working on cutting stones, marble, he said that he had such a severe pain in the stomach that unless he took a brick and heat it up and then he would let the brick sit on his stomach
with tremendous heat, almost burning him and that would ameliorate the pain. That is the kind of amelioration we get for Mag-p which is the same amelioration we get in Nux-v.
Nux-v. need also warm applications in order to feel better but not as warm as that. When you see that intensity, then it can be Mag-p.
Magn-p. cases, I would not know quite a lot about them, just a few hints. There are people which are quite nervous, quite sensitive, the Phos. element together with the Mag. seems to give a great sensitivity.
In the morning, this Magnesia does not have this unrefreshing sleep because of the Phosphorus element most probably, you know the Phosphorus is refreshed very much in sleep.
Because of the Phos. element Mag-p. is not so much unrefreshed, as Mag-m and Mag-c.
They are nervous people, people that are quite on edge, I would say.
Amelioration from warmth on every symptom, whether it is headache, facial neuralgia, colic pains, urinary pains, cystitis etc.
A cystitis which is better warm, the woman has to keep warm the genitalia by hot bottle applications etc. This can be Mag-p. or Nux-v.
So what you have to remember in Mag-c. is the sickly appearance, the tiredness, the anxiety and especially when the anxiety is together with some trembling.
A feeling of trembling or inner trembling or even external trembling. When that anxiety, especially if it is about something that is going to happen, an accident for instance. There is a constant feeling that an accident is going to take place.
As soon as they go to bed, this anxiety goes away.
We have Mag-c. when we see that sour idea, whether it is in temperament, whether it is in perspiration, whether it is in menses, whether it is in vomiting, in any kind of discharges.
Which is again the same idea as?
Hepar  sulphur and Rheum.
When you have an aggravation of sleeplessness between 3-4, or after 3, aggravation between 3-4 and when the liver is affected, when there is tiredness, aggravation from draft, don't think only of Kali-c, think of Mag-c. as well.
Also when you see this symptom of 'while eating warm food aggravates', the headache, the pain, the facial neuralgias, the stomach pain, the anxiety, the perspiration comes etc,
that is a keynote of Mag-c. and think of Mag-c. in children that do not thrive, do not grow, with pale skin, this yellowish type of skin. Earthy skin.
And of course worse from milk, whether it causes colic pains or diarrhea.