We shall be talking now about Mag-m.
We can say again it's a liver remedy. It's a remedy that has as main characteristic, a kind of  temperament which we call sour.
This has been developed through years of liver and digestive system misfunctioning.
When we see that sour temperament with indigestion, we'll think of Mag-m.
Which other remedy can have that? It is Nux-v.
But Nux-v. is completely different as we shall see. These people have a kind of bitterness. They feel unhappy and quite tired.
Eventually they will reach a state of having an aversion to make an effort, an aversion to think and a state of mind which we call dullness of mind.
They are people that have this kind of bitterness inside but not the hardness or the thorny kind of bitterness that we see in Nux-v.
Nux-v will be aggressive, irritable and will have this bitterness irritable, aggressive. Mag-m.  is the opposite.
It belongs to people who have a kind of aversion to fighting and quarreling. Because of that, they cannot tolerate, they cannot stand too much quarreling and fighting and noises in their immediate environment.
It will be the people that will seek actually to pacify everybody around them; they are the pacifists.
Which is quite opposite with Nux-v. Again indigestion, a sour temperament in Nux-v but so much aggressiveness and so much anger, so much quarreling.
With the least thing they will fly a temper and they will quarrel, they cannot control their temper. Mag-m. do not want that. There is fighting, they say calm down please, stop.
Mag-m. children that have already a dysfunctional liver, the digestive system is not doing well and the parents describe the children as very frightened when they hear the parents fighting.
And they want them to calm down, they say please mother, please father. These can be Mag-m. children.
The Mag-m. patients are very sensitive to any kind of confrontation. Confrontation which involves either themselves directly or even to other people. They are very sensitive to this kind of vibrations.
They have a strong sense of duty. They are people that will do whatever is right to be done.
And they easily overload themselves with a lot of tasks and a lot of responsibilities.
Then of course they come into a state of anxiety because they cannot deliver what they have promised, what they would like and have undertaken to deliver. And they come into a state of anxiety.
When they are in that state, they will have such great anxiety that they go into bed and they cannot sleep anymore. The same as Nux-v, sleeplessness but from too much thinking in Nux-v.
Here is the anxiety that they have not done, they have not delivered what they should have done.
This state, the sense of duty together with the emotional sensitivity to others, eventually leads to greater restlessness and fidgeting.
Over this restlessness, they become restless with fidgety and indigestion and they cannot sleep.
Some cases they cannot sleep the whole night; they will remain awake and they will sleep towards the morning.
And then when they will wake up, they will feel totally unrefreshed. It is a great characteristic of Mag-m. that when this anxiety state develops together with the dysfunction of the liver,
when they are go into bed even if they sleep the whole night, they wake up in the morning in such a state, that it's indescribable.
The body feels absolute heavy, they don't want to talk, they do not have the energy to talk. They feel completely stiff all over.
Mag-m. therefore becomes one of the main remedies which has unrefreshing sleep. You see when we go to our books and we see unrefreshing sleep it doesn't mean anything.
The way I describe it to you is that state that they will describe it to you, their waking state. Or if you go in the Repertory it will say in the morning aversion to talking, something like that. This state is the real state of Mag-m.
What is very interesting is that many times, with Mag-m. even with little ailments whether it is a flu or it is a common cold they may get into a very restless and anxious state on lying in bed and closing the eyes.
They feel very tired, Mag-m. very tired people. As we'll see it progresses that state of tiredness, it becomes more and more and we see another state that comes.
They are quite tired and they feel they must go to bed. They go to bed and they lie down and they close their eyes, these 3,4,5 minutes.
And they develop a state of anxiety. They are tired, they want to stay in bed, the state of anxiety comes and does not allow them.
And the restlessness and they turn around and they try to keep in bed and they cannot. Then eventually they have to jump up from bed and walk up and down to calm themselves down.
And it is phenomenal how much the symptoms which are appearing when they lie down and they have a common cold, the nostrils are blocked. And immediately comes dyspnea and dysphoria and they cannot breath,
then the anxiety, the restlessness and then it is a syndrome all together which builds up while they are lying and having their eyes closed. They have to get up and walk up and down, up and down and then they are relieved.
That becomes characteristic of Mag-m. people but Mag-m. now breaks down the whole system. It makes the whole system feel tired and old.
The tissues become dried up. There are rhagades, cracks in the corners. The skin becomes old looking from dried up situation.
And it's very characteristic with Mag-m. people that as they go through suffering in life and then eventually the liver starts breaking down, the digestive system is not working a lot
more disappointments, more dysfunction of the liver, more waking up in the morning very tired, more constipation, more indigestion, they feel tired and more tired.
And then one day they go to the mirror, they look in the mirror and they say, 'my God! I've become old suddenly' they realize. And the moment they look at the mirror they don't have the energy to liven up.
It seems there is a vicious circle. Looking at the mirror makes them feel more tired, more old and one of the main characteristics of Mag-m. you will see this tiredness, this indigestion, liver, the waking up in the morning.
Also they will say 'I've become old'. The feeling that they have become old, they look old and then eventually an unsocial feeling comes where they want to be by themselves.
They don't want company, they don't want to go out to the parties. The woman will say to her husband go by yourself, I'm too tired to come.
There is no energy.
And you see how sensitive, they become sensitive to noises, sensitive to quarreling. It is the noise, the quarreling and all that they feel they cannot handle.
So they have to have peace in their surroundings. Duty bound also. Just try to make a spherical kind of understanding of this patient.
Duty bound. They undertake responsibilities. They want to deliver, because they do not have enough energy, then anxiety, then restlessness, then effort.
Almost nervous effort, energy, they pick up nervous energy to deliver what they have to do. That makes them more tired.
They go to sleep and sleep gives them no relief. They wake up in the morning in a terrible state.
And then they appear as if all the time they are in a sour temperament. We are using words, I cannot describe it more, I have to use words.
The sour temperament because they have been suffering a lot. Also things are happening and they are unjust.
They don't like them, they want to react. It is not a revolutionary reaction towards injustice that we see in Caust.
Caust.  will see injustice, it will jump, it will fight. Mag-m. will see injustice, it will try to balance things.
Caust. will fight, it's the anarchist. Sometimes in Caust. children you will see they are doing things that are very aggressive, very anarchistic.
Why? Because they cannot tolerate authority. Anything for them is authority. 'Don't tell me how to do it. I can't.'  This is the attitude of Caust.
And if they see injustice, they feel now I have the right to kill. These are the people who put the bombs. The anarchists.
Give a Caust. case and give him a bomb and tell him that this man is unjust, he will put a bomb. He feels that he has to do it.
Give him Caust., he doesn't care anymore. Not really but almost.
The old people will say that people who are affected by conflicts and confrontations, their liver may be affected.
The Mag-m. exemplifies exactly that situation. Confrontations will affect almost physically the liver.  They will make the liver dysfunction.
We had an aggravation from lying down in all symptoms and especially when we have anxiety and restlessness.
It's stiffness, heaviness, dullness, a state of confusion in the mind, it's terrible the way that they wake up.
This is the number 1 remedy. If somebody tells you, nevermind what is the condition he is suffering, 'when I lie down and I close my eyes then comes anxiety and restlessness and I have to get up'. This is a Mag-m. case.
Another characteristic is the aggravation from salt. The aggravation from salt in all forms.
Whether they eat salt can be aggravated, eating a little bit more salt than the normal can aggravate their situation very much
and also going to the sea, it seems that the muriatic element like Nat-m is aggravated in the sea. The Mur-ac. is aggravated in the sea.
The Kali-m. is aggravated in the sea. The muriatic element seems to be aggravated in the sea.
Mag-m. is aggravated by eating salt also which is a characteristic of another very well known remedy, aggravation from salt.
Who knows which is the number 1 remedy? If somebody tells you 'as soon as I eat salt, I become very ill'. There is one remedy which is very prominent on that.
Phosphorus.
And another remedy is Selenium.
Aggravation in the sea, which is another remedy which has very much aggravation in the sea? It does not belong to the Muriatic elements.
Mainly it's a nosode but not Medorrhinum or Syphilinum.
It is Tuberculinum. It is aggravated in the sea very much.
Also another remedy which is a complementary of Nat-m? It's aggravated in the sea also.
Sepia.
Mag-m. is a cold remedy, aggravated by cold but in spite of that they may have warm feet, so much warm that they stick them out of covers during night in bed. They have to put out their feet in bed.
There are a few other remedies which are cold and warm in their feet.
Calc., Lyc., Sanic.
Sang. is a warm remedy.
Chamomilla also.
So Mag-m. you will see that they are cold, affected by cold, their feet are warm but what they want is to go out and walk in the open air.
So it is the same characteristic as another remedy which has that. Feels cold but wants the cold air?
It's Lycopodium.
The morning aggravation, the restlessness, the worse cold may lead you to think which remedy?
Rhus-tox.
How you differentiate? Rhus-t. wakes up in the morning very stiff with pains but Rhus-t. has nothing in comparison with Mag-m. has not the unrefreshness, not the heavy feeling, not the dullness.
It is the stiffness in the joints and stiffness on the muscles which makes a Rhus-t. case. They want to get up and move about to relieve the stiffness.
Rhus-t. has a characteristic which is very great in desires. Desires?
Desires milk very much. In Mag-m. there might be some desire for milk, there might be some aversion to milk. But what is most characteristic is that if they drink milk they will have an aggravation, they will have diarrheas.
Severe diarrhea which comes after drinking milk and a general aggravation from milk.
They have a desire for sweets and also for fruits.
And a strong desire for vegetables. Sometimes that can be an aversion to vegetables like the Mag-c.  Mag-c has primarily aversion to vegetables.
Mag-m. you will find sleeping on the left side mostly. And it's ameliorated by sleeping on the left side.
But if the liver is affected when they sleep on the left side, they have a dragging feeling as if the liver is dragging down.
They have quite severe jerkings,  electric like jerkings. Especially by the time they lie down, it's the time of aggravation for Mag-m.
Once they lie down whether it is dyspnea, whether it is the headache, whether it is the diarrhea, whether it is the colic pains aggravated during lying down, especially the first hour of lying down.
And all the Magnesias are aggravated by slight touch.  If you press deep hard it is OK but slight touch aggravates the pains or the situations.
Mag-m. can be quite hysterical because of that sensitivity in the nervous system, as I have described, they sometimes perform in a hysterical way.
And many times you will find some numbness in the extremities, indescribable, during a crisis of almost hysteria. Numbness in the lower extremities.
Also there is a great anxiety by the time of dinner, in the evening. During eating in the evening, it comes a great anxiety.
Anxiety also while reading but as I told you the psychology is such that they retract themselves. The take away themselves from society  and they go on reading.
And many times they like reading and their fantasy, their imagination is very active during reading. Exaltation during reading for instance. In a person who has been having that kind of temperament we indicate Mag-m.
They do not have much anxiety about their selves. Anxiety about health is almost unknown in Magnesias. Very few fears also.
You can see some fear of robbers perhaps which is almost natural.
Dullness of intellect especially on waking in the morning ameliorated by going into cold air.
They don't want to exert themselves. The dullness becomes worse if they press themselves to keep on doing intellectual work.
Woman becomes very excitable during menses.
The tendency for suicide is very minimal in Mag-m. but in the morning there is what we call a loathing of life. They just don't want to go on living.
That is in the morning when they wake up. It takes them about 3/4 to an hour before they can function again after sleep.
We have some characteristics in the head.
Headache which is mostly on temples ameliorated by hard pressure, is a characteristic.
Hard pressure ameliorates in general, it's a characteristic but especially the temples.
If you find a symptom like feeling as if boiling in the head, when lying down especially upon that side, that is a keynote.
Also headaches which are relieved sometimes by a few drops of lemon, they have to take some lemon, a few drops of lemon to relieve the headache.
That can become characteristic of Mag-m.  Also relief from lemon, from eating lemon, sour is another remedy.
Which is the remedy? It starts with P.
It's very characteristic, you have to remember that remedy. If there is an amelioration from eating very sour things, especially lemon.
You will see it in headaches, in stomachaches, in colic pains, in everything, they need sour things.
Which is the remedy?
Ptelea.
The headaches of Mag-m. can last 2 or 3 days continuously, without any interval.
Sleeps and wakes up with headaches, 3 days, then after a month again. After one and a half month again.
This can become a symptom of Mag-m. or which other remedy?
Ferrum metallicum.
Also a headache which is ameliorated by pressing the eyeballs strongly. It can be Mag-m.
A headache comes in woman around the period of menses, either during, before or after menses.
Headaches which come before, during or after menses. Or it can be before, during and after. Around that period headaches, then it can be Mag-m.
Margins of lids become inflamed and crusty.
A coryza which is ameliorated in the open air can be Mag-m. and in alternation of the coryza from dry to discharge.
Neuralgias, facial neuralgias that they may become better after warming the face or after pressure.
In the stomach we have the aggravation from milk and many times also fruit and fat aggravates the Mag-m.
Eructations that they are like garlic especially when they have a crisis of convulsions. That ends up in eructations at the end of the crisis
of convulsions, then it's only Mag-m.
So after milk we have diarrhea, we have indigestion, pain in the stomach.
We have an enlarged liver, especially the left lobe. Enlarged hard liver and colic pains in the abdomen around 1 o'clock in the morning will indicated Mag-m.
Pains in the right hypochondria extending to the back, like Chel. and Lyc.
Pain in the liver region when lying on the right side.
We have constipation which is difficult to evacuate the stool with ineffectual urging, which makes it again like Nux-v.
Insufficient stool like Silica or Nux-v.
There is a constipation, sometimes in the babies during the first month when they have the pains from the teeth.
When together with the pains of the teeth, constipation comes, the remedy most probably is Mag-m.
The stool is hard, knotty and large.
But after milk, it becomes diarrheic and mushy with tending to be yellowish white in color.
In urination we have cystitis with difficulty to urinate and has to press a long time before he can void a little bit of urine.
And it is characteristic of Mag-m. they cannot pass urine while standing but they have to walk. As soon as they walk, the urine.... it's very difficult.
Sometimes they have an insensibility in the urethra and they may lose urine  without understanding it.
Mag-m. is one of the main remedies of loss of this sensation during urination. They don't feel whether they urinate or not. Together with Caust. and also Arg-n.
In women we have frequent suppression of menses. Either too frequent or suppressed, irregularities in menses.
Leucorrhea in the morning on waking together with Sepia.
Backache which is aggravated by coition, by sexual intercourse.
The sexual sphere of Mag-m. is not presenting a specific interest. It's almost normal. There is no much to be noticed there.
I'm just trying to give you the most important things to remember. If you remember what I told you, it's more than enough to be able to recognize a Mag-m.
Yet we do not have the full range or maybe it does not have other symptomatology on mental-emotional level to be able to pin it down.
Mag-m. also, you must remember in sleep if the person says, 'I wake up in 3 a.m. and cannot sleep after that time', one of the main remedies is Mag-m.
An aggravation at 3 a.m. in general can be a Mag-m. It's not only Kali-c.
So to make a resume, to remember the remedy, it will be a remedy which is when an individual who is quite tired, is going through life with many many grieves in life
has become weak, tired, looks old, feels old, has developed a bitterness and a sour temperament, he is cold but ameliorated in open air, his feet are warm, he wakes up in the morning
very unrefreshed, his time of aggravation is 3 o'clock but mostly when he lies down and closes his eyes, he has anxiety and restlessness.
These things you have to remember and you will be able to recognize together with this idea of this individual.
Don't give Nux-v because when you will see that, you will give Nux-v, you will do nothing. You give Rhus-t., you give Nit-ac.
you give all kinds of remedies, nothing. Why? Because the person does not have the personality of Nit-ac., of Nux-v., it is a different personality all together.