Do you know what a lily is?
A flower. What flower?
I just had an idea now, a revelation.
The lily is the flower that was given to Mary, the mother of Christ. That flower was lily.
What it symbolizes? It symbolizes purity and morality and something which is clear, pure, moral.
And tiger? A tiger is something wild, it symbolizes an element which is wild, aggressive.
Lil-t. is actually the remedy which has a big conflict within itself between moral considerations and sexual considerations.
It appears to be a remedy which has strong moral conscience or religious, very strong considerations and at the same time a strong sexuality.
It's very interesting, it's exactly the lily and the tiger, the purity and the aggressiveness within the same remedy.
And this is the main theme that goes through. This conflict you will find it going through the whole of the remedy.
It's a constant battle between moral feeling and sometimes the moral feeling takes over and suppresses the sexual.
Then the other time the sexual considerations become so strong that they become lascivious. Lascivious thinking.
And then in the Repertory you will see 'religious despair alternating with sexual excitement'.
That's the only remedy that has that conflict and within that conflict the whole remedy is built.
You understand now the energy how it goes inside from one extreme to the other. And that is why we have Lil-t. as being one of the most aggressive, irritable remedies, that they are really dissatisfied inside.
Irritable, dissatisfied, she does not know what is going on inside her. It's the type of woman and fits mostly women, that will switch off from religious considerations to nymphomania.
The can go from one to the other. Very religious, very sexual and the conflict within the individual.
In order to suppress this it has to work hard and then this energy builds up and we have the element that we call in a hurry. Hurried feeling.
There is a lot of energy which has to be spent and has to be spent in such a way as to suppress the sexual energy which is arising all the time.
Out of this conflict arises a feeling of guilty consciousness.
When this conflict goes on, then starts having some fears and the fears will be what?
Fear of evil.
And then fear of insanity also.
And this is the person where you can find it in women who have suppressed their sexual desire completely and they have come to the morality side of their remedy and we have a type of person who is a spinster.
A woman who has not had a love affair ever in her life and then the energy becomes so aggressive inside her and nothing satisfies her and she does not know why.
Because of these moral considerations. She has decided consciously that I don't want sex and the sex drive is so strong and tries to repress it.
And all the time the battle is going on and as a result we have dissatisfaction, tremendous irritability. Nevermind what you try to do to console her, she is inconsolable.
You cannot say to her OK don't make such a noise, she will bang doors and go inside, she will scream, go in hysteria type of behavior.
Then the religious despair comes. Religious despair means in the Repertory, she feels that she has done something wrong. I had some sexual thoughts and the thoughts are lascivious thoughts.
And then she becomes more despaired, now I'm not going to be saved. She's religious, she believes in the next life and because of the wrong she has done here, she cannot be saved, she will not go to the paradise or whatever is the belief.
Once in this excitement, in this state of aggression, the idea comes that she is not really living into the present. It is as if living into a dream but in a wild dream.
Then there is a state in which she grieves all the time, there is grief even if there is no grief, she must find something to grief about.
Do you understand the psychology? And fears that something bad will happen. She's doomed. She is going to go insane, she is going to lose her mind.
There is something bad which will happen with her health. Fear of disease. Here again we have fear of disease, fear of heart disease like Lac-c., this is different state of affairs.
Do you see the issues? But if you go to the letter it says 'fear of heart disease', 'fear of insanity'. Lac-c. fear of insanity, Lil-t. but they are different.
Completely different in their contact in the world, in the way you perceive them. They are not the same at all. Fear of some disease coming. Something bad is coming but what is the bad?
Most probably because she has done something wrong because she is not going to be saved, something is going to happen to her. What is this? She is going to lose her mind, she is going have a heart attack, to be very sick.
And then the element of hurriedness is very important with Lil-t. Lil-t. has a great hurriedness and it's like Tarent. They want to do 7 things at one time.
In the Repertory, Tarent. is not mentioned at all. Tarent. is very much in a hurry and Tarent. wants really to do 7 things at one time and yet in the Repertory if you go and see it, it's not there.
But the nature of the remedy is such that naturally you think yes most probably because the energy is great with Tarent.
And the energy is great with Lil-t. as well, so they go on and do work, work, work and the more they do the more they feel in a hurry.
And they do it in order to get rid of the energy which is inside and the energy is destroying them, why? Because it's a bad energy, it's sexual energy.
In Lil-t. we may see a kind of manic depressive state where mental symptoms develop and they go away and then we have physical symptoms.
Pains in the stomach, pains in the guts, sciatica, nervous pains etc. and then again the psychological picture comes up, the mental picture.
In religious affections it matches remedies like Hyos., like Lach., like Verat.
Symptoms that alternate, for instance, she is very depressed in the night and she wakes up in the morning and she has diarrhea.
You see how the mental symptoms alternate with physical symptoms.
And then she may go into depression and the depression goes away and there is a tremendous sexual energy which comes, a sexual urge.
And then if they let themselves go into the sexual sphere then they will be talking in a language which is lewd language
they will be thinking a lot, they will be acting upon the sexual energy and they will be acting aggressively. Tiger like. Nymphomania.
This tiger idea is towards this sexual energy that becomes too aggressive and overtakes the individual. And then again the lily element, the purity element that appeals to them very much, they must be correct, they must be nice.
It is a driving force inside them to have morality and then there is a conflict. And there we have a case of Lil-t.
Inside the head there is a kind of wild feeling like Medorrhinum.
It says now I'm going to lose my mind and then she has to shout to relieve this pressure.
And don't talk to Lil-t. just don't talk when she is irritable, you have to let her alone; otherwise she will take all the irritability out to you.
Whoever is present and is not going to attack, face to face attack but she is going to behave in such a way that she will make you feel absolutely guilty.
That you have made her so upset, you have made this, you have made that, that now she is crying because of you.
And nevermind how much you try to please her, she is not going to be pleased. That is the type.
And she has aversion to mental work, they don't want to work. There is a kind of confusion again in the head and aversion to anything which requires a mental strain.
Usually they want to be left alone. You will see in the Repertory it says, wants to be left alone. But this is the idea, wants to be left alone it doesn't mean anything as a phrase. You have to take it into the context of that person.
This craziness, this wild feeling and emotion inside the head that looks like almost vertigo, when they try to describe it, they will describe it as a wild motion inside the head, which is not vertigo but it looks like vertigo.
And here again is similar to Lac-c., because many times you will see headaches especially in the forehead which alternate sides.
These headaches usually come after an excitement which they have and an irritability and the feeling of wild feeling and motion in the head and this kind of dizziness or vertigo and ends up in a terrible headache. Tearing headache.
And with the headache what they have to do is they have to move out, to move in the open air and to get some fresh air and move about in order to be relieved.
They are aggravated if the stay in a room and especially if the room is warm.
Also in this condition of dizziness and a state of not being quite in contact with the reality, there comes a fear that they may easily fall down.
It is strange, for instance, you will see irritability in Lil-t. and the irritability will be most accentuated after an orgasm.
Instead of being relieved and happy, they are very irritable after an orgasm, after having sex or even after nightly emission. A man may have a nightly emission; they become very angry.
Sometimes also Lil-t. develops the desire to pull the hair of people that are in front of them. Which is the remedy that has that strongly?
Bell. Lach. also, Tarent. they have this impulse, this crazy impulse.
Also the mental symptomatology can develop after having sex; once they start having sex, it is excessive. It's the tiger element again. Then after this excess the mental of Lil-t. starts to develop.
And there is restlessness and in the restlessness there is hurriedness and in the hurriedness there is a compelling impulse to go fast, to walk fast, to do things.
We have a disturbance of the eyes again after orgasm. A visual disturbance after an orgasm.
When they become irritable, they don't want to eat, they develop an aversion to eating, aversion to any kind of food. Especially with upset psychological state.
And then we have this keynote of Lil-t. which is similar with Sep., which is the bearing down sensation of the abdomen, of the intestines.
The intestines feel heavy and dragged down. That is a very strong symptom of Lil-t. It comes as keynote and it is like Sep. but you see the difference between Sep.? Sep. also is irritable.
But Sep. usually will have aversion to sex. Lil-t. usually will have this moral feeling; either will say sex is no good or she will admit that the sexual urge is very strong.
Immediately with one question you separate one from the other remedy. When you hear 'my intestines they want to fall off', then you say 'how is your sexuality?'
That's bad, don't do it. But in the process you find a way to ask.
Also you remember in Sep.? You have a symptom where they cross their legs and they feel better. It's the same thing with Lil-t.
They cross their legs and they feel better.
With Lil-t. when is the period where they feel mostly this dragging down sensation? It's during menses.
Together with Sep. Sep. again has the same thing. Plat. also has it and some other remedies.
This dragging down sensation also can come during stool or while standing.
Standing becomes a keynote. I have this sensation of dragging down only if I stand. Then it becomes keynote and it is almost always Lil-t.
But the dragging sensation can keep on all the time and when they sit down and when they stand and when they lie down, they keep on having it. And when they sit they want to cross their legs, both Sep. and Lil-t.
Crossing the legs ameliorate is also with Murx.
They have a lot of activity in the abdominal area. There is a lot of sensations there. The abdomen feels short, distended, trembling inside.
A feeling of pressing in the hypogastrium, a feeling of pressing towards the genitals.
Also Lil-t. has the sense many times that menses are going to come, it's the same feeling as when the menses are coming.
With the constipation we have the same constipation exactly as Nux-v.  And here where you most probably give Nux-v.
Because you see the irritability, the ineffectual urging, they have an urging to go to stool and there is no effect. The same exactly as Nux-v.
You say, 'are you irritable?', 'Yes I'm very irritable'.  And you give Nux-v.
And also they have a diarrhea which looks like Sulphur where the diarrhea comes in the morning and they had to get up quickly and run. And it becomes like Sulphur.
Diarrhea driving out of bed we call it.
And there is a possibility that there is urging for stool and they can only urinate. When there is urging for stool, urine only comes out and there is ineffectual urging and only urine is coming out.
This again is a keynote and a keynote also is a lump in the rectum, a feeling of lump in the rectum, worse standing again.
The irritability of the nervous system and the irritability is around the abdomen, around the urinary organs, the stool organs.
I mean you will see constantly this irritation of the nervous system where it gives the feeling of urging. Urging to stool, urging to urinate and many times is ineffectual.
And then you have the real prolapse of the uterus like Sep.  again.
And if they get a cystitis will be a pain in the urethra outside, severe burning pain like Canth. and Cann-i.
The male also will try to suppress the sexual desire and because in the male the sexual desire is strong, then by suppressing sexual desire he may develop severe physical problems.
He may develop duodenal ulcer, he may develop tumors, he may develop epididymitis, he may develop different physical symptomatology by trying to suppress the sexual energy.
In Boericke Materia Medica if you look he says, 'sexual instinct awakened'. If you read that what it means? Sexual instinct awakened.
It is this idea that sexual desire, sexual drive is very strong. It's too strong, it's pathological. The sexual instinct if it is awakened, there is no problem.
Where do you see a problem? There is a period of life in every man or woman that the sexuality is awakened. That is a natural phenomenon.
Here what it means is not just awakened. It is that it is strong, powerful and the person is in a conflict with that instinct. That is the idea.
Or at least to their understanding the desire is too strong and too compelling and they are going to take them to hell and they fear evil then.
Why? Because you give in to sexual things and then the lascivious. Because the desire is strong, the more it resists the more the thoughts become lascivious.
And then the moral on the other side pulls the individual and then there is the conflict. And then we have Lil-t. case.
I give things a little bit exaggerated, I take them to extremes to show you the ideas underneath.
It's not that every individual you will find at that extreme but talking to the individual you will see the conflict, you will see the intensity.
It might be not very strong but it's going to be there and then with the bearing down sensation you see it's not Sep.
In the female we have a peculiarity, a keynote. The menses are flowing as long as there is motion.
If she goes and lies down in bed, the flow of menses stops.
As long as she is moving around, the flow is keeping on.
And the menses are profuse and dark in color.
And because of what we mentioned before, lying stops and getting up continues, we have intermittent menses.
Sometimes she has to walk to have menses. This becomes almost a keynote and Nat-s. has that as well.
He has pains or tumors in the ovaries and especially the left ovary and the pains extent from the ovary down to the thighs.
Especially on the outer surface of the thigh.
Sometimes there is deep pain in the genitalia, which alternates with pain in the heart.
And that is the time where they become fearful about having a heart problem.
The bearing down sensation will be in the uterus as well. The uterus will feel as if it wants to come out completely.
In the abdomen has quite a lot left sided problems, like Lach. And if it's a tumor in the ovary it will be left sided, if it's a cyst, it's a feeling of swollen area on the left side.
A feeling of constriction in the heart, especially in the night;
and they have to walk bend because of that constriction. They cannot stand up.
There is a fluttering sensation in the heart that wakes her up and then she is in a panic.
'Now I have a heart attack', a fear of heart disease.
And the fluttering of the heart or the pain of the heart may come again while she is lying down.
The remedy in order to have an outlet needs this constant motion. You take this person and you put it down to lie and it's aggravated in general. It needs that motion, it needs that occupation, hurriedness.
And when they urinate, they must urinate immediately. Otherwise they have some repercussion upon their health. The pains become stronger if they resist the desire to urinate.
There are a lot of similarities between Lac-c. and Lil-t., if you go and take the words. But in reality the two remedies are completely different.
They have this heat on the soles and in the palms both Lac-c. and also Lil-t.
Lil-t. also has another keynote of being worse from the evening of one day  till the next  morning.
About 4,5 o'clock it starts an aggravation and ends next morning. It goes right through the night. From the evening of that day, right through the night to next day.
There is another word which I see here it's written and that gives a good idea. It's an English word 'snappish'.
Somebody who will say something abruptly in an irritated manner.
So you have all this activity, all this irritation, the conflict, the better motion, it has to have motion, worse lying down, worse standing.
The bearing down sensation, the irritability, the cursing and then the wild feeling inside the head and then the confusion and the feeling that he is going crazy.
And then the religious element. Despair, religious despair about her soul, where she will be saved. They are great issues with Lil-t.
Well that's it. Thank you.