Most probably you will make a mistake and prescribe another remedy, usually the remedy will be
an anxious remedy like Phos., like Ars., Nit-ac.
You will think of these remedies until you see no effect...
...and the patient presents a very
great anxiety about his health.
The problems in Lob. center upon the lungs
and the digestive system, the stomach.
Where there is a combination of an individual who is suffering with stomach problems, dyspepsia
gastritis, vomiting and at the same
time complains about respiration...
...that is a case of Lob.
Lob. people are very concerned
about their possibility to breathe.
Breathing is becoming a very important factor. They will tell you that 'I cannot breathe'.
The lungs will be examined and almost never will be found something really pathological.
So it is a dyspnea which we can say is out of anxiety.
A dyspnea which comes with some
emotional disturbance or some fear.
They have a tremendous sensitivity
to cold and especially to cold draft.
For instance, they will tell you that it is totally impossible to sit on a room with air condition.
Immediately they become dyspnoic and then the panic comes and then they have to leave the room.
There is a panic which usually
comes together with the dyspnea.
So they are individuals who are serious, who will describe to you their ailments in a very serious manner.
They are closed, they are serious, not very communicative but behind their description you will perceive  the anxiety.
But it is not the anxiety of Phos.
They will try rather to hide the anxiety.
If you ask them, 'do you have anxiety?'
They will say '... yes' but actually the anxiety is tremendous.
Because the lungs have nothing and he says, it was impossible to sit there in this room and they have to leave.
They can leave parties, they can leave theaters, cinemas, any place which they feel there is a draft or an air condition.
They are people that they will
not run to the emergency room.
They don't reach the point where
they will go to the emergency room.
They feel that they have to
do something themselves.
They feel that they need
to rely upon themselves.
Though the panic is so much, I have almost seen nobody of Lob. going with the panic attack to the emergency room.
Where you will see these Acon. cases, you will see the Phos. cases, the Ars. cases, all these cases
they will go to emergency room.
Also they are individuals, as I said,
which keep inside the emotions.
If something is bothering them, they will not
be able to express it. They will keep it inside.
And eventually the stomach gets
upset and irritated and inflamed.
During the dyspnea attacks, they feel also sometimes that their heart may stop and there is
a peculiar symptom which they have. It is an emptiness and a feeling of nausea together with emptiness.
This emptiness extends on the chest and mostly in the heart.
They are patients who will not give you a lot of symptomatology also. That's why you battle with them.
That's why you prescribe wrongly for several times before you realize what is really going on.
Of course such individuals almost never smoke. You will not see any of these people smoking and if they go
into Lob. states they will quit smoking.
The very idea that somebody is smoking in the room, it will make them run out of the room.
Once I had a case of Lob. with a Minister.
And I was prescribing Nit-ac.
and I was prescribing Ars.
He was very dry individual and he
says, 'give me your telephone'.
And I had to come to Alonissos
to do my holiday by that time.
And I did not have a telephone here.
I had a house but not telephone.
He was the Minister of telecommunications. So I said 'I don't have...', 'You don't have a telephone?'
He says, 'make an application', many years ago so I can... To get a telephone here in Greece you may wait
3-5 years during that time.
Make an application and write in the application that this is your professional place.
By that time I was just coming for holidays. I said, 'no I cannot write that because this is not true'.
He said, 'but it doesn't matter, just write it'.
I said, 'I'm sorry I cannot write it. You write it, if you want'. He wrote it himself and I got the telephone within a few days.
I just want to show you the kind of anxiety that they have. If they feel you can help them, because
give Nit-ac., Ars., a little bit better and
maybe the anxiety ...but not real cure.
This remedy is not easy to perceive. Now for me it's much more easy but during these years it was very difficult.
When you discover a remedy really, it's very difficult, your mind does not go straight.
Now if I see a case, I will recognize it.
Stomach, emptiness, dyspnea which has no pathology with anxiety and panic attacks.
Do you feel that any remedy of which we
have done is looking exactly like another?
Do you see the difference, the uniqueness in each remedy?
In a symptom or two, a lot of remedies are lookinglike each other but when you perceive the picture
it doesn't look, it is unique.
This is the idea of learning Materia Medica of course.
That is the most important to
get it and to remember it.
Then you will be able to recognize it.
Ther. is another remedy that will look
like the remedy we did yesterday, Asar.
The reason is that both have a great sensitivity to noise.
They will say, noise makes me feel pain in my body. They can have a toothache and noise it can ...
...they have a slight pain in the ear
and the noise will make it unbearable.
They will have a pain in the stomach
and the noise will make it stronger.
Noise really exaggerates
the pain in the body.
And these individuals will have
a triple symptomatology.
They have the sensitivity to noise, they cannot sleep and they have vertigo, something between dizziness and vertigo.
It's not that the things are turning. It is that it is strong dizziness which approaches the idea of vertigo.
These are also individuals who have
lived a life of sleeplessness.
They have never almost slept to be satisfied by sleep and the picture they will present is a picture of a mind
which is confused and dizzy and vertigo.
And then it can reach the point of even having Meniere's disease where we have the real vertigo
with nausea and the vomiting.
They are dissatisfied individuals that
they find no pleasure in anything.
They do not have the possibility to do a lot of work, due to that state of the mind and due to the vertigo
and due to the dizziness.
And due to the fact that they feel constantly tired because they did not have enough sleep.
You have an aggravation from motion and especially with the vertigo they have to stay in one place
with the least motion. It will look to you like Bry.
But Bry. will sleep. These people their main complain is sleep and Bry. will not have the sensitivity to the noise.
Due to the fact that they cannot perform,
they feel they never have enough time.
Time is not enough or time passes too quickly.
You have a case that looks like Kali-bi. with a lot of discharge, with sensitivity to noise and sleeplessness
it's not Kali-bi. But if you have a case where there is a lot of discharge, the discharge is sticky and there is
sleeplessness only between 2-3 o'clock, then that's Kali-bi.
But Kali-bi. is a different individual than this one.
These individuals are dried up individuals because of intense sleeplessness.
They have been suffering for so many years.
They are dry.
You see the person and you
feel there is very little energy.
They will speak in a manner which is soft, they will not get over excited about things, there is no energy left.
And they are exhausted and they will go to bed and they need to sleep and of course they will take these
earplugs and put it. Because in the night, forget it. They try ... and they sleep lightly and not deeply.
And they have the impression, they will
tell you 'I have not slept the whole night'.
So every day they are exhausted.
They cannot go and have a deep sleep.
Ther., I have seen it in anxiety of conscience. There is some kind of anxiety but not in all individuals
and there is some kind of mental disorder
which is expressing itself with some rituals.
They have some rituals.
They take a bath in a particular manner.
The mind of Ther. is not clear. It is a confused mind and they need to have a kind of order to do things.
Otherwise it becomes difficult for them.
Vertigo, dizziness, 'I'm suffering. I can't sleep'.
This is the idea that you will get from the individuals.
And you give different remedies.
They will never come because the noise makes pain in my body. They will not come and tell you like this.
They come because they cannot sleep. They have sleeplessness and you enquire about different symptoms
of different remedies which have sleeplessness. Is this Sulphur, one of the Kali's, Ars., Sep., Aur.?
And eventually when the mind comes in Ther. and you ask about noise, then they will say 'no I can't stand noise'.
That is definite.
But they will not give it to you as
a primary symptom of their case.
So unless your mind goes to Ther. and ask
for the noise sensitivity, you will not get it.
Back pain aggravated by noise or sits sideways on a chair, which are peculiar symptoms which I have not seen.
-I have a question on Ther. You said
that they are somehow ritualistic.
Which remedies would you consider in
autistic people, who need this ritual but in...
-Autistic are not ritual.
Rituals have people who are not autistic.
They have to do certain functions in order to start their day, they have to do first this, then that, then this and that.
If you tell them, forget these two portions it's not possible.
They are people who are not mentally retarded. Autistic children are totally mentally retarded.
-I mean they need a strong program autistic people. Everything has to be in order.
-No, they are not fastidious. They don't need everything to be in order. They need to do certain things in proper order.
They need to do things in a certain
order. This is ritualistic.
What can we say about Nux-m.?
They are patients who have two main problems. The one is dryness of the mucus membranes.
And when we say dryness, we mean real dryness.
The lids stick. No tears, no salivation.
The tongue sticks on the palate.
And they will have to sip water to moisten the mouth without having any desire to drink the water.
Sometimes they can even spit it. They just take the water and spit it, to moisten the mouth only.
Thirstless, excessive dryness and at the same time a state of mind which is very dreamy.
We say, live as if in a dream.
They will start doing something and the telephone rings and they will go and talk to the telephone
and forget totally what they were doing.
They are putting things on cooking and this
can be forgotten and the food can catch fire.
Their mind is not there at all in the job, they cannot concentrate in the job they're doing.
Somebody comes to bring something. They go out, they have been talking on the telephone,
they will leave the telephone, go there and forget entirely that they were talking on the telephone.
The telephone is gone out of the mind.
That state is like being drugged.
It is not an unpleasant state for them. They are in a state of wonder  but the mind is totally disintegrated.
Also they will be fainting. They are ready
to faint. How is the state just before fainting?
A little bit before fainting where you don't
really perceive what actually is happening?
Things are becoming dazed. That is almost constantly the state in which they live.
And if they have a little shock,
they may just go and faint.
And the shock comes easily if
they see somebody is hurt.
They cannot stand somebody is hurt and
blood is running and ... they will collapse.
In that state, it seems that there is some problem with the circulation or the supply of blood to the brain.
And what you will have?
Either the fainting or the sleepiness.
They can be talking and
they can be falling asleep.
They will read something and they cannot concentrate on what they are reading.
As soon as they concentrate
on something, sleep comes.
Narcolepsy, we have this expression.
Hysterical people, hysteria with fainting.
I can't stand it.
Straining in the stool can make them faint.
We have this combination of sleepiness, over powering  sleepiness like which other remedy we have spoken about?
Opium.
You will have a difficulty
differentiating with Op.
And what will be the difference? Something which you have to ask immediately to differentiate?
-Op. is in an alert mood.
-No. Op. is not alert, it's in a happy mood.
-Op. is painless, it doesn't feel the pain.
-There is no such a dryness in Op.
-That's it.
There is no such a dryness in Op. We said, main problem is dryness of mucus membranes. In Op. it doesn't exist that.
So immediately you see this state, they describe the state of their mind and the over powering sleepiness
the narcolepsy... You get sometimes you get a student who has this Op. state and you will see them sleeping
almost 3/4 of the time  in the class and
then they open their eyes and they go back.
I had a case like that. I said, come here...
Op. is juicy, thick lips and happy, satisfied.
The typical Op. is almost in a
constant state of good mood.
But this good mood is maintained by lies, by just going through life in a very not correct way of contacting
with the other people.
But they cannot keep awake.
It's not possible. They fall asleep.
This narcolepsy state is not easy to cure also. It needed several repetitions of Op. before she was able to stay awake.
Another element which is there and it looks like Carb-v., because of the fainting, because of this....
... lack of power and the bloatedness, which
both have, you may confuse it with Carb-v.
Also the women have problems bearing children. They may have a history of spontaneous abortions.
In general these people are prone,
are sensitive to little shocks.
Whatever shock it may be, it has a disproportional effect upon their health.
Apart from make them faint, they may have a small fright which other people will not have any effect
with Nux-m., it may have a big effect in the organism.
It may stop the menses. She has menses and the menses are stopped. And next month there are no menses.
If you have the beginning of an Alzheimer which will present this lack of concentration, forgets what she has been doing
in that state what she does not realize really, it is not an unpleasant feeling which she has, it's very strange.
Yesterday she was describing the state, she says emptiness, nothing, it's not unpleasant, it's not anxiety.
In Nux-m. is like living in the present, having no past at all, even 5 minutes ago there is no past, forgotten.
What is here, the telephone
and what is the next thing.
The past has been totally wiped out.
In a case like this that she was describing, immediately you ask, you have dryness of the mouth?
'Yes, I have dryness of the mouth'. How much? How much is important. The intensity.
Because if you open the Repertory and you see 'Dryness of mouth', you will see 200 remedies.
What you are looking for in
Nux-m. is excessive dryness.
It's a syndrome which has this dryness.
There is a syndrome which has this
dryness with dryness of the conjunctiva.
They have to put every hour artificial tears
to wet the eye. That is the case with Nux-m.
And the mind also is drying out.
And the emotions become dried up, they don't have strength, the resistance is very low. That is the type of Nux-m.
Is this her case?
The more you know, the worse is
to find the remedy, I can tell you.
It's better you know 20 remedies and
you give Monday Sulph., Tuesday Calc...
Why the hell I have to squeeze my mind to do differentiation? I feel the problem that you may have and...
I understand very well, it's much more
easy, you just give whatever comes.
Take 20 remedies, the french way, take
them all, something is going to happen.
Something is happening but not a cure.
And then you have to battle so much but I'm sure that if you take these correct lines of prescribing, in the beginning
it may be difficult but as you progress in years and you insist on that line, what happens is your knowledge
increases, increases...If you take the other
easy line, your knowledge is going down. Even if you know.
By the time you reach to prescribe 25 remedies together, you will say 'it's better I give up Homeopathy'.
Your knowledge is finished, it's very
strange. This knowledge does not stay.
This knowledge, if you practice incorrectly, it
will fly away. It's very peculiar, it doesn't stay.
Because it's so much and unless you put
it into practice every day, it will not stay.
But for these smaller remedies, we have only to remember 3 points. Remember them not by itself, not dryness only.
Remember dryness and sleepiness. And when you remember dryness and sleepiness, then it comes
that sleepy state which is going on in the mind.
This is a very important remedy.
This is a very important remedy today
because we are all going crazy.
Because of over stimulation and we're going towards ...
It's very interesting that when I started Homeopathy back in 59,60,61,65, I would not prescribe this remedy.
As the years go by and I see difficult cases from the Center, more and more we need this remedy.
It's a remedy that corresponds to a state of mind which is over stimulated, a mind which is very acute
over stimulated but there is a kind of peculiar twist.
A twisted mind, not a straight mind that thinks straight. A mind that thinks a little bit twisted.
Also there is a strong element to show up myself, to show up how clever I am, but covered up.
The little children even which are a lot of them today, which are over stimulated because they hear information
here and there and their mind absorbs all this kind of information and you see these children they are
very serious, they put very serious questions.
You see 7 years old and he talks about
'what is your idea about God?'
'What's your idea?', 'Well, I think he is the zero.'
And then you talk very seriously
and they are very serious.
But in their mind is not the healthiness of a strong mind; it's the acuteness of a diseased mind.
They perceive things and they perceive also your faults, if you tell them a lie, they say why did you tell me a lie?
The main element which I found out with these people is that this twist in the mind it comes on the feelings
and it comes on the physical body also.
When you walk, you walk in a straight manner.
You put your feet one in front of the other.
The Verat. want to do something else. The organism leads them to do a movement which is an extra
movement of the leg.
The eyes they go like this. For them, they will do an extra motion, it's very difficult to describe.
But if you get the idea, then you
will recognize it immediately.
The mind is... and the emotions
are... and the body is restless.
You get the children in the office, they will not stay quiet in an interview. They will just move up and down
asking question, taking this, 'what is this?
Why you ask me this question?'
'Because I want to know how you feel'. 'I don't think you are right. You should not ask this question'.
This excessive restlessness it may appear for instance in the knees. They sit down to study and there is
inside the knees, this restlessness.
And they have to get up, they cannot study.
Inner restlessness, outer restlessness, restlessness of the mind, quick minds...
but there is this kind of twist, as I said.
I told you about that child;
I've been treating this child with Phos.
He came to my house here and the door had a net and there was a little open in the end of the net.
Then there was this boy and
I caught his eyes looking at this.
The impulse was if I could
just kick that and open it.
I caught his thinking and I forgot about it.
Then we left and then I go back
and I see the door is like this.
Of course I said, 'Lefteris come here.
Who did this?'
He thought, 'how is it possible that he knows if I did this when nobody was present. How could he know?'
'Lefteris tell me'. So his mother comes, she says 'Lefteris never tells lies. So if he had done it, he would say'.
But Lefteris he didn't deny it, he would keep quiet. I would say, 'Lefteris why did you do it?'
and Lefteris would pretend...
But he would not say, 'I did not do it'.
His mother said, 'Lefteris did you do it?'
So I made it a point, every time they would come with his mother, the first time he comes, 'I say, Lefteris why did you do that?'
First, second time, third time, third day, fourth day, 24th day he said to his mother, 'why do we go to George?
I can't because I feel depression,
he will ask me about the door'.
He never said but I wanted really to know what he was thinking? What is this destruction element
I wanted to find out and next year they
come for holiday, they come to my house.
'Lefteris will you tell me now why...'
He thought 'he must have forgotten'.
I pressurized him in a very nice way but I pressurized him and then he said, 'I don't remember'.
So clever. He did not lie, he did not deny openly but he never gave an answer and when he admitted
he did it he said 'I don't remember'. 'I just want to know your thinking, what you were thinking'.
He tried to remember, 'I don't remember'.
And there is another element in Verat. which is very strong and looks like the Caust. element.
They are the supporters of the weak.
In the books it says...
the savior, he preaches, he goes out when he is totally mad he preaches to save the world.
But in the pre-stages of that, there is an
element of protecting others who are weak.
They work in a company. They will be the ones who will jump on the boss, on the authority and attack him
and say how much he has been
unjust for this or that person.
They also get fixed ideas that these persons are bad, these persons are good, never mind what you tell them.
The fixed idea is there and he will keep on insisting on his own idea of what he has understood.
The restlessness will lead them, as the mental restlessness progresses, it will lead them to do things which are useless.
They are on the telephone, like this.
It's not possible to sit down and talk. They take the telephone and go up and down, forget it.
The moment the mind works, the physical restlessness becomes more and more.
The physical restlessness also makes them not being able to concentrate on one thing they are doing.
They can be broken in their attention. They will do this and then they do that and then that...
Eventually if they progress in their mental disturbances...
What is the difference between a person who is quite healthy and who believes in God and who is praying to God
between this person and Verat. also is
praying to God. And is praying constantly?
What is the difference where his praying is crazy and the other person's praying is healthy?
You take the symptomatology of the remedy and you see that the Verat. people have this element of 'I am clever'
'I am important, I am strong, I am going to protect others'.
That element in praying it is exactly the barrier between the praying and the other person.
In praying you say 'I'm very weak,
I'm nothing, please help me God'
Because when you pray,
usually you ask something.
You cannot pray and say,
'I'm great, look how clever I am God!'
That's why eventually he reaches that state where he goes out and says, 'Repent! Repent!'.
He will take a big banner and write 'repent' or he will shout and walk up and down, saying 'repent, you sinners!'.
But all this is out of the need or recognition of 'how important I am'. It is not a humbleness.
They will look very courageous, they will attack the authorities and the other people may be admiring
them for their courage and for their acuteness.
But all that underneath there
is an element of self promotion.
That twist is there. What is this twist?
I don't know.
I'll give you another example with the
little one I was talking about.
They were coming in my house about 10 children and he was the youngest. He was 5, the other children
were 7,8,9, 11... and they started running up and down while we were discussing and eating and the children
got excited more and more.
At certain moment I shouted to them. I said, 'shut up, stop! all the children stopped and kept quiet.
Lefteris turns and says to me, 'who are
you that you will not allow us to play?'
I said, 'you play but not in this manner.
You're shouting and running, what is this?'
But he was the only one who says, 'who are you to tell us...'
They are haughty, it says here, it's not exact, they are haughty but they will not show it overtly.
They will put clever questions
to show how clever they are.
They will not say, 'I'm clever'. They try to do it in a manner where you can't really say, you are haughty.
It's an underlying issue.
Because of this ability to talk and the mind which is sharp, you will see they get very easy communication
with others and with the women also.
So very easy for a man to get a girlfriend.
Verat. is mostly indicated in men.
But the element 'I want you to perceive' is that element of sharpness, twisted, at the same time the idea
of the savior which is behind.
And which is not the real savior.
Somebody who really wants to
help others does not do it in this way.
Especially in spiritual situations.....
....you don't promote yourself, you try to help others, you try to see what is the problem of the other person
and help them, without promoting yourself.
Verat., through their action, they will feel
very good when they become the saviors.
I'm suppressing you and a Verat. is there in the class. They will get up and say, 'you are suppressing us
you are doing this and that'.
He will appear to be the savior of the class and they like afterwards to come and say, you did very well and all that.
Then eventually he will go to madness and... 'repent, repent!'.
But it starts much more subtle. Then you see
the restlessness and you see this tendency.
It is difficult also in these cases the patient will not give you the information that he is doing that because
it's his natural condition.
The others around the person will tell you of actions of that type and then you confirm your prescription.
Dellusions they are Christ or a person that has saved the world.
In physical symptomatology we have coldness of the whole body, a feeling of water running on the skin.
Similar to what he described but with Verat.  you have more the feeling that it's running out. They drink some water
and they feel the water goes and runs on the outside.
The water has gone really inside. Or the
water feels running in their body.
This coldness and the tendency of this remedy
to produce diarrhea and vomiting, especially
forceful vomiting like a rocket.
And easy collapse from vomiting.
The body becomes very cold and vomiting, diarrhea and therefore was used in older times, in cholera.
It was one of the main remedies for cholera.
When I was in India they have told me of certain cases in which Verat. has helped in the cholera epidemics.
There is a great need because they lose these liquids, great need, thirst for cold water, cold drinks.
Desire for fruits, especially sour fruits,
unripe fruits and desire for lemon.
If you see this combination,
lemon desire and salt....
....if these two are strong in a case,
that's a case of Verat.
What they do? They take a lemon,
they put salt and they eat it.
This is how you treat the children. The children instinctively will ask for lemon. They take lemon, put salt
and eat it, they go up and down. If you have
an asthma case with this and restlessness, yes.
Many times we have cured
asthma in children with Verat.
It is strange that children today instead of being Calc., Calc-p., Sulph., they are Verat., so many children.
Why? Because of the condition in which we live and because of hereditary predisposition which becomes worse and worse.
Any kind of problems, during menses where the woman is upset with pains and then she has diarrhea
diarrhea before menses,
with vomiting, with pains... Verat.
Was anybody in a case in Germany in this hospital where I took the case of a woman with ...
-We saw it in the video.
-This case unless you know the remedy, unless you know what she was doing with her eyes, you cannot
recognize the remedy.  She was doing
something with her eyes ...
I always find it very difficult to describe it. I have seen it with their hands, their movements.
The movement is not harmonious, it's a twist.
Or the foot or the hand or the elbow or the eyes there is a kind of twist, it's not normal, it's not straight forward.
I perceive it very quickly when I see it because I know what is exactly but I want you to understand it.
Because it's very important point for Verat. If you understand it, then you can immediately spot it.
If you don't understand it, forget it. You will see it in front of you and you will pay no attention.
-Will they be easily offended perhaps? Especially if they see that somebody is not recognizing them in what
they are doing or they have no respect?
-No. There is not a case of easily offended because they believe in themselves and never mind what you say
their idea is this, finished. They know.
They can be fixed in their ideas and nothing will change them. You insult them, you tell them, nothing.
-George do you remember the student in Celle? After every interview he went to the patient and said
George gave you the wrong remedy
because I know you need Verat.
-In Celle it was a doctor from France, the poor guy every time I analyzed a case, he had an antenna
where he was examining the medicines.
The antenna says, this is your remedy and every time, all the cases that I had examined they were Verat.  cases.
Eventually they told me, he goes and says everybody, he has an antenna... I said 'OK you come.
I want to know my remedy'. He put down the remedies, he goes over the remedies and stops to Verat.
So he had given Verat. to everybody.
I said to the class most probably he needs Verat. and next year unfortunately he was not in the class.
I asked about him and he was in the mental asylum.
He was mentally disturbed and
most probably he needed Verat.
But they will not come and ask for help.
They don't realize the problem.
-Tell me if I am wrong. What it says to me is that if somebody is haughty but they are so clever that to be
obvious about it wouldn't be. They have to downplay it. They are nuts but in a secretive way but somebody
for example who is a name dropper. Who makes like it's not a big deal to know someone famous.
They downplay things because
for them to be obviously haughty is not clever.
Also what it sounds like to me, I forgot
what I want to say....what remedy is that?
- What you say is correct, they don't like when somebody is more clever and they will not overtly say to others
'he is not' but he will undermine
the other person who is his enemy.
because, as I said  they set their minds
in evil, he is evil and he is divine.
It is a fore runner of a serious mental breakdown.
By the time they don't have the real mental breakdown, you cannot say.
For instance the child if I had not given Verat.
by now he would be mentally very disturbed.
If they go for years and years and I have seen like this child, this man that we're talking about, I have
other examples also. Where everybody who understands Verat. says, 'he needs Verat.!', but he thinks
'I'm clever, I know why
should I ask for a remedy?'
-He also thinks with the over stimulation
of the media that they get old fast.
Especially in children, if they want to be a little bit more special than other children that they have to do things
with a corky way, just a little bit extra.
-Exactly. They want to be something special, therefore they need to do something extra, not the ordinary.
Because the ordinary everybody is doing it.
I have to be special and that special they
canbe twisting the truth, twisting the facts.
Taking a fact and seeing it from a different
aspect and becomes the opposite.
-It's the word circumspect like with Arg-n.?
-No, no.
I don't know exactly the meaning of the word.
-I would like to know something about the coldness in children.
-Usually it's a cold remedy but this
element does not exclude...
If they have the mental picture I'm describing, I will ignore the ailment but if they get an acute, like a diarrhea
or lung problem, then they have to be cold.
In the chronic condition, the coldness is
not absolutely necessary condition.
Desires lemon and salt is very interesting, also you get sometimes neither lemon, nor salt but out of 100 cases
80 cases they have these desires.
It's very frequent.