As I said, you cannot really get away from studying Homeopathy. It's a subject which needs constant aplication
constant study. The knowledge is too much.
The results are quite satisfying if you know what you are doing.
Until now I can tell you with my experience and seeing what others are doing, people did not know what they were doing.
They were giving homeopathic remedies but they did not know.
Many times they would give a correct remedy and they would not know.
That is the biggest problem with Homeopathy today.
You give a remedy, it has acted and you don't realize how it has acted or why it has acted.
And you say, this remedy did nothing, take another one, take another, take another one and eventually
you spoil your own good prescription.
I believe she has taken before Ignatia, she has mentioned Ignatia. We will see whether Ignatia will act now, yes or no.
How is that Ignatia will act now and did not act before?
You have to think about these things.
And that is what you are learning and I understand as I said, it's very difficult because the subtleties are very different.
For instance we'll talk about Lyss. today. Hydrophobinum or Lyss. is the same.
Hydrophobinum or Lyss. comes from the saliva of a dog who has rabies...
and as you will see there are symptoms in Lyss. which look like, which remedy?
Which look like Stram. and what are the similarities between the two remedies?
It's the fear of water and the effect of running water and in both remedies there is some fear.
Another similarity is the violent temper.
Actually in Lyss. there are even differences in these two similar symptoms.
In Lyss. the idea is that the sound of running water brings a state of inner excitement, in such a way
that the bladder is paralyzed.
And the person almost loses urine.
Therefore losing urine during hearing running water, it is an indication of Lyss.
Lyss. also is an abusive remedy. The idea is not so much violence; Lyss. will not reach the point where it will hit...
or will kill like Stram. But Lyss. will be abusive with their words. They will attack with their words.
Lyss. will be similar in their contact with Lil-t. but Lyss. does not have the sense of Lili-t. which says
'I have done my duty, what I had to do and therefore you owe me, you have to obey'. No.
This remedy is more abusive, more authoritative.
Especially you get people who have money, who have some kind of authority and they will treat the subordinates
in a very abusive manner.
Lyss. has fear of animals but it's not at all the intensity with which the fear of animals is with Stram.
Stram. is much more attacking, much more violent, physical violence.
This is verbal violence.
I found also that Lyss. is a remedy
that you will need in claustrophobia.
Terrific claustrophobia.
They cannot go away from their house.
They feel comfortable only inside the apartment.
Going around the block is almost impossible for them...when they have this claustrophobia case.
Finding themselves in a traffic is impossible,
they will just leave the car and go away.
They are afraid that they cannot get away from the place where they have been.
Also it is very strange, she has a fear of water but Lyss. will do exactly the same like the patient yesterday with the bottle.
They have a bottle and they test whether they can swallow, they feel that they cannot swallow.
Therefore in order to be sure that they can swallow, they have a bottle of water
which they take and take sips very frequently.
It is not thirst, it's only a sip to make sure that they can swallow. And many times they have difficulty in swallowing.
If you give them a little bit bigger pills, they will not take them. They say, 'forget it I will not take that'.
So I say, 'OK put some water'. 'Yes, this I can do'.
The disease is such that makes these individuals very demanding from others and if they don't get what they want...
they suffer very much. 'You should
have done this for me!'. That attitude.
Tremendous anxiety on anticipation.
They have to have an appointment.
By saying they cannot go outside of their house, I don't mean that all Lyss. cases cannot go out of their houses.
In the beginning stages or when they don't reach that severe claustrophobic state, they circulate, they go out.
But the idea is my throat is tightening up enough and I cannot swallow. And I don't like to be in a room.
Lyss. will sit there, next to the door. If they will come here and they have that kind of anxiety, forget it.
But not every Lyss. will have this symptom.
So they have an appointment, the excitement is there. Can you imagine the nervous system of a person
who hears the water running and he feels almost paralyzed, there is an excitement inside and they have to rush to urinate.
Many times this picture or similar picture will come from people that have been treated with anti-rabies injections.
I don't know the contemporary treatment what it is but the older treatment it was consisted of some severe type
of injections that they were doing in the abdomen.
And this treatment is terrible and leaves the individual invalid for the rest of his life.
Definitely it will have a side effect whether it will be very big or a smaller one, it doesn't matter but always when you see
that in the history, expect at a certain point that Lyss. will be indicated.
Another thing which I have seen is that the voice changes. The patient will tell you, my voice has changed.
There is quite an impressive difference in the tone of their voice.
They have a peculiarity also because you see this strong individual, aggressive, abusive, very abusive...
and when it comes to the point where they will see some suffering, they are paralyzed.
They become like Caust. or Phos. even in their desire to help somebody who is suffering.
They feel they are suffering, they are open.
Feeling the suffering of others means an openess on an emotional level, where the person feels has no protection
against the idea of suffering of somebody.
This Phos. case is exemplifying this very strongly.
They suffer themselves, the Caust. also. They can faint. The Caust. is mostly on injustice, the Phos. is mostly on suffering.
This remedy also has this peculiarity, abusive, strong, authoritative, hard to subordinates; yet he sees somebody...
with fever, with pains, they are paralyzed. They say, 'I can't do anything; when I see this, I'm finished.'
In their sexual sphere are quite excitable individuals who will be satisfied with some kind of strange sex.
The nervous system is such that in order to be excited, they need to have some peculiar, sexual desires.
They can be bi-sexual, they may want kinky sex.
The Americans say it, I don't know if this is an expression but I have been educated in America on these matters.
They have explained to me all these details.
Is it correct, you are from America?
-Yes.
-Americanized Cuban, is this correct kinky sex?
-Very good. My education was in Berkley.
What does it mean kinky sex?
-Very strange and unusual act.
This is what I've only heard, I have no personal knowledge.
The sexual activity in the States can be very erotic, it can include of sadomasochistic tendencies.
There is a more of a desire to achieve certain levels of excitement that go beyond ordinary intercourse
and it often involves pain, abusive behavior toward the partner, humiliation, derogation and ways of feeling
a sense of superiority or inferiority. And it's made to elicit an emotional power play between partners, 1,2 or even more.
There are actually clubs or organizations in certain cities of the U.S. where they indulge these activities.
-Great progress.
This person, what do you think according to the information he gave, will be indulging in what kind of sex?
-Power.
-The power, the sadistic because it's abusive, it's strong, it wants to inflict pain and all this goes with the description.
But usually in the consultation room we don't indulge into such information because information
from the sexual area is difficult to elicit really and to make the individual give you the information, unless you are in America.
Otherwise very difficult. With the Greeks, how is your sex? Normal. All men are normal. Italian also, all normal.
I believe Israelis also are very normal.
So it's very difficult unless you understand the nature of the remedy. Stram. what kind of sex may have?
From the nature of the remedy you understand. The same you understand the nature of sex of Staph. or Ign. or Nat-m.
we've spoken about the sexual sphere of these remedies.
For Nat-m. we have said. It has a sexual life which is very inhibited?
You see Nat-m. is a very closed person. Therefore in sexual matters will behave also in a closed way
and the vagina will be dry, painful, no enjoyment and difficult reaching orgasm.
But because of the suppression on the emotional level, on the other hand when they come into contact with a relationship
in which they feel comfortable, then they become over excited.
And then they become very, the Repertory
says, shameless in bed.
That means that they like to talk with
words which are exciting words and if the excitement goes
beyond a certain point, that is the time where the individual comes with instincts and does this.
So the nature of sex is according to the nature of general pathology.
In this case definitely we have a sex, in the books we find...
'complains for abnormal sexual desire'.
Another symptom which comes with this excitement of the nervous system, the nervous system is excited
then the senses become very acute.
And sometimes they can hear fantastically well, they are best for spies. You can be talking there and I can hear
what they say and the taste and the smell is very acute. And sometimes there is in the taste a change.
Because the taste is very acute, they may taste something differently than the ordinary.
The taste in the night it can become quite bitter and then they have the need to spit.
Spiting is also an interesting function of Stram., of Bell.
And they have an indescribable anxiety.
Very strong anxiety like the Phos. anxiety.
You prescribe wrongly in those cases because you don't recognize them immediately...
so you prescribe different other remedies.
The claustrophobia and the anxiety Lyc. and there is no this tension but you say it doesn't matter.
And then the thirst is there in sips and then you think that's Ars., with the anxiety, with the fear. Nothing.
Then maybe the water is not so much, like Phos. wants a lot of water but still I will try Phos. because ...
there is that state of anxiety, that tension.
When you are there and they are affected in the nervous system, you have them in front of you and
they are vibrating from energy and anxiety.
I remember one case, she was a very rich woman.
In order to come to my place, because she's asked me to go her place, I'm talking back in 1970
and 'I said no, I don't go'. 'You have to come.
She cannot come.'  I said, 'I'm sorry she has to come'.
She came in a Rolls Royce with two people and said, 'I've never done this before. Come so far from my house'.
So far it was about 4-5 km and I did not know
the case and I prescribed wrongly of course.
Once wrongly, twice wrongly... after 2-3 months later they call me on the telephone.
She is in a terrible state, she has locked herself in a cupboard because she didn't want to commit suicide.
She reached a peak of tremendous anxiety, I was giving several remedies but nothing was happening...
apart from changing a little bit the symptoms but finally all the anxiety came up.
They had a gun in the house and I can't remember she locked the gun or she locked herself...
something like that. Not to take the gun to kill herself.
She was like this for 20 years, she could not go out, she could not go to a function, she could not go anywhere.
But she would not take allopathic drugs because you know they have big pills, forget it I will not take this.
I will not swallow this because if I swallow this, then I'm dead because it will stuck there and finished.
I did not know Lyss. by that time and she called me one day and she said, 'I am chocking because
the tongue has swollen, closing all the air.
And they called me and I had to go to her house. I saw that terrible state, in that condition.
I looked at the tongue, the tongue was not swollen. The feeling was that the tongue was closing up the whole pipe.
During that time I gave a remedy you never heard, Cajuputum.
I gave her this remedy and next day she was calmer and she came back to normal state.
And it was by one symptom of Lyss., I can't remember now, she mentioned.
After this remedy the picture of Lyss. started to be more clear.
And if I remember well she mentioned losing of the urine while opening the tap.
I said 'Have you ever be bitten by a dog?' She says 'yes'. 'What age?', 'Six'. She was eating something
and a dog jumped to take it and bite her lips at the same time.
And immediately she had the injections.
A few years later she developed this symptomatology. Eventually the symptomatology became worse,
worse and she was by that time I saw her, 45 or 50 and she suffered for years.
And then she was the first who subsidized my Greek book. I had written a little book "The New Medicine" she subsidized it.
She gave the money to be published.
Hydrophobinum, high potency and the whole syndrome started going down slowly.
In one and a half year, she was almost normal.
She never needed another remedy because she had a strong constitution.
-There is a rubric 'sympathetic, felt the same pain as his brother' and Lyss. is the only remedy.
I heard about this rubric that the way came into existence was that two provers proved it and the one had
a particular pain and the other said, yes I have the same pain.
So it actually meant that they had the same physical symptoms but in the Repertory says sympathetic attitude.
Can you comment on that?
-What I have seen, as I said, is the abusiveness and at the same time the sensitivity towards the pain. But I cannot say.
This is a peculiar symptom and you write it but it's not my experience. Not everything which is written here
is my experience but if it's a strange rubric, then I give it, maybe you may need it some time.
-By many homeopaths Lyss. is described like a victim. For example Sankaran and others...
-Maybe you misread the paragraph, not possible. You misunderstood.
-They are feeling tormented all the time and this aggressive reaction is only a defence.
-I understand. If you take the words of the Repertory and you try to augment this without the knowledge...
what is happening really is that they are very demanding.
So if they don't get what they want, they feel they're tormented. It's a different thing all together as a concept.
My husband has done this for me and that, that's why I have a young man now outside of the marriage.
They feel that they don't get treated as they should be. It is not the idea of the victim, the idea of the dog that attacks.
This is the main idea.
How is that they become such whimpers when they see somebody suffering and you see very strange things?
This woman, they would give me the information, she was very abusive. She was also using the other people like this...
At the same time she would be very sensitive to some others that according to her they were suffering.
And she could not tolerate their suffering.
But definitely not the victim. You take this word and with imagination, you make it... he is tormented, he is the victim.
No, he is not the victim at all. The others are victims. I can assure you about that.
-Is it anyway similar to Anac. that could be so violent and so sensitive?
-That's a good point to differentiate.
Anac. is also hard and rude but it's hard and rude when he is not seen.
In people or animals to which he has absolute control.
Who is the people who have absolute control? Only your children and your animals.
To the children and the animals, they can be very rude but this remedy, Lyss. is authoritative. It has self confidence.
The other one is without any self confidence. So the hardness or the rudeness or the desire to give pain
in order to feel some feelings is when they know they can do it.
With Lyss. forget it. For instance it's the husband who will get whatever they think and will just...
tell the husband, tell the authorities... there is an abusive element.
A rabid dog will attack anything, a lion, a bicycle, a car, whatever. It's more or less the same situation.
-Would you also think of Lyss. in cases of dogs or cats for example who have been vaccinated against rabies
but do not show this fear of leaving the house or other symptoms you just mentioned?
-Why to give it to the cats or dogs unless they show signs of extreme attack, extreme violence?
After having been vaccinated, maybe you can try. It's not my experience but I would think of it in case the dog
is very aggressive or has become very aggressive after vaccination.
Because the nature of some dogs is to be aggressive. But if after vaccination, then they are aggressive,
then you try Stram. and you try Lyss.
-I'd like to know if it is claustrophobia or agoraphobia? Because you said he can't go out of the house.
-Agoraphobia and claustrophobia is both in Lyss.
And especially they will feel it here, agoraphobia which you feel that you are chocked.
-I would be interested to know whether dogs which have been vaccinated against rabies, can transfer this on to people?
-It's not been recorded such an instant, I don't know, it has not been in my attention.
The woman who is coming this afternoon, you can ask this question.
-Would you give it to human being who had been bitten by a dog who has rabies?
-And the human being survived?
-Immediately after the bite instead of getting the injection.
-No, no.
First of all immediately after the bite you don't know whether the dog had... because the dog has to be killed
and examined to see whether it had rabies.
So if you give it in any case, I don't know. It's a very virulent virus.
It's the same thing as if you give a dose of hydrocyanic acid.
Can you save this person by giving a homeopathic remedy? No.
Because the poison is too virulent and cannot be counteracted by the homeopathic remedy.
It's almost like poisoning of the blood.
-It seems for me to be a little strange to see that a rabid dog will bite really but Lyss. patient  only has some
virulence in words. Because you often see a similarity between real remedy in the nature and the patient
but now it's different  it's not really biting, only barking I think.
-Only barking but very badly.
You can understand what happened to me. I was with a medical doctor and we were abused actually
because before I found the remedy, several months elapsed. And she was not getting better.
And every time she would say, 'well you have made me travel and go through this torment, coming here
and here I am the same as before'.
I said, 'oh god she is coming today.
Please God show me the remedy'.
It is terrible and especially if you are Carb-an.
If you are Carb-an., because you don't have energy...
Carb-an. is one of the remedies that do not have stamina. And they have a basic weakness, their will power
has gone down their stamina has gone down, their mental power has gone down.
And what will happen with such case? They are like a nice old man.
That means you can do whatever you like with him. You can abuse and if you are a homeopath and you are
in a Carb-an. state that weak state, then she will telephone you and say, I want to see you. You are exhausted...
you are finished and you don't have any more energy and you say OK.
This remedy takes a lot of the abuse of others and the will of others upon you.
Because of the definite weakness and there is a kind of a desire for this remedy to do his duty.
To do whatever he has to do, properly.
Then people can take advantage, especially if you are in a position of a doctor. They can take advantage
and they can say, 'I need to see you tonight'. And you have appointments up to 12 o'clock.
You say can you come at 12.30? Yes I will come at 12.30, they don't ask you.
I have been several times in that condition where people will telephone while I'm eating, while I'm dreaming and I keep on talking.
I don't say I'm eating now, would you please...
For instance Lyss. will never ask you, even if she hears you are just chewing, it doesn't matter, they will say the problem.
And you are trying to swallow and to listen to this, it's terrible.
You see the pathology is such that you get all these poisons from the effects of the outside, which
the organism cannot process.
The lymphatic system which processes the toxins is not working properly and that is why it will develop
so much malignancy in the lymphatic system, lymph nodes become enlarged.
And then you will have of course malignancy as an end stage on the lymphatic system.
Once these abcesses develop there is a terrible burning feeling, exhaustion, burning feeling, gland swollen
and you see the life is going away from that person. You can keep him alive for a period of time with Carb-an.
Carb-an. also is a hot or cold remedy?
It must be cold.
By the time they go to bed, then they become very chilly.
They have to cover very much to warm up, why? Because they lie down and the organism stays immovable, there is no heat.
On the contrary there is coldness and it develops more and more and then they develop chills.
So they will say, I feel cold. In which condition? Especially when I lie in bed. It's the main remedy for that symptom
and it's a keynote, a symptom on which you can rely.
The weakness will be very much more if you lose blood.
Women losing the blood every month, during this period of menses they feel very weak.
In Carb-an. we don't have anxiety about health, we don't have fear of death and we have the pushing of the organism
towards the limit.
The individual does not have the trigger, the necessary mechanism that stops them from going further and further.
And there seems to be a lack in the will power. The individual thinks I don't have enough strength to say no...
to stop when I have to stop.
Diabetes, many times you have abcesses they don't close and if the individual is cold and especially
having chills when going to bed, then that is a case of Carb-an.
Hodgkin's disease Carb-an., as long as the pains are burning with coldness, with lack of desire to live.
If I live or I die it's the same thing. That is unnatural. The individual must be afraid of death.
If you are not afraid of death in a case where you should, that is a symptom.
And if you are afraid of death without any reason, that is even worse symptom.
You will see some headaches. Feels as if blown into pieces. He has to sit up at night and hold it together.
Also many times because they keep feelings inside, they don't shout.
The natural tendency will be for an organism who is so tired, when somebody is pressurized to say, leave me alone.
Like Nux-v.
Nux-v. when they have reached their limits and somebody is demanding from them, they can explode...
the same with Sepia. This remedy, no. And therefore the stomach is of the main seat of disturbance...
and cancer may develop, stomach cancer, lymphs are very easily swollen.
You get a Carb-an. and he has submaxillary lymph nodes swollen for years, with this weakness pushing himself.
You do this, I do this, I do that,  and then the lymph nodes develop until...
you realize what is the remedy and you give
it and then they can protect themselves.
They say no, I stop now.
-A Carb-v. which is not in an acute state how would be differentiate because both seem to be indicated in older people.
Is it the fanning or lack of lymphatics been affected in Carb-v?
- Carb-an. will not have that desire for fanning, I've not seen it where with Carbo-v. the desire to fan is very strong.
Both are white, both are bluish in their lips...
and Carbo-v. also has a very fine cold perspiration which we don't see it in Carb-an.
Carb-an. is deeper than Carbo-v. It's deeper and more destructive.
You will use it much more times in cancer than Carbo-v.
-I have seen some cases of Carb-an. where the patients are very sympathetic towards their parents or their sisters.
Is it right?
-Yes, that's correct. This is what I say, they sympathizing with the suffering of others. That's why they can be pushed
the homeopath or the doctor to exert himself and to do.
And if it is the sister or somebody in the family that is even more strong.
Also they feel the circulation is not strong, the circulation is just supplying blood to the brain and they can be having
that symptom of fear that they may faint. Fear of fainting without fear of death.
For instance Lac-c. has fear of fainting
but then it becomes great fear of dying.
Carb-an. has fear of fainting but without fear of death.
It's almost a physical symptom.
-Two times I had a very interesting experience with Carb-an. in extreme situations.
The one time was a very severe heart attack and the person showed as if she was dying and she got Carb-an.
a C30 and after 5 minutes she was very well.
-What were the symptoms?
-She was very pale and she had cold sweat and her breath was very slow.
The next time was in the beginning of my homeopathic study and it was a patient with very strong pain on his neck.
His orthopedic doctor always gave him pain killers intravenously.
And I gave him the same medication and he developed an anaphylactic shock.
And he looked as if he would die any minute.
And with Carb-an. recovered, that was very good.
-Well Carb-an. and Carbo-v. are both on the verge of fainting.
What I have seen is that the one is just fainting, the other one is understanding that I will not make it.
Carbo-v. does not have the time to understand.
Carb-an. more staying alive with the fear of fainting in that respect.
Also Carb-an. does not need that.
-He told the sympathy to sister and mother. It must be related to home sickness because the home sickness
is very strong. And Geukens said he knows people where they have to leave their country for example
from Russia to Israel  and they died of cancer because they could not be away from home.
That is true. I forgot to stress this point. It is a major aspect in the Carb-an. pathology, like Ph-ac.
In the chronic pathology, you get this tremendous urge to go back home, to the original home where they were born
where they were playing as children and if they have left the place, then they can develop very strongly
this home sickness element.
Very good that you mentioned that because I'm in Carb-an. state...