The main idea with Calad. is that we have over excitability, sexual excitability.
Easy sexual excitability but no potency.
Therefore it will be a good remedy for impotency.
One of the main remedies together with, which are the other remedies for impotency?
You just remember 3 remedies in the impotency. Calad. Lyc. and Staph.
Agn. also but very seldom an Agn. case.
Much more frequent will be Lyc., then Staph., then Calad.
The history that you will hear is that young men, especially men, they have great desire for sex which also
can go to sexual deviations. Because of over excitability, they can go to sexual deviations but at the same time
there is sexual deviation and excitability,
and at the same time  you have a kind of impotency.
For instance, I will give you an example.
They are very excitable when they meet with a woman and they start having a sexual intercourse.
During this sexual intercourse, the penis relaxes and the interest goes, it just goes away.
That becomes usually a number one problem for this young man where the erection stops and  also the pleasure stops.
The characteristic is that, for instance if they try to masturbate, while they are doing it, before they have an orgasm
in the middle of this masturbation process, the penis relaxes, they lose all the interest.
They become almost nervous wrecks.
What they will do? The desire is so much and yet it's cut off.
-Smoking.
-Smoking? Actually the cases which I have seen are Greek cases and they all smoke.
I just want to give you the peculiarities and to see how you differentiate one remedy from another.
Because you have several remedies which they lose interest or the penis relaxes with the sexual act like Nux-v.
It is also over excitable, the moment they start coition, it is gone.
Calad. they continue and I have found out something very interesting, what they have described.
They try with mental power to keep the penis in erection.
They will try mentally to stay in erection where eventually the organism gives up and the erection goes.
But not in the beginning. The Arg-n. and the Nux-v. they lose erection immediately, once they start going.
Especially Nux-v., they start and with immediate starting, they lose erection.
With Calad. they will lose erection after some time and while they are feeling great pleasure and great excitability
suddenly the whole thing collapses.
And then we have these cases in which we say that the people are suffering with mental depression, with impotency.
Impotency brings up a state of nervous depression and all this excitability that cannot find outlet
can bring the person in despair. And because they cannot have normal sex, they go to deviations
and they say, 'let me try to see homosexuality,
if that will make it more interesting'.
Eventually they may go into a kind of depression, where in the back of their mind is always the idea that
they cannot have normal sex and they can behave totally crazy.
They like a woman, they get excited and yet they are terrified to go to bed with her.
Because they feel, if I go to bed I lose face and I'll make a fool of myself.
Later on, they go to the state where they become indifferent towards sex and you will have men saying that
I have stopped even trying to have sex, since many years.
Yet the excitability and the desire becomes bigger. It's not that they lose the desire and they say
OK I lost the desire, forget it.
The desire remains, the impotency
remains, they go into depression.
I remember cases where they said, for instance a young man after trying different kinds of sex
homosexual, not homosexual, all kind of deviations he did not act normally in his function and decided sex
is not good for me and he finished with sex.
So they come to us with digestive problems, with heart problems, with palpitation and they have forgotten about sex.
And you give them Calad. if you see that picture, how they came to that depression and they start getting interested in sex
and then they can perform.
There are some peculiarities also.
You will see here fear of cutting himself while shaving.
This you can say, it is a fear that everybody may have, no they don't. This is a strange fear because
they never cut themselves and every time
they shave, they feel oh I may cut myself.
There is also an anxiety about their health which they will make them go to the doctor and attach themselves
to the doctor because they feel more security by having a contact.
You will give Staph. usually because suppressed sex and impotency, you will give other remedies
before you come down to Calad.
If you get this general idea, then you may catch the remedy.
Otherwise the fear of being cut in shaving you will find it but it is a rare symptom.
If you find it, it's great but it is a rare symptom.
When Kent describes Calad. he says, it belongs to people who have a lot of sexual activity
and then they become impotent.
They are totally impotent, you see the excitability that gives you the idea.
They see a woman in the street, they observe her and with their fantasy they almost have sex with her and then
they have an orgasm, without erection.
This is an extreme case, a little bit too extreme, Kent was describing because maybe he saw 1 or 2 cases like this.
It is not a state which you will really find in every case of Calad.
Today just watching a woman and having an orgasm is a very seldom phenomenon but the idea is that
the excitability is much, where the potency is very low.
A woman also has the same problem, great excitability and during the intercourse, they lose interest.
It becomes almost impossible to continue with the sexual intercourse, they say please stop.
In the middle, where there was excitement, then suddenly you see the woman becomes totally disinterested
and she cannot, she says stop please.
I know what you're thinking but it's wrong and then the man will ask why, what is happening and the woman
is a nervous wreck because she knows
that happens again and again.
And she does not know why and you see the organism is depleted of energy.
It comes to the mental depression here.
This mental depression is accompanied
also by very weak memory.
They have to write down everything that they have to do; otherwise they will forget very easily what they need to do.
It's a disturbance which affects all levels and usually they will not come for impotency.
I found out the Calad. cases, they have been doing this for years and they have decided or they have suppressed.
I remember another case, a young man said he was reprimanded so much in his young age for teasing the women
for doing things like that, for masturbation, they parents they have seen him.
They reprimanded him so much that he
felt he should not do anything about it.
When he was a little bit older he found
out that he could not really perform.
Later on he decided this is not good for society so therefore forget about sex.
When he came to us he was a mental wreck with all kinds of fears, anxiety about health, they become
almost hypochondriacal.
Their memory is failing and everything is breaking down.
It's very interesting to see the reappearance of the sexual function, how it comes under Calad.
Together with the failing of the memory, together with the mental depression, we usually have sleeplessness.
And the sleeplessness is of the type that they are afraid to go into sleep. They remain awake for long period of time.
And if they do go to sleep, after a few hours, they're getting up. They don't have enough sleep to recover.
Characteristic is that they're bothered by flies. If there are flies in the room, they will always go to the Calad.
The reason is that they have sweat which is sweet, sweat with most probably a lot of sugar inside
that's why it says Calad. is bothered by flies. And if you ask, they will never say it as a symptom but if you ask
they will say yes, it's very strange all the flies will come to me. It's because the sweat is sweet.
Sensation of something crawling or an insect in the face.
Calad. also will be indicated in eruptions around the genitalia, like the Anac.
They have coldness of single parts of the body.
Eruptions around the genitalia, eruptions
in the vagina itching within the vagina
which brings also a feeling
of voluptuous scratching.
Also these organisms are affected a lot by smoking. Smoking is like poison for them.
It's not that they have an aversion.
Ignatia has an aversion to smoking. If they smell a little bit, they cannot. Spig. also.
They are affected by smoking, they become worse by smoking. Smoking aggravates them.
That is the reason for instance that sometimes they say, give Calad. so they can stop smoking. This is a proving of Calad.
You understand? They found out that if you give constantly Calad. 30, every day, eventually the organism makes
a proving and smoking makes the person
feel bad and eventually they drop smoking.
That's nonsense because it is not a curative action, it is superficial; the moment you stop taking Calad.
then the craving for tobacco will come back.
During the course I will give you one or two cases of Calad. to see if you will recognize them.
I don't want to give it to you now because I give you the idea but this idea you have to recognize it within the context of a case.
Tongue swollen with an excess of saliva can
be of course a symptom of Merc. as well.
The Calad. people I have noticed that maybe they smoke but smoking makes so much worse their system.
Eventually they damage the bronchi and there is a burning sensation which stays there for years.
They stop smoking and yet this damage that was done stays for years.
With the sexual neurasthenia, with the mental depression, with the memory failing, with the insomnia
towards what pathology they will be going?
-Towards mental case.
-Yes but what kind?
-Towards arteriosclerosis in the brain.
-Also they can go towards Alzheimer's disease.
Do you have a theory of why Alzheimer's is so much an epidemic today?
There are so many cases of Alzheimer's today, they are talking about hundreds of thousands of cases.
People who can live for many many years, they don't die and they count them on the life expectancy level.
-Because mostly the physical symptoms are treated but not the emotional and the mental sphere
and somehow our soul is starving.
It does not get enough food and so this is expressed on the mental sphere.
-I feel that the problem of Alzheimer's is a very complicated one and it's a product or a by product
of the way we live, the anxieties in which we are living the insecurities plus the medications that we are receiving.
And the whole race actually is pushed in this way towards a condition in which the mental is totally destroyed.
And they come to us and they say, can you cure Alzheimer's? It's not a matter of Homeopathy curing Alzheimer's.
It's a matter of the whole society, changing course of actions.
So don't fall into such traps as answering such questions. Say no, who cures Alzheimer's? Give me somebody
who cures Alzheimer's and then we also cure Alzheimer's.
But what we see with Homeopathy, there are certain types of people, one of which is Calad. that are going towards that state.
And with Calad. we can prevent or we can prolong the coming of Alzheimer's. That we  can do.
But once the problem is established, forget it. At least for the cases that I have tried to treat in Alzheimer's
I can only keep them on a level.
Then at a certain point you treat them for some time and they stay on the same level or a little bit better but they are not happy.
Then they try the other drugs and you see immediately they go down.
And all what they gained, is lost within months. All what they gained in 3 years of treatment, they lose in 1,2,3 months.
So you see how difficult it is to measure things like that because they say OK, if we have given these drugs
from the beginning, he might have been better.
So you can never win, you can never prove the efficacy of Homeopathy.
-The initial Calad. there seems to be a little difference between Sel. which also has reduced potency
but excessive sexual desire, so what would differentiate if debility comes in both?
-Sel. will not have that kind of sexual excitability. Sel. may have dribbling of the sperm, especially during stool
but not the real excitability.
These people are really sexual maniacs.
You have to have that element of sexual over excitability to prescribe Calad.  together with the impotency.
-Do you recommend to put it in the rubric 'sexual desire-easily excited'? It's not there.
-Absolutely.
Very easily excited.
-A case of Calad. this was a woman, she was 43 years old and she had been treated for a period of 12 years
with antimycotic medication for constant infection and itching of the vagina.
I was searching for the correct remedy for 3 years, I didn't find it and only because of her husband I finally found it.
He said, every time her belly or her abdomen gets cold, her feet cramp and I found this rubric and it only
contains two remedies; one of them is Calad.
This woman was very anxious about her health. for 12 years she had been living on a sugar-free diet and she always
complained of coldness of the abdomen but only of the abdomen.
I couldn't find out anything about her sexual life. The only thing I ever heard that came through her sister in law
and she had told her sister in law, I'm not going to tell them everything.
-That's a good point because there is another point with Calad.  They are very shy talking about their sexual matters.
For instance, if one makes a remark to them that maybe you have homosexual tendencies, this is so hurting
so deep going because of his gesture or whatever a friend says, I think you have homosexual tendencies.
If you just do it like that in a Calad. case, it goes inside and they feel such shyness that they have described it
as if somebody is grinding on their soul or on their bones.
I feel such shyness inside and they will not talk about it. I have cases that they have taken years before they tell me
and you give other remedies.
But the shyness element concerning sexual behavior is very great, it seems that they have   a guilt
concerning their desires for sex.
You know the Americans call kinky sex,
they are the types that have these ideas.
Bomb them with a bomb of Calad. so they come back to normal.
Also it's very interesting, we say that we have remedies that select an organ to do its action, like the liver or the lungs.
Here we have the sexual organs where the main impact is and it's very interesting that a little girl she develops worms there.
That means there is already a weakness in the area. And the fungus infection.
There is a weakness in the area of such people.
And it will be interesting of course to get information like if he was insisting in this case, what type
of sexual contacts she was doing?
He will have much more information about the type of sex, she was involved.
But it is interesting that again comes the shyness in talking about these things in this remedy.
Another remedy which is very shy?
Silica is a very shy remedy, they will not talk. Also Bar-c., they will not talk. Also Nat-m., they will not talk.
Especially about their sexual contact.
Nat-m. get excited for instance with saying obscene words during the sexual intercourse.
That excites them tremendously the Nat-m., they will never tell you. They are very shy to discuss about these matters.
Platina on the other hand they can tell, Orig. they will tell you all kinds of things. Lyc. also.
Lyc. they speak easily about their sexual
conduct or misconduct or sexual problems.
Calad. is not one of them.
Caps. is a remedy that is a specific for inflammation of mastoid process. A specific.
The first remedy that you are thinking.
I have given it several times and only one time failed and I had to give  Aur. for that case.
They will have an effect in mastoiditis in any case. Also if the person is fat and flabby like Calc.
And they're sentimental and emotional but more especially if they express this feeling of nostalgia for their old times
where they lived, where the parents are, where the home is what we call in general homesickness.
Fat, flabby and homesick and at the same
time if they are awkward in their behavior.
When we say homesickness is not the usual. Everybody from time to time may be homesick.
With Caps. it is a tremendous homesickness. They lose totally the present. They go into the past with a nostalgia
which is so strong, so powerful
that almost it is as if this can kill them.
A nostalgia so strong that they feel they are melting away. Something intangible, something they cannot reach anymore.
The mind goes back. They had a love affair and they have their youth and how they played, the mind goes back
and sticks there. There is a feeling that they think they are going to die. I can't stand that feeling, it's so strong, so powerful.
Out of the three remedies which they have strong homesickness, which is Caps., Carb-an. and Ph-ac.
out of the three remedies Caps.
is the one which is strongest.
It says with strong letters, sleeplessness from homesickness.
They lie in bed and this is a burning out of the organism.
Tub. has a similar condition. Tub. will have a nostalgia and an impulse to leave the place and go to another place.
It's a similar situation but not exactly
because you can be confused.
Tub. of course will be rather slim, they are quite plump. Obesity is one of the main problems with Caps.
They have that same burning inside of the yearning of Tub.
They think they cannot live anymore. They lie in bed and all the time this feeling is so strong that they cannot go to sleep.
Of course this is another keynote, by coughing they feel pain in distant parts; they cough, they have a pain in the knee
or pain in the bladder or in the elbow.
This is a peculiar symptom in the way that he described coldness of the abdomen, at the same time cramps
on legs for Calad. It's a peculiar
symptom which gives the remedy.
Desire for pepper is another strong symptom which also has it another remedy which has desire for pepper.
Lac-c., they take red pepper and they can eat it. I asked a woman, I said no you will not eat this red pepper.
She said, give it to me.
We had her as a guest, she was taking the salt and putting a lot of salt. I said, do you like pepper? Yes. How much?
We had this little small red peppers that if you touch them, just touching them it burns the whole head.
She took the pepper, she started to eat.
I said, oh my god. I know your remedy.
Little things like that. It has to be very strong. The desire is much and they can eat it, they can tolerate it.
-Whenever it says desire for pepper in the Repertory, it means chilli peppers or just normal black pepper?
-It means both, the burning mostly is the idea, that they need that stimulation of burning.
But honestly the eating of that is unbelievable.
-In Israel we can eat it. At least half the country is like that.
-I will bring 7 peppers for the Israelis in here to see if anyone can eat this.
-We are in the other half.
-I make a test, a research project to see how many of the Israelis can take this red pepper I'm talking about.
Just eating this without even having any kind of lacrimation.
In India is different. In India is a culture since eons for this. They have the genes to assimilate that. India is different.
I'm talking about ordinary people like us.
Who can eat chili pepper like this?
Thirsty after stool, also it's a peculiar keynote that you have to take into consideration.
Also the indolence in this case, the mind is really  flabby, the mind is not functioning and it's indolent, lazy.
They don't want to think. Caps. is not good for homeopathic study.
Because they have to be alert all the time and they cannot.
I prescribed one of the first cases, when I returned back to Greece, I had some medical doctors working with me.
So one would come in the morning, the next in the afternoon, the third in the evening, they would stay with me
and they would suppose to be learning Homeopathy.
I would tell the remedy, they would write the prescription, in the meantime learning Homeopathy.
One of them, plump one, after a few times he said, I leave you my prescription pad and you write the remedy.
He was coming to leave me the prescription pad and he was leaving. I could understand that it was too much
for him to watch what the patient was saying.
He was coming from Cyprus actually. He was living in Greece but coming originally from Cyprus.
One day as we talked because I wanted to see why he is doing that, he is not interested really?
Then we talked about and he said...
'I'm always homesick for Cyprus. I live here in Greece but always I'm homesick for Cyprus'.
I saw his indolence, fat, flabby, I said give me your pad.
He was so well after that. For years he remained without any need in any other remedy.
Just little things like that but they go right to the essence.
You don't need to remember too much. Just remember the crux.
-Mr. Vithoulkas may I ask a question regarding this feeling of homesickness with the old people?
I had a case of an old lady, 78 years old, she is quite fat, she was complaining about pains in her joints.
Burning pains and she is quite fastidious, so it was natural for me to prescribe Ars. But nothing happened.
At the same time she also told me that she used to have 6 big cups of coffee per day.
During this interview she was constantly talking about that life now is really bad and those time when it was
the old Russia, Soviet Union life was much better and since that time her husband died and the Perestroika
and so on and she has no future, nothing good is going to happen in this country.
Could it be such cases of these old people who cannot adjust to the new environment in the country
when it changes and they always try to remember how good it was?
-I will tell you. Usually they have burning pains like the pepper, but may be other pains.
But I will not think of Caps. in this case because the nostalgia is not a complaining.
A Caps. will not complain, life was better then. It is a feeling. There, my home and they remember, the love affair.
They almost killing the emotions, they cannot talk about it.
This is a real problem you have in Russia because many people at this moment, as Russia has not found itself yet
many people are feeling what the hell with all that capitalism, it was better with communism.
So it's not a matter of what I'm talking.
What I'm talking is a feeling.
How can I describe this? It's very difficult
to give you exactly the situation.
Like you have pain, so deep in your soul that you cannot anymore live with what you have been living with in the past.
It's not a despair, a sweet pain, longing.
Very sentimental but it can kill you.
It feels 'I can't stand it, I will die with that feeling'.
It is so strong, that is a Caps. situation.
I remember also from my experience, I had taken Caps. once and I felt that what others they were telling me, I felt it.
Suddenly I had that enormous nostalgia for the past. I'm somebody who forgets my past totally, back is finished
I never think about it. Suddenly it came back all this. I said, my god I can't live with that feeling, it's so strong
I'm going to die.
It was just for a few hours. It passed
the next day. But it was fantastic!
Suddenly my past came.
I could remember like a film.
I had forgotten all that and suddenly everything was coming back, an unbelievable nostalgia.
So when I see it, immediately I pick it up.
It's good also from time to time to try some remedies, if you have good health.