Eup-per. is a remedy that has the picture of influenza when influenza is affecting all the muscles of the body.
When you have a generalized muscular pain with the feeling of malaise that influenza is producing, nevermind
in what type of disease whether it is diarrhea, hepatitis, influenza or cold, then the Eup-per. is the remedy.
What is the difference between Eup-per. and Rhus-t. because you will confuse these two remedies, quite strongly.
It is several differences.
First of all the Rhus-t. is much more restless and much more worse from cold.
This remedy is not ameliorated by motion as is Rhus-t.
Though the muscular pain is stronger in this remedy, much stronger and in Rhus-t. you will see a lot of stiffness as well.
This remedy is something between Rhus-t. and Bry.
Eup-per. is a remedy worse from motion, is a thirsty remedy...
whereas Rhus-t. usually is not thirsty. It is thirstless. Sometimes Rhus-t. is also thirsty.
But here in Eup-per. you will not see the typical restlessness of Rhus-t. where it turns, is a bit better, then it has to move again.
Here is rather painful but they prefer to stay in one place.
But all the muscles till the bones, the pain feels right inside the bones.
The whole body and the malaise and weariness is very strong. It has the same reaction to coughing as Bry.
They feel very painful in coughing.
We say, it holds the chest. It holds the chest because the pain is very strong and the movements
of the pain makes it stronger.
Which is more of the two?
Is Bry. in this respect pain from coughing
or Eup-per.? Which is worse?
Bry. is worse. So when you have ... it is very obvious, then you will think ...
Because there is thirst and in Bry. will not be so much pain in the muscle. The muscular pain will be less for Bry.
This is the strongest remedy for muscular pain, the strongest in the Materia Medica.
It feels broken. The joint feels broken. The pain is right to the bones.
Where Bry. is not so sore in her skeleto-muscular structure.
It says 'delusions, he had walked along distance'. It is not a delusion.
When they describe the pain, they will describe it as if you had exerted and the muscles are very painful. It's not a delusion.
And delusions that will go out of the mind. It is a state in which the individual says, 'I think I will go out of the mind '
which is the same as fear of insanity.
It is not a delusion, it's wrong word but it is written in the text. But I'm explaining it to you.
In the text is written like this but what actually means is that sometimes you hear patient saying
'I think I will lose my mind'.
And they say delusion. It's not a delusion. Delusion is something different.
The painfulness in the eyeballs, the painfulness can affect also the muscular structure of the eyeball.
When they turn the eyes, they feel painful.
You have to understand the malaise feeling, the pain, the bone pain that goes inside, the muscular pain
and the pain affects all the muscles, even the eyeball muscles.
This remedy is ameliorated quite strongly with perspiration. Perspiration ameliorates the pain.
This symptom vomiting of bile during and after chill is of no importance really but it appears as a keynote
which I have not seen but if you ever find it, you can use it.
Bruised feeling as if broken bones all over the body, this is the idea with Eup-per.
Moans with aching pain. Of course if you
pain so much, sure. The pain is too much.
-Trends to Arn. this feeling of being broken.
-Arn. has totally different picture. The pain is in the surface for Arn.
In the surface of the skin. That is why the idea is 'don't touch me!'.
This boy/girl here you can touch them
you can hold them, it's no problem.
With Arn. you will see the immediate touch... That means the pain is centered in the surface.
It might be very strong pain but it's a different kind of pain all together.
It's a thin pain. Here is a thick pain, a deep pain, it goes inside.
In Arn. you have to have in a flu, let us say where you will compare, the painfulness on the surface.
Euphr. is a remedy which you will recognize
by looking in chronic conditions of Euphr.
In acute conditions also, why?
Because all the force of the disease is upon the conjunctiva.
The eyes become red, burning, lacrimating.
At the same time the nose is running but the focus of the disease is on the conjunctiva.
The eyelids they stick together, they are inflamed, the conjunctiva is inflamed, it's burning.
There is chronic condition when the eyes are affected, the conjunctiva is the main remedy.
At the same time it can have a feeling of malaise. The head feels dizzy and full and sick.
The whole head in a flu, in an influenza, in a cold, the whole head feels very heavy, very dizzy.
It cannot think and the eyes are red and lacrimating.
And the nose is running. The nose runs but it's not burning.
While the tears are so burning, the nose discharge is not burning at all.
They have a symptom which would look like Puls. where they get better in the open air. They need fresh air.
Especially in the head.
And they are better washing with cold water, for a few minutes. If they wash with cold, they feel better.
The same like Puls.  You get headaches in the Puls. and they put a cold application for a while and they feel better.
The head is full and dizzy and I don't know if I give you the idea of the head...
When the eyes are burning and you don't want to think.
The head is full, headache is there.
You lie down with Euphr., it becomes worse.
But it is not a matter of immediate being worse. You lie down and a whole situation becomes
worse and worse and you try to sleep. Then you get up, you go, you refresh, you put some water
and then you try to lie down again. Lying down is worse.
Though if this inflammation goes down to the larynx and you start coughing and you have intense coughing
this coughing is not anymore worse in the night.
It is the opposite. It's worse only in day time.
Fl-ac. in its mental-emotional sphere represents the degeneration in the moral sphere.
Degeneration, what do I mean by that?
They are sexually very easily excited individuals. They are enjoying very much and you understand that
if you overdo this then eventually it becomes degeneration.
This is the time when sexual matters are treated in a very materialistic, physical way.
Stimulation of the physical level, absolutely.
I had a case typical and I could not get the remedy. Then he was describing his sexual life and I said, what is happening?
He said, sometimes I wake up in the morning and I don't know who is the person whom I slept with
what is her name, who is this person?
That kind of sexual behavior. It's a degenerated kind of behavior.
There is an inner anxiety eventually which
leads to strong anxiety about health
and anxiety of conscience that does not allow  the person to relax and sleep.
Who gets anxiety about their health?
Phos., Ars., Arg-n., Agar., Calc.
This is also one of those remedies which can lead to tremendous anxiety with the fear that something
will happen to their brain. It will be having
a brain stroke and they will be distorted.
You know how in a brain stroke the face is paralyzed and it is distorted?
Shall I get this? Shall I remain like this in the rest of my life? This kind of things and they cannot sleep
they cannot go and relax and sleep.
It takes them 2,3,4 hours before they go to sleep and if they go to sleep, they wake up early.
It's a remedy that affects the varicose veins. Varicose veins are quite strong feature with this remedy.
This symptom 'runs like a faucet', what it means is they sit and the nose runs constantly with no stoppage, water.
Another strong point with Fl-ac. is the falling of the hair in spots.
Sometimes you have the state of alopecia areata but this is not necessary.
To reach that state of alopecia. It's just falling in a place.  In a place you see the hair it has been very rare.
In alopecia you see a place with no hair. In this you see a place with a few hair.
Not thinning, less hair. There is a place with less hair than the other place.
They are suffering from heat and sometimes Puls. will be confused with Fl-ac., why?
Puls. has a lot of varicose veins, aggravated by heat and this remedy has the same.
We have an easy decay of the teeth with cavities.
-Sometimes you get in Fl-ac., like in Nat-c., you get a sensitivity in both, cold and heat but mostly is heat.
-I ask for one symptom. It is a patient who is compelled to move about energetically? What does that mean?
-It's a restlessness but brisk restlessness like this.
It is a restlessness but not simple, it's more with energy. This remedy has a lot of energy to spend.
I have seen in this case people with tremendous sexual energy and they cannot control it at all.
That energy may come as a restlessness which has a lot of energy.
-George what complains do they have? With what they come to the doctor?
-Different. Except of these ulcerations, venous stasis, varicose veins, hemorrhoids, sleeplessness, anxiety.
If it is on the mental level, you will get extreme anxiety with sleeplessness mostly.
If it's on the physical you will get decay of the teeth, decay of the veins.
-Does that sexual energy always have to be there or can it be that with young people maybe this energy
is shown in restlessness?
-In physical energy yes also. But, as I said, they are easily excited. They start from young age, having sexual
pleasures this is a remedy which enjoys
very much sexuality, sexual pleasures.
Eventually they enter into a state of fear of dying, fear of what is going to happen to me, what is going to happen in my health?
They try, as much as possible, to keep a good health, to enjoy further.
It's a remedy which is centered around itself quite a lot.
-How do we differentiate from Lyc. on the mental-emotional?
-First of all, these guys here they are not afraid at all.
They can go and meet the Queen of England or they can meet the Prime Minister and no problem.
Secondly, on sexual energy Lyc. is much more on a superficial level. There is a superficial sexual energy in Lyc.
Once they overdo it, they lose the energy
and the capacity and they become impotent.
That's why Lyc. is one of the most frequently indicated remedy in impotency in men together with Staph.
Staph. for another reason, not because she or he overdid it but because of the opposite reason.
Staph., you see a man who comes with impotency but he is shy and he says, 'I like my wife
but I cannot have sex with her'.
Do you like other women? Maybe you like another woman and that's why you feel impotent.
He says, 'no I like my wife, I want to go with my wife and I cannot'. This answer you will never get it from Lyc.
Lyc. will say 'yes I'm impotent with my wife. How do you know? I can be very excited but if I try to go
a few more times, then I'm impotent again'.
This is the story of Lyc. The story of Fl-ac. is never mind what, I can go with this woman.
-How do you differentiate between Plat.
and this remedy in sexual desire?
-First of all this remedy is down to earth; that means no grandeur ideas, it's a materialist. Let's go to bed now.
And this remedy is satisfied. That means it has sex, enjoys sex and it's OK.
With Plat. there is a lack of deeper enjoyment where it leaves out something to be desired.
That is why the woman does not know if a Plat., whether she has an orgasm or not. She thinks she has an orgasm.
10 minutes later, she wants more.
Just to give you another example that comes to my mind from a recent case.
Plat., she says to us, 'during the sexual intercourse I have up to 20 orgasms'. What is this? I don't know.
You see we can only conjecture that she does not feel in depth any kind of satisfaction and there is no the normal
cycle of excitement, then a peak, then...
There is an excitement, the peak, it stays, it goes down, then up again, down, up again.
With Fl-ac. there is satisfaction and either the woman or the man they will not need to have sex repeatedly.
Next day again.
It's every day, 365 days a year. You say, my god at your age 365 days a year? 'No, no I must have it.'
-You said 365 days the year and when I was younger I thought that was normal.
-Very good. Fl-ac.!
It is correct what you said, when I was young but I'm talking for a man who is 60 years old. It's too much.
When you have started at the age of 14 and you are 60 and all these years every day you had sex
that is beyond my comprehension.
That kind of energy. I think if I had that kind of energy I would have changed the whole world.
Not spend the energy.
In Fl-ac., I feel it is a feeling of just me and my pleasures. And that's why they go eventually into that state
of tremendous anxiety about their health.
And a guilt conscience which is very deep.
When this guilty conscience will come up, will have a lot of problems.
-Why do they have guilt conscience?
-Because they do all these kinds of things but never mind what you do in the depth of your mind
there is always a kind of control, of what you are doing.
And there is a kind of critical attitude because of your conscience and they know they have done too much.
They had too much pleasure and they know that this is not correct. And therefore they develop strong guilty feelings.
They just come as pathology, the guilty feelings. The anxiety that they will die or that they have a disease
because they squander their life and things like that.
-Normally do you see them having family and children, taking responsibility?
-They may have a family but can a man like this stay married?
The men usually separate because the
wife cannot tolerate all that behavior.
The responsibility also is not very much.
They don't care about the children. Ok, they are there
we support them, give them money.
-They are usually known for weakness, if you think of Mur-ac., Pic-ac, where there is specific weakness from Fl-ac.?
-I have not seen it in Fl-ac. so much weakness, no. We cannot talk as a main feature, the weakness.
All the remedies they have weakness. If you see weakness, all the remedies are there but now if we speak
about the main features of the remedy that remedy in spite of being an Acid, I have not seen the weakness.
-Calc-f. also has a tendency to jump from bed to bed, isn't it?
-I don't know. Not as much as this remedy. This remedy is really impressive and you will not be able...
You will give Nux-v. because it's so energetic, you will give Tarent. because they are very much in a hurry
it gives you the impression. And then you give all these energetic remedies that you know and nothing helps.
And you give the Fl-ac. and then you see the veins are developing and then they can sleep.
It goes to the physical body and then they become  more quiet.