Many times you have to prescribe very quickly in a busy practice.
There are certain symptoms or signs that are almost sure that you don't need to take very thoroughly the case.
These are for children now I'm going to talk about because I have found out that in spite of the fact that there are
such signs by taking a case thoroughly,
you miss the right prescription.
If you have these keynotes which I'm going to tell you, the first remedy that you have to think and give
is the one that I will mention.
In children from babies to 12 years old, if you see perspiration here on the cervical region during sleep
strong perspiration, where the pillow becomes wet, the remedy is Calc. forget all the other remedies.
Whether it is a pneumonia, diarrhea, nephritis, epilepsy, it does not matter.
Excessive salivation which runs out of the mouth, even when the child is held in the mother's lap.
It comes with the mother and the salivation runs out not only when the child is lying down but when it's standing
like this in the mother's lap. First remedy Mercury.
You see them in the table they take salt and they put it in their mouth. What is the remedy?
The remedy is Nat-m.
But if you open the Repertory, you will see several remedies there with capital letters. None of these remedies will do this.
The only remedy that will do it is Nat-m.  Why?
Because the craving is very strong.
You examine the children and you cannot find anything and then you come and you say salt.
Salt? She takes it and eats it. Finished the case.
When you see an eruption in the nates and the perineum like the one I showed you on the video, reddish
reddish like this, if it is pale red, it is not
correct, it has to be reddish like her dress.
Medorrhinum.
Repeated vomiting in whatever case but especially with coughing.
Coughing which causes vomiting, Ip.
Children they go to bed and they rattle, especially in the middle of the night it becomes prominent
and many times they wake up also because of the noise and the noise can be heard in the room, the remedy Kali-s.
Thirst but the child seems to be afraid, it doesn't moan, it doesn't do anything but it's terrified, afraid, Phos.
Thirst with fear.
I told you, as an example, I will give you Phos. Maybe you don't understand because you have to be
to be observant in such cases.
The mother many times does not understand what is going on in the child.
She doesn't understand that the child is fearful.
I told you about this case with the meningitis, where the child was lying next to the mother and the mother
needed to hold the child's hand.
And the child was afraid to be left alone.
The parents though they were homeopaths they could not see the picture. When I went there and they gave me
all nonsense because they said meningitis and they give all this information, what is important for me is how much
water the child was asking and whether the mother could leave the child without holding the hand.
And that was a cure of meningitis the same day.
Phos.  especially the children, have fear of being left alone. They don't want to be left alone.
It says desires company. Fear of being alone.
Big warts on fingers, in the Repertory
it says, Lac-c. I say Thuja.
A lot of warts on the face, big warts, strong warts, Calc.
Moaning and groaning, children with teething, of course Cham.
But moaning and groaning and complaining, no reason for that, they cannot themselves give a reason
or you cannot find a reason, it is Calc-p.
Open fontanelles which have remained
longer than they should again Calc-p.
Moaning with digestive troubles, either vomiting or diarrhea, but the child really cannot be satisfied...
....Ant-c.
Hot head with cold feet, Bell.
You see what I say, you know. Forget that you know, what I say is when you have that symptom
you think and give this remedy. This is the idea. Otherwise most probably you're making a mistake.
Pay big attention to these symptoms.
Otherwise you will make a mistake.
Hot head but hot feet also, again with high fever and red face, because the face in Bell. is red, what is the remedy?
Acon.
The red face is there, the head is hot and then you touch the feet but the feet are hot also
and the fever is high, then the remedy Acon.
The position in children that they sleep with knee-elbow position, if it is persistent, Med.
What other remedies they sleep in that position?
Kali-c., Calc-p.
Didn't we have here the case with the child that we analyzed the Calc-p.?
Colics in children with rumbling in regular intervals, every two hours, they go away and again and again
what is the remedy?
Illicium. They used to give the old mothers the mother tincture.
Colics where the child has a lot of eructations.
Lycopodium.
Colics where you turn the child on the abdomen and it becomes quiet...
Belladonna.
Colics where you take the child and you press his feet against the abdomen and gets quiet...
Colocynthis.
Child that he cries when you put him in bed, Borx.
It doesn't matter what it is, whether it is an inflammation on the uppermost part of the digestive track
or going down with colics or aphthae, you have that symptom, don't think of another remedy.
You have to give first this remedy. You cannot get away from the remedy. Each remedy has a very characteristic symptom.
I will not say symptom, you know what we call essence. Now we reduce the essence to one symptom
to make it more practical. Especially for children. Otherwise you are lost.
If you have this, you can deal with most
of your acute cases from the telephone.
Because these things are by telephone prescription.
As you know the problem with Homeopathy is that you undertake a case chronically and then you have to treat
every little thing which is happening in the child or in the grown-up.
You have to take care of this and deal with that. It's terrible.
Because you are never paid for that. Most people they don't like, did I tell you that he had colics and you sent
this remedy and you want to be paid, what for?
Potency for all these, so far, except of Acon.  you can go higher.
I gave an example. You put the child down, never mind what it has, maybe he has aphthae
he doesn't have to have aphthae. He may have colics.
The inflammation may not be here, it might be deeper in the digestive track, wherever it might be
in the stomach, nephritis, whatever.
Fever which is not synchronous with the pulse. What that means?
It means that when you have 39 fever, the pulse should be 110. If the fever is 39 and the pulse is 75
this is not synchronous and the remedy Pyrog.
Very good, you know everything.
When you have a child who is restless and the mother says, they like very much salt and lemon, the remedy Verat.
You don't go away from this remedy.
You may have other symptoms, here and there, some keynotes local keynotes, forget it. Just give Verat.
Child catches his genitalia all the time? Hyos.
Tremendous distention, the child is bloated.
No gas, no burping.
Raphanus? It has to have pain for Raphanus. Pain in the left colic flexure, where it is incarcerated here and the pain is there.
Colchicum.
Tremendous distention of abdomen where the air does not come out, up or down, is caught inside there.
And there is dyspnea and all kinds of things. Colch.
Vomiting immediately after drinking water, Phos.
Vomiting immediately after eating.
Ferrum metallicum.
No symptoms, you have a high fever, a tonsillitis, Ferr-p.
You see high fever, you see inflammation somewhere but the organism does not produce specific symptoms, pains.
So the mother will give you this, that's all, she has a high fever. How is he doing? He walks around.
Nothing else? No.
He may have a pneumonia and you do not understand how the coughing is not strong yet etc.
Ferr-p. will cut short.
When a child wants to be caressed in the back, scratched like this, he likes it very much, that's a symptom of Sulph.
Everyone likes to be scratched in the back.
Ingrowing toenails in children, Silica.
Very offensive perspiration not only from the foot but all. The child has very offensive perspiration, not sour, offensive.
The remedy Psorinum.
If the offensive perspiration is in the feet, it's a lot of remedies; then you cannot differentiate but if the perspiration is
really offensive and the child smells badly and then you have sour perspiration, then you start to differentiate
between Calc. and Rheum.
We can continue like this and differentiate this and that remedy and then it becomes useless because
you don't remember anything. And you say, forget it, let's go to the Repertory and start all over again.
The idea is that with this information, you will be able to handle a lot of cases, acute cases that otherwise
will require a full repertorization.
It is not good for the homeopath unless is under stress, to know the pathology and prescribe on pathology.
Because if we start differentiating in diarrhea, you will see 35-50 remedies in diarrhea. Just try to remember.
And then you differentiate the bronchitis and the type of coughs, you try to remember. Forget it, this is not to be remembered.
These little things you can remember. Most of them you know already with the Materia Medica. You can keep them in mind.
But try to remember everything which is in the Materia Medica and in details like diarrhea or constipation
the types, forget it.
You will tire your mind and you will not be able to do good work.
I remember in one of the schools in Bombay Homeopathic College, there was a teacher
who could quote by heart the whole Materia Medica.
The students knew that if they go to be treated by him, could never find the remedy. He could not contact his brain
and connect the information that was there
with what he was seeing in front of him.
So you can become addicted in quoting symptoms without understanding the impact.
A good homeopath starts from basics. Learns the basics and adds with experience a little bit more, a little bit more...
And I will tell you also my experience when I started treating patients, I had 3 months of studying.
I was studying for 3 months when I first took a case and it was very successful. And then every case I took
in South Africa where I supposed to have studied all by myself, the successes it was unbelievable the success.
I can say, I lost no case. Now I can lose cases. By that time, no. Why?
Because I understood the method. I had no experience, I had no all this knowledge but I understood
what I had to do, how I had to study, how to
take a case, what was important in a case.
And I had to connect the important things, what I could see. I was observing very much every case and what is
most important, what is stressed, then
I go and read all the Materia Medica.
This remedy stresses that point, the liver,
she has the liver, give her Chel.
This is the idea. You cannot learn all the Materia Medica by heart, neither you should believe that anybody knows
all the Materia Medica by heart. It's not possible. Therefore you need only a good system and study of the case.
You see we come down to Ars. when we study her case but we came down to Ars. by thinking a lot about the case.
And then Acon. and then this, that, Phos.
and then finally something clicks.
I've told you again that in South Africa one of my first cases was a young pianist, whom I liked very much as a woman.
And I took her case and I wanted to cure her. I studied the case, no medicine. I studied the whole day
I was studying the case repertorising this way, that way, nothing. I went to bed, I slept. Next day I woke up.
As I woke up everything was in my brain.
The remedy is Ign.!
I gave Ign., it was beautiful cure.
I mean it was such the passion for finding the correct remedy that all the information stayed with me during sleep
and worked through the computer.
The moment I woke up I said the remedy ...
I had studied all angles, I was not happy, I was not satisfied, this remedy, that remedy, nothing.
Suddenly it made sense, this. Give it.
This is the idea that if you have this feeling,
the remedy going to act. Now I got it.
Many times this feeling has come, you have sat with a person, you have studied and you discussed
and suddenly you go out and friendly you speak and she says two things and make sense and you find the remedy.
It's very strange.
You have to know so much and yet the real information which you need is so little, so few.
That's why in the old times homeopaths
they would prescribe on keynotes.
And they had successes of course.
But today the pathology is so complicated and so gone inside the mental-emotional that things are not anymore
as simple as they used to be.