Cancerinum or Carcinosin whatever you like to call it, it's the same.
When do you prescribe Carc.?
Even 20-30 years ago when I was practicing, I would seldom give or think about Carc.
Today we have to think much more frequently about that remedy and not always as the main remedy.
Many times as an intermediate remedy As I have mentioned for level 3 and 4 where we use a series of remedies
Carc. and Med. are coming quite frequently in the process.
Especially when you are stuck with a case you may be thinking of Carc.
You like to have some indications when Carc.  is really indicated.
I'm trying to give you first the original picture, the constitutional picture of Carc.
Which you may recognize especially in children.
More especially children with asthma or children who repeatedly have colds and acutes.
Also children who are suffering with hay fever.
The type of the child that you will see in such a case is a child which the parents will say, what a nice child.
She is very obedient, she is very considered. She is very good in her class. I don't have to press her to study.
She is duty bound.
Immediately you get the idea of Staph. You think that this child is suppressed by the parents.
I found out this is not the case. The child by himself, by his pathology I would say, they want to please others.
They are so sensitive to the reprimands, if somebody will make a bad remark about them.
They avoid at all cost this kind of hurt.
I'm talking too fast and I see computers are getting fire and there are some others who just enjoy.
Therefore I would say the basic idea is extreme vulnerability.
The child is very vulnerable, it's like the pains  which they come in the end stages of cancer, when you have cancer
in the bones where the pain is excruciating.
If you have seen such cases, you will feel a pity because they shout, they scream, they feel the bones are broken.
In such cases of course Carc. will not be indicated. I have never given it in such a case.
I don't think it will do anything in these conditions.
What Carc.  will be indicated very frequently is when you have an extreme hereditary tendency.
The mother had cancer, the father had cancer, the uncles have cancer. In these cases where you see
the hereditary cancer is running through
the family, it's almost a must.
There is a time where you have to use Carc. Maybe not as the first remedy sometimes as a first but definitely
it's going to be a point where you will use Carc.
It's very interesting also, I have thought of Carc.   cancer is an aggressive, expansive, destructive disease.
From the point of view of the signatures if somebody was proving Carc. with his imagination will say
expansive, destructive and these ideas of cancer. We see exactly the opposite here.
Constructive people, children who are not destructive.
You know all the children are knotty, these Carc. children are never naughty. They are never doing something wrong
to displease the parents. The parents always almost invariably, will say 'such a nice child!'.
It might be a child of 18,19,20.
This is in 99% of the cases.
Now, very seldom you will meet
another type and I have mentioned it.
Another type which is a fat, insensitive and self-centered individual, who will be like a bulldozer.
Whatever is in front, he will eat, he will grab, he will steal from his mother, from his father, as long as
he can satisfy his own needs.
That child also it may meet but it is 1%.
99% is the opposite type.
Actually in the literature which I have read concerning Carc.   I have seen only one such case.
And in my experience I have two such cases.
All together they are 3 cases but we have to mention this type
as well because of the possibility.
As you may understand also these children are so sensitive, they don't like atrocities. They don't like to hear
that somebody was hurt, that somebody
had an accident, his arm was cut off.
In this respect it will remind you of another remedy which is ... Calc.
Phos. can hear about such things, no problem hearing about such things, but when he sees these things
when in front of him he will see something
he will be the first one to run and try to help.
It is somebody who is concerned about the pain of others. Here we have the vulnerability, the feeling of pain
from hearing stories like accidents,
atrocities with human beings etc.
A case of a man whose main symptom, there was only one symptom but made him impossible to work
impossible to function. He was invalid
to understand the fear of humiliation.
There was such fear of humiliation which reminds you again in such case Nat-m. usually is given.
Because you see fear of humiliation, Nat-m. is very strong. But in this case it is something beyond this.
It is much bigger, much deeper.
They cannot tolerate the least hint about something bad with them.
These children are lovable children and also they give love themselves to the parents. They also need affection.
They are the children who the parents know
they have to say a good word for them.
If they don't say it, the child still craves it but will not come out and ask.
Like Puls. will ask for affection. He will say to his mother 'hold me' or the wife will say to the husband 'hold me'.
She will ask for this affection. Puls. they need it as a physical need.
You hold her even if you do it without feelings, still it's OK. Puls. feels good. It's the idea of consolation.
They need this affection.
These children need it but they are proud at the same time. 'I do my duty, I do everything correct, so I expect that
you give me affection, you give me love,
not that I will ask you'. It's different.
So you see this remedy how it goes between Staph. between Calc., Nat-m., Puls.
Yet they don't fit to any of these pictures
really. They have a picture of their own.
Such children, as you may understand, if they are not shown the affection they expect
easily they feel 'I must have done something wrong' and a guilt feeling starts developing.
And from the fact that they will not talk you get the impression that they will suppress their feelings
they will hold back their feelings.
It's not actually a suppression because we don't see with these people the outburst of anger which we see with Staph.
Staph. will hold, hold, hold back but one time she will have such an outburst, she will start throwing things, swearing, telling things.
Sometimes we say that Staph.
could go into acute insanity episodes.
They become totally crazy
once this anger overtakes them.
They can become for a period of time totally insane.
In such cases the remedy can stop an insanity crisis from tonight by tomorrow. Tonight you give the Staph.
and tomorrow  they have come back to themselves.
If you don't give Staph.  they will find themselves to the mental clinic.
And once they start putting chemicals and things like that, then this episode may drag for months before they realize
that the person is back.
This kind of cases like Verat., Tarent. cases these cases that Kent had seen  he made that statement
for those who know, which is a little bit too much.
He said, if they let me go the insane asylums, I will take most of them out. This is not true.
Never mind whether you are Kent or whoever you are, it is not true.
What it is true is that the acute insanity
can be cut short by the correct remedy.
But the schizophrenia, hebephrenia, the that which starts as a basic disease at the age of 16,17 around that time
and then continues with hallucinations and delusions and then you get such cases at the age of 30
after 20 years or 35 or 40, forget it. It's very few cases that you may manage to bring back into sanity.
-At the age of 23?
-If immediately with the starting of the situation, you see the picture, this is Tarent., you may stop it.
-Even after some years?
-Once the years go by, schizophrenia is like a disease that destroys areas of the brain slowly, more and more
which cannot be replaced.
It is like M.S. which destroys parts of the nervous system, demyelinates parts of the nerves and that is finished
it creates a plaque at this place and then it's finished. It's almost like that. In the beginning of M.S., you have
great success with Homeopathy. Once the plaques are formed and the paralysis is established to
that degree  then the best you can do is, hold the disease.
But with schizophrenia is even more difficult, once there are years of that condition.
I have several experiences with this type of mental disorder, which even with the best selected remedy
I could see an amelioration for a period of
time and after a while, there is a relapse.
You repeat the remedy nothing happens. Maybe still we don't know the laws, maybe I had to repeat frequently.
By that time I was not repeating at all.
Maybe but my experience is that this type of mental disorder is very difficult to handle. Unless it's acute insanity
in which case you have fantastic results.
With these children, especially those who do not have this rapport with the parents, children who need that affection
who need that love but they feel 'I have done something wrong, that's why my parents do not love me.
They love my sister, they love my brother, they don't love me'. These children are expressing the emotions
through dancing and then you have dancing ameliorates.
The movement of dance expresses the
emotions that they have been holding in.
The same with music. They enjoy
music and they feel better with music.
We have a color which is "cafe au lait". Cafe au lait is a kind of pale brown, earthy color with blue sclera.
It is very characteristic that some other keynotes are amelioration or aggravation, either of the two, in the sea.
Strong amelioration, strong aggravation in the sea. Also we have a knee-elbow position for relief
especially with the asthma, like Med. Knee-elbow position in asthma, like Kali-c., like Calc-p.
Desires also are very similar of the desires of Med. It desires salt, sweets, especially chocolate.
There is an inordinate desire for chocolate. Very strong and it has to be really strong because if you ask
who likes chocolate?
You see almost we have 90%. This is not Carc.
When they say I have to have 2 blocks of chocolate a day, then that is Carc.
That might be also Hydrophobinum
or Phos. but mostly Carc.
Alcoholic drinks, cold drinks, fat, spicy food, chocolate, all these desire you will find in Med. as well.
It's very interesting that they have similar symptomatology. It is interesting, why?
Because it shows that the miasm of gonorrhea going through the humanity had finally ended up by aggressions
on different levels, had ended up in cancer.
This sudden expansion of tumors, which is characteristic of Med. we see here as well.
Dark moles also, a lot of moles which are very dark, which maybe in a case they come up so suddenly.
While you treat a person, moles are coming up and they are black, you have to think of Carc.
This blinking of the eyes, the abdominal pain you can find in the Repertory but the idea of Carc. has to be there
this nice man, nice woman who cares
about others, who wants to be loved
who wants but he does not ask for love, her behavior is such that demands affection almost, without saying it.
-This blue sclera must be ?
-No, it is not necessary. You have a case where the personality will not be of that type but still there is
amelioration in the sea, better with the knee-elbow position, desire salt, you have given Med. and has
not acted, then your mind should go to Carc.
You have another case where it looks like Staph. She is so nice, they describes the personality and you think it is Staph.
and it has not acted, your mind should go there.
You have somebody else who says, 'I can't hear about any atrocities, any accidents, it's very painful for me'
you have given Calc. no effect, you have to think of Carc.
-I had a patient who had a lot of these symptoms, a young girl and it came out between Puls. and Staph.
but on the medium she was always Carc. She was about 16 and I was afraid to give it, as the first remedy.
-You can give it, no problem. You can give Carc. like you give any other remedy  there is no problem.
The problem is when you think that in every cancer case, Carc. is going to act. It's not going to act.
In every case the remedy which is indicated will act. Sometimes you will have this remedy indicated
at a certain phase of the treatment.
-I have two questions. One, the knee-elbow position in lying or also sitting this way?
-No, in lying.
-The second one is, Carc. you can give from certain potency only? Not a low potency?
-1x? I don't think you give 1x.
-Some people say that you can give it only from 200.
-You can give 12C easily but the experience is that you need a higher potency.
-We had one child and we were treating it because of neurodermatitis and the child had such a black mole
on the back and we gave Carc. The neurodermatitis went better and psychological it was much better
but the mole became a bit bigger and also a
bit more dark. What do you say about that?
-That's the right direction.
- I had a Carc. patient which had such a big mole 20 cm all over the abdomen  black
and it went light brown after 3 years.
-Anybody else has experience with black moles, Carc.?
I would like to hear your experiences in this remedy  as well.
-We had somebody who had a black spot here on his upper shoulder and after 2 years of treatment
this spot on the shoulder disappeared and afterwards on his temple a wart with hair appeared.
He still wants to dance in an extreme way.
-What potency he got?
-C200.
-One time or repeatedly?
-Repeated twice.
-She had a patient who had a mole on her back it was described to me as a black mole. She had previously
removed and after treatment with Carc. for severe depression amongst many other things, the area
where the surgery was performed began to suppurate and discharge for a period of 4 1/2 months.
Large quantities of serum and other materials. And then after that period of time it went completely
and the scar where the surgery was performed completely disappeared.
-Wait a moment. It was discharging after the remedy or before the remedy?
-After the remedy it was opened up again and began to discharge. And large quantities on regular basis.
-There was an operation, the operation healed somewhat...
-Completely. It had been a year or two before I had seen the patient.
-And then it opened up again and discharged. That's excellent reaction.
-I had a child belonging to this 1% of other Carc. types, with one of the worse neurodermatitis I ever saw.
It was violent, it was 2 years old at the time.
It would squash snails, it was very violent
and aggressive with other animals.
Really tortured his parents and was absolutely insensitive to pain.
I did not find the remedy and another Dr. gave Carc. and the neurodermatitis disappeared completely.
-Very good. I forgot also to give this point, insensitive to pain. The opposite.
-In Germany it's said that Carc. is very dangerous to give in cancer case. A doctor has reported a case
where a pregnant woman got Carc. and the child was aborted and the mother developed cancer and died 3 years after.
And it's said in Germany it's very dangerous to give it in cancer cases. In cancer cases it can be such aggravation
that you never get out.
-This is not my experience but I have given it in cancer cases and I have seen no effect. That is true.
Real cancer. I mean end stage cancer.
But to have this kind of reaction also maybe I put a question mark because the abortion does not necessarily mean
that it comes because of Carc.
The abortion may be programmed already and it would happen in any case.
In the same way that you give the wrong remedy and something happens to the organism, he has a heart attack
or he has suicide and then you say, oh I gave Med. and he committed suicide. So be careful of Med.
I have my doubts concerning such severe reactions. I have not seen it. Maybe, I don't know.
- You said that people who need Carc. are rather fastidious and do you observe also this permanent control
if the door is locked or the stove is switched off?
-This fastidiousness is there. You get a child who is very organized. I would say perfectionist, these children
are perfectionists, they want to do everything very correctly and they do it in a natural manner.
They are not forcing themselves to do that. It is natural, that's why we say fastidious is one of the elements.
Now going back I have not seen a case cured in this problem with Carc.  I don't know, maybe somebody has seen it.
-George, I also have a question in those Carc. children. Do we know anything about if they develop cancer later
if they are not treated because sometimes
you hear talking about cancer personality.
It's a soft person, non aggressive,
doesn't fight for its needs.
-I don't believe that. I have seen cancer cases developing in very lively persons, very extroverts, bon viveurs
dolce vita people and suddenly... the cancer comes.
I don't believe that you have a cancer personality. What I believe is that all the chemicals and the influence
of the environment and the influence of the stressors that come to the organism, eventually push
the organism towards this direction.
And this is why because we have means of stopping the intermediate reactions. People will not die now
from an acute condition easily. We have the means to stop it and then the organism gets the effect
and keeps the effect inside.
I have a case I'm treating with Tourette's syndrome. It's terrible case.
Where the man has no feelings, no connections, it's almost a case of schizophrenia.
And he goes with that he does all kinds
of movements and he holds back.
Taking his story he says, 'I remember when I was 5 years old, I had a pneumonia and the doctor said that
I will die most probably from the pneumonia. They gave me a lot of penicillin. It was in the beginning
of penicillin era. They gave me a lot of penicillin and I felt since that time, the disease stays inside me.
After a while I started doing movements' and then he started doing different things. He cannot touch if I touched this
and then it developed into a terrific state of suffering.
If you meet him, you will not understand anything but inside he says, 'I have no feelings, I have no enjoyment
I've never felt what is life but I feel a cold
running in my body without breaking out ever'.
He never got an acute. He, himself does not know the theory. He said, 'how can I get a cold?'
'George I almost got a cold, I need a cold to break out what has stayed inside since the age of 5'.
He is 39 now. He was saved from the pneumonia of course.
-The Carc. people or children would you say that they might take on some mission which is too difficult for them?
-They are duty bound. They feel that they have to perform their duty. 'This is my duty, I have to go to school. '
You tell them now you have to go to school.
They listen, so 'I have to go to school'.
Every day they have to go to school, they cannot miss a day of the school.
This is a mission, if you stretch it you
may take it as the idea of a mission.
-I had a patient who identified himself with some duties he got as a child. He was at the kibbutz.
He was born in a children's house and he didn't see his parents too much and he identified his parents
in the kibbutz in the children group. Anyway when the kibbutz movement became disintegrating
in the last few years, it's changing, it's not the same, he told me that he was trying to revive it. And he identified
himself with the movement, he felt he was disintegrating too. I was wondering if this is a characteristic for Carc.
-Not necessarily.
-I'm sorry I didn't understand, if you gave Carc.  to the Tourette man? What remedy he needed?
-I have tried half of the Materia Medica so far.
By the way the last remedy I've given is Carc.
I don't know the results yet.
It's a very severe mental and neurological case and I just keep him and he says, without Homeopathy
I would have been in insane asylum.
He feels he is in the limits.
-Do you also observe like the opposite of being timid and careful so that sometimes you find some people
like this type who is very duty bound and proper and then they talk about bungy jumping or parachute jumping?
-Parachute jumping I don't know. What I know is that these people are stimulated in their mental part and they need
food for their mental activity. Where they find food for their mental activity? In reading stories, books.
Most of them they will read a lot of stories books and some of them will go of course more to the science
and concentrate on reading and accumulating scientific knowledge.
They are book worms and they live through this their fantasies and their emotions because the books is a safe place
to live the emotions, the stories in the books.
But not all the people who read a lot of books, they need Carc. You have to get the feeling that these people
are really vulnerable, they will be very easily hurt and therefore the book gives them a safe place to play their emotions.
That is the idea.
Like dancing also, they release their emotions, listening to music they release their emotions.
But especially reading romantic stories,
they are not aggressive in sexual matters.
Some they have a little bit more energy for sex and some others they have less, they are going towards the impotency.
But the emotional side is very vulnerable, you looked at me in a kind that you put me down. They feel it inside.
Even the look, even the little hint is felt.
-I want to ask how the emotions change after having taken Carc.
-They become less vulnerable, this is definite. About the sexual? This remedy does not have a particular effect
on the sexual sphere. I have not seen excessive sexual desire or total disinterest.
It's something in between.
Therefore the effect is not something which you are asking or you are investigating a lot with this remedy.