Pall. is an interesting remedy
and the symptomatology of Pall. will be created in a person who has an emotional insecurity and at the same time
has strong feelings.
And there is a third factor which takes part in this complex, and it is an unexpressed egotism.
Why I say unexpressed egotism? These people they feel they are something special but they will never say it to anybody.
So this feeling 'I'm something'
you can imagine a lot of emotions inside, I'm special, I have a lot of emotions but at the same time
I have an emotional insecurity.  'Am I accepted by others, shall I be accepted?'
You can imagine the conflict which arises
inside, in such a person.
And in order to balance these elements inside the person, they need outside approval, outside flattering.
In the Repertory it says desires flattering or something like this. Desires to be flattered but it is not a simple flatter.
It is a flatter which has to be all the time.
Because all the time there is unbalance because of the insecurity, strong feelings, the egotism, the feeling
I'm something but I don't have to say it myself. Others have to tell me, I'm something special.
So there is a hunger for this approval from the social environment.
You get a boy or a girl who needs Pall. and they go to a party and in the party the others don't pay attention to them.
They will stay without speaking, without saying a word, expecting others to approach them and the idea is to say
you are so clever, you are so good looking, you are so this, you are so that.
This does not happen and they go away and they are into pieces. They go home and they are absolutely in pieces.
They are depressed, they don't want to live anymore.
But if in the party somebody has paid attention, has given them approval, they are very happy.
It is so much the idea that 'I'm special and I have to be taken special care', so if this is not happening
then they almost reach delusions that they have been neglected.
Everybody has neglected me. Nobody pays attention to me.
And then they suffer and suffer and from one extreme they can go to the other.
You flatter them, they are on top of the world, you don't pay attention, you don't flatter them, they feel
everybody rejects them, nobody wants to look at you or nobody pays attention.
They have a pride which is so easily shattered, so easily destroyed because others do not pay attention.
But see the idea of pathology how develops and because if the individual does not get this flattery to balance
you see it says: better with flattery.
It balances this inner conflict.
But if they don't get this flattery, then delusions of being large are developing.
I'm larger than the others, I'm taller than the others. Internal delusions.
But they will not have an open confrontation with others. On the contrary they will avoid any kind of real, external confrontation.
You see everything happens inside.
And therefore they will be people that will show a real lack of self-confidence. They are never sure about themselves
unless somebody assures them. Somebody
tells them how good they are.
You get Pall. children. They will go to school and in the school it happens that the teacher helps the child
by praising and they go to the top of the class.
They change school and the teacher pays no attention and they drop to the last. They don't care to work.
'They don't appreciate me, they don't understand me so why should I make an effort?'
You see the instability of this remedy.
Also you get a child who has average intelligence and he has a delusion almost that he is very intelligent.
'I know' but he will not say it to anybody. This is an inner thing.
But inside all the time expecting that from outside somebody will come and say 'yes, you know, yes you are good'.
Now this idea of 'I am more than I really am',
this idea is very interesting how it will show in tumors or cysts  which become very large.
Especially in the women, we have huge tumors. If suddenly there is a tumor which is too big you have to think of Pall.
especially if the tumor concerns the ovaries.
Cysts in the ovaries which take huge size, it is as if the organism cannot find outlet and blows up the organ.
The sexual desire for Pall. is quite strong but unexpressed. That means the individual feels the need to have
sexual activity but due to the fact that these people are closed to the communication of others they do not get
easy outlet for this function. You understand, emotionally insecure people do not attract others, even if they have
strong feelings but if they are revolving around themselves and their image, they do not attract others.
Therefore in spite of having strong sexual urge, they have to resort to masturbation to release it.
Because it's difficult to communicate.
We say that this enlargement of the ego or the need for enlargement, it may show in huge tumors
but there is a conflict which is going on, a strong conflict. See how it shows on the nervous system
by producing convulsions ticks and especially produces a syndrome which is called Tourette syndrome.
There is a syndrome in which the child goes into ticks like this and at the same time it makes noises
and it's interesting that the noises he makes or the words he says, they have a sexual connotation.
I'm sorry but these are facts of life which you have to consider when you have in front of you the patient.
So therefore what we observe in these people is that in order to be excited sexually, they like to hear
or to say obscene words. They are excited by obscene words and they like to hear it also.
You understand that these people, if they have arrived to the point where the ticks are, it is more difficult
to get a sexual partner.
So when they get one, they become
over sexual and similar to Platina.
With deviations and things like that.
But what is interesting with these boys/girls is that...you see the opinion of others for them is very important
he told me I'm clever, he told me I'm stupid.
So we see in that syndrome which we call Tourette's syndrome, the children go to school for 5 hours
and nobody knows they have the ticks.
In the school they are totally composed, no ticks at all because the opinion of others matters so much
that the mind controls the electrical activity of the nervous system.
It totally controls and makes them composed and nobody from the class knows that they have this problem.
It is as if all this super energy which is produced in the nervous system, is somewhere being conserved
within the organism and when they go home,
this thing is released and the parents go crazy.
And they go to school, nothing!
It is impressive the difference.
Most of the Tourette syndrome they will control in a social environment but Pall. controls totally.
It does not want to show anything.
Pall. is one of the main remedies that you will use in such a situation. Of course you don't use it only for that situation.
You understand the inner structure of the person, the need for flattery, the need to be approved, which also is the need
of Anac., the need of Bar-c.
They have similar needs but Bar-c. never thinks, I'm super. On the contrary they think, I'm stupid. Anac. also.
These people think, I'm super, I'm very clever,
I'm very intelligent, nobody recognizes this.
And they can be very clever but even these very clever people, need support and they need flattery
in order to balance. Otherwise they cannot balance.
So the Pall. people are in a constant fight, constant conflict within themselves.
You hear the story and also they will not say much to the doctor.
The real constitutional Pall. will not say much, is very reserved.
They expect others to come to them, they will not go to others.
So they will not talk very much.
This is a remedy that you will need many times
in starting Tourette's syndrome.
You see Anac., Sil., Bar-c. will tell you, 'I feel totally incapable of doing things'. These people will not say I am incapable.
They say, 'the others think that I am incapable'.
It is different but this 'the others not recognizing me', is tremendous. 'It kills me'. They go crying.
So you realize as a secondary action, the emotional insecurity. You say, why he needs so much support from outside?
You put things together and eventually you come down to the idea of Pall.
Peculiar symptom is 'as if something hanging from the throat'
And a feeling as if the uterus will prolapse.
The huge tumors is characteristic and especially in the woman.
Headache across the top of the head, from ear to ear also is a keynote.
Across like this.
Better with pressure or rubbing.
The patient will never tell you so exactly, he will just indicate that the pain is from here to here.
Whether it is like this or like this, is not important.
-I would like to share a case of Pall. There was this woman who was 23 years old and was training
to be a lawyer and the pathology for which
she came, were severe headaches.
They were very peculiar, the pain would come in the occiput, as somebody gives a very hard blow to the head
and she falls unconscious with the impact of the pain.
All her tests had been done and the doctors were thinking perhaps she has epilepsy because twice she has fallen
in front of automobiles, because of the pain. But epilepsy was ruled out in the EEG and she was on strong
painkillers for this and there was disturbance in her menstruation also. An ultrasound revealed that she had
polycystic ovarian disease which is a syndrome where you menstruate every 3-4 months
because the hormones are not in order.
This was all there, no modalities, nothing else and on questioning about her personality, she has this
typical pathology in the mind. She thought that she was never judged fairly in her exams, that she needed
to be to the top of the college but the Professor did not understand what she was saying.
And the exams were not fair because she was the best in the College but it was not with haughtiness
she did not say she expected me to understand that she is good and that the rest of the world does not understand.
After giving Pall. 200 and 1000 and then another 1000 in the period of 1,5 year, her menstruation became totally normal.
But she had long cycles which is expected in PCO people, 14-15 days and the headaches were gone absolutely
and I follow her up for 2,5 years and she is fine.
-You see there the headache is on the occiput as if a blow, it's a new kind of headache. It's not important
with the headache you can find the remedy. You can find the remedy by understanding the patient.
Ruta is a well-known remedy for treating traumas in tendons, in periosteum, in connective tissues.
Also it's a very good, specific remedy for bursa the kind of cyst that develops near these tendons or joints
where there is some special action of the tissues. Sometimes they develop a kind of bulge which is a kind of
cyst called bursa. I don't know if there is more modern expression for this. This is the old expression.
If anybody has a ganglion take a Ruta 200
and tell me tomorrow if it's gone.
It's a remedy which is restless, which is having similar symptoms with Rhus-t. and worse with cold and wet.
A remedy that usually does not want to communicate.
Because they develop easy vertigos
you may think that they need Bry.
There is a state of mind which is foggy and sluggish and slow and there is a better word, bewildered.
It's very interesting that Ruta is one of the important remedies in panic attacks.
With this mind which is bewildered, with this slowness of the mind, especially when they find themselves
in a hot environment, the panic attack comes.
Panic that they are going to die and they have to rush to emergency room.
It is an anxiety that they cannot define. It is an anxiety, a panic state which they have not been able to define.
I have asked them afterwards, can you tell us what you were feeling before? I was not able to get a good description
of their state. It is a panic attack which paralyses them, which leaves them helpless and fear that death is imminent
that death is coming.
And they have to get some help.
There is fear of evil and fear of water like Stram. or Lyss.
In this mind which is slow and not functioning very clearly, still they have a kind of dissatisfaction
with themselves, dissatisfaction with others.
They can become defiant.
'I don't accept what you say'. It is not contradiction.
It is within the idea of dissatisfaction which this remedy has.
If you talk to them you will see they feel like not committing suicide but saying that this life is a burden for me
it is too much to live.
This dissatisfaction is not an alive dissatisfaction, it is rather resignation 'I cannot live life, I cannot walk
I cannot go along, I cannot move'.
In children who are studying and because of the study they develop headaches, the main remedy is Calc-p.
Also Ruta has to be considered in such cases. Especially if the child complains of the mind not being clear.
They try to read and by the movement of the eyes a kind of headache or vertigo is coming up and the child
has to give up studying.
Sometimes the headache is like a nail which drives in. You will use this also in lumbagos where you have...
a symptom like Bry., where with the deep respiration you feel the pain. And it's better lying down.
I would say this remedy is between Bry. and Rhus-t. without having the thirst of Bry. and having
the restlessness of Rhus-t. and the mental picture of Bry.
Yet they don't want company but if they go into the panic states, they have to be accompanied always
by somebody to feel secure.
So if somebody comes with vertigo or panic attacks for instance, the mind is sluggish, slow and if he tells you
especially that most panic attacks come in the heat, 'if I get too warm I go into a panic attack', that is Ruta.
That's all you have to remember about Ruta. If I tell you more and more, you will remember nothing, at the end forget it.
And of course for traumatic cases, this remedy is a traumatic remedy when the joints are traumatized
and especially the periosteum. When there is a blow and there is a pain and the pain is really because
of the trauma of the periosteum, Ruta becomes a specific like when we have this bursa/ganglion, whatever you call it.
-Is this indicated for carpal tendon syndrome?
-Yes.
-Did you tell it's a remedy for ganglion on the tendons?
-I had a case with a ganglion on the wrist and it went away, it got very soft for two days and then it was absorbed
by the body but it grew again.
-After Ruta?
-After Ruta, it grew again.
-And you repeated Ruta?
-Yes, it went away again but it grows again, it's the third time it grows now.
-You gave Ruta it went away. Then it came back. You gave Ruta again, what happened?
-It went away again.
-And then it grew back?
-It's coming up now, it's growing very slowly.
-Maybe it needs a third dose.
You see this kind of treatment is a superficial treatment but many times it is impressive.
Because sometimes it grows so much especially in places where there is some friction because of the work they are doing,
they develop this bursa and they have to be operated. Then you give a remedy, they go to the surgeon, he says where is it?
But it's not the way. When you have the picture, that picture of the mind, when you have this difficulty
the tendons get stiff and break, that is why the muscles that move the eyes, have a stiffness.
So there is an effort, then it becomes headache which looks like between vertigo and headache and sometimes
the headache will end up becoming like a nail which is going inside.
-For differential diagnosis with Rhus-t., is it true that Ruta does not ameliorate from motion?
-No, it is not especially ameliorated. Ruta has restlessness, also it has another symptom you may find
if you touch them by the time that they sleep,
for instance, there is a big reaction.
What we try to do here is to give you the basic, so you stick to that and not to keynotes that maybe will be misleading.
-George since we're learning Classic Homeopathy, I want your opinion, each time there is a local
treatment on one's particular symptom, we're talking very often about Arn. etc. you consider that as a suppression
to avoid and in case of acute you have to give the remedy straight away, you can work on the constitutional
so what is the solution for that?
-Yes many times I would say we give remedies and we ameliorate symptoms, not the patient. This is not good.
You, see I like to see an aggravation. If somebody comes and tells me, 'I got your remedy and I feel very good'
I do not like it. Most of the cases they report aggravations.
Therefore that means in an aggravation that you have touched deeper.
If you see immediate amelioration either you have touched superficially like you say, a symptom
or the case is incurable, like this case that was presented. Every remedy brought an amelioration.
Now you will say what do you expect from Diphtherinum? Is it going to be an aggravation? I say yes most probably.
If that touches deeper the case and starts a curative reaction, it will be an aggravation.
And what will be the aggravation? I cannot say in this case. The organism will decide, whatever.
But if you see a case incurable, you give a remedy better, you give Sulph., it worked beautifully
Caust., Nat-m., all the remedies gave an amelioration.
Finally we say this case is incurable, that's how we know the case is incurable.
-I see quite often people come and patients come with overuse of the body, like digging too much in the garden
having problems in the shoulder and tennis elbow. What I mostly do I start with Rhus-t. and see how it's going on
and I don't have a good feeling for Ruta, so my question is what kind of acute condition, you would give Ruta?
-In local symptoms.
I would say Ruta if you have an aggravation from heat where in Rhus-t. you have an amelioration from heat
you can make the differential diagnosis.
Of course in aggravation from heat, you will have to differentiate between Guaj. also and Led.
You see these people who play tennis, they are quite strong people, usually they are healthy, they will not give you
general symptoms. But even then, you may try to see if you can get something more general.
-I want to ask again about the aggravation story. I have quite a lot of fight with some homeopaths who said that if you give
the Similimum, there is no aggravation because of the same energy. I would like the truth because
some people say, my patients don't have any aggravation and they are really good.
-This, no aggravation and then really having a cure is a possibility for very few individuals.
In 1978, we wrote a paper. We made statistics in our cases, how many had initial aggravation and it was 80%
and we wrote a paper for the International Congress.
By that time the idea of aggravation was not even coming into possibility at all.
And of course the idea of a cure was also far away, at the same time.
Most of the doctors at that time they were describing mixtures of remedies and they were trying
to reduce the symptoms. But this is not the idea here.
-I'm getting a bit confused concerning the temperature modalities, in your paper it says aggravation
from exertion, from cold and dampness.
At the same time when you gave the example of the panic attack, you said especially it occurs when somebody
comes into a warm environment. I can't put the two together.
- This is what we see many times. Actually the panic attacks, this tremendous fear of death is
when the organism gets heated.
In the arthritic pains, we have restlessness
and worse cold also and worse damp.
You can have both like you have both in Nat-c., you have both in Merc., you have both aggravations.
-If a patient shows an aggravation in a severe disease, like multiple sclerosis, it might be as well a spell
of the disease itself, not an aggravation brought about by the remedy but the spell of the disease.
How do you differentiate and how do you deal with this?
-The aggravation is such a case is gradual. The aggravation which I'm talking about will be something
which will come from one day to the other.
And most probably will not concern the pathology itself, like in this case. That means she may not develop
a further inability to swallow.
She may develop a headache, she may develop more perspiration but not necessarily the pathology itself.
The organism will decide but even if the pathology is aggravated for the time being, still it is a sign of course...
that there might be a possibility. Because the aggravation may just continue without being able to reverse it.
In incurable cases we may have aggravations that if we wait, it will go on and on and on.
In incurable cases we have aggravations which end up into speeding up.
-When I take a case of Ruta which is not basically chronic, is this possible that I'm just having local symptom
that is due to over exertion, like ganglion?
Then I don't get any symptoms of the mind. From what I understand they only develop when I get deeper and deeper
into the pathology of remedy. And how then will
I recognize Ruta, just because of the ganglion?
-This is what I said, if you don't have deeper symptoms, you prescribe on superficial symptoms
and such superficial symptoms can go away but at the same time do not touch the general condition of the patient.