The Kali-ars. patient how we recognize him?
Usually are people quite
controlled, quite
proper, quite duty bound
like all the Kalis.
You suspect very little that
these people may have an
inner anxiety of the type
that we shall be discussing.
The anxiety is so great, anxiety
together with fear which
mostly concerns their own
health, their own survival.
They are critical people,
they are matter of fact in
all respects, businessmen,
managers, industrialists,
bank managers. This type of
people that you will not expect
to see that tremendous fear
that arises at certain times
where they are totally paralyzed. And
this is what makes Kali-ars. different.
Kali-ars. is a remedy
which from the pathology
point of view will be
indicated in asthma cases.
Because it's a remedy which is
aggravated in general during the night.
It's a remedy that would not
like to go to bed. This going to
bed is a time of torture for Kali-ars.
whether it is anxiety
or whether it is asthma or itching.
You feel that there is a
kind of malignancy which
appears also in the physical
body as cancer of the skin
and more especially epithelioma.
Severe skin eruptions
especially when the eruptions
have a dry form and severe
itching which is worse
undressing and in bed.
They are people who will
be having tremendous fear
most specifically fear of
having a heart attack.
It's very interesting because you
will confuse it many times with Ars.
or with Phos., it's
very interesting that
they need company. It says
in the Repertory or in the
Materia Medica, they need company
and better from company.
What that means? I will
explain so you differentiate.
These people they can get
into panic attacks which are
totally unbearable. It's
something beyond the physical
something metaphysical is happening.
They don't understand what it is.
They cannot comprehend what
is happening inside and
they feel suddenly so much
alone, so much loneliness
so much isolation. They
feel as if somebody has
died and has become totally
isolated and fearful.
At that moment they
need communication,
they need to start
talking with somebody.
These people will get in the
middle of the night, two
o'clock, with a panic attack.
What is happening? I'm dying.
And they have to speak to
somebody and they pick up the
telephone and they telephone to
their mother or their father
to their friend or somebody just to be
talking, to make sure they are alive.
The panic is so much, I'm
dying, I'm going to die, as
long as I talk I'm not going
to die and this is the idea
better with company and
worse when they are alone.
They are serious people with
a tendency to depression.
They are critical and
suspicious, they are not
open people that they
will give out themselves.
They rather take but take
is not like the Phos.
idea of communication.
These people don't need
to communicate their
real feelings, they just
need to communicate.
Just to have somebody to talk, it doesn't
matter what, as long as they talk.
You understand that talking is under
this condition of fear and anxiety.
-I want to know if talking
is similar to Lach.?
-No, no. Lach. also we say they
go to bed and they feel in hell.
When? In the beginning
when they cough
and they have dyspnoea, they
suffer, then they go to sleep.
Then they wake up in the
morning and they are again
in a kind of aggravation state.
These people they can
sleep for a while but then
they wake up at 2,3,4 o'clock
and that is the time mostly
of the aggravation. This
is the time when they may
get the panic attacks.
During the night especially
when they live alone.
They are people who usually do
not have strong family ties.
They support the family but
the emotional part is rather
cold; that's why they are
very critical of everything
and that's why they
get easily very
suspicious and then they
go into depression.
If they suspect that his wife
maybe is looking somebody,
they get jealous without
expressing the jealousy.
Instead they become depressed.
Jealousy which has as an
immediate reaction not fighting
but depression it has to
bring to the mind, Kali-ars.
So Kali-ars. is an
anxious, restless and
nervous and sleeplessness
and panics and fear.
Fear of something unknown,
they cannot put down exactly.
But as you have this patient
maybe you don't find the
remedy in the beginning, they
will bother you quite a lot
because of the heaviness.
This is depression,
together with anxiety,
together with fear.
It's not a light anxiety, they talk about.
They don't want to talk about.
They call the friend, they
call the mother, they
call the father, nobody
must know what's going on.
That I have such a
tremendous fear which
eventually crystallizes
in fear of heart attack.
They don't want that others will know.
In later stages they can become
indifferent, depressed...
...and a kind of idiocy,
it's not exactly the word.
They can be in a state of
Alzheimer eventually. The
sleeplessness and the restlessness
which is going on for years
plus the anxiety and the
tremendous fear eventually
brings down the breaking
down of the mind
which eventually starts
losing the memory
and goes slowly into
this anoea (dementia).
Also they are people who are
not hopeful, they will usually
express this despair that there
is no way that I can be well.
There is nobody really that can help me.
I will give you some example
also of how they behave.
You see a very logical man, a
very compact, you don't see
somebody who is uneducated
and yet the panic is so much
that 'now I have this, heart
attack, now I have that'.
They have to go to the specialist.
They will not say to the
mother, father 'I'm going to
have a heart attack', no.
They will go to the specialist
and say, 'please have a look,
I feel the pain'. They create
the pain out of anxiety
and they have some pain and
the cardiologist usually
to whom they go makes a
cardiogram and says nothing.
It's the people with the most
cardiograms in their hands. When
they come to you they will come
with a series of cardiograms.
Usually from one cardiologist
whom they trust.
I remember a case who
said to him, he said
listen you are a busy
man, I'm not so busy man.
You've come so many times, you gave me
so much money, you wasted your money OK.
So I'll make a proposal to you.
That every month you will send
me a check and every month I
will send you a certification
that your heart is all right.
You don't have to come
so you don't waste your
time but you will be happy
and I will be happy also.
I told you so
many times your heart
is OK and no problem.
It was very strange that
this particular man
after treating him went
out of Kali-ars. state.
He telephoned one day,
he says 'George do you
remember me?' I said yes.
It was 15 years later.
He said, 'who am I?' I said, this is you.
He says, 'I
want to tell you something.
I had a heart attack'.
The most strange thing you
remember he was afraid all these
years, now I had a heart
attack and I was not afraid.
He was amazed, I could
remember even his name and
his case of course. His
case was a very strong case
because this man was so strong,
so powerful. I remember
in the waiting room they were
several individuals sitting
and several doctors working
in different rooms and I
was passing, going from one
room to another to see
the next consultation which I had to form.
And at a certain moment I
felt almost a power behind me
and I turn and I look at this
man and then I go inside.
And of course he got inside
and I see his name and in his
name, he was coming from NY
this man but he was Greek
but living in NY and in his
name the man who brought
him said, be careful
he belongs to the CIA.
So I look at the paper and
say, oh it's you. Then he had
no problem, he told me. He
said, I did everything in life
I wanted to become rich,
I became rich. I was
in the American army, I
did this, I did that.
I have not been able to beat Valium.
I have to take
constantly Valium to keep
out of these panic attacks.
So this kind of hard man you
don't expect that they will
have such a deep anxiety, fear
and almost metaphysical fear.
It is like disintegration.
Actually his son after
a few years he came to me
with similar symptoms.
His son did not know why
his father was coming.
The father never told the son and the
son was with almost identical symptoms.
Also Kali-ars. acted
beautifully many many
years till the son did
not bother me anymore.
But these cases are really the
most heavy panic states cases.
-Will you be surprised that
this guy had a heart attack
or what is the kind of
realization of internal fear?
I mean do you think that
it should be a connection
or is something which we
should be surprised of?
-Don't forget this man was very rich.
As I said, he
was going to the cardiologist
every week for years.
At least one time the week he was to the
cardiologist making a cardiogram etc.
He had visited the best
doctors all over the world.
He followed the advice of
many different people.
Finally he ended up taking
Valium 3 times the day.
The problem was the anxiety.
After the anxiety was
finished, he did not bother
to come from NY anymore.
He was going for different ailments.
For a flu he would go to
the local doctor, for
15 years I did not know
what he was doing.
The interesting thing was when he
phoned me, he said 'I am this man'
and what impressed him
he said, 'I went to the
hospital with a heart attack
and I was not afraid'.
He was amazed himself what
I've given him during
that time which made him so
well that even if he had
a real heart attack, he was not afraid.
It's a different level all together.
But I cannot know, let us
say the question may be:
if he had followed all
these years homeopathic
treatment, would he have a heart attack?
That is a good question.
I believe no, but
nobody can prove this.
-We can give Kali-ars.
to a person who has
frequently extrasystolism,
palpitation?
-Yes as long as the aggravation
is in the night. If he wakes
up in the night, if he is worse
with cold, Kali-ars. also
has cold extremities like Verat.
It is one of the
remedies that will be indicated
to Raynaud's syndrome
as long as he has this kind of
character, closed, not communicative.
There is a kind of inner
connection in the building of a
remedy and the connection
is this: you have malignant
anxiety which will end in a
malignancy like epithelioma
in a case where the heart
is suffering quite a lot.
That is why they get this
tremendous fear about their
heart because the heart suffers
for different reasons.
In this particular case suffers
because it does not have the
possibility to communicate
with his wife, to communicate
with his children. He says,
my son does not understand me.
I am rich, I have a
big shop in NY center
he doesn't walk to take the shop.
This is unbelievable for me.
So this kind of man who has
no particular feelings if
the feelings go down and
then up comes the anxiety
and the restlessness this is
heading for a big problem.
-If we give this remedy in heart
problems, we can give high potency?
-Up to 200 you can give. It depends also.
Extrasystole
may mean nothing. It's only
an electrical disturbance
but it might mean consequence of
other more serious conditions
in which case you have to be
a little bit more careful.
This man is very strange.
Still he calls me once a
year or every second year
just to say 'how are you
when are you coming to visit
me' and things like that. He
has no need for remedy. That
means his needs are covered
by local doctors. He did not understand.
He came the first interview,
the first follow up,
he came and I said, how are you?
He was very hard.
You felt nothing? 'Nothing'.
One month, 'nothing I
didn't feel anything. What can I do?'.
This attitude.
Then you are in a problem because you
say the remedy has acted or not?
I said OK, I'll give you another remedy.
Take some placebo.
Second month, a little
doubt, is it possible?
After going to all these
doctors I come to this
little man here, I'm talking
about 30 years ago.
This young man sitting there in
a basement in Athens, I have
travelled all over and is it
possible that I will be cured
by this one? I could see the whole thing
because his thought was so strong.
Don't forget I turn around to
see who is grabbing me? It was
like somebody who most probably
is very willing to be well
he says this is the master.
He looked at
me and the vibration
made me turn around.
And when the third month
he came with a ring,
I remember I told you,
for my wife, he said
'I'm a free man, you made me a free man'.
He also said this famous, 'if
anybody ever tries to do something
wrong with you, you call me
and I will come with a gun'.
-The pharmaceutical companies?
-First I have to know who is the one.
To kill all the
pharmaceutical companies, that
would be very interesting.
But this shows the character,
how suspicious, in the
Repertory you read suspicious.
Unless you understand
the kind of suspiciousness,
it's somebody who is critical
and suspicious, thinks a
lot, doesn't go along with
what you tell him, he has
to decide for himself.
This is the type of Kali-ars.
people.
Let's talk about another remedy, Sabin.
Sabin. we know it mostly as
a remedy for women with the
problems centralizing upon
the reproductive organs.
The reproductive organs are in disorder.
Where we have tremendous
hemorrhages with big black
clots, the woman hemorrhages
(bleeds) almost constantly.
And it is many times a dangerous
situation when they come
to you because these hemorrhages
don't stop easily at all.
Of course they have easy miscarriages.
But what I want to discuss
mostly is the type of woman
who has these uterine
problems or sexual problems.
These usually are women who are closed,
not communicative, not social ...
...with a passionate nature,
sexually passionate.
They have strong sexual
desire, strong passions.
They feel lascivious, they like
different things and going
with different men but their
character prevents them
from becoming common women
almost, going with any man.
So they are women who can even
reach the state of nymphomania.
Usually you will confuse them with Nat-m.
because they are
closed, discontented, they don't
talk about their feelings.
If you try to pacify them, if you
try to console them, they don't
like it, they are aggravated
from consolation, like Nat-m.
And due to this fact that
they can communicate very
difficult, they have a feeling
of being forsaken by others.
This feeling can be expressed and
you may be thinking of Puls.
because they are better
from cool and fresh air
and they are worse from warm, like Puls.
They don't cry easily but
they cry in their sleep.
All the grief they keep
it comes out during
sleep where they may
be start crying.
It's very interesting also
it is a remedy that does not
like to listen to music. Music
strikes some chord inside
that aggravates them and
brings them to the point
where they want to cry
and they don't like it.
Like Nat-m. don't like to
cry in front of others.
But once they get very angry
they can explode and then
they end up in sobbing,
after exploding in anger.
They are people who will not talk
very much, they don't like to
talk, they don't like to communicate
but they talk in sleep.
You see actually in them
the idea of emotionally
loaded individual who
cannot express this passion
this intensity in normal life and the
activity takes place during sleep.
Kali-ars. we said avoids going to bed.
The Sabin. is
tired and looks for the bed
and looks for solitude.
In this respect will look again like Nat-m.
You see again how
closed it is but she is not hurt,
she is closed but not hurt.
Nat-m. closes because there is a
trauma, a pain in the psyche.
They are closed and not
communicative, don't like to
talk, like to stay by
themselves, like to stay alone
but the night there is activity.
They can
talk, they can cry,
they can do anything.
And due to this hormonal
disturbance which brings about
the excessive sexual desire,
you see the activity
in the uterus where the blood flows
and black pieces are coming out.
You see also the inability of
the uterus to hold the fetus
and you have miscarriages,
especially in the third month.
And the characteristic
pain is this pain which is
from the sacrum to the pubis,
there is almost a line.
They will describe the pain absolutely
like this, and this is Sabin. 95%.
If they specify that pain and
you see the metrorrhagia.
The woman has come usually in
due to stop the metrorrhagias.
We have a case on video, Sabin.
on video on the other group,
very interesting case. Maybe
later on in future seminars.
Where we have to present
cases, I will show
this case because it's
very typical Sabin.
That's all you have to remember.
Miscarriages,
uterine with a lot of
blood, blood with clots.
How many of you have prescribed Sabin.
so far?
In Sabin. we see two things.
The menses are very
profuse, long, protracted
and with black clots.
At the same time in other
cases we see really bleeding
all along, bleeding which
stops for 2-3 days and then
again starts and continues
and it has this heaviness
and dangerous. You feel
that she is going anemic
she is losing so much blood,
that's why she is in danger.
Sometimes you will
see fever arising.
But the bleeding is heavy
always whether it is within
the menses or whether it
is because of a tumor
of a myoma, polypus or because
of malfunction of the uterus.
-I have a question not so much about Sabin.
Many remedies
in Materia Medica are
coming up regarding music.
Given the nature of when
Homeopathy developed
and started where many
provings were made
the music that was
available then is very
different than the music
it is available now.
I found that some of the Repertory
information is not really
accurate and I just wondered
if you comment about that?
-That is true but when we
refer to this sensitivity, it
has to be really strong, that
means you suspect Sabin.
and you ask do you enjoy music?
She says no.
Straight forward. I even don't listen.
This is the answer.
When you get such an answer,
no individual will give this
answer even if they are unmusical,
even if they don't listen
If they listen by chance they don't mind.
They mind the noise.
It seems that there is a kind
of sensitivity in the ear
and if the noise is
strong, then it seems to
penetrate the whole organism.
It is similar to Ther.
Ther. also cannot tolerate
this noise and they feel it
in their body, as pain. But
here music is rhythmic.
And this is strange, the Ther.
does not have this
sensitivity to music; it has
sensitivity to noise and Asar.
which is even worse in the
reaction towards the noise,
will plug their ears but not in music.
They like music.
But any kind of noise
and especially the
squeaky noise when we
write with the chalk.
-Concerning Sabin., the
duration of bleeding after what
time you would expect that Sabin.
could stop bleeding?
How long would you have to wait?
-It depends. If she comes for
profuse menses, not real bleeding,
then you can wait 2-3 months
to see if it's regulating.
But if she comes with
profuse, pathological
bleeding then you have
to wait a few days only.
In few days you have to see the reduction.
You can give high potencies,
they act more quickly,
especially in such bleeding
which I'm talking about
you have to give 1M, 10M, 50M
unless you have a cancer of course.
If you have a cancer in the uterus
which is bleeding is different.
Anybody else had a typical Sabin.
case, do you remember?
-I heard about women that
make experiments with Sabin.
in different potencies to
bring about a miscarriage.
-Did they succeed?
-Partly.
-It's very strange.
You see in order to bring
a miscarriage, let's talk
clear, you have different
vibrational frequencies.
Here is Sep., Sabin., Nat-m., Ign. etc.
The subject, the woman has to be very near.
If she is Sabin.
she will be cured, not only
she will not have miscarriage
but in case she was going to have a
miscarriage, she will not have it.
So this case is out, is cured.
In order to have really such
an effect, has to be really the
next vibrational frequency.
That means you catch
somebody who is very
sensitive to Sabin. without
being Sabin. exactly.
In such case there might be a
possibility, if you take Sabin.
low potency, frequently, maybe.
But if somebody's remedy is here and Sabin.
is here, it will have no effect.
-I have a young woman and she
had 3 times a miscarriage.
In the end of 2nd
beggining of 3rd month.
And when she had the
fourth pregnancy, at
that time I worked
with low potencies.
But I told her to take Sabin. C30
once the week and she kept the child.
She said that the uterus did not
have the force to keep the child.
- I have a case too which proves that
Homeopathy is not placebo effect.
One day a woman calls me
that she has dog and this
dog has got puppies and
since it has delivered
the dog has constant bleedings and
the doctor wanted to do hysterectomy.
I didn't see the dog but another
prominent thing the woman told
me is that since this time the
dog was very sensitive to touch.
Sabin. helped up to now,
this dog to have puppies.
-Very good. It is also
interesting for us that we study
in such detail the human
imbalances, is very interesting
that if you go in the
Repertory, if I remember well,
you will see another remedy
which has blood with clots
which is again Platina, which
is again a very sexual remedy.
What has to do the
sexuality or the non
satisfaction in sexual
matters with blood clots?
You see how the disorganisation
of the organism is pointing
out certain indications where
it might be the problem.
But this is how also we learn about
the inner structure of human beings.
Not everyone will be like that
but you ask, she says very
profuse, with black clots.
Most probably this is a case
of a dissatisfaction in sexual energy.
The sexual
energy is strong and there
is an inner dissatisfaction.
These women they
have sex but no real
satisfaction, they don't
end up into real orgasm.
They end up into something
else which is more or less but
they are very excited and there
is no end to their desire.
The desire remains. When
there is real orgasm, the
desire goes away for a
period of time at least.
With Sabin., with Plat., with Orig. we
don't see that kind of satisfaction.
We see the excitement and no satisfaction.
Also the mind of Sabin. is
many times a confused mind, a
mind as if there is intoxication,
there is sluggishness
a kind of fog with
aversion to do mental work.
They are ready to do other
work but not mental.
Therefore their memory drops
quite early and we have
disturbances of memory,
disturbances of concentration
disturbances of interest in
professional life, if it
is a profession that needs
the function of the mind.
So you see to bring an individual
into real balance, mental,
emotional and physical, here
you see the over activity
in the reproductive system and
slowing down of the mental activity.
You see the feelings are strong but
kept inside, not communicative.
And you see the outlet
of all disturbance as a
flow of blood, it's
tremendous and the black.
- Under 'male, ganitalia, increased
desire' you have Sabin. in second degree.
-I don't remember now.
What I remember definitely
is that I had a lot of
cases of female Sabin.
but what we said except
of the uterine bleeding,
all the rest can be applied
to men who are closed
full of feelings inside but
not being able to express
these feelings. This
activity takes place during
the sleeping time where
they talk, they cry, they
perform and all that and
the increased desire.
-I would like to ask a question about Nat-m.
Because we are
comparing certain aspects, the
closeness and everything.
What about the sexual desire, is it strong
in Nat-m., you have seen that often?
-The Nat-m. because of
lack of communication they
keep inside and they don't
express, they don't go out
and seek partners. Therefore
the desire is very strong and
when they come into contact,
this desire is detonated.
But there is satisfaction, there is no
the nymphomania, one after the other.
There is satisfaction,
they become very sexual.
In their expression, once
they let themselves they can
become very expressive and very
sexual but with an orgasm.
If this closes, in Nat-m.
it can go deeper and closes
this function, then comes the
depression which is deep
and they are indifferent and unable
to have excitement, enjoyment.
The Sabin., the Platina have enjoyment.
They don't reach
that peak of enjoyment which
releases the organism.
It seems to take away, there is a
production of certain hormones
in the system, male or female
which have to be neutralized.
I don't know how the
mechanism exactly. They
have to be neutralized
by what we call orgasm.
In Sabin. and in Gamb.,
in Orig., in Plat.,
they don't reach that satisfaction.
Nat-m. yes.
Closed, feelings are there, not
expressed yes, worse consolation
yes, but in the sexual sphere
if they let themselves.
Because a Nat-m. woman can
be approached by 10 men,
she will pick only one and
maybe none of the 10.
She says I don't like
them, next year, next
time we'll see. They
retain themselves.
The Sabin. is not selective.
So all these of course differentiate
the one from the other.