Something else that we have to have in mind, when we say 'ailments from suppressed eruptions'
we usually mean that the beginning states, that means during the eruption, the same remedy was indicated.
It was the same remedy that went deeper.
You don't understand that?
You have a skin eruption which
you suppress by cortisone.
And then you have asthma and then
you give Caust. and the case is cured.
Asthma was cured by Caust. Most probably when the original eruption was there, Caust. was still indicated.
That is most of the times.
Of course there is a possibility that you have another state and you have another remedy.
But it is also useful to know that when, after skin eruption, you have given a remedy and it acts
the same remedy may be indicated for
the eruption, when it comes back.
Graph. is one of these remedies which
creates a lot of eruptions in the body.
So if you suppress a Graph. eruption,
you will have problems in the inner organs.
What is affected mostly is the stomach.
Duodenal ulcers or severe gastritis, which appear after suppression of skin eruption
most probably indicates Graph.
When a skin eruption is suppressed
and produces cramping pain or cramps
most probably the remedy is Cuprum.
In this remedy the first thing we see it is a slowness, a heaviness of the body, in general.
The body is heavy, the physical body is slow,
the mind is slow, the body is heavy and obese.
The eruptions of which we have different types usually are discharging and the discharge which comes out
is sticky and it's like honey. It's not like honey exactly but when you touch it, then there is a kind of string.
You touch the eruption and it's sticky.
If you touch the eruption and you go like this and there is a string up to here, then the remedy is Kali-bi.
Too much information.
If you can remember it, it's excellent of course.
You need to go through restudying your
notes and really keep it in your mind.
Because these things have to be
learned almost by heart.
We have an obese individual with a lot of eruptions, who is at the same time, sensitive individual
it can cry easily, they cry without reason
and especially they cry, if they hear music.
It brings such a melancholy, they cry, without knowing why. Music will force them to cry.
An interesting part of Graph. are the nails. Except of the skin, the nails also are affected in, let us say, 90%
of the cases of Graph. you will see the nails are affected and they are either deformed, corrugated or breaking easily.
Also in psoriasis, you will
see the nails are quite affected.
Which are the remedies which are
very much very affecting the nails?
Calc. yes and there are some other
remedies like Sil., Nit-ac., Thuj.
Now you get a case of psoriasis and you see the nails are totally distorted or gone, eaten up by the psoriasis
and the psoriasis is concentrating upon the nails.
The other body is left free but this part is affected; that means you will have to search a remedy
which affects specifically the nails. Which
is one of these remedies? Graph.
You see how important it is?
You get duodenal ulcer. You look
at the nails, they are corrugated.
You can predict almost that he had an eruption, it was suppressed and now he has a pain in the stomach.
You can do that, like prophets.
Deformed nails, brittle, thick and hard, corrugated also.
Also another characteristic is concerning the areas where the skin is connecting with the mucus membrane
which again are the lips, the corners and which are also the rectum, the anus, where we see fissures.
Fissures in the anus.
In the eyes also yes.
Discharge which is thick from the
eyes, which is thick and sticky.
Discharge from the ears which
is sticky, yellowish, offensive.
Discharge from fissures which is
yellowish, sticky. From fistulas.
Another seat of action is the ears where they get chronic otitis with hearing impaired, with discharge.
Also it is one of the main remedies for photophobia. They cannot stand a lot of light. Intense photophobia.
Callosities, calluses on the soles.
Mostly on the soles, sometimes on
the palms but that's not frequent.
Aversion to salt, aversion to
sweets, aversion to fish.
Meat and warm food is secondary but if they have a case where it has these 3 aversions...
... you better think of Graph.
There is no other remedy which has
these 3 aversions combined.
-Is the discharge from the ear concentrated
more on one side rather than the other?
-In the books it says yes but I have not confirmed that. That's why I don't put attention into that factor
because you see one ear in the books and discharge from the other and you miss the remedy, no.
The main idea is here obesity, photophobia, desires, aversions and discharges and the nails which are deformed.
The problem is that you learn this and you may have a case of Graph. if you are busy practitioner
after 3-4 months. If you are not a busy practitioner, you may have a case of Graph. once the year.
You have to learn that and remember it after
a year when he comes and you say
he was shouting to us something like this.
It happens like this because I shout
too much, you will remember.
It was something with G... G... not Gels.,
Graph. You open the book and then you confirm.
These are the main remedies, later on we go to less important remedies that will be indicated even less.
Graph. also to my experience are people quite healthy, talking about names of remedies which are healthy.
Graph. people are quite healthy,
quite down to earth.
No nonsense, no flying of imagination,
neither deep depressions.
They are obese people but
their body is built solid.
"Bowers", farmers.
It's the one word I know in German
that I can pronounce.
Graph. is the representative of the these persons. Strongly built, with eczemas
with fissures, with nails deformed
and you will find these cases.
These people also they can tolerate quite a lot their deformities and they stay good for many many years.
There is a time when the itching becomes really unbearable and then they go and take cortisone
and internal problems start and
that's the time when they come to you.
Here is a Helleborus.
HELL - eborus to remember the state of Helleborus is the state of hell.
I have never experienced in any other remedy, the anxiety, the agony, the state of the soul
which is in hell and it's burning, suffering.
How the Christians they describe hell where you have things which are boiling and people inside.
Despair and extreme anxiety but when you realize that state, extreme anxiety. What happens to me?
Have you been on a boat where it's going up
and down and then you want to vomit?
There is a feeling as if your soul
will come out of you.
Without the boat, the soul wants to come
out from here, from here, from here.
And there is a state which really
you say 'God help me!'
And you see the individual will go like
this, restless, seeking for help.
Actually stating 'help me, help me'. What happens? He can't describe, he can't say.
You think he is going to die but from what?
The soul is coming upside down, inside, the sub-conscious has come up and it's overwhelming, it's hell.
When you see this case, the anxiety state with Hell., you give whatever and will not touch, will be worse
Ars., Phos., you give Calc. nothing, Nit-ac.
You try all kinds and it comes there this anxiety, this fear, fear with anxiety, with upset inside.
If somebody was trying to pull out your soul and the soul cannot come out. If it's out you say OK I'm happy.
You cannot die, you are in hell and
they are pulling your soul out.
This is the state of Helleborus.
Answers slowly, weakness of
memory, all these are words.
What happens is the sensorial
part of the human being is blocked.
And looks but does not look, he looks but he does not see. He does not see you clearly, I mean.
When we see, we see the
eyes, we understand.
I see her eyes and I know what she thinks, her fears, her anxieties and I see more or less what she thinks.
The Helleborus will look at you in a state
of panic and you see he cannot see.
If you ask him what he saw, he cannot describe. He cannot hear, that state is such an anxiety.
I remember my father in law.
He got at the age of 80, he got leukemia.
After extraction of some teeth, he suddenly developed leukemia and I didn't want to interfere.
My mother in law... OK take him to hospital.
They took him to hospital
and started with chemotherapy.
One bunch of chemotherapy 7 days, then 7 days no chemotherapy, then second bunch with the idea to have 3 courses.
In the middle of the second course,
it was a total collapse.
The blood was oozing from all
over, it was coming out.
The plateles were very much down and then the hemorrhage started and it is the end of the case.
So they stopped the chemotherapy
when they saw this condition
They said it's a matter of maybe one
more day, he will be gone.
Then I had the right to interfere with the case in the hospital. In the hospital it was one of my students also.
So I could manipulate easily
the whole situation.
He said, worse, we stopped, we don't
anything more, finish. You can do.
And I remember I gave him immediately
Merc-c. and then immediately after that, Phos.
and immediately after that he
developed that state of Hell.
He was half lost with the hemorrhages. The third, fourth day he came into that state of Hell.
All his life he was a very patient man, very quiet, patient, nice, soft and then he started becoming restless and calling...
Hell., the next day he was calm.
In 15 days I took him out of the hospital.
Plateles we had over thousand.
In 1 month all the readings
were almost perfect.
He still felt weak and he improved
until he was considered as cured.
But I remember that state of Helleborus because you see the person how he becomes under the state of Helleborus.
I have one or two cases on videos,
you will see more or less that state.
Of course the memory is affected also, forgets what he just read or done and there is irresolution.
Worse from 4-8 p.m.
That is interesting because we have another remedy, which is worse 4-8 p.m. How many know this remedy?
Yes Lyc. but you see in this remedy
we have the same hours.
Meningitis, encephalitis, rolling of
head from side to side.
With the anxiety, rolling the head in bed.
The chewing motion in mouth or the grinding of the teeth usually comes from an irritation of the meninges.
Here we say chewing motion of mouth.
Bores head into pillow, vacant stare, brain cry.
And we have aversion to apples,
total, it's very strange.
What apple has? It has a chemical which the body feels it is like poison. I don't know what it is.
I have cured a case, severe case
of allergy that was eating bananas.
Give me bananas.
Very strong desire for bananas!
Tub. I gave Tub. and he was cured.
Urine is dark, red, almost black. This
is the tendency of the inner bleedings.
Then we have the dark, red urine like coffee.
The bleeding from kidneys,
from lungs, from everywhere.
Ailments after meningitis or encephalitis.
What is the ailments? It's the state in which I described to you, the loss of memory, forgets.
Where did I read this? I can't
remember, all this kind of things.
The rolling of head, from
side to side is characteristic.
If you have seen one case, then
you never forget it again.
It is a state in which the agony is so much, help me. If you don't help them, they have to go to the asylum.
You cannot stand that state for long.
-I want exactly to know what looks like this person, when looking? Does he look as if he is looking through you?
-No. It is the agony and helplessness. 'What
shall I do now? Do something quickly!'
I remember a case, he was going like that.
'Help me, help me, oh God!'
You stand back and you say,
what is this? What remedy?
If you don't kno, you had it. Because
you cannot take symptoms in that state.
It is extreme. Do you like sweets?
Some homeopaths they go into
that. What does it matter?
The whole thing is collapsing
and he is saying...
You have to get the essence. Tell me the idea. If you don't know the remedy, never mind the idea.
-Can this state be the beginning of heart attack?
-I don't know, maybe. Not in my
experience but maybe.
But I would doubt because that state which I describe, is a mental state, quite deep.
Therefore the heart at this moment, it will function properly. It will not be involved.
But you may have an anxiety, which can affect the heart which can be Lach., can be Aur.
This is possible.
Of course not all Hell. cases
will be that extreme.
But you get this dullness, this feeling of cannot think, forgets. What does it remind you?
It reminds you of Alum.,
very good. Who said it?
It cannot think, cannot make a decision. Forgets names, forgets words, forgets numbers.
They complain of a mental dullness
together with a feeling of anxiety.
Students are very difficult to pass
examinations when they are in this state.
I knew a student, not Greek, I can't
remember now which country he was.
He was trying to pass the examinations
for years in the University.
He could not. His mental state was so dull, so difficult to think and he was in a terrible anxiety
because his parents were paying for his
studies and he wanted to please the parents.
And the more he wanted to please the parents, the more the anxiety was coming and there was this kind of anxiety
agony and at the same time the
dullness and cannot concentrate.
You help these cases and it's like
taking them out of hell really.
Niger is the black color.
It's a flower but the color, black,
the darkness, what we call the hell.
I don't wish anybody to be in that state.
Hepar Sulphur.
Over sensitive to pain. You see how strong it is?
Fears suffering. Suffering is
very intolerable for Hep.
They are afraid very much of injections,
things that sting them, wasps.
I was treating once a grown up man, I thought he was a Hep. case. I said to him, 'are you afraid of injections?'
He said, 'Oh my God let me tell you what happened when I was in the army'.
In the army they undress them and they put them in line, the officer is putting an injection, next, next.
He says, 'I could hardly managed to reach.
By the time he was ready, I collapsed'.
'The idea that he was going to inject to me, was totally intolerable. So I fainted, I collapsed'.
This kind of sensitivity.
I described to you another type where the person was fighting with the wasps and the bees and he was running all around.
These are very characteristic. Another characteristic for this remedy is over sensitivity to whatever pain.
They are people who are suffering
with mental and emotional pain.
A person is so vulnerable that you can imagine the family situation, for little reasons it will make them suffer tremendously.
A woman with her mother, usually
there is a kind of competition
between the mother and the
daughter because of the father.
They both want the father for their
own. Usually there is a competition.
That can kill a Hep. patient because that competition is felt so much, so deep
that can really torture the person.
It can really bring about such torture that you may have malignancy developing.
Organism who is so sensitive
to pain, which is physical or stinging.
They feel the psychological
attack as if there is a sting, a splinter.
That's why the pains of Hep. are like splinter.
They get this pharyngitis or laryngitis
and the pain is like a splinter there.
Similar with Nit-ac.
In Hep. the idea is, the sensitivity is such that
he feels this sting, he feels whatever is pointed
and the pain is like a splinter.
Splinter like pains in the throat,
knees, gallbladder, wherever.
Sensitive to cold air or slightest draft.
Who is sensitive to cold? The remedies
that are very sensitive to cold are
Arsenicum album and Calcarea carbonica.
This is more cold than all the others with the characteristic that if they are in acute condition
the moment that they take out of the blankets one hand, then there is an aggravation of the situation.
They cough more, they feel more the pain.
So draft is very much affecting them
and also taking out just a little bit.
They say, if I uncover one part,
the hand goes out of the blanket
immediately the cough starts
being worse, the sneezing starts.
People who are so cold that they have to cover almost everything and leave only this side, to breathe.
We have an over sensitive person who
reacts towards society in a peculiar way.
He feels inside him this vulnerability and
giving out also an impulse which is violent.
He wants to do violence.
He wants to put things on fire.
He wants to kill. He wants to
do some kind of violence.
They are people with that sensitivity which are attacking, which can become rude and ruthless, abusive.
And the impulse comes to kill like another remedy that we shall be talking about....
.... desire to kill, which is Hyoscyamus.
It's a remedy which we are using for skin eruptions, especially acne vulgaris and boils.
Unless we joke we cannot exist.
Acne which is painful,
which cannot be touched.
Painful to the exposure of the air.
And has desire for fat and spices. This is
the peculiarity for Hep. Fat and spices.
And she is better in a
warm, damp weather.
That weather which we have today,
damp and warm is good for Hep.
These people can stand very hot weather. We say warm but they can stand hot weather, damp.
They feel worse in a dry environment.
Cold and dry, the north winds which
are cold and dry, make the Hep. suffer.
-Hep. being sharp tongued in his
form of attack to people?
-Sharp tongue I'm not sure but definitely they
are people who have strong feelings.
They feel vulnerable, that they
have been abused.
And when they talk back, they talk in bitterness and in a kind of an abusive way but not sting.
They can be irritable, abrupt,
abusive, angry.
For instance there is a remedy
which we will do later on, Sepia.
Sepia is a remedy that will understand
where is your weak point.
Very soon they will feel where is your weak point and they will say something exactly to that point.
This is spiteful. This is not with Hep.
Hep. is abusive, they will fight.
Sometimes they will have impulses
to kill.
But not real killing.
It's not the remedy that will take
a machine gun and kill people, no.
Iod. is a patient who is burning
very fast a lot of energy.
Producing, burning out food
and transforming it into energy.
So much energy that they
cannot really stand one minute.
They have to be on the move, they have to be restless, they cannot sit down and study and read.
They cannot sit down and do anything.
You can understand the inner probe that
there is inside. Something pushes them.
The energy is pushing them to get out the energy. Otherwise they feel they'll go crazy.
If you tie an Iod. person, on a chair, and say, you will sit there for one hour, he will go crazy.
He will break the chains.
It's not possible for him to stay.
That is the central theme and of course with this energy which is produced, you can expect that is producing a lot of heat.
So it's a hot remedy, very hot remedy with palpitations and a person who needs a lot of food.
Because the food is burned out and then he needs more food and he feels very empty in the stomach.
Once the food is in the stomach, there is a calmness, for a while. The headache calms down
the pains calm down, the
psychology calms down.
And after a while that the food is gone, then it starts again the restlessness, the emptiness, etc.
Profound ability in great emaciation.
They eat and they lose weight.
Never mind how much they eat, they lose weight because they burn more than what they can eat. This is the idea.
Then we have profound debility. The debility comes once the pathology starts and you have really a deep pathology.
That means the thyroid, which is the first to break down, in Iod. cases, then once it breaks down there is great debility.
A characteristic in the mental sphere is...
...they have a compulsive neurosis and they feel always that they have forgotten something, like in Caust.
Caust. they feel they have forgotten to close
the stove, the door. Did I lock the door?
They come back, they look and see it is locked, they go away, still they can come second time.
They get up, they go to bed, the Caust. and this is a similar situation with Iod. but the Iod. on top of this
it has a compulsion for counting.
Counting the money, how much money? They put it back, they take it out, they count it again.
They go to the wardrobe. They count how many things they have in the wardrobe. They close it, they go back.
It's a compulsion to count.
The mind speeds up and controls the individual.
In compulsive neurosis we have the control of the individual by his pathology, the mind pathology.
It says motion ameliorates. Sure.
We have constant motion of eyes,
especially in cases where we have a fever.
Especially if the fever is affecting the brain.
We have a brain fever, that means encephalitis, meningoencephalitis etc. We see constant motion of the eyes.
We see atrophy of testes,
ovaries or mammae.
Where do we see undescended
testicles, in which remedy?
Aurum, who said it?