I want to give you the picture of Op. in a
nutshell and compare it with Nux-m.
You will sometimes vacillate
between these two remedies.
The reason is that both have a tendency to sleep which is so great that they can fall asleep anytime.
Who has added Ant-t?
Pierre Schmidt, maybe.
What I want to explain to you now is the kind
of sleepiness, which we have with Op.
Before I explain I want
to give you some facts.
When somebody is in coma, we say the best remedy we have to bring out of the coma a patient is with Op.  correct?
Op. produces a state in which the brain has the tendency from being sleepy to being totally asleep with coma.
In this process sleepy to coma, there are stages, in which Op. is sleeping so heavily so deeply that says, snoring.
There is a respiration which is arrested with Op. during sleep, so much that the person who sleeps
usually Op. are men, the woman does
not does not hear.... stops. Nothing.
.... are you alive?
What is the underlying pathology?
Where it's localized?
It's localized primarily in a malfunctioning
of the thyroid. Low function of the thyroid.
Low pathological function.
As a result we have obesity, Op. people
are usually fat, really fat, huge.
You have to realize now that such people who can sleep so easily, when they sleep they go so deep
into the process of sleeping.
When we want to stop somebody from being very restless, alive, we give Ritalin. What it does?
More opiates in the brain, so the person feels quite happy and can go to sleep very easily. This is the idea of Op.
This picture is the pathological picture of Op.
You remember Nux-m. The sleepiness
also is there, overpowering, why?
Because we said she is in the beginning
stages of sleep all the time.
Because the etheric body is out,
is detached already.
In order to sleep you have to
allow your etheric body to come out.
You don't do it consciously. It just happens.
But if you are anxious, if you are thinking all the time, you have a problem, you cannot sleep.
Because your mind is there, is aware. You don't allow yourself to relax and say,' I'm lying down now, I'm going to sleep'.
If you have a grief, you have been insulted, you have been rejected by your boyfriend, girlfriend.
Especially these facts will keep you awake the whole night. Because you are thinking, she insulted me or jealousy.
So in order to sleep you have to relax to let the brain flood with opiates, with serotonin more.
And then you relax, you go to sleep.
The psychological state of Nux-m. is that
she is in a wonderful, dream world.
Op. is not so much dreaming because  the opiates are much more overpowering and he just goes straight to sleep.
But all these remedies, in the process between going to sleep and be ready to sleep, they have delusions
because they are in another world. They are entering and going out to the dream world.
That is why there are delusions. All of
these remedies they have delusions.
Later on we'll speak about Cann-i.
and I will give you the comparison.
So the Op. will be used, as I said,
in the coma from whatever reason.
Whether it is a brain stroke or
whether it is a tremendous stress.
The Op. state comes when the person
has to face and unsurpassed fright.
A fright with which the person
feels I cannot deal.
Then the organism gives up at this moment and in order to survive there are opiates in the brain.
By the way, if there is an earthquake, don't move because this is an earthquake proof building.
Op. can be given once you are out but if everybody tries to get out at the same time, some injuries
will happen on the way out, not because
the building will be falling.
Once I was teaching in Rousoum Yalos, in a small room, I had put 100 people in half of this. They were packed absolutely.
And an earthquake comes and there were benches, no corridors, one had to jump over the other.
I saw some of them they stood up, ready to go out, through a small door like this, with glasses. They would break
the glasses. I said, sit down, don't be afraid. The building is safe, don't move. Nobody moved.
An earthquake that could have
killed actually because of the fear.
The earthquake is something you feel,
it's not something that you can control.
You don't know when the building will be falling but here in Greece we have been through a lot of such phenomena.
We got used to them and the buildings
are built in such a way that ...
Op. has different other symptoms but at this moment I don't want to mention, not to confuse you
because the idea is to get the total impression
of the person who needs this remedy.
I think I gave you enough
information to remember.
An interesting other remedy which
connects with Nux-m. and with Op. is Cann-i.
What Cann-i. is doing?
The first effect of Cann-i. is to create a situation in the brain where the brain is running too fast.
The brain starts being stimulated, starts
having ideas, one after another.
And these ideas have to be expressed. So the Cann-i. patient will feel that he has to understand and to express
a theory about everything.
It is something similar to Sulph.
but this situation is pathological.
It is not a philosopher who
is investigating. It is superficial.
Any problem that appears with the Cann-i.,
has to be solved and putting a theory situation.
So you have a brain that is stimulated and it is running and then it becomes loquacity.
Theorizing, loquacity. The brain is stimulated and the stimulation is such that it does not allow the Cann-i. person to stay grounded.
It flies away and that is the time when
delusions and illusions start manifesting.
Cann-i. is perhaps the number one remedy for having illusions, delusions and perceptions of hearing thing
seeing things out of reality.
You have to understand that a person who is under the control of Cann-i., cannot control anymore.
So the idea comes to the person
that I cannot control my mind.
And I need to control, I need to be grounded.
The Cann-i. peoplee they will express anxiety about their own health and mostly the anxiety
goes towards the fear of
losing their sanity, loosing their mind.
The speed with which the brain is going out of control, is bringing as a secondary effect, this fear
'I'm losing control, I'm losing my mind'.
Once that state is established, we have a syndrome with these people of panic attacks
which can really lead them to total craziness.
There is no control at all.
Can you imagine somebody 20
hours a day thinking I'm getting crazy?
Sometimes this fear becomes so big that there is tremendous panic and they need the support of the doctor
they need the support of somebody to talk.
What is important for us to understand is
that such a mind that has gone out of control...
...is ready for the mental asylum,
so severe condition.
In their delusions, during this time, they feel that their body is leaving them. They cannot control it, they cannot bring it back.
Sometimes in their panic, they will see parts
of their body... they will see the hand lifted.
Without moving the hand but
they see it coming out.
You can see how Cann-i. brings the brain in such a state where dream and reality are mixed together.
Why people get caught in this
habit of taking marihuana?
Because this pathology which we describe comes after a lot of use of marihuana, in one hand.
On the other hand comes when the
organism is weak towards this direction.
It has a weak defense mechanism and
it's ready to go out of control.
As I said other times, the young boys who are using marihuana and they go again and again and take it
if it gives them these panic attacks, they stop.
The panic attacks are so strong that after this, they stop. But the boys don't stop they usually go on and take it, why?
Because it creates a state of pleasant feelings, a state in which they say I feel that I have more love for others.
You remember the movement of Beatles, in 60's? You are young, you don't remember the 60's.
Anyhow the Beatles in the 60's they found out and they say "don't make war, make love".
That was the idea they promoted.
How came this? It was because of marihuana.
Because marihuana in the beginning stages, as it increases the pleasure in the brain, it increases the desire for sexual contact.
Therefore we have people with stimulated brains and stimulated sexual desire, which eventually is going to destroy both
the brain and the sexual desire.
In the end the people who use marihuana frequently, while they were having excessive sexual activity
eventually they become impotent.
I remember a case from (?) I remember a young man, very good looking, he was brought by an older woman
as a companion.
As I found out he could nothing
sexually but anyhow.
He gave me the story how
he had become totally impotent.
He says, 'we used with other people , we marihuana and one day in a party, I used marihuana
that was 7 times more than
the usual dose', they used to take.
They were group of men and women. He had several times, that night, sexual contact.
He says, 'when I woke up in the morning
after sleeping, I was totally finished.
I used to be a camera man in television and he says, 'I tried to go to my work and I tried to look through the camera
and it was not possible for me to
concentrate my eyes through the camera.
I was totally exhausted. I was empty emotionally, I was empty in my mind, I had no thinking. I was totally empty.'
Out of this excessive stimulation that
forced this organism to go through.
So he was really a wreck.
His case reminded me of what?
Cann-i.?
No. Not anymore.
Now the Cann-i. picture is gone and
now his picture was indicating Ph-ac.
That was a picture of Ph-ac.
I remember I told him, 'if you want, I don't know if I can cure you. Maybe you damage yourself irrepairably'.
Take this remedy and I will advise
you to go back to Italy, he was from Italy.
Go back to Italy, leave the work,
go and become a sheep leader.
Take some sheep and take them around in the mountains and let them graze and drink the milk and eat
very clean food and maybe after 2-3 years
you may get back your organism'.
I don't know whether he followed my advice or at this moment is looking at the grass from the wrong side.
Such is the effect of this wonderful spiritual drug, such is the real effect. It ends up to that state.
And some politicians  they want to let it free.
There is no problem, let it free,
let everybody become a drug addict.
And everybody knows that
marihuana is the great door to hard drugs.
They start all of them with marihuana then cocaine, then heroine and then  a hero who died at the age of 28.
This is terrible.
The one is Op. the other is a kind of opiate, yet the pictures are not the same, you cannot confuse.
Op. even if they have paresthesia, even if they have some delusions, you will never see them going into panic attacks.
Very happy.
Sometimes I have prescribed Op. without really the person having taken any Op. at all or anything like that.
From his physical pleasure that you will see, a materialistic person, who enjoys life but in a sleepy way.
Where the other one, the Cann-i.,
you will see the stimulation.
They talk, talk, they come to you and give different theories. They tell you they have an explanation
for everything which happens, you are
thinking is this a Lach. case, no. Is this that?
Then, if you know the remedy, the mind will go to Cann-i. and then if you ask about their anxiety concerning their health
from the very beginning stages,
there is already quite a strong anxiety.
Anxiety and fear. Fears, delusions, illusions, they hear noises, voices, they see phantoms, they see terrible things.
This is the situation, this is the differentiation. Op. also has many times strong constipation.
But some other times there is
constipation alternating with diarrhea.
And some other times there is diarrhea.
You don't have to have like Alum.
Alum. is a mind which is not clear.
This kind of mind is sleepy.
The mind of Nux-m. is dreamy.
The mind of Cann-i. is stimulated and
stimulated and lives in a world of ideas.
Ideas without coherence, without use.
Somebody is thinking about his job , he has some thoughts, maybe quite a lot of ideas.
This is not Cann-i. because they have purpose.
With Cann-i. people  the theories have no purpose, they have no end. They can make a theory for everything.
A mind that cannot rest. And eventually they become like invalids, not invalids exactly.
Because a lot of people they
get out of this habit. That is true.
They can get out, once they
have a little bit of power.
But almost everyone who made excessive
use of marihuana  almost everyone
has this particular mind which
is a mind, which is gullible.
They will accept anything.
You can tell them, I found a remedy which is panacea. And this remedy you can go and buy it there or find it there.
They will go and try to find the remedy. They don't examine whether this can be logical or not.
You can tell them anything.
I saw the other day a man from Sirius, I saw
him walking in our street. And they say yes.
These people say, 'oh yes!'.
Especially if you tell them things of
supernatural phenomena. They will accept.
George, why not?
Somebody was telling me that he had an
intuition that such a remedy will cure cancer.
He had an intuition, that means it's a serious thing. Let's find out about his intuition, they don't investigate.
I told you the other day about
this psychiatrist, 45 years old.
He said to me how you came in
contact with Homeopathy? I said, why?
He said 'because I hear the story'. 'What story?', 'That you were in the car and the car was crushed
the door opened, you were thrown unconscious in the street and this book fell from the sky on your lap.
You woke up, you opened the
book and you said that's it'.
I couldn't believe, he is a psychiatrist, he is attending my classes, he wants to become a homeopath.
I said, 'have you used marihuana?'
'Oh yes, sure'.
I go next day to the class, the Americans, it was a class like this size. I said, who has used marihuana?
All the hands are up. I said OK, who
has not used marihuana?
I'm talking about 1983-84, around that
time drugs were very much in fashion.
They were different ideas about these drugs that the humanity could become more spiritual, if they use marihuana.
Actually I tell you a secret.
If there was a group of people who are controlling the planet, through financial and ammunitions, armies etc.
and they wanted to make the planet, the people to be subdued and not revolt to anything they would impose
they would promote marihuana.
This group will not touch marihuana but marihuana is very good for the people, so it can spread.
And there are politicians, people with some logic, just because they used it themselves, they say why it's not good?
Cigarette? You don't dare smoke anymore, cigarette is very bad, marihuana is OK, it's free.
Can you imagine this kind of understanding in the human race, what is going to be the effect on the human race?
If you want to become a puppet and they will tell you this and you believe it, marihuana is the best.
Marihuana should be spread and everybody should take marihuana. Even Bill Clinton.
He came out publically and the journalist
said, did you use marihuana?
He said, yes I used marihuana.
Even the President of the USA admitted publically he was using marihuana.
And the people will say, why not? If Clinton who is such a clever guy uses marihuana, maybe I will become also clever
by using marihuana.
Marihuana is damaging because you
cannot force, you cannot open areas...
Our brain has all the possibilities of the world, you cannot imagine the possibilities of our brain.
But these possibilities are closed, are blocked.
You can stimulate and open some possibilities.
You can open some possibilities which
are beyond your capacity to handle.
But if you stimulate, the possibility may come and then you have what they call a spiritual experience.
But you will be paying later on for this spiritual experience because it's very interesting, very nice.
But if you repeat it again and again, one day you're going to pay and your brain will be burned out.
These are my experiences concerning the drugs.
George is conservative. I'm not conservative, I'm open to everything but at the same time I have my critical mind, right there.
You can come and tell me anything,
I will listen, I will judge it.
But if I had not the experience that I have seen all these dramatic lives, the drama in the lives of the young people.
You cannot imagine what dramas the
families of such people are going through.
I don't know in Germany today but in
Greece today the problem is dramatic.
Because we're retarded. The "good" things
are coming with retardation in Greece.
First come to America, then
England until it reaches here.
Now it has reached here the problem.
Is anybody who wants to
contradict what I have said?
That means you all agree.
The main thing is really not to go and experiment. It's a bad experiment.
When I was in India I met with an American and an English man. We investigated about spiritual people.
Both they used to take drugs. The American was in an ashram and there he had stopped. The English was free.
So they were debating and I could observe how the English would persuade eventually the American
who had stopped for a year, taking drugs and how cunningly he was trying to make him also take marihuana.
He tried with me. I said forget it.
He understood there is no place.
But the American, he could see he was ready and then he left and the American stayed with me.
And I said, 'you are fool, if you take, you
are fool'. And he said, 'maybe I will not take'.
The next day, the same. The third day,
he had taken marihuana.
-I want to tell about a patient I had once that he never took marihuana but one day he had a blow in his head
and a voice told him "Vittorio is Christ".
A delusion, without taking any drugs.
-That's absolutely. I don't say that all crazy people  have taken marihuana. No, I don't claim this.
What you describe is a case of schizophrenia where people become Napoleon or Christ or whatever.
That means there was a trauma in his brain which inflamed an area and opened an area.
-No, no. He had a stressful life at his home, with his wife and afterwards at his job who cracked down
that was overstressed. That was
the reason he got in a Cann-i. state.
And he was so happy for weeks.
And his family said, our father is crazy
we must bring him to a mental hospital.
And then they gave him a lot of
drugs and he got depressed.
-Did you treat him?
-We gave him Cann-i.
-And it had an effect?
-Of course.
-Very good.
This is what I say. You may have a blow and you don't need Arn, the organism develops a picture of a different remedy.
-It was not a physical blow. He had
like an explosion in his head.
-Yes, the same thing. It's not different.
A stress which has come over his possibility to deal with the stress, it has an effect. There is no question.
The stress was too huge for his organism to handle it and that is why the predisposition which he was having
from his parents, came up as a mental problem.
There must have been a predisposition in order with a big stress to have this change in the brain.
It's very interesting that the brain controls so much our life that whatever happens in our brain, is not possible to fight against.
You can fight against everything which happens in our body but once you get the idea in the brain
that you have cancer and this idea overtakes the brain, then forget it. Nobody can take it out from your mind.
It's so powerful. I have cancer and the word cancer brings you into a panic state.
-George could you maybe tell us about your experience with people  who are using alcohol excessively?
- The excessive use of alcohol brings to the mind remedies like Cann-i. also and when it comes to the real
deep alcoholic state where they see demons and phantoms and delusions, such remedies as Cann-i.
are the main remedies that can be
used in deep alcoholic cases.
Of course remedies that affect the liver also could be useful in alcoholic people but you see another
argument is when alcohol became
free. What happend?
The alcoholics all over the world became
from a few thousand to a few millions.
Not a few, many millions of alcoholics.
Because it's free.
If marihuana is left free, the world will go into a state of zomby. Whatever they tell you, you will say yes.
No, we are making a peaceful
revolution in medicine.
Never bombs, never kill. Only save
lives, I hope. This is my wish for you.