Well today I'm going to give you
only Materia Medica, no jokes.
I'd like to say a few things concerning the
type of Materia Medica which I'm giving.
Many of you perhaps you have noticed that in certain remedies, I speak about two sides of a remedy.
Like in Lach. I have spoken about the loquacious Lach. and a Lach. type which is very reserved and will not speak very much.
About Lyc. I have talked about the permiscuous Lyc. and also the kind of hermit, a kind of spiritual person who becomes extremely moralistic and very strict, not having sex etc.
In Medorrhinum also two different types.
And it seems that there is a kind of polarity in the remedies. The information I'm giving you- and that is very important for me and for you I believe-
the information I'm giving you is the experience of my patients, that I have seen, treating thousands and thousands of cases.
It is not an intellectualization of the remedies.
So in some cases where I have seen the different facet, I'm giving it to you, in other cases, in other remedies where I have not seen it, I'm not giving it.
I'm not giving you stories, I'm giving you facts that when you apply them, you will see they work and that is very important for Homeopathy.
I have heard a story that medical doctors, quite a lot of them, say 30-40 medical doctors, they sat there for one day, discussing why Sep. has aversion to sex.
And they are spending the whole day, discussing why Sep. has aversion to sex. And they were intellectualizing attitudes and this and that.
Everybody came out with a total confusion concerning the aversion of sex of Sep.
It's very simple, Sep. will say
'I don't like to be touched'.
You can talk about the intensity of the aversion to sex to Sep. and you may also connect it with the hormonal system but that's all.
Once you characterize that and you say this is a strong aversion to sex, Sep. does not want to be touched, she likes her husband, she is OK with him, talking etc.
But as soon it comes to sex, that is the idea of sex, not touching Sep., aversion to be touched.
You can touch Sep. without having sex desire and she will not mind. Touch Sep. with sex desire and then she will react immediately.
It's a chemical reaction to Sep., she cannot
stand that, she cannot stand to have sex.
That's all. 5 minutes. What the hell they have been discussing for one whole day?
The information I'm giving you is just my experience and not intellectualization things.
Another thing I want to show you. For instance, I've written Zincum maybe in the final form of what is going to be published, so I will give you an example how you will read and how I mean it.
It writes: the action of Zinc is primarily of the tissues of the nervous system, the central as well as the peripheral and also the meninges.
It seems to excite the nervous system and produce an irritation which initially manifests itself in a symptomatology of hyperactivity
until eventually it reaches a state of complete prostration of dullness and finally of stupor and unconsciousness.
It is through the deficiency or excess of Zinc in the tissues that the symptoms are brought about.
The main idea is that there is an erethism  of the meninges and the nervous system which can manifest itself on different levels.
We have a prominent characteristic of Zinc which is in our books do not mention frequently.
A tremendous hyperactivity of the extremities, especially of the hands and legs.
In a grown-up this may often be caused by suppressed eruption.
He will show chorea like movements, though it's not chorea movements but appear predominantly when he makes an effort to talk or to listen.
When he tries to have a conversation, for instance, with another person.
In that instant we will see a continuous
agitation of his hands and legs.
It can be explained as the result of an inner irritation of the nervous system which does not give the organism any chance to relax.
People affected on this particular level of the nervous system, which is mainly the spinal chord, will have an over active mind, being able to grasp and express ideas quite easily.
There is an abundance of ideas and so we see that we should not always expect the zinc person to be a dull minded person.
Once this erethism goes deeper, affecting areas of the brain, the person becomes disturbed on an emotional level.
He is constantly dissatisfied, nothing pleases him and he will reach a point where any noise and especially anybody talking in his presence will make him feel miserable and irritable.
No wonder that such a person is complaining constantly and about everything. His health, his family affairs, his wife, the husband, the children etc.
Not only do these patients feel miserable themselves but they also become unbearable for everyone else.
They are not getting any sympathy since they torment everybody with their complains.
Their state of mind can become so chronic that it actually becomes one with their character and the way they used to be, may be forgotten completely.
Sometimes the erethism of the nervous system can reach a degree where it even produces fits of violent anger.
Eventually a breakdown of mental functions will ensue; the mind becomes dull and there we have the first keynote of Zinc, when we see this dullness accentuated, becoming worse by drinking even a small quantity of wine.
The mind of the patient becomes slow, the thoughts start wandering or vanishing. His concentration becomes weaker and weaker.
Well this is what you are going to read. I just read you the beginning. I will not read the whole thing.
-Why not?
-It's boring.
-This is what you are going to read
and it's going to be boring.
And rightly so, why? Because you
don't use your imagination.
I will say the same things now with
my experience, what I have seen.
And you will see perhaps another way.
I mean the remedy may become
more vivid in front of you.
What I have noticed in Zinc is an irritation
of the nervous system on all levels.
A stimulation of the brain that brings about a lot of ideas. A lot of ideas are coming and they are talked about.
And there is an irritation of the peripheral nervous system and then what you see is these ideas coming and then you will see the body starts moving.
You will see some cases where, when they talk,  they will move hands, feet, the whole body is in a constant motion.
The mind is in a constant irritation, in a constant erethism. Ideas are coming, they are expressed and the whole body keeps up with this pace of ideas.
It is a super irritation, super erethism of the nervous system.
This idea comes with Zinc. When we have the excess of Zinc appearing in the body and then eventually this irritation, these ideas will slow down
and will go to the other extreme, where there is dullness of mind and he tries to think and says, 'what I wanted to say?'
And then another idea comes to the mind and then this idea is going away and then you are asking something.
Do you think that Zinc has a desire for milk?
'Do you think that Zinc has a desire for milk?
No, no I don't think'
He has to repeat what he heard
to sit in his conscious mind.
The mind is so dull that he has to repeat the question in order to understand it himself.
From that over-irritation to this dullness, there
is a kind of grades that will go through.
And then the nervous system will follow and then the meninges will be affected and will be edematous and the pressure within the brain will ensue.
Then this erethism will reach such degrees
that sometimes they will have to shriek.
It's a tremendous, a very aggressive, irritating and chilling shriek with the nervous system, that we shall see many times in children after they had a polio vaccination.
It seems that the reaction of the body creates an edema in the meninges, makes the child very restless in bed and in the night especially,
while it's sleeping, will shriek in a way
that is really frightening.
It's interesting here, I have the description of one of the doctors of the Center that had a case of that type.
She says, some relatives of mine came to my house with their child who was 4,5 months old and asked to be treated because the pediatrician had diagnosed a bronchopneumonia.
Enquiring what was wrong with the child they told me that the fever was very high and the pediatrician had given antibiotics but they seem to have no effect.
They put the child on the sofa and the child had a look that was very penetrating, she could not sleep.
Constantly was moving its legs and especially the heel of the feet.
She says, not one moment this movement stopped. It was constant.
And the mother said that these motions are on
a basis of 24 hours, the child never stops.
The child from time to time, she says, 'it would shriek some terrible shrieks that I had never experienced before and neither I want to experience again.
It was like the shrieking of an animal.
It was chilling, you cannot imagine.
And as she was sitting there with open eyes, penetrating look, she would shriek, as if it was a shriek from a dog or from a wolf.
I got a fright.'
This is very descriptive of the shriek and of the irritation that the Zinc creates in a human body.
When you have a case of Zincum then,
you have to have that intensity.
Waking the child and.... this is not Zincum.
Now you know that the parents will tell you -and this is almost every time- the parents will tell you, it was chilling. You know chills on the spine because a chilling shriek you got really a fright.
So you see the irritation of the nervous system. Then you see the movements and then you see the movement in the leg, especially on the heel, day and night.
Zinc is one of the most prominent remedies in restlessness of feet, when lying in bed, great restlessness of feet.
And with this irritation they go to bed and what happens? Big spasms, the whole night, the whole body goes like electric shocks.
The moment that they fall asleep o r while
they are asleep, Zinc is constantly pushing.
So they are from fibrilations, to twichings, to spasms, to convulsions, to jerkings, to unconsciousness.
When you have a Zinc case, you will have to have this erethism, this irritation, whether it's on the brain by these constant ideas coming over. Whether it is in the body, whether it is both.
Then you have a Zinc case.
Once I was asked to treat a mathematician. He was a mathematician and I was asked to treat him for his heart problems.
He had some heart problems, I can't
remember now, it's about 20 years ago.
I was asked to treat him for his heart problems and he was a maniac, he was talking mathematics, he was like that constantly.
I said, what is your problem? 'My problem is,
the heart here, I don't feel well'.
Go and take this case, you see 'heart-arrhythmia' and try to find the remedy, forget it about the heart symptoms.
If you don't see that...
If I did not know Zinc, how
would I have treated him?
Never with the physical symptoms
that he was describing to me.
My God what an irritation. A mathematician, he was very good mathematician of international repute.
You couldn't feel at ease at all. It was constant. I talked to him slowly, I talked suddenly, nothing. Every time he would give me an answer and he was moving up and down and ideas and mathematics...
I prescribed Zincum 1M and within two months he brought out a big skin eruption, on the top of his head.
Very ugly skin eruption of a gray, whitish color, dry, with scales, not discharging but very little.
He could not have remembered it but he said
'it might be that I had it as a child'.
Now we must remember that when we have any kind of convulsions, fibrillations, twichings which have come about after suppressed eruptions, we have to think of Zincum.
Zincum seems to have a weak kind of defense mechanism. That is why it's so much irritate, so easily irritated.
It is a weakness of the nervous system that cannot balance, cannot keep grounded the person. It's either too fast or too slow.
Then when this reaches the emotional level, it is something that cannot be expressed emotionally.
So what cannot be expressed, it remains inside as a kind of dissatisfaction and always something is wrong with something.
Zinc women especially that will go around complaining, complaining, and my child should be first in the class and now was second
my husband should earn more money than he is earning, my other child should be going to the school when it's not....Everything!
The same thing with emotional level. And then in the book what you will see, in our Repertory it says, 'torments everyone with her complaints'.
Has anybody even seen the rubric?
OK by chance you may have seen it.
What does it mean in reality?
It means that kind of dissatisfaction, of constant ... 'why this, why that, I want this, I want that'... they cry.
The woman will cry. You will say
this happens only in Greek.
Somebody came yesterday and told me the
'the husband syndrome? Not here!'
I said OK, tomorrow I make a statistic. I will say, the husband syndrome never here and if nobody talks and everybody remain serious, I will accept what you said.
It may be less but it might be still here.
So this wife also that torments everybody is not in Greece only. It is a state of mind, you may be more controlled, you may be more disciplined, you may not show.
I'm tormenting everybody with my complains, I'll try to keep on but inside the tendency is there.
So when you have your patient and then you ask, the idea will be there. The husband or the child or the daughter or some relative will tell you, yes this is what is happening.
They will tell you here, they will tell you even in Norway that this is the situation where they really torment everybody with their complain.
Considering the appearance of Zinc, they quite frequently will have a sickly appearance with withered face.
I think Kent describes it well, he says 'emaciation of body, the skin looks withered, the face pale, wrinkled, unhealthy, sickly'.
The words he is using, maybe it appears to be repeating but it is exactly, the skin looks withered, the face palid, wrinkled, unhealthy, sickly.
You see the difference now? I just told you what I have been reading to you. But now you have another idea perhaps of what you will be reading.
If you read now, with this imagination, with this intensity, then you will have the real picture of Zincum.
Otherwise you'll say... the nervous system....
all these nonsense.
Homeopathy is something alive. Something that unless you understand what is written in the books, in a vivid manner, you are not going to recognize it in the patient.
And it is mostly this information that gives you the possibility to discover a Zinc case. It is this idea.
He has to repeat the questions so that his mind can grasp their meaning. Apart from Zinc, this is also in what other remedies?
It is on another remedy which is
Causticum and sometimes Sulphur.
When we see this state of mind we also observe that the patient is making mistakes while speaking. He uses the wrong words.
His mind has become scattered and the conception of ideas is very difficult for him. It is difficult to reflect, to conceive.
One time the ideas were coming too fast, the other time is difficult to conceive ideas.
What are they talking about? And this is the time when they will be bothered very much when others are talking in front of them.
There is a talk in front of them, they are people talking and they get irritable. They will leave the room.
Not in the beginning stages. In the beginning stages, they don't care. Whether you talk or you don't talk, they have their own ideas and they can be there writing, doing their job.
There is a lot of ideas, a lot of activity going
on in their mind and there is no problem.
Once the mind becomes slow, then that's why in the books we see, conversations aggravate him. The conversation is only a noise for him because it's so fast the ideas that he cannot perceive.
Once he cannot perceive the ideas, he cannot follow them up.
Once he cannot follow the ideas, then he is irritated because what he hears is just noise.
A patient who is suffering with Zinc symptomatology seems to have very weak defense mechanism, which is easily overthrown by any kind of suppression of discharges.
Suppression of menses can bring about a symptomatology, especially spasms (clonic, tonic) and fibrillations and jerkings.
And also can produce depression, sadness which will disappear if the menses reappear.
The menses can be 3 months late, 4 months late and the woman goes into a state of depression and dissatisfaction and does not know what is wrong with her.
Then the menses reappear and the whole thing lifts up. We don't have this in other remedies. We have it in Lach. but in Lach. is before menses, pains, headaches, vertigos etc. come.
Once the flow starts, then we have the amelioration. The anxiety goes, the depression goes and the pain go. This is different.
Here we have delayed, suppressed menses and depression because of that. Menses are coming, depression is lifted.
Considering his state of mind and his difficulty in keeping up a conversation, it is easy to understand why the Zinc patient is sad and wants to be alone.
What I explained to you just now. They cannot follow the conversation, it is difficult for them.
The ideas are too fast. They just leave.
They want to be left alone.
It is the depression of his nervous
system which leads to this state.
One has to be careful not to confuse Zinc with Aurum in a case where the depression is ameliorated in the evening.
Here in Zinc, we have an amelioration in the evening. An amelioration of the general state
and in particular of the depression.
In Aurum we have the same thing.
It says, 'in the evening I am better'.
So there is depression, there is sadness, there is the idea of committing suicide because of this dissatisfaction and life is not interesting, is not joyful.
The idea of committing suicide is there and then they meditate upon committing suicide.
And once they reach the idea of really doing it, it is a reverse process which happens with Zinc.
They feel unable to carry on their decision, they are afraid, 'death!', now they are faced with the idea of death. And a peculiar calmness comes on that moment.
They meditate on death, they want to commit suicide but once they reach the point where they feel almost ready to commit suicide, then a calmness comes.
This is a keynote for Zincum which is very different from Aurum because we have said in Aurum, when they meditate on death, Aurum cases, they feel almost relieved.
Almost relieved not emotionally but in their
own minds, they say this is a possibility.
Now I have the possibility at any moment to commit suicide, to stop my life. They know they have that possibility.
'I can do whatever I like with my life. I have
the possibility to stop this suffering life'. That brings about a state of relief.
In Zincum it is calmness, it is an emotional state that comes on. In Aurum it is a mental outlet because they know 'I can stop my suffering, ah it's OK, next time'.
And both they have amelioration in the evening. Both in the evening, their depression gets ameliorated.
But the depression of Zinc and the depression of Aurum in spite of this coincidence, these similarities, has nothing to do the one with the other.
The depression of Aurum is a very serious situation, very great.
Nothing, no light at all and the idea of suicide is so strong and it comes from very deep. And they are not afraid to do it.
Zinc, the moment they think of... they say no. I don't have the courage to do it. It is inside a cowardice feeling, a state of weakness that they will not carry it on.
In Aurum it is the belief that they can
do it and they will do it.
Aurum meditates very logically 'this life has not any meaning for me anymore because I have lost...'
-actually they may have lost nothing, what they feel is- 'I have lost the possibility in my job to advance
people in my work don't anymore appreciate me. My wife does not appreciate me, my children do not need me anymore'.
Every department of their life, when they meditate it is a dark area. Therefore they meditate upon committing suicide for long period.
And when they find themselves in a high place, I have been described this by patients, several times, when they arrive to a high balcony with all this depression
with all this suffering they go through, it's a tremendous depression like a steel sitting on their chest. Something metallic, it's a terrible feeling.
They look down and they say, 'this is
your chance now, jump'.
This is when they jump actually. That is why Aurum usually commits suicide by jumping from a high place.
It is the peculiarity of Aurum to have the impulse to commit suicide, when he is on a high place.
Outwardly they may appear to be similar in
their depression but there is no comparison.
For the one who knows, he will hear somebody telling his symptoms he will say no, no this is not Aurum or this is not Zinc. Wait a moment, be careful.
We had once a girl of 18-20 years old, quite young, in an Aurum state. She really wanted to commit suicide.
We gave Aurum and I said to the doctor who was attending the case to advise her to lock the door inside the room.
To agree that for 2-3 days she will lock the room and stay in the room without the possibility of jumping and she stayed locked for two days.
During this, after taking the remedy, she said, 'constantly I was thinking of suicide. She was going to do it any moment and I would not like to take the remedy and jump'.
You understand what is the situation, so when you have that situation, put somebody to guard that patient fro 2-3 days before he goes out of the depression.
Don't tell 'take Aurum and go'. Because he may just take Aurum and jump at the same time.
You never know. You don't give time for the remedy to act. You have to protect your patient. So it is very important because you may lose a case like that.
Concerning now his sexual life, how do
you think that Zinc will behave?
-Strong desire.
-Very strong desire.
It's the erethism which affects the sexual desire irritates, brings a desire which is very strong to the extend you may call it violent desire for sex.
If you go to the Repertory and you look, you will see 'sexual desire-increased': capital. 'Sexual desire-violent': capital. You will see Zinc is capital in all this.
What happens is, he is so excited when he is with a woman that usually what happens is that because of over excitement, there is a very easy ejaculation.
It comes to orgasm too fast and therefore Zinc is one of the main remedies for easy ejaculation together with Lyc. and Graph., for different reasons.
But you will see the erethism, the easy excitement, excited easy, you will see it in capital. 'Desire violent': capital. Very strong for Zinc.
And this desire usually remains when the mind is dull, the desire for sex still is quite strong and of course very easy orgasm.
So the erethism of the nervous system can appear as twitching all over the body and especially the extremities, as jerking, spasms, convulsions.
You will see this motion of the head which is characteristic also on another remedy.
Helleborus.
They had this rolling from one side to
the other and the hands are moving.
You see this erethism sometimes, I don't think you will see it here, I have seen it in India in a case of pinworms.
They have it a lot there, this child was full of pinworms and he was like that.
You will see this aggravation, I don't know physiologically how is the connection between pinworms and the nervous system.
But it is known that convulsions
can come about after pinworms.
You will not see actually this type of cases because you will get only in the hospital. But anyhow just as an information is interesting.
Chorea-like movements and these spasms
can reach a state of total unconsciousness.
You see it will be spasm like that and it will be unconscious the child or the grown-up.
The erethism can reach a state of violent delirium characterized by efforts of the patient to get away. He will try to get up and go away.
He may become very agitated, very irritable, very angry and he may need restrain to keep him in bed.
In Zinc attention should be paid to the constant movement of the extremities, especially of the feet, when lying in bed and to the automatic movements of the head.
I will give you some little details because this is easy to remember now.
Now you know Zinc.
You will have headaches which are peculiar. What is the peculiarity?
Occipital pains with a tendency to roll the head and at the same time you will see the same movements on the head, as you see in spasms.
He will roll the head like that and move
the hands, in strong headaches.
Another characteristic of the headaches is a headache with different degrees of temperature within the head.
The forehead can be cool and the
occiput can be warm.
And another characteristic of headaches, I'm giving you keynotes, is diarrhea during headache.
If every time he has headache, he says 'I have
a diarrhea', then this becomes a keynote.
In the eyes you will see rolling of the eyes, movements like rolling in the eyes and also stitching pains in the inner canthi, here. Very intense.
Also an inflammation of the
conjunctiva during menses.
This can be seen also in Arsenicum.
And also you can see strabismus.
Cracks in the corners of the mouth with twitchings in the face and cracked corners, Zinc.
They move their feet, they jerk, Zinc.
You will not get every time all the intensity I'm describing. You will get the idea, the erethism.
She can be moving the head and has these intense ideas but she will not tell you I have a lot of ideas.
You have to perceive that, you have
to see really what is happening.
Everybody likes to say he has a lot
of ideas but Zinc is really vivid.
And also in the mouth we have very easy looseness of teeth. The teeth become loose very easily and they fall off.
In the stomach we have gastritis
which is aggravated by wine.
Wine aggravates the nervous system, little wine and then the stomach, little wine, great pains.
There is an indigestion and sour vomiting.
A feeling of emptiness in the stomach like Sulphur around 12 o'clock.
Also what aggravates the stomach is
bread, milk and veal.
Vomiting occurs immediately after eating, in cases of gastritis, like which other remedy?
Like Ferrum Metallicum.
Colic pains immediately after eating, especially in the morning, breakfast and in the evening, dinner.
Also if you see an aggravation of his colic
pains, he says, 'don't talk, don't talk'.
They feel more aggravated by talking, by noises, especially talking, human voices. Then it can be Zinc.
In the urinary sphere we have the characteristic keynote, especially in prostate gland swollen, we have the keynote that he can pass urine only if he sits and leans back.
At the same time we have paralysis of the bladder with difficulty to void urine, to expel urine.
And many times involuntary urination.
We may have a hysterical almost paralysis of the bladder, especially in women and inability to urinate.
Involuntary urination during convulsions and during coughing or sneezing  is also Zinc.
Zinc usually has constipation but if you find that the person has a normal stool and when he drinks wine, there it comes constipation, that's only Zinc.
Also talking about sex in women, we have great erethism, desire for frequent intercourse and, as a result, we may have almost nymphomania.
In the respiratory system we have a keynote, cough aggravated if he eats sweets, if he eats something sweet, the cough will be aggravated.
There is a characteristic of the back pains with Zinc. The worse position for Zinc is seating, for the back ache.
Spots of pain in the lower back also can
be characteristic, in the sacral region.
And also the pain in the cervical area that makes the head go backwards, it is a drawing backwards of the head. That is also characteristic.
In the extremities, we have extreme weakness, trembling, twitching of muscles.
At around 11 o'clock when he has this hungry feeling, his legs immediately become weak and trembling.
Or he may have a difficulty, a pianist playing the piano, when they experience sudden great weakness in playing the piano.
That can be a characteristic of Zinc.
Trembling of the extremities with fever in bed. You don't get this irritation but the whole legs are trembling with fever.
If you get pain in the heels after drinking wine, this is a keynote.
These things you will see once in your life. Some of these keynotes but when you get this, you remember it.
The story I was going to tell you before the interval was how I started with Homeopathy.
I had an accident with my car and I didn't have anything to read. So I telephone a friend of mine, what was that black book of Homeopathy he was reading?
He said, Boericke's Materia Medica. I was in South Africa, I went down from another town to Johannesburg and I bought the book.
And because I did not have a car, I got into the bus to go back home. In the bus I started reading the book.
I read that book until Monday I had
read that book right through.
I don't think anybody has done that ever.
But it was so exciting for me.
It was revelation and a kind of a fever that
would not allow me to put down the book.
I was reading the book. I read it in the bus, I read it in the house, I went to eat in the restaurant and read the book.
And until Monday I'd finished the book where
I returned back and bought more books.
I've never regretted for reading that book because there are small remedies.
Of course I read it again and again, later on but there are small remedies that you will need them once in your life time.
But if you don't have that anamnesis, that knowledge somewhere, something has stuck into your mind which was impressive about the small remedy and then you hear it from the patient.
And you say, wait a moment, you go back to your memory and say, I read it exactly as he said it.
And many times I have remembered the
remedy and I have done a beautiful cure.
Concerning little things I gave you about Zincum, maybe you will not find them in every Zincum case but if you remember you may be able to make a beautiful cure.
I think I have given you most of the
important things of Zincum.
Also another characteristic with extremities is extreme numbness of the extremities when lies in bed.
In sleep, as we said, we have a hyper activity and restlessness and shrieks of the type that we described.
Many times they will wake up in a
frightened look in their eyes.
In the skin we have eruptions which appear slowly. Again the weakness on the defense mechanism, they will not blow up.
Zincum eruptions are easily suppressed.
If you see in the history a skin eruption that was suppressed within a day, with an ointment think of Zincum.
And we have convulsions in epidemic diseases which they suppose to break out with an eruption and the eruption does not come.
When you have convulsions because the eruption does not appear, think of Zinc.
In generalities, we have Zincum aggravated by cold and cold bathing.
Eating generally ameliorates and
tremendous weakness after a fit of anger.
As they are excited, they go into fits of anger where they shout, they express themselves very vividly
and then there is a period of hours
of great weakness.