We'll be talking about Zinc today.
The action of Zincum is primarily upon the nervous system, the central and peripheral
and also on the meninges.
It seems to excite the nervous system and produce an irritation,
which initially manifests itself in a symptomatology of hyper-sensitivity, hyper-activity.
Hyper-activity, which eventually reaches a state of complete prostration in the physical body
and of dullness and stupor and even unconsciousness in the mental level.
It is still the deficiency or excess of Zinc in the tissues that symptoms are brought about.
Excess of Zinc within the body or deficiency.
We have a hyper-activity, especially of the extremities,
which seems to come from a kind of irritation of the meninges.
A hyper-activity that is sometimes so much prominent that the individual will act...
you get the impression from the individual whether he is talking
that his ideas are so fast and his body is moving all about
that there is constant motion and hyper-activity.
I cannot reproduce the state...
There is a constant motion of all the muscles of the body
that allows almost no relaxation at any moment.
There is such an irritation, especially when the mind is active, that the whole body is moving also.
I don't know if you have come across the typical Zincum patient.
People that are active in their mind and they make grimaces, they make movement,
the hands are moving, the head is moving, everything is moving.
You get the idea that it is constant motion.
Now, this motion can be as I described or the motion can be motion in smaller muscles,
twitchings and quiverings of the muscles.
The initial level is that the mind is over active also and abundance of ideas are coming
with the Zinc and this over activity ends up finally into a dull state
or a prostration state that we see in Zincum many times or in Zinc picricum, more especially.
Once this disturbance goes deeper, on the emotional level,
then we see on the emotional side an individual who is constantly on a dissatisfied state,
constanly complaining.
Nothing pleases him and he will reach a point where any noise, especially people talking,
human voices will irritate him tremendously.
And he will feel miserable and he will start complaining, complaining...
They complain constantly about everything, about their own health, their family affairs,
their wives or the husbands, children etc.
Not only these patients feel miserable themselves
but they also become unbearable to everyone around.
They get no sympathy from anybody around because of tormenting everybody
with their complaints. They change their personality.
Once they are coming to a Zincum state, their character seems to change
and become a complaining person, all the time, that torments everybody with his complaints.
Why you did that and dissatisfaction...
People do not recognize them anymore. How did this person change?
Sometimes this erethism inside will reach such a high tension
that it will produce fits of anger, violent anger.
Eventually they will break down mental function will ensue their mind will become dull
and here we have the first keynote of Zinc, where we see that dullness is worse by drinking
even the smallest quantity of wine.
The mind of the patient becomes slow, his thoughts start to wandering,
he cannot concentrate his mind and sometimes vanishing.
This description will be good for what? For students.
Especially students who they have to use their mind in a very methodical way,
students of mathematics can become Zinc cases.
When they have thought a lot, it is all this activity which goes on and on and on
and then the mind eventually slows down, becomes dull and they cannot take anymore.
They try to concentrate and thoughts are flying away.
Their thoughts are vanishing, their mind is wandering all around, they are tired in their mind.
This weak state of mind will produce a peculiar state in the mind,
where the person in order to answer a question has to repeat it first.
This is very characteristic of Zincum.
If somebody, before answering a question, first repeats the question, then it becomes Zincum.
This symptom you will find also in Causticum and Sulphur.
When he is in that state, we observe also that the Zincum cases are making mistakes in speaking
or they use the wrong words.
As the mind is scattered all over the conception of ideas is difficult.
The confusion is mostly in the morning and, as we said before, after drinking wine.
The typical Zincum patient is a patient with a weak kind of defense mechanism,
which seems to be easily suppressed
and that is why we have convulsions, quivering, twitchings, after suppressed eruptions.
After suppression of menses we may have depression, sadness
and in the course of the day depression may come at noon or afternoon,
while in the evening hours Zinc is ameliorated.
Due to the fact that his mind is so slow, you also find
that the Zinc person wants to be by himself, he does not want to associate, he wants to be alone.
It is a kind of depression that leads him to isolation.
There is also another remedy which has depression,
which can be ameliorated in the evening,
which is the Aurum or it can be worse in the evening in the depression
and maybe also ameliorated in the evening, we can have both.
But Aurum usually has an amelioration of his general pains and state in the evening.
But in Aurum the depression is much deeper and much more serious.
The Aurum depression is an emotional state, the depression of Zinc is a mental state.
It is a tiredness from mental state that brings about depression.
The Aurum is a weak state of emotions.
The Aurum thinks that to get away from this life it's a relief.
The Zincum patient thinks that maybe it's good to commit suicide
but when really he is faced with the situation, he will never do it.
He is too coward to do it.
He does not have the nerve to really kill himself but the idea of death
with Zinc brings inside him finally a calmness.
It's a keynote for Zinc, when thinking about to die, there is a calmness that comes
and also he is too coward, he does not have the courage to do it, to commit suicide.
The irritation of the meninges will create especially in children a peculiar state
that is best depicted by the description of one of my students in Greece,
where she described a state...
She said that she was visited in her place by some relatives, who brought their child,
four months old and were asking from her to treat the child
because the child was with bronchopneumonia and they wanted her to give it antibiotics.
The fever was very high.
The child had been given some antibiotics from another doctor but the fever did not drop
and she says they kept the child in the sofa
and the child had a peculiar penetrating look in his eyes.
A look, she says, that was terrifying to look and see.
The child, in spite of staying for a long time in the house, kept constantly awake.
He did not want to sleep and constantly he was moving his legs, especially the heels.
She says, not a minute stopped doing that, it was terrible.
The mother said that he is doing this motion 24 hours constantly,
even when he was sleeping the motion was there, from the heels.
From time to time the child shouted some shouts that were penetrating and terrible.
She describes it, really terrible.
I've never heard, she says, such shrieking and I don't want to hear it again.
As if an animal like a wolf or a dog was shrieking, she says. It was bringing chills to me.
She says, as he was sitting there with his eyes like that, distended like that, he would...
You understand the irritation inside in the meninges, the high fever and then this feeling
which I've been described many times, this feeling of chills that comes when you hear
that penetrating voice from these children.
It's a very good description, though it is in Greek, I try to translate it.
She says, I came out and I was afraid and she said what is that?
Actually I remember this conversation, she was telephoning me.
I made her to reproduce it later and write it down.
This is a typical Zinc case, she telephoned me and she gave Zinc 10M, I think.
Within two hours the child was calm, the fever was dropped.
At the same evening the child played nicely in the house before they went home with the Zinc 10M.
The child was OK, it stopped all this.
It started eating because he was not eating for a few days and he had become cachectic.
This is another idea of Zinc. They look quite cachectic.
Do you know the word cachectic? Dried up, withered.
What happened is that the child after 20 days went back to her the SABIN repeated.
He had the first dose of SABIN before the incident and a repetition of SABIN,
the vaccination for poliomyelitis.
He had this vaccination 20 days after that incident and the mother telephoned again
to this doctor and she said that since two days after the vaccination,
the child was in the same condition, without fever now.
She asked whether did she take any other antibiotics or anything else,
she said nothing on the telephone and then 5-6 hours later she telephoned to tell
that the thing had started after the repetition of the SABIN.
She said I would never imagine that this was there and again Zinc
and the child was immediately calmed down.
This kind of erethism you will see many times after this vaccination for poliomyelitis
in the young children and when they will tell you about this shriek, especially in the night...
There is a shriek which usually it bring chills, something not human in that shriek.
So the erethism of the nervous system can appear as twitching all over the body
and especially in the extremities,
as jerkings, spasms, chronic or tonic convulsions.
Jerking is a great characteristic when they fall asleep, during sleep,
while falling asleep and during sleep, they will have great jerks.
Chorea like movements. It's not actually chorea but it's like chorea.
The head will roll into the pillow.
Sometimes you will have consciousness and unconsciousness coming and going.
The child comes out of consciousness, then he subsides.
They can reach a state of violent delirium, characterized by effort of the patient to get away.
He wants to get up and get away from his bed.
He may become so agitated and aggressive that he can be restraint only with great difficulty.
So in the Zinc suffers we have from the head various kinds of headaches,
especially headaches on occiput with the tendency to roll the head
and constant movements of the hands, of the upper extremities.
Also a characteristic is different temperature in front than in back.
Here, in front can be cold and here, it can be warm.
And diarrhea during headache is a keynote.
The other remedy that has that - diarrhea during headache - is Belladonna.
In the eyes we have convulsive movements and rolling of the eyes.
Stitching pains in the inner canthi.
It is one of the main remedies that has it. The only one that has it so strong.
And itching here in the inner canthi, which is aggravated by rubbing.
The more they rub, the more is aggravated.
Inflammation of the conjunctiva during menses is another keynote.
We see it also in Arsenicum.
Irritation on the conjunctiva, redness of the eye during menses and photophobia with strabismus.
The face of Zincum is pallid and wrinkled.
Kent writes emanciation throughout the body, the skin looks withered.
The face pallid, wrinkled, unhealthy. It's a very good description of the face.
Lot of wrinkles, unhealthy and in the history of the person moving, moving all about...
This kind of motion, moving all about and then in the history of the person a big eruption
that has been suppressed.
A lot of thinking, a lot of ideas all the time, mathematicians.
We have cracks in the corners of the mouth and twitchings in the face, a lot of twitchings.
This is the remedy, where somebody will tell you a lot of twitchings, a lot of jerkings,
a lot of this activity, your mind will not go to Agaricus.
It's another type, we'll describe Agaricus.
It's a lot of activity, in the nervous system an irritation, irritation...
That's how you have to imagine it. And then activity, activity, activity.
And then the mind slows down, it becomes dull and then if they drink a little bit of wine
the mind more dull, they cannot think. Looseness of teeth another characteristic.
The teeth become very easily loose, they move.
All complains like stomach pains aggravated by a little bit of wine, think of Zinc.
It has an aversion to fish, it's not in our Repertories, aversion to sweets and wine
and desire for beer and cold drinks in the summer.
Bread and milk can aggravate the stomach situation.
Vomiting immediately after eating or drinking, like Ferum.
Cramping pains in the abdomen aggravated by human voices, by people talking in the room.
They are irritated in their nervous system and they seem to take the impact in the ...
In the urinary sphere we have a keynote which is ...
they can pass urine only when sitting and leaning backwards
Sudden inability to urinate, especially in hysterical people.
Hysterical people that suddenly they cannot urinate and involuntary urination during convulsion.
Also when sneezing, coughing, laughing.
In the sexual sphere we have excessive erethisms very much irritation
they get very excited sexually and that is why we have the symptom of early, easy ejaculation,
premature ejaculation.
They get So much excited, so much involved emotionally that they have very easy ejaculation
like Lycopodium, like Graphites, Sulphur.
Also discharge of prostatic fluid during stool is a characteristic symptom.
In women we have again excessive sexual desire that can lead to nymphomania.
In the respiratory track we have the peculiarity, cough aggravating when eating sweets.
Zinc generally is aggravated by cold and cold bathing.
Ameliorated in general by eating and tremendous weakness after a fit of anger, irritability
and then exhaustion.
Great exhaustion after great expression of irritability. They have a fit of anger,
they express anger and then they have great exhaustion. General exhaustion.
There is hyperactivity in the sleep, sleeping restlessness and shrieking.
and a constant motion of the feet and jerking movements.
Tremendous restlessness of the feet.
The feet, as I described in the young child, all the great movements and twitchings are there,
it's an alive individual. We don't see anxieties, fears etc.
We see this great erethism and then we may see also the opposite state.
Great irritation, great emotionality and great depression, great ideas and great dullness,
great sexuality and sometimes the opposite, impotency.
More or less this is what we have as characteristics of the Zinc case.
-What is the difference between the shriek of a Zincum and Apis?
-The only difference is that Zinc is much more found in children,
especially of today, where they have been vaccinated by the polio vaccination
and after a few days they develop that. This is mostly Zincum.
I found that Zincum will calm down this symptom.
Apis is not like this, it's something...
Everytime they describe to me this shriek, there is this expression.
There is a chill. I cannot reproduce it because...
Apis can shout but it's more human.
You may be lucky to hear it once in your life because the parents will describe it to you
but when the parents will describe, they will describe this feeling of terror
that comes with the shriek.
-Are you often to prescribe Zincum as a constitutional remedy?
-Often no, not often. When you say often, you mean all the time, no, not often.
You have to give some Zincum, otherwise...
You see, unfortunately we have to know the remedy to use it once in a lifetime.
Sometimes you will use it only once but somewhere in the back of your mind
some information about that remedy must be there.
Zincum is not once in a lifetime.
Zincum cases you will be using - if you have a very busy practice - at least once in six months.
-Can you speak about the difference between Zincum and Tarentula?
-No, there is no comparison. Tarentula is another state altogether
we don't talk about this twitching, this irritation.
Everything is irritated. We don't talk about this with Tarentula.
Tarentula is mostly when we see the restlessness and the hurried feeling inside,
the hurried feeling of Tarentula.
It's not so much twitchings, convulsions like we have in Zincum.
Don't ask me questions of that type now.
Jerking in the night is a keynote, especially when you have...
Sometimes, if you don't prescribe it constitutionally, you will have somebody
who is very much irritated during the day, there is some kind of erethism.
And in the night they go to sleep, all the time jerking, jerking, jerking.
If that continues and establish itself as a pattern, then Zinc will take care.