I shall be talking to you this morning about Ranunculus bulbosus.
So Ranunculus bulbosus cases I would say they are touchy.
Touchy is somebody who is very easily offended, you tell something
and they are offended very much, so they are touchy, discontented and angry.
These persons are closed persons.
And they will give you the sense that they are weak and they are looking for help,
they will ask for help.
They will ask for help in a very respectful manner, you see it inside, Mr. Professor.
I remember a case that has been treated in the Center for chronic headache
and symptoms and all kind of things and he approached me in a very respected manner and
says Mr. Professor, we will not be able to see you for a while etc.
I gave him Sulphur, Dulcamara etc. but he was very faithful, he was coming
and then I treated him and I recognized the Ranunculus state.
Why this attitude? You combine now this touchiness, very easily offended,
discontented inside and a deep angriness with an outside appearance of please help me,
I know you are the greatest, great respect, please help me and underneath all that you recognize
a kind of anxiety which is going on concerning their health.
An anxiety which will never be admitted. They will not say I'm anxious about my health, no.
They feel that their ailments are so difficult and so peculiar
that most probably something serious is going on and therefore it is very justified to seek help
and to seek the best possible help.
Bulbosus state brings about a state of weakness generally
that will not allow the individual to work, to do his usual work
or if the case is not very serious, it's a vital syndrome, it's not a serious condition,
they will keep on going to their work but they will avoid any kind of further responsibility.
They feel they are too sick to undertake.
They are discontented but they are not ambitious, they are not ambitious and in their job
if they offer them a promotion that requires more activities and responsibilities,
they will not take it. They will try to avoid.
I mean the natural thing is to say, yes thank you, I will take it.
Not the Ranunculus bulbosus because they feel inadequate.
This touchiness, this easily offended and this discontent and this angriness
which comes out from time to time under stress, great angriness you will see.
It' so proper this man, it's so typical, formal, how he behaves now in such manner?
And also censorious, critical, the anxiety will appear more like a hypochondriasis.
They will deal with matter again and again that are not important,
especially concerning their health.
Another element which is there is a sense of lack of self-confidence.
With the outside people very respectful, very formal, very proper, with the people
that are closed to them it seems that the emotions are kept and they are brought out suddenly
and they have sudden outburst of anger.
The touchiness will go through all element, mind, emotional and also physical.
Touching them, pressure aggravates them.
For instance they will wear something, they will press the abdomen, they will press here,
they will press a point and all this will aggravate.
So many times you may confuse that with Lachesis.
The proper contact that they have adapted is always towards, for instance, not to smoke,
not to drink alcohol, it's not proper but you see this is an intellectualization
that has come about them and alcohol makes them very bad. They feel all the ailments,
especially the pain and more especially the headache aggravates tremendously by alcohol.
They are not alcohol drinkers out of properness but even most of the cases
if they do drink even a little, they have a big aggravation from alcohol.
So they don't like to be touched, affects them, alcohol affects them.
This proper sense goes through their sexual lives as well.
Usually are oversexed. But while they are oversexed,
they will not expressed their sexual feelings during their sexual act.
They will just be very quiet, very proper, they will try even there to be proper,
in sexual contact. It is a silent sexual act.
Alcohol makes them feel intoxicated very easily.
Now even without alcohol Ranunculus bulbosus will have the feeling of intoxication.
So in cases when you have headaches, when you have cervical syndrome
where the cervical vertebrae are affected  and there is pressure in the vascular system
and there is not very good oxygenation, the first symptom is dizziness
and the pressure here is stiffness around their neck and a dizziness
which eventually ends up into severe headaches, which are mostly on the right side
and mostly inside the eyes, which are aggravated by touch, aggravated by alcohol
and aggravated by cold and damp weather.
So you have this idea now, this man who is suffering with this cervical syndrome,
the dullness, the discontent, the suffering that he projects much more than he feels it maybe.
And then the formal thing, Mr. Professor will you be able to do something about my case?
The inferiority complex has a peculiarity, they may talk about their inabilities but deep
down they will feel they are being better than others.
In private talking they will say, I'm doing much better the work than him
but if proposed a promotion, they will say no, I'm not good enough for promotion
and things like that.
But they are critical, that's why it says censorious.
I will just read you from the Repertory from the mind, it says abusing anger,
which comes when? When he is very much close to his family only.
And ailments from anger, anger is so strong sometimes that will leave a kind of depression,
malaise feeling and not feeling well.
Censorious, concentration difficult, has a vacant feeling on attending to think.
You see this lack of oxygenation and usually the pressure here brings a feeling of malaise,
you can not talk, complete discontent.
I remember a case in 1968 that he kept on coming, exactly that picture.
He kept on coming for one and a half year, we prescribed... and nothing and I was desperate.
Then eventually the poor man left us when I recognized Ranunculus bulbosus
it was too late for him.
It was a case of Ranunculus bulbosus and I had prescribed Rhus tox,
Bryonia, Dulcamara, and he would say the exposal to cold,  the stiffness here,
the wet weather and then he was exactly that kind of person "would you please"
and he was coming one and a half, two years, I can't remember how long, without any offend,
we prescribed a remedy.
We finally went to the most sophisticated remedy, not Ranunculus bulbosus.
We did nothing, we lost him.
Confusion of mind, coward, discontented, dullness, escape, exertion aggravates,
from mental exertion.
He can not take mental exertion.
If he tries, he says I'm too sick, I don't want to think, I don't want to make more
but they are fastidious, proper people, they are able to do things.
They are able to accomplish and they are superiors, they like them.
And they like to promote them, they will say, no. Mental exertion aggravates.
There is also a general aggravation in the evening.
A general aggravation in the evening is characteristic.
And he is forgetful, indolent, irritability we will see in Ranunculus bulbosus in capital,
especially in the evening.
And we see loathing at work, you see the effort at work.
You see the doctor comes and says, now you are good enough to work.
You don't understand, I feel very bad, I can not go to work. That is the attitude.
You see in the Repertory here and there but to synthesize and to say
this is the picture I'm giving you.
Offended easily, quarrelsome, also restlessness is a characteristic of Ranunculus bulbosus
that will make you feel that it is Rhus tox. You will confuse Ranunculus with Rhus tox
because the restlessness is there but Ranunculus bulbosus is worse from motion.
Motion will not help so much. He is restless and he wants to go up and down
but he will not be ameliorated by motion.
Dullness of senses, vanishing of senses, inclination to sit,
complains from thinking aggravates his situation.
And violent also. He has some anger sometimes, the anger sometimes is so much
that it appears violent anger.
Ranunculus bulbosus is a remedy that mostly will cover arthritic, rheumatic conditions
and skin condition.
But they have a sphere of action around the chest, the muscles of the chest
are affected very much and also the bronchial and the lungs can be affected
with the typical left sided pain in Ranunculus bulbosus.
In Ranunculus therefore we will see the herpes zoster developing in the left side,
the intercostal neuralgias developing mostly on the left side
and the pneumonia developing on the left side.
Characteristic is a pain in a spot with circumscribed circle
upon the chest and the sternum.
Also it has pain on the inner side of the scapula while sitting and knitting.
With this inner motion, especially the women, they will have severe pain in the inner side
of the scapula that will make her very uncomfortable and they will have to give up...
I have seen this with Rush tox, with Kali bichromicum.
Sometimes Kali Bichromicum, the best remedy is Ranunculus bulbosus and Pulsatilla.
What is interesting as a general element is the worse from cold,
they are very worse cold generally and especially walking to a cold weather.
They feel the cold penetrates them absolutely and especially the painful spots.
The painful spots are aggravated by cold, walking especially.
They feel some kind of pressure, as they walk against the cold
they feel aggravated very much in their painful spots.
If we have a case, a situation where we have worse in the evening,
worse from touch and worse from exposal to cold,
this tripod you have to think of Ranunculus bulbosus.
Worse evening, worse touch, worse exposure to cold,
most probably is a case of Ranunculus bulbosus.
Ailments from anger can bring about a kind of trembling, twitching
and sometimes you may have an epileptic who has fits of epilepsy after anger;
we will be thinking of Ranunculus bulb.
There is also an anxiety which comes concerning their future.
Anxiety about their future and the family, this comes in the proper element.
They want everything to be safe, therefore they have an anxiety about future,
their own work, their own family but they will not do anything really
that requires an effort to better a situation.
Physical or mental exertion aggravates them.
The anxiety is felt mostly in the chest and many times in the heart region.
Coldness in chest in spots and when he is breathing cold air makes it worse.
The pain that is on the muscular system of the chest
when breathing cold air makes it much worse.
Either the cold that comes and touches them from outside or the cold air
which they inhale makes worse the pain.
And coldness in the sternum we have Ranunculus bulbosus capital, the only medicine.
I remember a case with Ranunculus that has been a distinguished spot in chest worse with cold air.
Inflammation on lungs and pleura with these type of pains, with the aggravation from cold air,
from inhale etc.
So motion aggravates like Bryonia but not to that extend, we do not have the motion aggravates
to that extend that we see it in Bryonia.
I think I gave you the basics of Ranunculus bulbosus with some little details
that you will be able to find in the Repertory.