There are skin eruptions which are much more mild and skin eruptions which are the externalization of a dysfunction of a vital organ
like liver or the absorption system which is going wrong or the hormonal system which is going wrong; therefore we have different degree of severity on skin eruptions.
I have tried to give you an idea
of a hierarchy of skin eruptions.
Which skin eruptions are bad, which
are good and which are in between.
This is not absolute but just as an indication.
Which group is the least disturbing?
What's your experience?
A group of skin disorders, the simplest, I found that something can be really cured quite easily is just simple cracks of the skin.
Another skin disorder which can be easily cured, is ulcers. Ulcers are easily cured and impressively.
Even sometimes you have indolent ulcers,
ulcers that are because of a bad circulation.
And you find the homeopathic remedy
and you see this ulcer disappearing.
And then you have these benign growths,
like condylomata and warts.
It's another class of skin eruption
which are easily manageable.
And then another class is carbuncles, boils, which start to be more difficult and then acne, mostly in the face and in the back, quite difficult.
Then you have the allergic eruptions. The more you go to these categories, the more difficult.
And then you have eczema. Then
you have neuro-dermatitis, worse.
Herpetic eruptions. Psoriasis.
Lupus erythematosus.
And finally malignant growths like epithelioma and also the Kaposi's sarcoma which appears in the last stages of AIDS.
Malignant growths in general which
you are treating really cancer.
So we shall be talking in the next hour about these different groups of skin eruptions and I will give you some indications of how you may be dealing with them.
We're talking about cracks, cases where you will see as the main skin problem, cracking of the skin.
The two main remedies that you will be thinking in such a case where the cracking of the skin is very apparent and very prominent, will be Sars. and Petr.
Also other remedies that should come to your mind is Calc., Carb-s., Graph., Nit-ac., Puls., Sep. and Sulph.
Concerning Sulph. I would like to make a general remark. I would say always look for Sulph. and give it with great caution.
Sulph. covers every skin eruption that you can imagine and it may be indicated, but may be.
Be aware of Sulph. because it will come prominent every time but it's not that every time is indicated.
As a general idea have in mind that Sulph. eruptions usually are accompanied by itching.
It's very seldom that you will see a skin eruption that requires Sulph. and there is no itching.
I shall be mentioning in my remarks many times, Sulph. but you have to be very careful because Sulph. can take care of the local eruption, without being really indicated.
Most probably in most of the cases it will aggravate the case, it will make the skin eruption much bigger without real amelioration.
You see in Homeopathy when you have an aggravation is very good. With Sulph. what happens is usually you say, oh you have an aggravation that's very good.
And the aggravation comes 1 day, 2 days, 2, 3 weeks, 5 months, nothing happens. That's no good.
That means that the remedy was close but not exact. So Sulph. can really aggravate the case without bringing about cure.
Sometimes also you will see taking away a portion of the eruption. It will take away the itching, it will take away some local eruptions.
From one locality it will take it away, another locality will stay. That kind of reaction be aware,  is not a curative response.
In order to have a curative response with skin eruptions, you will have to have an aggravation which does not last  usually more than one week.
It's very seldom that this aggravation will continue for more than 2 or 3 weeks.
And then always when that is a curative aggravation, always there is an amelioration on the mental, emotional level, the general state of health and the general energy.
So a good response from a remedy will be accompanied by an amelioration of other levels.
Energy, general state,
mental-emotional state.
When I mention remedies, I will give a few hints here and there in different eruptions. It does not mean that these are the only remedies that are going to be indicated in such a case.
There are other remedies as well but
I mention the most prominent ones.
And also examine your case in its general picture, in its mental-emotional picture and try to fit everything with the remedy that you're deciding.
Don't just go and give.
Sometimes there are some good results by using one keynote. For instance you're using Petr. for cracks but Petr. will not do the case.
Cracks that come only during winter. In Sars. goes away.
I told you Sars. is the main remedy for cracks. Deep cracks, constant cracks. Especially where? In the feet. The cracks of Sars. are in the feet.
Petr. it can be anywhere. Now if the cracks are worse in winter, then it becomes Petr. more.
And also Calc. because of the aggravation from cold. Also Sep. comes now into picture.
And Carb-s. also.
If the cracks are very painful, Sars. comes into picture, with Petr. second and then Nit-ac.  comes into the picture.
If the cracks are in the heel of the foot,
which other remedy is very prominent?
It's Lyc.. Also another remedy which is
not in the Repertory. It's Calc-f.
But if the cracks are on the tips of the fingers, the remedy that is the number one you would think, is Graph.
But if the cracks are general in the hand, fingers in general and hand, then again Petr., Calc. and Sars.
if you have a case where the cracks are mostly on the bends of the elbows and the back of the knee, the remedy - we had such a case in Belgium - Graph.
In ulcers in general, I'll give you a few general pictures like Ars. it's very good remedy. Anthrac., is another one. Carb-v. also due to bad circulation. Hepar.
Kali-s. and Kali-bi.,
Lach., Merc., Nit-ac. Phyt.
Puls., Sil., Sulph. again.
But if the ulcer is blackish, it has a black
color, which is the main remedy?
Anthrac. Carb-v. also can
be there and also Lach.
But if this blackish color is all around the
ulcer, then it becomes mostly Lach.
And of course the bluish, red color
belongs to Lach., also Ars. and Sil.
If these ulcers are burning, usually the pain is burning but when it's excessively burning, it's like fire, then the main remedies are Anthrac., Ars. and Tarent-c.
You see I give you mostly my experience,
I don't give you all the remedies that are in the Repertory. You will find a lot of other remedies as well.
Every eruption that will be ameliorated by cold application, cold water, any eruption and ulcers, will be mostly Led. and Puls.
The color of the discharge can become important, especially if there are peculiar colors like blackish discharge, we have Anthrac., Sulph., Lyc. Sometimes Bry.
When the discharge is of grayish color, it's
one remedy which is very important, Caust.
And green discharge we have Ars.,
Nat-s.  main remedies.
Discharge which smells like old cheese is one remedy, Hep. And when the discharge is sourish smelling, which are the remedies?
Calc., Hep. and in this particular
case Merc. also can be indicated.
When you have boils, carbuncles, boils that come repeatedly in the history of the patient, you have boils breaking out and again and they retreat, they break again.
And there is a history of boils in general, the remedy that you will be thinking is Hep. and Sulph.
Also Calc-s.  Brom., Merc., Calc. as well.
Boils that are enormous in size and of a texture which is....you palpate the boil and the boil is quite full and movable within the muscular structure
but absolutely it's not defused there. It's a hard mass with excessive burning pain, is Anthrac.
Boils, carbuncles and this kind of skin eruptions are still not very difficult to manage, to handle.
Usually they have a good
prognosis and good reactions.
There is another type of this disorder which is a generalized state of carbuncles. It's called hidradenitis.
It usually appears in axillae and on the inguinal region and eventually progresses and occupies the whole body.
Disfigures the body and especially the face it becomes completely disfigured, the nose.
This is a state which looks like carbuncles or boils but actually it's a much more serious condition
and it's not easily manageable by Homeopathy though we can have definitely quite a lot of success with this disease.
We may see long periods of aggravations. In this disease you may start in a case and you may give up very soon because of the aggravation which takes place.
And unless you persist for several years, you are not going to see real results in such cases.
This disease, as I said, is called hidradenitis and it looks like carbuncles or boils but it is not, it's a much deeper state of disorder.
In this case we have keloids. It's like smallpox. Every boil leaves a mark and many times the marks are keloids, much stronger.
Therefore we have remedies like Graph. and
Sil., Calc-s., Calc. which can be indicated.
I have found also in this type of cases, you will have the need of a series of remedies. It's not one remedy that will do it.
It's a series of remedies and my experience in such cases of hidradenitis is that there is a lot of emotional problems.
Usually a woman and they are loaded with emotions which were never expressed.
Very strong emotions that were never expressed and it seems that the body expresses this kind of emotions through these boils
that can become tremendously
big and disfigure the whole face.
I mean you can see a boil budging out from here and there and eventually when it will go down you will have a bigger or a smaller mark.
They will need to be treated on several layers. The 1st remedy, the 2nd remedy, the 3rd remedy, the 4th remedy and after 2-3 years
of treating such cases you may really notice some changes coming about. Once you treat them successfully in the beginning, you will have a big aggravation.
You don't see these aggravations with common boils or recurrent  carbuncles which we see in other cases. It's quite easy to have them.
We now come to eczema which is one of the most common skin eruptions that you will be treating.
Here the successes will become less because at this moment the general state of health is not strong enough to give you a clear picture of the remedy.
Eczematous cases they
don't give out a clear picture.
In these cases you have definitely to take into consideration general mental-emotional symptoms before you can find the remedy.
And also it is my experience in treating cases that they have been treated before by other homeopaths.
It's my experience that eczema after being treated for many years with Homeopathy it can
in a way be suppressed, in one way or another.
I'm going to show you a case on video, with a child with eczema that the eczema was treated and it developed some chest problems.
Some asthma and then eventually he developed some personality disorders and I will show you how the disease went inside and how the disease will come outside during  treatment.
Remedies for the eczema,
here we have to mention first Sulph.
Sulph. is the number one remedy that will be covering about 25% of the cases of eczema.
Other remedy which is very prominently indicated and has severe kind of eczema, especially in the face, around the eyes, the eyebrows, is Mez.
Of course again remedies like Graph. and Sep. Sep. actually is one of the best skin remedies and it will be indicated in many many conditions.
Eczema will be treated with Dulc. also. Dulc. many times will be indicated, especially if the eczema or the condition has come after an exposure to cold wet.
The same with Rhus-t.
Again Ars., Ars-i., Calc., Calc-s., Hep.
and both Jug-c. and Jug-r.
Olnd., Petr., Psor.
But here again you have to individualize and go to the Repertory. You will have to work with the Repertory.
I don't know how many of you are working with the Repertory but I don't believe that anybody can have in his mind the information which is given in our Materia Medicas.
Therefore it's absolutely necessary to use the Repertory. So going into the Repertory you will see a lot of modifications of these remedies.
It will give you a lot of information. I' m just giving you highlights now which is on my experience, what remedies will come mostly prominent in such cases.
In carbuncles I forgot to give you another
remedy which is very important. It's Tarent-c.
Did I speak about Tarent-c.?
Carbunlces that are discharging but still are very much painful, burning, Tarent-c. will be together with Anthrac.
Then Ars. and then Crot-c. and Apis
and Lach. of course will be indicated.
And we'll have remedies also that they will have a predisposition to alternate between skin eruptions and internal disorders.
Mostly if you see duodenal ulcer state alternating with skin eruptions or if you see immediately a relationship between
a suppressed skin eruption and the almost immediate appearance of a duodenal ulcer within 2-3 months after the eruption was gone,
the duodenal ulcer appears.
That is a keynote of Graph.
You can be almost sure,
certain that the remedy will be Graph.
Another characteristic of Graph. is when,  usually Graph. has discharge, it has a wet eczema, with a lot of discharge.
And the discharge is sticky, they describe it like honey. Sticky and yellowish, brown color.
Wet eczema also you will find in Lyc.,
in Dulc., Kreos. also. And of course Sulph.
But if the discharge is very thin, like watery discharge, then the remedies will be Crot-h. or Tarent-c. again.
If the discharge from the eczema, everything
that comes out is yellowish, this is Rhus-v.
Also Cupr. has this yellow discharge.
What is in Rhus-t. and Rhus-v.? Both they have a peculiarity, where the itching which both these remedies produce very intensely
the itching is ameliorated if they put the part which is itchy in very hot water.
Almost boiling water. They can just bear the heat. They put inside and that is the only time where they get an amelioration.
This is a characteristic of Rhus-t. or Rhus-v.
Ars. also is better in warm applications.
The characteristic of Olnd. is that the eczema appears mostly on the top of the head. And the eczema is mostly in children or in babies.
Another characteristic is also that there are thick crusts, very thick crusts, under which if you lift them, there is oozing.
And then we have allergic reactions, allergic conditions which some remedies produce.
And if we have a generalized rash, red rash, as an allergic condition, the first remedy that we will be thinking is Puls., Apis, Chlor., Bell., Vesp. and Rhus-t.
Of course Sulph. Sulph. always is there.
Even if I don't mention, Sulph. is there.
There is another remedy in generalized urticaria, where especially the urticaria is small, red bumps.
Full of little bumps raised and it becomes red, whole areas of little bumps raised of an allergic type of an eruption
with intense itching, there is a remedy
which we have to think, is Astac.
Do you know what it is?
Lobster. You have seen lobster? The color of lobster more or less has that type of appearance in small spots.
A generalized state. Astacus Fluviatilis.
If the urticaria affects mostly the extremities, then Chlor. becomes very important, Crot-c.,  Med., Cop., Lach. and Apis.
These remedies become important with
the most terrifying of this, the Crot-c.
where the urticaria can take enormous patches that become very red and really looking fiery red.
You will see the thigh, the whole thigh is swollen in a place. Crot-c. of course has a mental picture that goes with it.
A lot of fears, a lot of delusions almost with fears. We cannot give all the information about these remedies, I'm just giving you indications.
For instance if an urticaria or an allergic reaction comes mostly in the night, then we have Apis as the main remedy.
Bov. is a remedy that has an interesting condition in allergic reaction where the itching is so tremendous that a person has to scratch, scratch
and then there is tremendous anxiety in this person.  The person is in a great state of anxiety, in excitement at the same time.
And this itching comes and the body
breaks out to this eruption and this scratch bleeds and creates little wounds.
The whole body all the time from scratching
looks with little wounds all over the places.
Bovista also has another characteristic which is a kind of awkwardness. They become very awkward.
They want to take this and before they take this, they throw this, that one, then they catch this.
They don't direct their extremities very much.
If a case of asthma alternating with skin eruptions of an allergic type. An allergic asthma with a kind or urticaria alternating.
When the urticaria is out, the asthma is better, when the asthma is on, the urticaria is not there.
Then we have Apis again and
Calad. and possibly Graph.
An urticaria which comes every time a person takes a bath is mostly Lach., an Urt-u. as well and Phos.
An allergic reaction that comes in cold air, as soon as the person gets cold, the reaction starts, then we have Rhus-t., a possibility of Nit-ac. or Sep.
Amelioration with cold air will be Dolich.
and
Kali-bi. And sometimes Calc.
But allergic condition that comes after cold
and wet mostly Dulc., possibly Calc-p., Calc.
An allergic reaction that comes after exertion
is mostly Con., Merc., Nat-m., Psor., Urt-u.
Ant-c. has a reaction to meat. People allergic to meat in general, we have to be thinking of Ant-c. with a desire for cucumber.
Excessive desire for cucumber
and allergic reaction to meat.
We have allergic conditions
that come before menses.
Again Nat-m. which is very well known for
a reaction before menses, Kali-c. and Dulc.
If you happen to have travel case where there is nausea preceding the skin eruption, there is nausea or vomiting and then the skin eruption breaks out, then the remedy is Sang.
This type of allergic conditions you may be finding some of the cases are very stubborn and you may be battling for years before you can really bring them around.
They are not easy cases but don't forget Medorrhinum is one of the best remedies for this kind of allergic conditions where we have the swelling of the area which is inflamed.
And of course better
in the sea will be a keynote.
In urticaria I would think that a remedy like
Apis, most frequently indicated is Apis, Med.
Dulc., Urt-u. and Puls.
I would say these out of the most
frequently indicated remedies.
-In what potency?
-The potency, as long as you find the remedy, the potency always is going to act, whether you give 6X, 12, 30, 200 or 1M, 10M.
One observation in potencies also, I would say in skin eruptions, you do not have to go very high. 200 is a good potency to work with skin eruptions.
Also you can start with 30 and find out because some allergic people are so sensitive that they may have big reactions.
In general herpes zoster is Ran-b., Rhus-t., Variol. also one of the main remedies and Thuja.
Possibilities Merc., Lach., Ars., Graph.
If it happens they have a periodicity, mostly is Ars., possibility of Merc. and Phyto.
If you have cancerous affections of the skin, like epithelioma, Hydr. is an interesting remedy, Con., Kali-s., Lyc., Ars-i.
For melanoma we have Lach., again Con.,
Crot-h., Arg-n., Kali-p., Calc., Ars., Merc., Sulph.
If you go to lupus erythematosus, Nit-ac., Thuj., main remedies, Hydroc., also, Lyc., Sep., Phyto., Ars., Kali-cl.
For vitiligo, you will not cure vitiligo. All this as we go further to more serious conditions, we have less and less successes with homeopathic remedy.
In vitiligo for instance,
I have seen two cases cured.
Usually I don't see for vitiligo but on the side you see the progress of vitiligo and you see whether they are curing or not.
Vitiligo which is spread already 5-10 years,
15 years very little. It can regress but very little.
In children is another story because you get it very early. The child is reacting easily and I find Sep. is one of the main remedies for vitiligo in children.
The main remedies here will be of use like Sulph., Calc., Aur., Ars., Alum., sometimes Phos., Nat-m., Nat-c., Merc., Sil.
-Syphilinum?
-You can say it yes.
I have seen, as I said, some regression in vitiligo or I have seen a few cases, maybe there are 4 or 5 but very few cases that I see in grownups that the condition was taken away completely.
For psoriasis the main remedy is again Sep. Sep. why? Because Sep. produces scaly eruptions very strongly, dry eruptions and scaly.
Remedies that produce this state of affairs are good for psoriasis. Ars., Ars-i, Aur., Aur-m., Bar-c., Calc., Calc-s, Led., Mez., Phos., Sep., Sil.
Phyto. also is one of the main remedies.
Phyto. is very much similar with Merc.
Lyc. also you will see some times indicated. In acute cases, sometimes the psoriasis takes a very severe form with real inflammation
and you see the inguinal glands get swollen up because of the inflammation going on in the whole body.
The inguinal glands become swollen and there is a burning sensation and aggressive heat and pain in the whole body.
That can be ameliorated by Bell. and most probably we have to continue with Calc.
Another remedy is also Clem.
Ringworms, the main remedy is Bac. here. And Rad-b. also when the eruption is absolutely circular.
It's a circular eruption, an exact circle and it appears in different places and it becomes an exact circle.
Nat-m. also, Phyto., Sep., Tell.
also and Tub. of course.
Then in lower degree
Bar-c., Calc. and Graph.
Herpetic eruptions that come during fever. If during fever you have a herpetic eruption appearing, then it's going to be Nat-m.
Nat-m. also is the main remedy
for producing herpes in the lips.
If the herpetic eruption appears with a lot of itching, then we have Clem., Rhus-t. and Sep.
The case of ichthyosis is another serious state and it requires a lot of treatment perhaps
but the main remedy that will almost cure will almost take care of 50% of the cases, is Phos.
Ichthyosis is a congenital disease which
is quite severe with a lot of scales.
I remember one of my first cases that
needed Phos. in ascending potencies.
That was the only case that I had to prescribe 4M or something like that, which I don't know what kind of potency is this but anyhow she needed ascending potencies.
Unfortunately, due to the fact that we do not have a scientifically produced homeopathic remedy, that means we know that this remedy has been potentized 10.000 times exactly
because of that fact we cannot know exactly what happens. When we say we gave CM potency, 100.000 potency, 1.000.000 potency,
we don't really know whether this remedy was really potentized 1.000.000 times or it was just said that it was potentized 1.000.000 times.
But Phos. I have noticed that in ichthyosis acts very well and usually the ichthyosis cases need Phos. in great percentage.