It is this degree of intensity which
becomes important eventually.
Because if the person will tell you, 'I can't stand drafts at all', your mind goes to which remedies?
-Kali-c.
-Lobelia.
-Hepar.
-Silica.
-There are 3 remedies which are quite
strong, Rhus-t., Calc-p. and Cimic.
If there is a draft affects them
in the cervical region.
Calc-p., Rhus-t., and Cimic.
Therefore you have to be very careful because here you're going to do the most detailed examination.
The one who is affected by draft mostly in the lumbar region is not so much Cimic. it is Kali-c., it's Calc.
The Calc-p. is affected very
much in which kind of weather?
Just after the snow. This weather which
is wet and cold is a killing for Calc-p.
There are a lot of remedies which are affected by wet and cold. One main remedy is Dulc., correct.
But Dulc. how mostly will be affected?
Where in the body?
-Knee joints.
-In the joints yes, the pains in the
joints will increase. What else?
You will see that also it can affect the colon,
the guts and you may have diarrheas.
So exposing especially the feet cold and wet and getting diarrheas, the remedy is not Rhus-t. anymore.
It's not Calc., it's not Kali-c.
But if the person says 'worse from
drafts but I'm better from wet weather'?
Hep. and Kali-c. and Nux-v.
Except of Caust. Caust. is better
in wet weather. What he will say?
That he feels more energy and
his pains in the joints are better.