-I would like to know the difference between the aggression in Staph., there is a sweetness eventhough
there is an aggression.
The difference between this and Puls.
-The aggression in Staph. does
not manifest. They don't show it to others.
The aggression in Staph. is such
that when the person is by himself
he goes there and really becomes
mad that did not the guts to attack, to say.
During that time they can reach a point
where they can get something and throw it.
The aggression in Puls. is different. It's
an aggression which has to be shown
and Puls. can take something and throw it against the person, usually the husband.
But she makes sure that it will not hit him. She will throw it this direction, the man is there.
So it's a sweet aggression with Puls. and at the same time showing how she was hurt by the other person.
But it is a showing off in such a way to
cause the other person to console.
'You are so sweet, don't worry,
I made a mistake, sorry'.
Crying, the woman responds with crying.
But if you get the aggression of
other remedies is different.
Staph. shows also extreme aggression
if they are in an acute psychotic state.
She can be quite aggressive verbally
and also throwing things.
But you have to bring Staph., after years
of suppression, to the limits where Puls.
will explode every time,
every day, every week.
-In Materia Medica Viva, as you describe Gels., you say that this remedy has the impulse to jump from high place.
We meet that in Gels., in Arg-met. and in Staph. Can you tell us some elements about this symptom in Staph.?
Also it's Aurum. Aurum is the main remedy. Aurum they mean it, that means they are in a high place
depressed, they think they've lost everything
and at the spear of the moment they think
'if I just jump, everything it will be
finished. I can't tolerate it anymore'.
At the spear of the moment the impulse
comes and they jump. Aurum will jump.
It's a clear mind during that time but the suffering that it has been through, it's intolerable according to them.
'I can't stand it anymore. I can't stand it'.
They have described some of those people who survived from jumping, they have described saying
'I was in the roof and I was looking,
saying now is your chance, jump, jump'.
And there is a kind of elation. The
moment Aurum jumps is happy.
They find happiness in the idea of death.
Now Gels. is totally different. Gels. is a person whom you see he is dazed in their mind.
They live along but with energy, no joy,
tired, dazed in their mind
and they come to the balcony, they look down and say, 'I'll jump'. This type. The mind is not clear.
The balcony is pulling them down. Like Arg-n.
the heights are drawing them.
The Staph. has sparks of this idea, of this thought, when they are in a high place.
'I'll jump, I have the impulse'. An impulse mostly with a clear mind not with a dazed mind. But they never jump.
Those who are dangerous when they have these ideas are the Aur., the Ars. and the Natrum.
Especially Natrum sulphuricum.
Those people can really commit suicide.
Of course what I give you is general ideas. There are modifications in each individual but I give you the main line of thoughts.
Aur-m. is the main remedy that attempts
suicide, they really try suicide
but almost always it is because of
romantic reasons.
Aur-m. are erotic people.
Do you understand erotic?
Some good words are known very well.
They are people who fall in love
passionately and they get involved.
The other person at a certain moment
says, 'well I had enough of you, bye bye'.
Then they will commit suicide but not really.
They will jump from a place where they know is not going to kill, they take enough medications to know that somebody
will save them, take them to the hospital.
By intuition, it is not the
hard decision which is taken by Aur.
Aur. will find the best way to do it and usually will jump or another way is by fast driving car and hitting the car.
In these cases the Aur. tries to get rid of the
pain. There is an argument with his girlfriend
and there is pressure in him. He wants to do violence and says, 'it's not right that I will kill her'.
So he just kicks the door, goes and
gets the car, go speedy with the car.
As he goes with the car he is
thinking, 'I can kill myself'.
Then the opportunity happens, there is a tree, they turn the car and hit the tree and gone, this is the idea.
If they don't find the tree or the opportunity they may be saved because this crisis goes over and it goes down eventually.
So they may drive from London
to Amsterdam and calm down.
Not so long, just 20 min. half an hour, it calms down. If they manage to survive during this half an hour.
-Is there a remedy for someone who wants
to commit suicide if they are insulted
and as a punishment to the other person?
- This kind of thinking comes
with Lach. mostly.
'If I do it, I will punish the others'. The idea of punishing the other is the idea with Lach.
But of course Nat-s. has a different idea. Nat-s. are thinking all the time, the idea of committing suicide is there.
It's a constant suicidal depression.
At the same time they're thinking 'If I commit suicide, my wife who loves me will suffer...
my mother who loves me will suffer,
my daughter will suffer'.
And this holds them but it is a struggle really.
When they confess they will say, it is a struggle. I'm thinking that I will give such a grief to others but I really struggle to stay.
The world has no meaning for me.
Life has no meaning.
And it is usually the grief on an emotional
level where the Aur. is not always emotional.
Aur. mostly is the loss of their ambitions.
I was going to be the bank manager and somebody else took my position because they found out
that I had an off-shore company
and there is degradation.
The person has fallen from where he put himself, in a high position and be respectable by the society.
Suddenly if he loses that, the newspapers
are writing, he stole money, he did this.
This can bring about an Aur. state in
the individual and they cannot tolerate.
By this time if that happens, then of course they think also my wife does not love me, my daughter has left me
my son has done this to me,
everything becomes black.
Everything comes together as negative.
And that is the time they jump.
That is why -for those who know economics, politics- when the crash in 1929 in America, it was a financial crash.
During this period were recorded much more suicides from jumping from a high place.
It is well known that a lot of people jumped and killed themselves during the financial crisis.
These people could be saved if a homeopath would give them one remedy.
I've told you this story with the guy who telephoned me and said, 'I want to kill myself'. I was in California
in Berkley and he was in Las Vegas.
He says, 'I want to commit suicide.'
I had visited his house with one of my students, a medical doctor who had an affair with his wife, without me knowing anything.
They did not tell me I'm going to have an affair, I would tell him....
Anyhow, he said 'your student made that and
this and that, so therefore I will commit suicide'.
I said 'when?', he says 'tonight'.
'How?'
Near Las Vegas there are some very high rocks, quite vertical, he says 'I will jump from the rocks'.
'I'll take my helicopter, go there and jump'.
I said, 'I understand you, you are right but will you do a favor for me?' Because he had a respect for me.
'Will you wait until tomorrow?
You jump tomorrow morning?'
I said, 'you promise you'll jump tomorrow morning. I don't say, don't jump but jump tomorrow morning'.
He said 'OK, I'll jump tomorrow morning'.
So I said to his wife, 'do you have Aurum?', 'Yes'. 'What potency?', '50M'. You give him now, immediately.
It was afternoon. Next day I received a call. I said, 'what happened?' He said, 'I decided not to jump'.
The change was dramatic. I don't know if he would really jump but the fact remains.
He says, 'the hell with all that, I will separate
with my wife and I will not jump'.
I said, congratulations.
-He was a very famous, wealthy business man in England, he lost so much money with this financial situation
and he set fire to all his property, all his
family and finally himself. Is that?
-That can be but more sick than Aurum.
Maybe Aurum would have saved him.
But sometimes people are in despair, especially in America several people they kill their own family
and they kill themselves because
of the financial losses.