In my writings I have repeatedly emphasized the hierarchical structure of the human being.
In the healthy individual the mental sphere being the most central to normal functioning, exerts its control over the physical and emotional spheres.
We know the control of the mind upon these spheres. On the other hand, in other types of patients there is a weakening of this central controlling influence.
To this group belongs the Argentum nitricum. In the neurological system this weakness leads to clumsiness, incoordination and finally ataxia and convulsions.
In the psychological state, it leads to impulses which the whole mark of Argentum nitricum.
If we wanted to describe an Argentum nitricum case with few words, we could say that it is
an over emotional, impulsive individual with weakening mental faculties, that allow for
a lot of impulses and the host of fears.
An individual whose power of coordination and balance has been upset on all levels.
In the early stages of Argentum Nitricum, let us again go to the personality and understand.
We've been in the personality last time with Aurum and  I heard some comments, saying words, this is the fantasies of Vithoulkas.
When you go back to practice, you will find very soon it's not a fantasy, it's hard facts.
In the early stages of Argentum nitricum individuals are jolly, extrovert and optimistic.
Far from being egotistical, they are giving an attention in conversation.
They are people who enjoy the comforts of life. They have a strong sexual appetite, as well as appetite for tasty foods.
Salty and sweet foods and high living. And they will avoid ordeals at any cost. They don't like suffering. If they see suffering they go away. When you see suffering, there is no Argentum nitricum. In a situation with suffering, Argentum nitricum will say goodbye.
At the same time they possess a straight forwardness and simplicity.
These patients seem to be incapable of hiding their feelings for long.
For example, a person may be unable to hide for long a romantic affair from his wife.
He confesses the transgression and feels great remorse. Arg-n individuals may feel completely be overtaken by a sense of guilt for their actions and will cry with remorse.
They become very emotional and weep as they tell their transgression. I'm just giving some example.
I want to make it more vivid for you to understand the situation where you have a lot of energy.
And I tell you the secret: you have a lot of energy when an individual has no doubts. Doubt takes away a lot of energy, intellectual conflict inside it takes all the energy.
So they have a lot of energy, why? No doubts. The mind is not the controlling influence in them.
It's the heart, it's the feelings, the impulses. Impulsive, jolly individuals.
Let's have a good time, girlfriends, high living, intense living, no secrets inside, everything has to come out, it's plethoric. They're plethoric in their emotions like most of you.
He will get up in the class and say, that is me, he is an extrovert. He's an extrovert, he's full of life, full of emotions. He doesn't care is someone criticizes. 'It's alright, let's love each other'
It's the feeling which comes out, the emotions which are strong, the energy which is strong and it is not harnessed by the mind.
And that's why eventually we will see the mind weakened and weakened and we'll see how the impulses develop and overtake eventually the individual and he will start suffering.
Before he starts suffering, Argentum nitricum individuals will suffer a lot eventually because of things that we are saying but they like good life.
And good heart and good conversation and conversation on what? On an emotional level mostly. You see the contrast between one individual and another individual?
They may want to commit suicide also, sometimes they say 'I'm afraid but I want to kill myself'. It's a different thing all together.
Such an extrovert character. They are extrovert. Pains at this early stage have an impulsive element. There is an impulsive element in Argentum nitricum.
When he sees something, when he will be in a situation, he will be the first one to jump up and react to the situation.
You see the mind is not strong, it's not controlling, it's not the controlling influence.
Why the mind has become the controlling influence in the West?
North, West, why?
-A new organ? You claim nobody had any brain so far! Today we have brains!
We cultivated the mind in order to overcome pain.
In order to overcome pain and to have more pleasure. This is the idea and therefore the mind will try to avoid suffering at any cost.
By devising things, by finding out ways to get out of suffering. And because the mind is very limited and does not understand it's a stupid organ, the logical mind is a stupid organ, absolutely stupid and very limited in its logic.
It says well it's better if I sit like that because nobody will understand what I think.
There comes the homeopath and says, well I tell you how you feel now.
There are always playings that betray the mind. You cannot really hold everything. Somewhere you have to get loose and then you understand.
Now the Argentum nitricum don't need that. He says, what's the mind? The mind does not exist.
It's that type of person, I exaggerate a little bit but just to understand and to be able for you to construct the personality on which you're going to prescribe.
The characteristics are strong characteristics
for Argentum nitricum. Mostly, not always.
Red face, a lot of blood pumping. Thick lips.
We go to Natrums, these sensitive individuals with everything they see. 'Oh God, she looked at me! Maybe he is thinking about me!', Natrum muriaticum. An Argentum nitricum says, hello. You see the difference?
Now what kind of diseases are going to develop? One individual, the other individual?
And you see the logic behind the structures? We understand things more in depth by laughing and without losing our humor.
I hope you don't misunderstand me, I'm a very serious man.
I think I had given a little bit of Arg-n in Norway and everybody said, George he is Arg-n. The other day I was giving Aurum, ah he is Aurum!
So I've been through all the remedies.
The patient may be explosively irritable.
If his wife drops something, the patient may impulsively shout 'God you did it again.
Why the hell can't you hold anything?'
The temper is uncontrolled by normal mental restraints that we usually exercise. It flares and it goes away immediately.
Where Nux vomica goes like that. If it is to control Nux vomica, I was talking about Nux vomica yesterday, it starts burping.
You see the solar plexus, the stomach, the emotions are mostly placed in the stomach; that's why they will develop eventually duodenal ulcer, the Nux vomicas.
And they are so controlled. But some of them are very impulsive. Nux vomica are full of energy which is a little bit harsh energy. And that harsh energy burns them.
Argentum nitricum is another vibration. It's a jolly vibration; that's why the whole class eventually will laugh in the end. You see, feeling the character. Understanding the character.
If you see somebody who is very serious, you
will think twice. You have Argentum nitricum symptoms but this guy does not look like.
And eventually all the family knows that all these explosions are nothing. They mean nothing for the Argentum nitricum.
He may shout but he has forgotten. I shouted to you? What are you talking? I don't love you? I love you very much. They can cry.
It's all emotional excitement, it's not holding back. If you shout to Natrum muriaticum...  Argentum nitricum and Natrum muriaticum married together !
In the beginning the aggravation of both, terrific. It's very difficult to marry two medicines together.
But even two Natrum muriaticums, two Nux vomicas! Oh God, in the house there is constant battle, one throwing the other.
And if you get a Nux vomica with a woman Lilium tigrinum even worse. A woman Lilium tigrinum and man Nux Vomica, forget the marriage.
An Argentum nitricum can suppress tremendously a Staphysagria.
In some cases the patient may not show the irritability but only to his wife and to his family.
At work his uncertainty about his professional abilities and his inability to argue intellectually with his boss, makes him withhold his anger because he has a feeling of being inefficient.
He understands that. He understands his mind is not strong, is not powerful, is not very clear and therefore he tries to withhold.
Therefore the answer that you will get may be 'no, I'm not showing anger'. But you ask his wife. He forgets that in the house he gets it all out to his wife.
The emotions are robust, as we said, and the person is not highly refined and certainly not over sensitive.
You may get some sensitivity of course but the sensitivity that we see with Ignatia, with Natrum carbonicum, with Natrum muriaticum.
These kind of sensitivities which are, don't touch me. With the Nux vomica you feel that if you go against, you had it. You feel it at any moment.
With Ignatia you feel that if you say one more word, she may go into crying.
With Natrum muriaticum you feel a kind of distance between you and the person. It's very serious. Natrum muriaticum says, don't criticize me.
Aurum, as we said, cannot stand criticism at all. An Aurum with criticism will look absolutely the same as before and then this moment is destroyed inside. It's disappointed tremendously.
He is suffering, his emotions are becoming with great sensitivity. It produces a sensitivity for the person, not for others.
He will not be attacking easily the other person, the Aurum, almost never. He will not ask for help. He will not discuss it at all. You see the depression how it comes, you feel it.
Now Argentum nitricum, you do something to him and he immediately goes to a friend and he says, what has happened to me.
What has happened? I had this girlfriend and I gave everything to her and now she has left me. He cries, he expresses his emotions. After that, he is all right.
His emotions are too vital to allow wounded feelings or deep emotional scars.
This type of individual can be extremely sympathetic. He may be easily move to tears when hearing of another person suffering.
Like Phosphorus. Phosphorus is close, not Causticum. For Causticum sympathetic has to
be raised in the Repertory. It has 3 degrees.
It's in italics. You may still raise it but it is a different sympathetic. With intensity, seriousness. Here we have a serious situation.
This man is worth very much and nobody pays attention to him. This man is suppressed and the government has to be overthrown.
It's an intensity and a seriousness but not this affection. This expression of affection.
Also he will be better with consolation. Argentum nitricum will like consolation, will like to discuss.
At this early stage there is little mental pathology or at most only hints of the extreme anxiety or strong impulses which occur later.
The patient will seek attention mainly for physical complains such as an ulcer, colitis, vertigo, headaches etc.
It's at this point however that the patient may become vulnerable to mental over exertion. You see he cannot take up a lot of mental over exertion.
These Argentum nitricums being extroverts will take positions where they feel most happy, like myself. I'm so happy because I talk to you.
And they talk and they exchange energies and they do this, an evangelist, an entertainer, a priest, a homeopath.
But eventually after giving themselves to such tasks, they start feeling tired. Their mind becomes more and more weak. And then the problem starts.
One of the earliest symptoms of the mental-emotional pathology of Argentum nitricum is the weakness of memory. He starts first losing his memory.
The patient cannot longer perform as he did previously at his work, especially due to the failure of the memory.
The next thing that develops is a feeling of hurry. As he notices his inefficiency with the mind, he feels time is not enough to perform whatever has to do.
He wants to accomplish things but there is not enough time. You see the slowness of the mind is a complex, memory drops, mind becomes slower; at the same time obligations.
And then starts the anxiety and I have to do and I don't have enough time and then the feeling of hurry start to develop inside.
And he becomes very impatient and also he can hardly wait for an appointment, like Nux Vomica.
And there comes the great anxiety to arrive in time. He leaves home much earlier than what is needed for an appointment.
That is the time where the anticipation for an appointment, whatever it might be even a simple appointment, it may be an ordeal for him.
And he prepares much earlier. He will leave the house much earlier and of course we know that he will have complains from anticipating an appointment.
The anticipation may bring perspiration, palpitation, frequent urination and up to diarrhea. You will not see in every case of Argentum nitricum diarrhea on anticipation.
Sometimes you will even see that. But you will see perspiration, palpitation, frequent urination.
At this point the patient becomes aware of the weakening of his mental faculties.
He feels incompetent and inefficient especially when confronting some short of intellectual challenge.
It's the type of person that even if he knows the subject well he's going to talk about, he has great anxiety and anticipating to give the lecture.
You will see me every time I go to the bathroom before I come here. That is the Argentum Nitricum. I have to give the lecture.
And palpitation and it can reach up to diarrhea. Whatever the complain may be. You may have chronic colitis, then you see the pains.
There is a kind of, as if the whole organism lives on instinct. It cannot be controlled.
Where a Natrum muriaticum may wait 48 hours before he goes to urinate. I say, how you did it? I say it was impossible, there is so many people in there.
Nobody would have seen you. Impossible. But Ambra grisea cannot go for stool for a month. Because there are people that they will hear.
Impossible, they just hold it, they've constipation for one month. In hospitals, in other people places.
You see how each one of the personalities is behaving and we have to perceive and understand and recognize because such symptoms are so valuable.
You battle with a case and then it comes and says, do you have a stool easily? What do you mean easily? If you are in a friend's house, will you go?
The bathroom has to be on the other floor for Ambra grisea to go and have a stool. If it is next door, no they will hear me. I exaggerate a bit but this is the idea behind.
A Natrum muriaticum even if he goes to the bathroom, may not be able, the retention of the urine is automatic, is not controlled. 48 hours no urine.
With Argentum nitricum it doesn't matter who is in front. With the whole class, do it. That's the type of the person. M.Tyler describes a typical case:
A poor little school girl of 6 in such terror of anticipation that when the school bell rang, she put her head on her hands and vomited.
Argentum nitricum finished that trouble promptly. You see the girl, instead of having diarrhea, she had vomited. Don't' say, ah vomiting is not written in the book. It doesn't matter, it's the idea.
How she did it also is important because you may get another case. With total anxiety and mental disturbance which you may get vomiting in the school, where they get up in the morning.
I'm sorry I'm talking about the subject. When these girls year after year, they cannot face the world, the school and you see every morning, vomiting in a rocket way is Veratrum album.
But it's another child all together, the Veratrum album is a different child. It's the most I would say intelligent child of the Materia Medica. Very intelligent children, very serious.
I told you Aurum is always serious, always attaining, I have to be the first. You don't see Aurum reading detective stories.
Argentum Nitricum only detective stories, Aurum never, always a serious book, philosophy, science etc.
The children Veratrum album you will see a peculiar seriousness where they enquire about everything, about God. They look like Calcarea carbonica in this respect.
Religion, philosophy, understanding basic questions of life, you will see Veratrum Album impressively asking serious questions.
You see that child is not normal. A normal thing for a child is to play, to be happy and then in the morning the vomiting. Before go to school, it's not that they do not know their lessons
but the sensitivity in facing the world, they are
so sensitive and perceptive and understand
their parents. They are intuitive, they will
make remarks to the parents that the parents sometimes they will be ashamed.
Why did you tell a lie? Of course it is a lie for this and this reason.That is a serious child. 'You said a lie. Why you said it? Why didn't you behave right in that situation?'
They make remarks. They ask questions. God, angels, why people are suffering? Why people are poor? I want to know.
Somebody works more and somebody works less. Yes but this who works less, maybe he is not able to work more.
They are very high intelligent and then of course they go into teaching. I have noticed that if you treat Veratrum children, they become almost genius.
Eventually from mad, because the parents bring the Veratrum child as a crazy, and from crazy they become extremely intelligent.
They retain a kind of intelligence which is very very high. As if Veratrum speeds up the mind.
It speeds the body also, they can run, the autistic children. One autistic child in here and could run through and would never stop.
-Would you see the perceptive intelligence without the hyperactivity?
-Without the hyperactivity? Yes but they will have other things.
I can't remember now details but you may see a tick in their legs. They take the foot and push it up.
They do motions which are constant.
What I've tried in the Materia Medica I'm writing, is to give you the basic ideas. But it would be impossible if I was trying to give examples. It would be example after example after example and then you are lost.
If you understand the basic idea, it doesn't matter if it's vomiting now or have diarrhea, the basic idea is ailments from anticipation ...
Where the vomiting of Veratrum is when he gets up in the morning. It's not the anticipation. Anticipates perhaps to face the world, perhaps it's too hard. And this symptom I've seen also in Calcarea carbonica.
Nausea and tendency to vomit and vomiting in the morning on waking for years, since childhood. I got a case of hiatus hernia.
He was advised to be operated and he came to me and had all the symptomatology, and nausea and vomiting in the morning since childhood.
With Calcarea Carbonica everything went away plus the hiatus hernia. It's a few years now, no problem, no pains, nothing, no operation.
As the pathology of Argentum Nitricum develops, the patient seems to lose more and more intellectual strength and control. Rather he seems to be controlled, almost overwhelmed
by his emotional impulses.
Psychological pathology may begin in a different way as well. Often the patient may confront a type of shock which overwhelms his balance.
The beginning of pathology may be a shock that overtakes his balance.
Frequently these shocks come in the form of the death in the family. Or perhaps someone close to him develops a serious disease like cancer.
The patient then begins to develop great anxiety especially concerning his own health.
Also he may develop great concern or anxiety about others, his family or friends.
Argentum nitricum is one of the main remedies for anxiety about his own health. A hypochondriacal kind of anxiety.
He becomes over anxious or even frightened when he is alone. You see how much he needs the support of others. That's why he comes into contact so easily.
In the northern countries, from Sweden upwards, all right from Switzerland upwards, you will not get the type I'm describing exactly.
Because it's the culture, you are not allowed to express. So even Argentum nitricum will be much less expressive than the Mediterraneans.
Here we discover more easily the Arg-n. There it's not that you don't have Arg-n, it's that you don't discover them. Because they learn still to control themselves.
And not only he is afraid to be alone but he has great desire to have somebody near him, to have company.
When he is alone in the night, then that is the time when fear of death overcomes him.
As these tendencies towards anxiety and fear continue, he may reach a state of severe anxiety neurosis with irrational behavior.
In Argentum nitricum the fear of death and anxiety about health may reach unprecedented heights.
When alone, he can easily go into panic states, with trembling all over, mumbling, stuttering and even convulsions.
This kind of thing. 'I'm afraid'. He will express it. Especially in the night, when the night comes, they are alone and nobody in the room, the fear comes and gets bigger and bigger
until they start trembling and then they go into convulsions. So panicked they can become.
The individual becomes so irrational during that fear that feels anything may happen to him.
That he may faint, that he may pass away, that he may die, that evil forces will take him over.  All kinds of irrational things.
And usually what we see in Argentum nitricum is that he is very gullible. He believes anything anybody will say to him. Especially at that stage.
Believing anything, in that state with tremendous fear, tremendous anxiety he has to hold on to something. He has to hold on to somebody and it does not matter who is available.
Whether is the milk man or the doctor is the same, all the same. 'I feel I have cancer' and in that state, she may just take out her breast to the milk man 'Do you think it's cancer?'
I had a case similar. My aunt who had a similar situation what she did, she prayed for 3 nights and 3 days and was gone. Arg-n will go for 3 nights and 3 days to pray to see if that treatment is good enough.
I mean if he does not have anybody available, will telephone somebody and say, 'I'm in a difficult state'. Also they don't want to say exactly the state and the severity in which they are.
'I have a little bit of difficulties, you see what happens I'm afraid', also they may say instead of I'm afraid, they may say 'my jaw goes like that'. Or 'I have some spasms in the right side, what do you think I should do?', 'have a warm bath'.
Any advice, they will go and take a warm bath. At this moment the anxiety is so much that they have no rationality to discriminate what is he talking.
I'm talking to an irrelevant person who does not know anything and he advises me to do this. Why should I do it? There is no such thing, such rationality.
The anxiety, the fear are so great, overwhelming, they need to hold on to something. To warm bath, to sticking a pin in the occiput, jump 3 times right and 3 times left, whatever.
This is what I mean gullible at that state and they seem to lose the rationality really because they are under the treatment of a psychiatrist.
And then in the morning they wake up with psychiatrist finally. And the psychiatrist says another thing.
And then he does whatever the psychiatrist says. In the meantime, during the night he has done everything else that everybody else had said.
This is because they panic so much. 'I'm not going to go out' and the idea that this panic state is going to remain. 'I'm going to stay in that, the rest of my life. I'm lost, I'm finished' and then it starts the trembling and then it goes to convulsions etc.
When he is alone he becomes anxious, fearful of fainting and if you faint OK, what is the big deal with fainting? Faint?
See what happens, it's a good experience. Aah! Eventually she may try that also because somebody advised it.
But fear of fainting is tremendous fear, the idea of dying. See now how this jolly individual who enjoys his life, with good life, emotions, if shock happens !
And the idea of death comes into his life. This is the idea. The idea of death comes into his understanding. There is also death. I thought so far it was only drink a beer, having fun etc.
Now there is death also. This death can stop me from having all that enjoyment. And then the idea will overtake him, 'I lost everything', then next day there is nothing.
The anxiety subsides. The panic state goes away. And next night he is alone again and
again it comes up with tremendous severity.
The idea also that death is near, is approaching, is coming 'will get me'.
And of course in these conditions, usually the stories that will tell you is that they call the ambulance finally.
They can reach that state that they cannot control themselves. They have to take the ambulance. The people who work in hospital they may see such cases.
They are coming there in panic state, trembling, in complete total panic and you may inject to them, not inject, pretend that you inject and still I believe they will calm down.
Because it's the company, the assurance, the doctor is there. He says, I feel so much better.
Especially when he talks with his doctor. He feels much better after talking.
The fears are not always defined. What kind of fear? Fear of dying. Of what? Cancer. Heart disease It's not always defined.
But many times will be fear of heart disease or a brain stroke, if they specify on cancer. Mostly heart disease and brain stroke.
Sometimes you will see also, not to have a misunderstanding, you will see that some of these patients they will not confess to everybody, they will not say to everybody.
They can only confess to people who they feel they have a kind of connection with health. Whether it's a medium or a doctor, within this range. They can call the medium and the medium will say, well I feel that there is a cloud.
Ahhh! What shall I do to take out the cloud. He says, light up 3 candles. They will take it seriously, they will do it. I'm exaggerating.
Medium? You don't know what's a medium? A psychic person. I see in your past life you killed 7 persons. 'Ahhh! I did not know about it'.
They will take it seriously and discuss the possibility of having killed 7 persons. And that's why now they are destroyed.
It's not a joke. These are things that we have heard. I'm not improvising.
The type of person is interesting to observe. And then you say, oh God this is Arg-n , I've been giving Kali-ars. and Calc., Lyc. and all this but it's Arg-n.
What is very interesting in these cases is also another thing. Before the panic state, before the panic becomes bigger and bigger, they have to run to the bathroom with diarrhea.
Diarrhea before the panic state is almost exclusive for Arg-n. It's a keynote for Arg-n.
You see with their anxiety about health, in case it comes to their mind that they have cancer, they will have an impulsive fear for cancer.
The fear will jump out of the blue inside them and overwhelm them with the least thing, the pain, the pimple, the anything.
Here it is, I got it, cancer. This is cancer and the anxiety will develop until they go and they want to be examined. He says, no you have nothing,
it goes away. It's similar to Phosphorus.
We see it also in Sulphur this type of impulsion. But in Arg-n is much more accentuated, it's very sudden. It comes suddenly and overwhelms completely the individual.
In that panic state, there are not many remedies that will go.  Aconite, Kali-ars may go into such panic states. But not of that type, different.
When we have constant fear, constant anxiety, then we go to remedies like Agar., Nit-ac., Kali-ars., Ars., the fear can be constant.
With Arg-nis fitful, fear, panic. The idea is that he cannot logically explain things, neither he wants to do it. He wants somebody else to help him. It says, desires company, this is desire company.
Because of the weakness, he wants somebody to hold his hand. You hold his hand and you say, 'don't worry, I am here'. 'I feel much better'.
The more you do it, the more he will feel good.
The more you say, 'I'm here, don't be afraid', they will pacify. Tell this in a Nit-ac, in a Kali-ars and he will run out of your surgery and never come back again.
But Arg-n and Phosphorus need this assurance, to tell them. Assure Nit-ac and he will not come back. Assure Kali-ars, I mean superficially assure him, 'Oh, don't worry, this is nothing' he will not come back.
Because these people are convinced in another way that they definitely have cancer. So if he says, there is nothing the matter with you, he is a fool, he does not know anything.
Arg-n will say, 'he knows what he is talking about. I have nothing', he goes away.
The same with Phosphorus.
Also because of that anxiety the Arg-n may become a kind of hypochondriac who takes all kinds of medicine. Whatever he can find, he can get hold.
When he travels he will take all his pills, all his bottles, the stethoscope, the blood pressure instrument, his nurse if he has, anything to prepare for death.
Death may come at any moment and also going away from usual environment, he immediately feels unsafe. The fact that he leaves the place where he knows, his friends. Becomes uncertain.
Where am I going there? Where is the nearest hospital? Where is the nearest doctor? Can I have the telephone number of 3 doctors?
One is enough. No, no in case he is not there, in the night if I cannot find him, give me 3.
And also the impulsiveness is on the type of medicine he will take. That means somebody says, you have this problem? This medicine is very good for you.
He will try it impulsively, fitfully, he will try it for a few days and will give it up. No, it doesn't work for me.
And then another one, another one, take some oil mixed up with vinegar and salt, it's very good for you. He will do it.
In the beginning, I think something is doing. Eventually nothing, gives it up, another thing, another thing and to the only thing they stick is Homeopathy.
They really believe but still they will try other things because until you find the remedy.
These are the patients who go from doctor to doctor, asking for electrocardiogram, asking for reassurance all the time. They're going to the hospitals.
And when there is no solution, this patient has gone to doctor after doctor and the anxiety continues, the fear continues, then they go into a state of gloomy apathy.
If they are alone, they sit in a gloomy state, an apathy state and only when somebody comes into the house, they are in company, they can exchange and they can have back their joy.
And that is why in Arg-n we say, it's better with company. You understand what kind of company, when, it's always when he is not in the anxiety state.
He likes company to exchange ideas and to exchange their energies etc. But when he is in the anxiety state, the company is a must.
He must have a company. Otherwise he feels bad. And then the amelioration from company is tremendous. From dying goes into a state, within half an hour, where he has forgotten what he was having.
It is unbelievable the change that you can see.
Also he has a fear of seeing sick people, facing sick individuals.
That's why if a friend is in the hospital where everybody is sick the hospital, it's an prdeal for Arg-n to go and visit a friend in the hospital.
Because he is going to see this patient and that patient and that patient and say, oh my God all kinds of diseases in this world.
I can have this disease, I can have that disease, he improvises, that's why he has fear of hospitals because of that psychology.
And fear of fainting of course is very strong.
This fear of fainting can come at any time. For instance when they walk or they drive, they fear that I may have a fainting now and crash with the car.
And the fear becomes more and more, they get panic and they stop the car and get out and find somebody and say, 'can you help me?'
He says, 'what is happening?', 'I don't feel well, can you drive me home?'. The fear is so panicky, so tremendous, so intense.
And that is why in Arg-n we have agoraphobia, fear of going out into the crowds, fear of going away from the house or they have to have somebody before they can go outside of their house.
Eventually they may stay all the time in the known environment. Otherwise they go into panic.
As we said before, the impulsiveness is a major aspect of this remedy.
Impulsive thoughts, impulsive reactions, impulsive emotions, impulsive steps. What is an impulsive step? a jerky step.
It's this idea of impulsiveness which pervades the whole mental-emotional-physical aspect of Arg-n.
He walks in the street and a thought comes that as soon as I reach this corner, a brick is going to fall on my head.
The thought comes and the strange thing is that this thought comes but he cannot control it.
The thought comes that a brick is going to fall as soon as I turn, a brick is going to fall, a brick is going to fall and he can't go, he can't proceed anymore. And he changes way.
You see it's not an impulse like Alumina, Mercury and other remedies have impulses. This impulse is so strong that acts upon these impulses. This is the secret of Arg-n, acts, he cannot control.
Therefore as he goes, because the impulse comes that an accident will take place in the corner, he changes and goes backwards.
-But this is already a pathology?
-This is pathology already, yes.
This is quite deep already the pathology.
And I have described many times different examples. To give you an idea the thought comes that he should walk on a particular way
he should not step in the pavement on the lines, he should only inside or only on the lines.
Unless he does this, something bad is going to happen to him and he goes like this, he cannot avoid it, he has to do it.
You see the difference with other remedies which they do not have to act upon these impulses.
We talked about the weakness of the mind and this is what we meant. When a thought comes, an idea comes, overtakes the mind and he cannot but act according to this idea.
Kent wrote: when crossing a bridge or high place, the thought comes that he might kill himself or perhaps he might jump off or what if he should jump off?
And sometimes the actual impulse comes to jump off the bridge to the water.
He thinks 'what if I jump off this bridge and what if and what if' and then he goes near and he almost climbs the bridge to go over.
That is Arg-n because jumping from a high place is not only Arg-n, it's Aurum again jumping from a high place. An impulse to jump, what a difference.
In the Repertory you will see the same thing, Gels. the impulse to jump from a high place. What a difference! Staphysagria, it's another type all together who does it for different reasons.
In Aurum is an impulse which has come through a lot of suffering. He says, 'here it is, here is your chance, jump to the freedom'.
Arg-n says 'jump, what if I jump, oh terrible! If he is in a balcony and he goes closer to the balcony and he looks down and the impulse comes and he goes closer
and the impulse comes more and he is lifting his leg when he understands, what a fool I am and he goes back.
He does not usually jump because if any Arg-nhas jumped really, we don't know it.
What we know is the descriptions of these people who say, this is exactly what happens. And what is more important for Arg-n is not only that
I'm jumping, I'm going to jump and then they go, but they look down and there they are, flat, lying in blood the brains are off and they see themselves down there.
They see the whole scenery, not only jumping but having jumped, they make with their imagination the whole scenery.
These people you can see then going downstairs. Every time they go downstairs all the time they see themselves going rolling, landing in the end of the stairs.
And every time is the same impulse.