And of course fear of heights we have in Arg-n and also vertigo from heights. What is interesting in Arg-n is that he loses his balance very easily.
We'll see it later on when he develops neurological problems where he loses his balance, he has an ataxic walk.
He has difficulty walking in a balanced way and we see the same idea, ataxia. The same idea of a walking which is a kind of impulsive, not smooth. There is a tendency until we have
the real ataxic movement.
Losing something to hold on to. Like he wants psychologically to hold on somebody, oh you are here I can hold you.
Or in  the bridge, I cross this and there are big rails, left and right, I can hold them and I can walk. Take them out and tell him to walk, he will fall.
He goes like that. He will go down to his 4 legs to crawl on the bridge. It's impossible, the fear tremendous. Why? He lost the rails, he lost the holding.
Desire for company, this is the same thing. Why he wants the company? To hold. Why? He is losing his balance.
There are different examples I could give you. He makes different thoughts that have been described by different patients.
Like somebody may make a story in his mind while he is walking. And as he makes the story that somebody is after him and he's going to catch him and now they are looking after him
and the story is going on, the walk becomes faster and faster. Eventually he finds himself running.
And again he stops and thinks, 'what am I doing?'
He crosses a street and sees a car coming. He says, 'I don't know if I should run otherwise the car could over run me'. The idea I should run, he starts running
he crosses the street and he keeps on running, as if the car was coming behind him. And he hears the car crashing him, seeing the car overtaking him and then the impulse to run and to go away.
Then he sits to study and he cannot concentrate because an impulse comes, an idea comes.
He looks at the socket and the idea comes, what would happen if I would put a wire in the socket?
And then he tries to study and says, what would happen, what would happen and has to get up and go there to the socket, take the wire, put it in the socket, find out what is going to happen.
Do you see how he has to act upon the impulses?
And he always stop before. The moment he starts inserting the wire to the socket, then he realizes the danger and he takes it back.
But unless he does this, he cannot continue. This is interesting feature in Arg-n. This feature you will have to understand. It is not just an impulse. He has to act upon this impulse.
The impulses will be simply impulses in the beginning, shouting and express his feelings and emotions and eventually the aberrations of the mind and these ideas will have to be acted upon.
You know the story with the man I was fishing with. We got a fish which was very deadly. And I told him, don't touch this fish, it is very deadly, you may die. And it's really actual fact.
He was treated in the center for anxiety. And we gave him Sulphur and he was doing better. You know this kind of better, I'm sure you know very well of that.
Better, better, better for 1 year but always he was coming every month, he was coming for treatment.
And then as we went out to fish, I saw this tendency going to the fish, to touch it. I turn around and say, 'don't touch this fish, it's going to kill you'.
He would leave it and be quiet. No problem, you didnt' t insult him.
And then I turn and here he's coming back to catch the fish. 'God, don't touch it. We have to go out quickly if you touch it, we have to run out quickly and perhaps we will not be able to save you'.
3,4 times I said, 'let's go out but I have a remedy for you'. I tell you, he took Arg-n, he never came for consultation. For years. He needed a repetition after 1,2 3 years I can't remember
and then again very well.
-What's the difference from Phosphorus?
-Phosphorus does not have this. They are afraid. Phosphorus if you tell him not to touch, he will never touch.
Take a child which is Phosphorus and you say, don't drink this water because it's going to make you have pain.
Forget it. You say, drink that water, it will do nothing. No, no, no it will never touch it.
Fear something will happen in Phosphorus is completely different thing.
The fear that something may happen concerns an indescribable feeling that a catastrophy is going to happen.
Something bad is going to happen. Where is the bad? In yourself, you are afraid you're going to die?
'I don't know'. 'Your mother is going to die? Your son?', 'I don't know, I'm constantly in that fear, something may happen'. Now that has nothing to do with this kind.
It's interesting that fear of death is very strong with Arg-n and yet whatever is producing the possibility of death, he is attracted. Like Aurum. You see the similarities?
Impulse to jump, attracted to the jumping but Aurum will be attracted to a fit, to show off.
I will do something that nobody in the class can do. That's Aurum.
What you will do? You see this building? I will climb from the windows and I will go up to the top.
By outside? He says yes. He will do it. He is not afraid of dying and at the same time he is courting with death. He will do something that everybody else is afraid to do.
Arg-n is not like that, it's not brave. Argentum will avoid such a situation. But if he finds himself on a high place, his weak mind starts playing games with him.
It's a weak mind which is overtaken by the idea. This is what is important because I cannot give you all the examples in the world that you can meet.
The idea is that once the mind has been overtaken by an idea and the person is acting upon this idea, then we may have a case of Arg-n.
Causticum is different. Completely different. When Causticum reaches that state, it can be a simpler state, not a great anxiety but the fear that he has forgotten something which may cause problems.
Letting open the gas, letting the lights open, letting the stove open and somebody will enter in the night and he forgets and he gets up to go and close it. That never happens with Arg-n.
Causticum has to get up and check. Even if he knows but he cannot exactly remember. He thinks but he does not remember.
He says yes I closed it but maybe I did not and that can reach very pathological states. It  can reach a state where he can check his money.
Take it out, how much it is, measure it and put it back. Then he goes to the office, he takes it out, checks everything, checks the notes he has inside, put it back.
He goes back to the house, I mean this kind of checking. It can reach very pathological states, impulsive states.
I remember a woman preparing to go for a 15 days holiday, preparing the luggage and checking for 1 month.
One month checking the luggage,  15 days holiday. The husband says, I mean this is impossible.
The whole house! She checks this and put this and take out this and checks this and I forgot. Always the fear that she may forget to take the right thing and go with the right thing.
This is different.
Which other remedies except of Causticum?
Iodine is very similar.
Syphilinum yes in a different way.
All these actions, all these impulses, you have to understand it is very difficult to describe with words what I want to say.
And sometimes I describe a little bit extreme states but I can't do otherwise. Otherwise it won't be imprinted in your mind.
An individual who does strange things, what I call strange thing is something which we say why he did that? Why he behaved that way?
You do not understand and then from that little state of aberration, it goes into these impulses and putting wires etc.
If you happen to ask him, he will go into explanations which are not valid. You understand he just tries to find a way to cover up himself.
You caught him while he's putting the wire, what are you doing there?
'Well I did not know whether this was a socket for telephone or for electricity'. I mean you understand it's an explanation which is stupid.
It's not logical, he will try to cover up.
He, himself understands what is happening but still it will take time before he will go to the doctors and say, this is happening to me.
With constitutional Arg-n it is something which is with his character almost, this kind of behavior. It's imbued with his own character.
And the text says: he gave all sorts of queer reasons for his strange conduct. And the endeavoring to cover up his foolishness that he, himself realizes.
These words are words of a prover.
And also there is the other fear which is fear of high buildings, falling upon him.
If this fear is there it's a keynote of course.
Sometimes the brain fag is felt so much that he is out of reality. In such cases the patient becomes so irrational and obstinate that he may object for no reason. Just for the shake of objecting. I will give you an example.
You have a child and you have some milk and it's Arg-n and you give it to the child. You give the milk bottle to the child and the child will go like that, it will push you.
You say all right, you take it back. Ahhh, he wants it. You give it to him, it pushes it. Ahhh, I want it and it may go 10 times to do this before it will take the bottle and drink it.
Do you understand? There is an objection which is for the shake of objecting, it's not logical.
You will see this in grown ups, you will see it covered up. It's not obvious as with the child because it's crazy. People are saying, what is you want?
It's very interesting that I gave Arg-n in a severe cornea destruction. Very deep destruction and ulcer in the cornea, in the eye
where the child was paralyzed due to a shock and the eye remained open and the lacrimal duct did not work.
It became completely dry and created an ulcer, no antibiotic could help, it was a lot of pus, severe ulcer etc.
I said, Arg-n. It helped a lot but the parents say, 'I'll tell you something very strange'. 'What?'. He said 'the child for 15 days - or for less I can't remember - he developed that kind of behavior'.
It was a proving for Arg-n. 'We gave him something, he said, I don't want it, we gave a toy, no. We take the toy, I want it. But it doesn't really take it, it objects again and again', which proves that Arg-n has strongly this point.
As the pathology goes deeper, we've been describing different stages of pathology, the patient can reach a stage of compulsive neurosis or fixed ideation; he may be alarmed, fear that he has an impulse to kill someone. And impulse to kill his own child.
These impulses to kill others or one of the members of the family and many times his own child, are tremendously bothering him and when it comes to that state, he will confess immediately the problem.
He won't hold it back as before we said, when he had these impulses. He will not describe these kind of impulses; he will describe the anxiety, the fear death. He will not describe the kind of impulses.
Usually in Arg-n, you will describe for him and he will say, yes.
And it's very easy to see that the 'yes' is very straight forward. He is amazed to see how much you know about him.
And then you describe, do you have this kind? He says, 'yes exactly! You are a magician, you know everything!'.
At other times, especially  during acute diseases, they may develop the fear that they may die at a particular hour of the day.
He says, 'when the clock strikes 3 o'clock I will be dead, I know it'.
Another characteristic of Arg-n is his claustrophobia.
The patient may be completely incapable of entering an elevator.
He will just climb the stairs, even if the building is quite high.
His anxieties can be aggravated if he feels he is entrenched, closed, especially if the place is quite small.
The room feels like a tomb. There is a feel of death about it and he becomes quite anxious.
Also he may suffer claustrophobia while he is in the theater with a lot of other people. Claustrophobic in a crowd.
And this claustrophobia may come during fever, febrile state where he feels that the walls are very high and they are going to crash upon him.
He is going to feel very great fear in tunnels, when the train goes through tunnels, he goes into panicky states. He cannot enter tunnels.
Also fear of travelling by airplanes, why? You know the doors in the airplanes, when the hostess close the door, that is the time for Arg-n.
It's his best time, he waits for that, he looks at the doors. Still open, still we can jump and then it's final, inside there.
Then the anxiety, the palpitation, the panic state may come. And they may reach this stage where they cannot travel actually.
This is similar to Aconite and also similar with Calcarea carbonica.
Perhaps we must say that the patient must not have all this symptomatology I have described,
He is a museum what I'm describing. Museum symptomatology but he will have some aspects of the remedy and will be the type of person.
We must also understand the remedies by stages and degrees. And here we have to understand that from some anxiety
and some impulsiveness, he is becoming more and more fitful and impulsive, fidgety and restless. Trembling and convulsed and panicky.
You see he doesn't have to have all this pathology. He will have, depending on the stages, one stage, the second stage, the third stage.
From transient stage of impulsive behavior, he goes on to a crescendo until the whole nervous system is in a tremendous turmoil.
The memory breaks down completely and cannot remember words, cannot remember the name of the husband.
If she is married, to whom she is married; maybe that was an inner wish for many years and it is realized from the pathology.
It becomes very impulsive, almost asserting in a crazy way, shouts, demands, slaps her own face.
Especially when she cannot find the right words. Do you imagine what am I describing?
It's the pathology which has progressed now. It has gone into, what we call the state? It's Alzheimer's disease.
It's progressing towards that condition. Forgetting, who am I, who is he, the husband?
Where is the house? I don't remember. Where is this? And then he can be impulsive and say, tell me this word, tell me I can't remember.
I'm talking about a crazy person. But crazy in that way.
It's very difficult to describe. I don't know how much you understand.
We may see the same idea of escalation, when we have stages of slight choreic movements to stage where the choreic movements are so violent, that the patient can hardly remain in the chair or in bed.
It reaches from lighter stage to more intense stage, to more intense stage until in choreic movements he cannot stay in the chair. He just falls of the chair.
In the last stages Arg-n will produce a state of apathy, indifference with complete loss of memory, cannot find words, trembling all over, ataxic gait and the face looking much older than the actual age.
Here we have Arg-n looking older. This I have not found in younger patients. They're looking quite all right.
When Arg-n reaches that state of deep pathology, then they have a look of very old face. They are 60 and they look 80. They are 50 and they look 75.
So Arg-n is one of the warmest remedy in our Materia Medica.
Kent: there is a marked aggravation from heat of any sort. And the patient is ameliorated by cold water. Cold bathing, cold applications. Walking in cold winds.
All this relieves the patient. You see this fits with the intensity which is inside, with the circulation which is strong.
With the palpitations, with the violence. He is not violent, what I say violent is the violent action of the circulatory system.
Usually the complaints are worse in the summer.
Another factor which aggravates the patient is lying on the right side, where he has palpitations, a kind of dyspnea, flatulence and abdominal colicky pains.
All this can be aggravated by lying on the right side.
We mentioned already that Arg-n is important in convulsions and during the convulsions the patient may lose completely consciousness.
Before the epileptic fit, he may have the sensation that his body is expanded.
Besides these actual epileptic disorders, we sometimes find trembling of the whole body and especially after breakfast. In the morning after breakfast, we see a general trembling of the whole body.
There is a general tendency for growths, papillomas, fibromas, warts, condylomata. Can occur anywhere in the body and a tendency for easy ulceration.
Not so much on the skin as much on the mucus membranes.
General trembling weakness, there is also a peculiar periodical weakness.
The patient may feel very well, good energy and suddenly his energy drops completely to the extend that he cannot lift a paper.
And that remains for a few days and goes up again and continues. And then again sudden drop.
It seems perhaps this is disturbance in the suprarenal glands, I don't know.
The weakness may come with exact periodicity or at irregular intervals.
You don't have to have exact periodicity every 3 months, it may be 2, 5 months, it may be irregular, every 4 months. But it may not.
The patient also becomes extremely irritable after such attacks. Everything will irritate the person.
And there is usually a despair which comes after these periodic weaknesses, that nothing can be done about his condition.
A general characteristic of the pains of the remedy is splinter like pains.
It's a remedy that would be indicated in multiple sclerosis, in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, myopathy, epilepsy, chorea. This kind of nervous diseases.
In the head there is a sensation of enlargement of the head which is felt as painful congestion and fullness especially during pregnancy.
The sensation is ameliorated by wrapping up the head.
There is a sensation as if the head becomes big and they take a towel and put around and they feel the head is going back again.
Headaches may be produce by emotional excitement but more especially from frights and also from mental exertion.
Headaches have a slow, gradual onset and rapidly decrease.
Sometimes we see a very sudden headache, not in gradual onset but the usual is the gradual.
And we see again an amelioration from pressure.
Headaches end many times, when in their pick, end in vomiting.
Headaches worse at night with the warmth of bed, aggravated by strong odors, even if the odors are perfumes.
Boring headache in left or right prominence, left mostly.
Right frontal eminence, worse motion and extending to nape of neck.
Left headache here which extends to the nape of neck, which is the other remedy?
Bryonia.
Headache on temples extending to upper jaw.
Headaches as if the bones of the scalp were separated.
Vertigo from high places of course and vertigo when closing the eyes, vertigo going through a narrow bridge.
The vertigo is like an experience of being drunk.
Sometimes this vertigo is accompanied by tachycardia, inner trembling and a feeling of fainting.
And in epilepsy, an attack of epilepsy can be preceded by vertigo. First vertigo and then comes the attack.
Arg-n has a big effect on the eyes.
These complains generally occur from overuse and from heat, in warm rooms and ameliorated by cold applications.
There is a very characteristic thing in the eyes, as you remember, the conjunctiva can become very red and it's a big piece of redness on the white, that you can see sometimes quite big and quite strong red.
This sign may indicate a case of Arg-n, especially if people have it chronically.
And they describe this redness as raw meat, as you cut open and it's like raw meat.
Why they describe it as raw meat? Because it has the appearance of something which is freshly cut. It's so vivid. It's not a dried up thing.
This looks really as if you cut some piece of meat and it's fresh.
Purulent discharges from the eye. You will see the conjunctivitis will produce a lot of pus. You have a lot of pus produced.
And there is redness. The redness can be on the whole conjunctiva but more peculiar is when you have an area which is completely separated from others; it's not a diffused redness.
It's an area which is absolutely red, red spot in the conjunctiva and you see it immediately and it gives you that impression of something which is freshly cut.
A similar condition you will see with what other remedy?
With Medorrhinum. Medorrhinum produces severe conjunctivitis and severe inflammation with a lot of pus, with redness, with the inflammation the lids are inflamed. Terrible thing to look.
In epileptic condition we see dilation of the pupils before the convulsions.
Tremendous photophobia also.
Photophobia is aggravated in a warm room and this is a grand keynote. Photophobia aggravated in warm room. If the room is warm then photophobia becomes much worse. If you remember this, that's a good keynote.
Dim vision of the left eye with headache on the right side.
And it has sudden presbyopia in young persons. In persons you don't expect to have presbyopia like me, sudden presbyopia which you don't expect to see.
Ulceration of the cornea and purulent ophthalmia especially in the newborn children.
Inflammation of the eyelids with thick crusts.
In the ear we have noises with vertigo, ringing in the ears accompanied by partial deafness.
Ringing in the morning in bed, ringing in the ears. Pain in ears in the morning after rising.
All these are peculiar symptoms for Arg-n but are so many, it's impossible to select some.
Somebody asked me to give Materia Medica constantly, nothing else. He says, give Materia Medica.
-No.
-Even if you say yes, I'm not able to do it. You see I have to put a lot of energy into shouting for 6 hours.
Somebody who just speaks 6 hours drops dead, on the 5 and 1/2 hour.
In the end I want you to find my remedy; after I've given you all this information.
Strong flatulence not always. You don't have to have it. Sometimes you don't see it at all. Especially when you have the anxiety states, the flatulence is missing completely.
Desire for sweets, Arg-n very much.