I want to read you something from Margaret Tyler, what she has written in Aurum in her pictures.
She says: 'some of us could tell tale after tale of patients in these days of world wide commercial depression, who reduce to despair by straighten means and anxiety threatened suicide.
And yet we are rapidly restored to life, to hope to renewed effort by a few doses of homeopathic Aurum'.
You see it's the experience of every homeopath. It's not that I'm telling you stories to give Aurum, no. She lived 60 years ago. And she lived through that depression period.
In the development of the pathology of such individual we must not forget his cachectic emotional life.
The emotional coldness that eventually develops, the continuous emotional winter that shapes so much of the individual's actions and decisions.
It's individual that live in an emotional winter, snow, cold, white. We have much more suicides as we go towards the North, Sweden had a high rate of suicides one time, not lately. Finland also.
An Aurum individual feels that he lives constantly without the rays of the sun, without any sun. Without hope, without warmth.
He feels a kind of situation where everything becomes dark, cold, dark, still, not moving, hard. The sun, hope, the rays, the warmth are gone away.
And the coldness and the darkness and the despair and the suffering which is so deep and so tremendous that will not allow him even the possibility to save himself.
There is no possibility that he will get out of it. There is such coldness, such darkness, there is no hope.
He had a financial ruin, he turns around and he looks upon the possibilities. He says I have friend, he may be able to lend me some money for some time. He says no. The answer inside him is 'No. He will never do it, I don't believe he will do it'.
He turns around to a banker who is a friend, he says 'he could save me. He says no'. He turns around, he searches for some light, some hope, he searches inside before he jumps.
And the answer always is no, no, no. And then he goes towards other departments like his wife, 'could she help me? She could not help me really.
And in any case I never treated her justly and I was always very cold. She will not help. And he goes to the children. They cannot help. Why should they care?'. He goes around, there is nothing to hold on.
Eventually we shall see the pathology as develops, there is one thing that he may hold on but usually it is nothing. It's darkness, darkness, coldness, no feeling, suffering, depressed.
And then the decision comes. I can't stand it and they jump.
What also can destroy an Aurum individual is constant criticism. If people around are criticizing him. He cannot stand it.
Especially criticism from his closest associates. And he does not need an overt criticism. He needs just hints. If somebody goes and tell him, 'you know your friends say something so and so about you'.
He says, 'it doesn't matter' but inside him he is destroyed. Outside he will say, it doesn't matter. Inside tremendous! Somebody else says, 'so and so about you', another criticism and another criticism. That is a situation which is very dangerous for an Aurum individual.
Why? Because he believes that he works, he is just, he is doing write, he tries to do everything correct and what he receives? Criticism.
And that contrast inside him brings the downfall. He is going to have a breakdown.
He expects that everyone understands his high ideals, his high aspirations and the inborn justice that prevail in him. And therefore he cannot take criticism.
Or he feels that they misunderstand him. They do not understand me.
The anarchist now follows another path all together.
An Aurum anarchist can be very passionate about a cause. And he can become an extremist or a terrorist.
And what he does. He seems to court, to flirt all the time with the possibility of death. You see an extremist going underground, he has all the time the possibility of maybe caught or maybe killed.
That situation excites them and makes them feel that they are alive, that they do something which is correct.
The idea that any time he can be killed. Instead of taking them away from the activities, it makes them be more active in the terrorist act.
What an Aurum individual, an anarchist feels inside is lack of joy of course. Now he confuses that lack of joy that everything is wrong outside in the society.
He cannot see anything right because inside him there is no joy, there is no way that he can enjoy himself.
So what he sees inside him is darkness and lack of happiness. So why should he let such a society live? Destroy the society. Because it's a society without happiness, without joy, without any pleasure.
With a lot of injustice and immorality. You see the high ideals how they take another turn all together? Another path?
And they go towards something which Aurum has inborn in him, an inborn violence. There is a violence inside Aurum that we shall see later on.
And this violence is not expressed all the time, it's not overt but it's going to come from time to time and it's going to be very violent. Therefore in the Repertory says, violent. It's very violent when it comes.
He is excited by the idea of death and invites it. Therefore he may engage in underground activities that create the risk of death and provide him with his needed stimulation.
Interestingly when such a person arrives at the brink of success, such as when he is just about to assume a position of authority or leadership in the group he will usually drop out from the group.
It's very interesting, the same idea with the relationship.
In a relationship he will say no, the relationship is not perfect, so he will withdraw. But he is in love. One says, how he could be so much passionate, so much in love and can leave the relationship?
Now the same thing here. How much this man was so passionate about the group, the anarchist and then he did whatever he did, within the group becomes somebody that everybody admires.
And they say now you are the leader. He says no, this is wrong and that is wrong. He starts criticizing and he leaves the group.
This is the story that you will hear.
Such individuals will seek another group, another ideal to serve with eventually the same consequences.
During his depression Aurum thinks that the light has completely gone. There seems to be a hardness.
In English you say induration. Something that becomes indurated, hard. Induration of the feelings. The feelings are withdrawn and become hard.
This can end in a malignant, emotional ulcer. You see feelings is something alive. It's not something static. No. Feelings go like that.
They go like that and little, little, little they become hard and they become a mass which is hard but at the same time is alive.
Now what is going to come out of that? It's a malignant ulcer, the idea of hardness and then eventually the malignant ulcer.
This very same idea of hardness, of induration and ugly ulceration we see running through the remedy and affecting the glands, especially the uterus.
Induration of the uterus, or the testes which are, peculiarly enough, the organs of expressing love on a physical level.
Why Aurum has so many times induration of the testes? Hardness, swelling indurated testicles? Induration of the uterus?
You see the organs that are involved mostly with the physical love and exchange of emotions, they have become indurated.
And that's why we see black letters for Aurum, indurated testicles.
Which is the remedy that has the worse kind of induration in the uterus? Where we see fibromas, full of fibromas in the uterus?
It is the Aurum muriaticum natronatum. It's a combination for Aurum. For keynotes prescribers, if they see an indurated uterus with a lot of fibromas, Aur-m-n.
Sees no possibility for changing his life. No possibility to change.
You understand this kind of induration? Something which is indurated is not flexible anymore. This induration imagine it in the emotional level.
It will produce an ulcer, it will produce something very ugly, death finally, inside and violence by which Aurum can be overtaken.
It's the emotional ugly ulcer. You see a person who was before, so well behaved, so nice, so controlled, suddenly to behave like mad.
Like an open ulcer, that's ugly. The same thing you will see it on the physical body. The same induration, ulcers.
It's very interesting that during that time when he is in a high place and he is in a state of Aurum, how they have described it certain people.
They say, they hear almost a voice, it's not a delusion but it's almost like hearing a voice saying to them, 'jump, jump. Now is your time, jump, jump, jump' and they jump.
It is like an impulse to jump from a high place. It's really an impulse that can start like 'jump, jump' and then the confusion, the emotional suffering and then the life which has no purpose for them.
All these are mixed up that moment and they see a solution, as a freedom. 'You are going to be free now if you jump.
You will be free from suffering, the suffering is so much, unbelievable and you are going to be free from suffering, jump'. This is the idea behind Aurum.
And the very thought of suicide, 'I'll jump oh yes I have the solution. I can jump, I can kill myself and everything will be finished and my suffering will be finished'.
That very idea brings relief. If they continue doing that, eventually they feel relief. The idea that there is a solution that they can jump and kill themselves, brings relief.
There is a peculiarity here that you may need some time, a person who does not want to live, who has no desire to live, yet they have a tremendous fear of hearing even the word, die.
Can you imagine this contrast? Some person who does not want to live and yet the idea of death is bringing shake.
It is an over reaction to the idea of death. A tremendous reaction to the idea of death. They cannot stand it.
So if you see that peculiar phenomenon between loathing of life on the one hand and not being able even to hear the word, 'dying' or 'death', then most probably this is a case of Aurum.
Aurum in general has a fascination for things that remind death. That can cause death, like being in a high place, like looking on a deep well, in a deep lake, a cemetery, reptiles. There is a fascination. The idea that this now can cause death.
They want to go near these places, they are attracted by such situations where death is. Like the anarchists, he is attracted by the idea 'I'm going now to establish my ideals'. How?
'By just putting bombs but these bombs can cause my own death. Either they can explode near me or they can catch me and kill me etc.' This situation is so attractive. He is attracted towards such situations.
I will talk a little bit about the industriousness of Aurum.
The depressed Aurum hides his depression from others and balances it with industriousness.
Despite his emotional turmoil, he maintains control over his mind and seeks to engage in mental occupation to avoid his emotional problems.
His work isn't the least bit compromised by his sadness.
He performs very competently right up to the moment he commits suicide. Aurum will not give up his work and will say, I can't work.
While the depression is going on the work outside is continuing and it's a kind of balance for him. It's a kind of relief for him to work, work, work.
Aurum will never ask for help or advice from a friend or relative in the matters on which he has problems.
He feels it's too degrading and he considers it's his problem alone.
The sense of responsibility is so strong that he cannot do otherwise although he might have liked giving up work.
He says to himself, 'I cannot continue this way' but still he continues without complaining, without discussing it.
So when you are confronted with a case of a workaholic, with a constant background of depression, you must think of Aurum.
Natrum sulphuricum? Yes we can. We'll talk about it.
In some other cases together with the depression he feels that he has lost all ability to think and perform.
He feels weary and listless; yet he does not relax, he does not rest. His sleep is disturbed and in short he feels that he is incapable of delivering his obligations.
Yet this is not easy for others to perceive because the results of his work are still quite good.
You see how strong intellectually he is? Before he breaks down intellectually, he takes a long, long process of pathology.
Because Aurum can work intellectually, can work, can work and emotionally can suffer tremendously.
How this man suffers so much, you say, not showing anything to anybody?
Usually an Aurum commits suicide before reaching a state of imbecility.
So he will not be imbecile, he will have suicide before the imbecility.
Yet sometimes the pathology can progress so quickly towards imbecility and can have a case of imbecility because of too fast progress, that passes the phase of suicide and you may get sometimes the imbecile Aurum.
Aurum is especially indicated when these states inside are perceived by him. He says, I'm losing my mind. I'm becoming incapable in my mind and that disturbs him a lot.
If the person perceives that and it is expressed, then that can be a case of Aurum.
We talked about anger and violence for a self reproach.
In Aurum we have self reproach, self criticism and anger.
The self reproach can take a self destructive turn like smoking a lot, drug taking or alcohol drinking.
There is a self destruction which does not say, commit suicide. Instead of saying commit suicide, he smokes 60 cigarettes the day.
He knows it's the same thing. He tends to do that, just smoke, smoke, smoke. And everybody says but he smokes too much. Why don't you take care of your health?
He doesn't pay any attention, he keeps on smoking. Inside him he knows that he wants to die and he does not care.
Or he can take drugs, for younger people it can be drugs or can be a kind of anarchistic activities.
Let's say for a man who is executive, a managing director. This managing director has a very hectic emotional life.
And one day he is criticized by his boss. He does not say anything to anybody, he goes on, he broods, he sits, he thinks.
And his wife is concerned. What happened? Because she can see it, what happened? They don't want interference, they want to solve that problem by themselves.
And if his wife keeps on saying what happened, that can irritate so much the Aurum individual that they can burst out into tremendous anger and violence.
He has no tolerance for being pressurized. He cannot tolerate, he says leave me alone and the wife says but I see that you are not feeling well.
Pfff.. immediately he will do like that.
And if his wife keeps on nagging and telling things and interfere with his brooding then he can have violent outbursts.
In all our remedies, we observe several stages of pathology and we should never limit ourselves to one idea only, like suicidal depression.
Now in these cases with the executive, you may not see the suicidal depression but we see the brooding, the silent thing, he sits by himself, he will not talk. Something has happened to him but never talk to anybody, never say anything.
His wife is pressurizing and you see the outburst of tremendous anger and sometimes violence. Now the violence I have to describe. The violence usually is not directed towards human beings.
He will not take the hammer or the knife and throw it to somebody, a human being. The violence would usually be directed to objects. They can break this, 'leave me alone. I told you many times, don't ask me!'.
He can hit the wall, he can break the glasses and he can leave in a fit of tremendous anger. And pressurize, I can't stand anymore, then the depression, he goes to his car, he puts it on and full gas.
And during that time he wishes I would have an accident. I wish I had an accident. He drives in such a way that he wishes another car would crash upon him
that he would take his car and crash against a tree or a wall. He accelerates and goes through traffic, something will happen.
Eventually all this turmoil through that outlet is calming him down and after an hour of such driving may come back home and he will continue brooding but he will be calmed down.
You see the anger and the violence is different. Violent also in Nux vomica and is Stramonium and Belladonna, there are different kinds of violence.
That violence the idea is self destruction. That is the idea behind everything. That is where he is always led. To a self destruct, to a downfall.
The violence if you see it, if you are in front, if you are present, it can be tremendous.
Because you see a man breaking glass by kicking and then it's not enough. He feels that he has to let the anger out more and then he takes the car and then he does things.
I'm bringing you examples that have spot our of the cases. It's not only that. The modifications can be quite different and you improvise and think of other possibilities.
In the Repertory it says 'violence'. Now what it means? It means violence under such circumstances. It says, intolerance of contradiction.
Yes but what kind of contradiction? That kind, under these circumstances, this type of individual.
Do you see how they take meaning all these simple words?
Whatever I told you, most probably you will find it one way or another, under some description but what is very important for us is to understand the whole personality.
And we go now to another aspect of Aurum which is very interesting.
We said before that is a man who goes towards depression, towards darkness. More darkness inside, no light but these are words that do not convey the real suffering.
The real suffering is coldness. If you have your hand squeezed by a tremendous pressure, squeeze your emotions, how you feel? This is how he feels.
It's tremendous coldness, he can't move at all, it's pressurized, it's tremendous the suffering and the darkness and all that.
Now he has to find a solution. What is the solution? 'To die. I can't live, I must die. I have to commit suicide'.
During that period, certain Aurum individuals, will develop a symptom which is praying to God.
They pray and pray. This praying takes two forms. On younger people has one form. You feel the depression and you have to hold on to something.
We said, he does not find anything to hold on to. Suddenly the religious feeling develops within the individual. God may help me, God may save me.
And there is suddenly a desire to pray to God, to ask from God. And these younger people with depression, they are going to hours and hours of praying.
There is a kind for relief for them to kneel down and pray. And if you ask them, if you really get the information on these people, what they will say is, 'I like to pray'.
But, they will say, 'I think I'm praying too long'. They go to bed at 10-11 o'clock and until 1 o'clock in the morning they found themselves praying.
'I think I pray too long'. This is the pathology that you have to understand. Otherwise this brings such a relief that they feel it's a natural thing to do, praying.
We must not confuse this praying with the natural tendency of the human beings that they have to pray, from time to time or perhaps every day, depending on the religious group they belong.
This is a different praying. It's more conscious. In this Aurum it is a driving force inside him. We say 'praying', they do pray and eventually they calm down, their depression lessens. But it's a driving force inside. They say, otherwise I feel very bad.
Before we spoke about the anarchists. We must not confuse that situation with conscious people who feel this world is unjust and we must bring some justice.
But there is some logic in that. They don't go and throw bombs. What are you talking? Nonsense. Aurum throws a bomb. Everybody is killed.
This is an extreme action, it is pathology.
When you strain your hand, when you pick up more weight you will feel some pain. This pain is not pathology.
Pathology will be when without any reason, you get a tremendous pain. This is pathology. So do not confuse what I'm saying with the natural tendencies of human beings.
The adult who prays is praying on another level. Again it's a compulsory praying but much shorter.
How we are connected between us? You think we are connected because I'm talking and you're listening, right?
No, it's not that. We're connected because I give something of my feelings and this is what makes you attentive.
Feelings connect the human beings, not intellect. A person feels disconnected and isolated if he has no strong feelings to connect with others.
He cannot feel connected. He feels isolated. He feels alone. You see the idea now in this state he feels connected with nobody. Why? Because everybody has disappointed him.
The world is no good. The world is full of suffering. How can I trust? And live and be connected?
All these questions come and then the idea of God comes and says God is something which cannot betray me.
So I can let my feelings towards God and he is holding on to the idea of God. The idea can help him, can save him actually.
And then he prays from time to time. We have seen it with people who do not believe really.
Who they said before, I'm not thinking about God. What is God? Then under the depression of Aurum, the urge comes, to pray, to feel connected and to stay alive.
This is a way for Aurum to stay alive. To be connected with life. Because he has been disconnected through everything else.
A remedy imprints upon human beings, its own seal. It's like putting a seal. Sulphur, Phosphorus, Aurum as a constitutional.
This Aurum is going to develop the pathology on all levels of Aurum. Now what is the pathology on different levels of Aurum?
Somebody needs to differentiate between the Aurum depression and the Natrum sulphuricum depression.
What is the difference? Natrum sulphuricum is a different individual. It's an individual who is a responsible individual again but not of that depressed kind.
Natrum sulphuricum may go through serious grief. A man who lost his child, a man who lost his wife whom he loved very much.
He will not talk again, he is not talking, he is not communicative but is a man who loves, his emotions are not dead.
Therefore he feels for others. A man who loves is somebody who feels, this person loves me, I cannot hurt him by committing  suicide because they will suffer so much.
They consider that, the feelings are alive and they consider it so strongly. Now we have a contrast between a person who has lost his wife and does not want to live.
Because is a Natrum sulphuricum, everybody must want to live if he is in a healthy state. But being in a Natrum sulphuricum state, he does not want to live.
Because my wife for me was everything. But my daughter who loves me very much is going to suffer tremendously if I commit suicide.
So inside him there is constant struggle between I don't want to live but if you do it can you imagine how much is going to suffer?
Do you know how much is going to suffer? Yes but I don't want to live. Then there is another event proving him he doesn't want to live.
But then again, your daughter, your children. Don't do that for your children. And there is a constant struggle. That is characteristic of Natrum sulphuricum state.
When you have that state, you have a different individual and you have a different description of how he wants and why he wants. That's why we described how he wants to die, why he wants to die;
in order to be able to differentiate eventually and to say, yes this is an Aurum case.
Aurum has a strong sense of duty but only in an intellectual level. It's not only that. Aurum has a duty because he feels he must be successful.
In order to be successful, he must be responsible. If he is irresponsible, things will take their own turn. Why? Because the others must adore him.
It's a whole syndrome and once you see this syndrome, then you have a state of Aurum.