I will try to give you information about different remedies and I will try to give an information which is 3-dimensional, an much as possible.
You may remember the remedies as personalities, as live entities. So therefore you will have to excuse a little bit my metaphors and vivacity and acting.
I don't want to give a stiff seminar.
I will give you the final information, final for the time being. The way I speak sometimes creates a lot of misunderstanding.
He says, George is an egoist. Final Materia Medica. It's not final, it's final what I finalized writing.
You are going to take this information and add it to your knowledge and you present eventually a much better information.
So this is the final information as I wrote it down on Aurum Metallicum.
And as we all know, Aurum-Gold imprints upon the human organism the idea of self destruction, of annihilation, of death.
When injected into the living human organism tends to deprive the person of the will to live. The person does not want to live.
It is the principal remedy, which develops a state of loathing for life, a desire to die.
And a strong tendency to commit suicide.
As several other remedies correspond to this suicidal depression, we'll concentrate now on the peculiar characteristics of Aurum. And we'll start with the personality of Aurum.
As we said, the central theme of Aurum is extreme depression and loathing of life which progresses to suicidal thoughts and finally self-destruction.
What I have said so far has been clearly described in our books so far. Everybody is supposed to know this.
But an extreme depression does not usually develop over night.
And for homeopaths, for us it's very important to prevent a state than treat a state.
So what I'm going to give you as information is how a person, what is the make up of a person who is going to develop such state as suicidal depression.
Which is the particular personality that is going to develop this desires to die.
So the pathological Aurum condition usually arises in people who possess a serious and introvert character.
They are generally closed people, responsible and quite refined.
Serious, responsible, refined. At the early stages of pathology, one can sense that they avoid superficial contacts.
They tend to remain rather aloof or self contained.
Generally they are very disciplined and highly ambitious people.
They seem to have, the fundamental conviction that they are destined for a superior and esteemed position in life.
Slowly they build the character, the personality of the person who is going to develop Aurum symptomatology, just remember that.
We have to recognize this character beforehand to prescribe Aurum and not allow him to go to deep depression where may most probably commit suicide.
Aurum, we must not forget is the metal gold, it's gold.
So if we personify gold, how gold would feel, superior from the other metals, having the highest position possible, it's the analogous of the person who has that inside him.
It is as if they feel that a high position in life is their birthright.
It's very interesting in Aurum how much you will see, how much of the personality of the gold, if we can say it this way.
This characteristic that I'm the highest, I'm the superior characterizes immediately what?
The egotistical quality of Aurum people. There is an egotistical element in them.
Though they may not spoken out, they may not say I'm superior because they are serious, they are refined, they are responsible but what they feel is important because that element is going to be affected eventually.
When they are under stress, it is that element which is going to shake them inside, that egotistical element which will bring eventually the downfall of the person, of the inside.
They want to be and feel they are more capable than others. They have that conviction because they feel that they have a high intrinsic value like gold.
They set very high standards for themselves and work hard to achieve those standards.
You see the serious element is not a person who is a superficial egoist, it's a person who works hard, is ambitious, I'm destined for high position, responsible, they work, they attain
and during that time where they have attained whatever it is, the stress comes, the grief comes, the upset comes and what happens?
We have to understand the inside psychology of the person to be able to prescribe correctly.
And if you are careful and you perceive these elements, then I'm sure you will be able to recognize Aurum, never mind what is saying on verbal level.
But through this seriousness and ambition and diligent self application and industriousness, they seem to lose the sense of lightness and cheerfulness in life.
It goes away from their life. They become serious and heavy.
What you perceive is that seriousness, that application, that heaviness, no joy.
They will often say or convey the impression that throughout their life has been a pervading sense of seriousness with a touch of sadness.
There is a touch of sadness, even in the very first stages of Aurum.
It is as if a constant background of sad music is played and is accompanying the events of their lives.
As the pathology develops they will eventually go into a state of self reproach.
Self criticism and finally a feeling that they are worthless, incapable of accomplishing anything.
And the life process of an Aurum individual will actually observe the turmoils and reactions of the rising and fall of gold.
You will see gold people will believe, shooting up, it becomes the god of everybody, my gold, my gold.
Suddenly there is going down, suddenly. To see that in the personality of the person, how he rises, believing in himself and events around him and beyond his capacity to control bring the downfall suddenly.
I would like to go now into speaking about the Aurum children.
How we will recognize these children. They are children who are serious and aloof. They stay by themselves, not communicative.
Even at an early age it is difficult for them to establish close friendships.
These children are usually ambitious and attain prominence in their class at school.
Their parents will describe them as serious. At the same time one can see a sensitivity and a refinement in these children.
And we can say that the weak point of Aurum children or even Aurum grown ups is what? It's the mental level, the emotional level or the physical level?
It's the emotional level. Their weak point is their emotional level. That is the level which is going to be affected.
Their mind will remain almost intact, even under a lot of stresses. The emotional is the one that is going to suffer primarily.
Not that the mind will not suffer eventually. If you drug somebody with gold, you know the gold injections that they give for rheumatoid arthritis
if you have an Aurum case where you give Aurum, gold injections, you will have a tremendous proving.
And in this proving you will see the destruction of the whole human being, mentally, emotionally etc. but what is prominent in Aurum is the fact that their emotional level is very weak.
They are vulnerable emotionally but at the same time they are very strong intellectually. Intellectually strong, emotionally vulnerable.
Externally one sees a person who appears quite normal. The vulnerability and extreme sensitivity is inside and not readily apparent on the surface.
You will not see a child who will be frightened, fragile, no. You will see a serious child, intellectually very strong, he will ask you questions and he will give you answers.
But when you touch the emotional level, you see the weakness.
Once they leave the shelter of the home and enter school, they inevitably encounter some difficulty, being a critical remark by a teacher or fellow students
some problem with school work etc. Critical remarks will have a tremendous and immediate effect upon these children.
You see the Aurum child has an idea about himself, is serious and everybody says he is so clever, he is so intelligent. But nobody has understood the weakness in his emotional level and then he goes to school.
And the teacher does not know about the child. He passes a remark like that. Little remark and the child is destroyed.
The weakness is that the analogue of the stress and the effect is not normal, is abnormal. The stress is  very little.
The remark is not so big. He says, why don't you write today clearly? You didn't write clearly your lessons. A remark like that, ahhh I did not write clearly.
Everything is lost, the child can fall into a depression, why? Because there is a predisposition in that child. We're talking about Aurum children. So you see the stress very little, the effect too great.
Their emotional body cannot tolerate such remarks and they seem to break down very easily. A normal child will not be so significantly affected by so slight remark as the Aurum child.
The child will not show to anybody this reaction. This reaction, what he felt it will remain by himself.
He will not go to his mother and say, my teacher said I didn't write clearly. That's Pulsatilla. Pulsatilla also can go and I'm destroyed, I didn't write clearly. That's Pulsatilla.
The Aurum child keeps this shock inside, I did not write clearly, I did not write clearly. You see, it's different all together. You see the seriousness, the internalization of things.
Phosphorus? You didn't write clearly. Ah my god I didn't write clearly. Next time I'll write clearly.
Nux Vomica will say, I didn't write clearly? I'll put fire to the teacher. It's a different reaction from inside.
The Natrum muriaticum will take it inside also like Aurum but one day, two days the effect will be off. The effect of the grief is not as great as the effect on the Aurum child.
That is how a man goes back in his life when you examine him. And he says, 'God I don't remember when I have been joyful. I really never had joy in my life, since childhood'.
This is how they will discuss, how they will give you their cases, since childhood. There was always a sad element in them.
You see they remember because the remarks stayed inside and created that thing that we'll call later on, steelness. A kind of metallic, we'll discuss about it.
Instead of showing the reaction, an internal doubt about his own abilities begins to grow.
And he begins to feel that the world is not a fit place in which to live.
You see the child does not discuss the matter. It discusses it only with himself and he says, if that can create so much suffering in me, I don't know if I will be able to live in this world.
It's not clearly as I say it. It's a sense, it's a feeling which the grown up will realize and will say, yes I have been thinking all the time.
Is this a fit place for me to live? It's not that the child will say, well I don't know if this is a fit place for me to live, no.
You will not get that response. What you get is the seriousness, the ambition, the feeling, they try, they want to be first, they must be first; otherwise they are destroyed, they must either be first or die.
You understand how we're building the personality. I want you to go inside that person and understand the personality and feel the personality. I try to describe it with words of course; there is no other way of communication.
And if we had time I would show you 10 cases of video and you would see different aspects.
He will not express his doubts and concerns but will continue trying to attain the goals of his ambition.
Further education etc. Yet throughout his entire life a sense of bitterness remains and he continues to feel that the world is a cruel, uninviting place.
Eventually this attitude leads to deep depression and suicidal disposition.
These children are not emotionally expressive. They are not affectionate, they are not warm children.
It's not the child that says, 'ah papa I love you!', they embrace, no. Inside, hard and become more and more.
As we mention, they are introvert and serious; however they do need and demand affection. Aurum does not give affection but demands adoration, affection.
They demand in different way, subtle ways but it's like the gold staying there, golden stature, everybody looking and then stays cool, giving out nothing.
No warmth, no affection but expects that everybody will enter and say, oh you are great.
Later in life, when they have established for themselves a prominent position in their career or in society, they seem to receive affection because they are esteemed by others.
They will receive praise and commendations from parents, teachers and later society. They will create that situation where they will have this. They need this affection and approval in order to survive.
It represents a kind of food for their weak, emotional nature, enabling them to maintain balance. An Aurum who does not receive attention, affection, admiration loses his balance.
We'll see how he loses his balance eventually; he goes more into depression and eventually shoots himself.
And we'll see how he will develop eventually, how the businessmen when they have big financial problem they will jump from the balcony.
Their exaggerated self confidence causes them to believe that they deserve the adulation they receive.
But with the first grief they experience, they become very hurt inside and disappointed.
They will react angrily to the situation. But the anger remains inside, unexpressed. And eventually they develop resentment.
You will see different phases. Of course there are certain stages we see that they become violent. The anger comes out. Just remember what we said, the anger remains inside.
They don't get admiration, they become angry, resentment stays inside. They don't talk. Eventually the anger and the resentment will come out in fits. And then we'll see how much violent they can become.
The Aurum child seeks the company of older persons. He exudes seriousness and most probably wants to understand intellectually what is this that is causing so much pain in the world.
It's a serious child that has felt very deep pain, has felt emotional pain. Aurum are capable of feeling tremendous emotional pain.
The pain they can feel is unbelievable. Immediately the child will say what is this I'm feeling? They don't want to discuss it verbally.
So they go and seek the company of older person, I want to know, they ask questions but the questions are not direct.
They will try to understand the world, they put serious questions. What is this, what is that? What is happening? Why my mother separated with my father?
I want to know why my uncle lost his money, what happened to him? They want to know why the teachers in the class were very angry and irritable.
It's amazing how many questions an Aurum child has and how much he understands. So much that the parents are not even aware of this fact.
Usually the parents of an Aurum child are not aware that the child understands so much and thinks about these matters.
It is because of their sensitive natures that they suffer silently with even the slightest reprimands.
The Aurum child is sure to have been hurt from the very early years because of the contrast between the importance to which he attaches himself and what others see in him.
Do you see the contrast? The child is growing with the idea 'I can, I'm superior, I can attain, I'm higher, I'm more clever, I'm this and that'.
As he goes with these ideas then comes the reprimand from the teacher, the teacher or the parent says and that causes the problem.
He believes in himself and if others do not, this destroys him. That's how the conflict starts from the very beginning.
It's interesting to observe here that an enormous amount of tragedies have unfolded in the history of mankind because of this vain belief in gold and the consequent loss of it.
A lot of tragedies in the world have taken place because collectively we believed in gold and the ups and downs of it brought about tremendous tragedies in the world.
Human beings have attached tremendous importance to gold and when they lose it, they feel that life is not worth living anymore.
You see in Aurum you will see that element that financial loss is of tremendous importance.
We don't see this with other remedies.
She is cold. If she is affected by the ventilation what are the remedies? You are very sensitive to drafts.
Kali carbonicum, Rhus-tox, Silica, Dulcamara, Calcarea, Psorinum etc.
But the slightest draft? Kali carbonicum, it will feel the slightest draft. Hepar sulphur will have a repercussion if uncovers one leg, one arm, coughing.
We're going back on the adult and we'll say that these persons are possessed of high ideals.
Great self confidence, self discipline, serious mind and who seek both to dispense and receive justice in life.
Just imagine now this person. This person encounters the first romantic affair in his life.
The dynamics in such relationship are the following: the idealistic Aurum enters the relationship with his whole energy.
He gives himself to the relationship entirely. I'm talking about the first romantic relationship that the Aurum will come to. The first love affair.
You imagine the high ideals, the justice, the things in the person. He has not understood the world.
And he goes to the relationship, he believes in that relationship. He gives himself up totally to such relationship. He immerses himself totally
in the idealism of the romance.
The relationship provides him with the warmth or the affection that his nature needs.
After some time in this relationship, he will start to observe various details which he does not like in the partner.
And he will eventually become more and more critical. He begins to withhold his affection for the least thing.
He begins to withhold his affection with little things such as is his partner should look another man.
They are sitting on a cafeteria, romantic affair and the woman sits casually and looks at another man. The Aurum, it becomes big thing for Aurum.
But he will not discuss it. He will not say anything. He will take it inside. I have to be careful.
And then he starts being critical.
Such events will take place more and more. Such things will happen every day more and more. And more and more he will withdraw his affection.
He will hold back his feelings, why? Because his feelings are not strong. The affection is not a strong feeling, uncontrollable, so he can reserve it, he can hold it back.
Because he feels more and more that this relationship - what he tought is wrong - is not perfect, it's not ideal. Now he sees some faults in the relationship.
He becomes very critical about the other person, critical about the relationship and he doesn't want to give anymore himself. He tries to withhold.
But in this effort to withhold his affection, destroys the relationship and what is usual in these stories to hear is that this man ended the relationship.
And he will end the relationship without any previous hint. The woman will fall out of the sky. She says, why?
It is because of these critical remarks every day that brought him to the realization, this is not ideal, this is not what it should be and therefore I have to stop it in order to prevent myself from going into pieces.
They feel behind it is always the emotional weakness. The emotions are not strong.
You see to what part in your life you defend yourself very much. To the part where you are most weak.
And Aurum is very weak in emotional. He is going to defend that emotional part in him because he knows if he let it loose, it may destroy him. And we really see certain Aurums cannot follow that course that I have described.
You see we learn this course from people who stayed alive but there are Aurums who jumped and we never learned exactly what happened to them inside.
When the relationship was broken by the woman, the man jumped. Therefore we conjecture in those cases, because we have approached the problem very closely.
We heard stories where people are ready to jump. And they told us, eventually they confessed, if you make them speak they tell the whole story.
And you see how they feel and how they think until the moment they jump. We do not know how they will think by the moment they really take the decision.
But I've heard descriptions of people who were very close and they have described to me exactly the situation and that is how we know, how we understand the process.
A person is loathing to face an impending future failure in the relationship. They cannot face it. Consequently he tries to avoid such a failure by being the one to end it first. But he does so at a tremendous emotional cost.
Subsequently the rupture of the relationship,
he will feel torn to pieces with grief.
He will suffer insomnia, often talking to himself when trying to fall asleep. This talking will occur in fits and jerks.
This is the night where he told his girlfriend 'that's it, it's finished' and he is hard because don't forget it's the woman that he loved before.
He cannot just say, 'leave me alone' no, he suffers. He has not discussed what he has observed all these months or years with the relationship.
He didn't say, 'oh yes you say you love me but you looked another man as well'. He is too proud to say that.
So in his mind this is certain; she looked again and again at another man. She has done this or that which is not all right.
And eventually he comes, takes the decision himself because he is responsible, he is not discussing things, he is not telling things and then getting answers.
He says that's it, finished. The woman says, 'why, why?', she cries, she makes a whole of a noise. No, he has taken his decision and he is very hard.
You see the reduction of the emotional, how the emotional becomes reduced more and more and more until it will become a steeliness inside, a silence which is like steel.
And he makes himself so hard. Forget it. We are not for each other. We are not made for each other. He will say all these things and he will go to sleep.
The woman says, this man is crazy. He never had an objection while suddenly he gave this solution. She goes to sleep and it is impossible to sleep.
He goes to sleep and then they talk but not blah, blah, blah. In fits. They think inside, 'she is going away, she didn't react properly, she really did not love me and yes I was right'
this is going in thought and then outside the other person will hear, 'no, no, go away, go!'.
You see a jerking talking with little words. It's
like a heater that you press, press and
suddenly it has to get out some steam.
That idea you will see it again and again in Aurum and we'll describe another situation.
So this man will go night after night in that state. He will wake up with anxiety a few hours after sleep, 3 hours of sleep and then wake up with tremendous anxiety, then the talking will come, this jerky talking.
And the turmoil starts and the fight of the person to be able to survive because self destruction is going to be the main theme for adult Aurum.
Self destruction is like lead towards self. Destruct, destruct, destruct and it goes like that in a crescendo and then they commit suicide.
But everything will happen inside without anybody understanding anything outside. Outside everything will be perfect.
Nobody will understand or feel anything. You have to realize that a man who makes a lot of noise:
'Don't tell me that because I will kill myself!'. This is not Aurum. Aurum will not come and tell the physician, 'you know something I want to commit suicide'.
He will say it at a certain point but he has to understand to whom he is talking, whether the doctor is serious, whether he understands him.
All these conditions before and if the doctor says, 'what I feel is, there is this kind in you, what do you think, how do you feel?'
He says, 'well I think you are right. I never enjoy. I always thought about death, even as a child I always wanted to die, I didn't want to live. I don't remember any time that I wanted to live, I just wanted to commit suicide. I thought many times'.
This is the kind of answer that you will get but not immediately. He is serious, he is introvert, he is not communicative, he has not a strong emotional side.
You have to take all these things into consideration and make the picture.
He is going through all this turmoil inside him. He will remain closed, silent, not communicative and brooding.
Aurum will soon lose all its ambition and reach a state of complete loss of hope.
Making it easier for him to exit to leave this disappointing world.
There is another aspect of Aurum that may develop in some of the Aurum cases and this is the resentment and the vengefulness.
The idea is that you go into that state and you feel the state. After such a grief, resentment and vengefulness lay to his character. He wants to take revenge in his next lover.
What happened, it was a very disappointing thing for him. He did not actually realize how all this took place because it was so intense inside.
And after this suffering that he went through, what is left is not a feeling of love or affection or disappointment.
What is left is a feeling that next time I'm not going to be in the same state. I'm going to show you.
This tendency or revenge comes inside.
And then an Aurum will act very coldly towards the next relationship.
He practically gives nothing from himself apart from an intellectual communication. He gives nothing from the emotions.
The emotions have been kept closed.
The new relationship is established primarily on an intellectual level.
The Aurum individual being considered attractive, especially because of his mental capability.
However Aurum can display a lot of sexual excitement in the relationship.
Aurum are quite sexually excited without involvement of the emotional side. It is an intellectual relationship which has another aspect which is the sexual aspect.
The emotional is missing almost completely. And unless a relationship has communication on those 3 levels, it is an unbalanced kind of relationship which is not going to end happily.
Problems are going to develop.
Eventually in such a relationship what is going to happen is - usually - the other person gets attached to such a person who is cool and always remote and a feeling that you will never be able to communicate or to conquer her or him.
Because of that feeling or remoteness, there is a cold remoteness that is very strong, it is there, he is not giving himself.
Because of that there is always, always an attachment of the other person to that person. He gets more attached and more attached.
Once this is felt by the Aurum, then he treats the other person coldly and almost cruel.
And then it starts a kind of game where he will be very critical, he will inflict suffering to the other person and at the same time silently he will suffer himself.
Because it's not a crude person, he is a refined person who understands, who has perception, who is very intellectually grounded, who understands what he is doing.
When I say that, this is going to cause suffering and the other woman or man is suffering and then they suffer themselves.
And there is a kind of vicious circle because the more they suffer, the more they will go into depression, the more they go into depression, the more remote will be and the more of this situation will arise.
Eventually an Aurum person will feel that there is no way, that he may have a successful love affair in this world.
What makes him come to this conclusion is his realization that he is completely incapable of dealing with rejection.
A rejection which has the motive that somebody is admiring him and at a certain point stops admiring him.
This is a fear of a downfall that I am financially very strong and if I lose this position, then everything is lost.
This person admires me very much and if I lose this admiration I'm done.
You see how much they depend upon others, upon the admiration and that is why in the beginning we said, they need the admiration and the love and the affection of others.
This makes them live. They are not people who can live. They are people born to destroy, to die.
The idea of death and especially death through self destruction is intimately inborn with the Aurum individual. It's very strange situation.
He feels that he will not survive if he is rejected by his lover and immediately considers the ultimate destruction for himself, which is suicide.
They say, now it's finished if the lover say to the Aurum 'it's finished, we can't go anymore', then the first thing that the Aurum person will think is suicide. 'I don't want to live'.
But at the same time he refuses to accept any kind of fault in the relationship. He wants the relationship perfect.
This of course happens not because Aurum is always pure, you see he goes for perfection, he wants perfection.
Are you perfect? How do you demand perfection from others? In a relationship you demand perfection? Are you perfect? He is not.
He is not perfect himself but he cannot do otherwise. He sees things in an idealistic manner, in an idealistic way.
He is like gold that does not accept impurities. If you put impurities you will see it immediately.
For gold person, impurities are seen too much. You put an impurity inside, it doesn't match with the gold and all together. You will see piece of black lead there. He will say, what it is?
It spoils the gold, it spoils the perfection. It's the same idea with gold. He does not want to see the impurity. He sees the impurity very much on the others.
That's why he's always very critical. You see in the papers and the book says, brooding, critical and statements like that. You don't understand the statement unless you understand the personality.
Everybody can brood but why, for what reasons? Under what circumstances? This is very important.
Let us talk about the reasons and the ways that Aurum will commit suicide, why?
We said that business and finance success is very important to Aurum. They are going to business because of financial dream.
Despite of being competitive, they are very competitive, hard working businessmen, they retain a high degree of sensitivity.
They are very sensitive about their obligations. So much so that when they are faced with a serious financial failure, without a way to meet their obligations Aurum people will be unable to see a way out.
They cannot tolerate the possibility of financial bankruptcy. They cannot tolerate the financial downfall.
Because of the implications of personal and professional situations that will be raised.
Can you imagine, I'm a successful businessman, I pay all my duties, I'm just, I'm doing this, I'm doing that. All this is going on in his mind all the time.
The moment that there is a financial downfall, then he says, now I owe him these money and I cannot pay him. He cannot face that situation.
It is impossible I owe him and I cannot pay him back. There is no way out. So their mind is fixed on that idea. They cannot find another way.
And that is the time that without giving any hint or anything beforehand that somebody would understand what they are thinking, without any hint of what they are going to do they find themselves in a balcony and they just fall and
kill themselves.
It is the situation where we had in the financial crisis of 1929, people jumping from high places, financial suicide, these are the type of people.
I mean you know the stories, you know how many people jumped from the balconies because they could not face.
The depression goes on, I mean it will not go from one day to the other. It will go from a depression, bigger depression, I cannot face, I have this obligation, I have that obligation.
Then they paralyze inside, they lose the capacity to work, to think out solutions. They seem as if they have no capacities at all. At this moment they feel that they are not capable at all.
And that they cannot face the fact that the other people will not anymore adore them, they will not anymore admire them.
But on the contrary they will say, you owe me so much money, what happened. That they cannot face.
And they commit suicide. But what is interesting in this act is that Aurum people chose a high place from which they jump down.
A sudden fall. A complete downfall. Crash. The market's crash.
Diseases are not apart from our society, in which we live and what we do with our lives.
And how an Aurum is developed, why he committed suicide, he never said anything to anybody. That is the usual story.
He never said. He looked quite all right. He had no problem. I mean yes he may have some financial problems but I'm sure he would get out of it.
Everybody else thinks he would get out very easily, he cannot face it unless you give him a high potency of Aurum.
Then suddenly we have seen it from one day to the other, the person will come back to his mind and will see the problem as it really is.
He says, oh I will work, I will do something. I will find a way. Where before taking the Aurum, he was ready to commit suicide.
In Aurum cases, in these cases you will see especially with people who have become Aurum without being constitutional Aurum.
They have become Aurum because of their grief, of their stress at this moment. Like you become Ignatia, most of you, especially the women when you lose your lover.
You are not constitutional Ignatias, you may lose your lover, 'ah!'. When you see 'ah!' and similar, take Ignatia.
And then 'he is fool, I don't care about him'. It's finished the problem, that means you are not constitutional Ignatias. Ignatia is imprinted upon the organism under stress.
Like if you get a cold, Bryonia picture is imprinted upon you. You are not constitutional Bryonia but you have an acute situation where you become Bryonia at this moment.
Where you become Dulcamara or Rhus tox, where you become an acute situation, Ignatia, you become Natrum muriaticum or Aurum.
This Aurum which has been imprinted because of financial problems can be lifted from one day to the other. And you can see miracle.
It's another person next day, beautiful. And a person who is also an Aurum person as we described it from young age, he is not going to be recovered so easily.
The Aurum will help him but still the seriousness, the conditions underlying will continue. The person who is not Aurum constitutionally but who needs Aurum at the moment of stress, will be another person all together.
Aurum invests his belief in high ideals.
Wealth, justice, prominence.
These are ideas of Aurum. Should he be disappointed by any of these ideals such as been treated unjustly by someone in positional authority for instance, he can become quickly disappointed and depressed.
This painful experience can motivate him to try to reform society. To reestablish order and justice in the world according to his own understanding, ability and influence.
Consequently we have two types of people that they will develop.
Out of this disappointment that they go through because they need justice and they are treated unjustly, they will say I want to make the world just.
Now there are two types of people that can develop from such a stress. Constitutional Aurum.
The one is a successful businessman in the society and the other, you know what it is?
An anarchist.
You know anarchist?
I'm going to reform society according to my understanding and standards. I'm going to show you justice.
The successful businessmen will work diligently towards prominence within the establishment.
He will attain considerable heights due to his capacity for constant work, as he is workaholic.
Aurum is a workaholic, he wants to work. It's a driving force to work. You see if you analyze all this, his balancing outlets
you see emotionally he is weak, he needs to be admired and therefore he puts all his energy into working, attain, prominent, more prominent.
'I will become prominent, I cannot love. What he says inside is, I cannot love'.
And that's why Aurum is not loved in the way that an Argentum nitricum is loved or Phosphorus is loved or a Pulsatilla is loved. It's completely for different reasons.
They love him because of his financial security they give, the responsibility, the sincerity, they are sincere, honest, responsible, they admire him.
The Phosphorus will be loved because of his emotions. He will always lend money 'can you give me some money, I don't have'. You don't get anything material from Phosphorus but you get a lot emotionally.
I will provide you with lots of affection and lots of love and now you give me some money so I can exist also. You see the ideas? These are real things which are happening.
What I'm trying, I'm aiming at is to establish in your memory the type of person who will need Aurum and be able to recognize it in time, don't let it go through a long time. Because they will not talk.
You may have your child or your father, your mother, in the family. You may have cases of that type around you and you don't recognize them.
Wait a moment, now this person is Aurum, he is so serious, so ambitious, so working. Maybe you inquire about the stresses he went through and you find out.
Yes I don't want to live. This world is no good for me. This world is no good, not for me. They believe that the world is bad and unjust.