And now we are going on the physical level to see on a different system what Aurum can produce.
What situations we can face on physical level. We've been talking about mostly emotional and mental level so far.
Now we're going to see what Aurum is producing on a physical level.
The first thing that we know about Aurum is that pains in general bring on such despair that patients want to commit suicide, under the pain.
Again the same thing. There are terrible headaches, severe arthritic pains, colic pains in  the abdomen.
All these pains will lead the person to commit suicide. As we have said, pains drive the person to destruction, to commit suicide.
The pains are deep, boring type which are aggravated in the night. In the night they become much worse.
It's very interesting that we know Aurum is a syphilitic remedy and we know the syphilitic pains which come in the night, aggravated in the night.
But the whole structure and pathology of Aurum is perhaps an expression of the Syphilis that was injected and eventually suppressed in the human body.
We have today so many cases of syphilitic aberrations of the type of Aurum.
If you do practice for a long time and you practice in this way, you will see Aurum appearing quite frequently.
As you treat somebody during the treatment, when the syphilitic layer is coming up, you will many times see Aurum coming in the life of the person.
I have seen it quite frequently, I cannot quote exactly percentages but I would say 10% or even more of your cases will need one time or another.
During their treatment they will need Aurum. It is the syphilitic miasm which is coming eventually. It might be the first or second or third or fourth remedy but it's going to be quite frequently.
So syphilitic pains are aggravated during night obliging the patient to get up and walk.
Kent describes the reactions of Aurum to weather and I would like to quote from him. He says, there is one grand feature running through the Aurum state.
It is the manner in which he is affected by temperature and by the weather. Here are some symptoms that relate to the whole man which must be examined in this connection.
Desire for open air. This patient resembles Pulsatilla. Just to temperature but Aurum is not mild, gentle and yielding.
He is obstinate, irascible, the very opposite of the Pulsatilla patient.
I would have to say here of course we cannot confuse a Pulsatilla case with an Aurum case.
But when it comes to the imbecility state, when the pathology has progressed so much, we may see the same kind of silent brooding that we see in Pulsatilla.
Pulsatilla can have such an effect on a person that he goes into a state of total imbecility. He can't perceive, he can't talk, he can't eat, he cannot perform any function.
He just sits there for days after days and then you tell him to sit there, he sits there. You put some food in the mouth, Pulsatilla she will eat.
When Aurum reaches that state he may look some kind of similar but before that state he is completely a different person all together.
And the history of Pulsatilla and the history of Aurum are completely different histories, when you take down the history.
In connection with headaches, local, cold water ameliorates pain in the eyes. While the general situation is like Pulsatilla, that wants cool air, cold application ameliorates the headaches or the eye pains.
Averse to uncover, he doesn't want to uncover but desires open air.
And many symptoms of Aurum may disappear after cold washing. Therefore we have a general amelioration from cool bathing.
Another amelioration we have is from  music.
Music ameliorates the pains and the states on Aurum. What kind of music? They like classical music, serious music let us say.
We have another remedy which is ameliorated by music which is Tarentula. What kind of music? Rock and Roll, rhythmic strong music.
I've been described by a patient, he says I like music. How strong? He says so strong that the doors vibrate.
Therefore music ameliorates. It's not music ameliorates, it's something else behind the music. In Tarentula there is almost a physical amelioration from the vibration of sound.
It's something which brings about a circulation, maybe regulates the circulation of I don't know.
In Aurum it is a sad music, it is like Homeopathy. It is a sad music playing inside and a sad music playing outside and that ameliorates the sadness, the headaches, the pains.
That's why we have amelioration from music. One of the two remedies, you will see it in Repertory, the two capital remedies Tarentula and Aurum.
Also amelioration from walking in the open air. You will see another amelioration which appeals to the romantic nature, sensitive nature of Aurum, which is amelioration in the moonlight.
Music, moonlight, walking in the open air, soft music, you have to understand that every remedy has a logic.
It's not just symptoms thrown there. There is a logic behind. We cannot many times understand this logic behind the symptomatology. We may not be able to perceive it but we try.
Walking in the open air and better in the evening. The time that the sun goes down until darkness, that time there is a soothing inside the Aurum depression.
The depression is so heavy and by the time the sun goes down, as soon as darkness comes, the darkness which is inside, the contrast with the darkness outside it seems to ameliorate. It has more energy, less sadness, less depression.
It affects the lymphatic and glandular system by producing congestions, indurations and tumors in these glands.
We find lumps in the mammary glands. The ovaries and the testes are affected.
And it affects the heart because the heart is the symbolic organ for the emotions. Now the emotions have been suffering, eventually they will be localized in the heart and we have all kinds of heart affections and problems.
You see you have the impression that I bring another Materia Medica, it is not. It's the information which is there, which was there, which I saw in the patients and put it together.
That's all. It's not another Materia Medica.
Also it has rheumatic affections with swelling of joints, quite strong.
Many times these rheumatic affections, joint affections end up in heart problems.
We have angina pectoris, enlargement of the heart, problems with valves.
And we have thickening and induration of the periosteum.
In the head we have a specific kind of headache. It is located in a small area. The size of a coin. And mostly on the left base.
And of course we have trigeminal neuralgias.
The headaches are so strong that many times we have this impulse to commit suicide during the headaches, especially in this type of headache.
With one point, it's a point that you touch it with your thumb, like that and the pain is so severe that drives him to commit suicide.
Also don't forget that you may get alternating states of headaches  with depression. This kind of headaches, severe headaches for a period of time, 6 months, 1 year, 3 years headaches.
And then suddenly the headaches leave and the depression appears and the depression is deep and heavy. Then the headaches reappear and the depression goes on the background and on the front is the terrible headaches.
The head feels as if it is bruised.
Many times they have to cover the place of the headache, otherwise they feel air is going through the head. Painful air is going through the head.
Occipital headaches which are connected with cases of heart problems. During the headaches there are flushes of heat to the head, making the face red and shiny.
We also have loss of hair. Scalp, very sensitive to touch. Exostosis on the scalp and also boils of the scalp.
Vertigo on stooping and tendency to fall to the left. Vertigo which has to lie down in order to relieve it.
Worse motion and this vertigo many times is associated with sparks in the eyes.
In the eyes we have ulcerations and infiltrations of the various courtings of the eye.
Inflammation of the conjunctiva with burning heat and lacrimation which is ameliorated, this is keynote, in the moonlight.
Photophobia.
Kent made a very important remark while
he was lecturing on Aurum to his students.
He said, I'm going to read to you now from the eye. I'm going now to read to you from the books, he says, on the eye but remember the constitution that we must always have in view .
I'm trying to give you in the Materia Medica, what is peculiar to Aurum, as much as possible.
What I'm reading you is not peculiar only to Aurum. We had to have that constitution as well.
Otherwise it's difficult to differentiate because Argentum Nitricum has ulcerations of the conjunctiva, of the cornea, Medorrhinum has it. It's not only Aurum which has it.
Deep internal diseases of the eyes like iritis. Chorioretinitis and glaucoma.
With pain from inside outwards, worse when there is pressure. When you touch it.
And better in closing the eyes.
Double vision. One object seems to be mixed with another. Object seems jumbled up, cannot distinguish them, black spots, sparks, flames etc.
The upper half of the vision is lost. And this condition is found mostly in detachment of the retina. Protrusion of eyes, as we find in exophthalmus. With enlargement of the heart.
I will read you a small piece from Kent just to show you, the pictures that they used to see by his time and how these pictures have changed to much more what I describe as a mental-emotional picture.
We're not going to see these pictures. Kent says, the bones of the nose necrose. Syphilitic necrosis. The nose flattens down.
The bones are discharged. You see these people walking about with flattened down nose and if you get near enough to them, the stench will be observed.
They are nearly all syphilitics. A few remedies have the power of curing this syphilitic condition.
You see this description we will not find today. But it is interesting we don't see it but we see the alcoholism, the perversion, all the picture that I have been discussing.
Sour, bitter taste in mouth is a keynote. Syphilitic ulcers in the mouth esp. on palate.
We see in Aurum children, when the sexual instinct has just been aroused, at puberty and the hormonal system changes, the children may experience and complain for violent palpitations.
Flushes of heat which are followed by perspiration and palpitations.
Palpitations with great anxiety, almost agony and fear that I have a serious heart disease. Aurum is one of the remedies that has fear of heart disease.
When the disease is affecting Aurum on a physical level, we may not have so much the suicidal depression but we get the physical pains, the physical symptoms, the palpitations, the flushing of heat etc.
At the same time a fear that I have a severe heart disease.
Rheumatic pains end up in the heart, severe dyspnea with the involvement of the heart, endocarditis, with high fever and aversion to be even touched in the chest.
With endocarditis we have that peculiarity that the person, if you  go to examine even and put the stethoscope, he will not want to be touched.
He feels this is a big pressure, if you put it he feels it as a great pressure.
Many times the depression of Aurum, as we said, it's so strong and he does not talk at all. But in the night during sleep, he is sobbing.
-Only the children?
-No, the grown ups, everybody.
It is like the psyche is crying. When the logical mind leaves, cannot control anymore, the psyche is sobbing, is crying deeply.
We have dyspnea, worse laughing and worse at night and from warm air. Cannot lie down because of his dyspnea.
Now sexually how he behaves?
Sexually the Aurum patient is very active and passionate.
As he finds sex  an outlet to his emotional difficulties and inability of expression.
But as he has been hurt once, it's only the pleasure of physical contact with no emotional attachment and pleasure whatsoever.
He detaches himself emotionally and he enjoys physical sex. He is very passionate in physical sex but once the physical sex has ended, has finished, there is no connection.
The person is some stranger but he can be again very easily excited and quite passionate. The moment the orgasm comes he does not want to see the person, there is no connection, there is no feelings.
So the lack of emotional investment in his relationships, can lead him to have multiple contacts, without any really deep investment or satisfaction.
These people they seem to need frequent sexual contacts to balance their depression.
This situation eventually will deepen his depression. Because such contacts are not satisfying, they're just superficial and he needs this excitement
he goes for that but when the whole set is finished, then he is back to his depression and even worse.
Because he realizes again and again that there is no possibility of a deeper connection, of a deeper feeling of exchange, of love and affection.
Another characteristic is that in case where the sexual partner lets them down first, they are so devastated that they are ready to go
to extremes of depression and even suicide in spite of the fact that they have no real attachment to the other person.
He says, 'I didn't like her'. Then why so much reaction? It is the egotism who has been hurt. The egotistical element of Aurum that has been hurt.
And also women are very sensitive beings and they understand where a man is hurt and they can hurt.
The expressions that they will use is, 'this man is too serious, I can't stand him anymore'. The woman says, 'bye, bye I'm leaving'.
The Aurum is not attached to that woman. He could say, talking to his friends, 'I could leave her anytime'. The moment that the woman says to him that this relationship is finished, then he is devastated, he goes straight to suicide.
But why suicide? You were saying you did not care about that woman, he does not understand himself. It is the hurt egoism which is behind.
It's not that he cares about that person and therefore he will commit suicide now which is again another thing with Natrum sulphuricum or Natrum muriaticum.
They may have such tendency. They care about the others, they have feelings. He does not have feelings.
In another occasion you may meet a married man who is disappointed from his work, Aurum case.
And he is progressing towards a depression who cannot be aroused anymore by his wife.
And he seeks excitement outside of his marriage where he behaves very passionately sexually.
Eventually as there is no deeper involvement, he is less and less aroused by this affair outside.
What is going to happen? He will let this affair go away and he will search for another affair.
And in time he will have the desire to have sex but not the capacity, he will become impotent.
That is how we have impotency in Aurum. Impotency in Aurum does not come just like that. It's a process.
Why Aurum is so sexually excited easily and then it becomes impotent, this is the process. No internal connection, physical contact, a lot of excitement
then another affair, then again another affair, he finds himself impotent.
Sometimes Aurum patients will resort to masturbation in order to relieve the pressure.
But the sense that they are doing something wrong, complicates matters and eventually makes the depression worse.
You see in order to get out of the depression, they go to masturbation. Masturbation for them is not right.
Again the right ideas, the right things. This makes the depression eventually worse.
We have masturbation in young men who are very shy, introvert and they have inferiority complexes towards women.
Such young men they may not even consider the possibility of a relationship.
The possibility of real human contact is completely remote. You understand how they feel? How isolated they feel inside these young men?
-Are Aurum women?
-Much more men than women. I don't know why but much more men. I've seen similar things with women but definitely with much more men.
We must be aware that the sexual behavior, the sexual contacts of the human beings are many times determined by their pathology.
And that is why it is very difficult to change and even moral people may behave very immorally.
And that is why also, that we that understand the pathology in this way, it is better not to criticize what we see.
Many times we criticize without understanding a problem. And we pass judgment and criticism and we say all kinds of things.
As homeopaths, understanding the human nature in the way that we should and pathology in the way we should understand it, we should be able to comprehend why a person behaves this way or another way.
Especially in matters of that intimacy which is the sexual matters.
And not pass judgment, being critical about such contacts. It's better if we are able to do something about it and correct such behavior than criticism which has no meaning.
Why men more than women? Most probably because men were much more influenced by Syphilis than women.
We have nightly  emission, we have young boys whose testes have not descended.
And who of course portray the Aurum characteristics.
Atrophy of the testicles and in these cases we'll find individuals with a kind of hypochondriasis.
Isolated, looking upon little things and magnifying them.
Enlargement of the right testicle, induration is underlined very much. One of the main remedies for induration of the testes. Epididymitis, orchitis, balanitis and sarcosel.
In the female we have induration and ulceration of the uterus.
These indurations, these fibromas are much more prominent of course in Aurum muriaticum natronatum, as we said before.
The menses are late and scanty or they are completely absent in which case deep depression may appear.
The menses go less and less, the depression becomes more and more, there is no menses, big depression. This is a serious situation.
It's very interesting if we observe, for me it's something very fascinating.
We observe the emotions how they withdraw, they become hard and you see at the same time  the genitalia becoming hard, withdrawn, do not descend.
The organs through which we have contact, as I said before, which is the emotions and the genitalia also. These are the deepest contact, the two areas through which we establish contact with the others.
In Aurum they are both shrunk, not descended, hard, indurated. That's the idea of Aurum.
-Do I find that Aurum is associated with a group of people or countries?
-Well I would say that northern countries will have quite a lot of Aurum.
I would expect that England would have quite a lot. I would expect Sweden, Norway and Finland they will have quite a lot.
Now with a group of people I would say, not the basic people. You see it's very difficult to find an Aurum man who is a farmer.
Difficult to find but very easy to find a lawyer, an engineer, an educated person.
A person who works with his mind much more than others. The more educated class, the more sophisticated class.
But towards the North also is like that. People are mentalized, more living with their heads, not with their hearts.
And then you get the other pole. In Africa people live with their hearts, not with their heads, at all. It's only the Greeks who are in the middle.
It's a good question. Jf we have a constitutional Aurum, do we have to be careful in treating such case?
I'll give you an example. Let us say, somebody comes to be treated. You realize he's an Aurum case.
He confesses to you that he has a lot of suicidal impulses, not only suicidal impulses, he has attempted suicide.
He just doesn't want to live, he wants to commit suicide and he is definite about it.
In such a case it is best for the first few days after the treatment to either tell the family or the person with the family that they should take special care with this.
The more dangerous it is, the more you see he may commit suicide moment to moment, you just lock him in a room, after all.
You say, you lock yourself inside a room for 3 days and take the remedy. I mean you go to extremes but I think we had a case
the doctor is here who had such a case and we actually locked him inside the house. We said, you have to be locked for 3 days, stay inside the house, close the windows, close the doors and the family will know.
Not because I believe maybe the aggravation will go and then he will jump, I don't believe so much in that.
What I believe is that before Aurum acts, there is a time....you must not forget that a sick person has taken all around him, everybody into his sickness.
That means the manipulation by the person, the handling of the other persons around the sick person has taken a pattern.
Now you come into that pattern where there is a whole family, where the depressed man living there has certain pattern.
You come into the picture and you say, take this. Open your mouth, take this. What you're doing, you're breaking patterns, family patterns that they have been established through years.
How a change in that person may affect everybody around, what comments they may say, what things can happen?
So we try to prevent as much as possible having an accident, because it's a matter of an accident.
Maybe the Aurum is not acted yet and then the person goes and jump. He has tried 2 times and now this time succeeds.
Would you say to yourself, would you ask yourself whether that was because of the remedy you gave or not? Yes you will have a problem. Why you should have the problem?
And I have heard some other people saying, I had a case, it was a suicidal case, it was a Sulphur case, so I gave him Sulphur and next 3 days he committed suicide.
Now you hear that and you say, god a remedy can make him commit suicide. I am very skeptical about it because what I say is that this person was not Sulphur.
It was Natrum sulphuricum or Natrum muriaticum or Aurum and you gave Sulphur and he felt even this doctor cannot cure me and he jumps.
Why it is because of Sulphur? It is because you did not give the right remedy. So the idea is to prevent if something like that happens.
You go and see an Aurum case, it's a serious case. It's the type of person who really does it. Who can commit suicide. You have to take that into consideration. This is an Aurum case, he may do that anytime.
What time? Maybe the day after I gave him Aurum and then you have it in your conscience. It's better you lock him up.
-Does Aurum has compulsive thoughts?
-In a way we can say yes, he has compulsive thoughts but the thoughts are towards self-destruction.
I'm sure you all have people that you imagine they can be.
It's a very interesting question, the difference between a Causticum anarchist and an  Aurum anarchist. It's totally different.
Causticum we say it's the primary anarchist in the Materia Medica. We would like to differentiate between Aurum and Causticum.
Well, we'll do it. I'll take my last extra strength.
Causticum is full of feelings and he feels for the other person. The emotions also are very serious but the seriousness is intense.
He is always like that, very serious, what happened? This man hit him, he will jump and kill the man that hit the other person. He was a weak person. He is full of passion of sympathy.
Full of sympathetic feelings for those who are suffering, for those who are under pressure, under a regime who is suppressing them.
He is some person who is always looking for injustice. Everywhere he will see injustice, even if there is no injustice, he will see injustice.
Because he wants to see injustice, it is his nature. He says, I can't tolerate injustice and they have their own code of ethics, their own understanding of injustice.
For them it is injustice perhaps if you throw a stone to a dog and it's not injustice if you throw it to a man.
The idea is that he is going to find all the time injustice in animals, injustice in men, whatever is his particular, but the feelings are so strong.
He will go to anarchism because he cannot anymore tolerate the suppression of this government. The suppression of people.
How does it suppress? I saw it. But how did you see it?
I saw a man that he wanted to hold a red flag and somebody told him not to do it. He should be able to do it, he is suppressed.
They find a way to almost perceive everything as suppression. You see the intensity in the feelings.
Aurum is cool. Everything is inside. Injustice yes, this world is unjust, I will tell them, I must find a way to bring back justice.
It is a mentalized process, a playing with death to bring justice but in a completely different manner, completely different set up inside pathology.
Do you see the difference?
Causticum is one of the main remedies to be sympathetic. It says Phosphorus sympathetic. Phosphorus suffers very much for the others.
Will he ever become anarchist? No, why? Because he is soft inside, in his emotions. Causticum is intense.
And always there is an intensity in their eyes, in their look.
Phosphorus are very sympathetic especially if one is suffering really. Causticum does not have to suffer really. He may imagine that you are suffering and he goes against and he wants to take action.
Phosphorus will feel first that you're suffering, that you have the pain and then he will try to help.
He will think of something to help you at this moment, he will not think of breaking down the government because you are suffering.
He has a heart attack, yes because he is suppressed. He is so much suppressed by the government, he has a heart attack now.
But he does not do anything for his heart attack. He is sympathetic, but the anarchist, his mind will go further.
Of course we have the sympathetic element in which a person can cry. For instance in the hospital.
In another bed somebody is suffering, a Phosphorus case inside the room, they will leave, they cannot stand it.
Their imagination is exaggerating what they are feeling. They cannot tolerate that.
They can stay awake and sleep will not come, that's the sympathetic element towards the pain of others.
But Causticum progresses towards. It's a weak person, we have to help this person because it's suppressed. That is the anarchist.
So for tonight I think it's enough.