I just give you some small remedies to show you the idea of what we say, essentials.
What are the essentials of Ac-ac.?
Ac-ac. is vinegar. Do you know why they used vinegar in old times? I remember when I was young I was hearing
that women who were fat, they were advising each other to drink vinegar. 'Drink so much vinegar'.
They were some accidents of course from drinking vinegar and the accidents were that people lost weight
and they became anemic.
So Ac-ac., we see here that we have a few black things. It says severe gastritis, stomach as if full with vinegar.
This is an expression that you may hear with people who are skinny, who are pale, who are anemic
and have stomach problems. You can imagine, skinny, white, stomach problems and intense thirst.
There is one strong keynote which says impossible to lie on back.
As soon as they lie on back, they start having problems with their stomach, acidity, a sense of fullness, dysphoria.
So they have to turn immediately left or right.
It is one of the very few remedies that cannot lie at all on their back. So you have a gastritis, cannot lie on back, Ac-ac.
And you have this picture of white, pale, anemic individuals. It says anguish and anxiety, this is general symptom.
Anguish, anxiety, people who really look sour.
When the stomach is affected chronically, people get a particular psychology, which is a sour psychology.
You say, 'I don't feel well today, my stomach'. You do a particular grimace in your face.
This is the type of the person that you will see with Ac-ac.
In the gastritis we have emaciation of course, intense thirst for large quantity.
Intense thirst, you will confuse this with what remedy?
With Phos. first, not so much with Bry. but with Ars.. Because it will pale, skinny and anemic and anxiety, anguish.
There is another symptom that you will find in Ac-ac. You may have a high fever and then sweating and then
you wonder that they don't have any thirst. You see in chronic conditions the thirst is increased for large quantities.
In acute conditions, in fever there is sweating and no thirst, this is strange.
Worried about business affairs. What is another remedy who does this? Bry. and another one is Psor.
Calc-f also, very good.
Ambra not so much.
This is what you have to remember from Ac-ac.
Sour people, stomach problems, gastritis, intense thirst, anemia. Wasting, debility, weakness, so you have the picture.
This, you cannot say it is the essence of the remedy, it is some essential features of the remedy.
We don't have the full picture, mental-emotional picture of Ac-ac.
We have some essentials but these essentials should bring the mind to Ac-ac.
In All-c. you have to remember a few things.
Of course the one that everybody knows is that the nose is running watery acrid discharge, that makes red the nostrils.
The nostrils become red. There is lacrimation also. The lacrimation is not acrid; it's the opposite as the Euphrasia.
This everybody knows.
How do you recognize a chronic case of All-c.?
You will recognize by two things. One is a desire for onions. Excessive desire for onions.
And another thing which is not recorded in our books it is sleepiness, excessive sleepiness. Lethargy, lethargic.
And you will see in common colds towards the evening where the All-c. becomes worse, they become lethargic
they want to lie down and you just want to sleep. The head is full, the headache is there, the nose is running
the coughing starts and you are lethargic, especially in the evening time.
This sleepiness and this lethargy can lead up to the point where we have a mental case.
And a mental case that will look like Opium, sleeping all the time.
I remember a case, the mother said I gave him some money to go and buy something.
And from the house to the shop, he lied down and slept. I went there in the shop, he had the money
he couldn't remember what was to buy. He came back and he couldn't remember anything and when they brought the boy
the boy was sitting there with his mother and as the mother was talking, the boy was sleeping.
And a total indifference about the surrounding. Whether you are there or not it doesn't matter.
He takes out his penis and urinates, oblivious of the surrounding.
The mother said, we were on the train and he wanted to urinate, he urinated in the train in front of everybody.
I'm talking about a boy of 14 years old; it's not a small boy of 2 years old.
But this shows the tendency of the remedy on the indifference, on the non perception of the surroundings.
He is oblivious of the surroundings.
No signs of catarrh. Nothing. In these chronic cases you will not have.
One thing you have to remember that All-c. goes fast from the upper respiratory track down and starts
with pharyngitis, laryngitis and then bronchitis. And it can go very fast and in case that you are giving wrongly,
in a case of coryza you prescribe wrongly All-c., you will speed up the laryngitis or the pharyngitis and the coughing will start.
Also it is a remedy that you have to be careful in people who have sensitivity with their bronchial system.
That you don't give it easily because you will cause dyspnea. It will cause dyspnea very soon.
The cold goes down and people are sensitive and they start having dyspnea. That means the remedy was wrong.
Is pressed downwards, this is very important. Also All-c. is worse with heat, worse in the evening.
So you will confuse it with what remedy?
It's going to be confused with Pulsatilla because the moment the heat is there, the fever rises.
If you have a room which is very warm, the fever and the dysphoria arises; so they need to open quickly the window
to get fresh air and in the meantime they get fresh air, they are chilled. But heat makes them very much worse.
So therefore it looks like Pulsatilla. What is the difference?
The coryza with Pulsatilla is blunt. That means you will see no redness around this area.
With All-c. in 95% cases you will see redness around this area.
Which is another remedy which has this redness around this area in coryza?
Arsenicum. What is the difference? Ars. will need heat, All-c. will be worse from heat.
If you have a coryza that will start on the left side and go to the right side, the nose running on the left side
1 day, 2 days, then right side. Then this can be All-c.  What other remedy can be?
A remedy which is worse in heat and goes from left to right?
Lachesis.
Onions which is very strong, better in open air, hoarseness.
It's painful hoarseness. You do like this and you feel as if the throat is split.
All these remedies that we have talked, we have talked on the essential features.
We did not talk about the essence of the remedy, a little bit on All-c., a little bit we talked about it.
- I had a case of lumbago and I gave Bry. and this person had a sensitivity in the lungs. She had chronic asthma but not often.
And she got a severe asthmatic condition after Bry. for lumbago. Did you ever observe this for Bryonia?
- Most probably during the time of the lumbago he must have had some respiratory infection and the infection
went down, most probably.
-She did not have.
-Well it's very strange.
Most probably she had but she had no apparent symptoms because since she was sensitive in her lungs
I believe that Bry. was suppressing in this caseand brought the respiration down. How long it lasted?
-It was very severe, it lasted for several hours and was not functioning. She had to get cortisone.
-This is the same with All-c., in case there is an inflammation here and you give All-c. you may have this problem.
I cannot explain this if you take it as a proving...
-What's the pathology this sleepiness about All-c. is something very new that the texts don't say it.
I have a case of a 42 years old man who has chronic sinusitis for 20 years.
He has a sleepiness to the extent that I have to go out to the waiting room, call him that your appointment is here
and come into the chamber. He even sleeps if you have a little pause while you are talking to him. I gave him Opium
because his airways are so full of enlarged mucus back here and in the nose also.  Where is the pathology in All-c.
I understand about Op. but how does All-c. gets to this state of sleepiness? Is it the sleep apnea as we explained in Op.?
-I don't know. What I know is that if you eat a lot of onions in the night and you have sleeplessness, you are going to sleep.
Garlic and onions, especially onions will make you sleep.
Actually it relaxes most probably the vascular system because both onions and garlic bring down the blood pressure.
And because of that relaxation, the stimulation which is there on the brain, becomes less most probably.
I don't know the physiology, it's very difficult.
In this case you can try because it is exactly the case that we are talking, the sinuses are affected
and this tremendous sleeplessness. Try high potency 1M, 10M and write back to me.
We know a little bit more about Ambra grisea.
It's very interesting I talk sometimes as if the remedy is female and some other times as if it is male.
Which means actually in practice more times it's prescribed for females than males.
Sulphur is prescribed more for males, Lycopodium for males.
Anyhow the Ambra is more a female remedy. It's a remedy which has a very strange psychology.
She is very timid, very inhibited.
How do we know that? Because she feels that the natural functions of having stool or having urination
for her it is something which is very secret and she cannot relax if she knows that somebody is next door
and is hearing what is doing in the toilet. This is very characteristic and goes to extreme.
What you will get initially, you will get a very nice lady who will be very nice, very talkative.
She will respond to your questions quite easily and she will admit that she is very very timid.
But the timidity is especially concerning the action of defecation and urination.
The mind becomes weak and does not follow a conversation. When you are in company, you discuss with somebody
you hear what he says, you respond, things like that. When Ambr. is in company, cannot respond.
Either she will keep quiet, totally quite not understanding what's going on in the conversation
or she will keep on asking questions, irrelevant questions.
In a conversation you hear and then you respond.
Ambr. gets so excited, she talks and asks again and again and you say, what is she doing?
It is a beginning state of Alzheimer's. It is a beginning state of arteriosclerosis.
In sexuality also she is inhibited; she cannot relax and enjoy the sexual act.
They have to have a lot, to go on with long relationship before they can relax and can feel at ease.
It's a dreamy state of mind and forgetfulness. She asks questions, not waiting for answers, jumping
from one subject to another. You see these are expressions that you cannot otherwise say.
In the Repertory you have to give an expression but you have to understand the psychology.
A weak mind, does not understand what is going on, gets excited very much. At the same time being inhibited
and timid and how this person will behave. They will say nonsense. They will ask questions which are not relevant.
Loss of confidence. But you understand now the difference between loss of confidence in Ambr. and loss of confidence
in Bar-c. of loss of confidence for Anac.
Disgust in seeing others laughing. These are expressions of a prover, actually what happens is that she is not in communication.
Difficult to communicate, to be in touch. So if you are not in touch and somebody is laughing and I don't know why
he is laughing, then I'm disturbed. This is the idea. You got the idea?
Prematurely old. Why prematurely old? Because all this behavior is not the behavior of a person of 50, 60 years old.
It's the behavior of somebody who is losing the power of the mind.
Easily embarrassed of course and it says symptoms are aggravated in the presence of others.
This is not in general but mostly the presence of others is concerning functions of sex and urinary and functions of defecation.
Tries to please everyone, cannot say no. This is a symptom, have we spoken about Cancerinum? No.
You see Carc. has that also and this remedy has the same thing.
But this comes from the weakness of the will and weakness of the mind. In Cancerinum comes from other reasons.
- Compare Lach. and Ambr. on jumping from one subject to another. Lach. would be, you ask the question
and then next half an hour, an hour you are free. In Ambra that would be just confused answer?
- In Lach. you have somebody who jumps from one subject to the other. But in Lach. is a kind of loquacity.
That means she cannot stop. Now this lady gets excited in a certain moment, in a company, you go out and she listens
she gets excited and she puts some irrelevant questions to you.
Did you have tea? Oh yes, you had tea. And she answers herself. It is a state where she does not know what she is doing.
Lach. is totally different. She will start telling story. You say, 'what is your problem?' and she says
'shall I tell you the whole story?'. If you say yes, you had it.
She will stop by the end of the interview, one hour. Your time is over, she will stop.
But not saying exactly to the point where you asked, but bringing into the picture any associate pictures
that come to her mind.
This is different. You have to enter the psychology of the person. The weakness of the mind, you have to feel the remedy.
To be able to differentiate between one and the other. Otherwise flat symptoms will point out to something similar.
Eventually all the remedies will look similar. One remedy is all the symptoms, the other remedy has the same symptoms.
The other remedy has all the other.
Especially with some teachers adding information and information will make all the remedies look alike.
There is nothing in one remedy that separates from another.
Here what we need is to find the individuality. If I want to describe her, him, I have to give characteristics.
I cannot say they have two eyes, one nose etc. Everybody has two eyes, unless somebody is blind, you say one eye.
But you have to give the characteristics; so you look to this person you have to find the characteristics.
What are her characteristics? You look at him, you say the characteristics, the shape of the face, shaved, tall.
She, with different hair and glasses. You give two characteristics. And you go to the class and say
somebody with reddish hair and some glasses and intense look.
This is the idea with Homeopathy.
This is what I try, to pass the information to you so you can differentiate the one individual pathology
from another individual pathology. This is the whole idea with Homeopathy. Why is not Cham.
why is not China and not Calc-p.? This is Ant-c. Why?
You know in the older times when I taught, students used to get mad.
But it does not have this! They look in the Repertory and the patient would have said, 'I have a pain in the big toe'
between other symptoms. Then I would say  OK this is Pulsatilla case because it's typical.
And somebody would get up, look in the Repertory, pain in the big toe, there is nothing.
No Pulsatilla has pain in the big toe. We had to get away from that strategy.
You may sometimes find all the symptoms, that is very good. But sometimes you have to go to essentials.
So this lady may come with kidney problems, with gallbladder problems with respiratory problems
with heart problems, it doesn't matter. You will not be able to come down to the remedy
unless you go to the essentials and you understand. You say, this is Ambra grisea.