I will talk about Ant-c.
Ant-c. cases are people that are very sensitive, very introverted and very sentimental.
Sentimentality actually as an excess here seals the Ant-c. patients.
The sentiments are very easily excited and the sentiments can become very powerful inside. It  can be over flowing.
This kind of sentimentality, the easy arousal of sentiments and the sensitivity on the other hand affects these individuals mostly on the area of the solar plexus.
And we know the impact of the emotions on the solar plexus and in consequence the stomach area.
So therefore Ant-c. cases are very sensitive in the area of the stomach and the stomach will be the first one to show the imbalance, wherever it might be.
We have to imagine these open, in the beginning, sentimental, sensitive patients that are under stress and the sentiments are becoming quite hurt. And the impact is taken on the stomach.
Under such stress they will withdraw and they will usually become sulky and will live with their imagination much more than the real contact with the real life.
It is for that reason that when they lie in bed in the night, the sentiments will arise and they will be a strong imaginative factor that will make them over excited.
Eventually this over excitement will lead to a state of anxiety. So anxiety in the night lying down.
It is also very peculiar that when there is something going on with their health and the area which is affected is the digestive system.
If they have digestive problems, they become over sentimental. If they have fever, they become over sentimental.
Also this sentimentality is apparent in women just before menses and of course is well known that Ant-c. is affected by moonlight.
It's the moon that represents a lot of the feelings that affects them so much, especially when they are in a sensitive state.
When something has happened in their life and they are very stressed and they will go for a walk and look at the moon and they will become almost ecstatic.
The sentimentality becomes so powerful during that time and it seems that it's connected with that mellow light that comes from the moon.
Because they find themselves in that state of over sentimentality also when the windows are with yellow colors and light comes through these windows, that is the environment where the Ant-c. patients become anxious and excited in their emotional state.
The sentimentality of Ant-c. is so great that many times will lead them to do things which are foolish.
Can you imagine the state where the emotions are beyond the control of the individual and lead them to do things which they look ridiculous.
Concerning Ant-c. children I have found out that they look very much like Cham. children.
They are very much aggressive, dissatisfied and complain. You will see the Ant-c. child will not be able to sleep the whole night. It will be up all the time and he will complain.
He does not know what is wrong with him and for instance the mother will say to calm the child, look at this car, it's a nice car. It's not a car.
He is not happy, he is not satisfied with anything. 'Let's go in this place where it's nice to your friend John. No! I don't want to go to John. Where do you want to go? I don't know'.
You go to the child and you try to calm the child, you want to talk to the child. You will see the reaction when you try either to touch them or to look at them, there is an immediate reaction.
The reaction is very very similar to Cham. and many times you will mistake for Cham., especially when you see the case superficially.
The Cham. state will come usually in dentition period where especially the young ones will bring the first teeth out.
The Ant-c. child can be 3,4,5 years old and still has the same reaction and you will think that he's teething . It is because something bothers him and he does not know what it is that bothers him.
I just remembered a case of Ant-c. when I first gave this lecture this summer in Alonissos, I have just prescribed for a child that was in Alonissos, not in the group but connected with the group, I gave Cham., because of such behavior.
The child was not happy, was not satisfied, it was screaming, it had a little bit of fever and so I said OK give a dose of Cham. 30. Nothing happened.
And as I was lecturing about the remedy I remembered the child and I said the child most probably is Ant-c.
The reason was that I have been with the parents, I have been having dinner with them and the child asked for cucumber all the time.
Cham. behavior in a child that has desire for cucumber is an Ant-c. child.
When I went out of the lecture the mother came, that same day, she said we're worrying about the child, for 4-5 days it has not slept, we have not slept  and we're here on holidays.
They were coming from England in Alonissos and his father says that unless something is done for the child, we're returning tomorrow to England. The holiday was spoiled.
That kind of aggression. It's very difficult to find words. I refer to Cham. children because most of you must have seen some Cham. children.
And most of you, you will have missed like me and give Cham. instead of Ant-c.
So the child got at 10 o'clock a dose of Ant-c. 200, and by 10.30 he was asleep, in the morning and he slept and after that everything went OK.
Some of you, you must remember this case.
There is also an element which is running through Ant-c. and it's a warm element which is within Ant-c.
Anything warm makes the Ant-c. worse. Whether it is something warm they drink or outside warmth or fever makes them feel worse or alcohol.
Whatever raises the temperature and it seems that they have no tolerance in raising of their temperature especially if they found themselves in front of an open fire. Then everything that they may have, is aggravated.
Here again we have an exception where the headaches sometimes are aggravated by cold bathing. Cold water in the head may aggravate the headache.
Then they have great prostration, weakness. The weakness is quite strong and similar to Stannum.
There again in Ant-c. we find the loathing of life, we find the desire not to live, it's not a suicidal disposition, it's a desire not to live anymore because of the prostration.
There is prostration but no restlessness. In spite of the heat, there is thirstlessness. There is no excessive thirst as one may have expected.
Sometimes they have suicidal thoughts and this is worse in the night, in bed. You will see the aggravation in the night, in bed where the anxiety rises
the sentiments are very strong and by that time some Ant-c. will think of committing suicide and the method by which they will contemplate to commit suicide is by shooting themselves. And of course especially in disappointed love.
Ant-c. you can understand because of the sentimentality they will get attached in a love affair. They will get attached to the other person very much.
Due to that attachment they become vulnerable. The sentiments are very strong. They are attached.
The other person says, it's finished. They can't take it and that is the time usually where they seek to shoot themselves.
Actually ailments from grief, in that respect Ant-c. should be much higher. I don't remember in the Repertory how it is but if I remember well,  it's not very strong.
They develop, as we said, anxiety in the night and after midnight as well and an anxiety about their future.
They get easily discouraged, they are persons that cannot take very much the stresses of life, easily discouraged.
Fear of death sometimes, not strong but they become fearful from sudden noises.
Irritability, as we said, in the children especially and during headache the irritability of Ant-c. is very strong during headaches.
They don't like to be looked, do you know why? Can you imagine?
Because there is irritability and there is great sensitivity and the emotions are very strong and looking usually to each other it's not with great sympathy.
And it's an indifference and they feel very vulnerable to this kind of looking. It's like as if somebody is bare, open and somebody else is looking inside him and they don't like it. And they will withdraw.
The same idea with touching the Ant-c. It's not that they feel painful if they are touched, they don't like to be touched. It is a kind of sentimental rawness.
Like Causticum feels like raw, like the skin is not there and the pain feels as if the skin is not there. Ant-c. feel as if the protection of the emotions is gone
and they cannot bear the touch of another person. That's why we have aversion to be touched, aversion to be looked.
And when the child is in an Ant-c. state, that is why it becomes very irritable. And you will see the child behaving exactly like Cham., wanting the mother all the time to hold him.
The child will not play naturally with the other children, will go to the mother. At the time it comes to the Ant-c. state looks very much to the protection of the mother. And it will stay there.
I try to show you the vulnerability and the sensitivity of the remedy.
In that respect it is that Ant-c. does not like socializing very much.
The socialization with Ant-c. is something that sometimes they can take it but they don't like it.
That's why in the books you will see 'misanthropy'. Do you know misanthropy? It means that they dislike other people. It's not that they dislike, it is that state of vulnerability.
And when they are in that state, they become very sulky, very withdrawn.
Can you imagine a very sentimental person, very withdrawn? Why? Because he is vulnerable and he does not want to be hurt again.
How he can be hurt? By coming into contact. He does not want any contact and he becomes withdrawn.
And that person he goes out in the night, walks along the side of the beach, looks at the moon and the emotions are freed, he is alone, he is there with the moon.
The light produces a kind of stimulation in the emotions. We don't know how? We don't know what happens actually, how can you find the pathology but that is really happening.
The moon is there and the emotions are over flowing and they can be writing poems and they can be very sentimental. And they can be crying.
When they are just broken in a love affair, the worse time is when they go to bed and they start thinking and the emotions are coming, they are alone there.
Then they see no outlet. The impulse to kill themselves is so strong that they have to get up and walk up and down before they take these thoughts out and then they can go back and sleep.
In the text it says, 'makes verses'. But you understand the context under which this may happen. It doesn't mean that every Ant-c. is a poet.
It is the inclination there, it is the sentimentality, the state that you're looking for.