You read the information, then what type of the person you get that Ant-c. is?
It says, aversion to be looked and to be touched. Romantic and sentimental, especially in moonlight.
Emotionally immature, ailments from disappointed love, introvert, emotionally unbalanced, solar plexus
stomach or entire digestive tract is affected by emotion. Children irritable, dissatisfied, complaining, peevish.
It's what we call an emotional remedy. A remedy that is guided by the emotions, it's driven by the emotions.
The child becomes very emotional and what is the seat of emotions?
It is considered to be the solar plexus.
So the solar plexus in this remedy is very much affected and the area of the stomach is very much affected.
So you get an individual who is getting all the time, with every emotion, pain in the stomach or pain in the area of the stomach.
A cramping pain on the solar plexus then that will bring you the idea of the Ant-c.
Examine this person and find out whether this is an intellectual person or a person with emotions.
You find out it's a person with emotions. Likes and dislikes. 'I don't like him. Don't look at me'.
You see the children they are acting very much like the child you saw, the Calc-p., very similar.
With the difference that will not be peaceful even with his mother or his father or his brother and he will react
emotionally to what he wants. He wants this and he will not stop screaming and moaning.
And the mother gets desperate, I want to kill him. He says, give me this, give me that.
There is a little bit more aggression than you saw there, more aggression and more feelings.
Not so much this restlessness as you saw in this child.
It says the child... aversion to be looked or to be touched which is closer to which remedy?
Chamomilla! Cham. and Ant-c. are very similar.
You did not know that? Now you know.
In children that are suffering with digestive problems.
And they are moaning and groaning and they do not know what they want, the remedy is not Cham., it's Ant-c.
In children where the teeth are the problem and the child is acting this way, then the remedy is Cham.
Cham. acts during the time of dentition. This does not act on the time of dentition.
Ant-c. is a person who can express a lot of love, a lot of emotions, a lot of affection. They can express when they want to.
That means when there is some object for their adoration.
They can express when they fall in love and they fall in love especially in women we see it.
Many times the idea of falling in love without needing very much the physical contact.
It's a romantic idea which can be expressed through that remedy. These people are romantic.
They like the nature, they take a walk in the nature and especially if there is moonlight, fullmoon
then the emotions are becoming very overwhelming. And they really express their emotionality in such an environment.
So you get the idea of the romantic element, the problems with the stomach, you get headaches which are
aggravated in the heat of the fire. Ant-c. is generally aggravated by heat but heat of fire is much worse.
Ant-c. people will say, 'I cannot sit by the fire'. You know fire places you have in your countries because most of you
come from cold countries, you have fire places.
Ant-c. will never sit next to the fire. Immediately they will feel unwell.
Also there is a possibility of alternation between stomach problems and head problems.
Headaches alternating with stomach problems. In Platina we said what?
Mental conditions alternate with sexual hyperactivity.
You see the essentials? These are essentials.
You get a patient and tells you that I suffer with headaches, when the headaches go away, I get stomach problems.
One of the main remedies - there is another remedy also which has that, Nat-c. - main remedies
Nat-c, Ant-c.. Immediately it comes to mind.
You get alternating states on the mental level. Platina is one of the possibilities. Alternating states on mental level.
Anger is transferred into laughing. Laughing is transferred into weeping and vice versa, these hysterical reactions.
You stop and you say, well I know your remedy.
-I wish to ask you if this alternation is not characteristic symptom for Ant-c. because I saw also on other levels
on many levels, many alternations and I wish to ask you about your experience.
-No wait. There are alternating remedies, there are different remedies.
In this remedy the alternation is between stomach problems and headaches. That is what alternates.
There is a great keynote which shows the digestive dysfunction and that is what?
It's a tongue which is totally white.
Not only white, it's like snow, as if snow has fallen on the tongue.
How you see the snow when it first falls and leaves a little bit underneath. Mostly is white but not glistening white, not like this white.
This is glistening white. The tongue of Ant-c. is like cotton, they say cotton. You understand this idea?
You see the tongue and it's not something compact. Very white, not compact, like snow.
Once you see it once, you never forget and if you suspect Ant-c., you say put your tongue out.
These are little secrets. Maybe the others take the case, case, case, symptoms, symptoms, symptoms
and you say open your mouth to see your tongue.
The other one takes, takes, takes, 1 hour, 2 hours and he says, Sulphur. OK nothing. Give Ant-c.
It's like this. Homeopathy is like this. You don't have to analyze the character, project about the character, no.
What you are interested in is to get the characteristics. You got the characteristics, forget about his sexual life.
All this is interesting.
Why is interesting? Because each one wants to know what the other is doing, that's why it's interesting.
And if you go on this way, you will not learn but if you say let me see, Ant-c. acts this way.
Then you are learning but if you are curious, you are not going to learn. Curiosity is not good.
Curiosity is only to understand the remedy.
And don't jump into conclusions. Because each one has his own personality, character etc, and does not belong to the remedy.
It belongs to the personality.
I never had a problem though I always had somebody next to me. Now when I take a case I have hundreds next to me
but in the beginning I always had at least one person sitting next to me. And almost very, very seldom had any problem
asking any question and the patient feel uncomfortable answering.
Why? Because I was not asking out of curiosity. I was asking out of need to learn and the patient would understand
immediately that and would give you all the information you need.
In spite the fact that somebody sitting there, not talking, who is this person, what is he doing?
And when there in tete-a-tete, one to one people are difficult to talk. But if they see you are really interested in their health
and not in their personal life, because if you are interested in the personal life then you start hearing stories and stories
which are irrelevant to the case. What you want to know is, there is a element in this case that can give me a new information?
Worse heat, in open fire.
Desire for cucumbers also is a keynote.
I treated a case of pneumonia in the hospital in Athens, in children's hospital where has been given antibiotics
and the child was in a terrible state. Lying almost breathless and with high fever and the parents asked me
to go to the hospital and treat it. I said, 'what he wants to eat?'
They say, 'only cucumber'.
Now there was a TV session and the father came in the TV and said, 'I will tell you my experience. I had my boy
he was dying in the children's hospital, in that department and Vithoulkas came, gave him something
and next day we took the boy and we went out'.
Because of cucumbers, it's unbelievable but it is like this.
Digestive problems of course. All kinds of digestive problems which mainly effect the digestion
affect the stomach, the solar plexus but also the rest of the digestive tract. From the beginning to the end.
No, sour cucumber. Cucumber. Fresh cucumbers.
Sour they don't like. It makes them feel worse, especially wine which is a little bit sour, forget it.
It can bring headaches, pains in the stomach, all kind of problems.
Just remember that and if it happens and you just ask to see the tongue.
If you know the remedy, immediately you go and ask certain key questions. You get the feedback.
Actually this was the complication of a chicken pox, if I remember well. Pneumonia after chicken pox or something like that.
And the child was really dying in the hospital, under allopathic treatment.
The keynote for Berb., this thing that will put you the idea is the radiating pains.
The pain starts on one point and goes different directions.
Where you will find these pains usually? In what conditions?
Conditions mostly of stones, kidney or gallbladder stones. Especially kidney stones produce this type of radiation.
So therefore the constitution of Berb. is a constitution that produces stones. Usually such constitutions
are people who hold in. They keep inside, they hold inside the emotions.
These people may want to communicate but they never communicate on a deeper level, on their real emotions.
And it seems something is cramping and is holding back the elimination.
And therefore the kidneys especially, they become full of stones.
In Berberis also you have people suffering with arthritis where the different joints are suffering in different times.
You get some pains on the left shoulder joint and then after this is going away then there is the knee, then there is the hip joint.
Then there is the elbow joint. Then there are the  wrists and the joints are suffering in continuation or in rotation.
So we call these, wandering pains. These pains are characteristics also of Puls.
and Formica rufa, very good.
They can come back to the place where they started and then again they go away. They don't stay in one place.
So either they move around or they radiate, the pain radiates. In case of a lumbago where the lumbar region is affected
then you may see the pain radiates all over the abdomen. From the back it radiates around the abdomen.
Usually these people do not have enough stamina but they are not also very tired. It is an organism
who looks tired but it is not the tiredness that we see in other remedies like Stann., like Ph-ac., Mur-ac. and all that.
We also have another keynote; solitude is unbearable.
I mean not having a communication and having to live with themselves, they are not doing well. They are people of action.
Not of meditation.
You have pains which are like the pains of Eup-per. Because they feel the muscles as if they are beaten.
Which is very characteristic. When in a case of influenza, all the muscles feel beaten, 'my whole body feels as if I'm beaten'
the first remedy that comes to mind
is not Rhus-t., it's Eup-per.
So this remedy has rheumatic pains on the muscles and arthritic pains and the limbs feel as if beaten.
Urethra it says burns when not urinating, better after urination. These are mechanical things which happen.
Because this remedy produces a lot of stones. So if a stone is there and it is stuck and by urination it goes away
the pain is relieved. That symptom just confirms the idea that this remedy is producing a lot of stones
and maybe small stones which are going out frequently.
Also, I don't see it here, the remedy is aggravated by motion like Bry. Motion aggravates the pains.
- I want to ask something about Berb.
If there is a case with kidney colic and the patient has aggravation
through moving, we give Berb. And then perhaps if he is a little bit better but his condition changes
and he gets better from moving, then what should we decide?
-Most probably the remedy was wrong and now you need Rhus-t. But it is hypothetical.
And hypothetical is difficult because you can add or subtract essential things from a case.
And once you subtract something essential, then it makes no sense.
So it's better we speak on real cases.
-Would it be a contraindication if there is a kidney colic and the patient is better from moving to give Berb.?
-Better from moving? If at the same time the pain is radiating, really radiating, you can give it.
Borx. will affect mostly the upper part of the digestive tract causing aphthae, very painful aphthae.
In order to confirm that this is a case of Borx., you have to have fear of downward motion.
Even going with the lift which goes down slowly, they have an anxiety.
Going in a car, sometimes the car goes up and then goes down, it's like the soul comes out. They are frightened by this motion.
You put the child down, when you have the child and you put it a little bit down, like this...
and then you put it slowly down, the child is OK.
He has diarrhea, give Borx. It has inflammation in the eyes, it doesn't matter, Borx.
We have the sensation of cobweb on hands and face. They feel there is some cobweb and all the time they will do like this.
Trying to get it out.
Also we have leucorrhea which is very profuse, it's watery and the feeling that is running out. It's very thin.
Something which is like Phos., why? Because these people have sensitivity on sudden noises
and that's why they express fear during a thunderstorm. But mostly what they are bothered, is sudden noise.
When they study, when they are concentrated into something and there is some kind of noise, even not strong
it can jerk them. Coming back to their bodies.
Of course these are the children that can never go into a swing. Forget it. They will not even try.
There is an external trembling on sneezing which is a keynote that very very seldom you may find. But if you find it's a good keynote.
After sneezing, trembling.
I had a very difficult case of chronic cough where finally they told me, the cough is ending to a sneeze.
I said, Oh God for 3 years I have been given half of the Materia Medica without effect. For God shake why don't you say so?
Cough day and night, mostly in the day time but the coughing so strong and after eating. Finally she gave me this.
I don't know if this symptom developed after all these remedies I gave or it was from the beginning.
But when she told me, I said very good, the remedy is Agaricus. Who said Agaricus? Very good.
We have not said this. In Agaricus we talked last September. Was this keynote there? No.
You see you don't find it, you find it very seldom but it is really a good keynote to remember.
Like this, if you can remember trembling on sneezing.
Agaricus has in the end of coughing, they have a spell of coughing. In the end there is sneezing and it's finished.
Or they eat and as soon as they finish eating, the cough starts. Both these are keynotes for Agaricus.
Unless you have this little thing, never mind how much careful you take the case, you don't get these little keynotes
forget it, you cannot find the remedy.
I've given Kali -c., Kali-p., Kali-bi., Nit-ac., this, that, Puls., God knows what I've given, no effect.
Canth. is a good remedy to wake us up.
It's a very intense remedy, a remedy which produces intense inflammation. Very intense inflammation.
If this child was a Canth. case within 24 hours you feel it's going to die, the inflammation is very strong.
And mostly the inflammation concerns the genito-urinary system.
They prefer to be inflamed in this part, I don't know why. The interesting thing with these remedies
they are preferring to affect certain parts of the human body.
Canth. prefers the genito-urinary and the moment the inflammation starts, almost immediately you see blood.
Can you imagine an inflammation that takes place and in a few hours you have blood running because of the inflammation?
Can you imagine what strong burning pain they will experience these people? They will go to urinate and they will shout.
When you examine a case like this, of cystitis, you say 'is it a burning pain?'. 'Oh, very strong!'.
'Do you shout when you urinate?', 'No'. This most probably is not a case of Canth.
I remember a case a mother had the children. She would cry and the children would get upset and she was trying
to hold herself not to shout.
A lot of power not to shout, so the pain is such that you shout. This becomes characteristic of the case.
And a better even confirmation is that in spite of the pains, in spite of the severity of the situation, there is desire for sex.
The desire for sexual contact is tremendous, like Platina.
The men will have such desire that the erection during the night will be painful. They wish it could stop.
-May I ask something just for clarification. The pain before urinating and then it says and/or and then what is missing?
Does it also mean during and after urination?
-During urination is the main problem.
And after sure because it's inflamed. The urine passes and burns it. So during the urination, before, after the urination
but mainly during and after urination you have it. You can imagine, the urethra is inflamed. If you could open the urethra
it oozes blood from the inflammation and at the same time there is desire to have sex.
And if they do have sex, of course if men have sex, it's tremendous the pain they have during ejaculation
still the desire is there. So you can see how Canth. rises the sexual instinct and causes this kind of inflammation.
But whatever is the inflammation, if it takes that intensity, any inflammation, and at the same time you have an excitation
of the genitalia, the sexual instinct then most probably is a case of Canth.
The idea is not to stick to words. The idea is to get the idea, the idea of the remedy, the idea of the intense inflammation
which is so fast that blood will come out. It can be a colitis. You see in cases where you will have a food poisoning
and within a few hours pains will start and diarrhea will start and then a few hours later you have diarrhea with blood.
And then the patient is going fast to the next world, that's the case for Canth.
Theses cases actually you will see in the hospital mostly. There are cases that soon they go to hospital
because of the intensity of the progression of the case.
Strong sexual desire should be written with very much bigger letters.
And then we have some fears which look like fears of Stramonium.
And of course fear of water we have it also in Lyssinum or Hydrophobinum. Fear of water.
But fear of mirrors and shining objects, this combination is with Stramonium.
Lyssinum of Hydrophobinum is the same, not two different remedies.
You call it either Hydrophobinum or Lyssinum.
And of course this remedy now, in which case you may be use it, another possibility?
Where do you feel this sudden burning, unbearable pain?
When you burn yourself with fire. You burn yourself with fire and then the patient is going crazy with the pain, the burning
and he is fast going away to the next world, Canth. is really amazing what it can do.
I don't have the experience of hospital cases of second degree burns in which we could have been using it.
But between first and second degree where you have this really burning and you don't have people hospitalized
and you have given Canth., always Canth. has ameliorated the pain.
So the idea is the fire. Fire to the genito-urinary system, fire, excitement.
It's not excitement which is feelings, it's instinct. Sexual instinct is roused.
-What about burns from chemical?
-Burns from chemical, if they have this type of pain and this intensity, sure, anything.
Use Canth. in burns and you will see your experience. Not in little burns. Maybe other remedies.
Pains are burning and raw. It's a combination of burning and the skin is raw, that means
you don't have a skin anymore; it's finished the skin.
The mucus membrane is finished; it's eaten up by the inflammation.
You don't have to know more.
-If you have cystitis and this burning pain but it is at the very beginning. But it is not that strong like you describe it, can you  think?
-Usually you will not think of Canth. If it starts with a little bit of pain, no Canth. You have to use other remedies.
If you use the wrong remedies and the inflammation becomes really bad, you may reach the point of Canth.
-I had a case in my clinic just a short while ago. It was a motorcycle driver who had an accident
not much happened but 3 days later he had a constant erection.
And he had seen other Homeopaths before and he had received Op., Rhus-t. and Arn. and did not go away.
And then he went to the hospital because the swelling glands were deteriorating,
and they suggested to operate on him but he didn't want that and that's how he came to my office.
This was the only symptom I had, this constant priapism.
And I asked him whether he had any complains during urination and he said 'yes due to the priapism, I have a lot of pain'.
And so these were the only symptoms I had and due to this extreme pain I gave him Canth., high potency
and after 2 days, the erection was gone.
That's why I wanted to ask again because what I know of Canth. is that  they have infections over the genital urinary system
with priapism, that is my knowledge.
-Not necessarily. They have desire for sex, they have erection, strong erection, painful and they say God help me.
This type is another type which can happen. It doesn't necessarily need the inflammation of the cyst
or the urethra but it is very good in this case, you did very well you gave Canth.
-My impression also was that in the beginning he didn't really mind this constant erection. He seemed to enjoy it.
Only after 3 days it started feeling suspicious for him.
-That is true and I will give you some dangerous information now.
-I wanted to ask if this remedy is also good for very strong sun burn? Feeling like very much heat.
-Yes if the sun burn is really strong and burning the whole body, Canth. most probably will do it.
It's interesting also to observe that in such cases they have sun burn, at the same time the sexual instinct is roused.
I mean how this happens, nobody knows but in the sun burn, they are sitting under, it's burning and at the same time
there is strong sexual desire. That is definitely a case of Canth.
-Which potency would you suggest in such strong case of sunburn?
-200, 1M around that area.
-Perversions.
-All kinds of perversions.
When there is such sexual excitement, I don't like to go and describe perversions and things like that
because then it becomes like kinky lessons. But all the remedies which they have strong sexual excitement
they can have sexual perversions of all different types. I don't know them neither I ask the patients.
You don't need this. You don't need to know what kind of perversion somebody is doing but if you see a Canth. case
you know it can do anything. Or a Plat. case or a Tarent. man, or Nux-v.
Nux-v. is famous for perversions.
But with Canth. I will tell you because you may get this sometimes.
You get a woman who did not have sex for a period of time, 3 years, 4, 5 years.
And then she falls in love with somebody. Passionate and she has very passionate love and enjoys that.
This woman has a possibility that will develop without any reason symptoms of Canth. with severe cystitis or urethritis.
That means the passion which arises the sexual energy to that level, then it causes inflammation. It's very strange.
I have examined these cases. 'Did you have an infection, your husband had an infection?', 'No, no,no'.
'Your boyfriend?'. 'No'. Just out the passion that she developed this kind of cystitis we are talking about.
-Because I've seen a case of Canth., he was obsessed when he was 17, somebody told him that he stinks
and since then, now he is 37, three quarters of the day hides in toilet, putting toilet paper in his genitalia
busy with his stool all day long.
-That most probably is a case of Hyos.
-Yes but he had a lot of other things which was Canth.
-The Canth. has to have the intensity; it's like an inflammation that takes you to death.
A woman gives everything she has, all the passion. Like leading herself to death.
-Is  it possible the other way around? For example, a woman has a very strong desire for sex usually
and now she started have sex and after that, 6 hours after, she had twice a cystitis.
She called me at 6 o'clock in the morning and said, it's really burning, she was nearly crying.
-Yes it is. That's the case. That's a case of Canth. exactly.
-Staphysagria?
-Staphysagria maybe but the first remedy you are thinking once you see this...
Also this can happen in new married women, if especially they are chaste. If they are chaste, that means they don't practice sex.
They go to marriage and they let themselves loose and they enjoy very much and a few days later
they come down with severe cystitis. This is a case for Canth.
Once you get the idea, the moment that you will hear the story, the information will come and you will prescribe.
-What about cases of a chronic cystitis which cease but after sexual intercourse keep reoccurring.
Would that also be a case of Canth.?
-No, unless they have that intensity but just simple cases of cystitis, no. Other remedies you have to think of, Med. in this case.
The intensity is important, the erection has to be painful, I'm suffering save me. It has to have the intensity.
That is a remedy that really is slow to perceive sensations, feelings, very slow and cannot accommodate external impressions.
It's too much for Cocc. It gets tired, exhausted especially after loss of sleep.
They lose sleep 1,2,3 10 days, 15 days no sleep and then it comes a state of anxiety
and at the same time slowness to adapt to external impressions.
What do we mean by that? Cocc. cannot travel. She says, 'I cannot travel anymore with the car, especially if I'm sitting on the front seat'.
Because the impressions as they pass with the car cannot be absorbed, cannot be accommodated.
And there is the tendency to vomit and tendency to vertigo and nausea. Vertigo and vomiting and nausea on accommodating motions.
It is one of the main remedies we use, wrongly for me, for sea sickness. When you came with the speed boat
and some of the people could not accommodate that motion; Cocc. will tell you 'it's not possible for me
to go on a boat because of the motion. When I go into the car, I have to close my eyes or to hold my head
not to have this side pictures'. As the car goes by, the side pictures are those that bother mostly.
They have to look in front and it seems that the whole nervous system comes to a stand still, into a slowness.
And then that nervous system does not transmit or transmit very slowly the impressions.
So you pinch somebody and it says 'oh!', after a few seconds.
The signal from the foot to the brain takes a few seconds. It's the same thing with optic signals.
They cannot accommodate it, then there is vertigo. These people are exhausted, unable to think
the mind becomes very slow and they develop an anxiety about their own health but also an anxiety about others.
So in this respect they will look like Phosphorus very much.
Anxiety for themselves, anxiety for others. 'My mother is sick, I don't know what to do but I have this dizziness
all the time in my head and I can't travel, I can't go into the boat'. And then this slowness.
And slow, slow, slow, what happens in the end if the nervous system becomes very slow, more slow, they are paralyzed.
So we have paralysis which usually does not have any sign of pain. No pain. Paralysis with no signs of pain.
Weakness of neck muscles, heaviness, the head falls down.
These are slow developing cases of M.S. We have some type of M.S. which is a progressive paralysis.
Usually it is diagnosed as M.S. but it is not the typical M.S. It's a paralysis which goes slowly  and becomes
worse and worse, year after year.
So it is a degeneration of the nervous system.
This is a case of Cocc. Especially if this paralytic state is accompanied by vertigo, by dizziness.
And even better if the whole thing has started after long periods of sleeplessness.
-I wish to ask you about Cocc. and M.S. because I have a patient with M.S.
He is 15 years and I gave her Cocc. but I was really not satisfied because she had no vertigo.
-15 years of M.S. or the patient is 15 years old?
-She is 40 years old with 15 years of M.S. and first of all I gave Causticum because I was really disturbed she had no vertigo.
And what do you mean about this? I thought that Cocc. must have vertigo in these kind of problems.
-When there is vertigo and this slowness of reaction to receive the signals, then it is a Cocc. case.
Most probably maybe it is a case of Plumb., of Cupr. whatever, especially if there are any pains, any cramps.
Periodicity also, this does not show.
-In sea sickness how do you differentiate Tab. from Cocc.?
- Cocc. will not vomit. It will have the nausea. Tab. will be much stronger. In Tab. we see immediately
the person becomes white, tremendous nausea and vomits.
So the intensity is different but for the sea sickness, I mean for the time the person has sea sickness
to tell him take Tab. as a preventive before you go instead of taking Dramamine, take Tab. or Cocc..
forget it, it will not act. It will not act.
-But George in low potencies I have the experience that children for example, they take the remedy and acts good.
They get sick when they go to the car and if you give Cocc. D6 before they enter the car, I have a few children and it helps.
-Before they enter the car?
-When they start, the Cocc. is in the car.
-No in my experience.
-Maybe it's placebo effect.
-But if the boys cannot travel really, they have a problem maybe Cocc. is their constitutional remedy.
You can give it in high potency and they can be cured. But to give it as a preventive and next time give it again, this I doubt.
Of course if you are giving low potency, it's like you are repeating a low potency and maybe one day you find out
they don't have it anymore. They are cured because Cocc. was indicated as a remedy for example.
-You can't give it as prevention?
-You cannot. I said, you cannot give it.
-But dentists have the problem that our patients in certain treatment, they always have the problem of vomiting.
For instance taking braces or by taking X-rays and we have to help them. And I found out
that you touch them like this this helps more than any homeopathic remedy. I forget the name
you touch here 3 times and you tell them now you are very quiet and this will help.
-If you hypnotize them !
-But it's very important because they are very afraid just before.
I have been very nice myself many times when I am in despair, I say calm down please, nothing helps.
-You can say I can give any Ipecacuanha sometimes?
-If they vomit very easily? If you give them Ipecacuanha you cure them from their problem with their colitis.
-I have a very peculiar case. There is somebody who immediately falls asleep if he is reading 3-5 minutes
although he has slept already. And I couldn't help him with the Colch. or with the Nat-m. What would you suggest?
-I would suggest Opium or Nux-m.
Sensation of hollowness or emptiness in the head, chest or abdomen is the same as.....
Phosphorus!
So you have to combine immediately the information, one with the other, so you don't stick your mind to one remedy.