When a case is a case of Aesc.?
Is this from Germany? Yes. Very good quality.
It is  very difficult, you see this and then you try to make the signature. What signature can you make out of that?
Sometimes there is a possibility to connect the one with the other but do not make the mistake of trying to find
in every plant or in every animal substance the signature.
That means connect qualities of the plant with qualities of the mental or emotional picture of the patient.
So with Aesc., what is the main issue here? Where we see the patient?
What we have to perceive in order to say this is a case of Aesc.
And out of the keynotes that are given here what do we discover?
That we have two characteristics mainly. If you look at the symptomatology, there are two characteristics.
One is the venous congestion.
A kind of stasis, a kind of heaviness.
This heaviness stays upon the mental picture where the concentration is really very difficult.
Where the venous system is affected so as to produce mainly congestions and primarily hemorrhoids.
But now a lot of medicines are producing hemorrhoids. What is the specialty of this remedy? What it does?
It has severe protruding, like grapes, hemorrhoids. They are painful but at the same time, this pain has
a repercussion on the sacral area of the patient.
And especially the junctions on the sacral area.
Therefore it will be an individual who will be suffering all along with severe hemorrhoids which are protruding during stool.
And at the same time it will be an individual who will be suffering a lot with his sacral area. The sacral area will be very painful.
Especially sacroiliac junctions. And the main problem with Aesc.  will be the inability to stoop.
There is no way that they can be stooping. It is absolutely impossible. Bending forward.
It is a remedy that will produce a mental and emotional heaviness. The depression on Aesc.  is not very severe
but it is a depression that comes with a dullness of mind and a dullness of psychic, of emotions. They don't feel alive.
They stagnate, the emotions stagnate, the mind stagnates and it is not alive.
It says confusion of mind on waking.
Why do we have that? Because of the stasis in the venous circulation. They lie down for hours and then there is a stagnation.
They wake up and they feel confused and dull.
But is this enough to prescribe Aesc.? No. What you have to have is to have the hemorrhoids, the sacral affection.
If you see sacrum affected a lot, immediately the question I have to put is, 'do you have hemorrhoids?'
'Yes, external hemorrhoids. I have to push them in. Every time there is a stool, I have to push back the hemorrhoids'.
And you will see the whole organism is rejuvenated. 'Now my mind is clear'.
They don't understand because they have lived in that situation. They will not tell you 'my emotions are low'
once you give the remedy and they feel back again the health, then they start describing what we see here.
It says morose, frightful, ill humored, peevish all these are descriptions, only words to indicate that kind of
emotional dissatisfaction which is there with Aesc.
So stooping and another difficult position is walking.  Stooping impossible.
And the pain, when you will ask them to point to the place, they point exactly to the sacroiliac junctions.
Where is the pain? They point out to the sacroiliac junction, that is most probably an Aesc.  case.
You ask about the hemorrhoids, yes. You ask about the morning waking, the difficult concentration
and you will get all the rest of the story.
Of course such individuals where walking is painful, stooping is painful, would like to lie down.
Knife like pains which shoot up in the rectum. And you have this slowing down of all the different functions.
The heart is working, laboring, the stomach is not performing properly. You see that slowing down action on the whole organism.
Where veins are engorged or affected, in any part of the body. Whether it is laryngeal veins or whether it is veins
in the eyes where there is a distention, a fullness in the veins, the idea should go to Aesc.
You don't give Aesc.  when you see a keynote of Aesc.   You don't go and give Aesc.   especially when you treat a chronic case.
You have to perceive that this is really an Aesc.  case, not because there is a keynote of Aesc.
Is there this heaviness, the stasis, this engorgement, this dullness? Then the effect is fantastic.
You get a person who has hemorrhoids, external who are pushing every day but he is vital, his mind is working fast
his emotions OK, wait a moment, this is not Aesc. You have to have this heaviness.
Also the veins are having this bluish, of course all the veins have this purple color.
What I found out with the medicine, is that a lot of human emotions are because of chemistry. Not because of the character.
And yet as a society we accuse such individuals. Ah, he is very irritable. He cannot hold it because the chemistry is such
that means the imbalance in the organism is such that he cannot hold it back, he cannot control it.
But you go to religion or religious groups where they teach discipline or even in the families, especially the
German families or the Norwegian families, the northern countries in general. They teach the children how
to control their emotions. That is not a very good practice because the parents should be educated to understand
what is pathology and what is bad character. And when it's pathology they should take the child to a homeopath.
Then the child is not abusive anymore
the child is not so destructive anymore.
This is a bad child who wants to destruct everything and things like that. You give a Tub. and the child becomes an angel.
You get a woman who is so cutting and abusive and hitting, especially the husband gets it and you give Sepia
she becomes such a nice person. You see she changes totally. He says 'what a nice person you are.'
The husband says, 'you are such a nice person'. This is the reality, this is the real her apart from pathology.
Let's the weather is stormy and there is this pain and this is impossible, to do this, they go like this and at that moment
you come and you say something to them to irritate and then they become very abusive.
But you take the context out of which they become abusive.
Also Aesc. has a great characteristic the same as Merc.
Metallic taste in the mouth.
In this course we have to speak about smaller remedies because we finished most of the main remedies.
We can go to the next remedy which is Aml-n.
You read this remedy, how you recognize that remedy?
Explosions of heat.
This peculiar, explosions of heat on the upper part of the body, almost never in the whole body.
You get flushes of heat during the climacteric period. These flushes are generalized flushes of heat.
With Aml-n.  if there are generalized flushes, go away. But if they say, the flush becomes in the face
sudden and intense, that immediately should put your mind into Aml-n.
Anxiety, something will happen now, like a flush. Something bad is going to happen now.
This idea of flushing of an anxiety with its sequence. Something bad is happening at this moment.
These flushes of heat are extremely strong, intense
and therefore the woman especially, because this is a woman's remedy mostly, she will seek out fresh air.
Therefore you will confuse it with which remedy?
Flushes of heat, desire for fresh air, she has to come out.
Puls. but the whole class has to say Puls. That means I'm not a good teacher.
If I did not make you understand that Puls. is hot, nevermind the sudden. Sudden is a new element that may come
but flushes of heat and then she has to have fresh air, is Puls.
The whole organism, goes to the window, she has to go out, air. That's Puls.
Aml-n. has explosion of flushing and then air.
What I want to draw your attention to is the explosion, the intensity and then it is the face. You touch here is cold
you touch here is very hot.
You have flushes, they say it's only here. You touch here is cold, you touch here is cold, here is very hot.
The ears flushes. You touch here hot, you touch there cold.
That is Aml-n.
And there is of course something else which is intense and profound yawning which does not satisfy.
Yawning and stretching which does not satisfy, you will find in neuromuscular diseases.
You may have a case of M.S. with this dissatisfying yawning, with this stretching which cannot stretch really.
It stretches but does not satisfy, it doesn't release the tension of the nerves.
Plus some flushes which are local, then it doesn't matter if it is myopathy, myastheny, A.L.S., M.S., it does not matter
this is a case of Aml-n.
There are other remedies where we have this dissatisfaction and yawning and it is indicated in M.S. Which is this remedy?
Lathyrus.
This remedy also has that but does not have the flushing, does not have this heat production in certain areas.
Explosive production of anxiety. Like a flush.
And then it subsides.
This anxiety what it reminds you? Which remedy?
Anxiety, something bad is going to happen, not fear, not fear of death.
I don't say sudden fear of death, what reminds you? I say anxiety that something bad is coming. I don't know, I can't describe.
Phos.  this indescribable anxiety. 'What are you afraid of?', 'I don't know but it is so strong'.
It is the same with Aml-n. but in Phos.  keeps there almost all the time, only when he speaks
his mind goes out and he is back again, the anxiety comes.
With Aml-n. is a flush of anxiety.
And with this anxiety, there is restlessness. He cannot sit in one place.
You have another symptom that shows the effect of Aml-n. on the nervous system, which is convulsions immediately after delivery.
The woman gives birth and then goes into convulsions. That is the remedy.
You get an angina case
with pain, with local flushing and with constant stretching and he cannot keep still.
You say, keep still, don't move. Impossible.
This remedy will be confused in flushes with which remedy?
Glon. Also with Bell.
Also Bell. can have these sudden explosive flushes but here the quality of the flushes is that
you touch the other area, it is cold.
While the flushing area is so hot, the other areas are very cold. Around the Bell. has what? It has flushes in the head
or in the body where the extremities are cold. Do you see the difference?
And then you make prescriptions and he says, my God how he did it? If you know these little things, you just touch
you say take this remedy. In a case of angina, you may see fantastic effects. In angina cases where you will find the remedy
and there is not really blockage of a major artery, you may find, the whole issue is resolved.
Yes, when the heart is involved.
Also it has another characteristic which is like Bell., pain in the ears with throbbing.
Where you give first Belladonna, it does not act. Aml-n.
If it throbbing with pain in the ears, the pain in the ear is synchronized with the pulsation of the heart.
Then is Belladonna or Aml-n.
Of course you may expect also that in case there are such local flushes, you may sometimes see faintness.
With anxiety, when these flushes of anxiety, something is going to happen, in a case of heart involvement, you may see fainting.
In general you may see these sudden flushes of anxiety when there is a disturbance in the circulation.
During the menopause you may see these flushes or during a bleeding. You have bleedings and at the same time
you have these flushes of anxiety and the faintness.
Immediately your mind will go first to Phos.
Phos. of course has to have the thirst, the burning feel inside.
But in case you don't have that, what will differentiate Phos. from Aml-n.?
There is bleeding there is this anxiety, there is a fainting feeling what will make you give Phos. and not Aml-n.?
-If the anxiety is constant or by flushes?
-If the anxiety comes in flushes.
-If the anxiety is sudden.
The anxiety of Phos. is a floating anxiety which goes on. It comes and goes like flushes.
When a woman has flushes, you understand how she feels? There is for a moment great heat and then subsides.
In the same way the anxiety in Aml-n. comes which is similar with Phos., similar with Caust. but then subsides.
No anxiety.
And then next time there is a flush, then the anxiety comes.
-Are always the flushes with the anxiety?
-No but when you have that symptom. What we discuss here is the essentials of the remedy. If you see that
your mind should go there. This is what we're teaching. There are so many modifications and modalities but this
we do not concern. We concern in case you have that symptom how you differentiate between one and the other.
- In the keynotes what is the difference between intensity and degree?
The other remedy Aml-n. had keynotes underneath. And there are two columns in the back, saying intensity and degree.
-The first column it says value is, first is lowest value, two is italics, three is bold. This is the first column, it says value.
If it is bold, it is three. If it is italics, is in two.
The size of the rubric means that if it is 1-1 or 2-1 or 3-1 it means that on the whole Materia Medica is the only remedy that has that.
There are no other remedies. If here it says 2 or 3, there are 2 or 3 other remedies which have that symptom.
The symptoms which are given as keynotes, you don't have to remember. You hear it but you can forget it
because if you have that symptom, you go to the Repertory you will see it's the only remedy. OK, you can forget this.
What is important for you is to perceive the structure of the remedy. What the remedy is doing.
That is important, that you have to remember. And connect it in your memory with some other remedies
that you have learned already. Aml-n., Glon., Bell., Phos. anxiety.
If you can do that, then you have a lot in your mind. If you try to remember the keynotes, you will have a problem
because you overload your head with unnecessary information, which you can find in the Repertory straight away.
-What is the difference between Glon. and Aml-n.
-You have to answer actually because we have done Glon.
If you go to Glon. you will see that Glon. say, 'I cannot have sun at all'. Sun is the great enemy for Glon.
Here we don't see in Aml-n. inspite of the flushes, we don't see this great peculiarity.
Then Glon. we talked about in headaches. It's purely a remedy which affects the vascular system
causing tremendous headaches.
We don't see with Aml-n. so much headaches. We may see some effect on the mind and the effect is anxiety.
On Glon. we see the effect and the effect is like Aesc.
Both these remedies they may be driving in a place and suddenly they don't recognize, where am I?
And then flashes back the picture. Both Aesc. and Glon. have this.
Aml-n. has flushing anxiety. It's different.
-The point that you made before about not having to memorize the keynotes as much as getting the structure
of the remedy, if I wanted to differentiate in a case of Aml-n., the keynotes from the structure what would you call,
you gave us certain keynotes, how would I think about the structure?
-The structure is the sudden flushes, the sudden anxiety, the desire for open air, that is the whole structure.
It means that the effect is mostly on the vascular system and then on the nervous system.
The structure is that the flushes concern an area,  localized flushes. That is structure.
Then you have a keynote here which is whatever, you don't have to remember.
What you see here, you have the information from the Materia Medica, what is the predominant?
What impresses you in this remedy?
The idea is also that you learn to think. I'm not going to think for you all the time because if you are in private practice
then you have to have learned the way to look at the Materia Medica.
So what impresses you in these symptoms? It's written there.
Just read and think. And see whether we agree in our evaluation.
-All the blackness.
-Correct.
All this blackness, black discharges, black boils, black, black.
It says also as if a black boil, silent suffering....
Silent suffering. Anthrax, you know how painful it might be and black and discharging black fluid.
Imagine this in the emotional.
Some people who have been really hurt and keep inside this black boil. We describe it as black boil
but actually try to imagine how such a person is.
It's a boil, it doesn't break out. It is inside and it is black, it is the emotions that are really very painful but hidden inside.
How a person will look like?
It will look like as if it has gone through a lot of pain silently and it says premature old age.
This is the result of that suffering without crying.
I've given once this remedy to a person. She cried for several days, cried, nonstop as if she never cried before.
If you see the video after the lecture, you may recognize the remedy. You see how tired and given up. The pain is inside.
You think life has gone.
Feels the death is approaching. But here is not a fear of death.
It is 'well, death is coming, I'm dying', it is a realization. It is not a fear, it's not an anxiety. The suffering is so much
who cares if he lives or dies? That is the situation.
And of course such persons how do they feel about having sex? You get a married woman. Forget it.
It is not exactly aversion to sex. It is no energy for that function.
They can work but like robots. Do this, do that, they go exhausted, they lie down, they try to recuperate.
Their skin has become really old.
In a very young age. 35,36 and the skin is like a woman of 65.
It's very interesting also that you will notice in such cases that, you ask this person 'have you gone through some suffering?'
You can see it obviously, there is no question about that. A lot of suffering. She will try to remember.
She will not remember an incident in which she really felt very bad.
It has gone inside, closed in a boil like this and kept inside there.
If the boil breaks out, then there is a release of the emotions, feeling better. If the boil stays like this, she will keep
she will say 'I don't remember'. Nothing can break this boil.
Her life is a torture, is a turmoil, is terrible, yet she will not remember a specific incident to relate to you.
I lost my husband and therefore, I lost and therefore, I do this and therefore.
This is enclosed and kept inside and can't remember.
Of course this remedy will be required, will be indicated in cases you have repeated boils especially
if the discharge is dark.
It's very interesting also that such persons will like to stay in the house. They don't like to go outside of the house.
It's not a case of claustrophobia so much as they feel more comfortable in the house.
Once they go out from the house, they feel uncomfortable and unstable.
That means they need the protection of the house.
A keynote is coldness in the abdomen, which goes down the legs. Coldness in legs and back when dressing.
That means after certain motions, coldness in legs and back.
This coldness indicates the local coldness. It's a reflection of the inside coldness which this person feels.
You look such remedies as Sep., as Arg-n.,
as Sec., which look prematurely old.
And the pain intense and burning with all these boils.
So you may have a boil wherever in the body. It may open, discharges, closes and during the period it discharges
the boil, the general symptoms are better. She feels a little bit better. Then closes, then she feels bad again.
Then for years she may have boils which are opening and closing with burning pains, very painful.
Tarent-c. and Anthraci. and Ars. have severe burning pain in boils.
-How do you differentiate this premature age, this internal grief? It sounds also like Nat-m. in many ways, so what's the distinction?
-This person has given up life, it's exhausted mentally and emotionally. Will not give out any signs of life.
Nat-m. has nothing to do. Nat-m. will be closed.
'You have suffered?', 'Well,...', he knows very well from where it started what he has suffered.  It's different picture all together.
Nat-m. will never have this old appearance.
-What I'm going the sense of is, I see the silent suffering, I see the coldness, I see the darkness,  the closing down,
would you find this remedy with some sexual abuse? Where the child was not allowed to tell the parents
or felt there was no way to go with it?
-Absolutely yes.
And then keeping all this grief inside. The child has been abused, has been abused by the parents
by the husband. Then there is a series of abuses and then she cannot remember anymore.
She says, well, maybe. You get a response like this.
But what you have in front of you is a terrific suffering of a human being.
You cannot remember anything?
I mean I was not able to elicit response and to tell me, after that I became like this.