Today I want to speak to you about Lil-t.
Little tiger.
What is the patient who needs this remedy? How this is produced?
It is produced basically out of a big conflict between morality and sexuality.
Sexuality is an energy which everybody has. It has to be released through natural means.
If this sexuality is kept inside and
it is aggressive or even more it is...
...quite strong and perhaps lascivious, perverted...
...this causes in the individual a fear inside that if he expresses such kind of sex, then the people will be against...
and then there is a repression of that.
And if this is really strong and the repression is equally strong, as a result we see a twist in the character of the person.
Then the person becomes snappish and nasty.
It is a person who will attack. They are persons who become very angry with the least provocation.
'I didn't say anything!'. 'You said it, you hurt me'.
'My God what did I say?'
They are so easily hurt. The hurt and
the reaction it is much more than in Nux-v.
You don't say in this case, it is irritable. It's not exactly irritability, it's the dissatisfaction inside
...because of the lack of sexual release a dissatisfaction...
...which causes dyspnoea, suffocation.
And that suffocation comes out aggressively.
I have said many times that this remedy is a remedy that is indicated mostly in women and mostly in unmarried women.
Not only unmarried.
They have to have the element of sexuality repressed and not satisfied in their sexual life.
They will be like spinsters. A woman who has not married ever. Who has not ever had a love affair.
Because of repression of sexuality they stay aloof and they have such a character that the other person...
...cannot approach them very easily. Because they are so much hurt, so easily and so much attacking if they are hurt...
...that they put out any person who comes in contact or tries to be sexually advancing.
So, strong element of religiousness and strong element of sexuality. If the sexuality takes over, she may have...
...aggressive sex or she may have lascivious sex or she may go into a period of satisfying this need.
Then the religious aspect comes over and this contact is stopped and then the Lil-t.  pathology develops.
It's very interesting because we talked about sexuality and repressed sexuality and then what do we see?
We see the woman is collapsing, out of order, is prolapsing, it doesn't function, you don't need it.
Then there is a very strong sense of prolapsus inside.
Therefore she would look very much like Sepia.
What is the difference?
The difference is that this remedy is much more active and powerful and with energy.
Sepia is without energy. Energy is lacking on the emotional, in the physical, in the mental. This one here is
very fast to react and to bring out arguments and say, 'I have done everything for you, you have done nothing for me'.
The religious aspect plays a big role here, in Lil-t.
Because the person will find solace in their contact with deity, whatever it might be.
The deity in Jewish religion is different, in Hindu is different, Christian is different, whatever you call it.
But they find solace in having a contact with
the deity because they are duty conscious.
This remedy is very duty conscious and
there is a sense of hurriedness inside.
They have to do, they have to perform, to do this, to do that, 'I cannot stay'.
'But you are exhausted, why don't you sit?',
' I can't.'
And then he says, asthma...
...and gets up and go and digs the garden.
He has to do, he cannot stay.
It says here profound depression of spirit. Of course you understand the life of such a person who becomes unsexual
but out of some kind of dissatisfaction in relationship.
They ask too much, they ask different things.  I mean it's not a matter of going into details of that type.
Then from this state of aggression, nastiness and snappiness, they may go into a state of apathy. Depressed and apathetic.
Depressed, apathetic, religiously inclined...
...and the anxiety comes that whether they will be going to the next world and what is the condition and how can I be saved?
There are questions which they don't bother many individuals but when it comes to that pathology...
... the question of salvation can become very bothering.
It's there all the time in the mind of the people who need this remedy.
So this remedy looks very much like Sepia.
It looks Sepia because they need to act.
But the action is a sense of duty.
I have a duty, I have two children and I have
a husband and I have to look after them.
And you ask 'how is your relationship with your husband?' She says, 'no sex'. 'How many years?', '20 years'.
What's the problem? Asthma.
Coughing. And the cough is better on the open air.
They cough inside, they go outside in the garden and the cough stops.
You go to the Repertory, it is one of these strange, rare and peculiar that we see.
We see only two remedies to be in this rubric.
The fears mostly are fear of the evil, fear of something bad happening but that has the connotation of the evil.
Of something which is religiously bad.
So with Lil-t., what do you have to have?
You have to have either the hurriedness and the snappiness together with a feeling of bearing down sensation.
They describe it stronger than Sepia.
The expression is as if the whole abdominal content would go out. The same way that it is described in Sepia.
And of course this condition is worse standing, of course and better lying down. Sepia is better sitting, crossing the legs.
The hurriedness feeling you will not find in Sepia. The religious affection you will not find in Sepia.
We spoke in Sepia for people who are going into spiritual quest.
Spiritual quest is different than this one. This is the fear of God.
The fear that I will be punished, that I am a sinner and I want things which are sinful and I should not do it.
And then they say no and the organism is pushing them. It's a chemical disturbance.
You will be surprised how much.
The chemical disturbances are leading you, it's not pure mental or choice.
By choice I'm this or by choice I'm that. You are not by choice, you are by chemistry.
You are your hormones. And that's why you prefer this or that way of expressing your sexual desires, needs etc.
There are very female hormones. Tarentula will go out and get somebody in the street and have sex.
And she goes back and says, what am I doing?
But next time she will do it. Lil-t. has that. I should not do it because God will punish me.
And that conflict comes inside and
then you see the snappishness.
Man or woman it doesn't matter.
Always the sense of duty. 'I have done my duty'. It's very strong in Lil-t.
'I have done my duty, so you better listen to me'.
They are quite domineering people, whatever they want it has to be done. The others have to do it.
A sensation of lump in the rectum. There is a peculiar symptom, if you ever find it
which is a feeling of congestion in the chest if
the desire to urinate is held, cannot be satisfied.
They want to urinate and there is a congestion in the chest. You have asthma and you have to urinate...
... before they urinate they have to hold, there is a congestion in the chest.
Such a remedy will have angina pectoris with the feeling of the heart being cramped in a vice.
This is common symptom which you will
find in many remedies, in this pathology....
...but you have to have the hurriedness
and this kind of nasty character.
I have prescribed Lil-t.  exclusively with women.
I don't remember a male having Lil-t. You had a case?
-A male patient you prescribed, he had heart problems and when you gave him the remedy you said, it's the first time
I have prescribed Lil-t. to a man.
-I don't remember it. Maybe.
If I could remember all the cases.
Also this confirms what I say. I don't know why but remedies are fitting more women than men.
Sulphur is more for men. Lyc. is more
for men. Puls. is mostly women. Men also.
But exclusively men or exclusively
women they are very few remedies.
Lil-t. it seems to have a peculiar connection between female hormones and this religious affection.
Verat. has religious affections, Hyos. has religious affections, Lach. has religious affections.
This religious affection is similar to Aur.
What God is going to do to me?
You will in such cases many times a lot of eczema with women, a lot of aggressive eczemas which are itching
and look like Croton tiglium, scratching and aggressive.
Lil-t. comes to the house, she is a working woman and she has a maid in the house which she prepares the food.
And she comes to eat, she has the eczema,
and she puts the food, the mother, whoever.
Pushes the table, why? Because a little bit more in quantity onion that she would like.
And the mother is trembling. The monster is coming. Exactly the salt. 'I told you, you don't put salt.'
This kind of behaviour. I exaggerate,
it's not all Lil-t. like that.
I just saw a case who prescribed Lil-t.  and maybe she is in the class.
But I exaggerate to give you the idea of snappish, nasty.
And also you see that in this person there is no the satisfaction of love.
When there is a release on that level, there is a deeper satisfaction which goes away with Lil-t.
I don't know if I am able to communicate the idea.
That's all you have to remember, no more.
-I don't know who said but he said you can get a good picture because of the name, Tiger, Lilly. That is a soft person
but if they go into this state, they are like tigers. You said it.
-Yes I said it. The way I describe
it, you can imagine it.
You feel a person never satisfied but very duty conscious.
Very conscientious.
So there is this God tells me to do this correctly, I have to look my children, my husband  I have to do this.
Then what about your organism? It needs this or that. No. This is not allowed. God will punish me if I do that.
Of course this has to be in the extreme because everyone has some problems in these areas.
And they think am I Lil-t. No, you are not but there are degrees in that.
And Lil-t.  has this suppression to strong degree and then the problem develops.
In the end of each Materia Medica you can ask me some questions, if you like to complete the picture.
-How do you get a sense of the sexuality? Do they tell you or can you pick it up?
-You're treating a case and she has a prolapse of the uterus and you think of that, then you ask about the sexuality
and then you get an answer. It depends if the person is married, a married woman maybe she has tolerated some sexual action.
Then she will downplay the idea of
sex and then you ask about religion.
Then immediately you see a different response on that. Religion yes I have. Then you investigate a little bit more.
Without intruding too much because these are deep issues. And we know quite a lot what is happening in an individual
especially when we spot the remedy and we see the problems. We understand almost immediately
what has happened. We can tell events
of their life almost. Because if you know that
this is the context, you can describe more or less the situation. That does not mean I have to intrude
but you put some questions because they are sensitive issues.
You put some questions and you get the answers and from that you get the impression.
If they are honest people they will tell you and people around Lil-t.  are very important.
Because if they give you this idea of snappishness and easily hurt, they will go into a retreat, he hurt me, out.
I go to the garden, I go inside.
You get some other people who are more open and they will tell you more. If you go to America, you examine
an American woman they will tell you everything.
American women are liberated in these matters.
Is this correct, Mr. America?
You can discuss with American woman anything almost?
-There are some Lil-t. s that I have treated who have become non denominational reverends because they had such
a strong desire to serve that they themselves have become reverend.
And they liberated both in the religious and they also maybe gay and be liberated in the sexuality as well.
-That's correct.
Also if you look at the American plays, the serials, the 'bold and the beautiful'...
...and sometimes you just click like this and the American woman is very much towards this.
Because the liberation on the one hand made her believe that she can liberate and she can enjoy whatever.
If the other time comes the conscience and says, what are you doing and then the conflict comes and under
this conflict become like tigers.
American women I'm afraid. They will kill you. What did I say?
Mur-ac. is another very interesting remedy.
We have to pass from one state to another.
We need a little bit of quietness before we can plunge to another level of pathology.
Mur-ac. is of course famous for an exhaustion which we call total exhaustion on the physical level.
It says the lower jaw hangs down.
They don't have enough strength to bring it. When you go to sleep, when everything is relaxed like this.
There are semi comatose states with so much exhaustion that they cannot even turn in bed.
They don't have enough strength to turn in bed.
You put them in bed, here is the bed and here is the pillow and the people are lying down there on this pillow.
They cannot stay on that pillow for more than half an hour. Slowly they slide down and they find themselves with the head here.
They cannot get up and go back to the pillow.
This is the case where usually you will find in acute cases, with fever, whatever type. They use to call it
blood poisoning fever, typhus also.
But also you will find it in exhaustive diseases which are affecting primarily the liver.
You know the liver is the one organ that gives energy and that is why Mur-ac. is one of the main remedies
for liver dysfunction and liver affections.
To give you the dimension of exhaustion, I'll give you an example of a patient.
I have a patient in United States and they telephone me, he is in terrible state with blood pressure 250...
...terrible pressure, young man, 38-39, total exhaustion and I said 'OK you come so I can treat you'.
He says, 'it's not possible because I can't move'. He is totally exhausted. What can I do?
They phone again and they decide to come. They start a journey from Los Angeles to New York.
Stay 3-4 nights where he slept all the time. NY-London sleep,  London-Athens sleep...
...and I was this year it was my summer holiday and he had to come. My secretary picks him up from the airport in Athens
to bring him where I was having holiday. It was not here it was in another place where he could come with the car.
He comes there and I see this young man totally exhausted, we knew each other very well, he says....
...'Hi George where is my bed?'
The secretary says, he was on the back seat of Mercedes, sleeping all the time, the whole journey, he was sleeping.
That is the type of exhaustion for Mur-ac.
Here we have a high blood pressure and most probably at this time I was thinking of pheochromocytoma...
supra renal gland, malignant tumors which they cause such high blood pressure and exhaustion.
I think catecholamines which is measuring how far this may have been, they have been raised
there was a big suspicion for this malignancy.
I asked him one question.
What was the question?
-If the urine comes slowly.
-No.
-Do you like meat?
He came with his girlfriend. His girlfriend brought him, she gave me the whole story, what has happened actually.
He exhausted himself very much in his work, totally exhausted. And he used some marihuana and then some drinking
and push himself and suddenly collapsed. They tried to give Homeopathy, they tried to give Acupuncture, no effect, nothing.
He was there about two months in that state and he had to take high blood pressure medication.
I will tell you something that you can remember. Nat-m., Mag-m., Mur-ac. there are all very much worse in the sea.
The Muriatic element, I don't know why it has a bad reaction near the sea.
So when I asked him this question, he says all my life I don't like the sea, I don't go to the sea, I'm worse in the sea.
So was it possible that this Mur-ac. was even his constitutional remedy? Most probably yes.
Because under Mur-ac. in 3 days we started going out for a little walk.
Can you get up? Yes I can. Can you walk up to the corner? Yes. We go back, we come back, OK.
Fourth day we go further. Fifth day we go further. Sixth day, 7,8 day we leave the place and we come here in Alonissos.
9th day we stayed in Rusum and he started jogging slowly.
10,11 day he starts jogging all around Rusum
you know it goes round and up again.
1,2,3 times very good. On the 17th day he was feeling so strong, he said 'I'm going back'.
He was near the sea. But after the
Mur-ac. he was not swimming still.
But you don't have any more this
sensitivity to the sea, exactly.
But that is the type of exhaustion we have with the Mur-ac. Another thing that the Mur-ac. has due to this weakness...
...we have easy hemorrhoids which are very painful. They are mostly coming in pregnancy and if a woman
is suffering a lot during pregnancy with hemorrhoids which come out and they have to push them in
and very painful to any touch any walking, then most probably the child will be born with hemorrhoids.
The baby can have hemorrhoids as well.
It comes as a hereditary predisposition and the baby has hemorrhoids.
So due to this symptom it has been found out that babies who have hemorrhoids, they need Mur-ac.
I remember Pierre Schmidt when he came to Athens one day and he was examining me, putting questions.
One of the questions was what you will give to a baby just born with hemorrhoids? I said, Mur-ac. My compliments.
This is something which I have not seen but something that Pierre Schmidt and others confirm
that Mur-ac. will have an effect.
Involuntary stool while passing urine, urine passes slowly...
... all this a description of the exhaustion and the muscular paralysis.
It is a remedy, this weakness can lead to muscular paralysis eventually.
You will have to differentiate Mur-ac. and Bapt. also because Bapt. is also very exhausted during fever.
Both of them they have offensive secretions.
The perspiration is offensive, the stool is very offensive and you will have to differentiate between the two.
A big point of differentiation, who can tell? Because we did Bapt.
Another thing that you will see immediately in the face.
Mur-ac. is pale. Bapt. is brownish, reddish.
Mur-ac. is much more exhausted than Bapt. Bapt. even when she is in semi-comatose state and she will come out
and give answers, there is some life in Bapt. In Mur-ac. there is no life.
Mur-ac. of course you will have to differentiate with Stann.
How you can differentiate with Stann.?
The discharges in Mur-ac are offensive. In Stann. they are not.
The complexion no. Both Stann. and Mur-ac. will be whitish.
-Stann. is unable to speak or worse from speaking. Mur-ac. I don't think so.
-Mur-ac. doesn't speak at all.
-Stann. is in respiratory and Mur-ac. is physical weakness.
-Most of the Stann. affections will affect the respiratory tract, they will affect the power to speak especially.
That means if they speak, they become very exhausted.
And that is very characteristic. Stann. is a tubercular remedy, affecting the lungs primarily...
...Mur-ac. affecting the liver primarily.
So if you see total exhaustion, almost like this in asthma cases you will not go and give Mur-ac. You will give Stann.
You see the Stann. they cannot make a move, they just get up a little bit and go to sit there.
They collapse.
This you don't think of Mur-ac.
Mur-ac. you will think mostly in fevers and where liver is affected and there is this kind of exhaustion.
Therefore you will need Mur-ac. in cases of hepatitis with exhaustion.
Also in Mur-ac. you will see the organs in a collapse state in general.
You will have prolapse of the uterus, as well prolapse of the rectum.
-We said Mur-ac. will have this restlessness. How does that fit to the exhaustion?
-It's an inner restlessness which I have not seen it externally.
It writes here restlessness. You can say this is inner restlessness it's not the restlessness that you see externally.
Also it says 'loud moaning persistent' and then it says 'suffers in silence'. These are things in the Materia Medica.
What it means actually is that when you see these cases fever and this exhaustion you will hear...
This is the persistent loud moaning.
And suffers in silence.
He is almost dying, the way that you see him. You ask, do you have fear of death? No. No fear of death, they don't care.
It's so much the exhaustion.
Fear? No fear.
They don't bother, 'let me alone'. It is like Bry. Many times we confuse Bry. with Mur-ac. actually.
Because Bry. has that collapse state, that exhaustion, especially with respiratory problems.
And Bry. also does not want the contact. Suffers in silent you can say, the same thing.
But Bry. can be confused with Stann. in problems of the respiratory tract and especially asthma.
-George I have a question concerning the patient you are talking about. You said he had exhausting life...
...but did you also find a deep grief coming to such a bad condition? Did you find emotional grief?
-No.
You see the Mur-ac. state is a state you have to perceive it, the exhaustion is so much that they don't care.
They slide down, somebody who goes to death position.
It says suffers in silent , all these are expressions that you have to put them in context and the context is
that state of exhaustion that makes you totally indifferent, no fear.
If there is a kind of exhaustion like that and there is anxiety and fear of death, with such kind of exhaustion
then you go to other remedies; they cannot be Mur-ac. Most probably is a Phos. case.
Bry. is a remedy that usually will be thirsty, so you will see the thirst which is not in Stann.
Then Bry. is much more like Mur-ac. in their dealing with others. They will say 'leave me alone'
by meaning, by signs, by whatever.
I have been in a Mur-ac. state and in Stann.
case and I know the situation exactly how it is.
I didn't care, let me die. Why not?
It says vertigo on moving the eyes or lying on the right side. This is the only remedy in the Materia Medica
and I have tried to give it on that, it will not act unless there is the exhaustion.
You have the vertigo, unless you have the exhaustion, you will not give it.
This case of Mercury that we have been discussing, he remembers the exhaustion.
The exhaustion was like this, if you remember. But I did not give him Mur-ac.
I gave him Bell. Why? Because the exhaustion was together with a severe headache.
I remember the patient symptoms more than the patients many times. It was that type of headache
the context was not a Mur-ac., it was not Stann. He had vomiting, headache, exhaustion, he says I can't lift the water.
This strong man lying there with 40 fever, not being able to lift the water, you think of Mur-ac.? No.
Because we didn't speak about headaches. In this case we speak with 250 blood pressure and no headaches.
He didn't complain of headaches. Of course blood pressure is not always accompanied by headache
but in this high blood pressure, there is some effect on the head.
The head feels at least congested and full. In the Mur-ac. is rather the giving up of the organism.