I've found that they deeply suffer with
what we say psychogenic dyspnoea.
A dyspnoea that seems to have
no pathology, psychogenic.
And they are people who are always
very anxious about that dyspnoea.
A tremendous anxiety and a fear and almost sometimes reaching panic with a little bit of dyspnoea.
You see that the lungs are almost clear or absolutely clear but the person has a kind of dyspnoea which comes about.
And he feels absolutely paralysed with fear that he is going to die because of that dyspnoea.
That kind of personality. It's a person
who is very much meticulous usually.
A person who sees details, like Arsenicum. They will come with their notes prepared, what is happening and I had this and I had that...
'Do you have dyspnoea now?', 'A little bit yes', And you try to auscultate, to see and there is nothing yet you see a tremendous anxiety concerning that.
Usually they will tell you that this dyspnoea will come about if they are a little bit exposed to any kind of draft.
Or any exertion.
But the draft becomes almost a fixed idea.
So they work for instance in Athens, which is very hot in the summer and he's in a appartment with aircondition and he prefers to work in the heat but putting on the air condition.
Now from that condition where we say it's almost psychogenic, it can reach a point where the dyspnoea can bring about a kind of coldness of the whole body, palpitation, drop of blood pressure and a fear of imminent death.
On the whole you can say that these people are kind of hypochondriac. That is how they appear to us, no real cause and they make a big fuss about.
You see a certain type of cases that you would give, I will tell you later on, you will see that this remedy can be mistaken for Carb-v.
The coldness comes, the palpitation, the kind of cold pespiration, the drop of the blood pressure, you may confuse it with Carb-v. During the acute crisis.
But when they will tell you their cases and you will see the aggravation which they have on lying down in the night, the aggravation from anything tight, they cannot tolerate.
With that kind of dyspnoea and tha lump in the throat you will feel that this is a case of ...
....Lachesis.
But again it does not appear because the sensitivity to draft is so much and the anxiety about his health and they are meticulous individuals.
Lachesis is much more vivid and much more extroverted; these people will usually tell you their symptoms just this, this and that.
They will not go beyond the point to describe any psychological state. You just see the anxiety.
Because they come again and again. It's very interesting that they suffer so much and they will not say, I have tremendous anxiety about health.
They feel that this is logical. The way I feel I cannot take breath, I will die. So they do not say,
'I have an anxiety about health'.
You have to deduce that from the intensity of the pathology which is not there and on the other hand from where they will describe their own crisis, their own symptoms.
I found out that they are people that give out symptoms when their history there is a mistreatment of a serious lung problem, say a pneumonia.
And they had sometimes tuberculosis in the younger age, treated but it seems that from that point onwards something else is left
in the respiratory system and they cannot
cope whenever this crisis comes and goes.
It's very interesting also and it has similarity with Lachesis in the fact that symptomatology can appear if there is a suppression of discharges.
Suppression of menses can bring about tremendous colic pains in the abdomen and also to the sacrum with tremendous aggravation from touch.
Pains on the back here that the person cannot lie down, because there is a touch of his body against this, they cannot lie down.
-That you will find it in women where they have gone and took a bath in the first day of the menses or the second day of the menses
and the menses stop because of the coldness, they took a bath in the sea I mean and this kind of things come about.
So we have with Lachesis the lump in the throat, the aversion to tight clothes, the aversion to touch the aggravation from touch
and also a trigeminal neuralgia which usually appears on the left side and it is aggravated by touch.
The difference is that Lachesis is a
warm remedy and it is a talkative remedy.
These people will not talk beyond their point.
They are very composed, serious people, not extroverted at all, not the type of Lachesis.
In my prescribing I have made a mistake and I have prescribed Lachesis several times instead of Lobelia.
And it didn't work and then Lobelia came.
There was one case where I prescribed first Lobelia and it didn't work and then Lachesis acted.
It's not in the things that we are absolutely clear, these remedies intervene with each other's symptoms.
But if you remember you had this aggravation
of lying down, they lie down and they are aggravated, they are aggravated in the night.
You see how close they are with Lachesis. And then there is sinusitis with Lobelia, especially on the right side, not on the left.
We have also difficult breathing when menses
do not appear. It's the time for menses to appear and they do not, it' becomes difficult breathing.
Also difficult breathing from exertion
and when they are upset.
And very much aggravated this difficult
breathing  from exposure to cold and draft.
Sometimes these cases will exhibit a constant kind of dyspnea and that constant difficulty of breathing. This will be aggravated only during a draft.
What is interesting to remember is
that there is a fear of death.
The other is that they have this dyspnoea and they get an anxiety that something is wrong and they may die.
They have different intensity to their anxiety.
Also this can appear as a
sensation of pressure in the chest.
Sometimes pains can bring a fainting feeling or when the pains become a little bit intense they feel they want to faint.
Also they have a feeling as if the heart will stop.
Pains in the uterus and vagina and in the abdomen, better by drawing, lifting up the legs together. Like Colocynthis.
And this is even better when they
lie on the left side, like Chelidonium.
So tubercular patients, when you see the tubercular tint. There is tuberculosis in the family, there is something running in the family or in the person.
When here is this kind of
syndrome, think of Lobelia.
The way she describes the kind of dyspnea: I feel I'm going to die and I feel dizzy, I have a constriction on my throat.
And heaviness on the chest. My throat
becomes closed and  I cannot breathe.
At that time I become panicky and in the  beginning there is a flushing and then I feel shivering.
The time of dyspnea I have the feeling that there is a pressure on the ears, from the inside, outside.
I constantly have this oppressive
feeling on the chest and in dyspnea.
Also this is a symptom a constant feeling of dryness in the mouth, without thirst.
This is another description. If I eat late in the night and by 2-3am, I wake up with cold perspiration, with rumbling and a feeling that
I'm dying and I become panicky.
panicky. You see this theme,
how it comes about on these cases.
Sexually I found that these people behave
almost normally, they have not much disturbance in there except that they're a little bit over sexed.
And it's interesting that in some of these cases you will see a fear of snakes, that you will also in Lachesis.
As I told you there are serious people
and they do not accept to be offended.
They are offended very easily, they are proper people but they don't like to be remarked, especially when it is unjust.
This dyspnoea feeling. They say they have to constantly do it. What reminds you?
If you see somebody sitting there, Ignatia. You see I had another case that was coming from another homeopath, also my student
but some of my students have left
5-10 years ago, I'm not in contact.
And immediately he gave Ignatia. Now this
man had a big disturbance from Ignatia. Ignatia was close but nothing curative happened.
And when he came to me and he presented the picture of Lobelia very clearly, I prescribed Lobelia in the beginning and it was an aggravation for 3-4 days and then cure.
There is a possibility that you may confuse it with Ignatia, sometimes with Carb-v. and mostly Lachesis.
From desires there is some
desire for sweets and fat.
Another strong symptom that you can note
down is aggravation from bath in cold water.
But if they come out to the open air, they
can be ameliorated, open air ameliorates.
Drafts and cold bathing is very bad for
them but cold air, outside, can ameliorate.
They are so sensitive to the atmospheric changes that one could think of another  remedy which is very sensitive to changes on temperature...
Rumex.
When you see the coldness during the time of crisis, the blood pressure goes down and the freezing and the cold perspiration.
You may confuse it with Carb-v. It reminds you of Carb-v. If you go on the acute crisis and you see the person lying down because they are  anxious persons and they may call you.
You may be treating such a person already and you just give him different remedies but he is not making progress. So one day he calls you and you see his picture and you give Lobelia.
Also symptoms like Lycopodium
and red sediment which are not far.
What I tell you is the experience
and this I have to make it clear.
This is not to replace the Materia Medica,
neither in my Materia Medica I give everything everything but I give what I found out in my experience as most important and useful of symptoms.
And maybe you will find a case with red sediment which is not Lycopodium, it is Lobelia but to me it has to be that type of person behind.
So what is more important for me is to give you the type of person that have experienced that they need Lobelia.
And to give you the most frequent
symptoms that I have met.
So you don't have in your mind a lot of information but rather a skeleton on which you can build your symptoms.