If you look on the notes, what do you have to remember about Bov.?
It's written with big letters.
Especially for women, diarrhea before or during menses. This is characteristic.
The other you have to remember is awkwardness and the third you have to remember
is a kind of peculiar anxiety. I will describe the mental-emotional state of Bov.
It says awkward but this awkwardness comes from a state of anxiety and a state of inner hurriedness...
and a state like manic depression.
The first time I met this, I could not make heads or tails. There was a woman sitting there and she was saying...
'Dear Mr. Vithoulkas I'm suffering so much!'.
I was there and she was looking there, she was not looking at me.
Pouring out all the information.
She was not there, she was not composed. She was in a state of anxiety, mania. And in that state when you have
this awkwardness together with that, you have
a feeling that everything is exaggerated.
In the book it says 'enlarged sensation'.
That means you may feel bigger. The fact is that you get the feeling that whatever she feels is too big and...
too strong to contain within herself.
Bov. is one of the remedies that has a lot of skin eruptions and sometimes terrible skin eruption with excessive itching.
Which looks like Rhus-t., looks like Anac., like Crot-t. but with tremendous itching.
It's neuro-dermatitis of a type...diffused neurodermatitis in the whole body.
Here it is not mentioned at all, it doesn't matter.
I remember in Athens in '76, I presented a case to the Congress there and they were the famous Pasquero
very famous doctor from Argentina, Ortega, a famous doctor from Mexico, it was from India, Chand was there.
We presented a case of skin eruption.
Again like the other case I told you about Plb., you remember the case I described, this was a woman
of that type, with skin eruption.
I don't know how the 3 of them prescribed Sepia.
I saw this case of Bov. Awkward. She says, 'oh my God, I drop everything, I break everything!'.
They go to wash the dishes and every 3 months she has to buy a new set because the set is gone
then she needs another one. Apis, Nat-m., Bov. are very awkward persons together with the anxiety
you feel they do something but the mind is not there. Is not in what they are doing.
The mind is always in a state of anxiety for no specific reason. I have not been able to say, they have financial problems
or they have anxiety about health problems.
It is a super anxiety.
I remember the first time I met this, the medical doctor who was taking the case called me and said, come there is a case there.
He was overwhelmed himself.
She said, 'Oh Mr.Vithoulkas! I suffer so much!'
You sit back to disconnect and to be able to think, now what is this case? And I don't remember
how my mind went to Bov. and I asked
about the dropping of things and she says,
'I break things and we are poor, we don't have enough money and I break so many things'.
Then I said, what about menses and diarrhea before? 'Oh yes, every time!'.
And then scratching. 'I can't live anymore, I can't stand it.'
That type. If you have this, this is a Bov. case.
A case like that was presented in '76, he says Sepia, Sepia, if one says one remedy then all the other agree.
Shall I take Sepia? Yes, yes take Sepia for a few months before. I was sure Sepia would do nothing.
Because you always think with Homeopathy, I may be doing a mistake, I maybe miscalculating, I maybe misjudging.
The symptoms are so subjective.
You don't see a boil there, 5 cm black, oozing black stuff. You see it is the soul who is oozing, all this pain
the blackness, what is the remedy?
-Anthracinum.
-Yes, very good.
Then this is exuding, this anxiety state.
It says, enlarged feeling, the head feels enlarged or the heart feels enlarged, the whole body feels enlarged
but the idea of enlarge is within the context of what I described to you.
If somebody says, I have a feeling that sometimes my head is big, this is not Bov.
This can be Kali-ars. or other remedies but not Bov. Bov. will not tell you like this.
My head! .... It's different. 'I feel my head is enlarged'. No Bov.
It says I cannot wear a tight. This enlargement, this feeling of expansion.
It is a sub-manic state, I would call it.
And they cannot have tight clothes and they speak a lot and you think of Lach.
But you see this over exciting about this kind of things and then 'can you have tight clothes around your breast?' No.
Actually they will come with very loose clothes.
You know the modern collant is not for Bov. and is not for Lach.
They'll say 'I feel very comfortable with loose clothes'.
Perspiration smells like onion, it is a little symptom that you may be confirming.
It says, as a strange symptom, numbness on the posterior part of tongue.
These kinds of strange symptoms you may get differently, she may not say about the tongue; she may say it
about the root of the nose.
With all this state of anxiety, all this state of excitement and anxiety, put them together and then you will have this.
Bapt. is a remedy that I think Margit is able first hand to describe it because she was on the hospital
in Germany and she was lying there in a state.
She called me on the telephone and I said, take Bapt.
-I got into a state of very high fever, with a terrible diarrhea, I never experienced anything like this...
and you cannot imagine the offensive smell of this diarrhea.  It was horrible!
I got into a really strange state, I thought am I really here, am I there?
Then I was brought to the hospital and they gave me Ph-ac. and it didn't work.
They sent the stool to the laboratory and then I called you, you asked 3 questions and you said, take Bapt. 10M.
Then I got well very soon. Next day the stool was examined and it was typhoid fever and the whole hospital
was a homeopathic hospital and they said how did he know? How did he know, he doesn't even have access here?
But after this, for 4 weeks I was in the strangest state. I felt like I was the earth, the whole planet and everything
which was not right, hurt me, like every street, every car.
I got in such a sensitive state, I was not much myself anymore, strange state really.
-What was the 3 questions?
-You asked, are you exhaustive, is the stool offensive and another question about the stool, if it is watery?
But I think the clue was exhaustion because
Ph-ac. is not exhausted with diarrhea.
It was really a state that you don't know who you are, if you are somebody else. It's very difficult.
I did not have this feeling that I was parted but I had the feeling that...
my soul went away and stood opposite for me and it was very hard on me, it told me all kind of things.
-Your soul?
-It was outside of myself. I had this double feeling.
The soul told me why do you get in such situations, it was outside of myself.
- Margite telephoned and said, 'I have a very high fever and I have diarrhea and I'm exhausted'.
Most probably she described that state in which she was and I felt this kind of fever, has brought about a state
in which you are not anymore present.
You are in a kind of a delusional state.
Once you have a high fever with offensive diarrhea, I asked the diarrhea is offensive?
She says, 'very offensive!',
I said, OK thank you. It's finished.
The moment I get the feeling that she has a high fever, because somebody gets a high fever and feels better than before.
But the Bapt. gets a high fever and then they go into delusions and then she may go almost in half a coma.
That's why you may ask questions, she may answer and then back again into coma.
That is in real typhoid fever where because of these qualities of Bapt.
Bapt. is one of the main remedies for typhoid kind of fevers.
There is another point also.
With the fever there is a brownish, red face with the idea that the person is not there, is not present.
They can describe this, what they call confusion. There is a great confusion which the person has
and cannot come back to himself.
It cannot be absolutely present.
Then this idea comes where he feels scattered. One person may describe it, 'I feel one piece there, one piece there'.
Another person may feel, 'I'm two persons', another person will say, 'my soul is out and my body is here'.
It doesn't matter. High fever with diarrhea which is offensive and that state of mind, this is Bapt.
These are hospital cases. Bapt. are really hospital cases.
That means the person starts with a fever, he will not start on Bapt.
He will start with Bell. he will start with Acon., with Bry. etc. Then the zymotic fever progresses
and that type of fever which is brought about
by typhus then the delusional state comes and then the person
starts going deep into slumber. This is the English word.
When you're dozed heavily. When you cannot wake up.
If they ask you 'what is your name?' and will say, 'George...'. That's a Bapt. case.
You mean you ask just one question, if it is too deep and of course the room smells all together because
all the excretions are offensive but especially the diarrhea.
So high fever, diarrhea offensive and then you have a pneumonia case where the fever continues
you prescribe one remedy after another, the fever continues to be high, there is a time where you see the person
really going into comatose kind of state and you get very afraid and suddenly he has some very offensive diarrhea.
That is a case of Bapt.
The organism cannot tolerate the fever. The fever overwhelms the person and the person goes into coma.
Closes and opens his eyes, if you try to talk to them, they go back into comatose state.
You're having the children, how is called this angina ludovici?
What is a very severe tonsillitis where the children can die; they are different types of tonsillitis.
One tonsillitis is 'ludovici cynanche' is called in Greek.
An angina which is called ludovici angina.
I refresh your allopathic knowledge.
-One question about the typhoid fever. If you have a typhoid without diarrhea, do you give Bapt. as well?
-Yes, I can give as long as there is this type of color in the face, the comatose state and the feeling of being
separated, 'where are my pieces?'
And you will need this in progressed stages of fever, not in the beginning. In the beginning, even if it is Bapt. case
you will not be able to recognize it.
Because unless you have these points, you cannot recognize Bapt. Unless the person says immediately
goes into the mental state of being separated or scattered.
An inner feeling also of restlessness but the tiredness is so much that they cannot move. Just exhaustion.
These children, unless you get the remedy quickly, you better give antibiotics because they will chock up and ...
I have seen two cases in my life. One we managed to cure. The other went to antibiotics.
And the doctor who was attending was not a pediatrician because the doctors see cases in Athens, from old to small.
They are not separating. So he did not recognize the seriousness and by that time they used to give me a paper
in which I prescribed. I would prescribe 60 cases, I read and I prescribe, I read and I prescribe.
And of course I prescribed wrongly and the child came to me and I said, this is not a simple tonsillitis, be careful.
And this case I remember it went to antibiotics finally.
-Do you remember what the angina looked like?
-The problem is that the doctor takes the case, he brings me the paper, so I read the description.
I don't have a direct, so I cannot really tell you. But what is important is that the fever continues to be very high
and continuous, the tonsils are very swollen
and there are lymph nodes around the area
which are growing and you see the child
will go very soon into a comatose state.
This is the time when if you have this idea of scattered ...
The idea of health is, what do they say when they have a health, they say I'm not centered.
What do you mean centered? I am together.
The disease goes to go the opposite way. I'm in pieces and Bapt. has this very strongly.
That means is very seriously ill.
That means death is imminent.
In the death process what happens is actually the disintegration of the soul eventually.
You get  this disintegration of the body
with the soul. They are disintegrated.
The soul goes away, you little ones don't be afraid.
The soul goes out, the mental-emotional goes out and the body disintegrates.
But this fact, this disassociation is a disintegration.
So this disintegration is the idea of death. The idea of death goes into entropy, goes into total entropy.
Then the whole world comes back.
And this disintegration may continue after death, that means your soul, the pieces, the organs of the soul
or the organs of the mind are also disintegrated and going back the way that the organs of the physical body
are going back to minerals and vitamins.
In the same way the disintegration of the soul, unless you have integrated yourself into a being.
Through your evolutionary efforts to evolve as a real human being.
Which is, we come back to the idea of health, love. Love unites, hatred divides.
So you make yourself full of love, you are leaving this body in a unified state and you remain as a human being.
You leave this body full of hatred, then you are going to be divided into pieces.
The Bapt. state, my head is going there, etc...
That is why when the patients are dying, the general idea is bring a priest so he can confess, so the hatred
what he has kept inside, as dividing elements, are out and are gone from the soul.
So the soul can remain united. That's why the dying patient you have to help in this way.
You keep them with their senses alive, with their brain alive, not make them vegetables because once they are
vegetables where is the possibility?
We kept this man 6 months, as vegetable. He has no chance this man in the last transition to do whatever he has to do.
Because by the time one dies, there is the truth. It's finished, that's it, we don't have anymore to go.
So what are you going to do? Then that moment they need to confess. Mothers who hated their children, they apologize
children who hated their mothers, they apologize.
Then there is a kind of release and then the soul goes out more happy.
But in our medical world, they don't pay attention to any of this. They say you make them a vegetable
and we'll see what happens. Maybe
he will survive, maybe he will die.
Most people die in the state of vegetable.
Few survive this vegetable state. And Bapt. is therefore close to death.
You understand you have a Bapt. case, you know death is near. Don't play. Be aware.
The organism reaches to the point of disintegration. You see the idea?
-I thought till now and I heard about acute cases of Bapt. and when you say that this is very close to death
it's looking like to be only for acute and subacute cases.
Do you have the experience also with chronic cases?
- I cannot remember now, I don't have it in my mind. Most probably I have prescribed a few cases
but these cases most usually you will find before getting totally disintegrated in their minds. Before schizophrenia.
You can save certain individuals who are going towards schizophrenia, towards this breaking up.
Once they have this feeling of breaking up in themselves and at the same time there are very offensive discharges.
Maybe this physical symptom: brown strip in center of tongue. Like this.
You get a symptom like this and it may lead you to the idea of Bapt. and curing a severe mental case.
The offensiveness is in all discharges. It's not in diarrhea but in diarrhea, as she said, you cannot imagine
the foullness of the offensiveness of diarrhea.
The offensiveness is the idea of disintegration. When something disintegrates, then it has bad odor.
The same with the soul, when the soul disintegrates.
You will think of Brom. in two pathological cases. One is in respiratory problems, asthma and also when you have
lymph nodes, lymphatic system which is swollen lymphs, which are swollen and hard.
Two characteristics, the one is aggravation when the person is over heated.
Like another remedy, a very well known remedy,
Pulsatilla.
And also a peculiar aggravation is when somebody who is a sailor and lives in the sea, he gets
problem when he comes ashore.
He comes back to his village and the problem starts. Usually is an asthmatic condition.
Brom. also will look like, in respiratory problems, like Ant-t. This has a lot of mucus which cannot come out.
In the hospitals you heard this when there is a
lot of mucus in the chest and there is no power
to bring it out and to clear the lungs.
This rattling stays with the respiration, strong rattling the one that I reproduced.
Eventually I will even die for you to show you. Showing, showing, then finally I will have to show how you die.
Wait until I finish the course, that's all we need. To finish this course, then you die.
It is natural, you see a lot of my students they thought once George has taught us, most probably he will die.
Because I always said, I have a bad health and blah, blah and everyone thought after this course, he is finished.
And this is the ambition of every good student.
The teacher dies so I can become next. No it's OK, I'm just joking, don't worry.
Neither you or me we are going to find the time of death because this is preordained by other forces
which have nothing to do with the jokes.
Brom. patients have something which is between Con. and Puls. You remember Con.? Remember Puls.?
There is something of that type. That means they are hard individuals. They are not flexible.
That's why they have that information, very hard lymphatic node.
You see the people who do not eliminate, who keep inside, the lymphatic system which main function
is to eliminate the toxins, is not able and the person keeps it inside.
Therefore they keep inside the emotions and they become emotionless.
You remember the end stage of Puls. that we have described?
How Puls. they will sit for hours like this not talking, not responding.
You give something to eat.
It's similar this remedy.
And this state will be either coming because of a mental or emotional shock or will be coming as a deterioration of the mind.
The mind becomes slowly more and more deteriorated and then it reaches what today they call Alzheimer's disease.
No emotions; sit there and stare without
any emotions without any thoughts.
Stony hardness, where the brain is full of hard points.
The brain is all the time with this synapses,
with communications, receiving, giving out.
This brain becomes more and more hard, more and more stony.
And if you perceive it, your mind should go. And you ask, show me your tongue.
Sometimes tricks like this, will help. I'm talking about Bapt.
Touch your knee.
Which is the remedy which has cold knees?
Phosphorus.
You see how you remember?