Ant-t. has a lot of similarities with Ant-c.
The only difference is in Ant-c. there is a catarrh of the stomach.
In Ant-t. there is a catarrh of the lungs.
It is the main remedy when there is weakness, catarrh of the lungs,  the lungs are becoming full of mucus
and there is a noise which can be heard by all people around.
Old people who are suffering with chronic bronchitis usually have that. When they come in an exhaustion state
when they approach death...
and you hear a lot of mucus in the lungs and there is no strength to bring it out that is the time for Ant-t.
We have said certain things about Ant-c. and especially the peevishness and this type that we see in Cham.
in Cina, in Calc-p., a similar thing we see with Ant-c. in the children when they have upset stomachs.
The same peevishness the same kind, 'don't come near me, don't touch me!'.
The idea is very strong with Cham., with Arn., with Ant-c. It's also quite strong, not as strong as Ant-c.
but this remedy also has aversion to be touched.
They don't want to be touched, that is an inner state that they don't want somebody very close to them.
They need isolation, they need to be by themselves. It's a suffering person who wants to be by himself.
They can become quite impossible, especially the children they will shout and behave like Cham.
but when the ailment is in the lungs, then you prefer to give Ant-t. especially with asthma children
where they suffer during the night and there is a lot of rattling.
Difficult children with asthmatic conditions, with a lot of rattling  in the night, they will get Ant-t. and they will feel better.
The asthma is a condition, especially when it is established, it is a condition when it will need 2-3 remedies
before you cure the case.
Also when this remedy is indicated, the person wants to vomit in order to bring out the mucus. The mucus has
nothing to do with the vomiting the area is different but still they vomit, they bring out mucus from the chest.
The same thing with Ipecacuanha.
Ip. is very similar to this remedy in asthmatic conditions, especially of the children.
It has strong rattling, nausea but the prostration of this remedy is different.
You see the difficulty. You have a pneumonia case where it has gone a little bit further and the child
is battling with this and then it's prostrated and then 'leave me alone', it's not Bry., it's Ant-t.
They will behave like Bry., they will behave like Cham. but you see the prostration, you hear the rattling
and the tendency to vomit then the remedy is Ant-t.
So with this great accumulation, with great prostration, there is a strong sleepiness of course.
Because the organism is deteriorating and wants to recover.
So what you will see in children especially, you will see children that you don't believe the can sleep with this cough
and they sleep and it continues.
And you don't think that with this cough, this child will sleep and yet it will fall asleep.
You see there are differentiating points which are subtle.
And of course the idea of the sleepiness, while you have this prostration, while you have this cough
while you have this inflammation, there is sleepiness and it says yawning during cough.
Of course it is the desire to sleep which brings the yawning.
The remedy which will be indicated in very young age and very old age.
Ant-t. is given a lot to the children, a lot to the old people.
The old people they say they die either
from bronchitis or from fracture.
They fall down, there is a fracture and eventually from old age.
If they are quite strong. Otherwise they die from heart, cancer and all other. But if they are strong, they will fall down
they will have a fracture or the lungs are the weak point of the old persons and then Ant-t. can give them a lease of life.
It is very interesting how, and we cannot explain it, how a new remedy is coming upon a person.
He has an accident, he has a fear, he has a shock, he has this, he has that and then the picture changes.
Then you have to go, first this picture, then the underlying.
You have to be very careful when you take the case, what happens?
Just because we have this old man and we're talking about, a year and a half ago, he had a vertigo.
He tried to get up from bed and he had very stiff neck as a cervical syndrome and he had vertigo and he fell down.
He asked me to go to see him and he was lying in bed, he was terrified, he was really terrified.
Because his whole family has a history of brain strokes and his father died 72, his sister 74, all the family around 70.
That's why he used to say to me 1 more year, he was terrified of stroke.
Now he had this incident with the vertigo and I gave him Sulph., first remedy, without much taking of the case.
Then I found out that nothing was happening and I waited and he was terrified. I saw his blood pressure
every time I tried to take it, is high. Then I wait, it's coming down.
And then this anxiety and this influence of I'm going to take my blood pressure.
Then I got the idea of Phos.
Once I gave him Phos. then he started feeling better, more important is the next day  he was not as anxious
as he was all these days. I kept him for 2-3 weeks expecting that Sulph. would have some effect. No.
I gave him Phos. the next day he was calmer and a few days later, he came out of his house and he started circulating.
He was terrified with the idea of having a brain stroke.
And vertigo for him was a prodrome for a stroke.
He was terrified and I did not realize and the shock of the vertigo changed the picture.
It brought out a Phos. layer.
In the same way you hit your foot from the bike and you bring a layer, bruises and all that, of Arnica.
In that same way, a mental shock can bring a layer of Ignatia and what we have been talking about
a layer of Aur-m-n. in her case.
You see she has been helped when she was having different elements by Sulph., by Lyc. and Sulph.
Or you have a bronchitis, you may need Ant-t.  And then you go back to Caust.
The problem that you have to be careful is that once you start a case, then all the remedies you are going to give
they have a sequence, they have a logic.
It is not take this, take that, take this, take that. It doesn't do harm but it may confuse you in such a way that finally
you can do find head or tail.
That is the dangerous thing.
You tell me which is the constitutional remedy for yesterday's case, is it Nat-m. or is it Nit-ac. or Ars.?
You cannot say, what is my constitutional remedy. What is the remedy I'm in at the moment.
But tell me your constitutional remedy, so if I tell you what is your constitutional remedy or what I think
is your constitutional remedy you are going to be saved, no.
I may say a remedy that I may see some elements of that remedy but you may need that remedy, third.
You need first another two remedies which I don't realize.
You're treating a person and is extrovert and you may have given Plat. and then suddenly you see this person
closing up without much effect.
Some grief is coming from the past and brings out a Nat-m. layer. Then you have to give it and then maybe
you continue again with Plat. or you give Sepia, whatever.
But if you fix your mind into Plat., like he was saying yesterday and is also the practice of Kunzli.
He is a very good doctor, he died but he followed Kent. He has his own experience.
He said, once you find the remedy keep on giving this remedy to the end of his life and repeat, every day for years.
This is not my experience. Like this man Sulph., Sulph. 17 years but he has strong constitution.
Sulph. and like when he had a bronchitis he needed Bry. and some other remedy, I can't remember now
he had severe cold and went to bronchitis.
Then Sulph. did not help.
Then I had to go to acute remedies to treat the bronchitis.
You cannot say, give Sulph.
Sometimes he will get better in spite of Sulph. or in spite of everything you are doing. That is another thing.
You cannot say because I gave Sulph., he is better.
So we're talking about Arg-met.
Arg-met. and Arg-n. are quite different persons.
Arg-n. is very extroverted, talks, anxieties and all that.
Arg-met. is not anxious, is not extrovert. Actually he is unsocial because of the pains.
You can imagine somebody who is suffering with his joints a lot, rheumatoid arthritis cases, cartilages, mostly affected.
You get the feeling that they want to be by themselves like the Bry. cases.
They are not interested in social, they don't have energy.
Arg-met. is one of the most severe cases of rheumatoid arthritis states with a lot of deformities.
It affects also very much the vocal chords and creates a aphonia, like Phos., Caust., Hep.
But the vocal chords seem to produce nodes, sclerosis. You see the vocal chord if they are looked
they will say that it has calluses, nodes, nodules.
The heart also is affected and will be indicated in cases of acute rheumatism that has affected the heart
and there are easy arrhythmias.
It's a very interesting symptom.
They feel very uncomfortable with this arrhythmia and then they have to sigh and the arrhythmia
goes down for a period of time. A deep sigh which relieves the arrhythmia is Arg-met.
It is very characteristic of Arg-met.
Another characteristic is the jerking on falling asleep. Very strongly, to the extent that they jump
they jerk and the hands go like this.
They wake up. The jerks are very severe jerks.
With Zinc, the other person who is with Zinc, who sleep together, they will tell you how they jerk constantly.
But they don't wake up. These people they jerk violently and they wake up and then they go back to sleep.
The hands go like this as if electricity goes through.
The loss of voice it says here it comes from overuse of the voice but it is not the overuse.
It is when there are nodules in the vocal chords, then mostly are indicated.
Otherwise the loss of voice from singing, talking is more akin to Arg-n. This is more severe loss of voice, more permanent.
And it comes because of some pathology which is there and the pathology is this thickening of the vocal chords
or making nodules in the vocal chords.
And we have also one of the most terrible opthalmias, you know blepharitis, when the lids are inflamed
to the extent that are totally closed and full of pus. The little meibomian glands, which are on the margins
are inflamed and they are full of pus, they are swollen and closing the eyes. They cannot see.
These cases we don't see so much today because immediately the mothers put disinfectants
they put local things and they keep the inflammation on a low level.
One case I gave you to study, this case is taken from old journals. You see how they describe? This is typical.
It is taken from old journals who they have seen these cases. Today is very seldom that you can see such a case
unless there is somebody in a village or people who do not have access so easily to modern medicine.
So the case I gave you is a case of Arg-met.
Who prescribed Arg-met.?
Who put it as a second remedy?
Also this remedy makes the system quite tired and looking much older than his age, worn out individuals
with these constant pains and deformities.
You will need this also when you have an affection on the testes, when the testes are inflammed and swollen
and especially if it is the right testis.
In the book it says, the left ovary, I don't know, maybe.
And when you have that pain, the pain is much worse by the clothing touching the testes.
This touch of the clothing upon the testes makes it very painful.
This was a case I saw in Berlin, that was diagnosed as rheumatoid arthritis in a little child with very deformed knuckles.
Very severe with loss of voice.
The child could not speak almost at all and the diagnosis was rheumatoid arthritis.
It has been to 2 or 3 children hospitals.
I said, no this case is not rheumatoid arthritis, it is a different syndrome it's much more severe case.
I don't agree at all with the diagnosis. The mother was a medical doctor and unfortunately I had to tell this
in front of her and that the child had very little possibility for a cure.
When the mother heard me saying that, that this is rather hereditary genetic disease, it's a new syndrome
I cannot know the syndrome but definitely is a severe case, it's not rheumatoid arthritis.
She took the child to another hospital and finally the child diagnosed as a syndrome which is a deficiency in ceramidase.
It is an enzyme which affects the cartilages very much and affects the voice, exactly the symptomatology of the child.
The fact remains that these children are only a few cases in the whole world so far recorded and the expectancy of life
is very short. They die quite soon.
What I said as a prognosis it was confirmed exactly. It is very difficult thing, when you say they child
has rheumatoid arthritis. With rheumatoid arthritis the child will not die.
When you see rheumatoid arthritis in children, we call it Still disease.
It's the name of a doctor who described this rheumatoid arthritis in children.
The knee becomes so big, the leg is little and the knee is tremendous but they will not die  they can live quite long.
But with this disease they die very soon.
-How are the modalities of arthritis? Because I have a case, Cina, I gave her the wrong remedy but she doesn't have
acute arthritis, she has this deforming arthritis with symptoms of Rhus-t. But it never helped.
And eventually she developed nods on her vocal chord and she often says, it is from over straining.
So she got operated now and she has the same hoarseness. Can it that be Arg-met.
-Yes that's the case. You see if this case now has jerking during sleep, if you ask her specifically, because maybe
they will not say and they say yes jerking during sleep, and if there is any affection on the heart
with heart irregularities and this heart irregularity is better by sighing, it is absolutely.
Actually they are very tired individuals, worn out. When you say worn out, you see the skin and it is the skin
of a much older person.
I remember a case in Berkley. She could not sit on a chair and give me the case, we had to bring a table
and put her down and she was lying and giving the case.
Arum-t., this is another children's remedy.
Arum-t. is one of the remedies you will recognize by looking at the child or the person.
Why? Because all the aggressiveness of the disease seems to be around the mouth and the lips.
The lips are dry and red and cracked, and peeling off.
You have a bronchitis, you have whatever it might be the problem, even colitis but here is affected
the area around the mouth is always affected. And this is how you are guided in this remedy.
And the desire is of the person, to pick on this membranes as they crack and they become a little bit loose
they usually try to get them out and then it becomes more inflamed and more red and painful.
It's bothering them, they need to pick.
It's not a matter just to take it out. No. They pick and the same way children who bore  their fingers into the nose.
The bore them into the nose constantly.
That is an indication for Arum-t.
Also the discharge from the nose is quite acrid, burning and that inflames the upper part, even more
and makes a syndrome which is quite obvious for anybody to see.
And that's why you see the case, it doesn't matter what he may say.
Irresistible desire to bore fingers.
The mental symptoms, I don't know some peculiarity of Arum-t. From grown ups where I have given it
I have not been able. You give it to a case and the person has a character.
You cannot take the characteristics of that person and say, this is it.
Because even if you think so, you go to the next case and you don't see the same characteristics. So forget it.
If you teach especially, you have
to be careful not to give a misinformation.
Because a lot of misinformation is coming today in the teaching of Materia Medica because nobody can really control it.
So if I have a case and I have a character and you show this in her case, her personality, many people
confused it for pathology. It's his/her personality, it's a pathology, they are two different things.
The other one we say Tarent. Do you think by Tarent. she will change her personality? No.
She will just lower a bit the music.
It's not going to change the personality. The personality or the quarrelsome, she may not be quarrelsome
but the tendency when the pathology is there, it will be to jump up and fight.
Also she had symptoms of Caust. and Sulph.
By the way we came back to your case, so is this a case of Aur-m-n. and then Tarent. and then Sulph.?
Is this a case of Aur-m-n. Tarent. and Caust. Is this Aur-m-n., Caust. and then Tarent.?
All these are possibilities, you see?
The main thing is that you have a reason for giving this or that remedy. If in your mind you are confused
you are thinking different remedy, let's give this one, this is not good.
You have to know why you are giving this remedy, why in yourself. You have to have a justification.
I'm giving for this and that reason, OK it doesn't work. Then what do I have to do, the next thing.
Then you know what you are doing. Otherwise you just give remedies, one after another
without knowing what is happening, whether the remedy is affecting or not affecting.
-I just wanted to know, if you ever saw Arum-t. in Kawasaki syndrome because they've got these lips and the lymph nodes.
-I have not seen the exact case but it must be yes. It must be indicated.
You may see this case in children's epidemic, where we have scarlet fever in which again the effect on the lips is obvious.
Again in this remedy you see the hoarseness from overuse of voice, of changing continually
from deep to hoarse uncontrollably.
This remedy will be indicated not in hoarseness from overuse but if there is this change, from one state to the other.
This is the characteristic, not the overuse, the hoarseness from overuse.
Changing of the tone of voice, from one to the other.
This will happen usually in cases of hay fever, allergic conditions that affect the larynx.
It's a kind of laryngitis that comes and goes.
In the Arg-met. the hoarseness is a steady feature and it is progressively worse and worse feature.
So the pathology is different. The underlying pathology is different.
In this course most probably we will not
be able to see the acute remedies so much
unless there are some children they fall sick etc.
There is a question here, when does one prescribes a complementary remedy, under what circumstances
that complementary qualities make it a consideration rather than same or other remedy?
The indications always are the symptoms. And if the symptoms indicate a remedy which in the book it says
is a complementary that is one more confirmation that you can go and give it.
In a case of Staph. who develops symptoms of Caust. you say well symptoms of Caust.
I would prefer to give Caust. than give Phos.
Because Caust. is complementary to Staph. but according to the symptoms always.
It is not a case where you will just go and give a complementary remedy just because it is a complementary remedy.
You never do that. You have the symptoms, you think of this remedy and suddenly you open the book
and you read this is a complementary, OK I'll give it. It's one more confirmation.
If it's not a complementary, do we know that
Nit-ac. is a complementary to Nat-m.? No.
It doesn't matter. She has Nit-ac. symptomatology, we give it.
-I would like to ask about the inimical for instance. It says on Phos. is an inimical to Caust. and Caust.
is an inimical to Phos. What are we doing with it?
-They say inimical because they have similar qualities. To prevent you from prescribing something which
can be similar, it can be quite close, that means it will disturb the case, they say inimical.
What they have observed was that when in a case Phos. was indicated and Caust. was given, what you did
was only to aggravate the case.
Because it was very close, the qualities are close.
The constitution, the make up are quite similar and the Caust. and Phos. they differ only in the...
...degree to which they se injustice.
Phos. will see injustice and will suffer, OK. Caust.  will attack. Phos.  never.
Both they see suffering, Phos. will immediately run to do something, Caust. no.
You have somebody who is sick, he is suffering, it's not so anxious. Phos. is very anxious.
-I wanted to do it in practical because sometimes we have this mistake between Phos. and Caust. So if you give
by mistake Caust. can you give Phos. afterwards?
-Yes sure.
-That's what I wanted to know.
-But if you gave Phos. and is doing well, then you think it is now a case of Caust.  most probably you are making a mistake.
Most probably by giving Caust.  you spoil the case.
-But that doesn't apply to all the remedies that are similar. I heard that Nat-m. and Ign. are very similar
but I never heard that they are inimical.
-They can be yes. When you have given Nat-m. and it has acted very well and then you go and give Ign.
you may aggravate the case.
Unless Ign. is really indicated.
You upset the case and you bring depression again and things like that, you have upset the case.
-I heard that some remedies don't follow well,
like Lyc. doesn't follow well after Sulph.
-This is not my experience. If it indicated, if you have symptoms of Lyc. after Sulph., you can give it.
It was Kent I think who said you start with Sulph., then you go to Calc. and then to Lyc.
So in between Sulph. and Lyc. comes Calc.
These are ideas, maybe Kent was not able to explain everything or was not recorded that in order to
give the sequence you have to have
the symptoms of these remedies.
You don't do it mechanically. You start a case with Sulph., then you follow it with Calc., then with Lyc. No.
You start with Sulph., the person became cold, still the desire for sweets is there, the cold feet and perspiration
yes, Calc. Still the headaches are there.
Then you come to Lyc. where the headache stayed on the right side, the bloatness is there and then
you give it and you complete the picture.
Many times he said that these triple-remedies will be indicated in rotation. You go one time and then you start again
Sulph., Calc., Lyc. But this has to be always according to the symptomatology. You don't do it mechanically.