What is the essence, what is the essential?
We say anemia OK but a lot of remedies have anemia. It's not only Ferr. that we give it in cases of anemia.
What is characteristic of Ferr. in anemia or in Ferr. cases?
-That they look like in spite of the anemia.
-No. Let me say it myself, it's better because we don't have time and people are tired and you want to go for an interval.
You will recognize a case of anemia when the patient will tell you that he has a kind of restlessness
which does not make him happy to lie down.
He is not feeling good lying down.
He needs the restlessness, he needs the movement and he needs especially to walk slowly.
People that get anxious in bed and they have to get up and by walking in the room slowly, then their energy
comes back and their ailments become less.
Why is that?
Because they need to stimulate the
circulation to get more blood to the brain.
I will tell you something which
is characteristic for this remedy.
They need to stretch all the time. It is a
kind of a pump, pumping blood to the head.
These movements give more blood and they feel more at ease. It is a remedy which is also very irritable.
Because they don't have enough energy, they get very easily irritated, they cannot contradict, they cannot fight
they cannot go into such situation that they need stamina.
And they are aggravated a lot by noise and by the slightest noise like another remedy, Asar. and another one, Ther.
So these are the 3 remedies primarily that with the slight noise they are aggravated.
They are people who feel tired and yet there is a redness but a redness which if you look at this redness is not healthy.
It is something that reminds you that the person is rather sick.
It is a redness which is not real red,
a little bit red and then the rest is white, pale.
Can you imagine, paleness with a little bit of rose, not red.
You will see also from people who are using Ferr. in doses because they are anemic, a lot of iron, they cannot tolerate
and immediately they vomit or they have diarrhea.
So Ferr. patients they cannot tolerate the food and they will easily vomit, very soon, after eating.
The food goes down and then it comes up, out again.
Of course in such weakness they are, we see a disturbance of the circulation with irregularities in the heart function.
Vertigo is one of the main themes, especially vertigo which will come from a disturbance of a circulation.
They bend down and they try to get up and there is vertigo.
They rise from the bed, there is vertigo.
It's a characteristic a headache which will come periodically, every 3 weeks, every 4 weeks
but will last for 2 or 3 days constantly.
And during this time, they cannot touch food or drink. During the headache for 2-3 days they cannot.
Because if they do, immediately they will vomit.
So constant headache that comes periodically for 2-3 days, the first remedy we're thinking is Ferr.
Desire for tomatoes is strong and aversion to eggs also is strong and it is characteristic.
Who has aversion to tomato?
I do not remember if I told you so therefore I cannot ask.
Aversion to tomato, very seldom, who has aversion to tomato?
Aversion to tomato, raw tomato?
I don't say the remedy.
I have seen strong aversion to tomato, they cannot touch in Hyos.
Who has aversion to eggs?
-Phos.
-Now is Phos.  Sulph. also. Ferr. and one more remedy?
Caust. no. Caust. has desire for eggs, soft boiled eggs.
Colch. yes, the smell of fish especially.
Aversion is also to Nit-ac. Nit-ac. many times will have aversion eggs, Phos. will have aversion eggs, Sulph.
will have aversion eggs. Ferr. will have aversion eggs.
These are little things, you go to the Repertory and immediately you see it. You don't have to remember by heart.
If you remember it, just your mind goes quickly to these remedies.
You found it? Aversion eggs.
-It says aversion to tomato and aversion eggs.
-But that's the polarity, you have said that one remedy can have the opposite.
-No, Phos. has aversion eggs, not tomatoes.
The addition is with your number.
Maybe. I just talked the last day about these additions. I saw something unbelievable. I saw in this Synthesis
I saw that I'm supposed that I have done a proving on Scorpion, or something like Scorpion, different
than Jeremy did and I have put
symptoms of Scorpion in the Repertory.
I said, when did I do it? In my previous life? I've never done it. So I'm trying to find who is the source
of this misinformation. There is some misinformation going on. I have criticized the way that provings
are done today then most probably somebody with a twisted mind thought OK we'll put this
as George has done a proving also and gave symptoms of Scorpio.
There is another possibility that maybe I read a case or I had a case who had aversion to tomato in the Phos.
which I don't remember. Maybe one case
like this and then they took it from there.
What I know is Hyos. I have seen it repeatedly and I can confirm it. Desire for tomatoes for Ferr. it has to be
really only tomatoes. You eat only
tomatoes. You eat in morning, in breakfast etc.
Who likes tomatoes? Everybody.
So it's not a simple desire for tomatoes.
It has to be really...tomato!.
You say, OK I have a salad of tomato,
I can eat it. Not like that.
The main thing is worse lying down, better sitting, better motion, better stretching. It's like pumping blood into the body.
That is a case of Ferr.
It affects the joints, the shoulder joints but especially Ferr-m. affects the right joint.
Ferr-m., I have confirmed it, it has cured cases of peri-arthritis or arthritis of the right shoulder.
The false plethora, they call it. You see he has some redness, that is not.
Merc-c. will be replacing Merc.  under what circumstances?
It will be similar as Merc.  but there is a difference. What is the difference?
-Burning?
-Not burning.
There is an intensity on the symptoms which is more greater than the Merc. Intensity, the symptoms are very intense.
They are much more dangerous they appear much more dangerous than the Solubilis.
You will get this constant urging for stool and the stool will be with blood.
That means you have ulcerative colitis
of the worst type, with urging all the time.
20-25 stools the day, burning yes, acrid discharges but blood also. It's like burning the mucus membranes.
Like the mucus membranes being burnt out very fast and the ulcers they will spread.
The colitis goes very fast and it's aggressive.
Merc. is a colitis remedy but much
more benign.
This remedy is aggressive.
Which is another remedy we have been
talking about that aggressiveness?
You will see that aggressiveness, that burning also there and this spreading out quickly?
Canth. also will give you this
impression as Merc-c. It's very exploding.
The nervous system becomes very active. That is why there is a tenesmus, the bladder is constantly
needing to urinate but only a few drops. And the stool, you have constant desire for stool and there is
a little bit of stool and a little bit of blood
and then the burning and the pains, and then again
immediately, they cannot leave the toilet. The one crisis comes after another.
Which is another remedy that has
this frequent tenesmus for stool?
Nux-v. It also has this tremendous tenesmus
but not as aggressive as Merc-c.
Merc-c. you see the blood, you see the pain, you see the burning. In Nux-v. it is an irritable colon but not so much.
When you see the blood, when you see the mucus membranes, the mucus in the stool, then you have a case of Merc-c.
Another action of this drug is on mucus membranes.
I have seen one of the worst cases of conjunctivitis.
Conjunctivitis which really can make you almost blind.
It is so painful, so breaking out that only constant cortisone can keep it in bay.
It says acrid lacrimation.
But here the lids are not the main problem. The main problem is the conjunctiva where Arg-met.
mostly the problem is with the inflammation of the lids. Meibomian glands are infected.
And then you get Arg-n. which has this severe conjunctivitis, severe redness on a spot.
You see the eye here.
This is Arg-n.
You get redness like raw meat.
And if it is quite like this, it goes towards Med.
If all this is inflamed, then it goes Merc-c.
You see the difference is that Arg-n. is like this. It's very obvious. This redness is very obvious and limited.
The other is much more defused.
This remedy also we will have excessive salivation, you will get the aphthae which are burning
and you will get
excessive salivation, especially the night.
With Merc., the salivation is mostly in the night while they are sleeping. With this the salivation is day and night.
Also in this Merc-c. you will have, it is not written here, similar impulsiveness to do some damage, to do something violent.
The organism is pushed to react in a violent way.
There is the idea of violence in the organism, the nervous system the way that they perform, the way they speak
the way they do business. There is some kind of violent in the system, in the nervous system.
It can also be affecting the digestive system then the violence goes there.
It's also interesting that once the violence goes all in the digestive system, then the mental or emotional violence reduces.
The effect also in the mucus membranes of the mouth, the gums. The gums get inflamed with aphthae, as I said
with inflammation, with bleeding and with pains which are burning because of the acidity of the discharges.
Therefore this is the remedy par excellence for ulcerative colitis, Crohn's disease, once the disease is really aggressive.
If you give it to an ulcerative colitis which does not have severe burning pains, which does not have this intense
tenesmus it will not have an effect.
The nature of the remedy should be there before it has an effect.