Hyperactivity of the nervous system, especially in feet and brain.
Movement of thoughts, movement
of brains and movement of the feet.
The feet cannot stop moving either in bed or while sitting.
So you will recognize these cases by looking in the feet because they cannot control the feet to just be quiet.
There is over stimulation and the brain also is over stimulated but not in a way like for instance, Verat.
Verat. has some ideas and some thinking or Coff., there is over stimulation.
Here the over stimulation is such as to cause a kind of dissatisfaction in the person.
It is the main remedy for complaining and dissatisfaction.
Restlessness appears on the ending of the nervous system causing especially in the face to do facial ticks.
And twichings on all the body.
Full of twichings.
And the next characteristic is that the moment they go to sleep, there is an electrical stimulation
of the nervous system, if we can say.
The moment they go to sleep, the moment that the mind goes to stop, all this electric charge, which is in the body
comes in the lower extremities and they jerk.
The lower extremities especially jerk.
Arg-met. they also jerk but all the body, hands and feet.
These are the main things that you have to have for a Zinc case.
The spine is like being on fire.
You have the same thing in another remedy.
In Pic-ac also you get this burning in the spine.
It's a remedy that will have these nervous reactions which may lead from simple twitching to convulsions
to epilepsy, after suppression of eruptions or discharges.
Usually with Zinc we see in the history a suppressed eruption and then it comes that stimulation
and the stimulation comes in the brain also.
When they think, they have to move the head.
They think, they are mathematics, you will see constant movement of the head.
They will not talk, they will not express ideas but together with the idea is the movement of the head.
You will see whether they try to control it or not, you will be able to see it.
Women who feel better with the flow. During the flow of the menses, they feel better and worse if the menses are suppressed.
You put a question to him and he will repeat first the question and then he will give you the answer.
That is characteristic.
Women that they have either scanty menses, where they should have more and dissatisfied in sexual matters.
Then they come into a state of constant complaining. Everything is wrong and they have to complain, complain.
In the end, nobody wants to be near them because of this sense of dissatisfaction and complaining.
Poor me, why this happened to me?
It's really like Nit-ac. on the level of health. These people do not have anxiety about their health.
Nit-ac. will complain about their health. Everything is health. Here is complaining about different things in life.
Especially that they are not treated well by others, they are not satisfied with the conditions around them.
Anything they can think about. It's not a matter of real problem. It's a matter of pathology.
Also I have seen it in convulsions, epileptic convulsions if they are exposed to the light.
Children that they will have a fit from exposure to the sun light, they go into a fit.
-Concerning sensitivity to light, is that sensitivity to intermitted light? Like photo sensitivity that is often in epilepsy?
-Not intermitted.
-For instance if you drive a car and there is an alley
with trees and they get intermitted light with flashes.
-No. Maybe it will happen also to that condition but it is light.
When from here he goes out into the light, he gets it. Intermitted also it can happen of course.
-I didn't understand very well what you said
about the spine. The spine is under fire?
-It's a burning feeling in the spine.
-Thank you.
-Zinc is one of the elements which the organism needs, most probably to build up the nervous system
exceptionally the nervous system. And the nervous system gets unsatisfied, I want more Zinc.
....the nerve endings...
-George, in children if they have measles and the eruption doesn't comes out and they say it's dangerous because
it might go to the brain.  Can you give them Zinc. or do you have to wait until it develops?
In order to give Zinc.  you have to have the twichings, some starting of the convulsions or the complaining, the dissatisfaction.
-It's not only when the eruptions starts.
-No because Caust. has that and Sulph. has that and a lot of
other remedies have that.
-What does the hysteria look like during suppression of urination?
-Hysteria with retention or urine. This is one of the strange symptoms. A person who does not urinate
the urine does not come out, then they go into hysteria. But I don't mention these case
just because it's on the third degree and it's alone, we have put it here, as I said.
But who has seen this? You can imagine hysterical reaction.
And there is a suppression of urine, you may be thinking if you just have good memory and you can remember it
and you say, that's very good symptom.
But who will see it, in your whole life?
What you will see is what I described to you and when you see it you have to recognize it.
This is a remedy which is similar to what remedy?
Agar. It's similar to Agar. in the activity of the nervous system, the twichings, the jerkings but Agar. complains
very much about their fear of cancer.
This remedy is much more intense than Agar. in the nervous activity.
Agar. does not have the restlessness of the feet. Here in the Zinc. almost all the cases you will see an activity of the foot.
They will sit there and they will do like this all the time.
-Did you say Zinc has no fears?
-No fears.
-Because we saw this little child from England once that you presented to us and he had the fear
that the world will fall apart.
-That is true but the fear did not go away with Zinc.
-A little remark. There was an epidemic virus in Germany in 1955 and it was found that all the people were
lying in bed and driving bicycle and this
whole epidemic was regulated by Zinc.
-By Zinc? I don't understand, there
was a virus epidemic, like influenza...
-Yes and all the people who got this virus were lying in bed and driving bicycle and it was regulated by Zinc.
-Yes, it's a good expression.
-In every homeopathic book you will see this aggravation by alcohol and especially wine, what happens
with them when they are drinking alcohol
and how often are you seeing this symptom?
-Not often. It's not one of the symptoms that you want to remember as a picture of Zinc.
Ran-b. for instance is sensitive to alcohol, you have to remember that because in headaches it makes them crazy.
Not in Zinc.
The problem with our Materia Medica, especially if we continue to add symptoms the problem will be that
all the remedies will have all the symptoms.
And then we finished. We will start all over again.
Because the moment that you see in all the remedies all the symptoms, how can you differentiate?
So unless you are really able to condense to a few symptoms that give the essential picture, where mostly you see
you will not be able to differentiate.
I can tell you if I take all the Zinc. cases and I write them down with all the symptoms they have I will add 200 symptoms.
But then it will be bad because people will say, this symptom is important, that symptom is important.
No, these symptoms are not important. What is important are these few symptoms that give you the idea of the remedy.
You don't need more.
Now in the Repertories it happens the same thing. They added symptoms which are not reliable.
Adding, adding, adding in the Repertory you will add thousands of symptoms which are not reliable
and the repertorization if you take it seriously, it will give you the wrong remedy eventually.
If we continue adding in the Repertory uncritically symptoms. This is a big problem and that is why in a meeting
that we had here before these seminars we recognized the need to have the Repertory cleaned up
so the symptoms that are in the Repertory they can be reliable.
Anyone wants to add in the Repertory. And they do provings and we discussed the last time about the provings
how they are done. Not reliable at all.
I told you, there was a group of Italian doctors that they wanted to do a proving; so they asked me
will you send us a substance with which
we can make a proving? I said yes.
I telephoned and I said find me the same remedy that Jeremy from England did proving of Hydrogen.
Just send me the same thing. And I told them to take and do a proving with Hydrogen. You will not believe.
They were the control group and then the verum group and the control group produced 15 symptoms
and the verum group produced 17 symptoms. None of these symptoms were similar to 2-3 persons.
One person produced 3, another produced 2 and they had all the symptoms to 17. And all those symptoms to 15.
None of these symptoms we had anything what Jeremy produced in the whole book.
A whole book of symptoms with one dose of Hydrogen 12C.
He gave it to 10 people and all these people, each one of them produced a host of symptoms.
Now these symptoms you take it and you put it in the Repertory. Forget it.
We destroy the science. It's nothing,
it will be reduced to nothing like entropy.
You know entropy, the idea that everything goes into a standstill.
If we continue to do things like that, in order to impress the Community, then eventually we shall destroy Homeopathy.
This is my prediction.
And that's why sometimes when I write I'm a little bit forceful and a little bit caustic.
Unfortunately I feel I have to do it.
Am-c. is a remedy that we use seldom.
It's not a remedy that you will use every day.
But it's a remedy that you will need especially in people who are suffering with the circulatory system and respiratory system.
Heart and lungs are involved with this remedy. This remedy is obese, is weak and it is caustic in its discharges.
Acrid discharges in obese people with
respiratory and problems of heart.
The palpitation is so easy with these people and they want to faint. And lying down makes the heart feel better.
Ferr. will look like this also but lying down makes them feel worse. Ferr. will also have easy palpitation.
They will lie down and the palpitation will be worse. Ferr. are obese people, no stamina, feeling of coldness.
So you will confuse them many times but there is a big difference. Am-c. needs to rest and is better by rest.
Ferr. needs to move slowly about to feel better.
Am-c. you will need it in acute pulmonary edema, where the heart is pumping very fast, where dyspnea is coming.
Where the person is ready to faint or you feel is ready to go into a comatose state and there is difficulty in breathing.
Such people if you can imagine, heart and lung problems, they go to sleep, they sleep in a state of aggravation.
Sleep cannot refresh them.
And they will wake up in the morning with heavy heads. And this remedy will be also confused with Calc.
But it's not as cold as Calc. Calc. is cold and is cold in the extremities; this remedy is cold but mostly aggravated by wet.
You will see the flabbiness, you will see the obesity.
And they have a face which looks like the cortisone face. Do you know the cortisone face?
This white flabbiness and then some redness is there and the dyspnea and the heart is involved.
Then the dischargeS are acrid. The menses are acrid, the stool, the urine, the discharge is acrid.
You see the condition is such, they cannot take any exertion. Any exertion will immediately make the heart pump
very strongly which will remind you of Calc.
Because you see this flabbiness there and you perceive this flabbiness  in the face mostly.
The face looks exactly like
the cortisone face, the victims of cortisone.
And with these patients of course, you will
notice that they get into colds very easily.
The defense mechanism is low and a
common cold will come and again and again.
And you think of Tub. or you think of Psor. because they have this but the appearance of this person
together with the weakness in the heart, weakness in the lungs easy palpitation, exertion palpitation
and this puffiness you have to think of this. Especially when the discharges are acrid.
They will produce a kind of burning.
Another thing which is quite characteristic is diarrhea in the beginning of menses.
With the menses there is diarrhea.
Which are the other remedies we have this?
-Bovista.
What is the difference between Calc. and Am-c.?
Because they both have flabbiness, obesity, worse wet weather, exertion makes them palpitate.
What will be the difference?
In these very symptoms. Now you compare these symptoms only. You don't bring desire sweets
of course Calc. desires eggs, desires sweets. Calc. also is perspiring here, I don't bring these differences.
I talk about this very symptom. You have this symptom and you have to differentiate between Am-c. and Calc.
What will make you decide one for the other?
-The discharges in Am-c. are different from Calc.
-Yes but I don't bring acrid discharges into the picture. I say obesity, flabbiness, palpitation from exertion.
What will be the difference?
-Despair of recovery?
-No. I don't want to bring another symptom.
I want with these 3 symptoms to tell me this is Calc. and this is Am-c.
I've told you already the difference.
-Calc. in the first stage are vital persons and Am-c. have weakness.
-It's more weak and therefore the palpitation will be much more intense. You see Calc. walks like this, nothing will happen.
If you climb up these stairs, this is a test for Calc. You climb up these stairs without palpitation, no Calc.
Every time there is palpitation, this is Calc.
Now Am-c. will have palpitation with the first 5 steps. That's the difference.
The difference is in intensity, the heart cannot take it.
And the second is the puffiness. Calc. is obese but in the face it is compact. Am-c. is not compact
it is pieces of swelled up tissues.
The cortisone face.
These are little things where sometimes you mention a remedy and I say, not at all, forget it.
Because of these little things.
-Can we also use this remedy in cases of disease from heights? When people start having these palpitations?
-Mountaineers disease.
No, I don't think so. Am-c. will not be able to climb.
You have other remedies which are more akin to this disease.
This sentence here expresses it. Constrictions, contractions, congestions are the three words that describe
the essence of Cact.
We will need this remedy in cases of
heart problems, heart infarcts, angina...
...where we have these feelings of constrictions.
The heart is felt as if it is constricted by
some wires, by steel hands.
And the constrictions can be anywhere.
And the feeling is very much but is also really constricted. It's not a feeling, it is also a real constriction.
I remember a case where a problem with a woman it was that she could not be entered by the husband.
Because of that constriction.
And the constriction is such that the husband was feeling it, in the vagina.
It is not an idea, it is a real constriction.
When you have organs which is round like the heart, the constriction is really felt very strongly.
And there is this extension and the constriction which is felt in the heart attack they will say
'I have a constricting pain in the left hand'.
The remedy is Cact. immediately.
And the constriction is very strong,
that's why it says, the patient will cry out.
It is strong constriction.
The constricting pains may be in the vagina, in the uterus, in the abdomen.
And they are connected with menses.
Violent palpitation, worse lying on
left side at approach of menses.
And the sensation of weight in the vertex is rather a congestion which is felt in the vertex.
Somebody was describing this congestion in this class.
When we have congestions, there might be epistaxis at the same time.
A high blood pressure which brings epistaxis and has any constriction somewhere is a case of Cact.
Delusions that the person is racked with wires.
Strong headache and nose bleeding.
The possibility is Cact.
Strong high blood pressure and nose bleeding. The possibility is Cact.
Congestion in the heart, congestion in the lungs and then it is difficult to lie down.
They have to be brought up, sitting with a lot of pillows.
There is an anxiety about their health, a fear of death anxiety to the point of becoming hypochondriacal.
Angina cases with a lot of hypochondriacal symptoms.
I'm dying, together with some constriction, the remedy is Cact.
Dear George please would it be possible to make a differential diagnosis?
-Yes I wish the same. Sometimes we can think about Bell. because there is this congestion
there is a lot of palpitation, even when
they have headaches there is palpitation.
But what I wish to ask you is about the intensity of the symptoms because Bell. is really very very strong.
How can we differentiate when we have these symptoms which are almost the same?
When there is no constriction.
-The Bell. palpitation comes not so much from heart problems. Here we have a heart remedy.
So we go away from Bell.  Bell. will have this pumping mostly with the headaches and with inflammations in general.
Inflammation, that means fever. In this remedy we will not see so much the fever activity.
We will see mostly the weakness of the heart or the action of the heart.
So if you are treating a case with headaches, unless you have congested head, it feels really congested
especially the vertex.
Bell. will be here, activity.
Usually they have the frontal sinuses inflamed, especially the right side and then the headache is here.
With this congestion the head feels congested. The congestion is felt on top. You have this differentiation.
Then the bleeding of the nose is not so frequent with Bell.
If the patient will tell you, I have these congestive headaches with easy bleeding, your mind should go more to Cact. than Bell.
We have other remedies also that congest locally.
One of the remedies we mention in this course...
...is Amyl Nitrate, local congestions.
-Another differential diagnosis might be Lat-m for acute myocardium.
- Lat-m. has the typical heart pain with the extension that goes like this, down.
Lat-m. you will use in typical heart infarcts when the pain extents to the left hand or to the back or both.
Here, in heart infarct you need the constriction.
If you have the constriction, as squeezed really, it's very strong that symptom.
The best for us would be to be able to have all the possible modifications of diseases in remedies
and each individual characteristic, the main characteristic to find it in the remedy.
We are battling today with similar remedies many times because we cannot get exactly the individualized remedy
that this person needs. And so we make concessions. OK I take this or that or instead of this, take that.
Instead of Sep., you give Lil-t., instead of Lil-t., you give Sep.
Because both they have (similar) and the effect is there but maybe we don't have the exact.