Nerve remedy, neuralgias of all types.
And this kind of pain that we see in trigeminal neuralgia where the pain is really nerve pain.
It's not a defused pain, it's along the nerve, you feel it is absolutely an inflammation of the nerve.
Left sided remedy.
it's a remedy also that is connected with problems in the eyes, especially high blood pressure, glaucoma.
The heart many times is involved. You have the pains in the heart very much aggravated.
Also I want to make a point which I have noticed when people say about the heart and they put the hand like this
with Spig. it can be less diffused.
The pain is more like nerve pain and it is aggravated very much by motion.
All angina cases are aggravated by motion, there is no question.
But the intensity that counts. When it's aggravated with the least motion, then it can be Spig.  case.
Also Spig. will show some symptoms of Lach.  Spig.  will be aggravated lying on the left side and the pain
will go upwards towards the carotid artery.
It's a left sided remedy, aggravated lying on left side and the pain like Lach.  from the heart will go up in angina.
Lach.  is very characteristic that the pain goes upwards and many times it constricts the throat.
With this remedy we have worse motion, which is not so much with Lach.
Worse lying on the left side and the pain shoots upwards.
In Spig. also I have seen sometimes extending the pain from the heart to the back and it can also go towards the right side.
A characteristic of Spig. is a pain over the left eye here where it is neuralgic pain extending or radiating
in different parts especially on the back.
Which is very similar with another remedy
in migraines, it's very similar with....
... Bryonia.
Spig. also is very strongly noted for pinworms.
I have not seen it much effective in pinworms situation.
Pinworms are small worms white which they come out .
When you have the high blood pressure, glaucoma, then you have this feeling of pressing on both eyes
is different than the neuralgia, the migraine pain where it's over the left eye, affecting the eye but extending back.
Another great keynote for Spig. is the fear of needles, of pointed things.
Which is the other remedy which has that?
Sil., Hep. also.
Who has fear of needles here?
3-5 persons.
We have to understand the intensity of a symptom because if something which everybody has
the intensity has to be very great in order to take it as a symptom, as I have said many times.
The most failures in prescribing come from the fact that we take a lot of symptoms, as symptoms
when they are not symptoms. A lot of failures come from that.
And then a lot of success comes when you pick up one or two keynotes and you prescribe.
-Could you please describe the fear of Spig. a little more in detail, what do they do when they are confronted
with needle? Do they get paralyzed, how do they react?
-No, neither freeze nor paralyze. They just say, I can't have an injection. They will try to avoid an injection at all costs.
If you threaten them with a pin of course they will react very much but it's not normal that they will be threatened.
So they live with this fear, no problem.
The moment the doctor comes and prepares the thing, he says, no, no, I cannot have it.
They will react more and more depending on their personality whether they will kick the doctor finally or not.
If they say, I have a fear but I can overcome it, this is not a symptom for Spig. or for Sil. or for Hep.
I have been described with Hep. a man in the army, sitting and they had the needle, giving vaccination
and they were undressed, one after
the other, they give the vaccination, they go.
He says, 'this is in front of me, I see the front man getting the needle and I collapsed'.
He collapsed before the needle was touching him.
But that kind of reaction it may be with Sil. as well or it might be with Spig. but the idea is that the person will tell you
'I don't like needles, I'm afraid of needles'. That is enough.
There are certain symptoms which we have differential points, not in all symptoms.
Desires warm drinks, it's another strong symptom. Aversion coffee, who has aversion coffee?
Who likes coffee?
So if you take as a symptom desire for coffee, forget it. Where is it going to lead you?
Many times I have been told desire for coffee, I ignore it. Aversion to coffee yes, worse from coffee yes.
-I would like to know which are the main remedies for occiput headache which extends to the forehead
and the opposite direction as Spig.
-The opposite direction as Spig. is Sang. but it's on the right side.
Camph. is an interesting remedy but difficult to be recognized unless you have an acute case where you have
a lot of diarrhea and vomiting and collapse and anxiety, restlessness, coldness internal, external.
Hahnemann was prescribing it for cholera because we have not seen cholera. Has anybody seen cholera?
Where, in which country?
In Nicaragua. Who else has seen cholera case?
Where? In Morocco.
Did you see it in the hospital?
You were a doctor there? No. Who has seen it as a doctor?
Can you describe the case that you have seen?
-I've seen a lot of cases of cholera, easy cases and very difficult, severe cases of cholera.
I don't know what you want me to describe.
-The severe case.
-The severe cases I have seen started suddenly with sudden, very strong diarrhea, watery diarrhea
nausea and vomiting and absolute weakness.
Very strong weakness, sometimes half an hour or one hour after the diarrhea it starts, they can't move
from one side to the other and the problem is they can't keep any water. As soon as they drink water, they vomit.
Immediately they dehydrate and they will die.
-The outside coldness?
-Yes they are freezing.
-Of course these cases we see can be similar to this kind of cases, not exact fortunately because in case you have
such a case, real case of cholera, then of course you know that you have immediately give infusion and then give Camph.
Which is the other remedy which has similar picture of that kind of collapse, diarrhea, vomiting?
Verat., very good.
And the peculiar thing is while the surface is cold, she wants the covers off. That is only Camph.
If you get this, external coldness, you touch and it is like metal. And yet they want the cover off.
Also here the sudenness of the appearance and the intensity. This is a remedy that develops very fast its pathology
when it concerns with the digestive system.
And you go almost into a state of collapse, the patient you will see, cold, cold, uncovered and thirst, anxious
restless and then collapsing.
Thinking of complains ameliorates, is a
very peculiar symptom that if you get it...
usually thinking of complains, aggravates.
During the peak of the acute, she may be making noises.
This kind of things which indicate that she needs help.
What remedy is this sneezing, very strong sneezing?
Sabadilla.
Sensitive to sunlight is quite strong keynote. You get sunlight eruptions and Camph. is one of the remedies
that you have to take into consideration.
Which are the other remedies?
Getting sun eruptions is a special pathology, I think of the liver, which produces eruptions with the exposure to the sun.
Camph. is one of the main remedies that you have to think of that.
When a person tells you that I get skin eruptions, wherever I'm exposed to the sun.
The remedies which are worse with the sun
are mostly the Nat-m., the Bell., Glon., Puls.
Was anybody here in Alonissos when we
treated a retarded child with epilepsy?
A retarded child with epilepsy, a child which was about 4 years old, he was totally paralyzed
no contact at all with the environment.
The mother, the father would talk but he had no contact with anybody.
Strabismus is usual characteristic of this remedy and what is the characteristic is frightful distortion of the face
this is what characterizes the nervous activity on the face, especially during convulsions, during epileptic fits
they are terrible to look.
So retardation, childish, it behaves like a child, with strabismus: Cic.
Behaves like a child without strabismus?
Bar-c.
Behaves in a violent manner with
strabismus then the remedy is Stram.
Violent distortions of the face with opisthotonos, Cic.
All epileptic fits have some distortion of the face. But there are some grades in this distortion.
This remedy has frightful distortion. You think
that the face is like grand guignol.
You know the grand guignol pictures we see with the distorted faces? That gives you the impression with the Cic.
There are cases actually that you will see in epilepsy or you may see suddenly in children, in the hospital
when you are in the hospital and you need that remedy.
Especially when there is this strabismus.
If you don't have so much distortions and you see this opisthotonos, in convulsions or epilepsy you will think of....
...Strychninum.
It is a remedy that sometimes will be treating convulsions after concussions in the head.
Post traumatic epilepsy.
Answers abruptly, you have to connect it
with the idea of not fully developed.
The way that they will answer is pathological, it's not answer abruptly in a normally developed person.
Moaning and groaning during sleep, shrieking and shouting before convulsions, that' s a good symptom.
In these remedies you will just need the idea of the remedy. Otherwise you may never need this remedy in your practice
unless you are in a psychiatric ward or working with epileptic children.
But a normal homeopath very seldom will need this remedy.
Retardation of whatever reason always gives the idea of Cic.
Dig. Jaundice with heart involvement,
this is what you have to remember.
What is the heart involvement? The heart rate goes down tremendously 42,45,48 this is called bradycardia.
Whenever you see strong bradycardia
the first remedy you are thinking is Dig.
People who have an effect on the stomach where they feel nauseous the stomach feels empty
and the stomach is a sensitive point in the organism.
Anguish with nausea, anxiety from
motion, a great fear of heart attacks.
They don't want to move in case the heart
will stop, which is the opposite with Gels.
Gels. feel unless they move, the heart will stop.
Slow pulse, it should be written with number 24 letters, that means huge letters like this.
Bradycardia is the main... Dig., I have never
given it where the heart rate was over 65.
It has to be low, under 50 is the best if you get it.
Actually in research I have suggested that there is a possibility for us giving a remedy to show the effect
of high potency in bradycardias.
You get under 50 in a hospital and you agree with the chief of the hospital to give every time you get a patient
with heart rate under 50, you agree to give a dose of 200.
Dig. 200 and see within a few hours the pulse rate.
This is an easy research that will show the effect not curing all the cases, some cases will be cured.
But definitely Dig. will raise up the pulse rate.
So you have the weakness on the stomach, the weakness in the heart the nausea, the anxiety  which hits the stomach
and every stress hits the stomach which is similar in a way to.. what is the remedy which is very sensitive
to the stomach area?
Nat-c. and also Kali-c. yes. What Kali-c. has?
Fear arising from the stomach.
Like which other remedy?
Mezereum.
Tremendous fear arising from the stomach.
But when we talk about pathology of the stomach, that means you have gastritis, duodenal ulcer
you have cancer, we're thinking of Ant-c.
Ant-c. is one of the main remedies that affects the stomach.
Anxiety which is felt mostly in the stomach...
...this is a keynote of Ars.
Dyspnea with constant desire to breathe deeply.
You will see an individual anyhow who has really a weak heart.
Weak heart, weak stomach, jaundice.
This remedy will be indicated many times in severe cases of jaundice.
When you have the nausea, you have the slow pulse and you have the anxiety that the heart will stop.
Mez. is a remedy of the skin, one of the most aggressive and malignant skin eruptions.
When we say malignant, I mean malignant.
I had to prescribe this remedy in a case that came out of the hospital, 25 years with skin eruptions but what kind?
I had no experience, she was bandaged all over.
She has just come out of the hospital without any effect, they said we can do nothing.
And then she wanted to show me and she uncovered the legs.
My God, I wanted to throw up, it was terrible!
It was thick cracking, oozing underneath, a green yellowish stuff and it was terrible to look.
She said, do you want me to uncover this? I said, no that's enough.
Otherwise you have to give me a remedy.
Mez. generalizes its action. It is in the face, it is in the lids, it's in the eyebrows, in the neck and the itching
the scratching, the suffering is tremendous. But mostly what you will see or you will differentiate is the thickening of the skin.
It makes the skin thick and cracks and peels off.
Mentally they do not have stamina. They
do not understand, they do not perceive.
They seem to be in a state of constant confusion.
There is a great sensitivity on the scalp also.
The scalp has a great sensitivity and if you just touch the hair, the head, it's very painful.
Leather like thick crusts, hair stick together.
it's a chilly person aggravated by cold and there is a great desire for fat.
They like fat in the same way like
Hep., Sulph. and Nit-ac.
Sudden pains followed by chilliness also is a keynote.
The chilliness they describe is very deep to the bones.
They say I feel cold in my bones, this is an expression which they use many times.
It looks like Graph. very much but you will
see the desire of Graph. is not for fat.
We have aversion to sweets and
aversion to salt, and desire for chicken.
Also in Graph., as we said, there is this discharge like honey, this is typical.
-I've been giving Mez. 3 times for a state after they needed Hyper. much earlier, in traumas of the spine and the back region.
Skin eruptions 15 years, 3 years., 7 years after such accident. All of them got skin eruptions, the child
and the grown ups and all went much better.
-After accident where the spine was injured and then they developed skin eruptions.
-Yes, much later.
-I do not know that, I have not seen it but it's interesting what you say. You have seen 3 cases like that?
-Yes.
-Very good. Mez. worked in the 3 cases?
-I don't work for such a long time, the child is 2 years now and went away but it was not the constitutional remedy.
She has been needing Tub. after that. And the grown ups, one has been needing Sep. but she never came back
and one woman had terrible, horrible itching for 7 years and as a young girl she had this bike accident.
Later on she needed Sepia.
-I'm not sure you can connect it
with a trauma or it was accidental.
-Can we ask one more question about the remedies you just discussed?
What's the difference between anxiety arising from the stomach and anxiety felt in the stomach?
-The anxiety in Mez., which we said, we're talking about anxiety together with fear of dying.
An anxiety together with fear of dying, that's something difficult to describe.
Definitely they will point out that the anxiety comes from the stomach and rises and overwhelms
the whole person and the feeling is, they are going to die.
Actually in the case which I described to you, this is an anecdote,  I gave a remedy and as you know
I was working in South Africa, in construction business and the next morning, they were calling me after the Mez. 200
in this woman, because she thought she was dying. They could not get me of course on the telephone
because I was not at home, I was at my work. Fortunately I was not there and it was a proving of Mez.
and a very good sign that the remedy was dead right.
It created exactly that anxiety and when the evening I came back  when they could get me, the anxiety was over of course.
This woman got a new skin in 45 days.
She got a new skin the whole body. She was terrible, 25 years in the hospital and after a few months
believing then that this whole thing has gone, the poor husband brought me an envelope about that thick with notes
of South African money and he said 'I would like to give this to you'. I looked I just saw how thick it was, just the notes
and I said, forget it, take it back.
He said, 'this is nothing what I give you. We are not believing, we are outcasts for 25 years, for the first time
in our lives we can go out, we can enjoy, we went to the cinema.
And you have freed my life, that's why I give you this money'. I still said, no. He said, you have to take it.
I said, no I don't take money, I work in another work. He pressurized me, in the end he said, buy books.
I said, I have all the books I need, I don't need the money.
Of course I didn't use to take any money all these years and now I take money from the rich people only.
If I know they are rich, I will accept. If they don't forget it, you cannot persuade me.
Mez. 200 one time, I didn't dare to repeat it, not just because of reading Kent and all that but also because of the reaction.
He said in the evening, 'we have been trying to find you all the time because we thought she was dying
that was the end'. Finished. The woman was lying down, having all this anxiety feeling
she said it came from the stomach. She described exactly how it is.
This is one of the very first cases I treated. About 3 months after, I started reading Homeopathy.
And they say, Kent said, if you see a mental symptom arising after your remedy, you suppressed it
and things like that. Then of course I had palpitations because I didn't know whether there was a suppression.
Later on, what I'm teaching you now and I found out it was not like that. When you have a keynote symptom of a remedy
appearing after your prescription, this is almost
a sure sign that your remedy was correct.
Even if it's a mental symptom.
A lot of things have changed.
Also the skin looks raw because usually they have to keep the skin clean by different ointments
they put and it looks raw.
You see all this neuro dermatitis which is burning and it's scratching the whole night, they can go on scratching.
It's terrible situation.
I remember a German woman, she has been treated with Homeopathy for years in this condition. Forget it, nothing.
Only Mez. helped.