Sul-ac. is a remedy when you will see a case where the main complain is exhaustion and at the same time
a feeling of hurriedness inside.
They have to do things very fast.
There is not enough time for anything and at the same time exhaustion. And at the same time they cannot finish anything.
And at the same time they get irritable and excited because they cannot do enough.
It's a remedy that you will need in cases of asthma, when the asthma is always worse in city pollution.
With the pollution of the city, they get much worse. They say, 'it's terrible, it kills me to go to the city'
then most probably that is a case of Sul-ac.
I want to give you an idea of Sul-ac. hurriedness. We have this hurriedness in other medicines like...
Tarent.  it's the main remedy for hurriedness. In Tarent. very seldom you will see tired and hurried.
You will see a lot of energy and a lot of activity and very busy all the time.
Doing things all the time, performing 7 tasks at the same time, a lot of energy, so you cannot confuse them.
When you see these remedies in the Repertory, they look the same but actually in effect there is no comparison.
There is no way of confusing these two remedies.
... one who feels exhausted and tired and still
the hurriedness feeling will not leave them.
I had once a case when he told me
'I'll just give you an example' he says.
'I will give you an example how hurried I am. I go to the toilet'... and you flush after you have urinated or stool.
He says, 'I pull it first and the I urinate'.
This is characteristic, the hurriedness is such he has to perform, he has to do, he has to finish but does not have the time...
I remember another case where he has come to my office and he was so much in a hurry, perspiring
and he sat down, he gave me a few of his symptoms, very much in a hurry and before I was able to say anything
he picked up his suitcase
and he wanted to leave.
Wait a moment, the consultation is not over, I didn't tell you anything, I didn't ask you any question.
These are extreme examples but they show
the hurriedness, there is no time to lose.
Then there is this very characteristic sensation, as if the brain was loose, as if there is a place within the head
where it is empty. So if they do like this,
they feel the brain goes towards this side.
They go like this the brain goes on the other side. They feel the brain is moving in the same way, as the head moves.
Like Sulph., they are people who would like stimulants to be able to perform, like alcohol, like sweets.
If you compare the hurriedness in the Repertory, you will see Med. is very much in a hurry, Natr-m. is very much in a hurry,
Caust. is very much in a hurry but there are no other remedies which are so much in a hurry as Tarent. and Sul-ac.
Sul-ac. also in the way they eat, it is very fast. They gulp their food. They feel others also should do quickly
like Tarent. but if this is strong the person says,
'I like others to do quickly, otherwise I will hit them'.
This is not Sul-ac., this is Tarent. But if they say, 'I like people to do fast their work', it's a matter of intensity
in order to differentiate between Sul-ac. and Tarent.
They don't like water but if they
add some brandy, then it's OK.
Excessive perspiration.
You will get the feeling sometimes they are like Tub. because there is an excitable element in Sul-ac.
And the perspiration is very strong. And there is a kind of sourish perspiration like Rheum, like Hep., like Calc.
Sul-ac. is a remedy that you will
need in digestive problems.
Mostly, primarily is the respiratory and then
the second in intensity is the digestive tract.
The digestive tract can be affected and
you have gastritis, you have colitis...
...but without the feeling of hurriedness which is the main component of the mental-emotional structure of this remedy
...forget Sul-ac.
Another thing which you may find in the
digestive tract, is ulcers on the mouth, aphae.
The whole gastro-intestinal tract painful often, ecchymosis also is very characteristic.
Diarrhea which is like the Sulph. diarrhea
and you know the Sul-ac. smell.
Smells like the septic tank.
Spoiled eggs also.
Eructations which smell like spoiled eggs, diarrhea which smell like Sul-ac. Sul-ac. is characteristic.
These are the characteristics of Sul-ac.
-Could you say something about
the difference with Arg-n.?
-No, you cannot confuse these two remedies.
Arg-n. is not in a hurry in that way at all, it's a remedy which is very vital, a lot of energy, extroverts.
These people they are not extroverts, they are concentrated upon their particular anxiety.
'I have to do, I have to do quickly things!'.
This is the main anxiety which is revolving around in this remedy, there is no the idea of Arg-n. which is
if they do have anxiety, it's an anxiety concerning their health primarily. These people do not develop fears.
If you get a fear with Sul-ac., that fear most probably will belong to the next remedy.
Arg-n. is full of fears.
We see some characteristic like the perspiration, which is smelly and the diarrhea which is similar to Sulph.
and we see the desire for sweets and alcohol which we see in Sulph.
Sulph. also is very much in a hurry, the anxiety is there but when you compare the anxiety of Sulph.
you will see that it revolves around his health more and the Sul-ac., no. The Sul-ac. he will come to you
he will need a consultation but, as I said, it's not important. What is important to tell you very quickly.
I was amazed, he told me all these in one stretch.
And then he was picking up his bag and
he was collecting his things to go away!
This you will not see in other remedies.
If you think about the remedy or if you know the remedy, you will give it. If you don't know...
I'm talking about 1968 or 69, back a long time.
Anyhow I gave you the essence.
-Question concerning the language. Is the language fast too or do they stumble over their own words?
Are they hasty?
-The way they speak is very hasty but the articulation, as far as I know and I can remember the cases
they have no problem.
They are not stammering.
In Benz-ac. we have two areas of concentration of the problem. One is the kidneys and the characteristic is
a very heavy smell of urine.
Kidneys are affected with a
very strong smell of urine.
The other place of action are the joints.
Inflammation of the joints which can
end up having problems in the heart.
You get a history of gonorrhea. The gonorrhea is treated and then you get a history of arthritic conditions
which change place, from one arthrosis to the other. And eventually it settles in the heart.
This whole syndrome should bring to
the mind Benz-ac., except of Med.
Heart symptoms alternate with kidney problems.
You see the preference of this remedy
between kidneys, joints and the heart.
These remedies are prescribed mostly on this kind of pathology. Heavy urine, very strong color, very smelly
and the strange thing is when the problems have gone to the heart, the urine is nice and clear.
The aggravations are in the same ranges,
with most of the rheumatic, arthritic remedies.
Cold, wet, change of weather makes
the pains and the joints worse.
Trembling in the left side of the lumbar
region is an interesting symptom.
I have heard this one time only but it's very strange symptom and you think of this remedy.
The mental symptoms are something
like Nat-m. symptoms.
These are people who are affected in their kidneys, seem to be holding emotions and not expressing emotions.
They are holding emotions concerning
mostly the sexual sphere.
They don't express their sexuality and emotionality.
Persistent disagreeable thoughts and then eventually when it comes, forgetful of words.
In a progress state where you have
deterioration of the mental level.
Fear of becoming deformed.
They don't like to see also people who are deformed, which is like which other remedy?
Which is the remedy they don't
like to see deformed people?
Calcareas, they don't like to see
deformed people, they don't like ....
Fear that they have been followed
is a symptom of Med.
And if there is the gonorrhea and if there
is this fear, how you will differentiate?
The urine. If the urine is heavy
and smelly, yes exactly.
Simple things. Keep Homeopathy
simple and down to earth.
Med. has a fear somebody is following, especially in the night. The same thing you will have with Benz-ac.
When you have a case of gonorrhea where the person is developing symptoms from his kidneys or from his joints
then you will have a problem to
differentiate between Med. and Benz-ac.
If he tells you that the urine smells heavy, immediately goes towards Benz-ac.
Also a very grand characteristic of Med.
is, in the night feels better.
You go to main characteristics of the remedy, when you try to differentiate and then you see which one
is clear and which one is strong. Clear and strong, you push the case towards that direction.
How can you remember? You may not remember but you go to the Repertory and you see in the Repertory
and then you see the differentiation.
When you are learning Homeopathy in the beginning, we give you a structure how to take a case.
And we say, you take everything, two hours, three hours, four hours taking of the case.
I had one doctor in the center in Athens, she never went down from 3 hours. From 3-4-5 hours to take a case.
That's OK but taking all these details it's not going to clear up the case; it's going to make it really more confused.
Because can you imagine in 5 hours
how many symptoms a person can relate?
You ask a question, 'do you have that?', 'Yes I have that also'. So in the end, you don't know where you are.
Then somebody else comes and puts two basic questions, differentiate and says, this is the remedy, proceed.
This is what we're aiming at, trying to get what is essential in the patient and what is essential in the remedy.
Joints affected, swell, changing places, urine smelly...
That is why some people they make
beautiful prescriptions and very quickly.
Of course in the beginning you take the case, you take this, you take that, you go to the Repertory and you struggle.
But eventually you see more and more. And
what we're doing here is, we come to the basics.
You don't have to remember more than these ones.
You remember Benz-ac. has some problems in mental, is hypochondriac, is somebody who has some fears.
What fears? I remember something like Med. This is how you work; otherwise you will be lost.
Many times even difficult cases, because here all the cases we see are difficult cases, there is no question.
And many times when they sit there after 3,4,5 symptoms, I have an idea. I say most probably this is the remedy.
Of course I don't stop, I investigate
because we have to do it properly.
But in actual practice, when you are very busy and they telephone every 3 min. there is a telephone call
by somebody else and the patients are getting more and more, then you have to have this information
the basic information.
I have done miraculous cures which I don't remember at all. The patient comes and says, 'do you remember me?'
'No, I don't remember you'. 'You prescribed for me 20 years ago' and I can't remember where it was, why?
Because it was 2,3 symptoms on the
telephone and I said, take this remedy.
I remember one time I was struggling with a case of duodenal ulcer and I had given Nux-v. and Ant-c. etc.
One day this man who was a scientist, he telephoned me and says,' I have a meeting in the school
I go as a parent and I cannot face it, I'm trembling'. 'I said what? You cannot face it? How come?'
He says, 'all my life when I have to do
this in a meeting it is not possible'.
'OK, take a dose of Gels.  just before you go there'.
Next time he comes, he says 'for the
first time my stomach is very good'.
Because this remedy was not Nux-v., was not Nit-ac., was not all these nonsense I was prescribing, it was Gels.
Since then, I just saw him the other day, I said never again you had the problem? He said never again.
And I'm talking about 1969 or 70.
And it was this information, he said 'I can't face, I will be trembling because I'm going to speak in front of 10-15 people'
the parents of the class of his boy.
Because this is the essence of the whole thing which I had not taken into consideration, he never thought of
mentioning to me.
Symptoms tend to fluctuate according to the fluctuation of the urine. That is what I explained to you.
You get a relief of the physical symptoms, the pains, the swellings and the urine is heavy.
You get clear urine and the symptoms are...
That fluctuation indicates the remedy.
The patient will say, \when I have a clear urine,
I don't feel well'. And this is the idea.
The preference of this remedy
to cure suppressed gonorrhea.
After suppressed gonorrhea
there is hemorrhoids, fistulas.
Dribbling of urine in old men
with enlarged prostate.
If you take that symptom of course
you will find it in 55 remedies.
What you have to have is the original things we said about this Benz-ac. in order to prescribe.
You don't prescribe Benz-ac. because there is dribbling of urine in enlarged prostate because we have
a lot of other remedies, which have that symptom.
Involuntary biting of lower lip,
that's something which is peculiar.
Headaches of rheumatic origin alternate or accompanied by rheumatic conditions.
You see how we stress the idea of smelly urine.
Every symptom we say but it has to have urine which is very strong in odor, very heavy in color.
This remedy you will meet in cases
where they belong to the first group.
People who get gonorrhea belong to the first group. They are strong constitutions, otherwise they don't get gonorrhea.
They get gonorrhea and then the gonorrhea is not going right through to the mental to produce the anxiety
and to produce the hurried feelings and all that but it goes into the joints, it is a strong organism who can do that.
And you have to be careful, not simply offensive urine, it has to be heavy in color, very dark yellow.
And if you let the urine, the urine will settle
down and will have some sediments.