Sang. is an excitable person.
With a specific sensitivity towards the wet weather.
Wet weather aggravates all her symptoms. If she has a headache, it makes it worse. If she has an anxiety,  it makes it worse.
If she has a dull mind, this becomes almost like a torpor. She just can't think in wet weather.
So it's a remedy which very is strongly aggravates by wet weather.
It's a remedy which primarily will have an affection on the right side of the body and it's a remedy
for headaches which are situated on the right side of the head. Especially when the headaches start
from the right occipital protuberance, the headache starts from here and goes over to the eye.
The headaches are very strong, the inflammations which are produced in this remedy are very strong
and remind one of Bell.
But the great modality for Sang. is the nausea and the vomiting.
Almost all her ailments are accompanied by nausea which change up in vomiting.
There is a climax. If you see a Sang. headache, you will see the person is almost in a torpor.
The head is so painful and it goes higher and higher and higher.
The moment that the headache starts going up, the nausea comes up.
Then during the high peak of the headache, the person will go to vomit 1 time, 2-3 times, then with the vomiting
you will see a release.
Another thing which will make you look is sanguine. Sanguine is red. It means red in Latin.
So red cheeks like Bell.
And it is a remedy that you will need very frequently in right shoulder joint arthritis which is tremendously painful.
The arm almost becomes immovable. You have given different remedies and the arm less and less moves
until it is almost ankylosed.
It's very painful especially in bed. Once they lie down, the pain becomes excruciating and it can continue the whole night.
So if somebody says, right sided inflammation on the shoulder joint, worse in the night, the first remedy you think is Sang.
Also in their headaches are sensitive to light, sensitive to odors; odors will make them vomit.
They have an anxiety which rises and then they enter a place where there is some odor and the nausea comes
and they even have to vomit from odors.
It doesn't have to be a bad odor.
They have asthmatic conditions which are aggravated very much by any kind of odor.
Light also aggravates them. Wet weather very much.
Inflammation of the joints, especially of the right shoulder joint, in wet climates.
They go and visit a wet climate and then the inflammation starts.
Warm and wet it can be or cold and wet, as long as wet it's bad for Sang. This weather now here is a wet weather.
So if any of you fell down with this arthritis or periarthritis, it's the same, on the right shoulder.
Especially they can do this movement. It's totally impossible to do. To raise their arm it will go like this.
They cannot comb.
Then eventually the inflammation becomes more and more and it can be very severe.
But all their symptomatology is accompanied by nausea. Sadness, anxiety, fears accompanied by nausea.
When you hear this modality, headache accompanied by nausea and vomiting, when the vomiting comes
that is the 'lysis', the crisis is finished through vomiting.
Hay fever with sensitivity to odors.
And there is a peculiar keynote, for instance coughing which is ameliorated by passing flatus.
This is a very peculiar symptom. If you get it you grab it.
Coughing ameliorated by flatus.
Vomiting ameliorates headaches very strongly. You get a headache and they go crazy.
That remedy is one of the main remedies that in wet weather they become paralyzed.
The mind does not function, nothing functions and then the pain starts.
That's it. You don't have anything more.
With sexuality, they are people with excessive sexuality, with some eccentricity. Eccentric people
and also affected very much, especially men but women also, after sex. Very tired, finished, after sexual orgasm.
-When you have the shoulder pain, do you have any headache at all?
-When you have the shoulder pain is not together with headaches.
The headache is tremendous. It starts here, it goes over here to the eye and then no light, no smell, any smell
any light, any noise makes it much worse
and then the nausea comes, lying down.
They can lie for hours, for two days like this.
-And the redness of the cheek? With the shoulder I mean, does it have to be there?
-No, it doesn't have to be. If they say, I'm worse as soon as I'm going to bed and I suffer all night, as long as
I'm lying down, that is Sang.
You ask her whether she can put behind this, whether she can do that, she says impossible.
Raise your arm, nothing.
-I have a patient with the right sided shoulder pain and this patient tells me that she feels exhausted
when the weather is cloudy. Is that?
-That's it. Cloudy weather and at the moment the weather becomes cloudy and wet, she starts having headaches
pains, cannot think, cannot concentrate. Otherwise they are fast, they get ideas, they are excitable.
Nausea and vomiting especially with the headache, not necessarily with the shoulder. When I say anxiety
which is accompanied by nausea, they get the anxiety and then the nausea, your mind should go to Sang.
Valer. is a woman's remedy, as you can see, very seldom you give it to a man. Men are not hysterical.
Do even men get hysteria? Never. It's a woman's disease.
Hysterical, nervous temperament, oversensitiveness of all senses.
You see this restlessness, this hysteria, crying and laughing, changing symptoms.
A person who is very nervous and restless
and irritable and acting hysterically.
Then next day she is suffering with her stomach, she is suffering with some physical ailments.
And they alternate between mental symptoms, emotional symptoms and physical symptoms.
Sensation as if a thread hanging down the throat.
Sensation of a hair is Kali-bi. and Sil., sensation of a thread, Valer.
You know Sil. have all the time a sense that a hair has stuck in the mouth.
So they clean the tongue all the time and the same with Kali-bi.
Now with this remedy there is another hysterical symptom, they feel something is hanging over, a kind of
a string is hanging in the throat.
It can be the cause for them to feel that I have cancer. This sensation may give them the idea that they may have cancer.
They have symptoms like Rhus-t. where the pains can develop or the sciatica can develop during rest
and the sciatica is better on motion.
They have this feeling of Lac-c. and Lach. as if floating in the air.
It's a remedy which you need very very
seldom also. It's not an everyday remedy.
Because in the Repertory you will find a lot of symptoms in the sciatica section and lumbar region with Valer.
which do not work. You take the symptoms,
you repertorize, Valer. has never worked.
Unless you have this hysteria behind the patient.
The symptoms actually of Valer. are not easy to pin down because what we see in symptomatology...
pains and cramps come in different locations all these there are a lot of other remedies which have similar symptoms.
We don't get really something, child vomits
curd milk, this is in so many remedies. Thin watery diarrhoea
Rheumatic pains, constant jerking,
earache from exposal to drafts and cold.