Primarily a rheumatic  remedy affecting the joints worse always before a storm.
Worse cold, worse wet but primarily worse before a storm. They know when a storm is coming by the pains which are coming.
The  remedy will be confused with Rhus-t.
Motion ameliorates.
Especially they get epididymitis swelling of testes, especially the right side very painful, better by motion.
Heels also are very sensitive, rheumatic
pains which affect primarily the heel.
The heel becomes very painful in the same way as Med.
Med. has very sensitive heels in any case but it can reach a point where Med. is so sensitive in the heels
it's not anymore sensitivity, it's painful sensitivity, nd it is a crucifying pain to get up in the morning...
...they will go on into four, lying down before
they can get used in walking, in Med.
Rhod. is similar but not as strong as Med.
Another peculiar symptom is the way that they like to sleep. It's on their back with legs crossed.
The similarity with Rhus-t. is quite strong but if you see the heels sensitive or painful, then it goes immediately towards Rhod.
And of course if they say that storms are affecting them, worse before and during storms.
This sudden change of weather makes them feel very bad.
They can be also psychologically down with this weather, before a storm.
That's why they develop fear of storms. Faintness, confusion, excitement before storm.
We don't know much about the psychological state but when you use this  remedy, usually we don't have much
psychological symptoms. It's a rheumatic, arthritic  remedy and these people who are suffering with
rheumatism, with arthritis, they are quite  balanced people in their mental emotional.
It's a very good thing, for instance, treating somebody who is mentalized to see eventually the joints
being involved into the disease.
That's a very good sign, the same way that for another case would be a good sign to see a skin eruption.
So when you get these cases and they will tell you these few symptoms, either inflammation on the testes
or epididymitis or inflammation in the heels or worse before or during storms they are quite healthy people
belonging usually to the first group.
We have quite a different way of evaluating diseases.
Where somebody says, 'my child was never sick'.
I say, oh my God! Otherwise the child is very healthy. I say, yes very healthy.
I remember a case of an autistic child I treated for 8 years.
The child was not able to perform anything.
When he came to the office, we had some curtains and in no time the curtains were down, he just pulled them.
It was very strong.
It was like an animal, treated for 8 years. Then I lost this case, they didn't follow anymore and the last I remember
was when he came out with crops of words.
Manifested out of nowhere. It was very interesting. And the child was able after that to perform, to self-support.
He started playing with clay and he would go an buy things. His mother would say, go and bring me bread.
He would give the money, give me bread, he would take the bread, take it back.
To that extent I remember out of 8 years of treating this child, very difficult cases, autistic children.
But it was very interesting the great relief that came when finally the words came back.
-May I ask you a question? In the mentally retarded children how do you know that you should repeat the  remedy?
By what symptom?
I have a case of Bar-c. and the child before had never been sick and after Bar-c. it developed a cold and angina...
...and the parents didn't tell me. They went to another doctor and they gave antibiotics and after this
I repeated the  remedy and again an angina followed and a bronchitis.
The child gets Ritalin because of hyper activity and they have to make and EEG every now and then.
After some months the EEG was normal and before it was always been slow down and it's articulating
a little bit better but I have no idea when to repeat or how high I should repeat.
-In such cases you can repeat high and you can repeat a lot. You can repeat 10M every day until he has a reaction.
But, for instance, let us say the child develops angina. You see the symptoms and if the symptoms fall
within Bar-c., you continue. Otherwise it's better to stop the  remedy and don't give anything.
I mean don't give Bell. or other remedies we give in such cases because you may just spoil the action.
Like antibiotics, it was very bad. That they gave antibiotics in such a case. It's a pity.
-When you said that this autistic kid had these warts and it connected actually to Thuja and normally people say
and I found out that in the few I know and they are autistic, they became autistic after they get the vaccinations.
And it's connecting the Thuja again after certain vaccinations.
-I didn't say that the child was autistic because these warts were.... I didn't say that, I don't know.
But autistic children are very difficult condition to treat.
-I'm not quite sure if I understood you right. Did you say that the arthritic pains ....
-Arthritic pains if they are brought out in a mental case, it's a very good sign, as skin eruptions.
You have to rejoice when they say 'my ankles are swollen and my foot is swollen' then you have to be careful.
The idea is that you know what you are doing and you don't make so many mistakes. This is the idea.
Once you know what's going on, you don't make so many mistakes. Wait, it's a good reaction, you explain.
The patient will be patient.
If you explain and if you give a logical reason why you do this and why you do that, they will understand most of them.
If they don't understand it's their problem, it's not your problem. Your problem is to explain to them and to show
that you know and you feel comfortable.
'Ah! What is this doctor? I can't live, I have my wrist'......'Yes, I know'.
I will give you a remedy which is seldom indicated but it is an interesting remedy.
A remedy hich is full of life, energy, excitement.
And a lot of angriness, angry.  pulsation.
And a remedy that produces disturbances in
the circulation, it reminds one of  Tarent., of Bell.
And which ends up in having a malignant tumor, especially breast.
Cancer of breast is one of the remedies that we have to consider.
In the night they get excited and full of emotions and then it goes down and feel depressed.
A remedy which is very quarrelsome like Tarent.
They say after mental exertions, the brain feels agitated.
You can perceive the disturbance on the circulation.
Very emotional people. If they become upset, everything is worse.
Also you will see during the climacteric period, where again it stops suddenly this flow of blood and the circulation changes
this is the period where Aster. can show up tumors, can show up troubles, can show up insanity and delusions.
They have different types of delusions, hear voices, see faces etc.
There is also a delusion which is similar to Bry. They feel that they are away from home and they'll say
'I would like to go home'.
You will see the effect on the reproductive organs and also the effect on the sexual desire which is increased
it's much aggressive. Aggressive sexual desire that is not satisfied with normal sexual activity.
They need something else. You perceive the heart of the remedy.
The tumor breaking out, the circulation, the excitement, the night excitement, the sexual energy
the quarrelsome, the irritability, the anger inside.
This kind of people you will see that are similar to Tarent. or Bell.
There is a time of aggravation which is just before the Lyc. aggravation.
Lyc. is 4 to 8. That is before that, 2 to 4. That is the time of aggravation.
And aggravation in the night, in bed.
You will have headaches, epileptic fits that take place around that time, 2,3,4.
Each remedy has peculiarities and you will see in this remedy a symptom which is peculiar
anxiety on the upper part of the abdomen.
Felt on the upper part of the abdomen.
We have anxiety arising from stomach and this is a symptom I have seen very frequently with Ars.
You go a little bit higher and you see anxiety from stomach and you think of Ars.
This remedy is not as restless as Ars.
and it's not as cold as Ars.
An interesting symptom also is that epileptic fits are preceded by a kind of twitching.
Twichings all over the body, they may have here, here, here. 2,3 days before the attack.
Still it's a small remedy that you will use,
you will find it's picture very seldom.
Don't get the idea that you will get a case like this tomorrow when you go back home.
It has the feeling of the uterus pushing out like Sep., Lil-t. but not as strong as these remedies.
In Lil-t. and Sep. is very strong. Here it's much less in intensity.
The idea is that you have to get this excitable and quarrelsome and irritable and a person with a lot of
emotional and circulatory turmoil. This is the idea.
If you get a sedate person with delusions and problems in climacteric, fear of insanity, insanity etc. you don't think of Aster.
When you read the proving of this  remedy, you realize that this is a person who has abused sexual energy.
You get people who become impotent and because of that impotency they become depressed
dissatisfied, despondent.  At the same time there is an arousal of anxiety, especially concerning their health.
Sexual melancholy, you understand what it means?
'I cannot have sex, I do not have the potency though I like it'.
Now we have the solution. What is the solution? Viagra! Not Agn.
You first try Agn. before Viagra. It may help better.
They are individuals who are broken down in their constitutions.
The first thing that breaks down is the memory. They forget words, they forget what they want to do, they forget names.
They are absent minded, they cannot concentrate.
They try to read and they read the words and nothing sticks inside. You see the weakness of the brain.
-We all need it.
-Yes, why not. Especially homeopaths who concentrate too much on their work, they become totally destroyed.
Over exertion. In Homeopathy there are some of my students, when they find the remedy, they say
how many orgasms did you have today? How many times you found the correct  remedy ?
So Agn. after that because you have a sexual hyper activity with Homeopathy.
I got the  remedy !
Interesting also it has a symptom like Arg-n. where they say, 'I'm finished, I'm going to die' and many times
they will even say, 'I think in two months I'm finished. I'm going to die'.
You must have heard me saying this many times.
Delusions of smell, also of herring the fish.
History of repeated gonorrheas. You understand the type of the person, a lot of activities, a lot of enjoyment
and then enjoyment stops.
Absence of disappearance of milk in nursing women often with great sadness, she says she will die.
The milk does not come and then this degradation of the organism.
You see the peculiarity between Aster., it makes the whole system to build up in energy.
The other one it brings it down and still the end result will be the same. Death is coming near.
This remedy feels that it's near, it's not actually physical death, it's a feeling that the deterioration which I feel
in the way I feel, I'm going to die, maybe tomorrow or in two months.
This is the idea. With Aster. also you will see in tumors which they develop in very vital people with a lot of energy
a lot of sexual activity and if you enquire about their sexual activity you'll find out that it's not just normal sexual activity.
It will be quite a lot of other things.
In the end you get the tumor, in the breast usually. But it can be in the uterus, in the ovaries.
Asterias affects the reproductive organs.
Here in Agn., again the tubes that bring the milk stop and the woman goes into depression. She feels she is going to die.
Parts cold and relaxed, the sexual organs
are cold and relaxed. Total impotency.
Many times also the desire is totally gone.
With these remedies you just have to remember the essence. If you get the essence then it sticks in the mind
then the moment you will see the patient, something will remind you.
George was talking about it, a.... you go to all the a, asterias, that's it. Many times I found remedies like this
because it's not possible to remember everything.
-In the rubric, 'tells the time of his death', can you make an addition of this remedy because it's not contained in the rubric?
-Yes, predicts, foretells. You can make an addition. It's not there? In the Repertory?
-Which degree?
-Second degree you can put it but it's not in the Repertory already?
It has to be, just look in your Repertories.
-The Germans have the name monk's pepper for this  remedy.
-Very interesting also it means in Greek being a pure person. In Greek 'Agnos' means a person who is pure.
So most probably the monks were doing a proving of the mother tincture. They took the remedy
to lower their desire for sex and make them impotent.
It's a proving, they used it as a proving. The same way like women in Brazil I heard also.
They used the frog's substance from the glands, the bufo, they used to give it to their husband, without
the husband knowing what he is taking with his coffee in order to stop them from being so active with them.
They said, I had enough, take some bufo.
-Would it not be good time now to differentiate the different impotence remedies?
-They are too many.
We have from early ejaculation to total impotency but I don't think I can do it now. I have to prepare.
-He said in Germany it's common that gynecologists take preparations concerning Agn.
but what he meant is that they prescribe preparations that contain Agn.
I had a patient who was taking this preparation for about 3-4 months...
...and she fell into absolute deep depression and had the typical symptom that she will die soon now.
And that's why I told this woman and I try to spread it to all my other female patients that they really
have to be careful in using these preparations.
-Why they give it? On what indications?
-Troubles from the breast. And swelling of the breast.
-The gynecologist say it's so called herbal female hormone and it's used as such. A plant female hormone.
-Female hormone. So do they give it in excess of male hormones?
-No, not as a counteraction to male hormones but it's used if women have pain in the breast before menses
if they have menstrual problems meaning too frequent or long menses, strong menses.
Also if they have the menses too infrequent.
But especially for premenstrual syndrome.
It's frequently given during menopause instead of hormones without any big differentiation.
-Just because they are on climacteric.
-Usually it's prescribed as mother tincture and I assume that this patient was especially sensitive to it.
I have not seen this reaction to other patients.
-It's very interesting the confirmation of the 'predicts the time of death'. It's very interesting in that case.
-It's just as the colleague said before. Usually it's used generally for the so called hormonal disturbances.
-It is interesting since it's prescribed, I didn't know it was prescribed so widely in Germany, but it's interesting
from these side effects, whatever it comes to your attention to collect the side effects and to write precisely
what the person feels and to have it published.
This was one of our ideas concerning provings and this is a very good way of proving. Because out of the population
I just had an enquiry from England, the Complementary Medicine Association.
They asked this question. Let us say, in a population of 10.000 people, how many do you think
will be sensitive to Bell., Rhus-t. and Puls.? They put a question to me.
Theoretically if we had the possibility to give it. Bell. 30 to the 10.000 population, how many will develop some symptoms?
What is the answer?
Of course the answer is we cannot know but there is a measurement for somebody who has seen a lot of cases.
And the measurement is how many of my cases are Bell., Rhus-t. and Puls.?
So the answer I gave is about 20-50 at the most out of 10.000.
This is the same thing with Agn.  Giving Agn. in a population of let us say 50.000, you may have
30 cases in which you will see some side effects and these are very interesting cases.
And this is my objection concerning the type of provings which are done in contemporary provings
and are written in a book. You give a dose of 12C and you have thousands of symptoms.
How is that possible that everyone in the group develops symptoms?
It's not possible, it's totally impossible. Therefore a lot of these provings are false. The information is false.
Out of the group maybe one person will bring out a real symptom. So out of 1000 symptoms, perhaps 5-6 symptoms
out of 1 person may be belonging really to the  remedy.
- About the feeling of death is usually said that at the end of orgasm there is a feeling of a small death.
So maybe that feeling is extending in that case ....
-You are a philosopher but if you ask the experience of many people, especially women and men
they will say I feel rejuvenated after the orgasm. It is a matter of the organism, how it will react.
An organism will feel rejuvenated, another one will feel very depleted and maybe even with this idea.
But from a theoretical point of view you can say that you give the possibility of life for continuation and at the same time
you are getting older and you are going away, that is true. From a theoretical point of view, in actuality, it doesn't happen.