What is interesting with this remedy is the following. This is a remedy that sweats a lot. Is dreched in sweat.
But as soon as it goes to sleep, the sweat dries out and the skin becomes dry and burning.
Therefore there is no elimination and there are two points of sensitivity for Samb. One is the respiratory system
and it gets the impact of the non-elimination to the perspiration. The boy goes to bed...
...in the day time the perspiration is flowing, he goes to bed at 10 o'clock and at 10.30  the perspiration
is totally stopped, once he has been in sleep and there is no elimination.
At 12 o'clock, 12.30, 1,1.30 even 2 o'clock this child will wake up with a tremendous dyspnea. It becomes very soon bluish.
The perspiration starts again as soon as he wakes up with the dyspnea, the perspiration starts again
but the dyspnea will continue the whole night.
It is one of these remedies that they will tell you what time is the dyspnea, they say the whole night.
Actually it is not the whole night, it is after a few hours of sleep. This is the idea. In the Repertory maybe you will find
after 12 difficulty of breathing, asthmatic breathing, after 12.
The idea is that this elimination has to stop through some hours of sleep and then the lungs, which are sensitive
take the impact. Of course, as you may understand, this is happening why? Because at the same time
there is a sensitivity on the kidneys. The kidneys do not eliminate properly and that is why we may have also
a kidney problem with swelling of extremities. Especially of the lower extremities.
We have also suffocative attacks after fright. The child gets frightened and then it cannot breathe.
The difficulty is so strong, it is one of the worst asthma remedies, the difficulty is so strong and sudden
that there is a fear, an anxiety arising together with this suffocative attack.
Also Samb. has the tendency to dry up the natural discharges of upper respiratory, to dry up the nose
to close it and the person feels suffocating and nursing children, they cannot take the food from the milk of the mother.
Characteristic is, as we said, during waking hours there's a lot of perspiration but not so much in the head
the perspiration is in the body. It is one of the most perspiring remedies during the asthmatic attacks.
In cases where you will find a combination of kidney problems with asthmatic attacks, this is a remedy that has
to be thought immediately. But as I said, what you have to remember is the dryness of the skin. So much dry that
is burning during sleep but once he wakes up he is drenched in sweat.
That means very much but not so much in the head.
The difficulty mostly is on expiration, not so much in inspiration.
The lungs seem not to have the power to put out the air.
That's all you have to remember about that remedy. If you remember, you will recognize it.
-Is it mainly a children's remedy?
-Children because children today, you know the statistics.
Today the children of Europe and America are getting asthmatic attacks in tremendous numbers.
There are statistics that say 40% of the children they have some kind of asthmatic conditions.
Also there is evidence that this epidemic it has been produced by pertussis by the DPT vaccination.
And there are statistics that say that children which are vaccinated in some areas, the come up to 18%
of the vaccinated children, they have asthmatic attacks.
Where unvaccinated of the same country, they come up to 2% or even less.
It is very interesting that there is a study which says that if the children together with DPT, they are vaccinated
with BCG they don't get it. The percentage of those children who get asthma is much less.
So from one hand they make sick the children by giving the pertussis, instead of having the whooping cough
the acute and allowing the organism to develop antibodies and not being so easily affected by environmental conditions
instead of allowing this to happen, they don't allow the body to do that and the body does not develop
and then with the least provocation, it has a cold, it has an influenza, it ends up to asthma.
But then they say, if you give BCG to these children, it is the product from tuberculin, this percentage is much less.
So actually it is interesting that we counteract this cough or this asthma with Tub. and perhaps an idea will be
if they give children BCG and the children start coughing and start having chronic problems, maybe Tub. 200
will be an antidote. Because they antidote the one with the other.
They antidote the side effects of pertussis with BCG and there is a total confusion, they don't know what they are doing.
There is a debate finally  which is going on these levels. Finally, after me speaking for the last 30 years.
They have come to the point where they realized maybe they are right.
It is difficult for one who is breathing with difficulty to differentiate but sometimes they will be able to say, it is difficult.
It's not so easy to tell but sometimes they can tell you.
And worse lying down especially with the head low. It makes very difficult the breathing, they have to sit up.
Use Sabad. mostly in hay fever.
Where the nose, the pharynx, the trachea are affected mostly.
It is the upper respiratory tract which is affected and the characteristic is the spasmodic, violent sneezing
which comes  together with excessive lacrimation. You see repeated attacks of sneezing, the eyes are running.
I'll get symptoms of Sabad. very soon.
It's a cold remedy which is ameliorated by having something warm in the stomach. Warm drinks are desired and ameliorate.
They don't like cold drinks, warm coverings, warm drinks make the person feel better.
They go into the open air and as soon as the air blows the sneezing starts, the paroxysmal sneezing
starts and then there is a tremendous lacrimation.
Sabad. is known for something else which is characteristic in the mind.
It is known to have peculiar sensations about her body. Not like Bar-c. that the body is not harmonious
'I have too big breast or too big hips'.
Bar-c. always, even if they are thin, they will feel big, the hips are fat. This is different with Sabad.
Sabad. feels that maybe parts are shrunk or parts are elongated.
They will feel the nose is big, they have a big chin, the eyes are bulgy or are shrunk in.
These ideas in the mind are very peculiar of this remedy.
Another area of action is worms in children. Worms in the intestines.
And it's a peculiar symptom also that sometimes they feel there is a worm here in the mouth.
There is this sensation that there is a worm moving in the pharynx.
Hypochondriac people, feeling always that there is something wrong with their health and feeling also that
their case most probably is incurable.
They have quite strong fear of death, fear of devil and fear of water.
and sometimes it arouses the passion in a woman and you can see nymphomania. They are quite passionate.
Very strong nails, difficult to cut.
Sensation of a lump in the throat, it can be a sensation of mucus or a sensation of something hanging.
Like a bundle of hair, not one hair. One hair is different, the sensation of one hair is Kali-bi. and Sil. mostly.
They need to swallow to get it out or hawk it which makes it difficult.
But what you have to remember is the sudden explosive sneezing with a lot of lacrimation, running nose
with heat which comes to the head and in spite of that, they are ameliorated by warm drinks, warm coverings.
Sabad. will suffer in the open air.
Especially when the air is cold. When it's hot the air and it's little, no.
And we have convulsions in children from worms. You know that worms can produce convulsions.
When I was in India I had seen a terrible case of convulsion which had actually died from convulsions.
He was in a state with tremendous amount of pinworms and he was in spasm and eventually he stuck there.
India was an experience because in India the idea of life or death is different than we have here.
They gave irrelevant remedies totally, I was battling to give the remedy, I was sure the child could be saved
they say no the Professor said to give this remedy. I said OK the child will die like a typhus case.
It will be very interesting for us to have a hospital and to see the hospital cases and to show what Homeopathy
can do in hospital cases.
It will be very interesting, I can tell you they are going to have a shock. Because they don't want to see
these cases we treat, they don't want to hear about.
You say, I vaccinated my child and my child was paralyzed two days later and they say, no, no, don't even talk about it.
You lose your job.
I was seeing a documentary for the people on the war in Iraq.
There is this syndrome, the syndrome of the gulf war and I saw people paralyzed, young soldiers they are paralyzed.
The doctors who investigated their cases they almost lost their job. The files of the soldiers were lost.
They don't want to see and it's such a big evidence that the uranium of the bombs that are throwing now in Kosovo
the same bombs were thrown there. And thousands of soldiers were affected.
Who were affected? Mostly those who have been vaccinated against the gases, the poisonous gases.
They were afraid that Sadam would throw some poisonous gases.
And after by mistake they bombed their own tanks. When they went to check the radiation was so much
that a mission came from America. People dressed like astronauts and were covering this with sand.
They dig to put into the sand all these tanks
that were bombarded by the uranium bombs.
Because the radiation was so much and after burying them they go over the place and still the radiation
was tremendous! And people now are dying and there is a whole big thing in America but you see how they tried
again and again to cover up the whole story.
They don't want to listen what we say, they don't want to investigate the idea of vaccination.
They get numbers and statistics which are not well researched.
As far as I know there are more soldiers suffering from the syndrome than those who are actually affected
by some kind of radiation through bombing.
From what I heard, when they prepared for the war there is also that they tested all kinds of new vaccinations on the soldiers.
There was a mass vaccination. Everybody who went to the gulf had to be vaccinated.
-The Americans and the English. Not the other nations.
-But the Americans I can remember that they said it and these vaccinations had never been tried out before.
So whatever reactions you see, whether radiation or no, can also be reactions to the vaccine itself.
-This is correct, this is what I said. Those who were vaccinated were the worst victims.
They said that they threw the bombs and there was a lot of dust coming up and people came with their clothes.
One of the men who was suffering was a nurse, a doctor, undressing the people from the battle and taking
the dust of their clothes into her clothes and checking out the radiation, it was tremendous in the doctors' clothes.
It's a whole big documentary. Now with all these facts, all these people talking, doctors who try to investigate
how they lost their job, how the files were lost, how nobody knows what happened.
You ask information about these people and this doctor said, I received telephone calls who said, give up your patients.
And he said, I'm a doctor how can I give up my patients?
And they threatened him and finally he lost his position because these were doctors paid by the government or the military.
-With the actions on Kosovo now, they are actions in the U.S. to start to prepare ground groups for activity in Kosovo.
And because of the gulf war syndrome which many doctors and soldiers believe were induced by vaccinations
the many vaccinations that were given and the fact that their perspiration was suppressed, they used special suits
to protect against these nerve gases that were supposed to be used which by the way they were supplied by the US.
But the suppression of the perspiration with the vaccination is what they believe caused the problem.
And now there are soldiers in the US who are refusing to be vaccinated for action in Kosovo.
And there is a big controversy now in the Military whether the Military can force them to take vaccinations.
And there is a law suit going on.
-But you see in a country like America which is supposed to be the most free, the most democratic
everybody does whatever he likes, then it comes to the real problem, everything can be suppressed.
it's a terrifying thought!
We are guinea pigs.