We're going to talk about small remedies.
I have to make a little introduction concerning such remedies, as we will be talking about.
Students get excited, we're going to learn a new remedy.
The remedies we're going to talk this time you will need perhaps once or twice or three times in your lifetime.
And good luck if you can recognize it, when it comes. It comes unexpectedly.
The patients are coming one after the other and in the middle of all that, you remember maybe that this might look like this.
But this you're going to do it for each remedy. Once maybe for sure.
It is nice to know but very seldom to be used.
Most of the bulk of your patients will be covered by what we call main remedies.
In my years of practice which are completed 40 years, this year.
I didn't say it for applaud, I said it with a regret.
I needed very seldom such remedies to help me in the prescribing.
I found very early in my practice that most of the cases are covered by what we know to be the main remedies.
The Merc's, the Calc's, the Sulph., Lyc., Phos., Ars., Nux-v. etc.
So don't get over excited about small remedies because you are going to be disappointed.
Now I have to say a few more things concerning new remedies which are appearing.
And this is a good thing that we have some new remedies appearing.
The bad thing about it is that most of their symptomatology come from imagination and not from proving.
So you can use imagination quite a lot and then this information circulates and there comes an individual
who has given a remedy X. I hear also some remedies we are taught, they don't exist.
I mean chemically is not possible to make such remedies.
But the imagination of the teacher makes it possible and also made a symptomatology.
You get a practitioner who takes that remedy and gives it to most of his patients, most probably.
Out of his patients there is one or two that they are so suggestible that they will say, oh this remedy is excellent.
I had this, this, that, all are gone.
But you remember yesterday Nina, I think, she said every remedy I was given, in the beginning I was feeling very well.
So don't misunderstand the suggestibility of a patient, the placebo effect with the real action of a remedy.
As I have said many times, in order to have action usually we have reaction. We have an aggravation.
Somebody comes and says, 'I felt so much better from your remedy'. This you have to doubt most of the times
whether this is really so, whether the remedy was correct.
And we have to be very careful with this field, Homeopathy.
Because it's a new field, it's not controlled, anybody can inject into the teaching, anything he likes.
I have heard so crazy things which are unbelievable. I asked a few people to make a catalogue of these
crazy things which are going on.
One of the craziest was that a patient was coming wearing a shirt with lines, so the practitioner thought
definitely this is a case of zebra!
So he tried to take the milk of the zebra and give it to the patient. Of course there was an effect.
Because the remedy was quite exotic! I mean this type of things which are going on with Homeopathy
it is not a light thing that you can just ignore.
No. Because this passes into the information of serious people in Medicine and they say, 'they are crazy'.
'Homeopaths? They are crazy, forget them'.
So it has an action repercussion on the science of Homeopathy.
Like the other one who thought she was looking like an eagle and she took a feather of the eagle, potentized it
gave it to her and she was cured.
The patient was looking like an eagle.
She could fly. She was asking the whole class, what this patient looks like? And different people said different things
like a snake, like an animal, like a flower,
the whole class suggested something.
Somebody suggested an eagle, so she says that's correct. She looks like an eagle, that's why I went
and got a feather from an eagle, potentized it and gave it to her.
And then she believes it herself, she is seriously.
But she has mislead herself to believe that this was curing this patient. It is a placebo effect.
We talk about Collinsonia Canadensis.
These little remedies of course you will try after you have tried bigger remedies and they have failed.
Now Coll., I will give you the essence, what I have observed.
They are individuals who are very excitable, easily going into excitement and you can see their feelings
are over flowing, like swelling feelings.
A lot of feelings and over excitement and the organism takes the impact of such excitement and appears
certain symptomatology.
The main of which will be a feeling of swelling, a feeling of enlargement on the physical body in different parts.
Like the feelings inside they swell and they cannot be retained by the organism. They cannot be controlled.
In the same way the sensation is that the head is becoming bigger, larger.
They feel their face is becoming broadened.
They feel that swelling in different parts of the body but especially in the urino-genital area.
A woman will feel, for instance, in genitalia a sensation as if swollen, especially the clitoris.
The man will feel the testes are swollen, it's a sensation. It's not a real swelling.
They feel the anus is swollen.
With this kind of swelling and tendency to swell, we have actually a tremendous appearance of hemorrhoids
especially connected with constipation and menses in women.
There is a connection between the pathology of hemorrhoids and the heart.
So whenever there is bleeding from the hemorrhoids, in heart patients, the heart pains are relieved.
Also you will see an alternation between hemorrhoids and palpitation.
When the hemorrhoids are out  the palpitation goes away.
The hemorrhoids go in, the
palpitation bothers the patient.
Coll. is one of the main remedies that you
have to think in very obstinate constipation.
Constipation that doesn't move with anything.
The bowels don't move even if there is urging, there is no effect.
But most of the times there is no urging. They are just stuck and the patient will tell you the only way
to move my bowel is to take a lot of cathartic.
And then after taking cathartic, they feel very bad because the hemorrhoids come out, then they feel uneasy.
Don't forget these individuals are very excitable and anything that excites their system, makes them feel bad.
You may think of this remedy also in prolapsus of uterus or prolapsus of rectum and when this prolapsus happen
is quite strong.
As I said, the person is quite hysterical, excited easily and you may have hysterical convulsions during menses.
And such woman with constipation, with piles, who faint very easily when they have an abdominal pain
and this brings a tendency to faint or they do faint.
Also this tendency to become bigger like the piles become big, the rectum comes out, the head becomes big
the face feels big, the same with any part which is affected the sensation is or there is real swelling.
Sensation or real swelling can happen in affected part. If a part is inflamed, it will swell.
They may have a feeling of hands being swollen. The feet are swollen, there is a feeling or there are actually swelling.
But the general tendency is out of this excitement and the swelling of feelings, swelling of parts, feeling of swelling
sensation of swelling, swelling and then inactivity and collapse.
Which is the uterus prolapses, the rectum prolapses.
If a woman comes and tells you for instance, I feel my clitoris, I have a sensation it's always swollen
and you see there is constipation and with the constipation there are hemorrhoids most probably
the remedy is not Alum. Alum. has nothing to do with this because it's a different individual all together.
You don't give Alum. in such severe constipation, she will describe, because Alum. is dull. These people are excitable.
They are very quick to answer your questions and you see the feelings are over flowing.
It's not to be confused with Alum. or Bry.
Alum. and Bry. are two remedies which have malignant, severe constipation.
Together with Sil. I would say. Now each one has its own peculiarities that you cannot confuse.
When they have a headache, they want to sleep. There is a sleepy feeling during headache.
Convulsions during menses. Hysterical convulsions, not real convulsions.
This remedy gives you the idea of both the excitement and the collapse and then the swelling.
You have hemorrhoids and constipation and you have an excitable patient, think of Coll. to make it simple.
If such a person tells you that I have a sensation of swelling wherever it might be, think of Coll.
How many times I have given Coll. in my life? I think 3, 4 times.
And I don't remember even if these 4 times were all successful. You may have prescribed it but not successfully.
-One of her main complaints was that she was impressed easily and excited very easily, she was teaching yoga
and every time she was getting with clients, she was so impressed by them that she became bloated very quickly
and also severely constipated. She only very rarely had stools and could produce these with great effort.
She did not have hemorrhoids along with it but she was very bloated and also had the sensation of being
very distended. I prescribed Coll. in low potency and had hardly any effect.
-It's not necessary to have the hemorrhage.
Look at this portal system in Coll., it is affected. Therefore the heart  in conjunction has a repercussion upon this.
So when there is a release, the heart is released, therefore you have  patients with weakness of heart
heart conditions, constrictions of heart which are affected when the hemorrhoids are. This is one type of person.
The other type, which is the constipation type, it doesn't necessarily need to have the hemorrhoids.
You may have the hemorrhoids, when you have the hemorrhoids, they are quite strong, they are coming out.
The patient will describe the hemorrhoids as something huge in Coll.
What you described is quite in the description and if you still have the patient, I would suggest that you try
a higher potency or another pharmacy.
-I gave a low potency C6 or X6, three times the day and there was no effect.
-The problem with your patient seems to be quite on the emotional level primarily, being so excitable
and therefore you need a higher potency.
Like yesterday when we spoke about the case when the problem is on the mental-emotional, you need to go
high to touch upon such cases. So try, this is quite good description. You have to try.
We'll talk about Equisetum.
Equis. may prove to be an interesting remedy and maybe you will need this remedy more frequently.
I have used it in cases of people who are tired and they feel restless and at the same time  prostrated, very tired.
With an aversion to mental work which is a syndrome which we find frequently today.
Maybe when other remedies have failed, people who are irritable, restless and yet prostrated.
You see in Equis. there is a symptom. It says, the person is always like this, frown, in a state of inner irritability.
Such people do not like to be touched.
It's like a state of irritability, don't touch.
Not exactly the aversion to touch that we had in the case we had seen but a different kind of reaction.
Irritable reaction, nervous reaction.
It's also a remedy which you will use in children when you have failed in enuresis of children.
When you have failed with the different remedies and the enuresis persists, in a child 10,12, 13 years old.
The enuresis persists, you have tried different remedies, you have tried Rhus-t., Tub., Puls., Kreos., Bell., the whole lot.
And it fails, then you can try Equis., especially if the children are restless.
Equis. will be used mostly in pathology of the cyst, cystitis. Cystitis with all kinds of different symptoms.
Frequent urination, painful urination.
It has here, in the end of urination, actually after urination there is pain which continues for some time.
Great pain at the end or urination is wrong in the expression because which remedy is in the end of urination?
Sarsaparilla and another remedy?
At the end of urination means the urine has not stopped.
The urine comes to the end and the moment it starts dribling, in the end, then the pain comes.
Then the urination stops and the pain goes away. With Equis. is when the urine stops, then the pain starts.
Constant urging to urinate. It has a symptom like Nux-v., very frequent urination but very little urine is voided.
Therefore the less urine, the more frequent is the urge.
Don't forget this prostration. It looks like almost a prostration for Pic-ac. That's why you will use it in old people who feel
tired in their mind, restless, they cannot sleep, they cannot think they cannot do any mental work
and yet their bladder is paralyzed and retains the urine.
Retention of urine in old people, tired, prostrated, especially with brain tiredness.
Also retention of urine after delivery.
And a main sensation is a fullness in the bladder which prevents urination.
If they manage to urinate, this fullness of course is relieved.
We don't know more about these remedies.
These are good cases for publication. In case you have a case as long as it is not placebo effect.
If you have a case like this, it is always good to publish such cases because we may be learning a little bit more
about their mental-emotional pathology.
Diosc. is a remedy that you will need more than 3 times in your life time.
Who has a Diosc. case so far?
You will need Diosc. mostly in colic cases which are of a severe type.
That means the person out of pain is shouting, it feels that the intestines they just turn around.
And the tendency of the person is of course to double up.
In such cases almost automatically the patient wants to double.
And while she is doubling up, she feels the pain is even worse.
And then they find out that the best position for them is, if they can stand it, to over extend their body.
So they will sit like this.
They still shout but they know the moment
they go like that, it's much worse.
So they have to stay in that position, shouting and crying and this comes with a diarrhea or without a diarrhea.
These cramps can be uterus cramps, can be small intestines, large intestines, gallbladder, kidney colics.
The modalities will always be the same. It's cramping, stitching pain, tearing pain and the amelioration
will come when they sit up and they make like this, over extended.
This is a keynote which is not stressed in the Materia Medicas.
I don't know if it's even mentioned in the Materia Medica but it is a keynote which I found it is almost infallible.
And I have stressed it in other cases as well.
Another interesting thing for Diosc. is that while she is having such pains, these pains may just suddenly go away
and pains appear in the fingers or in the toes.
Then these pains become so painful
and the visceral area is ameliorated.
Also they will tell you if you ask them where the pain is extending the pains extend downwards and upwards.
They can go anywhere. They can go around. They can go up, they can go down.
When there is diarrhea, for instance, it's usually yellowish, thin, yellowish, frequent stool but the stool
does not relieve the colic.
Colicky people who are prone to have colics all their life. You get a case of colic or even pains in the back.
It's very strange how they can appear these pains in the extremities, out of the blue.
While these central pains of the back or the abdomen or the colics are releasing.
The type of Diosc. is an individual who is tired in mind and soul, who is avoiding company, parties, people
discussions, because they tire him and the
mind becomes more and more tired.
And then they start forgetting words.
Or they change words, one word for another.
They want to say right and they say left they want to say apples and they say melon.
But as the organism goes down and they feel tired and exhausted, at the same time they start having nightly emissions.
The men during sleep they have orgasms and these orgasms whether there is a natural coition or an orgasm
of that type, leaves the individual in a terrible state.
Either depression or irritability or discomfort, as if all the energy has been taken away from this individual.
After coition, after emissions, they don't like to sit down and read or do any kind of mental work.
Eventually they lose all their initiative for doing something creative.
One more keynote is that after stool, they feel confused, they feel the mind is not clear.
It is the opposite of which remedies?
Nat-s. and Calc.
Calc. and Nat-s. they have exactly the opposite. Their mind becomes clear and joyful.
Also this remedy has another symptom, for those who drink a lot of tea and as soon as they drink tea, there is a kind of
fermentation and there is burping and a lot of gas, comes out from drinking tea.
Also this remedy is a remedy which produces a lot of gas.
The colics are not continuous, they are coming in severe crisis, as I described, then they subside and they come again.
The intensity of the pain is tremendous. It's one of the most painful remedies of the Materia Medica in colics.
Together and even worse than Colocynthis.
And they are generally relieved by walking,
they feel they must walk.
The time of aggravation is in the evening and in the night.
especially towards the midnight, as the night goes on and midnight becomes very bad.
- I have a patient who is living with severe stress, their parents in law and her own parents are all evil.
And they're annoying her like tyrants. And when they have an attack even in the middle of the night they call her.
This patient has only a sensitive stomach and quite frequently reacted to Coloc.
What was interesting is that the patient said, 'when my parents or parents in law call in the middle of the night
I don't even discuss with them anymore. I cannot longer take it. All I do is to throw the phone.'
She was so exhausted all this time and then developed these cramps. The cramps awoke her at night
and in the beginning she tried to draw up her knees which aggravated everything. So in the middle of the night
she had to leave her bed, walk around and bend her back backwards. The cramps were really terrible
and no diarrhea or anything, just these colics. I had then prescribed Diosc., a 6X to take 3 times the day.
-I have a question. I repeatedly gave Diosc. for colics of babies. Those are babies who really terribly stretch
their back and bend backwards, as far as
they can, and now you said tea aggravates.
What kind of tea are you talking about?
-Black tea mostly.
-This is the case of an army person who was admitted in the hospital and when I had gone to examine him
he was leaning against the hospital bed, far back, against his back because of the pain
and he had beads of perspiration, he was running high temperature.
He had been diagnosed having pancreatitis, the pain was beside himself, he was receiving an analgesic
and in pancreatitis you can only put down the pain and give intravenous fluids for the whole thing to subside
on its own but nothing was helping him. The only indication was that he had to lean far, far back for this terrible pain
to subside; it was coming in spasms and his serum amylase levels when I had gone to visit him was 485
which should be less than 90. In the ultrasound there was quite a lot of fluid around the pancreas which is usual to have
during this time. I prescribed Diosc. 1M very frequently 2hourly until the relief would come and then to take it as SOS
and in 48 hours the pain was practically gone. By the 4th day his serum amylase level was down to 170
and then to 90 within a week time. Even the doctor in the army hospital said that this is too quick recovery
because the fluid was also getting absorbed very quickly around the pancreas. There was no complication
of cyst formation which generally comes after pancreatitis and no other remedy was given afterwards.
-So you are an army doctor now? Very good.
I presented some of the cases in a Congress, where about 15-18 Professors of Medicine gathered
and together with them was the head of the army medical, a general.
He was in the beginning... and in the end he told me that he will help the doctors who were in the army
about 10 army doctors are in the army at this moment, he will help them to infiltrate the medical practice
of the army with Homeopathy. He was really impressed.
And on Saturday I have an appointment with the second man in a Medical University in Greece who was
also present there and who is determined to put Homeopathy into the University.
One more remedy which has some validity as a specific.
Myristica.
It's a remedy which I have prescribed several times and it has given amazing results only with a specific situation.
When in the finger around, that part is inflamed and usually these kind of inflammations can be quite strong and persistent.
Myris. will give almost invariably some effect. This you give it only in the case when somebody  tells you I have this problem.
It is not a remedy that can be prescribed in a general symptomatology of the patient because we don't know
the symptomatology of Myris.
But perhaps out of these cases that you give it, maybe a constipation will be cured or something else will be cured
then you just write down the new symptoms
that were cured by this peculiar remedy.
As far as I'm concerned this is the only situation in which Myris. will really give an effect.
And not when there is a little bit of inflammation around here but when really there is progressed inflammation
with the swelling and pain quite a lot.
Whether it is foot or toes or fingers it doesn't matter, as long as it is around this.
Sometimes it has acted when the inflammation also is on another part, it is localized inflammation
but mostly on this.
This is a kind of miraculous remedy that by just looking you can say the remedy and then you have the effect.