I thought in this seminar just
because you are Germans...
...I'll make an exception to the program
that I usually have.
So what I'll give you as a present? I will make
a differential diagnosis of two remedies.
Alum. and Nux-m.
I will point out to the similarities
and to the differences.
If you go to our Materia Medicas,
to our Repertories, you will see
a lot of similarities between
Nux-m. and Alum.
Both they have a dryness
of the mucus membranes.
Both they have severe constipation.
Both they have a mind which
is not functioning properly.
So it can be easily interchanged,
one for the other.
What I will try to do is to give you the
difference in the personality of the pathology.
Something very interesting.
Both, as we said, they have dryness
of the mucus membranes.
But this dryness it gives a different symptomatology from one to the other.
What is this dryness in Alum., let's see first.
It is mostly in the skin, especially the back of the palms and especially to the colon, to the guts.
There is a dryness on the
lower digestive system.
Together with an idea of paralysis.
When a pure Alum. case tries
to have a stool, it is a battle.
The stool cannot come out. The peristalsis,
the natural peristalsis is not there.
The stool and the mucus membranes are dry and do not lubricate the guts so the stool can come out.
So it is a terrible state of constipation,
the worst possible.
They try, they try, they use mechanical means. but see now the idea of paralysis together with this dryness
together with this slowness because the mind becomes slow. The mind does not function.
There is a sense that when they are in the middle of a conversation, there is a sense in them of
'what is he saying this person?'.
They cannot perceive.
And they speak and by the time they speak, they hear their own voice and they say, 'it seems to me
somebody else is speaking'.
This slowness gives a symptom that
we perceive while taking the case.
The symptom is that the person tries to describe to us what is his problem and -I will exaggerate it a little bit myself-
- you see the frowning of the ... forehead.
You see how you will perceive it?
This is the effort...
To express. The effort to express.
It's going to be apparent to you.
They try, it's the same like the stool which
cannot come out. The words cannot come out.
And you will perceive this very clearly
because the Alum. is not so much aware
or she will not tell you that
'my mind does not function'.
You will see it, it's very obvious but she will not say it and you have to perceive it and ask specific questions.
'Do you really feel as if somebody else
is speaking while you're speaking?'
This kind of response you
will receive from Alum.
It is as if the humors of the body are lessened to a great degree and the movement becomes slow
the mind is slow, the guts are slow.
Together with this slowness it is the idea of paralysis in which we will use Alum. in cases of
M.S., in A.L.S., in different paralysis of the different organs, once constipation is there.
Almost always, not always constipation is
coming together with other Alum. symptoms.
For Alum. we have this kind of picture. If you perceive this and you hold it, I say it in a very nutshell
if you hold it, you will not miss it.
Now we come to Nux-m. which from the
books looks very much one like the other.
What is the difference?
The prime difference you will see in Nux-m.
the dryness of the mucus membranes is mostly
on the upper digestive, mouth.
There, the dryness appears so strongly
that the tongue sticks on the palate.
They wake up in the night and the tongue is stuck there. They make an effort to detach it.
There is also in Nux-m. a constipation, which
is similar but never as strong as the Alum.
Also in Nux-m. we may get
many times the opposite, diarrheas.
But the dryness in the mouth area and
also, that's a big difference, in the eyes.
The eyes become absolutely dry
and they cannot open and close their eyes.
They have to put tears in order to
lubricate and open and close the eyes.
Therefore it is a dryness which is centered mostly on the upper digestive and also eyes.
Where Alum. does not have this.
If we go to the mind of Nux-m.
you cannot say it's a slow mind.
It is a mind which is not present.
It is like a person who is day dreaming all the time, it's not present, it's not fully there.
It's not a matter of cannot find the
words to express, like Alum.
Alum. knows what she wants to say
but the word does not come.
With Nux-m. you can ask, she can answer and in two minutes she has forgotten she answered you.
You see the difference in the quality of the mind?
She is not present; she has answered
you but she has forgotten it.
She is cooking and somebody rings the bell
and she goes there and starts conversing.
The food is completely forgotten.
I'll use an expression which I don't know how many people you are familiar but in my books I have mentioned it.
She is living a little bit detached
the vital body from the physical body.
A little bit outside of her body.
They are living in a state of 'how nice'.
You know the state? Maybe later
on I will connect it with Cann-i.
But those who take marihuana - I have no experience but from descriptions that people have made to me -
they live in a wonderful state of mind.
But they are not present,
they are not there.
Marihuana has this effect upon the body to detach, the physical body from the etheric body
from the mental-emotional body.
And when this happens people who have a clear conscience, especially young people who are using marihuana
because I'm not going to use marihuana
neither any of you, you are grown ups.
Because the conscience is clean and clear  when this happens, they go into a state of ecstasy.
They go into a state which they used
to call in the 60's the spiritual state etc.
You experience the spiritual state of the possibilities we have as humans by taking a little bit of marihuana.
That is true but that ecstasy
is not healthy ecstasy.
It's a wonderful state of mind like Nux-m.
But without purpose, without coherence.
It is like breaking down the human
totality, the human entity which is one.
We have to be one in order to function
in this world. We have to be present.
Marihuana will break down this mind, will break down that and will leave us in a wonderful state for
a period of time and then comes the opposite state in which the person will go into depression.
And it needs another dose because it remembers what wonderful state it was, let me take another dose.
In this way you break down the organisms.
I'll tell you something which is political.
Some politicians claim let's leave marihuana
free, let's sell it anywhere like cigarettes.
I tell you this will be the
end of the human race.
Because what I have seen as the effect of marihuana in young people, sometimes is terrifying.
Because it leaves the body outside
of the physical body all the time.
That means they are living in another
world, in the dream world.
This detachment is necessary for us to happen in order to rejuvenate our bodies and it happens naturally in sleep.
In sleep you leave your physical body and you get the information you need and in the morning you wake up
and say, it's a new day.
That is a natural regeneration
of the human body.
But if you force the organism to do this by narcotics, by drugs, then you will get definitely the after effect. Finish.
You have to know that. Whether you use it or you don't use it, whether your children, patients use it.
You have to explain to them this is going to happen. What happens with people using the marihuana.
It happens that the mind
loses its critical power.
They don't have anymore discrimination. They cannot discriminate, this is right, this is wrong.
Where everybody knows
this is right, this is wrong.
People who have taken marihuana,
they have no discrimination.
Everything goes. Anything you tell them,
they will swallow it. They will believe it.
They are the nice people, love, love.
Yes it's nice to love but if that love has
come as a result of inner, esoteric work
that has made you from a human
animal to a real human.
That's inner, esoteric work. That means you have taken yourself and put him down and say you made a mistake
here you showed a lot of egoism.
You told lies, you did this and that.
And then you improve, you evolve as a human being but to take marihuana to improve, to live in a spiritual state
for a moment or two moments or two
years and then you have the after effects.
The organism will punish you.
The body stays outside and then fear of getting crazy, split, schizophrenia, fear of 'I'm becoming schizophrenic'.
It's a characteristic of Cann-i.
You will see the end effect. Fear of insanity in Cann-i. is the worst because it's a panic state which comes
almost 20 hours the day for
these people. It's terrible.
Nux-m. is not in this state, where they
get fear or panics. It is in between.
Still it's not gone too far.
As I told you before, when the organism
wants to relax, leaves the body and sleeps.
In Nux-m. it's exactly this. Because the body
is already out, you maybe talking to them
and you maybe looking in the Repertory because you search some symptoms they told you
and in front of you the patient is sleeping.
You see how easily they fall in sleep?
They try to read... and they go like that.
They will sleep at any
time without any problem.
It's not that they want it,
it just happens to them.
You understand how this function of going
out of the body is already ready to sleep
between dream world and real world.
That is the state of the mind of Nux-m.
Do you realize now that there are a lot of differences in reality when you examine somebody
between Alum. behavior and Nux-m. behavior?
If you have understood in depth
this, you cannot confuse it.
But it took me years and years before I understand these things and to be able to sort it out
and be able to give it out
verbally, to describe them.
I'm trying to describe something
which is intangible, which is subtle.
A state of the mind, its a very
subtle idea, to express it.
One has to live it to be able to transfer it.
Because if I use simply words, do you think you can differentiate? You will not understand the difference.
But now you understand that when you
have this great sleepiness, it's not Alum.
Little things but if you have understood,
you cannot make the mistake.
Alum. has anxiety, tremendous anxiety,
fears, not Nux-m. Nux-m. is ...
But the food she goes back to the kitchen and the food is burned out, she forgot totally
that she has put something on the stove
because she was talking and talking.
Finished, no food today.
Where is my wife?