I'd like to give you some information. These remedies are not finished and the information is not compiled.
I cannot really give you any good information
on the mental-emotional level of Sanic.
There are a few things that I have noticed.
Sanic. has a state of marasmus.
Marasmus of the body, of the mind,
of the emotions as well.
The mind becomes weak and usually there is aversion to any kind of mental undertaking.
Also if they do undertake something, they
do not have the stamina to go and finish it.
In a conversation they maybe jumping from one subject to another without really completing the subject on which they are talking.
There is some depression and also the feeling that something bad is going to happen.
In children we see some kind of reaction and obstinacy, they get very easily angry and they become aggressive and they throw things.
There are some fears that look like Calc.
Fear of dark, fear to work, fear that
something bad will happen.
They are easily upset, irritated.
Just a few general ideas. Many times you
will see a case which looks like Calc.
There is the perspiration, the desire for sweets, the desire for salt, perspiration around the occiput.
There is worse cold but there is a heat of
the feet that they have to stick out the feet.
A Calc. that sticks out the feet, think of Sanic.
If it is a case of Calc., you think it's Calc. but the feet are warm and they have to stick them out of cover, think of Calc. when all the other symptoms agree.
Especially when we have this typical symptom of perspiration of the scalp and occiput during sleep, which we all think Calc., then it might be a case of Sanic..
Also there is photophobia and lacrimation if there is some wind, which is again the same thing as Calc.
The only thing is that Calc. is
lacrimating from one eye in open air.
There are some ear discharges and ear eruptions excoriated etc. and the discharges of Sanic. usually are offensive and the offensiveness is like fish.
Any discharge from any place which
has the smell of fish indicates Sanic.
In the face we have acne and
especially acne around the chin.
Generally the skin looks unhealthy and also not nourished well. That's why Sanic. presents a state of cachexia, of mal nourishment.
Sometimes there is a burning in the tongue which is quite in the seat of the tongue and many times we will have to let it out and cool it.
We have desire salt, sweets,  fat.
In the thirst we have the same thirst as Ars., drinking small quantities frequently.
We have vomiting immediately after eating and also after drinking milk. The vomiting usually is forcible, like a rocket, like Veratrum album.
The abdomen is again like Calc., enlarged and flabby and many times children that are malnurished they need Sanic. instead of Calc.
We have a constipation which is like Sil.,
stool difficult to evacuate or  receding.
Sometimes you have flatus which is very offensive and sometimes you have involuntary stool and involuntary urination.
There is leucorrhea, there is also another smell characteristic of Sanic. and that is cheese. Like old cheese.
But the smelling of the fish is much more characteristic. The smell of old cheese is characteristic mostly of Hep.
We have all kind of lumbagos and pains in the back and in the extremities, we have this characteristic of uncovering the extremities.
The soles of the feet are burning.
We have quite a lot of cracks, especially
in the back of the hands here.
Sanic. has fear of robbers and
also dreams of robbers.