How many people have prescribed
Ran-b. so far in your practice?
It's not a remedy that is indicated very frequently but many cases which are going untreated, many times they need Ran-b.
we don't realize it and instead of Ran-b. we give other remedies. Which bring around a kind of
cure but it's not the right one.
It will take quite a long time if you give a similar remedy than when you give the correct one to bring about a cure.
I was also giving Ran-b. for intercostal
neuralgia when it was on the left side.
And almost that was the only thing that was working until I realized the type of person that
will need Ran-b.
Once you try one or two remedies before Ran-b. then more and more comes clear the idea of Ran-b., then you can prescribe it.
So I want to give you this
experience with such persons.
I'll try to epitomize the impressions and I would say that people that they need Ran-b., are touchy, discontented and angry inside.
Touchy means persons who are closed and easily hurt, very easily offended, very easily.
They appear to have a constant discontent inside them, discontented and easily offended.
The word touchy is very fitting for them. They appear to be weak and to seek help, to ask for help.
They seem to be very respectful of other people, they are proper. So they are sensitive, touchy, easily offended, there is a kind of discontent.
And they will seek help in a particular way because their remedy most probably will not be realized.
You will be giving different remedies, Ars., sometimes Sulph., sometimes Rhus-t., sometimes Dulc.
All these remedies they have
some similarities with Ran-b.
There is a characteristic of Ran-b.
When they come to seek help, they have a kind of respect that is given to the great Professor, Mr. Professor.
That respect, I don't know how it's called in your own language but great respect from a proper person.
'Will you please look my case? It's not that I'm not happy with the treatment exactly but some things are not going right
and I would like very much, if it is possible
for you just to have a look in my case.
And I very much appreciate your time; I know you are very busy and I have all this and...' he is seeking for help in a very respectful manner.
When you get to know them better, then they are very touchy. Great respect but the moment you say something that offends them a little bit
or you may not expect to be offended at all,
they get so much offended, they go to pieces.
I will give you an example. I recently had a
case and I was impressed by his reaction.
I asked a favor from him. I said, will you be able to tape, to make a copy of that, he is an expert in making copies and then I changed my mind.
I'll tell my secretary, I want more copies, give it to professional people. So I told him I don't need it anymore, it's OK.
He went to pieces. 'Why not? Did I say something that showed that I did not want to do it?', 'No, no it's OK, we just decided to give it outside'. Please...
This kind of respect which is too
much, which is going too far.
Now what happens with them is when they come to that state, the Ranunculus state, they have a kind of weakness and dullness in the mind
that makes them averse to undertaking further responsibilities. What they do the absolutely necessary, it is OK.
Once you tell them a little bit more, that little bit more becomes too much for them and they cannot perform it, they cannot do it.
There is a sense inside them, they are too weak, too sick, too unprepared in their body, in their physical fitness to take up some further responsibility.
And it is very interesting that very sensitive,
very touchy, very easily offended, why?
Because they think that they are very good in what they're doing; yet if a superior says to them
you have a future in our affair or you have a future in the school where you teach, there is a future in the bank where you are would you like that we promote you?
You take some more responsibility.
They will say, 'no please, I don't want it'.
They feel inside them that they are too sick.
'I have this headache which comes, indescribable headaches' and you get sometimes this cervical syndrome coming from osteophytes in the cervical region.
The circulation on the brain seems to be obstructed and there is a kind of dizziness, confusion, dullness and they are in a state of
'I'm not well. Mr. Professor, please'.
That kind of attitude.
You get eventually the idea that they are
very anxious inside concerning their health.
Because you take their case and they
say, OK headaches, stiffness etc.
But everybody may have headaches and stiffness but in their work they like to go forward, to be promoted. Why don't you?
He says, 'I don't feel well, I can't take much responsibility. I know it's very great for me. I can be promoted tremendously but I cannot do it'.
'Do you have anxiety? Do you feel really that you have cancer?', 'No'. They do not have anxiety of having cancer or a particular disease.
It's a kind of hypochondriasis almost where they just don't feel well. They may be coming again and again and you feel that this is a mental case almost with this kind of hypochondriasis.
It is not a big deal what you are telling me, the symptoms. The laboratory examinations will show nothing.
There is no real pathology underneath to account for this kind of behavior. Why is he behaving like that?
This is because he is Ran-b.
This is the idea. Another individual all together. How touchy they are, how offended they are and how respectful.
All this respect they expect you give it to them. You treat them with the same kind of respect.
If you don't, they become offended.
You will confuse that again with Nux-v. because they behave in this way, in their work, outside, in the society but once they are at home, most of the time they behave like that.
But there are some moments where the angriness is so great that it is released completely at a certain moment.
And there is such a fit of anger that I have been described as taking the child from here, lifting the child, with the idea to throw the child on the ground.
That was the fit of the anger. We have to treat the child, we have to give remedies to the child after this shock.
You see you don't get the idea because you are not familiar with the remedy. And you give Nux-v., you give Ars....
Because properness is another quality of Ran-b. They want to be proper. Everything they do it properly.
They bring you their cases very well written.
The symptoms in a line.
You get the idea that most probably he is an Ars. because you see the hypochondriasis. But the restlessness is missing.
The fear of death is missing. They don't care about death. What they care is just this kind of dizziness, headache... 'could you please help me? I cannot work'.
We miss that case. I remember cases later on, when I understood Ran-b., I remember cases where I have missed them, giving all kinds of remedies.
Cimic., Rhus-t., Calc-p., Calc., Kali's... nothing.
He would come with this respect and say, oh my god 10 years ago I had that case and it was a typical Ran-b. and I lost the case.
When I realized eventually what
is the type of Ran-b.
With those around them, very aggressive sometimes, beyond the normal reaction.
The child maybe shrieking, playing or making a lot of noise but still it's not that you grab the child and you throw it down.
And the touchy element. It will go into the physical almost. When they have a pain, touch aggravates the pain. They don't like to be touched.
They don't like to touch any point which is painful, whether it is a pain in the spleen, in the liver, in the chest, in herpes zoster, intercostal  neuralgia, whatever is the pain they don't like to be touched.
And yet also they are very sensitive to air, to open air or to cold water or to draft.
They will go out and they will have clothes and if a little bit of air goes through, immediately the pain becomes worse, immediately they feel miserable.
They have to be covered very well.
In Ran-b. we have an
aggravation from alcohol.
There is a strong symptom of alcohol. Aggravation from alcohol, especially the headaches, one of the main characteristics.
Yet I have found in Ran-b. cases a kind of aversion to alcohol or rather because they want to be proper, to do everything properly
and alcohol is no good to drink, they want to be proper and in socializing they say 'No. I'm not going to have alcohol'.
You wonder why he does not have alcohol. Sometimes because he is aggravated by alcohol, sometimes because of this proper element which is in them.
They want to appear proper, not doing something bad. It's very important, all this respect, 'Look how proper I am
and what do I ask you? Just a little bit of headache. I just want to get out this headache.
I'm so nice, I' m doing everything properly, I'm doing everything well'. This is the type of person.
The confusion of the head is as if they have drunk wine, as if they are intoxicated.
Even they have a great sexual appetite.
Great sexual desire.
But they do not express it, they will not. In a sexual intercourse, they will behave properly.
The sexual desire is great but the behavior is proper. That means they will never speak, they will never make sounds.
You see that proper element that goes through and you get the story.
You will be puzzled with such cases and then you will ask the wife, you will ask the children and you will get all the information finally. And you will say here is a Ran-b. case.
We're dealing unfortunately with human organism which are alive and all the time playing. It is like an energy which is floating, flowing. It's not a machine which is fixed.
All this sage, this understanding has to be taken into consideration before you can really do high standard Homeopathy.
Before you can really have results
on a steady basis, on a high percentage.
Otherwise you hit here and there sometimes a remedy, you get very excited, Puls. Everybody can recognize Puls. and Lach.
Sometimes Hyos. is mistaken for Lach. because of that reason, because of talking and you get excited.
And you really see the possibilities of Homeopathy. But unless you learn these little remedies that you will need ...
One day you will need Ran-b., the next day you will need another small remedy like Dol.
You have to know all of them.
This is very unfortunate.
Again another element is inferiority complex.
They will give you the impression with inferiority complex, yet deep down they believe that they do very properly and very well whatever they have to do.
Also they seem to worry quite a lot about the future, their own future, the future of their family, their children.
And when they talk to you, they will say
'yes. I have my children, what shall I do?
I have to have enough money to live with them because if it's something happens to me they must have money to live', etc.
But they will do nothing to promote their job.
Why? Because they do not have the energy. They feel that they are very sick and they cannot work, they cannot do more than what they are doing.
More or less this is the type. Then we have the intercostal neuralgia of the left side, which is worse touch, worse in the air, worse in the wet, worse taking a cold bath.
In the summer, for instance, they will not go to the sea and have a bath, if they have any kind of pain.
The pain is aggravated tremendously by taking a bath in the sea. It's not the sea that aggravates, it's the cold.
A characteristic pain of Ran-b. also is a round kind of pain, around the chest like a big spot, which is very painful, very burning and is worse from any kind of cold or draft.
The pain can be superficial, can be on the muscles or the pain can be felt deep into the lungs.
Together with this pain usually there is a malaise feeling all over the body that gives the impression that they are really sick.
There is another peculiar pain that you will get in Ran-b. in the back on the dorsal region, next to the scapula.
When they do little movement,
when a woman is knitting.
They do a lot of this and immediately there is a stabbing pain next to the spinal cord and between the spinal cord and the scapula.
It is just a spot, a pain on a spot there.
That pain can be also with another remedy
you have to remember about that, it's Puls.
And if this pain is on the upper angle of the scapula on the left side, between the beginning of the dorsal region and the end of the cervical.
Next to the upper angle of the scapula, it is Rhus-t.
But if the pain is as if your finger, put the finger right on top, exactly on that spot, they will say, that pain there...
Just as much as it is a finger, that is Kali-bi.
Extreme weakness, tiredness beyond
the pathology is a characteristic.
The time of aggravation for
Ran-b. is in the evening.
The aggravation from cold air, from wet, from cold bathing will bring to the mind usually the Dulc.
It will bring to the mind with this pain of the back, Rhus-t. But you will not have the restlessness of Rhus-t. and the type of Dulc. is another type all together.
They are not this type at all. They are
quite authoritative, another type.
There is an anxiety also which is felt in the
chest, especially in the evening and night.
And a general feeling of coldness in
chest is a characteristic of Ran-b.
This coldness can be aggravated, either by cold which comes from outside or from inhaling cold air.
With Ran-b. we can cure also cases of pneumonia, when we have cases of
pneumonia and cases of bronchitis.
With this oppression of chest, the inflammation, the aggravation from inhaling cold air, the cold spots on the chest, the aggravation from cold draft.
Pain also from deep inhalation,
it's not only Bry. It's Ran-b.
Walking aggravates but again in the open air. If they walk inside a small room, the aggravation is not there. Once they go out and they walk in the open air, then comes the pain aggravation.
Also there is another point quite strong. In the books it is not stressed but I have seen it in Ran-b. quite a lot and it is censorious, critical.
He becomes quite
critical of others, many times.
Fear when he is alone sometimes but not strong. Fear of ghosts also sometimes, not strong again.
Also there is another element, this proper element, this seeking of health. It may lead them many times, especially when they feel quite ill and painful, they seem to not be able to tolerate pain.
They go into meditation and try to seek solace and help from God. Which other remedy does that very strongly?
Aurum. Aurum is the main
remedy if somebody tells you...
I treated once a case of very severe
inflammation of testes on a boy, 20-22 years old.
In India. He has been treated by all the Professors and the Colleges and many
other people. Nobody could help him.
The testes were swollen and painful.
And he had different other symptomatology.
But the boy confessed to me that he had to pray. He says, 'I have to pray'. He was a Christian, there are some Christians in India also.
'I'm a Christian and I must pray but this is not a case that I can pray for 5-10 min. I have to pray for 1-2 hours before I go to bed. I have to do it. I can't stop it'.
This is the time when we have
a symptom "praying".
It's a compulsory thing. They cannot do otherwise. They have to pray. 'God help me', constantly praying.
It is like something which is
completely beyond the normal.