I would like to give you a small remedy
but maybe very useful sometimes.
I would like to give you the main points
of this remedy which is Dolichos.
Dolichos is mainly a right sided remedy,
which affects mostly the liver and the skin.
Its main characteristic is very intense
itching without an eruption.
A nervous sensitivity which comes to an exalted state, especially when we have that tremendous itching.
With this sensitivity building up in a Dolichos case, we shall have at a certain moment so much the intensity inside
and the despair because of the itching and the sensitivity that the person shouts... ah.
You will see this state in the last stages of cancer when the bile duct is obstructed and the bile salts are circulating within the body
and then the itching is tremendous,
is unbearable and is constant.
There is no moment that there is no itching and the itching is here and you scratch and it goes there and you scratch and it goes there.
This builds up inside the individual until that sensitivity builds up so much that reaches the point where really shouts, really wants to kill himself.
We have suicidal tendencies because of
that state, despair when this comes.
There is a kind of amelioration during the day. The day is bearable but as soon as darkness starts coming down, then the itching starts.
And the itching builds up as the time goes
by until 2,3,4,5 o'clock in the morning.
The individual can stay days
after days without sleep.
They are people that in the hospital they will be begging the doctor to kill them. It's such itching.
At the same time you will find something which is very peculiar to Dolichos and if you get that it's Dolichos;
together with the itching, together with the liver being affected, the bile obstruction is there; together with that you will get irritated gums with inflammation.
And there is a pain which is deep and
prevents sleep. It will not allow you to sleep.
If you have this kind of itching in the gums with a bit of itching in the skin also can be Dolichos.
But mostly Dolichos is when the itching in the skin because of bile salts in the blood is tremendous and the irritation on the gums is there.
These two, the combination
makes a Dolichos case.
Dolichos makes the person very restless, wants to get up from bed and move about all the time.
They cannot sit for a moment and as we said, it's worse at night, underlined 3 times and worse with warmth.
Warmth of bed, the covers of bed will intensify
the itching and will bring up the despair.
There is an amelioration from cold water and actually what ameliorates these cases are only ...
I remember a case on a liver problem with obstruction of the bile duct during the last months of pregnancy
where you may get such dysfunctions
and some problems.
And she was saying to her relatives to
hold her not to jump from the balcony.
The itching was so terrible and the only thing that ameliorated it was that they would make the bed sheets wet with a solution of vinegar.
She would be wrapped up the whole night with those sheets that made a little bit of difference, that made a little bit tolerable the situation.
This intensity where you will in a hepatitis,
if you have a hepatitis which starts with itching...
We have two types of hepatitis,
type A and type B.
Type A is of less infective hepatitis, the less strong hepatitis and type B, where the Australian antigen is positive.
In about 5% of all cases of
hepatitis, there is itching.
But there is a modification of hepatitis type A, which mostly starts with itching, and it is called cholangiolytic  hepatitis.
This is hepatitis type A but the main characteristic is this tremendous itching which starts immediately with the symptoms.
Therefore you have the urine in Dolichos, is dark, there is a constipation most of the times and if there is enema then you may get stool which is yellow.
But mostly there is hepatitis.
Another characteristic is that the
scratching does not relieve.
They will scratch and scratch and scratch and they will feel no relief from scratching.
What I'm describing has nothing to do with a
type of skin eruption that will have itching.
This itching I'm describing beyond comprehension. They will tear up the skin and then you will see blood running through.
There is much flatus with eructations, distention of abdomen with the desire to take out the clothing.
The clothing seems to be heavy.
So it's a remedy that will be prescribed mostly in hepatitis type A or in the end stages of hepatitis type B.
If the hepatitis is very severe sometimes will eventually go into that state of itching.
Symptoms of bile duct obstruction.
The despair, the sensitivity, the thoughts of suicide, a tremendous sensitivity which builds up, the shouting...
they shout like mad people and the desire to die, they are not afraid. They don't have fear of dying, there is no anxiety.
The only thing is the despair and they want to end their suffering by just committing suicide.
So this is a small remedy that it's going to
be very useful if you have that picture.
And it's going to act like a miracle. When the remedies are correct, you know how they act.
It's a plant.
I'm talking about the potentized medicine, I'm not talking about the herb that you go and drink it.