Manc. is an interesting remedy which in the beginning of my prescribing, I used to prescribe very infrequently, once every two years.
Until I came to know better Manc. and today
it is prescribed much more frequently.
Manc. is mainly I would say a phobic remedy.
But a remedy which covers a
specific realm of phobias.
So we have to have these combinations of fears and phobias that will give eventually the state of Manc.
Manc. I found it is indicated mostly again in women. And in individuals that are weak in will, with a weak will power and also weak intellect.
The intellect looks like the one that we recognize in Arg-n. but Manc. has not the impulsiveness of Arg-n.
Now this combination of weak will and weak intellect allows for certain fixed ideas to enter the mind and take hold of the mind.
In the beginning stages we'll see fixed ideas like a man may think that his wife is not really a woman but she is a homosexual who had an operation and now is a woman.
That is a crazy idea that sticks to the
mind and he cannot get rid of that.
It is an insane idea.
His rational mind understands that this is an irrational thought and he tries to get it out of his mind.
But the more he tries to get it out,
the more it gets hold of him.
They develop all kinds of these fixed ideas, especially in the night, in the darkness.
Fear of going out in the night alone.
In the night they have different ideas
coming and get hold of them.
For instance they have the impression that the cupboard is open and they look they are absolutely certain that the cupboard is open.
And this idea that it's open, I have to close it. Eventually they have to get up and close it but the cupboard is closed.
This imagination which goes on in the darkness, you may confuse it with what remedy?
-Causticum.
-No. In the darkness where they produce shapes?
Phos. mostly has that. In the darkness they imagine things. People standing there, shapes of different animals.
Here is not the imagination so much that causes the fear but it is the fixed idea that this has happened. The cupboard is open.
It is a fixed idea that they believe it is so.
So they get up to close it.
Now they have all these kinds of fears, fixed ideas that they cannot get them out of their mind.
Eventually the idea gets upon their mind that they are going crazy, which is characteristic of Manc.
They will try and battle to get away
the idea that they are going crazy.
The idea is fixed, they are going crazy. The person itself tries to battle and says 'no I'm not getting crazy'.
It says no, you're getting crazy, you're not getting crazy. So it starts inside a battle which is very true. Eventually it develops more and more and takes most of their time.
It takes most of their free time. My mind
is going crazy. It's a fear, it's a panic.
'I shall not think about. I shall
remove it from my mind'.
But again the idea comes suddenly in their
mind. 'You're going crazy'.
So this battle becomes very characteristic of Manc., the battle of 'I'm getting crazy, no I'm not getting crazy.'
There is another remedy who has that battle which makes them tired of that mental battle.
A suicidal remedy, they battle to kill themselves or not to kill themselves.
Nat-s. It has a similar battle inside them which drives them almost to the point of being tired from that battle.
Where the impulse is to just finish with this lifeyou had enough, this is not a life, this is not a world to live and then inside them they say
no, no, I must resist. I have my children, whatever relatives and I'm going to give them a lot of pain. I should not do it for them'.
And then again comes the idea, kill yourself, finish.
No, there is no way. And again, no I should not do it. This kind of battle, a similar battle on another remedy.
There is the peculiarity of these remedies and when you see that battle, the people will tell you, they will express these battles.
Whether is for being crazy or for
committing suicide is Manc. or Nat-s.
As it progresses this idea of going crazy, there comes darkness when they go to sleep. In the darkness there is an aggravation and the ideas take hold more and more.
We have fear of insanity during night, which is the remedy mostly which is mentioned in our Repertory?
-Calc.?
-No.
-Nat-m.?
A remedy which has aggravation in the night in general, is a syphilitic remedy. Mercury.
Merc. may develop similar pattern of Manc. in the night and is a tremendous idea coming to the mind, I'm getting crazy.
And they jump out of bed and they put on the light. I have to have some light and get over that state.
But when they are in the consultation room, they will not describe it in vivid colors, they will discuss it but they will not give you the exact words that you expect.
But if you enquire more and more, they will come up with the idea. They will make gestures like that. 'Something is wrong with my head.'
'What it is? You're losing your mind?', 'Yes, yes. That's exactly what happens. But I resist'. They will say, they resist. This is characteristic.
As the pathology progresses, the idea comes that during this they will become crazy and during that crazy spell, they're going to kill their own child.
We have other remedies which they have impulse to kill their own child, which are the remedies?
-Platina.
-Arg-n. is one, Sulph. is another, Nux-v.,
Thea, also, Plat. yes.
Plat. has impulse to kill in
general and Merc. also.
With Manc. is not an impulse so much, as the fear that they will get crazy and then during that craziness, they will kill their child.
It is not the impulse when they see something. There is a fear, 'I'm going crazy and when I'm going crazy, I'm going to kill my child'.
It's deeper. It's not the impulse
that we see in other remedies.
Other remedies they will see a pistol, a tool that will give them the impulse to kill. Manc. will have the idea of being crazy first and then she wants to kill the child.
During that time of crisis, they will almost shout out of fear and panic, especially if they are in an environment where it is conducive.
And they know that something is wrong now, they will let the child and shout out of fear.
Together with these characteristics that we mentioned already, we have another characteristic where we have a theme that
the soul of the person lives in darkness.
It's in darkness which
pervades the whole person.
And this dark element will come through
their describing to you their inner state.
That dark element eventually in some cases
will personify in the idea of devil.
The idea of devil comes into their
minds eventually in deeper form.
They will say that the devil is wanting them to be crazy, that the devil is responsible for the crazy  thoughts which are in their mind.
Some other times there is a dark element as we said and that dark element pervades the soul and also the sexual instinct, quite a lot.
Therefore there is perversion in the sexual instinct and a woman for instance will have a kind of desire concerning her brother or her father.
That, she understands it's not right and then out of guilt, personifies the father or the brother and then they appear to her as devils.
'My brother looks to me like devil. When I look at his eyes, he looks like the devil. When I look my father, he looks like the devil'.
This dark element eventually you will see in their description of cases, how it comes down to the idea of the devil.
And in the Repertory says, fear of being taken
by the devil. They have delusions.
One of the patients says, she has a lot of dreams with snakes but the snakes symbolize her own brother. And she kills the snakes.
The snakes in her dream it was as if it was the brother and she killed the snake. The snake is a symbol of sexualism.
And she says, 'I see my brother as a devil and I avoid to look at his side'. Consciously she says that; unconsciously is the darkness in that element.
We know Manc. has this sexuality.
But the idea of devil does not come
until certain pathology develops.
The idea is expressed explicitly that the word has a connection either with the inside, with the fighting, the devil wants to put his ideas in her and she is fighting the devil.
Or some other person outside is a devil
and wants to do something to her.
You see the mind how is undermined and the
will is undermined and these thoughts get it.
These cases are developing more and more in our today's society with the way that we live and the society we have developed.
And this remedy is going to be needed
more and more in your prescribing. It will do wonders when it's indicated.
The persons are suffering tremendously because it's not fear of devil you don't feel anything. When you hear the person saying, when you see them describing their state that they're going crazy,
you feel that what they are going through is a very shaky balance on which they walk. The least mistake will overturn them and they'll go crazy.
This is the impression they give and they suffer tremendously.
And the dark element and this idea of devil and this fighting inside starts to compose the idea of Manc.
Another thing that happens is that they go to sleep and suddenly They will see different kinds of color which they don't exist and then the fear comes.
'Oh, I'm going crazy' They have the impression that a kind of animal is going through. They turn around...it's a kind of jerk inside the brain.
The moment they get this fear is like jerking inside the brain. They look there and there is a picture on the wall, they look in there and they see the picture moving.
'I'm getting crazy', they paralyze, they will stop working. They're looking like lost people because all the time they have optical delusions.
Colours, moving objects, moving pictures on the wall. Somebody may have an optical delusion because he has something in the eyes but they don't take care.
For these people this phenomenon becomes a causative factor for the fear to jump up with tremendous intensity.
So this fighting of the devil, the expression of the person, you may confuse it with another remedy.
With Anacardium, fighting the evil forces. But in Anacardium always is the conflict between good and bad. Love and hatred.
In Manc. is the battle between myself and the devil. Myself and the evil forces.
And when they are reaching that state, going crazy or constant battle of the darkness etc. usually the sexual sphere is affected in a way and they attract sexual situations which are perverted.
And they go to the situation and the mind is confused and the will is weak and then they come out of the situation and they look back, and say what have I done?
The husband is the devil, the devil who has forced upon her a sexual intercourse which is not normal.
And these ideas they go on for years. And then in these cases during that time of being in that state, they develop solace in church in religion.
So what they do? They pray and they say,
'God save me from being crazy. I don't want
to be crazy, god please help me'.
In that respect when they will describe to you they will look like Aurum because there is depression in them. You feel very depressed individual.
And then you see the praying
and your mind goes to Aurum.
The Aurum prays in two different situations.
The one situation is where without knowing why they have the need to pray constantly.
And they go on praying, they go out praying. Wherever they are, they feel that they should pray constantly. Without knowing why, where it comes from.
They understand that it's too much. They say,
'I pray too much but I cannot do otherwise'. This is one type of praying for Aurum.
Another type is when they have been in a state of depression, real depression and they feel that they have lost all kind of connections with anything in the world.
They don't have anything to turn, to hold in the world. No husband, no children, no interest in their own home no interest in their friends, nothing.
And then the element of darkness coming upon them and then there is a feeling as if everything material has completely vanished and give no hope to that individual.
Then out of that complete detachment from material things he feels that now is the time, there is no meaning for me anymore.
That moment where the thoughts become conscious about that, he turns into God and says 'God help me' with the idea that they're going to die.
They're going to jump. 'Tomorrow, when I get up' because the Aurum aggravation is in the night and these things come in the night.
They think 'tomorrow it's going to be my last day. I cannot support that situation anymore. Tomorrow is the last day.'
But they receive that this isn't logical, this is not normal. So once they've given up completely, the idea of holding in something material, they turn on to spiritual.
It is not a spirituality which is going to stay. It is not something which comes out of a habit. It comes during the time of desperation and depression.
Tremendous desperation with a coldness inside, with a darkness inside. 'God help me'.
And this will give them a solace. This idea
will put them to bed, will put them to sleep.
That's Aurum.
The Manc. will pray out of the fear of being crazy. The dark element inside her.
Manc. is enjoying herself in this world.The  Aurum does not enjoy things, has lost any kind of enjoyment in material world.
Manc. is enjoying, is inolving herself.
Is an emotional person who needs the enjoyment of life. It's not a big depression and a big indifference to everything. No, not such thing.
But the intellect is weak and the idea comes 'I'm going to get crazy' and then the darkness inside, the evil forces that are trying to do that and then 'God help me'.
If you take it very superficially, 'praying' you may confuse Manc. or even Verat., Lach., all these they have a kind of religious insanity.
-What do you mean they enjoy themselves?
-Making the distinction between Aurum and Manc. Aurum do not enjoy anything in life, nothing is pleasure.
For Manc. everything is pleasure.
The sex, the food, the going out, the talking, everything we do gives  pleasure. To Aurum is pleasure. Both they reach a state where they pray.
Sometimes Manc. also out of this battle, these ideas which are crazy and they come year after year, they get tired.
They get absolutely tired with this situation and they think of committing suicide.
They have tendency to commit suicide, a suicidal part in Manc. at a certain point but then as soon as the ideas come, again the idea of evil comes into place.
So they say, the devil tells me to commit suicide, I'm not going to commit suicide. Because it's the devil who tells me to do it.
Another similarity you'll see between Manc. and Arg-n., there are ideas that come in their mind.
A Manc. is driving with the car and 1,5 meter away there is a man, she is passing with the car and then the idea comes, I have hit this person.
And they cannot continue going that way, they have to go all around back again to come back to see if they did not kill the person.
They have the impression they've killed.
So this looks like Arg-n. Also Arg-n. is from a high place. When Manc. has fear of a high place, they will describe exactly the way that Arg-n. will tell you the story that they fear.
When they see a height, they see themselves falling down and everything was in pieces.
It is very similar to Arg-n.
Similar ideas that stick to their mind, for instance that they pass with the car, they read something wrong and the policeman took their name.
So the policeman now has my number and
I will   get a ticket. Without a reason really.
Also fear of cancer and that again sticks as a fixed idea, 'I have cancer, no I do not have cancer'.
Fear of dead people. And it makes it
very difficult for them to go to a funeral.
So it is understandable how a Manc., that type of person, will be anti-social person. They don't like to go into great gatherings.
Also they have a lack of self-confidence.
In a big party they will the last
to get up and dance and associate.
-How that goes together with what
you say, they enjoy everything?
-They enjoy inside. They have not lost the feelings. They have the sense that they are half human beings almost because of that weakness which they have.
But their feelings are alive and they enjoy everything. They will sit there, watch and enjoy.
They do not have the self confidence to get up and take part and dance and associate.
And this kind of weakness, makes them have a feeling of being attached to the people who are living with.
Manc. depends a lot to the
people who is living with.
The husband, wife, the parents,
whoever is there.
And because of that attachment and that dependence, they develop an anxiety about the well-being of others.
You see in the books we have Ars., Bar-c.,
Phos., Sulph. for the anxiety about others., Cocc.
Each remedy has a peculiar anxiety about others. Now you can see Manc. how she is anxious.
She knows it's so deep that she has to have somebody to support her in times of weakness, especially in the night when she will have these fears.
And if something happens, they worry a lot.
That is similar to Ars. but Ars. is
not presenting this kind of weakness.
Bar-c., they are attached. It's the type of attachment of Bar-c. Because they feel inefficient the Bar-c. They want to hold on to someone who is strong.
More or less the same with Manc. But the idea that they need this person. The same as Ars.
But Ars. do not feel this type
of weakness of intellect as Manc.
Where Phos. and Sulph. have
completely different anxiety.
Also in Manc. I've seen another element. Because of that innermost weakness which they feel, they want to project in the society an idea of strength, of being strong.
They will not go around and tell that I'm weak. They rather present an idea that they are strong.
Therefore they present an idea which is different from the one they feel. They feel very weak.
But they say, I don't like that. I want to be
strong. Again the same idea, this conflict.
'I' weak, no I'm not weak, I don't want to
be weak, I want to be strong but I'm weak.'
They tell themselves, 'I'm strong, I can
do this, no you cannot do, you're weak'.
This is an inner battle which is going on and we try when they describe that case they will say
'usually when I feel weak I try to persuade
myself that I'm strong but I know I'm weak'.
-It sounds a little bit like Lyc.
-Lyc. they believe, it's a good question. Lyc. also deep down they are weak but they present an idea of being very strong.
Lyc. is external appearances. That means when they find themselves in a situation that no harm can be done, they can say anything.
Especially in women they make stories. They may say a story where a snake was, a big snake and I took the snake, they imagine that.
When a snake appears really in front of them, they run away. When the real thing happens to show courage, they are absolutely cowards.
But when there is no danger involved, they are the big men, the strong men, 'I can do this and that, I can fight with 3 people'.
When somebody bigger than them will say, 'go away', immediately they will go away.
That is the type.
Lyc. is one of the most cowardice
remedies of the Materia Medica.
And Gels. also. But for different
reasons all together.
Manc. gets for instance, irritable
inside and they will try not to show it.
They prefer small groups, they dislike large groups of people and sometimes they have a fear of crowds.
They are very easily offended but
they will not express their anger.
They lack the sense of humor
and they appear quite serious.
Such states of Manc. they will come about after a shock which has these elements inside.
For instance seeing a film, like 'The Exorcist',
a Manc. state can start from this.
Somebody who is Manc. can start from having a shock of that type, where evil forces are involved.
Also you will see a great fear of
something bad is going to happen.
And something bad which is indescribable eventually crystallizes in the idea, I'm going crazy.
The idea of something bad is going to happen,
is inside. It's going to happen to me.
Sometimes you will see a great
thirst before menses.
Physical ailments that can be cured by Manc., Respiratory system affected with hay fever, bronchitis. Skin eruptions, oily skin, colitis.
But mostly they will be treated for this mental-emotional state which I have described.
You can also sometimes confuse it with Puls.  because Manc. tends to be towards the warm side.
They cry a lot.
And like Puls. they are kind of
withdrawn or timid.
They weep out of self pitty.
Which are the remedies that
have fear of insanity strong?
Calc., Cann-i., Puls. and Manc. They are the first core remedies which have fear of insanity very strong.
Like Puls., Manc. they are ameliorated
by motion, by movement.
And therefore because they are timid, they will not get up and dance in front of a group easily but when they're at home, they put on the music and they dance.
Because motion ameliorates
them, it's like Sepia.
Now you have a whole picture of this remedy. With the fear of insanity, with the battle inside, with the darkness which comes more and more
in their soul, with sexual involvement and optical delusions, immediately is referred to the mind.
'I'm getting crazy', with the idea 'I'm getting crazy I'll kill my children'. And that picture when you see it, Manc.
And I'm sure you'll recognize
from now on these cases.
-They will always know that they have this conflict?
-Not always but in most of the cases I've seen. They say, 'I have battled with this idea a lot. I don't want to be there'.
And many times they will say it's the devil's work. 'I know it's terrible that happens but I cannot get rid of that'. Most of the cases I've seen that.
- They are going crazy?
-I don't know because I've seen these
cases with Manc., we've stopped them.
I have not seen further pathology where
they turn crazy and they still are Manc.
Most of the cases I have seen in the phobic states where Manc. has acted beautifully.
This state cannot be tolerated it very long. It's a very saddening state for the person and then you have to take drugs to relieve that kind of state.
-Do they also have fear of being
possesed by the devil?
-Yes exactly that's the idea. They will tell exactly I'm possessed by the devil. They'll described in other words.
- I had a case and she said that the devil told her that God was the devil and he was very scared about that and that the devil worked through her.
-Now in this case we're not sure about Manc. What we need is the element of this darkness upon the person.
There is an element of darkness which comes out, you see something which is not light and then you see the fear of insanity.
The fear that they are going crazy themselves. This is not enough to prescribe Manc.
This could be Kali-br. Cursed by God etc.
This idea may not be Manc.
-She had a fear of going crazy. At the same
time it was more light. Maybe it's not Manc.
-Why this  remedy is coming more and more?
-Because of the way that we live. The way we live like 'The Exorcist' the film is a product of our society.
Also the people go for things, for experimental things which are the brim of tolerance and limits.
Today's society has broken down the limits, has gone for things, for experiences which are beyond the  endurance of the system.
They push. You know the Essalen
experiment in America?
It's a famous institute in America with all kinds of experimental ideas which are very new, very fresh, very crazy and they take place.
They just originate from that Institute. That Institute is run now by people who are very intelligent.
One of these men who was running the Institute a few years ago, was one of the 10 most promising men in United States.
And one of my students had a connection with this Institute. And in 1980 we had a seminar.
Then I came in contact with the ideas that were going on and they pushed me,  just to give you an idea.
What crazy idea could go on. People would go there to learn to grow vegetables with natural chemicals.
So it was a group of 30-40 people, were the only ones who had books, no books were allowed for these activities which were going on there.
But the people who were digging the ground, producing the vegetables etc. they were all naked. The only one with clothes was me.
And you walk there, they don't pay any attention. I mean this experience, is not the nakedness so much that is important but the idea that they push themselves to the limits, the experiment.
Two people they jumped out and they committed suicide, while this experiment was taking place.
Excitement and what they thing is pleasant is pushing the individuals endurance of intellect and emotionality to the limit, and they go out of balance.
And once it's out of balance that society
is going to create Manc's, Merc's etc.
That's why I say that today we have Manc. I used to prescribe once every two years, here now in the last six months perhaps 10 cases of Manc.
-She was convinced that she was right what she said? But Manc. will be in doubt.
-Manc. will be in doubt. Not only she will
be in doubt but she will fight.
-This kind of fight means that he or she has to put the devil there herself? Because sometimes people who have troubles they go to the priest and then another person uses the idea on the first place. You prescribe Manc. then?
-No. It is an idea that happens inside, not with the other person. Also it's not just an idea, it is a fear, a panic.
Because somebody may tell you and not have an effect on you but if it has such a profound effect then Manc. maybe indicated in such cases.
In a Manc. case you give Puls., they are close.
And then it takes away the fear of insanity. But the impulse to kill the child is still there etc. You do not really see a deep action of the remedy.
You can imagine when you're shooting with 20 remedy what happens. It's creating confusion because too many attacking on symptoms.
- Drug poisoning seem to produce such symptoms. Such as LSD.
-Maybe Manc. can be used as
antidote in this case.
I have not seen delusions of the smell but I have seen optical delusions many times. What I'm giving you is not a book.
Initially I got the idea of the books and then
I had a feeling and then I got a feedback etc.
But then when a remedy is becoming much more in my mind, to look at the book is... I mean the book you can read it sometimes.