The desires and aversions
have to be strong.
Wants always to wet the mouth.
It is a characteristic of?
Ars., Bry. also.
Which is the remedy that wants to wet the mouth but they are not going to drink it?
Spits it. They want to wet the mouth because the mouth feels very dry but they will not drink it. Even a little bit of water they will not drink it.
There is a remedy which has tremendous dryness on the mouth to the extent that
their tongue sticks on the palate.
Nux moschata, yes.
Tremendous dryness, sticky mouth
and the tongue sticks on the palate.
They need something to water the mouth but they don't want to eat and they spit out water.
We do some comparisons.
Which is the remedy which is the
most thirsty in the Materia Medica?
-Phosphorus.
-Which comes close to Phosphorus?
Bryonia. And?
-Natrum muriaticum.
-OK let's go more specific. Let me see, which are the remedies which have great thirst for big quantity on short intervals?
Which are the remedies which have thirst for
big quantities on large intervals?
Bryonia, which other remedy?
Sulphur and Natrum muriaticum and it's Phosphorus. But Phosphorus can have short intervals also for large quantities.
-It's only Bryonia then.
-No, it's not Bryonia. It's capital.
The others are in italics.
Sulphur, Natrum muriaticum, Phosphorus
but they can have also shorts intervals.
What is the thirst? It's the need for
water in the human body.
From the pathology point of view
what do you find in such cases?
If they are seriously sick, what you
will see as a pathology?
They are not able to ask for water because they are in a case of comatose or semi-comatose state, what you will see in their pathology?
A phenomenon which is called dehydration. We see in such cases easy dehydration.
A person who is dehydrated very easy, it impresses you how easily he dehydrates, then you give Phos., Bry., Sulph., Nat-m.
Which are the remedies which they
have great need for sweets?
-Arg-n..
-Another one?
-Lyc..
-China.
-Arg-n. yes, there is a desire for sweets with a difference he desires things which contain a lot of sugar. Plain sugar and a lot of sugar.
Arg-n. will need sugar and a second characteristic is that in most of the cases if they eat the sweet, they become worse.
What is worse? The stomach. It creates a
lot of burning, belching, bloatedness.
Now the second remedy that
desires sweets really is Sulphur.
What is the characteristic of Sulphur
desire for sweets?
They desire the sweets especially
in the afternoon after sleep.
Also a lot of cream.
With white cream on top.
- Sulph. will also be aggravated?
- Yes but not as much as Arg-n.
It's not the characteristic.
When you have one symptom only,
it says eats sweets and becomes worse.
The first thing you think is Arg-n. There are
many other remedies aggravated by sweets.
But we're talking about something
which is stronger.
Lyc. also likes a lot of sweets and takes all kinds of sweets but the difference here is that he likes sweet liqueur but the sweet liqueur but will make him sick.
That will make him sick like the Arg-n.
gets sick from the sugar.
And they like it because it's very sweet but it makes them worse. They cannot digest it. It's too heavy for the Lyc.
There is another remedy Chin., which is in the Repertory which I have not seen a big desire for sweets on Chin.
Chin. is not one of the very desirous sweets remedy. In spite of being in black letters.
On the contrary we have
Calc. and also Phos.
With Calc. we have the same desire as Arg-n. desires sugary sweets, sweets with a lot of sugar.
And both Arg-n. and Calc. they require in their drink, a lot of sugar. Arg-n. in a cup of tea 2-3 spoons of sugar.
Phos. is known for his desire for sweets
but especially chocolate and ice-cream.
So you see from one symptom you can differentiate one remedy from another.
Nat-m. has not big desire for sweets and it's not mentioned in the Repertory I think I've added it because I've seen Nat-m. desire for sweets not as strong as this remedy.
-What about Kali-c.?
-Kali-c has desire for sweets not very strong but desire for sugar
They need the sugar.
- How strong would be if you have a person who eats constantly chocolate and also has salt on his bread.
- Arg-n. most probably will be the indicated remedy, because Arg-n. has also a
very strong desire for salt.
Also Phos. yes. But usually to see
both so strong, you see it in Arg-n.
In Phos. either you see desire for
salt too much or desire for chocolate.
- You mean either,or?
Either. And the other one is less but to have both very strong. Putting in bread salt in order to eat it and then eat a lot of sweets usually is Arg-n.
In case there is very strong desire for sugar and chocolate in a person. He had such a strong desire for chocolate that he had to make his own bar, 5 kilos a day.
He had to use a lot of sugar on the meat on the bread on anything. He wasn't satisfied.
- Usually that type will be Calc. Why? Because Calc. has the tendency to get fat whereas Arg-n. does not have this tendency. They eat but they don't put so much weight.
- She has said she's afraid of going over a bridge. It's quite a wide one but she couldn't ride a bicycle on.
- That makes it Arg-n.
- I gave her.
-What about the Lyssinum and the
chocolate? How often you see that?
- Lyss. can have desire for chocolate, sometimes strong but I've seen say 10, 20 cases of Lyss., 2-3 have this desire.
Med. has also both desire
for sugar and salt. Like Arg-n.
I think also Sulph. has before
menses desire for sweets.
If I look in my Repertory
maybe I will confirm it.
-Sulph. and Arg-n.