They also have vertigo in high places
but they will go up to find 5th floor.
Then we have Staph. and Nat-m.
But Sulph. also and these two remedies both Sulph. and Calc., you will hear them saying that if they drive to a place where there is a cliff
the idea of having a cliff there makes them absolutely dizzy. It paralyzes them.
They will go almost to the opposite
driving in order to avoid the cliff.
Because as they go along they feel the emptiness and the vertigo is strong.
Then you prescribe Calc. or Sulph.
You have to have information of that kind.
The Calc. has another characteristic of vertigo which is, can anybody remember it?
When they see other people, you see they are sitting here and they see somebody gone on the 5th floor and lean down there.
'They say my God! Please come in
I cannot see you standing there'.
One more characteristic of vertigo in high
places to all Calc.? Do you remember?
In their sleep they see dreams with vertigo high places. They see that they are in a high place and that they have vertigo.
When vertigo is mentioned as a symptom and
we take it in order to make our prescription,
it has to be something strong.
We can support our cases with vertigo high places underlined one or not at all underlined
but usually is not going to be Calc.
If the Calc. they have vertigo at all, it's
going to be quite strong.
Also vertigo in high places there is
another remedy which is Staph.
Staph. is more fear than vertigo.
Something between fear and vertigo.
Why fear? Does anybody know?
Fear of high places because Staph. sometimes has the impulse to jump from high places.
If they look from high places they have
the impulse to jump like Arg-n. mostly.
Now we're coming to the point where we must differentiate between Aur. impulse to jump from
a high place, Staph. and Gels.
They are shades of symptomatology
here. And it's not very clear.
Impulse to jump from a
high place on Repertory.
It says here 'impulse to jump
into the river':  Arg-n., Sec., Sil.
'Impulse to jump from high place':
Aur., Staph., Arg-n., Gels. and Anac..
Impulse to jump from a high place for Aur.
is a completely different thing than Arg-n. and Staph. and Gels.
So the differential diagnosis on impulse to jump on Aur. will not be just in a nice condition, he has no problem and he goes to a high place and then he has impulse to jump, no.
Aur. will be very depressed, he will have thoughts many times of killing himself and he never knows how. He has not thought how.
And the first time he finds himself in the terrace, he goes and looks and he says 'now is your chance'.
Out of great depression and as he looks down from high, the more impulse comes that they should jump.
But if it's a cool impulse, a cool impulse if you can say. It is not something that you can say they don't know what they are doing.
Then they know they say, 'This is your chance. Your suffering is going to finish now, you can jump'. Aurum.
You see this is the type of impulse that Aur. has out of tremendous depression, sadness, has lost everything.
Arg-n. is completely different. His work he is very happy, he is doing everything and he enjoys life etc.
And then he finds himself in a high place
and the impulse comes and he can jump.
It's another act all together. You see in the Repertory they cannot explain all these things.
The Arg-n. is very happy and then he goes to a high place and then the impulse comes and they imagine themselves falling 'Oh! How they will fall down, terrible'.
And then almost they put their foot to climb and go down. The moment they start doing the act, they retreat.
Now Gels. has also impulse to jump
but it's again a quite different affair.
It is usually done in a hazy state
of mind. The mind is hazy.
They have been suffering and suffering with headaches and things like that.
I'm suffering, my life is turn into pieces.
And then they go there to the balcony and almost they let themselves being drawn by the height.
It is a passive act of impulse. Like letting themselves to fall from a high place, it is that
type of individual.
In Staph. is fear. They have fear and vertigo,
they are afraid, they don't know of what they
are afraid. 'There is a vertigo but I have a tendency to jump'.
Also Staph's they are not supposed
to be mentally ill like Arg-n.
It's not an act of suicide
so much as an impulse.
Phos. and Puls.  have vertigo from high places also, it is a common vertigo from high places.
The accommodation from heights, it suddenly deepens in accommodation in depth and creates a kind of vertigo. This is a pure vertigo, is not very strong.
Usually they will have it once or twice in their life in Phos. and Puls. It can be there, 'Yes, I have vertigo in high places'.
Phos. will say 'yes, yes, yes!'. But you feel
it's not so strong, he says it in some way.
Where the other remedies will describe to you, they will tell you about their vertigo because vertigo is a big thing.
So even with one symptom, we go in Materia Medica, we can differentiate one remedy from another and then you will see and say, no that
is not Gels.. it's Aur. Or it's not Aur., it's Gels.
Then you repertorize, take certain symptoms but be careful that the intensity of the symptom tallies with the intensity of the symptom of the patient.
The intensity of the symptom of the remedy underlined 3 times, tallies with the intensity of the symptom of the patient.
Vertigo 3 times, Calc., Sulph., Arg-n.
But vertigo not underlined...Calc.
something is wrong. Maybe it's not
underlined, may be many things.