I would like to talk about Capsicum.
Capsicum is a remedy which is not used as it should
because there was no enough information about it
and reading the books actually there are not enough keynotes or precise information to use it.
What I noticed from observation all these years is that Capsicum can be indicated
in two different situations, in two different psychological make up,
which I think the one can follow the other or can be completely independent.
Before we go the psychological make-up
I would give you the physical characteristics of Capsicum which you will usually see.
The great keynote of Capsicum is obesity.
This is a peculiar obesity where the people feel that they put on weight so fast
that everything that they eat it turns to double the amount of food that they have taken.
What is also peculiar is that the stomach feels like a heavy sack
which is bloating from one day after another day.
Before I go further I want to make clear certain things.
When I'm talking about a remedy, I'm talking with the idea
that this remedy is the basic remedy of the person.
Sometimes you will get an added remedy on the top, as I explained you the other day.
What is going to happen in this case and what is the difference with that case
is that with this added layer you will see, when you give the remedy,
you will see certain of the suffering of the person goes away but quite a lot stays behind.
That is an added remedy, that is after antibiotics this Capsicum state is developed.
You go and give that Capsicum it takes away this flabbiness, whatever we talk about
and quite a lot of what we shall be talking about and then comes to the next level,
which is quite still suffering, the person is still not well.
But when we give a remedy here with Capsicum and we give it for that level,
then the changes which you observe are much more intense and deep and complete.
In all literature, in Kent and others, they speak about remedies
which if you don't know what to do, there is no symptomatology,
then you may think of Sulphur of clearing up the case,
then you may think of Thuja of clearing up a case; you know that idea.
Then you may think of Tuberculinum clearing up a case.
The clearing up of a case is actually this idea that there is a layer on top
which goes away with Sulphur, Thuja, whatever it is and when the next layer appear
and you can see it more clearly, the same happens with Capsicum.
Capsicum is one of the remedies that you may need as first remedy to prescribe,
to clear up the way.
Any remedy picture can come on top.
In such cases you don't get a really deep reaction but with second remedy
you get the best possible results.
When I described a Capsicum, I described it not on that level, on the lower level,
the typical Capsicum.
On this level you will see hints of what we are talking about now, not the full picture
but some hints.
So we see that we are impressed by that obesity,
which obesity now is coupled with an appearance which is quite unique again.
There is a flabbiness in the skin with a redness which is coming up
because of little fine veins appearing into the skin.
There is another appearance which looks like Capsicum, the drunk is the most close
description of a Capsicum face.
Bring that two degrees down, as far as intensity is concerned,
you know drunk is with huge nose and rough, I don't mean to that extend.
Bring this degree down, bring this intensity down and you will make a face of Capsicum.
So that tremendous obesity which has that feeling
that there is no strong fibers to hold back the intestines.
You feel that there is a flabbiness and then there is a sensitivity to cold.
So you get these persons that they will complain that they put on weight so easily,
they are so chilly and everything they eat, it turns to fat
and immediately you give them Calcarea carbonica.
What you will attain with Calc carbonica, what you will make in such a case,
what they will tell you when they come back? A Capsicum who takes Calc carbonica comes back
and gives you a report. He actually will say, I now have a better appetite.
And you will see they have put on some more kilos.
This is the predisposition towards the obesity and you stimulate in a remedy
which is very close producing obesity and you just make things a little bit worse.
Now you say I made a mistake, you go back, you look in the Repertory you see chilly
and easily tired, because they get easily tired and you give what? Ferrum metallicum.
Ferrum metallicum will make them feel a little bit more tired and a little bit more with palpitation.
They will come back and they will give you this report until finally you come to the point
and you say, see this face.
There is no face here that I can show you but I hope you understood more or less
what I'm talking about.
You put things together again, you say the chilliness, the tiredness, maybe is Capsicum
but now you want some more information about the person, about the psychological make-up
to secure that this is a case of Capsicum really.
What is the psychological make-up of Capsicum?
Capsicum are very sensitive people, very easily insulted, they feel easily criticism.
And they are very much aware of the opinion of others towards them.
Actually to survive they need the good opinion of others about themselves.
When they feel they are criticized, they go into a state of (?)
But the great mental characteristic of Capsicum is actually a sensitivity
which has a peculiar direction.
They get into state where a tremendous feeling of nostalgia overtakes the person.
They go into (?) of that kind of feeling. They leave in the past actually
and the events of the past take such, big part of their feelings
and the feelings are aroused to such an extend that they feel they can not live anymore.
They are overtaken by that nostalgia of the past.
They live in Seattle, they live in Connecticut but their years of childhood were in Washington,
so when they think of Washington and the events there which they are taking place,
they have great nostalgia. I must go back.
But they might go back to something which is lost.
This nostalgia comes because there was a love affair which was taking place in Washington
and the love affair was so unique that now they are in Seattle they think about it
and that becomes a tremendous thing.
A tremendously hurtful experience, not hurtful from the standpoint
that it was not happy by that time, no.
It was very nice and now there is something that they can not get it back
and how they are going to live now? The feelings are tremendously aroused,
as if the past becomes idealized, becomes absolutely...
There are no bad things happening in the past, all the past was beautiful.
What is happening now is very bad but the past was very beautiful and it comes up
and overtakes them and it is a feeling as if they can not live.
I had a medical doctor, a very nice man. You wouldn't understand that he was sensitive.
He was very social, very laughing person, with jokes and all that and he came once
and said to me, I don't feel well, I have depression and I have anxiety and all this
and I have that.
It is still the time where Capsicum was not understood by me and he was flabby
and he had that redness in the face and all that and of course I gave him Calc carbonica.
And then nothing has happened and I was searching and searching to find out.
I was talking a little bit more to him to find out that he was ready to go back to Cyprus,
the place where he was coming, now he was in Athens for the last 15-20 years.
He studied in Athens and all that and said, I just want to go back to Cyprus. I said why?
I asked him, there is a nostalgia for...?
He said, yes exactly I can not live anymore here.
He had his wife and children, he wanted to just leave them and go back?
Go back to what? I don't know. What is there?
Nothing but I just want to go back, there is something which overwhelms me
and I can not control it.
You see these are the feelings, the very easily aroused,
as far as past is concerned but in the books it says homesickness.
If you open your Repertory you see homesickness and Capsicum is there.
But a whole make-up is that easily insulted, you take something and he is insulted,
he will not retaliate.
It's not a person that he will make an argument against it but he will be very easily hurt inside.
Half people they can not go on for ever with this intensity of the feelings inside and this idea.
This past which can not be attained anymore gives a feeling of paralyzing,
the feeling of a person that can not keep on with life, he can not go on with life.
I think Kent mentions the suicidal disposition,
I think he says it's overwhelming suicidal disposition.
Actually I would like to have Kent's Materia Medica here.
Is anybody that has a spare one to give me? I want to look something.
I remember Kent is writing this and I believe she can confirm it, overwhelming (?) of suicide.
The way it is put there I think it is not given exactly the right context.
You see what they do is I can not leave the feelings of the past, they are so great
and the present is so bad, easily insulted. Somebody says something and oh,
he said it for me, he meant me.
He discuss it with his wife who was present in the situation or his friend and he says,
did you hear what he said? He said that for me.
No, the friend answers no. He said that because of that reason. No, no he said it for me.
And you can not persuade him but he is aware of what is going on,
as far as his (?) and especially a feeling of insecurity, which is inside.
There is a great insecurity which is mostly towards the financial side.
They do not feel insecure financially like the Bryonia, don't confuse that.
If you have that as a symptomatology, that is Bryonia.
I had a case, it was a skin eruption and I was taking the case and discussing with the man
and says no fears, no anxieties, I have some anxiety about financial things all over the world,
what is going to happen and all that. You keep on, some anxieties and you don't know what to give.
The wife tells you I want to tell you something about him when he is not present.
I said what? I'm interested.
She said, my god the financial insecurity that he has is so tremendous
that from the morning till the night, all the time he will speak for nothing else
but how we shall be secure.
We buy some (?) here and we have bought some (?) there and we have that security from that side
and that security from that side...
It is terrible, I can not stand it, I can not tolerate it anymore.
I don't care about security and I know that we are going to survive after all
but this is absolutely what is in his mind constantly. My god it is a terrible thing.
And I say that is Bryonia. That tremendous insecurity is Bryonia, fear of poverty,
fear that he will die in spite of what securities that has secured,
he will die as a (?) That is a tremendous feature in Bryonia,
which comes in Capsicum in less degree.
We talk about degrees and intensities in Homeopathy.
When you say anxiety, it doesn't mean a thing, when you say this person has anxiety,
it doesn't mean a thing but if you say this person has tremendous anxiety
and the anxiety was that she can not just sit in one corner, that kind of anxiety,
I don't know, there is a feeling which I don't know.
You get a description, it's not now anymore any remedy, it's one remedy and that's Psorinum.
That kind of anxiety is Psorinum, tremendous anxiety.
Tremendous homesickness, I don't want to live anymore, then that's Capsicum.
When you get fear of poverty, poverty, poverty all the time, that is Bryonia.
That's not prescribing on keynote, that's prescribing on essence
because we have found the weak points where... the chemistry of the body most probably
and the enzymes and the synapses produce such a state where they leave open spaces in the brain
which are concerned with financial security and they don't feed back.
They leave it open, anxiety and ... poverty and then... anxiety as what? I don't know.
So we are talking about degrees and that's why those that have attended my teachings
for some years, I've told them that I will change my prescription
if on that symptom you get two underlines and I said put three underlines
and that intensity of that symptom may change my whole prescription finally.
Just because the symptom is very intense it becomes another remedy.
So much intensity, so much sadness, depression, tremendous depression I just want to die.
I don't want to live. That is Aurum state.
The degree plays a very important part to understand the remedy in its degree
and its sensitivity and its peculiarity it is to understand Homeopathy.
I'm teaching you level 3 now, level 4 I'm teaching you.
Away from what you have learned to go and observe but that does not exist in the Repertory.
I mean when I have that I don't care whether in the Repertory is written pain on the right knee.
He comes and says pain on the right knee but your remedy is not there, what about that?
Maybe I'm making a mistake.
It's not that, it is because I prescribed on this context of things
that I disregard the pain on the right knee but sometimes when I don 't have that
and I have the pain on the right knee, I go and prescribe on the pain on the right knee
because I don't have this information, which is the essence, which is a deeper thing.
Now the easily insulted and the nostalgia, you understand the sensitivities of the person
and all that, it works on a level which is ...
Here is the normal level and here operates on that level. More higher in intensity.
So the five senses become acute. Eyesight, hearing is more acute.
Eyesight is very acute. Taste is very acute. Smell is very acute.
And he needs up to a certain time on that level over stimulated.
And now in this level is when he says I can not live.
The feelings are so strong that he feels he will die from feelings, from intensity of feelings,
he can not keep on going in life.
Now this state at the moment drops down to the opposite. This is the normal.
This is higher than normal.
Then he goes suddenly... he switches off and goes into a state
which is operating now under normal intensity.
Now what is the phenomenon on that state now and that can be Capsicum as well?
There the nostalgia is completely gone. The past is completely forgotten.
So you get a person who lives in the present and he does not remember, really he does
not remember. If you tell him, you don't remember that situation we were together there?
He can't remember. He passed as if he took a sponge and erased it.
Now what is left there as pathology...
One thing I forgot to tell you for that state, in this state which they are,
with the sensitivities, they have no fear or anxieties about their health, fear of dying,
fear of getting a disease. None of that area you will find in Capsicum.
When they go into that state again you see no anxieties and no fear
that are concerning his own health and his own well-being, as far as health is concerned.
No concern about that.
But what is left there is a tremendous anxiety and the insecurity he had in the beginning,
the material insecurity that he had in the beginning, it has become more now.
He is concerned therefore about his future and to secure his future much more than before,
when he was in that state, that brings about an indescribable anxiety,
which there is always in the background.
He works and he does what capable people do in their job but what they feel in that state
is that the mind that was working quickly...
Actually I would say that these people they talk with their feelings inside.
The feelings are so vague that produce thoughts. In that second state, they can't hear.
The feelings are subdued to such an extend that the possibility of reflection of a human
being stops and the process of reflection goes away completely.
So he realizes that he has missed something. He understands that this thing in which he is,
is not healthy state at all because events do not touch him anymore.
It is a kind of protection, self-protection which the self-mechanism is putting.
Before, the reason inside, the sub-conscious reason on such a case is that
before everything was making such a big impression, that stayed for life
and created such tremendous feelings inside but there is a point where he could not live anymore
with these feelings. Now what he does?
He cuts such of feelings, such of the possibility of receiving impressions from the outside world.
So he does not have feelings.
A great thing happened and he is not overjoyed.
A catastrophe happened, he is not overwhelmed with that. He faces it logically.
He says, now there is a catastrophe OK, what should we do next? That state of affairs.
But the reflection, the possibility of having these feelings which were creating thoughts...
What I mean by reflection? Do you understand it?
Is anybody who does not understand what is a reflection?
I will explain.
If you had not be described that case, you would never understand it.
You enter in that room or you walk out of that room in the garden
or we had been fighting inside here and then you say, too much fighting, you go outside.
And as soon as you go outside there is green and peaceful and all that.
Now you were inside here with the reflection that my god the world is bad and we,
human beings will never be able...This is reflecting on what is happening, what you see.
We'll never go to make it. Now this is the impression of the environment,
it gives you these thoughts automatically.
You go out now in this green and this beautiful and all that and you say,
oh my god after all... This is reflection.
There is a state of mind which is serene and nice and beautiful.
We can all work together, we can all make it, we can find ways...
The reflection because of the outside world, the impression that gives you brings
about feelings which are not exactly, as I call now, make them into thoughts.
They can be just states of being. That is reflection.
That is the outside world reflecting inside as the impression
and creating feelings and thoughts. That's a reflection.
That process, which is natural to human beings, stops in and does not reflect.
Because he was doing much reflection before and that caused him tremendous pain.
And he does not want it. He protects himself now. Green is nice!
He does not make it consciously. That is sub-conscious processes which go on.
He does not know what is going on. Actually he found out that after a series of antibiotics
or a shock he switched off to that state.
He remained 10 days attending the father and mother who were sick in hospital
and over tired and then the mother did not make it, she had a brain episode
and after that there is a switch. No feelings.
We say in Capsicum there is no feelings but it is not the state of Phosphoric acid
or Carbo vegetabilis where you see that indifference.
It is a minimizing of the impressions to the least possible, still the feelings are alive
but minimized, not strong feelings anymore.
The anxiety now overtakes and the insecurity is much more in this state.
And during that state we see that the sleep is disturbed and then he gets sleeplessness.
What kind of sleeplessness? He wakes up at 3 o'clock and he can not sleep anymore.
He has anxiety. Now he is very tired during all these days and these people
because of wrong assimilation I would say, they get that flabbiness.
Together with the flabbiness they get a feeling of being tired very much.
That feeling of tired is with brain also.
The brain gets easily tired, the body gets easily tired, the feelings get easily tired.
So when he goes to sweep is very tired and he goes to sleep immediately.
After 3 and a half hours he wakes up and there is a state of underlined anxiety,
which keeps him awake, he can not sleep anymore.
Now you may confuse that state with what remedy?
-Kali carbonicum.
-It is Kali bichromicum mostly. The flabbiness in the stomach and this tremendous
flabbiness, which is similar to Capsicum, is Kali bichromicum mostly.
I have been told by a doctor who took Kali bichromicum only, that a few days after taking it,
my stomach started become flabby, he said within a few days
he started getting flabby in the stomach very much.
So Kali bichromicum has a great characteristic as a general obesity,
it has it in italic but flabbiness around the abdomen and the stomach
is one of the main remedies, Kali bichromicum is one of the main remedies.
With the sleeplessness, which you get, you may confuse it.
The difference is that with Capsicum it is not the hour that counts
because if he goes to bed at 9.30, he will wake up at 1 o'clock.
After 3 and a half hours he will wake up and then what is going to happen,
he is going to stay two hours almost in a waking state and then he goes back to sleep.
Where with Kali bichromicum this person rather goes to bed at 1 o'clock in the morning,
he will wake up at 4,30.
With Kali bichromicum if you go to bed at 1 o'clock, he will get up at 3,30.
After 2 hours he will get up.
With Capsicum he takes at least 3 and a half hours, 4 hours of sleep and then he wakes up
and then he has the anxiety but because he is very tired he stays in bed and try to sleep
and tries for 2 hours, finally he sleeps again; he is so tired, he sleeps for another 3 hours.
And if he has the possibility, he will wake up late in the morning.
And then that sleep, if he can manage to take that second part, if he has the possibility
and the circumstances but that second sleep really helps him.
Otherwise he will stay with 3 and a half hours only and in a state
where he will be pushing himself all the time to do whatever he has to do.
In that state his mind, as we said, works slowly now.
He understands that he was a person who was perceiving very much before,
he was a perceptible person, very easy to understand something and now his mind is lazy.
It doesn't want to do anything unless he pushes it. His body is lazy also.
So he will have to push himself and since it's a person who is quite like Kalis,
that means his sense of duty is quite a lot there, he is pushing himself to do it.
But he will try to do whatever is necessary, absolutely necessary to keep on going.
The minimum possible. I'll give you an example.
He has his desk, he is a lawyer and he pulls out a case to study,
he studies the case of his clients and all that.
He puts all his effort and he concentrates finally on studying the case.
When the time comes where he has to take that back and put it in the file,
he doesn't have enough energy to do it. What he does, he leaves it there.
He pulls another file because to study, he will have to go and get it. He leaves it there.
3,4,5 cases are left there and then the books and he pulls out a book to study
because of such and such and he wants to look and the book is not there and finally...
he makes the effort to take all this and put back everything.
But he does not have the energy, you give him Capsicum and he will say, I'm ordered now,
I know what to do, I put it back, I take these notes and I put them in the right place.
Now he takes notes...
Sometimes I have sometime to classify and put it in the right envelop.
So he does the minimum of what is required from him.
A lawyer wants to present a case to the High Court and then he would postpone it
and postpone it until the last few days where he has to do it.
Then he takes it and pushes himself and tries to do it and he does it.
That is a laziness that is not a laziness.
I mean, you understand what it is.
It is lack of energy, assimilation is wrong and that's why now these people
what do they need in order to keep on going?
They need assimilation.
That's why there is a desire for alcoholic drinks, there is a desire for coffee
but there is a desire also, strange enough, for things which have very spicy taste and pepper.
Lots of pepper. They will put a lot of pepper, it seems that the organism needs that
to stimulate itself and you can have the Capsicum in desire pepper.
Red pepper and black pepper, anything that will be strong, hot, spicy.
Mostly pepper. Inordinate desire for pepper.
Kent was giving Lac caninum for that...
Desire and aversion, some will tell you.
This idea now, you understand that is (?) in every level and what is peculiar in that,
when a person is on that level is that they may have dreams.
During the dreams they live in a state of nostalgia that they used to live in the past
in the waking state. In it they have dreams of great nostalgia.
While they are in a place, they imagine that they are in Washington and a love affair
and the young years and what was happening there and there is a dream
which almost is frightening from intensity of feelings.
They will have the feelings that are waking up from a sleep.
I mean really that is if they are in that state. It is as if they are half asleep.
Like a person who operates with half of his brain. They are half asleep.
In that state also the sensitivity from being insulted, from being criticized is there.
What is lost in that state is that nostalgia feelings, this homesickness,
this over sensitivity towards that.
And then it is lost also the acuteness that was going together with that state.
The anxiety has stayed, the depression has stayed and the idea that life is not worth
living. After all he does not enjoy, again in that state. It is not a nice state.
And finally why do I work for?
I don't enjoy anything. And some thoughts of let me die, why not?
There is no fear at all about dying, about having a serious disease.
The Aurum depression that I was telling is much stronger, much stronger...
These people they will communicate with you, they will talk, they will seem to enjoy
quite a lot, it is not a deep enjoyment, a deep feeling that they have lost,
with a state of dissatisfaction from life.
Aurum can not. They can not enjoy anything. When that Aurum state comes, that's the end.
There is no anxiety on financial, material things.
That comes together with the feeling that people are insulting him, people are criticizing him,
so he can not rely on others.
You see the natural feeling of companionship is lost. They can not rely on somebody.
The husband or the mother or the sister or the parents, that is lost and they feel
that others are inimical, are against them to a much greater degree than reality.
They imagine that others are insulting them much more than they really do.
No, he doesn't go so far, it is the first hints of paranoia.
-Do they avoid people?
-No, they don't become antisocial but if you insult them, they will become psyche
and they will not talk to you. But they will talk with everybody else.
After a few days they will come back and they will talk to you also.
But they will get the feeling that you have criticized them. That has hurt them.
Not for long time, as long as the hurt is lasting. It is not like Nitric acid that can not forget.
Now coming down to local symptoms, Capsicum is very frequently indicated in mastoiditis
where there is inflammation of the mastoid processes and there are burning pains, very severe.
Capsicum is pepper. The idea of pepper and the sensation that causes must not leave your mind
and the pains of Capsicum are of a burning type.
You have a severe cold and there is redness on the soft palate and on the (?) there is
tremendous redness and tremendous burning.
All these details you can not go about and prescribe because there is inflammation
and redness and burning you will not prescribe Capsicum.
And that is the problem and that's why I'm not talking about details of that sort.
Because they will be useless.
What you have to keep in mind and you may use it is the whole, what I describe as the whole,
and the details will just confirm what you have been thinking about with a remedy.
There is another keynote symptom that Capsicum will get sometimes
that during cough only there is a tremendous offensiveness of the breath, as he is coughing,
which can be understood by the same person. By the person himself.
I think we have fear of being censored, it's written in the Repertory.
Just look in the Repertory.
-Yes.
-Is it by itself Capsicum?
-You see how strong it is? Censored, this is a word we don't use anymore, critical.
Fear of being criticized.
From what I have given you, I had information, hints from the Materia Medica,
from the Repertory to go and prescribe and have the feedback
and observe what has been done and then the picture has developed eventually.
It's not that I had some ideas on my own that some kind of enlightenment that this is Capsicum.
I observed and what I observed, I put it together and then I used it in another case
and I saw it worked and that is how I have developed what we call the "essences".
In the beginning I never thought that that's a big deal.
It was later that the people told me they are helpful.
In the beginning when I was teaching in the School in Athens I was giving Materia Medica
like that and I said, you go and study the case now and then one told me, no you must tell us;
it's much more easy to understand the remedy after we heard you talking
and put things together and then we go and we study the remedy.
Then it's much more easy for us to comprehend it. And that's why I give you this
and I hope it's helping someone.
You remember that it is sensitive to hearing.
That sensitiveness in hearing it becomes very acute if he is having chills, if he is feeling cold.
The feeling of cold is there I stressed that, that he is worse cold, in the beginning.
Now during that state where he is feeling cold the sensitiveness to noise is accentuated.
There is also a large sensation in the head and pain in the head during coughing
but this is also with many other remedies.
I just give you an example, what a Materia Medica could give as information.
It says, for instance, ulcers in the mouth, ulcers burning. (?) small, ulcers in the gums,
inflammation of the gums.
All this information is useless, if you take it by itself because all remedies have that
and it's very difficult to go by that local symptomatology.
And that's why we need information to differentiate between one remedy and the other.
Thirst before chill is characteristic, also another keynote is great thirst after stool.
It has diarrheas, all kind of enteritis, also constipation and it has hemorrhoids,
it has all kind of pathology which will not be very helpful to find Capsicum,
if you just rely on that local symptomatology.
Pain in bladder during cough also? Not very often because I think it's not so much indicated,
as we miss it many times.
It's one of the remedies that we miss quite a lot at least in the cases which I have seen.
They have this obesity here especially, don't forget that.
It's a tremendous feeling of a sac.
They eat a little bit and it bloats up and they feel as if they have eaten 2 kilos.
They have eaten only 250 gram of food and they feel as if they have eaten a kilo.
It's not a heavy thing, it's the general sensation. They drink a glass of water
and it bloats up in particular place.
Worse from exertion in the beginning, when they try themselves to put it into action.
But eventually they manage to put the body into some action.
-It's not like the Calcarea at all?
-Yes, there are differences but you can confuse it.
-Do they tend to be more intellectual or more (?) ?
-I think. I would not call them intellectual.
Sports and events? I can not say this.
-I can see how it's different in (?)
-They will not express it. That state, the second state,
down state will not be expressed in any way like Phosphoric acid.
Phosphoric acid will sit there and you will see that nothing touches him.
You talk to him and it does not matter. With Capsicum you have a live person in front of you.
He will laugh, he will talk to you like that, he will make jokes, he will interact with you.
Anything is according to what he understands his health and how he should be.
It's now functioning much less. He will tell you.
He will tell you that I have slowed down my mind and my emotions are not as vigorous
and alive as they used to be and they will describe it in the way I do it now.
Not the Phosphoric acid.
Sometimes you get the Phosphoric acid saying, I want to...I'm describing now Phos acid.
I went to... to high park. It takes all this time to remember high park, you see?
And I had a friend of mine who went to buy... ice-cream.
This, speaks slowly, thinks a lot, forget words... I mean I exaggerated a bit
but I have seen this is like that exactly, the way I described it to you.
So it's a different understanding. If I go inside and I see a case, I will not say, forget it.
Phosphoric acid is not Phos acid but if I see that I will say yes Phos acid.
You may think about that or Carbo vegetabilis.
-(?)
-Very good observation. Yes the mentality is quite different.
The Calcarea phosphorica is a dissatisfied person mostly.
It's complaining and complaining, moaning, sighing.
It's a different context all together with the Calcarea.
The sensitivity to cold is there, the  flabbiness is there.
Flabbiness in the stomach also is with Calcarea phosphorica and lowering of the mind
and not much reflection.
When I say there is no reflection I'll give you another example, to give you the degrees
and the intensity.
When I say no reflection in Capsicum, I do not mean a lack of reflection
that there is in Helleborus, which is much stronger. There it's really flat.
There is no mind there, nothing.
So in degrees and in (?) we have to be very careful and that's why we need the keynotes
to confirm what we see.
Ah, we see that is a keynote, we see it's worse during melting snow.
Ah, it's Calcarea phosphorica now what I see.
You see I confirm what I observe and I vacillate between Calcarea carbonica
and Calcarea phosphorica and Ferrum metallicum and Capsicum, which I have in my mind.
Then he gives me that keynote.
My mind goes straight there.
It's some confirmatory symptomatology always that will give you the differences most of the time.
... the second state can come about as another layer on a case.
It does not have to be in a person that you see in the that state,
you go back on his past and you will definitely see that state as well.
It's not necessary that when you back in his history you will see that state or that state.
That state can come about in a Natrum muriaticum case or in a Kali carbonicum case
where you see hints of what I talk about in Capsicum.
You see it as a top layer on this context.
-Isn't that true from (?) that you can see a stage (?)
-Yes, this is the idea that I have and which I have told you in the School.
What I have observed with the remedies and with the patients is that different remedies
have different levels of expression.
It's not necessary to have all kinds of symptomatology in a person.
For instance, good homeopaths with experience like Pascera actually.
Pascera is one of the best homeopaths existing and when he talked in Athens
in the International Seminar that was the first one that we had,
he said that when you see there are no fears, you can forget about Calcarea.
Calcarea is full of fears, all kinds of fears.
Now this is not my experience and I treated cases where you try to find a fear
in a Calcarea carbonica and it doesn't exist.
This level is completely untouched and natural and healthy, it has not been affected.
The mental-emotional level is not affected.
And you have only physical symptomatology.
So that's a stage of development of Calcarea carbonica.
The same with other remedies and they can go into different pathology.
In stages in pathology, mental-emotional pathology first stage, is anxiety
and this and that and second stage is delusions and hearing voices
and this and that and fourth stage is breaking up everything.
You know the Staphysagria? I mentioned a Staphysagria case the first day, I think.
A schizophrenia case, where she started throwing things...
OK, now when we talk about Staphysagria on a level
where Staphysagria is very much affected and suppressed and all that,
you will not see that aggressivity.
It will have to go to another stage of Staphysagria where the logic is cut off
and then the sub-conscious is throwing things.
This is the sub-conscious what it wanted to do all the time and it was not doing it.
That is another level in the development of the remedy
and in the development of the patient's pathology.
So they do have stages and we have to have in mind in studying the case
and seeing the patient in conjunction with the remedy,
that he maybe in that stage of the remedy.
The Veratrum album is a remedy which is indicated mostly in mental cases.
But I have given it to a pneumonia case and acted beautifully
without any symptomatology of the mental-emotional and these are examples
that many times you will see in your experience.
Therefore I have advanced the theory that there are stages in development of pathology
of each remedy, like there are stages in development of pathology within the person.
He goes from that state of pathology to another state of pathology, still the same remedy.
But another stage, another picture. So do not mix the stages
and do not expect to have stage two symptomatology in stage one necessarily.
Some hints of stage two might be in stage one but not necessarily.
You say, where is that? Not necessarily.
Where you see what I read you on Phosphorus hypochondriacal case. You remember?
I read you a hypochondriacal case where he ...what about my fianc,
should I get married now?
That stage of pathology of Phosphorus is different from the other stage
where we get the clear cut  fears, fear of the dark, fear of being alone,
he always wants company, he says fear of thunderstorms.
This is a level of mental-emotional pathology for Phosphorus
that if you overstep the marks you don't see anymore the fear of the dark.
You don't see anymore the fear of thunderstorms, yet it is Phosphorus.
Not necessarily you have to have fear of thunderstorms to give Phosphorus.
You see the person I read to you the whole thing, it has no fear of thunderstorms.
And yet it was Phosphorus.
So that pathology it is better, the fear of thunderstorm, fear of the dark,
not so much annoying as that state where his mind is defused in different things
and concerns in different other matters.
When you are treating a case like that and you give Phosphorus,
you may see coming back to stage one where he has fear of dark, fear of thunderstorms
and characteristics of that level.
That means he is progressing, he is doing better, don't touch him.
There are a lot of subjects which are still not clarified. I hope this is clarifying matters.
-(?) how often would you prescribe it without the physical symptoms?
-The cases I can remember now, I can bring in my mind they were all the obese type.
Maybe there is Capsicum state where there is no the obesity, especially in the first stage
I believe, in that stage where there is this coming of these feelings, maybe.
But I have not seen it. We must say 80% (?)
-Capsicum children?
-I'm not experienced with that.
What is also interesting is that everyone of us since we are taking these lines can work
and can bring information concerning these remedies, which are very badly
and inadequately described so far.
You can work and if you have a case give it to the Journals,
to collect that information slowly and complete it.
It's a lot of work that has to be done in Homeopathy in research. A lot.
And nobody can do it unless he is one remedy prescribed, he's a classical prescriber.
The others are lost completely. You gave three remedies, forget it.
What feedback can you get from that? The patient got better. Yes but so what?
As far as research is concerned, you don't advance the science at all.
In that second state whether there is still the sensitiveness to criticism
and the fear that will be criticized, yes in this state it remains
and it is almost accentuated, it's more even.
Fear of being criticized it is more, it stays there.