We''re going to talk on Aethusa. Did you have a look in Kent?
Then you know all what Kent describes about Aethusa?
All of the seriousness of the condition when it comes first with diarrhea?
The vomiting together, the vomiting in curt which is characteristic, the aversion to milk
and if he takes milk, he brings it out, very soon it becomes curts and brings it out and the
seriousness in the appearance.
The look of the person, he is looking very seriously sick with big sorrows.
Now all this that Kent is describing, he is describing acute cases actually in an Aethusa.
He does not give us a real hint on what is the chronic state of Aethusa
and we tend to use Aethusa until now on acute cases only.
I prescribed Aethusa on a chronic case quite early, that was in 1965, 1966.
Since then I have prescribed a few cases and what I found out; it was the chronic make-up,
the chronic condition of an Aethusa patient.
You have to be an artist to describe the make up of a person and I don't have a talent and
I do not speak well English but I'll try to do my best.
The Aethusa patient is what they call 'a man apart' or 'a woman apart'.
That means somebody who is living with his emotions, quite strong inside but not
communicative, not communicating them, not expressing them so much, actually very little.
This general characteristic of that patient what brings about?
It brings about a stuffing of the sub-conscious mind, a building up of the sub-conscious
mind.
There are people, as I said, that have strong emotions but they do not show them.
They will feel like tears are coming into their eyes but they will not really cry.
So the emotions are there but there is a kind of control and it's a kind of deep conviction in
them that it doesn't work communicating or I don't know how they've come to that
conclusion that they should not communicate these emotions.
So outwardly they may look like Ignatia but there is not the hysterical tend,
which is in Ignatia.
Ignatia after all breaks out in a kind of hysterical crying, where they don't.
But in the meantime the sub-conscious is full with the suppressions and the emotions that
these people get from the outside world.
Since they don't express it, they don't say it, they don't communicate it, then that
sub-conscious is always in a state of fullness, I would say.
Now what happens is when the logic, the logical mind sometimes goes to sleep, either on
the waking state or in sleep.
What happens is that they talk to themselves.
They talk to themselves either in waking state or in sleep and they will talk to themselves
when they are busy with their emotions, their emotions, their thoughts.
They go out by themselves and they walk and they are busy with their phantasies and that
is the time when they will start bringing out the stuff.
It is an interesting thing, I don't remember 'darkness aggravates' is Aethusa?
Yes, Aethusa is here, italics 'darkness aggravates'.
You will see in the Repertory, not in Kent's Materia Medica, quite a lot of hints of what I'm
talking about to you now.
Now with that loaded sub-conscious mind, they don't feel comfortable in darkness.
They are afraid that these sub-conscious things that they have been stuck inside,
they will come up with darkness.
The logical control will be lost and all these emotions will be stirred up and will come up.
So they are aggravated in darkness, they don't feel well in darkness and what they feel is
a heavy feeling in the chest, as if the air was thick and heaviness and then they have to get
up from bed and go and open the window and get some light inside and breathe and then
they will go back to sleep.
Now when they describe that state, you may confuse that state with a state that exists
with Lachesis or Grindelia or Cenchris or Carbo vegetabilis.
These remedies they have, especially Grindelia and Lachesis, they have an arrested
respiration, it is called.
The respiration is stopped and the moment that they go to sleep, they are on the process
of going to sleep, they feel that the respiration is arrested and they are going to be
suffocated and they jump up and they go and open the window.
Now the process is very much the same with Aethusa but in Lachesis and Grindelia is
much more a physical effect.
It appears that the vagus nerve, which regulates the breathing, is cramped or arrested or
paralyzed for one second.
During that one or two seconds that the whole thing happens, they feel that breathing has
stopped.
We cannot have an idea how that feels like but when these people describe it,
they describe it as something very dramatic.
Breathing stops and they cannot get another breathing and they jump up in terror and
they will go to open the window. In the meantime breathing starts again.
So it's not that physical with Aethusa, it's not that physical thing.
It is the darkness and the oppression of the chest that they feel that the dark is something
thick; which comes inside and they cannot really breathe.
But there is an aspect on Aethusa which is very interesting.
These people as they are loaded up, full with emotions, they have strong and nice
emotions, good emotions also. It's not only that they have bad impressions.
The only thing is that these people they are apart, they keep apart, they live within
themselves, for themselves. They need some kind of communication after all.
They cannot exist with that self content condition, which they are living all the time.
Now what happens is that you will see these people as animal protectors.
They collect animals, they like animals, they love animals.
They consider animals as human beings which they understand everything and they can
really communicate with them and they can really communicate with animals.
They will say hello Jiji cat how are you this morning? Ah you are not well.
They have 10 cats, 20 dogs, this type of people and they communicate fantastically.
They are attached to the animals, not human beings.
You will not necessarily find a kind of grief in their history, it is their make up when they
decide that communicating with human being is not a pleasant affair and they have decided
instinctively not to do that and they communicate with animals tremendously.
I had a case describing that and what about animals? Are you afraid of animals?
Animals, my best friends and all that. She had 10 cats and dogs and one got sick,
so she took him to the doctor to see him and the doctor prescribed some medicine.
When she came back home, she confused who was sick and gave the medicine to another one.
When she realized that, she said I was in grief for one month.
I mean they will not describe that state as something pathological, they just give you
information, they think that this is a state which is natural.
You have to love animals and everybody has to love animals but there is a line between
loving animals and living together with animals.
It's interesting again in the Repertory, I think it says 'delusions of animals'.
How in the sub-conscious this element of animals has come. I think it's also there.
Can anybody see if there is? I don't have a Repertory with me. It is there.
You get the impression that there is a fear here, I mean Boericke just copies information
which has happened, he never puts together things.
So you get the impression that there is a fear like Calcarea carbonica.
Calcarea carbonica has tremendous fear, she sees rats and has delusions of rats and is
afraid of rats. This is not the case with Aethusa, it is the opposite.
I'll just give you an example of what is the fear of Calcarea carbonica.
In the island where I have a small house, I saw a small rat in the house and I wanted to get
a trap. So my wife went to a shop and asked the man about a trap for the mice and he said
don't talk to me about that. That's why I don't keep it in my house, I don't want to hear about it.
So my wife told me and the physic was absolutely Calcarea carbonica.
So I said I'm going to test it, if that was a reaction really or he wanted to make a play or he
did really mean it.
So I went myself, I pretended I don't know and I said do you have traps for rats?
Please don't talk to me, I don't want to hear it.
I mean when he comes here for his tumor I'm going to give him quickly. He is a very fat
man with rosy cheeks and for Calcarea carbonica that information is absolutely valuable.
This, Boericke writes it but the way he writes it is as if he is afraid, it is not that he is afraid,
he is involved with animals quite a lot to the extent that it's best rapport that he has.
Now another thing which you can put together from the information that exists, there is a
real information that exists in the Repertory again on fear, on going to sleep.
It says there in the Repertory 'fear of going to sleep lest that he should never wake up
again'.
'Fear to close his eyes lest he will never wake up again'. You see in the Repertory,
Aethusa is italics. Can you find it?
Some Repertories have it with one, some with italics. I think we can leave it with italics.
I think this is a strong keynote symptom for Aethusa and it is really going to be there.
The moment that they close their eyes, that is when darkness really comes and their sub
conscious is aroused and they are living in an aroused state of emotional. They are not
calm, they are not serene people, they have strong emotions, they don't show them.
So outwardly they will appear like Natrum muriaticum or Ignatia but inside there are strong
emotions and I will give you another example of how they behave with animals.
Another lady who was collecting all these animals. Somebody went out with his dog I think,
together with the dogs from the lady's house attacked him and so much that most probably
he took a stone and throw it to the dogs and she said I wanted to take the car and run over
him, over that person that threw the stone to the animal. She has a tremendous connection
that exists with animals. When you give the Aethusa they will start discharging the animals.
They say now I don't have any more that kind of connection with the animals. That is
something which you feel perhaps is on the character or something like that but it is
pathology. And it is natural now, there is still the affection for the animal but it's on a much
more healthy basis.
I don't know that but they communicate, that's for sure.
Now again with this loaded sub-conscious, which is full of intense emotions, what you will
expect concerning their own people.
They are in the family, they don't talk, they will not express emotions and all that but they
fear that if somebody is hurt or died within the family, they will not be able to handle the
situation and they will go crazy. They say, no, don't talk to me about that possibility. How
you feel about your relatives and all that, if something happens? They say, don't talk about
that. I cannot handle it. I go crazy.
So you see again that part of aroused emotions and keep to their own but yet the emotions
are tremendously strong.
All this information allowed me once to cure a great spiritual man I was treating.
He was looking so old that you would feel that death is coming within a few months.
The big (?) in the face and he has been to all kinds of homeopaths, all over the world
because he was travelling and teaching and things like that and nobody was able to help
him. He was in a very bad state, he was taking allopathic drugs, he was losing his urine, he
could not contain his urine, there was a chronic bronchitis which was going on, which was
keeping almost a kind of dyspnoic breathing and there was a lot of mucus that was coming
out, tremendous weakness.
The emotions were very strong but very much apart, nobody really could communicate with him, come in real contact.
This is not enough to prescribe Aethusa but there was a sign, which is very characteristic
of Aethusa, if you see it. What it is? It is an eruption on the tip of the nose that they usually
develop these people. Just a small eruption on the tip of the nose which can be recurrent,
come and go or can be always there, either a bit more or a bit less but always there.
So if you get that, that should make you think of Aethusa and also Causticum.
These two remedies have that but Causticum tends to have the eruption within the nostrils
mostly and in the septum. Aethusa used to have it on the tip of the nose.
Eventually you see I understood Aethusa. It's not by that time that I'm talking about in 65-
66 when I prescribed in this case. I still didn't understand Aethusa very much but you see I
went away from all the other remedies that I might have given him and I gave him the one
that opened up the case. He had a big reaction, it started coming up a lot of mucus and his
lungs were clearing eventually. He needed soon another remedy but Aethusa really did the
whole trick, where he had been seen (?) in England, Elizabeth (?) of America, any popular
homeopath in India, every prominent doctor all over the world.
He finally decided that Homeopathy is not going to help him and had resorted to allopathic
Medicine. This man by this time was 69 years old, he is still alive, he has been 85 where
really the first time I saw him, I thought three months and he is dead. I used to go because
I was interested in spiritual people and I used to go to every spiritual man that I could meet
and have a private interview with him. When I saw him for the first time in lecturing, he was
looking so old, just to give you the impression that I could not look at him and I was looking
at the trees. He was terrible to look at him.
What Kent describes as a very serious condition, near death where it can become acutely
and soon or it can take many many years like him to bring him into that state.
So I said I'm not going to see him because to over exert a man who is in the bring of
breaking down it is not right. So I decided not to ask an interview from him and he was the
only spiritual person I never asked an interview because I felt he was going to die on 1966
and still he is alive because of Homeopathy.
There is a loading up of these emotions and they break out as irritability as the menses
approach. As the menses approach there is a great building up and a kind of irritability,
which is quite strong just before menses. Two days before menses irritability is very strong.
Two days during menses also. So between the first days of the menses and two days
before menses, there is a strong irritability which goes away as soon as the menses are
away. Now there is a peculiar circle as the irritability builds up in women.
The sexual desire diminishes and when the flow is over the sexual desire is shooting up.
Great desire after menses and then gradually going down until it reaches just a few days
before menses when it is nil, no desire. Before menses there is no desire and then menses
come and desire shoots up again; so it goes together, either irritability or sexual desire.
Yes, they will have their own theories in life, they are content in a way. They are self-
content, they seem not to need other people's theories to exist, they have their own and
they are content with that.
-Detached?
-Yes detached in an external way, that means they will never show the attachment but to
those who are attached, are so much afraid of losing one of them that can bring about
craziness. But this particular man, this spiritual man, had a brother who died at the age of
28, 29 and he was 30, 31.
The shock of his brother dying brought about tremendous changes in him. He went almost
crazy. He had a big order, he left the order and big changes happened because of that
death.
He was very attached to his brother but not spoken out, not showing. The moment that
comes the death he is almost crazy, cannot handle it, the emotions are so strong.
-It is very much like China.
-Yes, in a way you may say but there is no these loaded up feelings that there is in China.
In China there is inability to perform in the world because they feel tired, they feel unable,
they feel their mind is not working properly and when they go to sleep what is lacking in real
life, they build up 10 times with their phantasies.
They will go to bed and they will phantasize becoming this and that, whatever, their
particular phantasies, they phantasize all these things. It's something totally apart from
them and then next time they go and phantasy is coming up again and they go with phantasies, they build them up, they build them, 'building castles in the air'.
When they wake up in the morning and light comes on and look upon, what the hell, how did I do that?
There are similar states, we see the similarities with Ignatia in this case, with Lachesis.
With Lachesis when the flow goes away, youl have a big relief and the energies are coming back.
Now you may confuse that as Lachesis but Lachesis is relieved immediately,
when the flow becomes big there is immediate relief. You won't wait two days, it will be the first
day and that makes the whole difference. And then Lachesis jumps up from bed and you
may confuse it and give Lachesis in a case of Aethusa because they describe that getting
up in the night, I feel suffocated. When they say suffocated, you don't go really and
examine what that type of suffocation is and you see the relief from menses and you say,
what else do I want? Lachesis. And you make a mistake of course.
No, they don't have that, no jealousy.
-I'm not sure I understand, are they talkative, do they talk, they are quite?
-When they are in company they will be talkative and they will be talking about a subject,
they will take part, they will tell their ideas and all that. It's OK if there is company and if
there is no company it's also OK. But what they will not do, they will not communicate their
deep emotions to others. Emotional relationships are very difficult for them to establish but
they will talk about ideas easily and they are in a company quite good, taking part and
talking about. It's not that they sit there like Staphysagria where she avoids talking in a company.
Yes, quite a lot but as long as the emotions are not involved. They will not say, I love you.
I have great affection for you. That is very difficult. But that is communicating on an emotional level.
Communicating on a mental level it's easy for them and they can do it easily.
Communicating on an emotional level is very difficult. That's why they need the outlet with the animals.
When they say, hello cat, it's a communication on emotional level, it's not on mental level.
That is what they need.
I have not seen it myself but if you had a case like that, where the connection with animals
is strong and has to be pathology, you can give it, if it's a child like that.
Especially these children now they must be affected by milk, they refuse to take milk or if they take milk
usually there is a diarrhea or an upset on the stomach. You will have to couple it with other keynotes.
There is another element, I remember I described to you that sometimes there is a kind of
flash, it's not a flash, it's a change of color in the face and the look of the face becomes quite wild.
They have a wild look in their face. They go to the mirror and they look that
change, there is a physiological process which is going on and changes the look of the face
and make it look wild. That can happen during the menopause, the climacteric period with a
woman or other times also.
The differences with Natrum muriaticum are that Natrum muriaticum people do not have that intensity in feelings.
Their feelings are quite subdued and less in intensity and they are more.
How can I say?
The way I would see emotions in comparison is... Nat muriaticum are like that.
In comparison with Aethusa, the emotions are like that.
So what is the difference between this and that is that this has pointed emotions and aggressive emotions, more pointed.
These are stronger but there is no that element of maliciousness or it does not have to be maliciousness, it can be hurt.
An emotion which has been hurt and becomes pointed, becomes bitter.
When you get these people sitting in front of you, the one you will feel no vibrations that hurts you, with Aethusa.
With Nat mur you feel that what has happened to him it affects you also because there is a transaction on a level, as he sits there.
You understand his emotions are quite hurt and he is hurting you now also.
Aethusa are strong but not hurting. They have not been hurt so much.
These are very difficult things to communicate.
No, I can not say that there is a reason. It appears to have no reason for that inward
turning of their emotions and living with them within themselves.
It appears to be no reason,I don't know. Maybe we trace some reason later, I don't know.
This is information from 10 cases. But you see, you see 1, you see 2, you see 3, 4 and you
say what is the common element? Eventually you find out that there is some common
element with these people and you understand.
Temporary thing that comes and goes. Suddenly it becomes wild and stays there for some time and then it goes.
The mental ability. No, I have not seen but I expect this one is in a toxic state.
Aethusa on acute conditions can get in, then there is a kind of haziness or unclear condition in the mind.
But this comes together with the acute condition, which is a toxic condition mostly.
-Are any other remedies that we can confuse it with where animals become best friends?
-Not to that extend. That pathology I've seen it only in Aethusa but there are some other
remedies which will show quite a strong affection for animals and also Medorrhinum will
show an affection for animals, for nature in general and it includes animals.
Medorrhinum will appreciate very much flowers and they become excited with flowers, seeing flowers.
The same way they can be very affectionate to an animal but at another if the animal does not obey, time they can become very cruel. This you will not see it with Aethusa. With Medorrhinum,
you say get out or if the animal comes in the room and spoils something which is valuable, they will hit the animal, they become cruel by that time.
After this incident is gone, then they become very affectionate immediately. They will look and try to take it into the doctor. after it
So there is an extreme in emotions in Medorrhinum, which can become cruel on one side and very sensitive on the other side.
-Will they also tend to be cruel to the animal, without the animal having done something all of a sudden?
-Yes, I've seen that also. For some reason they hit the animal without real reason.
Child abuses, yes. Some extremes which are going on.
They are affected by heat and they are mostly hot in the summer, not in winter in a warm day, they don't bother but heat during summer bothers them quite a lot.
They say general things that they don't like the heat, they are bothered, it's not that they
will have a headache or will have a particular symptom under heat.
Again with Lachesis you may be confusing it.
They will be coming for any problem, for psychological problems, for having a kind of depression or anxiety or whatever it is, anything.
There is no particular department of action apart from the acute conditions where mostly the alimentary tract is affected.
But in chronic conditions... I had a case where it was a prostate gland which was building
In women you see Aethusa builds up before menses and after menses, in men it is periodical.
Periodically they get tremendous irritability and they look like Nux vomica.
This man got any remedy under the earth before he gave up Homeopathy. all
He was given this line, he was given Thuja, Nux vomica, Lachesis, Phosphorus, he was given anything.
They say there is a kind of change which happens in my face.  best
It's not a flash but the they can describe it is a flash and they look changes of the face and they just take another wild look.
I cannot say but I just remember that somebody mentions it because these things when
you don't know much Materia Medica they are just mentioned, they are passed by and we
try to find desires sweets, desires salt, something to hold on.
Like yesterday you saw what the problem was.
I was trying to find points where I can base a prescription and you see now the case?