We have another objective to establish an understanding of what is health.
And if we have accepted so far the idea
that an individual is functioning on 3 levels
actually we have to have a
definition that fits all the 3 levels.
What is the word that can characterize the definition on these 3 levels? The word is "Freedom" !
Health therefore, is freedom on the physical level, freedom from pain, discomfort. I'm not the slave of pain.
Did you ever have a toothache? Did you ever have a severe pain to see how much slave you are in that pain?
Can you think of anything else?
Forget it, you are a slave.
Freedom from pain gives the definition of health in the physical.
But there are people who say I don't have pain but I have general malaise, a general feeling of tiredness in my body.
So therefore the freedom from pain has to be completed by a sense of well-being.
So the definition on the physical level has to be like this. Freedom from pain has having as a state a feeling of well being.
I feel well. It's a long time since we felt like this.
When I was thinking about these issues and I was trying to get an answer, I have seen quite a lot of patients in the meantime.
I have seen healthy individuals. I remember a case of a villager who had come, not here, I was in Athens.
He was relating to me a case where his neighbour came and put the boundaries of his land a little bit inside his.
He says 'I took my gun, I went there and I shoot him'. And of course when he came to be treated he was after prison.
Very strong, but was he healthy? I thought this man is not healthy in his emotional side.
And then I treated a lot, here in Greece in these times 1960's still the Communists were people of great fanaticism and passion.
Down, the government and whatever !
And I saw their psyche was always in a state of, you know if you mention the word "government"....
And I said, is this a healthy state?
Then I saw other cases of people who were attached to another individual, usually a man to a woman.
A man came and he was a slave to
that passion for that particular woman.
His actions were irrational, totally
irrational, like the fanatics.
And you say, these are healthy people but in these levels something is wrong. What is wrong?
And then I saw spiritual people who were trying at least to attain it, they had a serenity and all that.
And how they faced all these
issues, with much more serenity.
The definition of health was completed by the idea of freedom from passion on the emotional level.
If you are very passionate you are the slave of your passion, whatever it might be.
Then I saw individuals who had no passion at all.
They were people that had no passion
for anything. No interested, nothing.
You lose your wife, it doesn't matter, you lose your home, it doesn't matter. He is a Mahatma, but he was not a Mahatma,
he was sick. He has apathy. That may give
you the idea of freedom from passion
but on the other hand you are apathetic.
So the definition on this level should be that the person has to be free from passion but he has to have inside him
a dynamic serenity, dynamic calmness. The calmness which is alive, not a dead calmness, not I'm indifferent.
I'm calm but I'm alive, perceptive. I think about everything, I perceive, I respond.
Somebody is suffering I respond, somebody wants my help, I respond, somebody wants to talk, yes.
I am alive but not passionate !
Either you have Homeopathy,
everyone has Homeopathy or die!
I take a bomb and I throw a bomb in the world because the world does not accept Homeopathy. I could be like this, why not.
Many of you think I am like this, it doesn't matter.
I am much more tolerant unfortunately.
So, I felt that the people who are really more in peace with themselves, they were more perceptive,
more ready to come to the rescue, that means you have more love. Love flows naturally, you don't say to yourself
'oh, I have to help'. If you say this, forget
it, the emotions are gone.
You make a program, today I'll help this, this and then you try to accomplish these things, forget it, this is not healthy.
But if you attain that state where there is no irritability, no passionate attachement to anything idea or whatever
then you may have a dynamic serenity inside
you and face calmly the situations.
Who can do it? Nobody, but I say this is the target of a healthy state. It is where we should be looking at
not that anybody is like that. Perhaps
some of you have some grandfather
whom you remember in the end years being like this but it's not an easy state to attain. So we are looking towards that.
And then we come to the mental state. The health of the mental state that is even more difficult to attain.
Because there we have to have freedom from - nobody has that - a healhty mental state
is a state where you are free from selfishness. You are not selfish anymore.
This is something for sure impossible for anyone to attain. All, we are selfish, I want this, I want that.
It is not possible to eliminate selfishness.
Because if you eliminate selfishness
that means the sense that I'm separate, I am a separate human being - this is selfishness;
I am and I want this, that and the other is 3-5 meters away, and the world is all around me.
If we can eliminate that then the state in which we enter is a different state. We can make a jump in the consciousness
and then we are actually connected with the cosmic consciousness, with God. Who can do that?
You see it is pure mechanics. The moment I'm here and I'm separate, I cannot be flowing into the consciousness.
I have the sense that I am here so everything will be limited, everything will be measured
from me to that distance, to the other person, to the other things.
If I can eliminate this idea, I'm nothing,
then I'm one with the consciousness.
It is a very high spiritual state towards which we may be going, freedom from selfishness.
It's the effort that everyone of us is doing every day to be able to be less selfish to be more in connection with that which we call God.
We cannot eliminate that. I feel that nobody can really eliminate his selfishness, this egoistic element which is with us.
It's not possible but we all try towards that goal. And I'll tell you something, the new generation
is thinking a lot on these lines. That is why by taking the wrong path they went into drugs, they wanted to
experience the sense of not being, so they took the drug and some of them they experience something so nice.
And then they became slaves of that passion which is called spiritual passion or whatever.
Because we can be slaves of our desire to become this, to become saints, one with the cosmic consciousness.