You told us that on the emotional level the freedom from passion will be the answer to health.
Do you consider there is negative passion
and positive passion in all the form of arts?
The greatest creative people of the world,
have all achieved things of passion.
You I believe, yourself, in a certain way
you are passionate about Homeopathy.
If you take the complete
passion from somebody?
- It's a good question. You see I am good as Homeopath. He is good as a painter and he is good as a musician.
These are qualities of the personality.
If I become passionate in a negative way as
I mean,
that will make me behave in a
totally fanatic way. That is disease.
That means, my passion has gone too far. I have become fanatic and everything is Homeopathy,
I don't accept any other system of Medicine,
I don't accept anything else.
Then, you'll look upon me and say,
well he's good but he's fanatic.
That means, in my psyche, in my emotions I am a slave of that quality of mine which is to be a good Homeopath.
It's ok but once I'm totally fanatic about it,
I am sick. Now what I mean passion?
I mean something that enslaves you,
it makes you a slave.
You may come and say, you are also a slave because from morning to night you think, you do, all is Homeopathy.
If I do this, I am also sick. The artists, most
of the artists, have a form of sickness.
I believe great artists have this freedom.
They paint something beautiful and they
leave it.
Some others they become absolutely engrossed with this passion and then there is an element of sickness in them.
You will say, Dostoevsky, do you know him?
The new generation doesn't know so much Dostoevsky,
Russian writer of previous years who wrote fantastic novels. He was an epileptic.
Does this had anything to do
with what he created?
Well maybe but he was free
of his disease in order to use it.
That means, I can have a disease and this disease creates a situation around me
then I'm sensitive and I use that situation
in a creative manner. This is totally different.
The fact remains that I'm sick
in a level which is not the mental.
It is the physical and it has
not affected the mental.
Mentally Dostoevsky was, according to me,
quite healthy mentally with a mind synthetic, artistic
but synthetic mostly, because his work was
quite a lot symbolic. He was writing novels
and symbols like the bigger writers like Shakespeare, their minds are clean and clear.
The moment they become slaves
of that quality, then that becomes sickness.
Dostoevsky was sick in his physical
brain and he had epileptic fits.
But without passion life is not interesting.
The moment you fall in love is the most easy
things for us to get high, apart
from drugs. And then you feel uplifted.
Well, a person who falls in love all the time there is something wrong with that, he goes into a passion state,
he becomes a slave of that connection.
For me there is a problem with him.
And you can see in Natrum muriaticums,
they fall in love very, very easily. Why?
Because they do not need real situations.
They look somebody and say,
oh nice he looked at me, everything happens in their mind. They are excited and then they go along
being in love for months. Then of course there is a time where they try to make it down to earth,
they get disappointed and then they
get in a Natrum muriaticum state.
That is a weakness of the organism,
on that level, which needs correction.
You give Natrum muriaticum
and they stop falling in love.
Well, not exactly like that, I exaggerate
a bit just to show you the situation.
You get a person, Tarentula, with all this sexual energy. A woman can go out in the street,
try to find a man just like that. It's noon time, hormones are rising, and she tries to find a man. This is pathology.
You give Tarentula, she will not go out anymore. Nux Vomica, these sexual remedies Platina, Medorrinhum.
I remember one Platina, she says, 'what have you done?' She never told me, she was going with a lot of men
but after Platina she said, I used to enjoy very much. What kind? And then they explain to me and I said,
'I'm sorry if you want back your
headaches, just drink some coffee
you get back your headaches and your enjoyments also'. You see, it's a pattern.
She was a beautiful woman she had a man this week, another man next week, another man third week
and there was a confusion when she came to me, headaches, confusion, depression etc.
It's ok I give her and say, oh I feel good but
I don't need anymore. If you don't need,
you don't do it. That's it.
-You agree that passion can be constructive?
It can be negative or positive?
- As long as it does not make you a slave.
Of course you love the woman you love.
But if you attach yourself... there is a point in a relationship, two people they get together
and they are very passionate
but they can also be free.
There is a time when one of the two gets attached, especially with marriage.
The day you get married, especially the
woman, feels 'now I got him'. You got him?
Now you are going to lose him. This is the time when the passion becomes negative and the
other person usually doesn't like it and starts going away. The moment you start going away, the other person goes behind.
These are rules which rule human behavior and then disease starts. This woman will be my patient,
in 2,3,4 years it doesn't matter. She will come
to the homeopath and say, 'fix me now'.
The moment that you are free from this, you have great passion to love and you feel free.
All the great love affairs that lasted were only those affairs that let free one another.
The moment that your passion overwhelms
you 'I want her, nobody will touch her',
then you are heading very fast for a problem.
The same with selfishness. The moment you feel, I am so powerful, the Prime Minister or whatever.
The moment that you have to lose or you have
to be free of that, you cannot, then you fall.
And then egotism and greed, I want more, more, more, no stop. You become so passionate.
Onassis, just to use a name that everybody  knows, he made a lot of money.
What are you doing? You are heading for severe problems. Onassis had an appointment with me,
one week before he fell ill,
when he came with his airplane here,
on Wednesday he had an appointment with me.
As soon as he came, he had a flu and the flu
was already affecting his lungs and he had a pneumonia. They hospitalized him in Athens, then they took him to Paris.
He had 70 medical doctors, from all over the world, the best and in 70 days exactly he died.
Every day they took away one of his organs;
they had a meeting, now we don't need this organ, take it out.
Cut half of the liver out, take out the lung, take out this, take out that and in 70 days he collapsed totally.
He came to me, why? Because he had myasthenia, he started to be paralyzed.
We made an appointment but we never came in contact. I never saw him. His karma was not  to see him, he went the other way
and he went fast. For me if I treat this man, he could not understand what he was doing.
He was stepping upon other people,
crashing them in order to make money.
Forget it, you are heading for severe
problem. The more egotistical you are.
Can you imagine somebody who is very egotistical, I am the best homeopath and somebody says,
'no you are not', you collapse. Egotism inside prepares us for disease which is quite serious.
I will describe to you the number 1, upper left. The white spots are the predisposition with
which this person is born.
There are predispositions on a low level, on the physical and the emotional and the mental.
This is a person with very good health.
That means he has a predisposition
here, for developing a skin eruption.
If this organism goes under stress he will develop a skin eruption first. If this is pushed forward, that means it's suppressed,
he will develop some deeper problems
let's say in the mucus membranes.
If this is still pushed inside, it may go up to mental level affecting a little bit his memory.
So there are other predispositions here which everyone has, that if this is kept on pushing, through wrong drugs,
then the predisposition will go deeper and
higher but the original predisposition is very low.
The big points are the points in which
each one of us have mostly sensitivity.
Somebody has sensitivity with their eyes.
Once they are affected, the first thing that
is affected is the eyes.
You have a high blood pressure and glaucoma. Hereditary predisposition for glaucoma. And you say at the age of 20,21
they are stressed and they develop glaucoma. Others have predisposition to develop heart problem or skin or kidney.
So not everyone under the same
stress will develop the same problems.
And there are organisms who
have much more resistance.
They are the lucky people who have
good organisms that resist and show
the predisposition on a very low level.
Then you go higher and deeper. And then you say deeper and deeper and then here you are
very close to destroying the
very deep part of the individual.
That is why you see sometimes just a love affair, the first love affair and a woman goes into a state of depression
and very soon goes into manic
depression or schizophrenia.
Why she goes into schizophrenia while another one she just cries out and overcomes the whole problem.
The natural reaction of the organism, we have defences which tell us what the organism can do.
And the most healthy people,
have healthy reactions.
That means if they must get angry, they get angry and they show it. If they must cry, they cry and they don't care.
This is a healthy reaction preventing a lot of problems that may come afterwards
if you keep inside.
That's why here we have a Nat-m,
a Nat-m here and here. All these can be the same remedy
with different predisposition. So this Nat-m
here, under stress she will cry out.
This here, she cannot cry anymore.
Crying is impossible for them. Why?
Because the predisposition for them
is quite deep into the emotional level.
They have a weakness in the emotional level,
the organ which is elected for reacting
towards a specific stress is not functioning properly and she will say, I cannot cry.
They lose their mother whom they love very much, they lose their children they cannot cry.
This is a bad situation which will lead eventually, because all the grief stays inside, it cannot come out.
The grief must come out naturally. You have a grief you cry, you shout. Don't be afraid of that reaction.
If you have grief and you see that the
person cannot express grief, you have a big problem to face.
Of course there are stages in between.
They can cry a little bit, they can cry a little bit more, very much or they cannot cry at all.
When they cannot cry at all then you
have here a situation which is quite serious.
Treating this patient here, you will move
down the predisposition towards these levels.
Always going towards the periphery.
Another thing which you have to observe
here, we say this periphery is the skin.
Now, see something which is very
important for you to understand.
An ailment of the skin on this level,
is a very severe skin eruption.
We have skin eruptions which
are of very severe order.
That means, the organism keeps it on the
skin but still the condition is very serious.
The moment that this kind of eruption goes inside, the whole person - you see this person here, here is the predisposition
it will go right deep in here. If this is pushed inside it will go right deep and destroy the person;
then you will have schizophrenia, manic depression and psychotic states which are very severe.
So a skin eruption is not so simple. We have eruptions which are simple eruptions, we have eruptions which are quite severe.
For instance psoriasis which can cover almost the whole body is a condition which is quite severe and I will put it on this level.
The moment that you push inside psoriasis, then you may have neuro muscular disorders, you may have psychological
disorders and the best you can have is psoriatic arthritis, that means a severe arthritic condition which destroys the joints.
The joints are deformed. This is the best; the next is asthma, the affection on nervous system,
peripheral nervous system, central nervous system where you have the psychotic conditions.
I have seen some cases treated with methotrexate. It is a very severe drug given for cancer.
And they have discovered that if they give it to psoriatic patient, psoriasis disappears. With what punishment?
The punishment is that these
people are driven almost crazy.
Their character changes, psychotic
problems, anxieties, fears.
In this model you will see something else.
You treat here the patient, let us say on mental level quite deep.
And if this goes there, that means outside, on that level on the physical body are the lungs.
So you treat here the mental or the emotional problems and then it goes to the lungs
and you have the development of a serious
lung condition which is like asthma.
So therefore sometimes you treat a case
and he says 'I feel better' and in 3 months later
the whole force of the disease goes to the physical body and then appears the asthma.
-On which level would you put somebody who cannot sleep at all? The sleeplessness.
-Sleeplessness most of the times is a disease connected with the emotional-mental level.
And actually not with this level but a level which is deeper which is the subconscious loading, the anxieties, the fears
which are not appearing as anxieties or fears. They appear in the subconscious during sleep
where after a little bit of sleep, they overtake
and then make the patient wake up and cannot sleep anymore.
If such a disease is treated allopathically the person may develop fears and anxieties which are quite severe.
They have not found a way to suppress this ailment totally. That means some people who have the problem
they have to take a drug to sleep, they are not cured and next day they have to take again in order to sleep.
If they find a drug that cures them,
that means after this drug, they now can sleep.
They will invariably develop psychotic
problems, usually phobias and anxieties.
-They stop dreaming.
-I don't know maybe the dreaming, we all dream, whether we remember or not is a different story.
But there are people really who suffer psychologically who don't remember their dreams.
You ask them do you remember any dream ever? No. They say 'I cannot remember any of my dreams'
and this for me points out to a block
in this level which does not allow communication.
Because dreams are of different kinds, not all dreams are the same. There are nightmares
and other dreams because of environment, you feel very cold or hot etc. you ate too much,
the wrong food and there are some
dreams which are informative.
They give you information. If you dream such
a dream you feel quite well in the morning.
And sometimes the information is very
exact for what is going to happen.
How many of you had such dreams,
once in your life. You see?
It's a phenomenon which is very common.
What about neurodermatitis?
Neurodermatitis is a quite serious condition
and goes up in the scale.
There are certain skin conditions which I don't remember now the names, which are very severe.
There are conditions like Hydradenitis.
Do you know Hydradenitis?
Which appears in the deeper tissues of the skin, it creates severe inflammations and then
you have big swellings and affects
the whole body, affects the face, the nose,
disfigures in the face, leaves keloids and it
is very painful condition with pus, discharging
for months or years.
They are not healing and this is a condition which is going quite high. There are other conditions which I have seen,
skin eruptions terrible, that you smell and you can't stand in the same room, it's terrible.
They have specific names which I can't remember now and they are very difficult to cure.
You have to be careful not to suppress them.
-Such skin conditions would arise
from a deep mental state?
-No, not at all. Leprosy which is not skin but it appears as skin on the periphery, is another severe disease.
You suppress leprosy and it goes there.
-Would a person being treated for such a skin condition and in the process the skin tends to
get better,
would it drive the mental up?
I'm asking out of personal experience.
I had cystic acne for the last 15 years.
This state brought out a mental state of not wanting to go out,
not confident and it brought up a mental state. I've been treated by Homeopathy for 15 years
no results and then I decided I can live with it because people still want me,as a physician, no matter how I look like.
-If you treat it locally, if you take antibiotics
and you put creams, you will develop most probably,
either cystitis or problems  with your kidneys
or problems with your lungs or liver.
Or if the organism is not strong
enough in this level, it may even go
deeper where it can cause depression, dissatisfaction. On the mental level,
you are never satisfied. What you are
saying it's true that the appearance
of such skin eruption causes social
problems which the social problems
affect all the organism and can cause mental symptomatology. But this is secondary.
It can go away very easily.
We say it's not always good to see such an eruption unless the eruption is of a low order.
The next question is, who is more sick?
A person with a heart problem,
a person with a liver problem, a person
with a lung problem, skin problem?
And previously to that understanding
your answer could be,
oh yes, the person with skin
problems is better. Not always.
If the skin problem is very high, we have a heart problem which can be of that order, right here.
And the skin problem will be there.
So treating the skin problem of that order you
may have actually the disease going
here and affecting the stomach.
And then treating this and you have another skin eruption of a low order, treating this, you go there
and you have some
effect on the memory; and you treat that and you have finally an eruption which comes out and it's of low order.
-To say that a skin problem is high or low according to the severity of skin disease or according to what?
-According to the prognosis that we have
and the severity of the skin eruption.
Is anybody dermatologist here?
Let us say, we have a disease on the
skin which is called Epidermolysis Bullosa.
How many people know this disease?
It's a disease which seem to affect the skin,
that means the person is born with no possibility to build the skin, he remains without skin.
The absorption, the elements which he needs, he cannot take and therefore the skin is not built.
You have children without skin.
If they touch anything there is a wound.
These children live up to the age of 7-8 at the most. This is a very severe skin condition
which leads to death.
Where an eczema is very low in order.
A usual acne condition is very low.
So if you are treating a woman for premenstrual problems and you cure her, you may see
she is developing some acne. This is quite good. But now if I ask you who is more sick,
a person with a heart condition or
a person with psoriatic arthritis?
Psoriatic arthritis is on the joints. Heart problems are on the heart; it is an organ which is more deep
more affected and therefore the answer that comes immediately is the psoriatic arthritis.
-I think it depends on how severe is the heart condition or is it just arrhythmia or something
that threatens life. It depends on the severity.
-But if you treat a heart condition and then arthritis develops what happens then?
Is it good or bad?
-Good.
-Good because it goes to the outside, yes.
But on the other hand you say that
the heart condition might be milder than the arthritic condition because it is psoriatic arthritis.
Reumatoid arthritis for instance is a disease which is much more serious than simple arthritis.
It is a systemic disease which affects the
whole organism and creates problems
with the joints and the person is really deformed.
You can have arthritis, rheumatism with no problem.
So what is the measure? The question comes many times, who is more sick the one
who is depressed or the one
with heart problems?
The one who has bad liver condition
or the one who has anxieties?
The one who has very severe skin eruption or...
It is very difficult to measure
health, to say who is healthy.
I'll give you another example.
We know that people with very
good minds died from cancer.
People who are saintly.  In India they have Ramakrishna, died from cancer.
-Krishnamurti?
-No Krishnamurti was my patient, he did not die. Ramana Maharishi, another saint from India
died from cancer.
You will find a lot, where the mind is so clear
and the soul is clean they still die from cancer.
So we have  to find a way to measure health.
To say, this person is healthier than this one.
In our effort to cure somebody we have to measure this, we have to know where we take this person,
from this point to that point. From this point which is low to a better point, which is high.
We have a case a man who works in a bank and he comes to us and says, 'I have this and this problem'.
Then we give a remedy and he says, 'I cannot concentrate anymore I have to leave the bank'.
Yet the ailments for which he came, pains etc. are better. He left the bank, this is no good.
He says, 'oh well I' m too bored',
he gives different excuses for not working.
Not good. That means we have done something to his organism which has promoted disease, not health.
-Some persons work in a work which is not good for them because they lack the energy which is needed for them
to find their own path in life. In such a case,
if they leave their work and begin to work
with something which is better for them.
This is not something bad I think.
-Yes, I don't talk about such a case.
I talk about a case where he says, 'I have headaches
and lack of concentration', you give a
remedy, the headaches are better but he says
'I cannot concentrate anymore in my
work and I have to leave my work'.
This is not a good development in the case.
It is different if by choice a person says
'now I'm going to leave this and do something else'. But his choice is limited by the fact that he cannot concentrate
and he cannot add numbers. So in this condition we say we did something wrong with the case.
What is the measure?
What measures health?
-We have to think how much the karma in which we live has to do with what is ill and what's not.
To think about our task in life and whether we have finished it. According to yoga we have 3 kinds of karma,
one of them is the one which we have to work on  this life but on the other hand we also have to build up in this life.
So if yogis and people with very good minds still develop cancer or other severe illness
that means that they are taken from us because that is their karma. They have to stop living
and there is nothing we can do about it.
This is something that goes beyond our work.
-My answer is that looking upon the problem in this way, is looking from the angle of spirituality.
I'm trying to look from the angle of Health.
How we, practically, can know what is going on in a case we treat?
How will we evaluate whether this
person is doing better or worse?
I have seen the most confusing issues when somebody gives a remedy, especially if the person who gives
the remedy is your opponent. You work in a
town where there are 3 Homeopaths.
One gives a remedy and then the patient
leaves him and goes to the other one.
He will say, 'well he gave you the wrong remedy'. What I want is that you have the understanding
to know whether really the person is
doing better or doing worse.
The person may be doing better but because now he has more pains, he leaves the one
doctor and goes to the other.
And he says 'I have more pains'. The question that you have to ask is 'how are you in these different levels?'
If you are better in these different levels then
I have to say, he gave you the right remedy but
I have to have the knowledge to tell you that.
And later on when I will show video cases, you will see what happens with the evaluation of a practitioner.
Oh you are doing so badly !
And the person is doing excellent.
Why? Because they do not have this
knowledge we are talking about.
This knowledge is absolutely necessary.
-I think we can measure health by looking
at how many inner prisons a person has.
How able is to say, ok I'm doing this or that.
How much he can make his own decisions
without having forces that tell him, he has
to do this or he can't do this because of this
and this reason, on the emotional or physical level. I think health is the absence of this kind of prisons.
-How much freedom you have, but how
do you measure? I'm trying to find a rule
that will measure the health of everyone
of us. What is Health, equilibrium.
-I think you have to look at the person as an individual and see if he is functioning better than when you saw him the first time.
So if this person when you first saw him was at least working and now he's lost his job this is not a good sign.
But had he changed his job and gone for something which makes him feel better, then that would be a good sign.
-You are answering on a specific example.
I'm trying to find a rule, a measure of Health,
a rule by which I will be measuring Health everytime. Because the problem we have to face here
is not whether the body is healthy but the whole human being is healthy. This is the problem.
The problem is that we have a human being
that has mind, spirit, body, psyche, emotions.
You see the idea which prevails in the Medical schools is that if the body is healthy, you go
you have a check-up and everything is OK, go.
He goes out, he takes a machine gun and kills a few people.
But his check-up was good. Yes, but you did not have the  means to make a general check-up.
-I think measurement could be if somebody is creative. You could measure by looking at his creativity.
Because somebody who has pain and in spite of that can continue his work and somebody
who has a few pains but does not have any joy of living. So I think creativity would be a way to measure.
-That's correct. Creativity, how much creativity
is in an individual. But if we leave it up to
here, will not be good.
I will tell you some people who are very creative.
There is somebody who has very creative ideas, for instance one of them is how to rob a bank.
He collects his friends and says we do this and that and we all become very rich very soon.
And then he has another creative idea of
how to rob the yacht of the person in the sea
and then another creative idea etc. I take this away which is not very good example
but I will take another example of the person who has a factory. I have a factory and I create a product
which is actually nothing but we go to channel 7, which sells such products and we present
this product; it's a ring right here you wear it
and you are almost cured by everything.
Next day everybody buys the ring, give me the ring and next day the man is very rich of course.
He had this creative idea. So somewhere we
have to find the balance of what is happening.
You know the robbers are very healthy
people; they can run so fast.
They can give excuses so fast that even the trained police go into a kind of limbo;
they don't know whether he
is telling the truth or not.
I mean fast minds, fast runners, what's
this, the mind is very clear, very fast.
So we have to have another parameter  to measure real health. What is the other parameter?
-When somebody is happy with what he does and is not thinking that he wants to do more and more which he can't do it anymore.
When you are happy with what you
do and what you have.
-They are happy if they get over
20million  they are happy.
I repeat the question. She says, you ask the patient if he says 'I feel better, I have more
vitality,
I sleep better', I know he's doing better.
But she's answering the question how do you
evaluate the effect of a treatment.
I do not ask this question at this moment.
But I'm asking another question.
I say how do you measure health in general?
How can you say this person is
more healthy than another one?
-I think how useful the creativity is for the
bigger society or how much he exeeds
the egoistic self.
-That's correct. I will give you another example
of somebody in Athens who is known for
working only for others.
He really works all the time for others. He helps anybody who is in need here and there.
He lives by himself very poorly but still
he tries to help everybody else.
Is this the super healthy person?
-No.
-So you have to strike a balance.
You use the creativity for yourself as much as
you use the creativity for the others. If you can have that balance where the creativity serves your needs,
at the same time serves the needs of the society, then most probably you are in the best
possible health.
Now, it depends on the kind of creativity ok. A carpenter is a person who creates a nice table.
If that serves others it is a good creativity.
That's why usually a good carpenter is
quite a healthy individual.
But the creativity of the man who produces this product and selling it 20 times over its price,
that man with all his greediness though he is creative, this is not healthy. A lot of people have such talents.
They have the
talent of making a lot of money.
That means they are selling a product that
costs little for much more. That is not
serving the society.
It's tricking the society. It's telling lies to the society in order to exploit the society, he is not healthy.
If I have some needs which I don't take care
of and always I give to others, that means
I am not healthy either.
So both extremes are going for disease.
-I think if you got the freedom to do what makes you most happy, you will be in the best position
to do a good thing for yourself and the rest
of the world and that counts for everyone.
-Exactly, this is what we have been saying.
If you are in peace with yourself,
you will be able to do the best.
But what I say is that there are a lot of people who are happy in making money for instance.
This is a happiness which depends on how much they earn. This happiness is not what we are aiming at.
Because the moment you are going to lose the money, you are going to be unhappy.
We've been talking about the cooperation of the 3 levels that you cannot stop your emotions
and do what pays you or you
think is your interest.
You have to go according to your emotions
and to that which is feeling best inside you.
There is no question about it. But if you look from outside and you make an evaluation,of your health,
after all this, you get a mark. And you say 100, 98, 97, 96 and it goes down.
So when a person is sick and comes to us we have to know to what degree he is sick, to measure his health.
And by talking and understanding, then
we are in a position to evaluate that he
is in degrees 87 or whatever.
-We can measure it by looking at the
product of creativity.
-Well, this is looking partially. What I'm saying
is that whatever is your creativity,
it depends on specific points which
characterize your personality.
It has to have the element of serving
your needs and serving society as well.
Unless it has this element, then
somewhere there is an imbalance.
A depression therefore how deep it is? When she says I cannot do anything due to the depression.
That means that her creativity has totally destroyed her, that depression is worse than
a heart problem.
She has a heart problem but still can
function, can create, can go ahead.
So therefore when you treat the depression
and goes into the heart problem,
once the creativity rises, then
it's a better state of health.
-This is a very relative way of judging
and the judge has to be involved enough
to understand the level of
evolution of your patient.
And then when you judge, each time will be all the 3 planes on how much better the person is?
-I say these things to you who are going to treat patients and you have to know what you are doing
and not spoil a good reaction of a remedy.
For the person himself is very difficult to measure the state of health in which he is.
For you also will be very difficult to know
exactly the measure of creativity.
What is the opposite of creativity?
Destructiveness. How much destructive
a person is? To what level?
In Scotland, this man killed all the children of
the class. If he had a check-up I'm sure he would be very healthy
in his physical body. Actually he was a gym teacher. Athletic, he was quite healthy.
But I'm concerned to bring out
another idea, how we measure health.
And this person measuring health, in this way
I'm talking about, it might had come out quite sick, quite ill.
It is a different idea all together but we are bringing new ideas, new thoughts in the
medical science.
Because unless we do that, there is no progress.
So I made you think about these ideas and
as we go along, these ideas will be more
and more
clarified and completed in their meaning
and we may have eventually, a kind of
check-up totally different from the
check-ups we know today.
I'm talking about a machine which evaluates
your voice, evaluates your look,
the texture of your skin, your
answers to certain questions etc.
Then you have a real check-up and you
say the person is healthy or not healthy.
Now the society you see it's gone totally
in the wrong direction.
Everything is material but we have the proof in front of us that not everything is material and still the medical profession or
medical education refuses to study the human being; it studies the human body.