Theory 17
Thank you. I see a lot of new faces. I want to welcome
you all and wish you have a fruitful week with a
lot of enjoyment and knowledge. I just wanted to
know who is coming for the first time in Alonissos.
Just give me an idea who has come before.
The Romanian group? The majority. Brazil?
Moldova? Croatia? Pakistan? Greece? There are
more from Greece. Egypt? Belgium? India?
I remember the phrase of a historian, Toynbee, who
said India the conquered will conquer its conquerors.
You are conquering the worlds with you philosophy and
your yoga. France? French are usually very scanty.
England? Russia? Only one Russian. Spain?
Turkey? Ukraine? U.S.A.? You come to
conquer us? Or we have a chance? Austria?
Ireland? Slovenia? Sweden? Latvia?
A lot of human races are coming together in a peaceful congress
and I hope that this peace that will exist here will spread
all over the world because at the moment the world is upside
down and I am afraid it is going to go much worse very soon.
I hope you will be the missionaries of peace
in your countries. Here we try to transmit
knowledge for curing people and we try to do
as much as possible with all our efforts,
heart and knowledge but this is not enough because the
world needs urgently good homeopathic treatment because
Homeopathy is either good or nothing. Either you find the
correct remedy or you are just upsetting the organism.
This is the problem with Homeopathy and this gentleman
here does not allow me to look at your eyes and
see how you feel about the whole situation. Unless
each one of you becomes a missionary of peace,
spreading the knowledge which you receive the world
has no chance, will kill each other, we’re the most
clever animals existing on earth and we can kill each
other very soon and totally eliminate ourselves.
I feel the world is preparing for a big clash, a big
conflict, I don’t know when it will end. I hope and
we pray it is not going to happen at least in our time.
Your time I don’t know… I hope not in my time too.
I was thinking what I shall say. It’s customary in the
first lecture not to see cases because this seminar
is primarily seeing cases. But it is customary in the
first hour to speak about some theoretical matters.
I was thinking what should I tell you and most of you have
heard about the levels of health. And most of you were
intrigued by this idea and you came to learn about the
levels of health. I thought I’ll give you my secrets;
how I arrived in this theory. What preceded this theory,
what happened and finally I came down with this concept
of the levels of health because this concept is new
not only for Homeopathy but for Medicine in general.
Most of you know that I started treating
cases in 1960, 55 years ago and by chance or
whatever you think, the will of God, people
were coming to be treated by hundreds,
so I had the opportunity to observe
what happened if one applies
the idea of Homeopathy, of the
similar remedy, in an organism.
From the first years I realized certain phenomena
that were happening after prescribing the correct
homeopathic remedy. I must tell you that by that time
my success in prescribing were much higher than now.
The reason is that the patients now are much more damaged
in their immune systems than they used to be during
the 60s and the 70s. Pictures of the remedies were
much clearer, therefore the successes were impressive.
You give one remedy and then there is an
aggravation in chronic conditions and then there
is an amelioration. My first observations
after prescribing the remedy was aggravation,
amelioration and soon after people would call me for
an acute. I have an acute, what shall I do now?
You told me not to take allopathic drugs so please
give me the remedy now because you are responsible.
Sometimes they were aggressive, they said you are
responsible because I never had this problem, for the
last 15-20 years I never had high fever. Now I have
high fever please give me the remedy to cure me.
I felt, invariably, I had this phenomenon
coming that means people who claim they never
had an acute before for years, now after
the remedy, they were developing an acute.
Then the second observation, if I prescribed a
correct remedy for the acute the effect on the
level of health of the people was impressive.
They were jumping into a state of wellbeing.
On the contrary, I was observing that those people
who either by ignorance they came to me for a
chronic condition now they had an acute and went
to conventional doctors to take allopathic drugs,
they took allopathic drugs and there was a relapse of the
chronic condition, then they would come back to me having
a relapse, why you had a relapse, I had an acute and
took antibiotics, cortisone and then I had the relapse.
I describe to you my observations in the beginning
years. I was realizing that when I was asking
them when did you have last time a high fever 39-40
Celsius. I can’t remember, when I was a child.
When I was prescribing a remedy
for their acute they were
feeling, they would tell me
many times, young again.
They have lost through the chronic condition the joy
they were feeling as children and now after the acute
and after treating the acute they were feeling again
as good as they used to feel when they were children.
Then I took the medical history and I saw that this
person who was having acutes with tonsillitis,
cystitis etc. 20,30,40 years ago these conditions
stopped getting acutes after a period of time.
Then I realized that most probably their
chronic conditions has started when they took
antibiotics and they suppressed their acute
condition, whatever it might have been.
Actually I realized that their condition has started many years
ago and then you could see in their medical history they were
developing certain conditions for which they would take more chemical
drugs in order to suppress the conditions that were arising.
As a result of this process finally a diagnosis
was put like now you have an autoimmune
disease, L.E., M.S., asthmatic condition. I shall
give you an example of what was happening.
I took the medical history of a person and says I used to have high fevers
until the age of 14, then I remember I stopped with the high fevers
and then I developed sinusitis and then I took antibiotics and then I
developed hay fever and then I had drugs for hay fever, anti-congestants,
cortisone to stop the hay fever bothering
them and eventually they started with
difficult respiration and after a while
they started with real asthmatic condition.
So when they come to us and I see the history and then I give a
remedy and there is an aggravation and then amelioration and
maybe after 5 months needs a second remedy and some cases after
a year a third remedy some cases after 2 years of treatment,
4 remedies already, then there is a reappearance
of an acute. I considered this as a
very important observation because I concluded
that the organism has a continuation,
the organism is not something broken, you have
tonsillitis, you give a remedy and finished with
it, then you have sinusitis, I give antibiotics
and finish with this part, then you have asthma,
I give you anti-asthmatic and
finish with this part, then
you have insanity… I say there
must be a continuation.
If the organism is not reset, if it
has not come back to real health
by a medicine or whatever then continues
to be sick on a deeper level.
It can continue every time to go into a
state on deeper chronic condition more and
more. I said wait a moment, something is
happening here that you cannot ignore.
That means you cannot suppress a condition
without having the effect upon this organism.
And this effect will last for life unless you
have the means to reset the whole organism.
What was the difference between treating people in the 60s
and treating people in the 21st century? The difference
was that by that time the organisms have not been
through excessive drugging and excessive vaccinations
therefore their immune system was still
intact and you can work with that
immune system and stimulate it correctly
and then you have the results.
But if the organism is harassed by
repeated injections and introducing drugs
that affect the immune system then
the harmony of the disease is lost.
Disease has a harmony but if you inject wrongly
different things to fight the disease, it
starts be convoluted, confused and what appears
in the end after 30 years of wrong treatment,
appears an organism who is confused and you cannot
see really what is going on. And then you have the
diseases we get here, they will give a catalogue of
pathologies of which they are suffering at this moment.
That means all the systems and organs of the
body have been affected by this process of
suppressing the condition. Give me painkiller.
This morning I had a case which I was treating,
she developed some acute so she took
anti-inflammatory drugs first and then heavier drugs
and she ended up in the hospital with panic
state. And then she writes to me "save me".
Because though she was a student, she had
heard some things here, yet she went and took
the anti-inflammatory drugs instead of
asking, I have this problem what shall I do.
Such an organism who is not allowing the
picture of the disease to manifest and
closes the expression of the disease… Our
imbalance has some expression all the time.
I don’t feel good, I feel tired, I have a
headache, the headache comes in the evening,
then I have some vertigo etc. All these
symptoms are expressions of the disease.
If you have a headache, take a remedy to stop the
headache, if I have a pain in the guts I take
an anti-inflammatory drug, if I have pain on the
right hip I take another anti-inflammatory drug…
You don’t allow to see the full imbalance of the
organism fully expressed. It is so important that
people who are quite sick with chronic conditions
to go through suffering allowing things to happen
so the one who is attending the case
will recognize finally the remedy which
is indicated. There is another phenomenon
which happens with homeopaths;
the moment that a patient has some problems calls the
homeopath and the homeopath immediately jumps giving a
remedy. That most of the times doesn’t correspond to
the full picture, it corresponds to the local picture,
therefore giving a kind of
suppression to the organism as well.
The homeopathic remedy can also suppress the
manifestation of the symptoms which you
know in order to reach the organism the
state which I call the harmony of disease.
The harmony of disease is when the disease has
manifested signs and symptoms clearly of a particular
remedy. This is the harmony of the disease, otherwise…
as the organism started with high fever acutes,
preceded into more chronic
conditions, sinusitis,
and then preceded to hay
fever, and to asthma…
by treating such an organism you start with his
asthma and his asthma is getting better but at the
same time the organism starts going backwards and
whatever was suppressed will manifest again.
Therefore, there is no one remedy that can be
given to a person and cure him for good. Because
this organism has stages of imbalance, stages
of diseases that have to come back one by one.
Therefore, slowly the idea of the levels of health
was created. And in this idea the most obvious sign
that an organism is doing better was the developing
of a very high fever. Not once but several times.
What I tell you in a nutshell
it was in the minds of medical
doctors, of homeopathic
doctors… it was in confusion.
Now he has a chronic condition, we give the remedy,
now he has an acute, we give another remedy…
and after 5 years a person with chronic condition,
comes and says he is in the same state.
Because it was just taking around the organism not improving
according to this order. Our organisms are constructed
in such a way that if something comes against it, a
nosological agent or stress or an environmental condition,
is able to face that stress and return
back to normal. I give you an example.
In a very hot environment like this
one, I am suffering, I am perspiring…
Perspiring is a reaction of the organism, perspiration is necessary
to keep the balance of it so the organism always has a reaction
whenever he is stressed by a stressor of whatever kind, the
organism will have a reaction and then the organism will come back.
I’ll give another example. You have an unfortunate
incident where a beloved person died or left you
– this doesn’t happen so much with the Indians but
with the Europeans- and there is a big stress.
You lost a beloved one, the natural reaction of the organism
is to cry for some days or 2 months and then organism
will say forget this, he is a fool, I am not going to
cry for the rest of my life and find somebody else.
This is a healthy reaction. An unhealthy
reaction is, I lost and this loss has brought
about a change in my energy complex level
and after that incident I cannot breath,
I try to take a deep breath and… you may have this
condition for years. And then he comes to you and
relates it to this and you say take a dose of Ignatia
and Ignatia makes the reset of the organism.
Now I can breathe again, together with
the depression that you have and all
the kinds of things… Ignatia takes
all these away and there is a reset.
You have to imagine that our organisms are receiving
since childhood a lot of such stresses, the
greatest of which are the initial vaccinations
which are given to us as babies in young age.
Because the vaccinations are addressed
to the immune system and they say
to the immune system you produce
antibodies so I cannot get a high fever.
When I realized this that actually the vaccinations were
to prevent having epidemics and acute conditions it was
damaging the immune system and not helping it. Today
there are 20 vaccinations which are given in young age.
You can imagine the confusion of the immune
system receiving all these vaccinations and
after a compromised immune system, a child
living in a family experiences some problems.
The man is treating his wife quite badly and the child is
looking this fight between the parents and is paralyzed
because he cannot do anything. Some children cannot
stand this and will hit the father or the mother etc.
A compromised immune system comes with the stress
and the child develops an asthmatic condition
and cannot breathe, and then he takes cortisone
or antibiotics and is becoming worse and worse.
And comes to the age of 30 is a damaged organism and
comes to the homeopath and says fix me. What do I have
now? I have some epileptic fits, I cannot think, my
memory is very bad, I have headaches etc… very difficult.
Who can fix it? The one who really
understands what has happened to this
organism. Unless you do understand with
the first reaction the person has,
you do not realize that this is a good reaction
and you give remedies to stop the effect. I
remember a case of a doctor, student of mine, he
was actually a professor of Medicine in the 70s,
he was the doctor of the French embassy.
The French embassy referred to him all
their problems, so the ambassador had
a son who was suffering with asthma.
This professor who was a younger student of mine,
he did not know very much, he took the case
of the child, brought it to me, the child was
taking homeopathic remedies but specialties.
In France they have specialties. A bottle for asthma,
about 30 remedies, other for headache, hay fever
etc. He was taking a lot of these for years and
there was no effect. The asthma was progressing.
They call me, took the case, brought the child and
I saw the remedy which was a miracle after all
these remedies and I said the child needs Sulphur.
The ambassador jumps and says "No Sulphur!".
Why? He said because when we gave him
Sulphur 7 years ago there was such a
reaction, it brought out eczema that was
terrible and we had to give cortisone.
The ones who were prescribing all these specialties were
supposed to be homeopaths and they told the father never
give Sulphur again to your child. I explained and I said
Sulphur is the only remedy that can save this child.
The next step is mental aberrations, psychotic
conditions. If you suppress the asthma,
it may seem to be better but then you
will have psychotic symptoms developing.
Finally he persuaded the ambassador to start with low
potencies of Sulphur and there was a reaction and
eventually came out treated the boy in continuation
with the appropriate remedies, I can’t remember,
I am talking about 1970-71-72
but I remember this exclamation
of the ambassador "Don’t give
him Sulphur, we are lost!".
If somebody claims he is a homeopath and does not
understand the theory of the levels of health darkness is
coming. Is preparing you for a dark period. We stay
together in the dark, I will still teach you, don’t worry!
From darkness to light! Don’t worry
because we have a backup system. We put
the generator if darkness comes we’ll
know what to do. At least we think so.
All these what I tell you are important facts for medical
doctors in general to understand themselves what
is going on with the human body. I have written an
article "The continuum of a unified theory of diseases”.
Who has read this article? So the rest of you is
uneducated. This article was published 2-3 years
ago in a conventional American journal and about a
month ago I received a letter from that journal
saying that we would like to have more articles
from you because your article was downloaded
by so many doctors that lead us… you know
what an impact factor is? Only very few.
The medical journals are evaluated and are given a number,
the impact factor, the impact the journal has upon
readership. I was teaching back in the 70s down at
Roussoum Gialos in a room about this number of people
you can imagine in a about half the size of
this place, one was in the top of the other
almost, packed, sitting on benches, hundred
people in less than the half of this.
As I was teaching there comes and earthquake, in the meantime
the doors were closed and only windows and glasses were
there. I thought immediately if people get panicky they will
jump through the glasses and will have a terrible situation.
So I told them, sit down there’s no problem at all.
Don’t move. I continued. They thought if he is
not afraid then most probably we are safe. The
earthquake was continuing. Then it finally finishes.
Then I say now if anybody wants to go out there is
one little door, go only through that door, don’t
panic, otherwise you may sit and I will continue
teaching. Nobody left and there was no further movement.
The problem is that the subject on which I am talking
as a try to make it as simple as possible, but yet
it is so new the ideas for you that you may need
some time to ingest and to perceive and understand.
I talk from experience and you are listening to this
experience with another aspect. You have been learning
in Medicine, if you have a condition which is determined
by these symptoms this is called L.E. condition.
Then the treatment is cortisone or whatever. You have
learned to think in this way and now what I am telling
you is to be careful because you cannot do that because
if you do it, it is going to have a side effect,
they call it side effects of medicine. It’s
not the side effects of the medicine, it is
the reaction of the organism towards these
medicines which are given. It’s the reaction.
When you take an anti-inflammatory drug for
your colic pain and there is as a consequence
a heart infarct, this is not the side of the
drug, it is the side effect of the organism,
the organism says I cannot tolerate this suppression,
don’t suppress me and then the condition goes to
a deeper level, leaves that levels of the guts and
goes to the heart which is a more important organ.
If you suppress this then it will leave and go to
the brain. Therefore, this new understanding in
Medicine is not only for homeopaths, it’s for all
people who are dealing with healing in general.
It’s not possible to touch an organism without
understanding this not because I am saying it. What I was
telling you is the result, the observation, the
experience of many years of treating chronic conditions.
And you are going to see such chronic
cases. The objective of this
seminar is to treat chronic conditions
and you will have the experience,
you will see how difficult it is when you have an
organism who is undermined through stresses, diseases
etc., how the signs and symptoms the organism is giving
are confused, are not presenting a clear picture,
those who know some Homeopathy will
see how much confusion there is by
looking at the case. Ok. Don’t laugh!
Lopez is a permanent student.
She has a special laugh and if she
starts laughing the whole class will be
laughing together with her. Do you want
to ask a question after all this talk?
– You talk about suppression through pharmaceutical
drugs, what is your view of the use of herbs, do
herbs suppress? – Good question. Herbs and complementary
supplements. The herbs is very interesting.
The herbs can have an effect if the organism
is in a quite good condition. If the organism
is undermined through a chronic condition
quite deeply, herbs will have no effect.
There are some organisms that will need a little bit
of a stimulation and this can be from herb and you
can have some effect but the cases we treat are so
deeply disturbed that herbs will have no effect.
Neither these supplements like vitamins. When I was
teaching in the United States I could see most of
the Americans were eating and having at the same
time a handful of different vitamins. All of them.
I am talking about the 80s. I wanted to
understand if this had an effect. What I
realized was that the food they were eating
was junk food that contained no vitamins,
so by taking vitamins there was some effect that
was keeping them in a kind of balanced condition.
None of them could claim that he was cured with
these vitamins or supplements. Just keep going.
It is different than when a homeopathic remedy is given
and resets the organism. Supplement means that I
need a kind of mineral or vitamin and then I take it
and keep the organism in a kind of a balanced state.
But for a cure you need the homeopathic
remedy which is correct. –
They can suppress? - I don’t believe.
He asked if herbs can suppress.
Herbs cannot suppress unless they find some
new types of herbs or they call it herbs
which contains some i.e. serotonin or opium
and they mix and then you feel good.
– What’s your opinion on, if they come to you on
suppressive treatments do you normally take them
off or you give the remedy on other medication?
– Which country are you from? USA? All of you?
That’s why I don’t understand you. Speak English
like my English! Repeat slower and clearer. – When
a patient comes to you on suppressive treatment do
you give the remedy while they are on the drugs
-… Or I wait until they get rid of the drugs
and then I give them. It will depend. If I
can get them out of the drugs without any
danger for their health, that is preferable.
But if somebody comes with a heart condition who
takes some drugs we cannot stop, if somebody comes
with epileptic fits and for the last 10 years he
takes antiepileptic drugs, we cannot stop them.
If somebody takes in ulcerative
colitis drugs for the
last 10 years, we cannot stop them.
So what do we do?
Either we say forget it you are not a
good subject for Homeopathy or the
alternative is that you take the
case while they are under the drugs,
try to find the best possible remedy and then you give it
together with the drugs and if on the process within a
month or two there is an obvious amelioration you advise
them to reduce the medication and you go along like this.
You give the homeopathic drug, you reduce the
medication as long as there is an improvement.
Because if you say take the drug and reduce the
medication, the remedy might not be correct,
so they have an aggravation because of the
stoppage of the drugs. – If during homeopathic
treatment of a chronic condition the kid
occasionally takes a product with preservatives,
with supplements and that acutes the disease, should we
give another remedy according to symptoms? Or we just
stop, see how it goes and then continue with one remedy
that was prescribed during the chronic condition?
– Your question is not clear to me. You repeat.
– For example, a chronic condition of a kid and
she took Calcarea carbonica for a period of
time and the she got a cake with preservatives,
not very good products and that acuted the
condition (swallowing , redness etc.)
that it was not before… - She had an allergic
reaction towards the preservatives..
– Should there be another
remedy to suppress according to
these symptoms or should we
continue with Calcarea carbonica?
– If the reaction was really due to preservatives and if
the reaction was on the skin it might have been the effect
of Calcarea carbonica and not the preservatives so therefore
the correct idea is to stop the Calcarea carbonica,
wait to see what happens after the aggravation and then
decide. If it is really a chemical towards which the
person is sensitive to, then you will have to give
another remedy in case there is quite a strong reaction.
If the reaction is, in general, on the
skin do not be in a hurry to give
another remedy. This is a rule. Leave
it to develop and see what happens.
I pray to God many times that I get skin eruption myself
to prove to you that I am waiting because God gave me
this reaction which is the best possible, I may live another
85 years… Why should I suppress it? This is the idea.
A skin eruption saves the life of a patient. Suppressing
is totally wrong. You became a student of Homeopathy at
what age? 70? 72! My God! How old are you now? He became a
student at 62 and now he is 72. 62 is a progressed age…
Very nice. He was a student of Roger Morrison.
Both of them. They live close to San Francisco.
–Nowadays many patients come with a complex
condition… - Nowadays people take complex remedies…
- People come with different layers of medicinal
diseases and we consider first layer, second layer,
third layer. So which layer should we start the medicine?
–The uppermost at the moment. He’s on level 7.
Start with the remedy for this level. – And for
that layer which symptoms should we consider?
Mental, physical central or physical particular?
–All. This is what we are going to say all along.
What symptoms or which symptoms we are basing our
prescription. We are going to explain to you on the live
cases. – Professor, in diseases like amoebiasis,
parasitic diseases, how do we have to consider them?
As acute or chronic conditions? Because
this condition for example in Peru is
very wide spread and how do we have to
consider them? – For instance amoebiasis,
we consider it as a severe chronic condition,
it’s difficult to manage it. Usually these cases
are chronic, acute conditions are considered
those who have high fever. – Thank you, sir.
In your experience has it even happened that somebody
with an allergy, has been completely cured and never
has repetition of this allergy on that particular
substance? – Yes it has happened but it is difficult.
The allergies in general which are the epidemic kind
of conditions of our societies. Allergic conditions
are mostly the effect of an undermined immune system
and compromised immune system to a great degree.
The immune system cannot deal
with environmental conditions.
You smell a flower and you get asthma.
This is not natural.
In order an organism to reach this
conditions it means it has been
undermined and compromised a lot
and deeply in his immune system.
Therefore the treatment of such cases is difficult
and takes a long time, that means you start and
then there is a relapse and then again and eventually
if they insist they get rid of it, of course.
The patients must insist coming to the
homeopath. – So, you would suggest that they
keep away from those substances… - Yes, for
the time-being. They have to keep away.
There are people, for instance who are allergic to milk
and eventually after treating them, after some years,
they try it and there is no problem but there are other
conditions which are quite strong and complicated.
They need constant attention and treatment.
Not simple. Allergies
are the punishment of the human
race for violating natural laws.
Allergies are mostly the effect of vaccinations and
other interferences in the human body and that
is why people who have not access to a lot of
medicines are very rarely suffering with allergies.
– George, can you offer or do you think it
would be useful offering a definition of
a drug and also a definition of a remedy?
Because to me they are two different...
– Definition of the drug is when we have
a chemical substance of whatever kind
and that chemical substance is able to
bring about changes in the organism.
If a chemical drug is capable of bringing about changes
in the organism is considered as drug and is considered
as inimical to the organism. A remedy if it is really
indicated is considered a kind of an energy, not chemical,
which stimulates the corresponding energy of the human
body. If a remedy which is an energy is able to stimulate
the human body is considered as a remedy. If a remedy
does not do anything, it’s nothing, it’s like water.
– How is the level of health in a newborn? – There is no
need to know the level of health beforehand. That means
if I know the level of health, then I know the remedy; no.
The remedy is known through the signs and the symptoms.
So a baby will have some signs and
symptoms. You give the remedy according to
them. If the baby is severely ill,
eventually will require some more treatment.
If the baby is quite healthy the remedy will bring
about a reset of his organism. When an Indian makes
like that… she says ok… half-half. – Please explain
the levels of health on the basis of miasms.
I would like to know whether the miasm during
suppression from first few layers to other is there
any change of the miasm from sycosis to syphilis?
I would like to know… - That is correct.
That means correct treatment will take away a miasm, let us
say the uppermost miasm is the sycotic, and this sycotic
miasm will be taken away by 3 remedies, Thuja, Medorrhinum
and Natrum sulphuricum within a period of a year,
then there is a possibility that the organism will
manifest the syphilitic miasm which will require
Mercury, Aurum, Syphillinum etc. We have seen that an
uppermost layer can go away not only with one remedy,
it needs 3 remedies and underneath you will see
a change of remedies an then it goes towards
syphilitic remedies and the psoric when the organism
breaks out to the skin, with a skin eruption,
then we consider most cases are enriched psoric
cases. But it is wrong if you think that I will
prescribe this remedy because it belongs to the
miasm. If you do that you will be mislead.
You think that a layer is sycotic and
therefore you give Medorrhinum. This is wrong
unless you have Medorrhinum symptoms you should
not give it. You have to be very careful.
– You said at the start of the seminar about the
importance of our mission as homeopaths in the
world. The challenge we face today in the world
especially concerning the vaccination in Brazil.
The vaccination in Brazil is mandatory and a
baby takes about 15-20 vaccinations in the first
year. – The question is what is your opinion
about recommendations, if we need to vaccinate.
If there is kind of homeopathic
drug that could minimize the effect
of vaccination since the vaccination
is mandatory in Brazil.
– Vaccination is mandatory in Brazil and
she is asking what to do if the government
says that you have to vaccinate the
child otherwise it cannot go to school.
The problem is that different countries have different
laws and I am not in the position
to fight with all the government all over
the world but what you can do is this;
if you understand that this idea is not correct
then you can have the argument of free choice.
That means if I don’t want to vaccinate my
child I take the responsibility for myself.
Your child is vaccinated and protected so why
should you bother if I don’t want my child to be
vaccinated because your child is protected? Vaccinate
the whole class and 2 students are not vaccinated.
Where is the problem? The danger is with my child and I
take the responsibility. You see? – Can I ask something
just to clarify… If there is any homeopathic remedy
in order to minimize the effect [of vaccination]?
– No. There is no homeopathic remedy that can protect
from epidemic diseases. That means if I give you a remedy
and I tell you now you are vaccinated, let us say Thuja,
and smallpox will not come to you. This is not correct.
What Homeopathy can do is when an
epidemic breaks out then you can
give the most indicated remedy, we
call it the genius of the epidemic,
you can give this to your
child so it can in a
way prevent the disease
from developing fully.
But we do not have a replacement in Homeopathy instead
because if we had that would go against our own
understanding and theory because we would kind of exclude
this organism from coming into an acute condition.
If we find a way to prevent acutes from happening
then we are making humanity more sick. You cannot
prevent. There is a natural selection. The most
weak will die first, and you cannot prevent that.
We have gone against that law of nature and what we have
done, we remained alive in spite of the fact we should have
died at the age of 18,20,40,50 and natural selection will
allow the human race to become healthier and healthier
otherwise if we interfere and we don’t allow
the natural selection then we are making more
and more sick the human race. This is something
which sound very bad but this is the truth.
You want to live longer but you live without
joy, without a feeling of real health. In
our societies very few people, grownups, are
able to produce high fever at this moment.
Unfortunately this is the condition
we have created through all the
drugs and all the things we have
discovered. – Can I put a question?
I came from a region with heavy industry
from Romania and in my region where I
practice we have many cases of heavy metal
intoxications. Chronic intoxications.
And I ask you if we can completely
cure these chronic heavy
metal intoxication. – Like
mercury, plumbum, arsenicum…
What happens with this is if you receive a
case and you give the correct remedy the
organism automatically will reject the extra
metal which is in excess in the organism.
– But it’s not acute, it’s chronic. Because people
live there and the ground and the trees are with
metals. – If there is a situation where this metal
is everywhere there is going to be a relapse,
even if the organisms reacts in the beginning
quite well… There is an idea that the airplanes
are spraying us with aluminium, barium,
strodium and these are quite bad metals and
we inhale them and we take them and create a
problem for us but we live in such a society that
these things can happen and this is unfortunate.
I don’t know how we can deal with this issue.
Fighting with the correct remedy is
one thing, but fighting politically
to stop doing these things, on a
governmental level… is another issue.