So, this is the model and what we can say is that this people here they can live up to 90 year.
If everything goes well, if they don't damage their health,
they're born with good genetic predisposition and their programming is to live more than 80 years.
In this group people will get a common cold or influenza once in a year,
once in two years or even once in three years.
Actually people with very good health they may not become ill for many years.
People who live in mountainous areas, who are farmers, you ask them
and they say "I have never been sick".
The acutes in this is very rare. As they come down they can have more acutes.
Now when they go here on this second group the acutes start to be twice a year
or three times a year they may have an acute. And here on level 6 we see very frequent acutes.
Even children who are having almost every month a cystitis and they get antibiotics
and finally the mother says all the year I have to give antibiotics to the child.
Or otitis repeated again and again, repeated bronchitis, all kinds of acute situations.
Now, what happens usually is that the pediatricians or the doctors who are treating such cases
they give antibiotics and at a certain time the child is well.
He does not have any more acutes. This a very dangerous situation,
would mean the child has gone on level 7.
He went down and now his immune system cannot produce any more acutes.
This can happen in early life like when somebody is 10-11 years old where acutes stop
and they are not sick with an acute.
If such people by good homeopathy are treated while on 7 or 8- rather on 7 I would say-
the first thing that happens it will be after the remedy a month later,
20 days later even a few days after correct remedy they start again developing fever.
So, that's why we say that if we give a remedy and the person develops a fever
immediately after the remedy that is a good sign and it means
that the person jumped from level 7 back to 6 or 5.
If the person is in these levels or even very down here
then it will take long time before you can raise him to this level 6 where he can have again fever.
You may treat 2-3 years a person before he shows that he can develop fever.
It's very interesting. It does not depend on the age. A person may be old but strong organism.
He can develop fever.
A person maybe a young person but his organism is very weak he cannot develop fever.
In level 6 the person gets easily acutes. Repeated acutes. They are the cases who never recover.
He has a bronchitis and then after two months again another and then after three months again.
So, in this level we have acutes which are frequent- levels 5 and 6 - .
At a certain moment the acutes stop, has been level 7.
Level 7 is not a bad state yet because it may be that with one remedy
that you give here fever appears again. That's very good level 7.
If you see that you give a correct remedy and fever does not appear
it means that the person will be either 8 or 9 and will need a series of remedies
before he can come back.
When he comes back from 8 or 9 position to 6 he is going to have a very severe acute
and many times life-threatening. And this is the time
where you have to be an expert to treat the acute homeopathically.
Because if you treat the acute with antibiotics or cortisone things will sink again back
to the lower level which shows that in the most of the cases antibiotics suppress the disease
towards a deeper level. Here people can start with being quite strong but they take wrong treatment,
they take antibiotics they come down.
The more antibiotics the more the health goes down. And they can sink very much down
and reach these levels.
As I said in these levels you can have any pathology.
That means the fact that the person has Parkinson it does not mean
that the pathology will be down here necessarily it can be here
which means that the person with Parkinson that from time to time he's able to raise a fever.
That Parkinson disease is curable with homeopathy.
You see how important it is to know this? Can your system raise fever?
That means is your immune system is in good condition then we stimulate it
and we may cure you.
All these things of course are very useful for homeopath
but even for non-homeopaths are very useful as well.
All doctors actually should understand this model because they must know what they do
when they prescribe chemical drugs, the damage they can bring about.
It's very interesting that in one congress here,
International Congress of Neurology they invited me to speak about the model and they had a fit.
Conventional doctors neurologists about 900 of them were in Hilton hotel
and I presented this model and I told them and none had any opposition.
So, there are quite a lot of other details about this model.
The problem is that within a week it's not that everything you learn
it is quite a difficult subject, homeopathy.
It's not learned in weekends and you have to apply yourself but once you learn it
it's very satisfying in the effects that it gives.
That when I am saying high fever I mean from 38,5 C and upwards. This type of fever.
Fever between 37C, 37,3C, 37,8C and malaise it shows an immune system which is weak.
Cannot give real fever.
This type of fever is the one that determines whether an immune system is in good condition.
Yet, there is one exception that when an organism is on the brink of dying,
destroyed when somebody is in the hospital lying down there with a lot of problems,
in a very bad condition and you see a high fever arising is not a good sign is not a good fever.
This fever is going to be the last it is the last effort of the organism
and usually what they do they give antibiotics and the person lives 2-3 days and then he dies.
-You're talking about the first groups which can be cured.
What can we do with homeopathy in the lower groups?
-Usually what we can do is up to here. From here downwards we can ameliorate the situation.
We can make them feel more comfortable but really curing them it's very difficult,
if not impossible.
You may think a case is 10 or 11 but actually is in level 9 because things are not precise.
This can happen. But here the reaction from the homeopathic remedy is totally different.
We'll speak another day about the reactions from the homeopathic remedy.
Reactions of the homeopathic remedy in different groups.
We'll take one by one groups and I will explain the possible reaction.
-If the people doesn't have fever for several years but doesn't have any illness...?
-It becomes to the first group. No fever, can be healthy, 1st level.
-It's about suppression how the level in this chart if it's the wrong remedy in homeopathy
and suppressed by allopathy how is the...?
-What happens is this, I will explain it to you. That's one level, not group. Level 4, ok?
A person can be on the top of this level with some symptoms, all these are symptoms
and when there is an acute or a suppression of whatever remains in the same level
but in the bottom of the level with different symptoms.
So actually the homeopathic remedy will bring a person from the higher part of his level
to the lower part but cannot make him jump a level. A treatment with real chemical drugs
can push the person down to level 5 or 6.
But the homeopathic remedy can suppress but within the same level.
I want to give you the reactions after the homeopathic remedy of people
of the different levels and what kind of reaction we expect
and what potency is the best advisable.
For the level 1 people you can give any potency preferably very high potency
because they have clear pictures and they have strong organisms.
In level 1 people you may not expect an aggravation.
Usually we say you have an aggravation after we give a remedy.
When an organism is quite strong and he comes to you to be treated usually will be for lumbago
or sciatica for a common cold, for little and peripheral problems.
Therefore you may not expect to have an aggravation with such cases.
Potency very high, no aggravation.
As you go down to the scale the pathology becomes deeper and deeper.
So in level 2 or 3 it will depend on the pathology you may have some reaction, you may not have.
This is another confusion which is within our community.
Some teachers they say there are no aggravations and my response to this
is "Have you ever seen a real cure in a serious condition?".
Most probably they treat people on this level, easy cases, they give a remedy and it's finished.
All the other cases they treat they go away they don't know what's happening.
So, either they treat such people or they treat only with placebo.
Placebo effect you do not see an aggravation. So either very healthy people or placebo.
If some teachers say they have never seen an aggravation
that means they have never cured a real case coming down the scale. They don't care.
The other thing that you have to have in mind is that when you give a remedy
it does not mean it does nothing.
In the example case that we saw, the Mancinella case,
he was having babbling sensation in cervical region, he took Lycopodium, it was gone.
He was having twitchings in the face he took Nux vomica, twitching was gone.
So therefore it is not that our remedy would do nothing if they are wrong.
They will something and sometimes they also do damage.
As I said there may be suppressing a case within the same level and bring the person down.
Because when I say in general dropping of the general state of health
it means general that means energy-wise, less energy, more depression, more anxiety
and perhaps less pain in this specific area in which you are treating. That is a suppression.
You have a spastic colitis and I have said many times give me any symptom
and I will make it disappear because if I give all the remedies fitting that particular symptom
the symptom will disappear. What happens to the general state of the patient this is another story.
You see how important it is to know what you are doing.
And here I'm trying to give you as much information as possible to discern, to find out
what is the result of your treatment. So if you do not see reactions here it's ok.
But if you come here in these groups where the organism is already compromised,
the immune system is in a low state of condition and you are taking such a case from this
and within this group you will find from mild to strong aggravations.
As you go down, you are treating headaches of the 5th level
that means the person still has good immune system to have some high fevers.
So level 5 headaches are quite strong headaches and quite frequent., once a week.
You give them the remedy and the correct of the remedy is to hear the patient say
"I had the worst headache of my life".
When you hear that, they call, you know what you are doing and they hear your voice being secure
that you know what you are doing and you say "Very good, it is a good reaction!
In one or two days you will be free from the headaches
-Is that so? Ok." Otherwise they take painkillers.
You know the idea this now after the remedy they gave me this "magician"
because sometimes they look the homeopath as a kind of a magician he's not a regular doctor
though he has studied regular medicine he says this is a magician
I went to the magician he gave me this and now I'm worse.
The patient will think that I went to the wrong doctor.
If that psychology remains and in your voice the patient will hear the least fear
"Oh my God what happened", you're finished.
The patient will go to the hospital will take painkillers, will take everything.
Once in the 1970s as a student I had a professor of medicine and he was just starting
and he was asking me for every case. For every case he would call me.
One time he tells me "I have the child of the ambassador of France"
because he was speaking French "He has asthma..."
I said "Ok give him Sulphur" he says "I cannot give him Sulphur".
I asked why he said because the French doctors when he was in Paris
they told him never touch Sulphur because if you touch Sulphur
the child is going to have such an aggravation.
Somebody gave him Sulphur the child had an aggravation, they couldn't wait for 2 days
and then they gave him all kinds of remedies. What remedies have been given?
He says half of the Materia Medica.
You know also the French doctors give specialties with mixed remedies.
I said to him this was the best reaction and the child would have been cured 5 years ago
when they gave him Sulphur but they did not know what they were doing.
And now 5 years the child is with severe asthmatic condition much more difficult to cure now
and the reaction was going to be much more difficult so I said to him
if you like give him a low potency repeatedly but you expect to have similar
or even worse aggravation. There is no other way.
The moment that you don't know what you are doing of course what do you want,
to make the asthma a little bit better give all kinds of similar remedies, not the Similimum,
not the exact and the asthma will be a little bit better and the child will be a little bit better.
But the child will never be cured. But I have to tell you also this;
that this a little bit better in a case of asthma it means that the disturbance
which is concentrated upon the lungs is going now to be diffused at the whole of the organism.
So therefore as much as the asthma is better the same amount will be worse the energy, the anxiety,
the depression or whatever is diffused in the whole organism
because the organism is one there are no parts.
It works as a totality so you stimulate and the stimulation is not correct,
is not towards cure but towards suppression.  Suppression is not an abstract idea.
For the organism suppression means that the relief you get from the local symptom
appears as a negative reaction on different other points of the organism
to which the person is sensitive.
-Asthma is a deadly disease, right? But a child can die from an aggravation.
So is it ok than to use allopathic methods during the aggravation?
-Of course.  You won't let the child die, you will use. You were here, I think,
when I explained how to handle asthma cases. You were not here? You were here?
In the previous course I gave a lecture explaining how you handle difficult cases
under allopathic treatment. If you are late you see what happens.
I sympathize with her because when I was in Canada I could not sleep at all.
So I was going to lecture half-asleep because I wanted to sleep during the time I was lecturing.
So you can sit there and listen when your biological watch is upside down.
You should be sleeping during this time.
So, it's ok, I will give you because this lecture is important
so I will ask Dimitri to put the lecture so l can sleep a little bit more.
Here up to here the reaction has no danger.
That means the reactions are such that cannot overcome the life force and make a total disaster.
But once the  organism has entered a real degenerative state which is not a pathology
which has been diagnosed as such,
autoimmune, LPE, RA is not a pathology per se as we know it from conventional medicine
that makes a person come to level 7 because in level 7 it can enter a person
who just manifests an aggressive high blood pressure.
You get some people who feel good but they have an aggressive high blood pressure.
It means that they take medication and the pressure is still high in spite of medication.
You think what is this? This high blood pressure is nothing.
This kind of blood pressure makes a person enter the level 7 or 8.
That means that this person from the moment his blood pressure became malignant
has stopped giving high fevers, cannot give anymore high fevers.
When you prescribe for level 7 if your remedy is correct
and if the pathology is not really very deep you are going to have an aggravation immediately
and what else?
You are going to have very soon after you prescription manifesting high fever.
That will show you your prescription was correct.
It is not correct your prescription when he says my blood was up to 21, 22
and did not go down and now with the remedy you gave Lachesis, you gave Belladonna,
you gave all the anti-hypertensive remedies that we know and now the blood pressure is 18
and says "I'm better". You know that you have done nothing.
As an homeopath you realize that the remedy was wrong. But the patient is happy.
From 21-22 the blood pressure now is 18, under 20
but you know the remedy was only close, not exact.
For him to have better state of health he has to have an aggravation
and he has to manifest also fever.
I'll tell you some examples. I was treating 10 years ago a case
with cancer of the head of the pancreas with metastasis.
He gave a lot of aggravations in the beginning of the treatment for a year he was terrible
the laboratory test was crazy the condition was absolutely dangerous.
He had been operated, opened and closed. They said you go and you will live a few more months.
That was the prognosis. And of course he did not have any other chance
so he had to withstand all the aggravations. The man is still alive. 10 or 12 years already.
The laboratory tests are normal but I still wait to see the high fever.
As long as I don't see the high fever that means I took that man from that level 11
and brought it maybe at the 8th level or 7th level where he feels ok.
I'm ok now, I'm working, I have a normal life.
But if I don't see the high fever I'm not sure that under stress his organism
will suddenly go down and explode the cancer which is lurking there.
Once I see the fever I say ok you're over there, you're finished with the cancer.
Not when the cancer markers are good, it's ok, it's an indication.
You know there are cancer markers for different kinds of cancer.
I'll tell you another story, just a similar story, ok?
Cancer of the breast in a woman, for 10 years trying to cure.
Finally she was going back to London, checked, markers ok, everything's ok,
cancer is gone, finished.
You're well now. And there comes one time and things happen all together.
She separates with her husband, in the meantime she was in love with another man all along.
The man says to her I have to stop the relationship I'm not prepared to separate and go ahead.
Another shock, a big shock. She was connected with a kind of spiritual teacher.
She discovers the spiritual teacher is a fake. It all happens in June, July, August.
In September what was thought to be gone
the cancer explodes with a total spread in the organism.
I was in America by that time and she was my patient.
There was one of my students looking her, and he said let's phone George.
She said you must swear to me that you will not phone. That she had decided to leave.
The problem was I was watching all the time for the high fever
and there was no coming for 10 years treating carefully.
The organism looks perfectly healthy but the stress was so much,
one stress after another, big stress, big stress, gone the organism finished.
After two months she dies. She lasted only 2 months.
What I'm saying to you is not a theory, it's the real facts.
You treat here there must be an aggravation, you treat number 8 it must be an aggravation,
you treat number 9 you may not get an aggravation anymore but an amelioration.
That means number 9 patient is in the brink of being incurable.
It is in the middle line, that means the organism improves, he feels improvement,
but if this improvement does not lead to a more clear remedy
this improvement is going to be a little bit of improvement.
It has to lead to a more clear remedy in order to understand that from number 9
is going towards number 8 with a better picture.
Because here the picture is very clear, the remedy is very clear.
The remedy number 3 is becoming less clear.
As you go down the first remedy which you need is less clear,
because in these levels you need 2 or 3 remedies to cure.
These are big, strong symptoms, these are smaller and smaller symptoms.
All these are modifications of symptoms.
This organism has been through a lot of stress because of this lot of stress,
this graph shows Ignatia picture.
But when this person is on this level 8 or 9 or even 7 underneath Ignatia
there are a few more symptoms like Natrum muriaticum.
Nat-m as you examine is not like this underneath, so clear Ign, clear Nat-m.
What happens is that as you examine you will see symptoms of Nat-m popping up in the face.
If further you will need Sepia or Sulphur you may get a symptom of Sepia as well,
or another symptom of Sepia. See, can you recognize now Ignatia here? Very difficult.
Because of some symptoms Nat-m there what shall I give, this remedy, that remedy...?
The moment the organism is compromised more and more, more and more levels of remedies
you will need which are there, underneath, popping up in the uppermost level.
And you have to be experienced and also very logical in your analysis to be able to separate
which is the first. Because if you give this remedy as first what you are doing,
you are pushing all these over the high picture.
Already from a confused case or a difficult case you make it more confused
and then it comes Sepia and you give Sepia and you ignore
that the first remedy should have been Ignatia never mind how many remedies,
half of the Materia Medica you have given the patient is not going to be well
unless you give the original, Ignatia.
But now after all these remedies you have given the Ignatia picture is gone.
Who is going to find out? Not even a master, or a very experienced homeopath.
So you have to understand that homeopathy in this respect otherwise you will treat group 1,
be happy with some successes 10-15%, here how many people today,
maybe in your countries in south America you have much more on level 1 people.
Here in Europe and America and Canada the percentage of these people is the 5% the most,
5% of people have remained strong.
In South America this group is 50% of the population.
So you have good successes with little knowledge.
If you know  some remedies well you will be treating more of the people successfully,
your success will be quite big.
In Europe you have to be really an expert because we are degenerated.
We are going towards extinction.
Here in number 6 or number 5 the organism is ready to be infected
and very easily with a lot of agents like bacteria, like microbes, like all kinds of viruses.
This group is proned to get everything. Therefore if they do not get treated they will die.
A huge part of the population of these levels there would be dead unless we had strong drugs
like antibiotics, cortisone etc. But they were well with the different epidemics with Tamiflu
and whatever else antiviral or antibiotics etc.
People are getting to life, to stay alive but they are paying the price. And what is the price they are paying?
The price is that after the Antibiotics they drop to these levels.
These levels they allow you to stay alive but with a life which is compromised. In what respect?
First of all joy of life is gone. You loose the joy of life, you loose the pleasure of life
where you were waking up in the morning and were very happy to be in this nice world.
Now you get up in the morning in a depressed stadt, gloomy state. I have not slept well bla bla bla.
You are alive -- that is good. But what are we doing through these means that we have found out to keep an organism alive?
Even in this 12 we have found means to keep people alive. You have a machine that makes you breath.
There is another machine for dialysis were your blood is going through. And there is another machine for the heart which keeps your heart...
And you are in a hospital you have a lot of money and the doctors they feel proud to put all this machinery keep you alive for how long?
For six month, for a year, for a year and a half. I don't know.
The patient themselves most probably on that stage they say "please let me die".
Because they are living hell in earth, before their time.
But in these levels we have ways to live and that's why the big issue is euthanasia.
You know euthanasia?
And they're debating, should we let these people on these levels die or should we keep them?
It's a big issue now. Who has created that issue? Conventional medicine.
Because by keeping alive organisms that they should have died normally at the 6th level
you keep them alive but in a compromised state. It's a new theory.
I don't know the solution, right? Because I cannot say take out all chemical drugs or antibiotics
and let people die normally and in a natural way. I cannot say that.
But I record the facts. The way I understand the facts. Unfortunately,
what I record is the experience of somebody that has seen 200.000 cases in 50 years
of practicing homeopathy.
Don't forget I had a big center with 30 medical doctors
and I was supervising there all these doctors and prescribing for cases.
The information, the subjects are big.
These results came from a study of a huge number of patients. And from different countries.
Because I was treating people in America, in Europe, in India, from every country.
So I know what has happened.
The most healthy people are, the areas; South America, you are one of the most healthy,
I don't know how many they accept that, Africa, Asia, Korea. These are the most healthy people.
The most unhealthy where do we find almost every one of these levels in Europe, in America,
in Australia and all the civilized countries. Canada. These are the facts.
Try to cure a patient here and you see how difficult it is.
This kind of difficulty you will find every time.
Because when it comes to this point and you give a remedy you will never see and aggravation.
Number 10, you will never see an aggravation. You will see amelioration.
That means the organism is already compromised and says ok you don't allow me to have this pain
I will have the pain somewhere else.
That means you will be treating here cases with cancer with metastasis
where the pains are excruciating, with metastasis, in the bone especially
and you will be relieving the pains but a strange thing will happen
that the organism does not stay in one remedy.
That means every week you will visit such people with metastasis you will see a new picture
and a new remedy is needed in order to relieve it again for another week
and another week until finally death comes. There is amelioration.
Homeopathy can ameliorate that state but not always.
And you have to remember this. For instance in case of an asthma, severe asthma,
especially when you have emphysema that means the lungs have given up,
they are not anymore able to breath, bring air in and out.
You give the remedy there is an aggravation, the person is going to die.
And you have to enter with allopathic drugs. This lecture is good I will give it to you.
But now concerning the potency here we said the highest potency we start coming down here
still 200CH you can give here is a trick.
If you get physical pathology in the 7th, 8th level you have to go low, under 30CH or lower.
But if the pathology here is psychotic the person is mostly mentally disturbed
then you can go as high as 1M, mental. In physical you will go up to 30CH, 12CH.
Here, this group I consider incurable by homeopathy, the 4th group.
Here the remedies that will act will be up to 200CH, from 12D or 12X.
D means decimal that means one over ten in the 6th or 12th power.
Or X which is the number ten in Latin. And we have 12CH centesimal,
one over a hundred in the 12th potency.
But the dilutions are made one over 100 they are not one over 10.
This is weaker than this one.
The 12X is a weaker remedy though in 12X you may still find
a molecule of the original substance in this.
In this 1 over 100 in the 12th is going over the Avogadro number
and there are no molecules anymore.
-Last year I was here because of heart problem you said you have to wait
and I have a fever after that of 38.5C.
If I had a fever again I should treat in homeopathically now.
-Yes. He needs to treat the fever.
-The question is what is the risk of having another endocarditis.
-It's a big risk I tell you.
I will explain I did not say everything but since he reminds me I will tell you
that here as I said there is aggravation and no problem.
Here if there is after the second remedy there is a jump from 8 to 6 this case
you are going to have a big aggravation.
The aggravation is such that sometimes we cannot handle it homeopathically,
not because we don't have the remedies but we don't have the knowledge to enter immediately
with the first symptoms because the aggravation here is what he says is going to happen.
Is going to be a pericarditis or an endocarditis.
This moment you have to have enough knowledge to control this otherwise it's dangerous.
And then therefore what happens is that many times while you treat the fever appears
and the reaction appears then get a fright from what is happening endocarditis
the symptoms are dramatic, you enter the hospital and has to take antibiotics.
Then antibiotics will push him down again all over so we call it a relapse.
Now he has a relapse because he took the drugs so you start again
but as you start again and again the organism becomes stronger and stronger
and the reactions are not so dangerous eventually.
The reactions are manageable by the organism and if the reaction is manageable by the organism
the picture of the remedy they give out is clear. And the result can be fantastic.