To talk to you about the levels of health and to give you some ideas
about what they mean.
Why I came to the conclusion that the whole of humanity belongs not to one level of health
but to several levels of health.
So the whole of humanity is divided symbolically not exactly into 12 levels of health.
So according to my understanding a person is born in the 1st level of health
the uppermost which is the best and some others unfortunate
have been born in the 12th level of health, which is the worst.
In the 12th level of health who belong? Belong all these children who are born with cancer,
with severe systemic disorders, with epilepsy, with autism etc.
Once is born with such a pathology belongs to the 12th level of health,
to very low level of health. And you may ask what do we need to know
which level of health somebody is...
Well, it's very important to know because if we have a case
that belongs to level 10,11, 12 which is the last group
that means we have in our hands a case that most probably is incurable with Homeopathy.
As we go higher in the levels of health then individuals who are chronically ill
with degenerative diseases will not respond to one remedy.
You may need a series of remedies before you can bring them higher and higher
in the level of health.
Therefore severely damaged constitutions they will respond partially to your first remedy
then the picture of another remedy manifests you give this comes up the organism a bit more,
a third remedy, a forth remedy  you may need before within a space of time 3-5 years
of treatment then you may say I have managed to cure such a person.
The problem with us homeopaths is that some people some of us we see cases
responding very well with one remedy and the confusion is that we get the impression
that all cases could respond in this way to the extent
for instance one of the Argentinian doctors you have to find the core remedy,
everybody has the core remedy.
This does not exist, because if an individual is going to be cured with one 1-5 remedies
in a space of time of 3-5 years, then you cannot say the core remedy,
out of the five which was the core remedy...?
But if you find patients that belong to the uppermost levels 1,2,3 strong constitutions
born with genetic predisposition to live for 90 years, then to such individuals
you may give one remedy and they respond beautifully.
But you can imagine now the confusion that we can cause to the world by saying
we cure this whatever pathology, because we have seen one or two cases cured.
Because they belong to the first group. But what is the peculiarity
and why this confusion has come?
Because in all levels we may have the manifestation of all pathologies.
That means we have a cancer case appearing in level 1-3, the best,
which we call the first group, which is the best group.
We may have manifestation in first group.
We have manifestation of cancer in group 2 which is level 4,5 and 6.
We may have cancer manifesting in group 3 7,8,9.
So what is the difference? The difference is that cancer on the 1st group is curable.
Cancer on level 1,2,3 individuals is curable. And we have seen some cases of cancer cured,
"oh we cure cancer...".
We don't cure cancer because cancer on level 7,8,9 if it manifests
that means it will be an aggressive type of cancer that will be exploding
that means within months you will have metastasis and the person dies.
And nothing can save him, not homeopathy not allopathy, nothing.
But cancer on the uppermost levels even can be cured as when the individual
changes his psychology and his immune system is activated. Why?
Because he realizes the life I'm living is very unhealthy.
So I change altogether my style of life.
The moment they take this decision to go away from the stress of life, which is tremendous...
The cases I am bringing as examples are real cases. Working emigrated in USA
and became rich with a lot of supermarkets and all this kind of stress.
And at the age of 60 go to the doctor say "I have bad news for you sir.
You have cancer on the mediastinum and the prognosis is quite bad".
He goes back, has his family there, he says "How long I have to live?
-You may live 6 months...more...". He said "Ok, 6 months I want to go back to my island
to live 6 months there. My last days...".
He was given now an interview to Greek television.
He says "In 1985 I came here, now it's 2005, 20 years later he is 79,
because they told me I have 6 months to live."
Go to  another individual who is the case..." I was told to  live this, this...
I came back here and here I am 15 years later, I am quite strong, my life has changed..."
So, we have to understand that the secret is that the organism has a defense mechanism.
We call it immune system which is being suppressed, until compromises
and the predispositions that are engrafted are manifesting suddenly.
If the predisposition was for rheumatoid arthritis he will develop rheumatoid arthritis.
One guy, he wrote a book in America. He wrote a book, he says "I had rheumatoid arthritis.
I was an industrialist with huge money etc. and they told me I'm going to be deformed now.
So, I gave up my job and what I did I started laughing. Here I am 10 years later
I am still laughing, not deformities and I am quite good because I was laughing.
You see we have to take into consideration this. I tell you this
because it is very much connected with what we are doing in stimulating the immune system
with the homeopathic remedy.  Similar things happen when you change the psychology,
the environment, the conditions. The organism suddenly flourishes,
the immune systems comes into balance and then faces the problem.
But you will say if somebody has a strong constitution and belongs to the uppermost group
how come and he can develop cancer from one day to another?
The answer is that if the stress they receive overweights the resistance of the immune system,
the stress is very big, the immune system compromises totally then it can appear.
I will give you an example from real life. I was teaching in Athens a group of medical doctors.
One of the doctors works in a hospital, chest hospital. He brings a case for discussion.
What is the remedy, because we have a case in the hospital
and who is coughing, coughing, coughing.
And these are the symptoms of the persons the man is 75, 73. Old man.
Older than me I am only 78 now. But anyhow, the fact is that he brings me the case,
he gives me the information, he is coughing and I say to him "Peter,
what happened and he suddenly a man who is a villager, a farmer in a small place in Greece
where people are healthy... What happened? Why? Something has happened."
He said this man had an illegal affair - he was married and he has grandchildren -
with a woman from the area who is also married with some children.
Suddenly this becomes known to the whole of the village and the stress of this man
is so great that he does not know anymore where to hide himself from everybody gossiping.
He was discovered suddenly to have this illegal affair. The shock for him is tremendous.
So, I said "Peter, you have to be careful because this is a case of cancer",
he says "Why do you say that?",
I said "Because the stress for such a man at this age and the symptomatology coughing
this means he has developed cancer of the lungs".
The fact is that my student has brought this case to me to check me
because I would say "Give Sulphur" and then he would go to the next room
where he left his bag with the x-rays and he would say "Teacher it was a case of cancer
and you did not recognize it. You are treating it as a common cough.
But he opened the mouth like that and he said "Why?" and I explained why I said that.
Don't cough and give me the idea that...
Why I was able to make a correct diagnosis?
Because I knew what I am trying to pass you as information right now.
That is does not matter how healthy an individual can be.
Once the the stress is great the manifestation of a severe degenerative condition
may manifest from one day to the other. But what is the difference?
That his cancer was cured. Because he presented a case of clear Sulphur.
And his case was curable because if the same thing was happening
in an individual of group 7,8,9 lower groups then by the time we were talking
he would already have a metastasis. So another example, I will give you.
Here where I live I had an old man about 70-72 he was my gardener I had noticed
that he had Parkinson because as soon as he got excited he would go like this,
his hands would go like that.
One day he comes and tells me "I hurt my finger. Can you give me a remedy for my finger?"
and I said "Ok, I will give you a remedy for the finger".
But he is farmer he doesn't pay attention. Everybody accepts, he's an old man...
What to ask...
But I had noticed that every time the man was coming he was so dirty in his clothes.
Sometimes I thought he had urinated his pants and he didn't care.
So I said ok this is a case of Sulphur. Because I knew certain other things for instance
he would eat the sweets and every time he would ask for tsipouro, tequila.
He needed some tequila, he eats sweets, he was dirty.
This is characteristic of Sulphur.  The lower jaw it goes like that. I didn't ask a question.
I'll give a remedy for your finger. I gave him Sulphur 200.
And within one week he comes and I see for the first time he has washed his clothes,
he comes and he is with clean clothes...
Now, a German television comes here and come to my house to show to the German people
George Vithoulkas what is doing and all that.
And there is my gardener and I tell them the story of the gardener,
and they see the gardener etc... This documentary was played in Germany 7 times.
Every time it was played I was receiving thousands of letters from Parkinson people
asking for treatment.
Of course some of them may belong to the group 1, but who? All the others... forget it.
We may improve a little bit but forget the cure of such people.
So the idea of the levels of health it became for me very important
and when I wrote my book "The Science of Homeopathy"- I wrote the book in 1976
and two years after it was published 1978 -
I put this idea of the levels of health without giving more information
because before I say something I want to be sure that it is so...
And only in 1995 when this school was established here I started giving the information
about the levels of health because there are some characteristics
about these levels of health.
Which are the characteristics? As you go down the scale and the pathology
becomes deeper and more serious you will have to lower the potency.
That means in the highest groups you can give high potencies,
no problem 1M, 10M, 50M, no problem.
But as the pathology becomes more and more you have to lower the potency.
You go to 200, you go to 30, you go to 12, you go even lower than 12, 12X
and when in the uppermost group one high potency may be enough in the lower groups
you have to repeat.
There is so much confusion if you do not understand these levels of health.
So much confusion about such low/ high potencies, repetitions etc.
Because some homeopaths have noticed that if I repeat the case goes very well
and then makes it a rule for every case.  What happens? Ok, I will explain it to you.
I may go to details but maybe it is important.
What happens is that when you give a remedy on higher groups
you give a shock to the immune system, you trigger the immune system
and after that the immune system comes back and starts doing the work, curing the person.
Once you have power in the immune system you will not have to stimulate it again
because the moment you stimulated it already you changes the vibrational rate
of the immune system.
So when you repeat it later on, after a week or two weeks
the vibrational state of the immune system is not there. It has changed already.
But in case the immune system is very weak you have to stimulate it
again and again and again...
Strong immune system; you stimulate it once, you leave it,  you wait.
You can wait for 1 year and you will see the patient is doing better and better.
But you go down and you give one remedy and you see in one week
there is back everything.
In such cases you need repetition, constant repetition.
So you see how important it is to know what are you treating.
What is the pathology really behind.
Is it possible?  So, another thing that you have to pay attention is...
You get a case with ulcerative colitis and you treat such case
and with one remedy the person comes back.
You have another case of ulcerative colitis and you need 3 years of correct treatment
before you can bring back such a case. So, what is the difference?
The difference is first on the genetic predisposition or there is another factor
which is how much a person who was born with genetic predisposition very high, very good,
how much he has damaged himself through wrong living, wrong medication,
a lot of medication, a lot of drugs, all kinds of drugs, alcohol too much, smoking a lot.
The level of such a person comes to a point when he comes to you
and says now he has arteritis because of too much smoke and drinking etc.
These cases that have been damaged through wrong living and wrong treatments
can respond much better than cases that genetically belong to low levels.
For instance, you will see children born with parents with very good health.
How old is your father? 85. How old is your father? 95.
And he is 65 and he has heart problem.
That means he has damaged his life because he comes with a very good predisposition
but does not pay attention to his own health.
Such persons he says "I had a heart infract or whatever damage in heart",
such a person will respond very well to the treatment.
But if you have another person with the same symptomatology. Your when he died? 65.
From what? Heart infract. Your mother?
My mother was psychotic and she had to go to the asylum etc.
He comes to you with heart problems.
It's going to be very difficult to cure and it's going to take a long time
because the predisposition is bad.
In such cases you will have to struggle but is most important in which
nobody pays attention is that you have to find first the correct remedy,
you have to find the time for the second remedy, to give it in time correct again,
the third time to give it correct...
That means in such an individual you will have indication of 3 different remedies,
they pop up their symptoms. You will have to give Ignatia first,
but some symptoms of Sulphur are manifesting as well.
Is it Sulphur or Ignatia?
And you have to decide which is the first remedy that you must start the case
in order the case progresses properly.
Otherwise you give Sulphur which is second remedy, you give it as first,
you have partial results and then try to give another remedy Calcarea
and then another and another and then you have forgotten the picture of Ignatia in lost.
You don't have it anymore.
Then somebody else comes who is more expert and says "No, the first remedy is Ignatia.
Give Ignatia" and the case becomes coming in order.
And then the picture of Sulphur is manifesting. Give Sulphur now and then Calcarea.
I'll tell you now the big secret about these levels of health.
Now the big secret is coming.
The peculiar thing is that in the uppermost level of health people can develop high fever.
Like most of the children. You see with tonsillitis, 40C, 39,5C... This is a good sign.
It's a sign the immune system is working properly.
Now what happens with mostly Western population, with Europeans,
with Americans with Canadians and this degenerated group of people.
Spain is also within this group. What happens?
Once a degenerative chronic condition begins there in no possibility for the organism
to develop a high fever.
So when you have a case in front of you and ask "when did you have your last high fever?
-I don't remember...maybe 10-12 years ago".
That was the time when his chronic condition has started.
Because once the chronic condition crosses and threshold after that the organism,
the immune system is busy with keeping up a balance.
He does not care about microbes, viruses.
That is why you will see in the flu epidemics who is getting the high fever?
Only the strong organisms. Those with degeneration they are protected.
Even if they do whatever to get high fever it's not possible for them.
So therefore in epidemic in 1950, 100 years ago almost, with the Spanish flu,
where there supposed to be 20.000.000 people dead, pandemic.
They show in the end that only the young and the strong where infected.
It's recorded in all scientific books.
The old and the infirmary, those who were suffering, they were spared.
This model explains why such thing happened.
And the conventional medicine do not still understand this very simple truth
and they say those who are in danger are those who are suffering
and you have to be vaccinated.
This means I am already very bad and I am vaccinated and I go to hell...
Because if such people are vaccinated they're going definitely
to have side-effects from vaccination.
Because you force upon the organism something which is foreign. You see the madness.
An individual is having a heart problem but his immune condition and belongs to group 3.
He is in danger of getting high fever with his heart in a bad condition.
You see the explanation how clear it is.