For this time I have a secret theory, which maybe it will be useful to discuss
concerning the birth of healthy children.
What are the conditions for a child to be born healthy?
I believe that this is a problem with the contemporary society.
And I think that the western population is going towards a degeneration.
One of the main reasons I believe that children are not born healthy anymore
or at least there is a small percentage of children born healthy.
The children are born with missing parts.
Not all of them they have what we call teratogenesis, missing a hand or an ear
but also from emotional and mental point of view, they are born with missing qualities
of these levels.
Why is that? I'll give you my theory which I hope it will be confirmed later on.
All the cells of the body they follow a general state in which we are at a particular moment.
Here is a cell and the state in which we can be is a state of excitation or depression.
So all the time the organism is either in a state of excitation or in a state of depression.
The more healthy we are, the more we have moments of quietness,
where the cells are in a state of non-activity but not in a state of not functioning.
There is functioning, there is dynamism but there is neither excitation, nor depression.
In these moments of quietness, these are the most important phases of the cells.
Why? Because in these phases there is a possibility to perceive or to conceive.
Perceive ideas.
The moment that your mind goes quiet, these are the moments new ideas are born.
Therefore the organism has been programmed by nature to conceive, to perceive during
moments of total quietness.
What means total quietness?
It means a moment during which no factor external or internal affects the cells of the body.
The cells are like relaxing.
We can put in these states, there is another state which is the state of sleep,
in which there is little paramorphosis on the cells. Let's examine what brings these states.
You will be able to understand in the end the issue and advise your clients
and give them correct advise but from a position of knowledge.
You say don't get drunk when you make a conception.
You will see it's much more than this to have a health child.
It takes much more than don't take drugs or don't drink alcohol.
It is something which is much more, it is something which is conception of an idea
or conception of a new child is a magical moment of creation.
We become like creators, little gods if I'm permitted to use such expression.
So therefore in order to be a little god, prepared to bring a child into the world,
you will have to be prepared properly.
So excitation or depression comes from two main factors, external and internal.
External factors are drugs of any type, prescription or non prescription drugs.
The second external factor in which we live is pollution.
And the third external factor in which we have to be aware today is what?
Let me see if you are thinking.
Radio waves, waves, radio, TV, cellular phones, antennas etc.
These three factors force our organism to be in a state of either excitation or depression.
These three factors are becoming more and more widely spread today,
they are used by more and more by people and these two factors are very much imposed
upon everyone of us.
The more we live in cities, the more we are subjected to such pollutions.
Maybe the people who live in high mountains or in far away areas are less affected
by this kind of situation.
Looking at this issue, the internal pollution, what can excite us or depress us mostly?
The main ideas? Look at inside yourselves and you will find out.
What is bothering you most?
-Inner restlessness.
-Loss of inner balance.
-Love life.
-Fear of any kind.
-More or less you stated, I will put it in a different way.
The first is insecurity.
We have created societies in which we have created insecurity for ourselves.
Nobody is secure anymore.
Can you imagine somebody being totally secure? No.
There are robbers, there are some people who may take your money, your property...
We have created a state of insecurity, which is almost constant.
We feel insecure.
That state will definitely affect the cells and will not allow phase 1 to be prevalent.
Rather phase 2 and 3 are the most prevalent.
The organism in a state of excitation or in a state of depression.
Exactly the same condition is followed by every cell of the human body and remember.
When there is conception both organisms are giving out live cells
that can have the possibility of coming together and creating a new born child.
Live cells.
We discard cells which are dead but during this function,
you discharge live cells in a condition.
Which is the condition and what happens during this meeting of one cell with the other,
the sperm with the ovum? What happens?
There is a miracle that happens.
The question is can the miracle happen when cells are in a state of excitation
or depression or can the miracle happen when the cells are in a phase of quietness?
Dynamic quietness, not apathy.
The second internal pollution that we create for ourselves is conflict.
Is it good to have sex or not good? Is it good to go there? Is it correct this or that?
Is it possible to do this or it is not possible? Socially possible?
How many times to have sex? Three times the week or three times the day?
All these are conflicts in which we are impeding ourselves all the time
and the biggest conflict is the fear of death.
There are the three big issues
in which we are affecting the cells of the body.
Think and observe.
This kind of pollution is it usual for people living in the mountains of Venezuela
or this is a state which is usual with people living in New York?
-Or Athens?
-Thank you for the correction. Los Angeles actually is best.
This is a state in which we have brought ourselves.
As a result we have a state in which women cannot conceive.
The problem of conception is becoming bigger and bigger in our western societies.
The problem of conception is tremendous at the moment.
And what is the advice that we give? Don't go pollution, don't go there
but still some conceptions are happening.
The question is these conceptions which are happening are complete conceptions
or they are teratogenesis? This is a question.
The gynecologist looks on the monitor and says your child is OK
because the hands are there, the nose and the eyes.
What about the other qualities of that human being which is going to be born?
Is he going to be missing the possibility to think, the possibility to discriminate,
the possibility to love, the possibility to exchange with others?
Is he going to be a kind of a monster not outside but inside? Born monster?
We hear of events where somebody took a gun and killed, just killed a child.
10 people, 20 people and you say what is going on in this world?
We are interested, we are investigating, we are thinking what is the real problem?
Maybe there is a possibility to correct the situation. What are these possibilities?
What shall we do? Can we do something?
We will reach conclusion, you will see very strange conclusions for the society
in which we live.
What I want you to understand is the phase of quietness.
I don't know how many of you, you have studied mathematics
and you have to solve the problem in mathematics and you battle?
At a certain moment, because you cannot solve the problem, there is a total quietness,
giving up and at this moment the solution comes. This is the mechanism of Creation.
Why? I want you to understand why.
Because at this moment there is no interference from these factors.
These factors for a split of a moment have been forgotten.
I must solve the problem, otherwise I will not pass the examination,
the insecurity and the fear. These factors will interfere for the creation of a new idea.
-You say that conflict is like a struggle. The minute that you give up,
you gain enlightenment?
-Yes correct, we'll go there.
Therefore in order to create we must not interfere.
That is the first thing we must understand.
But who creates? We are the creators but there is something else,
which interferes with the whole process, which each one calls it according to his religion,
calls it god or Mohamed or Allah.
There is another factor unknown, X-factor which has to be entering into the picture
in order to have a complete concept, that means a perception of an idea which is true.
There are a lot of ideas conceived by people but many of them have the sperm of disease.
They are not total ideas, they are not complete ideas and that is why these ideas can
also produce evil, can produce negative things.
Another condition in which your organism is in total quietness
is what the yogis try to attend. To quieten their mind.
They say the moment you quieten your mind something happens and they call it enlightenment.
Enlightened means a state in which you give up your own thoughts and ideas
and you are united with a state of consciousness which is much higher.
And then there is creation of life inside.
Why people try to get that state? That state of enlightenment is a state of complete bliss,
knowledge and bliss.
It's total bliss, total understanding. You are complete.
You feel you don't need any more the advice of somebody, the help of somebody.
All this is gone and you are complete.
These are very rare moments in which the organism overcomes the phase 2
and the phase 3 and gets into the phase 1, which is the phase of total quietness.
During this phase, if a conception takes place during this phase nr 1
and this happens from both parties, then you have the most possible healthy child.
Without missing qualities, without missing organs.
Nature has found a way to overcome these insecurities, conflicts and excitations.
That's why conception cannot take place so easily anymore now.
Because these phases are less and less.
Which is the way that nature has found to make you come to the phase 1,
without you doing anything mentally or emotionally? Making a trick.
My impression is that all scientists at this moment try to trick nature.
They will say eventually we could produce a human being without the participation.
But we will see now how difficult it will be such an endeavor and how dangerous.
So nature has found a way to bring you in a state of phase 1.
Nature has found 'eros', the Greek word is 'eros'.
In English they call it falling in love.
Nature has found a way to bring you to that state of total satisfaction,
complete relaxation, which comes when two people are in love.
They so much love each other that they lose themselves and they want to be united
with the other person to such a degree that they totally lose their individuality.
As an individual you don't exist, you exist in a communion with the other person.
That state has a culmination, what we call the orgasm.
There is this state of excitement and loss of individuality, loss of egotistical element
which is in you and then comes a moment that you discharge the live cells from your body.
You let these life cells out in order to be united.
These cells are in the state of most satisfaction.
That means they don't need anything else.
You have experienced everyone of you the feeling of a love, a real love affair
that ends into a complete completion.
The cells that are coming out are in exactly the state in which the individuals
are at the moment of the discharge, at the moment of the orgasm.
Otherwise you could not reach phase 1.
You would be either in the state of insecurity or depression or whatever.
Can we have a conception under this state or that state? We will examine.
What I want you to understand is how important it is when you have a child.
You don't have a child by just going Mr... can you come in bed with me,
so I can have a child with you. You can have a child perhaps.
But this child is going to be missing certain organs, certain qualities of the soul,
of the spirit. It will not be a complete creation for the good of the planet.
It will be somebody who is missing certain parts.
That's why you get patients who say I can never feel this or I have never felt that.
A lot of women never felt the enjoyment of orgasm, of love.
They say what is this? I don't know.
Sometimes we can correct this by giving Sepia, Lilium tigrinum, Aurum etc.
But you will see also the very interesting phenomenon because I have been observing
this situation for many years since the beginning of my practice.
Women or men will come with sterility.
You give a remedy and within the next few days there is conception.
Because, as you know, the moment that you give the homeopathic remedy,
maybe there is an aggravation but immediately there is a phase 1 state
in which the individual says I feel so good.
I feel so good, it is when the cells are in a phase of perception.
They are ready to perceive ideas, feelings or to conceive.
The moment you are balancing...
That is why Ignatia many times will be one of the remedies
that you will be using for sterility.
You give Ignatia and the next month the woman is pregnant.
It is very strange because for years she could not, because the anxiety was inside.
Shall I conceive or shall I not conceive?
So the homeopathic remedy actually creates the conditions in the body through
this balancing which brings suddenly for the body to conceive and to conceive correctly.
You may understand how incorrectly the medical world have understood
the problem of sterility. They say OK we'll solve it.
We'll do artificial dissemination and sometimes it is effective, sometimes it's not effective.
Sometimes is yes, sometimes is no. Most of the times is no. Why?
Because of that state.
The woman is not in a state of phase 1 by the time they do the dissemination.
Even if they wanted to use this method, they should bring the woman into phase 1
and during that time they should do it in order to have an effect.
But this state is not brought so easily because of disease
and that is why the homeopathic remedy balancing the body, it can bring about an effect.
It can be understood why we cannot overcome nature.
The things that we have learned from our history as human race were correct ideas
that we discarded by scientific thinking.
We are clever, we will find out, we will do this, we will do that...
By doing this we have rejected ideas that came from the past,
which are necessary for the regeneration of the human race.
Because if you have conceptions under that state or that state,
you will have constant losing of qualities in the human being.
I cannot do that, I cannot do that and then the race is finished.
And they were some facts of life, which we totally ignore and one of the facts is this.
Falling in love really. Who is falling in love? Do you think many people fall in love?
It is a particular state that maybe the individual must come.
You think that you fall in love.
Maybe you don't fall in love because in the back of their mind there is a reservation.
Shall I get hurt? I like this man but let me hold back a little bit of myself.
These ideas have been promoted more and more and have become the norm in the society
I'm not sure that the example I give you is correct.
But when we see the American model, it is very interesting.
The American model it is depicted in their films.
You see the film and you see the couples and what is accepted is...
I love you and suddenly one of the two says where did you put my shoes?
I cannot find my shoes. What the hell how should I know about your shoes?
Suddenly there is a divorce case because she cannot find the shoes.
Is this love? Each one thought there is love but actually what it was,
it was an individual who demanded his own. An individual who did not want to give
but only to take. And you see the American model comes more and more of that type.
Therefore when these two people come together, they are not in phase 1
in order to create a total human being but create a little monster, a little 'teras'.
In Greek 'teras' is monster, teratogenesis is born as a monster.
-What is the case with all those people who are living in arranged marriages
with no love before? Asia, Africa?
-This is a good question but in India, which I know, in which arranged marriage take place,
what happens is that they go to the astrologer and the astrologer looks
at the charts of the people and decides if they are compatible.
It seems, I don't know by what kind of knowledge that are usually right.
When these people come together and they find out about the qualities of each other,
they really match.
Where in our societies in which we choose by our standards the partner,
we are usually incorrect.
Why? Because of the divorce numbers in the one society and the other society.
You cannot live anymore, you say this makes me sick.
I cannot stay in that marriage because I will become sick.
So therefore the society, in which we live, has lost the capacity to recognize
the qualities of the other.
Unless two monsters are coming together, sometimes this may happen also.
Two monsters may come together and they match so much
that they maybe produce a good child.
This is a cell under excitation and if the other cell is going like this, then it may happen.
But usually it comes like this in the western society.
It's not a matching, it's a conflict.
We see the importance of falling in love, which is a human quality of great order,
which we have misused due to the incapacity to choose correctly.
There is another important factor which was since time immemorial,
which could bring people on the phase 1.
Except of 'eros' there is another factor, which could cancel this at least
the internal pollution.
What is this factor that was there since time immemorial.
We hear it from the depth of human existence.
-Belief.
-Belief, faith.
This state in which the individual lets his problems and says I give it to god.
There is a state of security that comes in, in which people they believe they lean on
and therefore they have a lot of phases in nr 1.
They are living much more phases nr 1.
That is why all people who are under a religious state, they can perform,
they can create better children...
For instance, since you are talking about India.
India is a country in which everyone spiritually tries to create something,
to evolve spiritually.
The same is with people of rather undeveloped countries.
The need to believe into something higher gives them much more phase 1 states.
I have heard people confessing murder, having taken drugs, having stolen things
and they confess under a religious belief and you see a transformation.
You see in their eyes a state of deep satisfaction.
That deep satisfaction gives them the possibility to be in phase 1 much more frequently
and therefore to have healthier children.
-Isn't this creating a lot of wars?
Islam are under a religious belief when they think that they are the only ones
and they are very aggressive. So I don't think this is so.
-We'll talk about that. When I say belief and faith, I mean real belief and real faith.
Those who create wars are the people who want to control others through religion.
Those who want to control and to get authority through religion are creating wars,
not the people who believe, but those who exploit those people who believe.
You believe? Yes. Now we have to conquer and they push them to wars.
But anybody who is really in touch with god, who really is in touch
with real consciousness, to go to war? Forget it.
On the other hand these people being on phase 1, they see clearly what is happening outside.
You remember when we spoke about the Kosovo war
and the Nato people being monsters of that type.
They were just killing thousands of people without blinking an eye.
And those who were outside looking said my god.
In the name of religion or peace we have a massacre of people.
We are spreading radio-active materials in the whole of Europe, killing people.
Why the radio-active materials are so dangerous for human beings?
Because they give a constant excitation of the cells.
They produce a constant excitation without any stoppage and therefore
we have mostly the teratogenesis, which we know, under radio-active influences.
-What I'd like to know is what role you, actually, see nurture takes in this?
If somebody produces a healthy child, can we actually corrupt this child and
make it unhealthy and can we take a child born in an excited state
and make that a healthy person?
-This is a good question but the child we are talking about in these phases are qualities
they are missing genetically.
What we see in these cases is for instance a case in which an enzyme is missing.
And the child will have this problem because of genetic predisposition.
So it is very difficult. If not totally impossible to bring back the qualities through
Homeopathy when genetically is missing the quality.
It's missing for instance the ovaries. The woman ovaries are not functioning genetically.
It's very difficult to correct that.
You get people who say I never felt love. This is not natural.
You talk to young women 25-30, they say never, not really.
What is missing? This passion which will be needed to bring them to the phase 1 state.
It's missing already from birth.
Is it understood that you have to project these ideas further in what actually happens
in our societies.
And say what was your state when your child was born.
That becomes a very important factor.
When you have to advice somebody, you have to tell that these are the facts.
If you really want a complete human being, you have to be in that state.
Otherwise, either no conception or the conception will take place with a missing part.
-I hear what you are saying to some extend but considering
that we are all supposing miasmatically sick, is really then no possibility
of getting a totally healthy child from anybody?
Because if we are miasmatically sick to some extent,
we must still possess some insecurity and conflict inside.
Therefore we never come to that total phase 1 to get an actually healthy child.
-It is not everybody. I don't say 100% we are sick, therefore we cannot get a child.
It's as simple as that.
What I say is that giving the fact that we go into marriages or into relations,
which they do not have these properties, these qualities,
then we are run into the danger of bringing out a child that will be missing certain qualities,
which are necessary for the regeneration of the human race, for continuing the human race.
And if we continue in this way, the race which we call today the western population
will be totally degenerated.
Here we are talking about the health of the people and we have to understand
what we are doing to ourselves.
Here is a place where we think of the future. We don't think, oh you have a headache,
take this remedy and kill the headache.
We have to see the totality of what is happening concerning health and we have to transfer
these ideas to the medical authorities and to medical institutions,
so they start changing a little bit their way of thinking.
Otherwise where do we land? Put a plastic heart, a plastic liver and two plastic kidneys
and we are happy.
The science. Is this science or is it monstrous minds?
The thing is that the monster here is not going to kill always but what is going to do,
to look for blood? We get it. Money or fame or whatever.
And in the name of fame or money we have scientists who are producing ideas
which are dangerous.
This is what has happened in our society.
Scientists we admire as accomplishments of science are coming from monstrous minds
that cannot think in a total way.
I found this, I will become rich, I will become famous...
It doesn't matter what is the consequence of what you thought and what you discovered.
And we as society we accept all this, instead of resisting.
What is resisting? Resisting is to get this third factor out.
If my time has come that I will die, I will die with integrity and with peace.
I don't have to live another two years with a plastic heart. This is inconceivable.
The problem is created here in the very beginning.
Because these children here they will develop...
If you miss a part, it's going to be replaced by another.
If you miss one eye, the other eye is very acute.
If you miss one hand, with the other hand you become very dexterous.
if you miss both hands, with the feet you can paint, you can do anything.
It replaces, in the same way nature replaces.
When you miss a part, the soul replaces it by another.
That means you miss the possibility to love but you are very clever.
They make you very clever. Who made you very clever?
The scientists producing something without heart.
Producing something that the heart is missing, that means the feeling is missing.
-There are two factors to overcome this.
One is eros and the other one is the state of faith.
Can you think of faith as a state in which you feel content, secure,
then I would like to ask if there are any interactions between these two to measure?
Between eros and faith. The reason for my question is the following.
Falling in love is something you cannot really control but faith and belief
that are part of Creation it is a point I can work out myself. That's why I ask.
-It's a very good question. The similarities are these.
Falling in love it happens to you because of another person.
You fall in love because you find somebody to whom you trust completely
and you give yourself.
Eros does not exist unless the other person reciprocates.
Then love is created.
Otherwise it is not eros, it is a feeling which is missing the bigger part of satisfaction.
The reciprocal love of the other person.
In the same way you can work on faith, you can pray, you can go to church,
you do whatever are your duties, you meditate but you need the approval.
What is called the blessing of god, which comes at a certain moment.
There is a state of blessing that comes, which is as if the doors
have been opened and then you in communication, you are accepted.
In the same way the phase 1 is when you are accepted.
Phase 1 does not come with I like this man or I like this woman.
This does not bring you to phase 1. Because you always want.
The person is missing.
When the person comes and there is this unification, then there is total calmness inside.
And satisfaction.
That is where the creation of such a child will be the most healthy.
It will be a child that even if it has some defect,
even genetically, mentally and emotionally will be very much balanced.
-You are describing a very frightful situation when you are talking about those two phases.
I mean the depression and the emotional situation.
If it can be inherited, it is like describing a new miasma.
-What can be inherited?
-Those two phases. If these can be inherited, it is like describing a new miasma.
-No, I am describing what we know as the existing miasmas.
The existing miasmas create more and more stages of that, they do not allow phase 1.
It's very little time, very little moments and that is why you need a very strong desire
for a person and then the satisfaction that you have finally, that person,
and then the conception and if it happens under this condition, then you have a good child.
But I will tell you something else also which is very interesting concerning faith.
In our societies, the idea of gurus have become very popular. What is a guru?
A guru is a symbol which is replacing god, in which the person has the need to project
that there is a perfect individual, very close to god,
to whom I can trust and I can communicate.
The need for faith was filled with the different gurus and spiritual teachers which appeared
In our society, lately very much.
Because the people who left from original faith, they went into a state of doubting and unbelieving.
They found themselves in a state of constant excitation and they tried quickly
to replace that deep feeling with a symbol, a human being who is perfect
and to whom I can trust totally my life.
Of course this is a very dangerous situation because these individuals
are exactly like all of us with certain weaknesses and when we found out that this is so,
then there is a big disappointment.
And then if you believe to a guru and you are disappointed, then you cannot recover anymore.
You see the whole situation how it has been created slowly?
By going away from basic nature.
We created an artificial world, which is going to collapse.
That is why Homeopathy is so important for the world because it has the possibility
to regenerate. To regenerate what has been degenerating all along.
When you see the possibility of Homeopathy in severe pathology,
when you see the possibility, then you are amazed.
What I want to repeat is to understand that this function of the human psyche,
the desire to be united, which we call eros, is a factor that should overcome this factor.
If this desire or this love is not strong enough to overcome these conflicts
and insecurities and fears, then we have not a completely calm state of selves.
The same with the belief and faith, it's not a matter of I believe in god.
It is a state of faith, a state of belief to bring up the relaxation of the cells.
If you ask anybody they say, I'm a Catholic, a Protestant, a Jewish,
a Mohammedan, a Christian.
It doesn't mean anything.
What we mean here is the real state of communication.
You commune, you feel that you talk to god and god talks to you.
In the same way this is in a love affair.
In a love affair you say something and the other person before you finish,
he knows what you are talking about.
And then there is a reciprocal communication in another than verbal level.
In that state, the conception of children is much more healthy.
The consequences of this theory should be that first of all
that children are to be born best when the young people, in young age, they first fall in love.
Because if this is overcome, and this is usually the case,
because they say we are not ready to have a family.
Let's wait, let's take precautions and later on when we have established our job,
when we have better houses, then we have children.
This idea is logical but from the point of view of health is wrong.
The children that are healthy will be more healthy, if they are born
in the first real love affair.
Because later on the mind interferes very much with the process
and does not allow this total relaxation, which happens in the beginning, unfortunately.
Another conclusion we can draw is that children which are programmed...
You program to have a child and then you have sex to have a child.
Later on what happens is that the woman becomes infertile and then there is anxiety
and every time they try to find out what happens.
This is not good condition for a child to be born.
The child is born and then you have to battle a lot with problems with children.
You see children that they have a lot of personality disorders.
Then you battle and battle and then eventually after going through
these personality disorders and you correct them,
you see manifesting physical symptomatology.
And you have infections, you have physical diseases.
What we state here is some facts, which can be accepted or cannot be accepted.
It doesn't matter but you as counselors, as advisers, you have to know these things
in order to be able to advise correctly.
After that it is on the choice and the freedom of each person to follow his fate.
It's not your responsibility anymore.
The love that goes away after 2-3 years and then they decide after 8 years
to have a child, this is not a good idea. It doesn't matter whether it is more practical.
I understand it is more practical but from the point of health it's not practical.
When I was in India, I lived in that culture quite a long time and so I can compare.
The Indians are the biggest stealers, they steal but they never kill.
They steal because they are very poor.
So if you are rich, they say OK you are rich, then can steal from you.
It is a survival instinct but the aggressiveness that we see in the West,
you don't see in India. You don't see the aggressiveness.
You may see it eventually if the societies degenerate
but by the time I was there in 1963, 64, 65 it was no aggressiveness.
Now if the Indian people come in the West and they are injected with vaccinations
and antibiotics and they enter into the western mentality,
of course they will become also aggressive but I say it as a whole.
There are a few couples only which are lucky enough to have this love continuing for years,
for more than 3 years. They are very few cases we see that.
If anybody of you have this, try to keep it like a jewel.
Don't misunderstand it and think that at a certain moment, maybe I can also divorce
and have another affair.
So these are some of the conclusions that we have to come in case we want to advice somebody.