<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tt xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1" xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#styling">
<head>
<horsedata><item name="behaviour_useEnterKey">linebreak</item><item name="editor_fontSizeCombo">false</item><item name="editor_valignButtons">false</item><item name="editor_boldBtn">true</item><item name="editor_italicBtn">true</item><item name="editor_underlinedBtn">true</item><item name="behaviour_transcriptMode">true</item><item name="editor_clearFormatBtn">true</item><item name="editor_alignButtons">false</item><item name="appearance_showMultiLinesTitles">false</item><item name="editor_fontFamilyCombo">false</item><item name="appearance_showBlackBG">false</item><item name="behaviour_autocorrect">true</item><item name="behaviour_titlesGap">0.072</item></horsedata></head>
<body>
<div>
<p begin="00:01:06.840" end="00:01:17.258" horseID="0">Here in Aconitum you see, fear of death and feeling that death is imminent or near.</p>
<p begin="00:01:17.330" end="00:01:35.640" horseID="1">Death is near, any case whether it is a colitis, an acute condition, a chronic condition of any kind, once he has the fear of death</p>
<p begin="00:01:35.830" end="00:01:50.778" horseID="2">and that death is very near: I'm going to die tomorrow, in 3 days, in 3 months, once there is this element </p>
<p begin="00:01:50.850" end="00:02:03.328" horseID="3">you will have to think of Aconite, agonizing fear of death. The fear of death brings agony. </p>
<p begin="00:02:05.640" end="00:02:16.908" horseID="4">You will ask a case, do you have fear of death, they will say, yes I am afraid of death.</p>
<p begin="00:02:16.980" end="00:02:22.408" horseID="5">If they say it like this, this is not an Aconite condition.</p>
<p begin="00:02:23.740" end="00:02:38.068" horseID="6">If the answer is 'yes my god I'm terrified!' then your mind should go to Aconite.</p>
<p begin="00:02:38.140" end="00:02:52.050" horseID="7">If on the top they will say, 'that not only I'm afraid but I'm afraid that I will die soon', this is more of an Aconite condition.</p>
<p begin="00:02:52.122" end="00:02:58.240" horseID="8">Never mind what is the problem.</p>
<p begin="00:03:00.960" end="00:03:31.328" horseID="9">Panic states, intense panic which has sudden, violent palpitations, red face, one sided numbness,</p>
<p begin="00:03:31.400" end="00:03:56.950" horseID="10">faint feeling, perspiration, trembling, vertigo, dyspnoea, fear of death. All these symptoms are symptoms which arise from</p>
<p begin="00:03:57.230" end="00:04:13.328" horseID="11">a shock that a person has had while his life was threatened, that means he was closed in a lift.</p>
<p begin="00:04:13.400" end="00:04:30.168" horseID="12">And he felt I'm going to die now, I suffocate, I am here enclosed. He found himself in an accident, threatened by a pistol. </p>
<p begin="00:04:30.240" end="00:04:42.618" horseID="13">That state which is created in such a situation, if it repeats itself again and again and again or if that state </p>
<p begin="00:04:44.480" end="00:04:57.928" horseID="14">that you can imagine how the person behaves under the threat of death if that state appears in any condition</p>
<p begin="00:04:58.000" end="00:05:02.160" horseID="15">that is an Aconite state.</p>
<p begin="00:05:03.190" end="00:05:18.080" horseID="16">- Could I ask you if this fear of death has to be for themselves or can also cover a fear of death , for instance saying,</p>
<p begin="00:05:18.120" end="00:05:23.808" horseID="17"> I don't wish to die because I don't know what will happen to my children, of if I die I don't know</p>
<p begin="00:05:23.880" end="00:05:29.020" horseID="18">how my parents will handle that or is it an individual fear of death.</p>
<p begin="00:05:29.130" end="00:05:34.328" horseID="19">-No, the shock has to threaten his own life.</p>
<p begin="00:05:36.770" end="00:05:56.048" horseID="20">And it says, acute symptoms arising from exposure to dry, cold winds. Another causative factor is dry, cold winds bring about</p>
<p begin="00:05:56.120" end="00:06:04.510" horseID="21">violent palpitation, red face, one sided numbness, faint feeling, perspiration,  fear of death.</p>
<p begin="00:06:21.500" end="00:06:29.440" horseID="22">-Can this state be caused by watching a threatening situation?</p>
<p begin="00:06:30.270" end="00:06:50.258" horseID="23">-Threatening, yes. This can be caused by watching a threatening situation, by watching some scene under which </p>
<p begin="00:06:50.330" end="00:07:05.300" horseID="24">the life is threatened, by a robbery, this situation can arise. But the idea is that it does not have to arise always from that cause.</p>
<p begin="00:07:05.520" end="00:07:14.688" horseID="25">I'm just giving you the idea to show you how the person feels, I'm going to die.</p>
<p begin="00:07:14.760" end="00:07:33.850" horseID="26">When somebody puts a pistol, in 2-3 minutes you are dead, right? It's finished, my life is gone.</p>
<p begin="00:07:34.360" end="00:07:48.448" horseID="27">You don't have to have the real fact that this person was threatened. What you have to have is the result of such action.</p>
<p begin="00:07:48.520" end="00:07:53.808" horseID="28">How a person feels when somebody puts a pistol.</p>
<p begin="00:07:53.880" end="00:08:03.848" horseID="29">It may never happen to this person but the idea is the same, the symptomatology of Aconitum is the same.</p>
<p begin="00:08:05.760" end="00:08:15.450" horseID="30">I'm going to die, I'm going to die! I'm dying! </p>
<p begin="00:08:17.450" end="00:08:31.928" horseID="31">Palpitation, restlessness. This panic states, nobody can live constantly in such panic states,</p>
<p begin="00:08:34.770" end="00:08:44.048" horseID="32">It is like a wave. It comes and then it goes <br/>and then the person is calm.</p>
<p begin="00:08:44.120" end="00:08:56.928" horseID="33">There is no problem, so panic states that come to great intensity and then they go. But when they come</p>
<p begin="00:08:57.000" end="00:09:08.848" horseID="34">these people need immediately attention. They are the people who will run to the emergency hospitals </p>
<p begin="00:09:08.920" end="00:09:16.258" horseID="35">to save their life because they feel<br/>that their life is really in danger.</p>
<p begin="00:09:16.330" end="00:09:33.518" horseID="36">In more chronic states you will see the same idea. If somebody tells you 'well I'm tormented by fear of dying </p>
<p begin="00:09:33.590" end="00:09:41.160" horseID="37">and I'm married and I have 2 children and I think I'm going to die and leave these children orphans'.</p>
<p begin="00:09:42.590" end="00:09:49.288" horseID="38">If somebody tells you something like this, immediately your mind goes to... because the question that you will have to</p>
<p begin="00:09:49.290" end="00:09:58.688" horseID="39">ask immediately is: do you feel that you are going to die soon?. 'Yes!'. This is Aconite. </p>
<p begin="00:09:58.760" end="00:10:05.008" horseID="40">'Yes, I think I'm going to die quite soon'. 'When?'. 'I don't know but quite soon'. </p>
<p begin="00:10:07.380" end="00:10:12.608" horseID="41">This is an Aconite. It does not matter what it is, you see?</p>
<p begin="00:10:29.040" end="00:10:52.728" horseID="42">And there are certain specific fears which are elevators, tunnels, fear that their heart will stop, fear of going in the airplane,</p>
<p begin="00:10:52.800" end="00:11:09.538" horseID="43">fear of earthquake, fear in a crowd, in narrow places all these situations are situations where a person feels his life is in danger.</p>
<p begin="00:11:10.920" end="00:11:18.778" horseID="44">If there is an earthquake here, you will immediately feel fear, right?</p>
<p begin="00:11:18.850" end="00:11:30.800" horseID="45">If any of you stays with this fear, in order to counteract this fear, Aconite is a specific remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:11:32.440" end="00:11:41.240" horseID="46">Ah, I'm going to die, again it comes, again it comes, Aconite.</p>
<p begin="00:11:50.570" end="00:11:56.460" horseID="47">Intense nervous restlessness, tossing <br/>about intense thirst for cold water. </p>
<p begin="00:11:58.200" end="00:12:07.968" horseID="48">This anxiety state which causes restlessness, the person wants to move all the time, up and down. </p>
<p begin="00:12:12.270" end="00:12:23.488" horseID="49"> You don't need to remember anything else for Aconite but if you go to the Repertory you will see</p>
<p begin="00:12:23.560" end="00:12:33.548" horseID="50">3.000 symptoms of course but you have to have this picture to prescribe Aconite. This is where your mind says,</p>
<p begin="00:12:33.620" end="00:12:48.108" horseID="51">when you see the patient, is this a case of Aconite? Immediately when you have that picture your mind will go to Aconite.</p>
<p begin="00:12:53.180" end="00:13:01.870" horseID="52">That reminds me something, Georges was taking about. What? Aconite. You know it comes like this.</p>
<p begin="00:13:05.940" end="00:13:16.608" horseID="53">Closed in an elevator, ah I can't go in an elevator. Why? I feel I suffocate, I feel I will die. Possible Aconite.</p>
<p begin="00:13:16.680" end="00:13:27.170" horseID="54">Fear of death? Yes. How strong? Strong. Yes. You feel that you're going to die soon? Yes. Aconite.</p>
<p begin="00:13:32.800" end="00:13:42.320" horseID="55">So learning in this way the Materia Medica it will be very easy to find the remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:13:47.560" end="00:13:53.788" horseID="56">-Your experience of having prescribed the Aconite in chronic disease, do you see there are people who </p>
<p begin="00:13:53.860" end="00:13:57.928" horseID="57">would be present these panic states in any pathology?</p>
<p begin="00:13:58.000" end="00:14:13.270" horseID="58">-In any pathology they can present this picture, this agonizing fear of death with the feeling that death is coming soon.</p>
<p begin="00:14:13.910" end="00:14:19.858" horseID="59">-But after you prescribed a remedy, let's say in 10M or 50M, and do you see that they're braced up in future </p>
<p begin="00:14:19.930" end="00:14:24.338" horseID="60">for the pathology or do they still presenting the same thing?</p>
<p begin="00:14:24.410" end="00:14:35.840" horseID="61">-It doesn't. The fear of death subsides almost immediately and totally.</p>
<p begin="00:14:35.880" end="00:14:39.870" horseID="62">-For future reference also?<br/>-Yes, for future reference also. </p>
<p begin="00:14:46.550" end="00:14:53.808" horseID="63"> You see you get these chronic cases of Aconite, it's beautiful to see how the whole syndrome</p>
<p begin="00:14:53.880" end="00:15:00.610" horseID="64">is counteracted and the person for years lives without problem.</p>
<p begin="00:15:17.590" end="00:15:28.738" horseID="65">The way I write what impresses you here? Two or three things, that's all you have to remember.</p>
<p begin="00:15:30.560" end="00:15:49.330" horseID="66">What impresses you? Fear of cancer, especially cancer. They are not afraid of fear of brain stroke, of heart disease,</p>
<p begin="00:15:49.360" end="00:16:01.488" horseID="67">everything is cancer. Everything is overwhelmed in this case with the fear that they have cancer.</p>
<p begin="00:16:02.880" end="00:16:14.400" horseID="68">The second is twitchings, spasms,<br/> convulsions, chorea. Twitchings. </p>
<p begin="00:16:23.400" end="00:16:31.858" horseID="69">So if you have fear of cancer and<br/> twichings the remedy is Agaricus.</p>
<p begin="00:16:31.930" end="00:16:38.848" horseID="70"> It doesn't matter what is the pathology,<br/> just two things and the remedy is here.</p>
<p begin="00:16:38.920" end="00:16:48.560" horseID="71">There is no other remedy that has this combination. The idea is the combination of 2-3 symptoms.</p>
<p begin="00:16:50.840" end="00:16:55.928" horseID="72">You get the combination correctly, <br/>you get the remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:17:04.000" end="00:17:15.618" horseID="73">Now of course, you have the main thing which is fear of cancer but this fear of cancer will present to you,</p>
<p begin="00:17:15.690" end="00:17:23.708" horseID="74">it will be presented as something which the patient is really concerned, about his health.</p>
<p begin="00:17:23.780" end="00:17:38.360" horseID="75">He will say this, this, that and he will end up with the fear of cancer. And then your mind will go to certain remedies,</p>
<p begin="00:17:38.500" end="00:17:47.468" horseID="76">one of which is Agaricus.<br/>Next question: do you have twitchings?</p>
<p begin="00:17:47.540" end="00:18:02.598" horseID="77">  What is twitchings? Oh, yes. Where? Here, there. Your case is finished.</p>
<p begin="00:18:10.240" end="00:18:21.008" horseID="78">You will not believe that this is how I go about finding the remedies. Because I have this knowledge in my head,</p>
<p begin="00:18:21.080" end="00:18:27.428" horseID="79">I short out the remedy, I say, not this remedy, not that remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:18:27.500" end="00:18:40.158" horseID="80">Which is the remedy George which has tremendous fear of cancer? 1,2,3,4. Ok, I eliminate quickly.</p>
<p begin="00:18:41.640" end="00:18:51.088" horseID="81">Now, this person I found out, that they develop this kind of fear, this kind of anxiety.</p>
<p begin="00:18:51.160" end="00:19:06.108" horseID="82">They are patients with weak character, with weak will, there is no will. There is some kind of weakness </p>
<p begin="00:19:06.180" end="00:19:16.258" horseID="83">in their character, dependency. They depend<br/> and they depend mainly on the doctor.</p>
<p begin="00:19:17.950" end="00:19:26.668" horseID="84"> Because you do not get immediately the remedy, you don't give immediately Agaricus.</p>
<p begin="00:19:28.210" end="00:19:35.928" horseID="85">When I started Homeopathy, I did not know Agaricus had that picture and I would prescribe Nitric acid </p>
<p begin="00:19:36.000" end="00:19:42.138" horseID="86">because it has anxiety about health. And I would prescribe Lyc., Phos., Ars., Kali-ars., Arg-n</p>
<p begin="00:19:48.420" end="00:19:58.608" horseID="87">and then one day I found out the twitchings<br/> and I said, wait a moment, Agaricus, finish.</p>
<p begin="00:19:58.680" end="00:20:07.568" horseID="88">In the meantime I had this patient for 2 years.<br/> For 2 years the patient is coming and going, Arg-n. a little better, </p>
<p begin="00:20:07.640" end="00:20:13.458" horseID="89">Phosphorus a little bit better, not really.</p>
<p begin="00:20:14.780" end="00:20:26.448" horseID="90">And the fear just to give an example of this kind of fear. I have seen it in a Medical doctor.</p>
<p begin="00:20:26.520" end="00:20:39.888" horseID="91">He works in the hospital. So in the hospital, he sees a case. He takes this case. This is a cancer of the colon.</p>
<p begin="00:20:41.130" end="00:20:47.418" horseID="92">The patient relates that I had mucus in the stool with blood etc.</p>
<p begin="00:20:47.490" end="00:21:02.478" horseID="93">Immediately he thinks that he also has exactly the same symptoms. He would telephone and say, well I just took a case </p>
<p begin="00:21:02.550" end="00:21:14.298" horseID="94">and I saw a case with cancer and I feel I have the same symptoms. What is the same symptoms? </p>
<p begin="00:21:14.370" end="00:21:21.148" horseID="95"> Mucus in my stool and sometimes I have seen also some blood.</p>
<p begin="00:21:22.240" end="00:21:32.918" horseID="96">And I said for so many years I treat you, you never told me about mucus. He is sure he has mucus in the stool </p>
<p begin="00:21:32.990" end="00:21:42.700" horseID="97">and he has blood in the stool and he now found the cancer, he has the cancer of the colon. </p>
<p begin="00:21:45.200" end="00:21:56.218" horseID="98"> One night he came in a panic state. He said, 'I'm getting crazy. I saw another case and this is....'</p>
<p begin="00:21:56.290" end="00:22:12.048" horseID="99">and then I saw doing this, in that state you<br/> know? His facial (muscles), they were torturing, chorea. </p>
<p begin="00:22:15.660" end="00:22:24.210" horseID="100"> He didn't have the chorea but I saw the activity on the nervous system with the muscles.</p>
<p begin="00:22:30.830" end="00:22:36.840" horseID="101">It's so terrifying, the fear is overwhelming.</p>
<p begin="00:22:37.930" end="00:22:44.618" horseID="102">He says, what shall I do? I'm finished, <br/>my life is finished. I'm dying from cancer.</p>
<p begin="00:22:50.200" end="00:22:54.000" horseID="103">Agaricus CM. </p>
<p begin="00:22:54.072" end="00:23:02.498" horseID="104"> I telephone next day and I said, how are you?</p>
<p begin="00:23:04.750" end="00:23:24.108" horseID="105">He says 'I don't know after this crisis I had last night, I decided that I should never again be influenced </p>
<p begin="00:23:24.180" end="00:23:32.630" horseID="106">by patients and by all this kind of cancer and all this'. I said, good decision.</p>
<p begin="00:23:35.360" end="00:23:44.770" horseID="107">What is the remedy you gave me? I said, I will not tell you the remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:23:47.290" end="00:23:55.808" horseID="108">He used to call me once the day and three times the day 'I have cancer, I have cancer, I have cancer'.</p>
<p begin="00:23:55.880" end="00:24:09.928" horseID="109">Three times the day for two years, he was one of my students. I mean you cannot cure your student, it's very bad.</p>
<p begin="00:24:17.600" end="00:24:30.308" horseID="110">Finally I told him the remedy but for years now he has not telephoned once. Maybe he took the remedy himself, I don't know.</p>
<p begin="00:24:30.380" end="00:24:43.788" horseID="111">But to give you the idea of the intensity that there is no logic behind, there is no logic behind that fear. There is no control.</p>
<p begin="00:24:43.860" end="00:24:52.728" horseID="112">Of course, these are extreme cases, you may find less extreme but still you see the fear of cancer. </p>
<p begin="00:24:52.800" end="00:25:03.378" horseID="113">You see the activity on the nervous system and the muscular then immediately you put these two things together.</p>
<p begin="00:25:06.370" end="00:25:10.808" horseID="114">Now I try to describe in a word what I told you.  </p>
<p begin="00:25:12.130" end="00:25:21.340" horseID="115">Their anxiety is such that they may drive you crazy with their complains that they may end up with cancer. </p>
<p begin="00:25:23.090" end="00:25:42.008" horseID="116">I've seen another case, a woman is pressing<br/> her breast trying to find the cancer. She is sure she has cancer.  </p>
<p begin="00:25:50.680" end="00:26:00.288" horseID="117">She presses and presses, one time maybe a little knob will appear after so many times pressing. </p>
<p begin="00:26:00.360" end="00:26:09.268" horseID="118">I mean if you press 20 times the day, most probably an inflammation will start and you will see something. </p>
<p begin="00:26:10.860" end="00:26:15.720" horseID="119">That is the kind of fear.</p>
<p begin="00:26:24.520" end="00:26:44.218" horseID="120"> And there is a connection in their understanding between death and graves, funerals, grave yards </p>
<p begin="00:26:45.640" end="00:26:53.720" horseID="121">always connecting everything with death from cancer.</p>
<p begin="00:26:54.490" end="00:27:16.918" horseID="122">There is an element of....I will try to explain: how a person who looks something and says, now this looks to me like a grave. </p>
<p begin="00:27:16.990" end="00:27:30.408" horseID="123">The mind goes to the grave, she goes to bed and says, this looks like my grave I don't want to lie down here.</p>
<p begin="00:27:34.720" end="00:27:41.230" horseID="124">You laugh but the suffering is tremendous.</p>
<p begin="00:27:52.750" end="00:28:06.888" horseID="125">Better during sleep, in this nervous activity it is better when they lie down, the chorea stops when they sleep.</p>
<p begin="00:28:06.960" end="00:28:24.430" horseID="126">They will have no problems and worse<br/> from coition. Sexual intercourse.</p>
<p begin="00:28:44.590" end="00:28:50.488" horseID="127">If they have sexual intercourse, <br/>afterwards they feel very bad.</p>
<p begin="00:28:51.520" end="00:29:03.528" horseID="128">So fear of cancer and worse after coition in general, this combination gives again Agaricus.</p>
<p begin="00:29:03.600" end="00:29:12.358" horseID="129">Pains that exhibited diagonally is another symptom that you have to remember. </p>
<p begin="00:29:12.430" end="00:29:23.900" horseID="130">Left shoulder, right hip, left elbow, right knee.</p>
<p begin="00:29:41.400" end="00:29:56.368" horseID="131">Children after chorea which develops after you punish a child. The child develops chorea, Agaricus.</p>
<p begin="00:30:47.100" end="00:31:03.778" horseID="132">What impresses us in this remedy? Involuntary or unnoticed stool on passing flatus, resulting in shame and irritability.</p>
<p begin="00:31:07.080" end="00:31:15.208" horseID="133">Little ones will drop all over the carpet, yellow drops of mucus and stool, you can imagine.</p>
<p begin="00:31:20.260" end="00:31:27.040" horseID="134">Dissatisfied and angry with themselves especially when the process of digestion starts.</p>
<p begin="00:31:34.190" end="00:31:52.400" horseID="135">Alternating states, hypochondriac, consider life a burden in the morning and in the evening they are content and happy.</p>
<p begin="00:31:58.280" end="00:32:10.208" horseID="136">What you have to remember here is that <br/>they suffer after eating, when the process of digestion starts</p>
<p begin="00:32:10.280" end="00:32:16.360" horseID="137">that means ½ an hour, 1 hour after <br/>eating they start suffering.</p>
<p begin="00:32:18.090" end="00:32:29.850" horseID="138"> If they have this symptom plus involuntary stool on passing flatus, the remedy is Aloe.</p>
<p begin="00:32:31.380" end="00:32:57.888" horseID="139">They feel very bad because they cannot retain, they don't have to pass real stool, it is some kind of liquid </p>
<p begin="00:32:57.960" end="00:33:06.050" horseID="140">or a little bit of liquid which makes the rectum always dirty.</p>
<p begin="00:33:26.040" end="00:33:40.160" horseID="141">Diarrhea, 5-6 a.m. is a characteristic of <br/>Aloe and also of another remedy, Sulphur. </p>
<p begin="00:33:54.050" end="00:34:01.408" horseID="142"> But these people they suffer this time, during<br/> the process of digestion and they have this </p>
<p begin="00:34:01.480" end="00:34:10.900" horseID="143">on passing flatus, they have involuntary stool.</p>
<p begin="00:34:29.680" end="00:34:50.928" horseID="144">They suffer usually with hemorrhoids which come out and they look like a bunch of grapes, ameliorated by cold bathing.</p>
<p begin="00:35:03.740" end="00:35:15.768" horseID="145">Cold applications in general ameliorate<br/> this remedy, whatever it might be.</p>
<p begin="00:35:15.840" end="00:35:25.448" horseID="146"> It might be a headache ameliorated by cold application. Hemorrhoids, ameliorated by cold application.</p>
<p begin="00:35:25.520" end="00:35:30.360" horseID="147">It might be a pain in the abdomen, ameliorated by cold application.</p>
<p begin="00:35:40.840" end="00:35:48.590" horseID="148">Which is another remedy which <br/>is ameliorated by cold application?</p>
<p begin="00:35:56.400" end="00:36:12.160" horseID="149">Ledum and Pulsatilla. Pulsatilla is a warm remedy. This is not a warm remedy; it doesn't have to be a warm remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:36:13.040" end="00:36:31.490" horseID="150">It has to have digestive problems with hemorrhoids and amelioration with cold applications.</p>
<p begin="00:36:55.420" end="00:37:02.320" horseID="151">Headache across forehead <br/>ameliorated by cold application.  </p>
<p begin="00:37:15.840" end="00:37:27.080" horseID="152"> Lumbago alternating with headache and hemorrhoids is typical, esp. lumbago alternating with hemorrhoids.</p>
<p begin="00:37:30.280" end="00:37:39.018" horseID="153">They have pain here and then the pain <br/>goes away and hemorrhoids appear </p>
<p begin="00:37:39.090" end="00:37:49.320" horseID="154">and the hemorrhoids go back and<br/> the pain in the waist comes back.</p>
<p begin="00:37:53.730" end="00:38:05.328" horseID="155">Mental symptoms of Aloe are not pronounced as to differentiate. They are people who are weary </p>
<p begin="00:38:05.400" end="00:38:19.808" horseID="156">people who do not have the joy of life who are anxious about their healthy with a hypochondriac tendency.</p>
<p begin="00:38:19.880" end="00:38:31.288" horseID="157">All the time dealing with their stool, with their digestion, I do not have good digestion, you know this type.</p>
<p begin="00:38:33.080" end="00:38:44.768" horseID="158">What I want on that state is to remember a few things. If we go expand, expand, expand, in the end</p>
<p begin="00:38:44.840" end="00:38:53.518" horseID="159">you will not remember anything. What I want you is to grasp characteristics of each remedy</p>
<p begin="00:38:53.590" end="00:38:58.408" horseID="160"> so your mind will go there when you see these characteristics.</p>
<p begin="00:38:58.480" end="00:39:05.920" horseID="161">What I told you about hypochondriacal state is too many remedies which have that. And you will not be able to differentiate.</p>
<p begin="00:39:06.000" end="00:39:16.568" horseID="162">But if you see that, your mind immediately will differentiate. So I don't want you to have a lot of information at this stage.</p>
<p begin="00:39:16.640" end="00:39:30.528" horseID="163">If you learn that and make it your own, then you can add and build the different other symptomatology.</p>
<p begin="00:39:30.600" end="00:39:42.498" horseID="164">I give you the basis on which you can stand quite well and be able to treat most of your cases, not all.</p>
<p begin="00:39:42.570" end="00:39:47.760" horseID="165">Nobody can treat all of the cases in any case.</p>
<p begin="00:40:11.900" end="00:40:21.748" horseID="166">What makes you impressed? Slowness of body and mind, severe constipation and inactivity of rectum.</p>
<p begin="00:40:29.250" end="00:40:38.660" horseID="167">Slowness of body and mind.</p>
<p begin="00:40:42.070" end="00:40:51.898" horseID="168">Progressing into a state of paralysis, paralysis of rectum, of extremities paralysis of mind, of emotions, answers slowly,</p>
<p begin="00:40:51.970" end="00:40:56.308" horseID="169">  time passes very slowly for them confusion of mind, cannot express their feelings. </p>
<p begin="00:41:00.290" end="00:41:09.360" horseID="170"> This is a whole syndrome where you get a person who cannot express their symptoms.</p>
<p begin="00:41:10.360" end="00:41:24.648" horseID="171">They come in front of you and then they stay almost without being able to express how they feel.</p>
<p begin="00:41:24.720" end="00:41:35.728" horseID="172">You say, how do you feel? And you see they make an effort to think how they feel. It is very difficult for them</p>
<p begin="00:41:35.800" end="00:41:57.068" horseID="173">the mind is very slow to express, to bring out. In the same way that the rectum is unable to bring out </p>
<p begin="00:41:57.140" end="00:42:04.068" horseID="174">to express, it is a feeling of paralysis.</p>
<p begin="00:42:06.490" end="00:42:21.198" horseID="175">Paralyzed feeling which ends up in actual paralysis sometimes. Alumina is indicated in Multiple Sclerosis</p>
<p begin="00:42:21.270" end="00:42:31.988" horseID="176"> is indicated in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Myopathy. </p>
<p begin="00:42:33.400" end="00:42:39.328" horseID="177">Severe constipation, inactivity of rectum<br/>even soft stool requires great straining.</p>
<p begin="00:42:39.400" end="00:42:46.320" horseID="178">    <br/>This is a very characteristic thing. </p>
<p begin="00:42:50.320" end="00:43:01.648" horseID="179"> No urging for many days, has to aid with the fingers. This is characteristic, the constipation is</p>
<p begin="00:43:01.720" end="00:43:09.428" horseID="180">so severe that they have to help with their fingers to bring out the stool.</p>
<p begin="00:43:15.480" end="00:43:27.328" horseID="181">In Alumina they come to you for severe constipation. You say, what do you have? Severe constipation. </p>
<p begin="00:43:27.400" end="00:43:31.038" horseID="182"> Then you ask, what else?</p>
<p begin="00:43:31.110" end="00:43:42.288" horseID="183">How do you feel? And then you see immediately that their mind is slow, not comprehending, you feel that </p>
<p begin="00:43:42.360" end="00:43:51.880" horseID="184">they don't understand the question. They stay and stare at you. They wait before answering. </p>
<p begin="00:43:56.720" end="00:44:07.398" horseID="185">And then this can go very far as to appear to have a mental case.</p>
<p begin="00:44:07.470" end="00:44:29.178" horseID="186">Mentally you feel they are retarded, very slow. They cannot answer, in answering they say 'am I speaking?'</p>
<p begin="00:44:29.250" end="00:44:41.148" horseID="187">Can you imagine? You have to use your imagination with Materia Medica you have to use a lot your imagination.</p>
<p begin="00:44:41.220" end="00:44:57.088" horseID="188">How a person feels, that cannot think, cannot answer; tries very hard to express an idea, to bring out the stool </p>
<p begin="00:44:57.160" end="00:45:14.808" horseID="189">and then the idea comes and says who is talking now? Am I talking, they hear their voice and they don't realize that they are talking.</p>
<p begin="00:45:16.970" end="00:45:30.208" horseID="190">It's very difficult to perceive these things. You have to be really sensitive and imagine how a person can feel.</p>
<p begin="00:45:30.280" end="00:45:47.760" horseID="191">They feel like they are going crazy but it's not the fear of insanity which prevails but if the fear of insanity prevails</p>
<p begin="00:45:48.100" end="00:46:00.008" horseID="192">then the remedy is different. What prevails is the difficulty to express, to bring out; that prevails. </p>
<p begin="00:46:00.080" end="00:46:07.698" horseID="193">That is the whole issue with Alumina.</p>
<p begin="00:46:10.920" end="00:46:19.878" horseID="194">They have of course fear of insanity because in that state in which they are, it's natural to think that I'm going crazy.</p>
<p begin="00:46:19.950" end="00:46:30.838" horseID="195">But they are not bothered by it, the bothering is the difficulty to think, the slowness of mind.</p>
<p begin="00:46:30.910" end="00:46:40.548" horseID="196">Everything seems unreal, fear of knives, impulse to kill themselves when they see a knife of blood.</p>
<p begin="00:46:42.350" end="00:46:58.130" horseID="197">When they see a knife the idea comes, 'shall I, oh I'm afraid I will take it and kill myself or kill somebody'.</p>
<p begin="00:47:00.860" end="00:47:06.288" horseID="198">There is another remedy which has that, which one?</p>
<p begin="00:47:06.360" end="00:47:22.228" horseID="199">Mercury has that but Mercury shall it have constipation? No. Mercury will have salivation for instance. </p>
<p begin="00:47:22.300" end="00:47:26.288" horseID="200">The combination is different.</p>
<p begin="00:47:27.680" end="00:47:36.978" horseID="201">Here, we have constipation with the fear of knife and severe constipation, Alumina.</p>
<p begin="00:47:47.160" end="00:47:53.588" horseID="202">Dryness of mucus membranes and skin, itching without eruption.</p>
<p begin="00:48:17.980" end="00:48:34.678" horseID="203">It's a dry person and see the peculiarity. Dryness of skin, dryness of mucus membranes, yet desire for dry food.</p>
<p begin="00:48:38.570" end="00:48:49.248" horseID="204">You will think that the person who has such dryness, would require a lot of liquid food. </p>
<p begin="00:48:49.320" end="00:48:53.748" horseID="205">No, they don't like it, they like the dry food.</p>
<p begin="00:49:04.810" end="00:49:16.518" horseID="206">They have an aversion and aggravation from potatoes. Itching without eruption also is a characteristic.</p>
<p begin="00:49:16.590" end="00:49:24.708" horseID="207">Dryness of skin, itching without eruption, constipation, Alumina.</p>
<p begin="00:49:24.780" end="00:49:43.300" horseID="208">Itching without eruption, dryness if skin with difficulty to express ideas,  the state of slowness of the mind, Alumina.</p>
<p begin="00:49:52.510" end="00:50:02.760" horseID="209">And of course paralysis, M.S., Alzheimer. </p>
<p begin="00:50:02.832" end="00:50:15.300" horseID="210">I mean you can understand we are describing a state of mind which is the beginning of Alzheimer's disease. </p>
<p begin="00:50:26.160" end="00:50:35.808" horseID="211"> The idea is to pinpoint the pathology of each remedy. Where is the pathology? </p>
<p begin="00:50:35.880" end="00:50:41.528" horseID="212"> Around the mind <br/>and what turn this pathology takes?</p>
<p begin="00:50:42.710" end="00:50:50.188" horseID="213">Around the digestive system and what<br/> modalities around the digestive system?</p>
<p begin="00:50:50.260" end="00:51:04.110" horseID="214">Within heart and what modalities? There are remedies which affect the heart, the guts, the stomach, the mind.</p>
<p begin="00:51:04.830" end="00:51:16.160" horseID="215">So what I'm trying to give you here is the primary seat of action of each remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:51:16.370" end="00:51:27.080" horseID="216">Mucus membranes, skin, dry mucus membranes, dryness of skin, dryness of mind.</p>
<p begin="00:51:29.070" end="00:51:39.800" horseID="217">You see if the mind is liquid then it runs out. Which is the remedy who has liquid mind?</p>
<p begin="00:51:40.570" end="00:51:52.078" horseID="218">Lachesis, loquacity they cannot stop. The ideas come fast, like Coffea, Lachesis, Nux-vomica. </p>
<p begin="00:51:52.150" end="00:51:57.400" horseID="219">Now this, it's the opposite, dryness.</p>
<p begin="00:52:02.240" end="00:52:27.858" horseID="220">When somebody is dehydrated, tired in mind and body, they will go like that and you wait, they try to give you an answer.</p>
<p begin="00:52:27.930" end="00:52:37.250" horseID="221">The same idea is with the stool they try<br/> very hard, nothing comes out.</p>
<p begin="00:52:37.322" end="00:52:43.600" horseID="222">They have energy. It's not a matter of great tiredness. </p>
<p begin="00:52:52.270" end="00:53:04.948" horseID="223">I don't intensify the idea of tiredness because all the remedies can be tired, all. But there are some remedies </p>
<p begin="00:53:05.020" end="00:53:12.848" horseID="224">on which we shall focus on the idea of tiredness. Alumina is not one of them. </p>
<p begin="00:53:12.920" end="00:53:27.640" horseID="225">Alumina has this dryness and difficulty of expulsion, of ideas, of stool etc. </p>
<p begin="00:53:33.740" end="00:53:49.140" horseID="226">I'm going to give you some cases which you will study and then, you can use your Repertory of course to get some ideas.</p>
<p begin="00:53:49.160" end="00:54:03.000" horseID="227">What mostly I want is if you can spot the main remedy that you would give first because of this information.</p>
<p begin="00:54:03.880" end="00:54:14.588" horseID="228">I want you to use this information and find out and you will tell me, in this case I would prescribe first that remedy.</p>
<p begin="00:54:14.660" end="00:54:21.668" horseID="229">Because these cases I'm going to give you are not typical of one remedy. </p>
<p begin="00:54:23.080" end="00:54:29.888" horseID="230">Usually they contain the possibility<br/> of 2, 3 or 4 remedies.</p>
<p begin="00:54:29.960" end="00:54:40.280" horseID="231">Which one you would give first and for what reason is very important, so we synchronize our thinking.</p>
<p begin="00:54:41.810" end="00:54:57.998" horseID="232">In order to solve such cases you need to remember this. That's why you will have to study today these remedies</p>
<p begin="00:54:59.760" end="00:55:05.520" horseID="233">read them again and again because on Wednesday when I will give you the cases</p>
<p begin="00:55:05.730" end="00:55:12.920" horseID="234">I will give you enough remedies, <br/>maybe one of them will be.</p>
</div>
</body>
</tt>