We have fear of death and panic, tremendous panic.
And a sense that death is coming. It's imminent. In the books it says that predicts the time of death.
This is in acute conditions. In chronic conditions you will not find that he will say, 10 o'clock I will die, we have another situation.
All the symptoms will not occur in one individual. With some individuals we shall have fear of death
vertigo, fear of fainting and intense tachycardia.
With other people we may have trembling, perspiration, urinating numbness, such as numbness of the half of the face.
Another group of patients may experience a
kind of psychogenic dyspnea like Lobelia.
And they need to take a deep breath.
Or we may have flushes of heat on the
whole body or especially in the head.
There is general aggravation time and
this is most frequently in the night.
Especially from midnight to 4 a.m.
And generalyl we have an aggravation from heat.
But sometimes aggravation from cold as well. 80% of the times is heat and 20% is cold.
And the crisis can be precipitated by heat, when they are heated up in a very warm room.
Now you see this individual with intense fear pounding tachycardia etc.
When the crisis come then that is the violence, the intensity, then there is the panic, there is the fear, all these are very intense.
When you converse to him, when he describes to you, he will not describe it with this intensity but he will say
is 'I'm going to die', he has tremendous fear of death.
So these patients are very sympathetic as we said. They need company and also they express their feelings easily.
This sympathetic element leads to a state of anxiety about others. They are concerned very much about
their relatives, their friends and they react out of proportion to something that is happening to a friend or relative.
What happened to you? Oh my God. The reaction is out of proportion to an event.
Because of that element they do not like to hear bad news. They have ailments from bad news.
You see there are certain rubrics in the Repertory that we do not see them in the patient, 'ailments from bad news'
we do not see that. You have to see the whole person.
I mean a crisis comes so many times, intense, the fear of death, perspiration, tachycardia etc.
Then they go out, they are sympathetic. It's the whole picture that will make a person Aconite.
Anxiety about other people. You have anxiety about others? Yes. You see it's an information which is useless.
What we're interested is to get the personality, the essence. Is that Aconite case?
And that is why we give the Materia Medica in this way, to make it alive. He says he is anxious about health, but he has not. Can't you see? He does not care.
In Greece for instance, the doctor asks 'are you sympathetic?'.' Yes very sympathetic'. Underlined 3 times.
All Greeks are sympathetic. Ok, this is not a symptom because it is a quality that everybody has and feels....
Sympathetic is a symptom when the person is really suffering because of the suffering of the others.
And he cannot control himself.
The sympathetic is you want to put is as a symptom has to be really suffering because of others and cannot help it.
I mean if a woman has a child, she is always sympathetic but a Phosphorus woman or the Aconite woman or the Sulphur woman will react completely different.
The Aconite in the Repertory says 'anxiety about others'. In Aconite we have an eruption and he says 'what happened, oh my God, what shall we do?'. It's an eruption and the anxiety about other is intense.
The Phosphorus has completely different. The Phos will act if everything is ok. He shows all the affection, all the concern, he is interested about you.
The Sulphur will not show it, the anxiety. The Sulphur will say, the child is late. It's usually coming at 12-1. They stay awake, they cannot sleep until they hear the door.
12.20 maybe he had an accident? And they get up from bed and they walk up and down, going in the veranda, watching the child coming.
Once they see the child coming, they will go back in sleep.
The Phosphorus do not take this so much imagination. When he faces something which is very bad then he becomes very sympathetic.
Each remedy shows the sympathy in a different way, the Arsenicum also has anxiety about others. Anxiety about others in Arsenicum is inner anxiety.
Whom others? Those that he is connected and he feels a kind of security having them, the father, the mother, the brother. What happened to my brother?
Because he holds on him and so he wants him to be well in order to help him in case he's not feeling well etc.
It is an anxiety on a reflex where he wants the support from others and he wants others to be well to support him.
It's a different thing in attitude, in personality. Anxiety about others it's underlined 3 times.
It doesn't say anything. It is not type of anxiety, is it the Phos anxiety, the Ars, the Sulph, the Calc anxiety?
So this we are interested to understand.
In the acute state we said the fear of death, that he is going to die now within half an hour, 1,2 hours whatever it is, but now.
In chronic states the fear of death that is imminent it appears to be within a span of time, let's say in 3, 5 months, in 1 year 'the way I am, my heart is going to give in and I'm going to die'.
They are actually sure that they are going to die and they make preparation.
They make their will and then they tell you that through the symptoms 'I'm absolutely sure that very soon my heart will stop and I'll die. Therefore I have to arrange everything that after my death everything will be taken care'.
He is a prudent man he's just thinking about his death etc. Here we take into consideration everything which is pathological. It's not natural, it's not healthy for one to think that in 3, 5 months I'm going to die.
This is pathology and we take it in consideration.
Except from the fear of death, Aconite produces  also claustrophobia, fear of dark and especially fear of crowds.
Many times he will not sleep without the light on.
And he will not go through tunels if he knows that the lift is going through tunel he prefers to get up and go 5 storeys walking but will not go into the lift.
Also you will not get an Aconite going into demonstration, when too many people are in the streets.
And they have also a fear of accident.
So much so that many times an Aconite will
not drive by himself. In order to drive they
need somebody else to accompany them.
Also Aconite has many times fear of disease and has to be added, it's not in the Repertory.
And also fear that his heart will stop beating.
It appears that those fears are gone and there is the least provocation, and then they come up.
In some cases there is an aggravation which reminds you of Lachesis.
And that is when they go to bed and they sleep for 10-15 minutes, then suddenly they wake up with tremendous fears, they jump up.
Now the difference is that with Lachesis the fear is not a fear of death; it's a fear of suffocation when they're falling asleep. By the time they go into sleep.
Aconite is a fear of death, is a panic which comes 10-15 minutes after sleep. You see the difference? It looks alike, you may confuse it but it's not the same.
It is 10-15 minutes, that means the person has gone into sleep and the moment that the logic mind has gone away, the fears that have been staying inside, they start suddenly.
And in such an intensity  that the person jumps up and he feels he is going to die.
Also there is an aggravation from heat. He may explain it that he is getting warm in bed, that heat aggravates him and brings the crisis of the panic.
Sometimes these fears instead of making the person to wake up, they appear as nightmares.  So they go through tremendous nightmares.
And another fear that can come about is a kind of "mora". You know what is a "mora"? No. I will describe to you.
When they try to wake up or they wake up without being able to move their limb. What's called this?
This can happen with Aconite. They wake up, they cannot move their limbs and they go into a state of fright and panic.
Anyhow what we observe in general is that
the fears that have been engrafted in the subconscious mind, they surface very easily
the Aconite people and they bring out these states of panic and fear.
The Aconite is also the number 1 remedy that is affected by earthquakes.
And it is an analogous state inside, like an earthquake happening. Inside the circulatory system is in such a turmoil as if an earthquake is taking place inside.
Sometimes the feeling of the earthquake inside is so strong that they wake up and they feel that
the ceiling may fall on them. They have the impression that there is actually an earthquake.
It's a tremendous commotion inside. These states are going on and on. I have seen a state of Aconite which is terrifying.
One of the time of aggravations of Aconite is this time, the twilight. And I've seen a case of Aconite in a state of agony coming every night when the twilight comes, where the person will go into tremendous fear and will sob in a such a way as barking.
Terrified, full of fear, not being able to express anything at the moment.
It was terrible experience once that a doctor had. He took the patient inside and while he was in the consulting room, it was about this time
the person started the interview and then suddenly that syndrome came and it was so intense that the doctor was terrified.
He said, 'come in I cannot handle the situation'. With this syndrome they would call usually the ambulance and give her injection, valium.
It was terrible, the fear.
With one dose of Aconite not only that crisis went away. It went away the whole. I mean this woman she was getting very frequently this attack.
So Aconite states can start from a million places like tachycardias, numbness etc and then we see the fear, fear of death, panic tremendous panic and then these terrific fears
which come indescribable, they cannot say what happens to them and most probably they feel the death is imminent. That they are going to die and they take them to the ambulance.
The claustrophobia also. I remember another case where the claustrophobia was so much
that if in the house they were 6 or 7 persons,
she would feel claustrophobic.
And she could not stay in that room. She had to leave. Therefore they say, I cannot invite my relatives in the house. With 6-7 people she felt claustrophobia.
So you understand the intensity of the claustrophobia.
Also there is a fear of suffocation, esp. in warm colsed places.
And sometimes you will get a fear of open spaces. It's the opposite, exactly.
They cannot drive into the autobahn. They can drive in the city, they can go anywhere. As soon as they come in the autobahn where the space is open, they go into a panic, into a fear. They paralyze, they cannot drive anymore.
They cannot say why this is happening. They go into panic and they cannot explain why.
I'll give you some characteristics of the different systems. In the head:
In general we can say there are tormenting sensations in the head.
Tormenting headaches and vertigo. There is contraction often and fullness often accompanied by great heat.
There is a very characteristic sensation of voiding inside the head.
There are headaches which can come about after fright or after exposure to cold, dry winds. And this with cold, dry winds is characteristic of Aconite.
The headaches are located mostly in occiput and forehead. One sided numbness of the face, as we said before
These headaches usually are accompanied by some kind of fear, fear of death.
Most probably Aconite will be indicated in a lot of cases with this tremendous fear, this upheaval.
The fever is very high, the headache is very strong.
When we have severe cases of encephalitis and encephalomyelitis.
In the beginning of such cases we do not have frequently the possibility to treat such cases unfortunately but from my experience
I've seen that Homeopathy definitely can work and ensure better. We do not have the statistics yet that it can work better than antibiotics.
I have seen some dramatic cases in children recovered.
-Have you seen meningitis with good results?
-Yes.
The problem we cannot see many cases to have such statistics. We see cases of the child of my sister or the doctors who are in the center, their children.
The children are connected very much with Homeopathy and their parents know very well about Homeopathy.
This is the only time where you can take such responsibility. Also I don't suggest to take such cases especially when we are not medical doctors.
You don't know what to do if the remedy has failed. You may have a difficult situation.
It's also indicated in conjuctivitis esp. when this inflammation of the conjuctiva has come about after the exposure to cold wind.
An inflammation becomes soon cured.
The eyes become very sensitive to light and there is great photophobia.  To sunlight and artificial light.
Also Aconite may be used sudden loss of sight after fright. If you have sudden loss of sight after fright you can be thinking of Aconite.
In the stomach you can have gastritis inflammation which will come about if somebody is over heated and drinks very cold water suddenly.
Then comes this burning in the stomach and the gastritis starts. Then Aconite is one of the remedies you have to think.
Also they have great thirst. Especially on waking in the morning.
In the abdomen you will find characteristic pains in the abdomen which extend to the chest.
Also retention of urine after a fright.
The Aconite is very much used in case of a newborn because of the fright coming out to the world. If the urine is retained then Aconite is one of the main remedies.
Sudden bronchitis.
Sudden inflammation of the ovaries in cases of suppressed menses.
But all these symptoms are very well described in Kent and this is one of the remedies he gave in all these details.
But I would say we are using Aconite say 80% in chronic cases and 20% in acute.
We have hundreds of cases treated with Aconite for 5 years, 10 years, chronic cases. Especially of this type I described to you.
Before we knew this remedy we would give Lachesis, Kali arsenicum, Belladonna, all other kinds of remedies that were not acting.
And when we came out with the Aconite picture, then we had a great friend in all situations.
All these symptoms the tachycardia, the vertigo, the headaches, the fainting they are not functional, pathological.
-I had a case where this lady she would wake up at night paralyzed. She couldn't move, she couldn't touch her husband to wake him up.
-Waking up in the fright in the night?
-Yes and also waking up in the morning just being paralyzed. She couldn't move.
-You mean from "mora", what I said that they can not move their limbs?
-Yes.
- Phosporus, Lachesis, Sulphur.
-In all these cases the crisis is coming and going? They are not constant.
-Yes they are not constant situations. They come and go, every 2, 3 days, every day, once, twice the day.
They are not regular crisis but when they come they are intolerable.
This is the idea that the fright took place. That fright they have it in the subconscious but not too deep and with the least provocation, with some sleep, it comes up.
With some thought that something may happen, it comes up. With too much heat, the crisis comes up. Going into a lift.
They are going to the road, they are driving the car, they are in a traffic jam, suddenly they look behind, they get into a panic.
-Can they suppress the crisis?
-They cannot, no. You mean suppress it by logic? No.
It is too strong, they cannot. They say 'yes I know but when the crisis comes they say, it's impossible to control myself'.
-Do you find that the fear of panic is always a fear of death?
-Most of them they will describe it as fear of death, most of them.
It's not only the fear of death because in some cases you will get the trembling, the fainting, you will get the perspiration. The fear of death starts and goes on in different stages.
-In Kent's Repertory there is a rubric which says effects of shock or shock in the mentals. Presumably you would put Aconite into that.
-Yes sure.
-What other remedies would you put in?
-I would put Opium, Gelsemium, Stramonium.
-Arnica?
-When we say shock we don't mean physical.
-You talk about mental?
-Yes.
-A crisis.
-When I give you this idea it's not that I'm covering the whole, because all remedies can have mentals. There is no remedy that can be left out of this.  I'm giving you the most prominent.
-I cannot say for what reason a person has a shock. Because he was too sympathetic to the other? Because he felt suddenly that something of this type may happen to him.
Because of different reason? Here the fright is not just a fright. The fright involves most of the time the possibility of death.
This is what I found out. I will suffocate now and die, or someone came and put a pistol etc. This idea is behind the Aconite causative factor.
In Homeopathy I found out that there is no, always. The word 'always', you can forget it. Most of the times, yes but always?
Because you will get sometimes the Calcarea carbonica who is warm, the Pulsatilla who is cold, the Arsenicum who is also warm, you will getthe Nux vomica warm, the Argentum Nitricum who is cold.
You will say but Argentum is suffering from heat, this person is suffering from cold.  How do you get at it? Because the whole picture indicates, it's strong for Argentum nitricum.
Therefore you have to ignore the fact that this Argentum nitricum is worse cold.
Another thing that you have to remember is that Arsenicum is very cold in his body but hot in his head, ok?
Sometimes the heat is there and they say, I'm suffering from heat where the headache is quite warm.
I remember in a hospital in Calcutta, where we had weekends sitting there for watch and the nurse came down, I was with another doctor.
The patient had tremendous pains, he was shouting. So rushed upstairs and we found that patient. in India, very warm and that patient was covered with four blankets
She was holding the steels of the bed and she was screaming a word 'jolti' (water). And then she was on her top with a fan and fanning her head.
When we went inside we saw this patient crying for water, and we give water and she was covered in the body where she was trembling like that and the face was absolutely hot.
We saw the whole picture of Arsenicum. You give Arsenicum and in 5 minutes the kidney colic was gone. You are not interested whether the colic was in gall bladder or kidneys. The picture is so intense and so clear.
I was asking what is calling? Because I didn't know the words. The impression is to warm the person. When I saw the blankets, 4,5 blankets.
There was a case actually by an American doctor who wrote the case and said, this person was warm and I gave Arsenicum and it acted.
And he was very angry by the teachers teaching that Arsenicum is a cold remedy.
Anyhow this is not a case where we will say definitely is an Arsenicum case, we still have to see whether it was Arsenicum and secondly
whether it was only the head that was warm and not the body but it is a fact that in Homeopathy
I found there is not "always".