Here in Aconitum you see, fear of death and feeling that death is imminent or near.
Death is near, any case whether it is a colitis, an acute condition, a chronic condition of any kind, once he has the fear of death
and that death is very near: I'm going to die tomorrow, in 3 days, in 3 months, once there is this element
you will have to think of Aconite, agonizing fear of death. The fear of death brings agony.
You will ask a case, do you have fear of death, they will say, yes I am afraid of death.
If they say it like this, this is not an Aconite condition.
If the answer is 'yes my god I'm terrified!' then your mind should go to Aconite.
If on the top they will say, 'that not only I'm afraid but I'm afraid that I will die soon', this is more of an Aconite condition.
Never mind what is the problem.
Panic states, intense panic which has sudden, violent palpitations, red face, one sided numbness,
faint feeling, perspiration, trembling, vertigo, dyspnoea, fear of death. All these symptoms are symptoms which arise from
a shock that a person has had while his life was threatened, that means he was closed in a lift.
And he felt I'm going to die now, I suffocate, I am here enclosed. He found himself in an accident, threatened by a pistol.
That state which is created in such a situation, if it repeats itself again and again and again or if that state
that you can imagine how the person behaves under the threat of death if that state appears in any condition
that is an Aconite state.
- Could I ask you if this fear of death has to be for themselves or can also cover a fear of death , for instance saying,
I don't wish to die because I don't know what will happen to my children, of if I die I don't know
how my parents will handle that or is it an individual fear of death.
-No, the shock has to threaten his own life.
And it says, acute symptoms arising from exposure to dry, cold winds. Another causative factor is dry, cold winds bring about
violent palpitation, red face, one sided numbness, faint feeling, perspiration,  fear of death.
-Can this state be caused by watching a threatening situation?
-Threatening, yes. This can be caused by watching a threatening situation, by watching some scene under which
the life is threatened, by a robbery, this situation can arise. But the idea is that it does not have to arise always from that cause.
I'm just giving you the idea to show you how the person feels, I'm going to die.
When somebody puts a pistol, in 2-3 minutes you are dead, right? It's finished, my life is gone.
You don't have to have the real fact that this person was threatened. What you have to have is the result of such action.
How a person feels when somebody puts a pistol.
It may never happen to this person but the idea is the same, the symptomatology of Aconitum is the same.
I'm going to die, I'm going to die! I'm dying!
Palpitation, restlessness. This panic states, nobody can live constantly in such panic states,
It is like a wave. It comes and then it goes
and then the person is calm.
There is no problem, so panic states that come to great intensity and then they go. But when they come
these people need immediately attention. They are the people who will run to the emergency hospitals
to save their life because they feel
that their life is really in danger.
In more chronic states you will see the same idea. If somebody tells you 'well I'm tormented by fear of dying
and I'm married and I have 2 children and I think I'm going to die and leave these children orphans'.
If somebody tells you something like this, immediately your mind goes to... because the question that you will have to
ask immediately is: do you feel that you are going to die soon?. 'Yes!'. This is Aconite.
'Yes, I think I'm going to die quite soon'. 'When?'. 'I don't know but quite soon'.
This is an Aconite. It does not matter what it is, you see?
And there are certain specific fears which are elevators, tunnels, fear that their heart will stop, fear of going in the airplane,
fear of earthquake, fear in a crowd, in narrow places all these situations are situations where a person feels his life is in danger.
If there is an earthquake here, you will immediately feel fear, right?
If any of you stays with this fear, in order to counteract this fear, Aconite is a specific remedy.
Ah, I'm going to die, again it comes, again it comes, Aconite.
Intense nervous restlessness, tossing
about intense thirst for cold water.
This anxiety state which causes restlessness, the person wants to move all the time, up and down.
You don't need to remember anything else for Aconite but if you go to the Repertory you will see
3.000 symptoms of course but you have to have this picture to prescribe Aconite. This is where your mind says,
when you see the patient, is this a case of Aconite? Immediately when you have that picture your mind will go to Aconite.
That reminds me something, Georges was taking about. What? Aconite. You know it comes like this.
Closed in an elevator, ah I can't go in an elevator. Why? I feel I suffocate, I feel I will die. Possible Aconite.
Fear of death? Yes. How strong? Strong. Yes. You feel that you're going to die soon? Yes. Aconite.
So learning in this way the Materia Medica it will be very easy to find the remedy.
-Your experience of having prescribed the Aconite in chronic disease, do you see there are people who
would be present these panic states in any pathology?
-In any pathology they can present this picture, this agonizing fear of death with the feeling that death is coming soon.
-But after you prescribed a remedy, let's say in 10M or 50M, and do you see that they're braced up in future
for the pathology or do they still presenting the same thing?
-It doesn't. The fear of death subsides almost immediately and totally.
-For future reference also?
-Yes, for future reference also.
You see you get these chronic cases of Aconite, it's beautiful to see how the whole syndrome
is counteracted and the person for years lives without problem.
The way I write what impresses you here? Two or three things, that's all you have to remember.
What impresses you? Fear of cancer, especially cancer. They are not afraid of fear of brain stroke, of heart disease,
everything is cancer. Everything is overwhelmed in this case with the fear that they have cancer.
The second is twitchings, spasms,
convulsions, chorea. Twitchings.
So if you have fear of cancer and
twichings the remedy is Agaricus.
It doesn't matter what is the pathology,
just two things and the remedy is here.
There is no other remedy that has this combination. The idea is the combination of 2-3 symptoms.
You get the combination correctly,
you get the remedy.
Now of course, you have the main thing which is fear of cancer but this fear of cancer will present to you,
it will be presented as something which the patient is really concerned, about his health.
He will say this, this, that and he will end up with the fear of cancer. And then your mind will go to certain remedies,
one of which is Agaricus.
Next question: do you have twitchings?
What is twitchings? Oh, yes. Where? Here, there. Your case is finished.
You will not believe that this is how I go about finding the remedies. Because I have this knowledge in my head,
I short out the remedy, I say, not this remedy, not that remedy.
Which is the remedy George which has tremendous fear of cancer? 1,2,3,4. Ok, I eliminate quickly.
Now, this person I found out, that they develop this kind of fear, this kind of anxiety.
They are patients with weak character, with weak will, there is no will. There is some kind of weakness
in their character, dependency. They depend
and they depend mainly on the doctor.
Because you do not get immediately the remedy, you don't give immediately Agaricus.
When I started Homeopathy, I did not know Agaricus had that picture and I would prescribe Nitric acid
because it has anxiety about health. And I would prescribe Lyc., Phos., Ars., Kali-ars., Arg-n
and then one day I found out the twitchings
and I said, wait a moment, Agaricus, finish.
In the meantime I had this patient for 2 years.
For 2 years the patient is coming and going, Arg-n. a little better,
Phosphorus a little bit better, not really.
And the fear just to give an example of this kind of fear. I have seen it in a Medical doctor.
He works in the hospital. So in the hospital, he sees a case. He takes this case. This is a cancer of the colon.
The patient relates that I had mucus in the stool with blood etc.
Immediately he thinks that he also has exactly the same symptoms. He would telephone and say, well I just took a case
and I saw a case with cancer and I feel I have the same symptoms. What is the same symptoms?
Mucus in my stool and sometimes I have seen also some blood.
And I said for so many years I treat you, you never told me about mucus. He is sure he has mucus in the stool
and he has blood in the stool and he now found the cancer, he has the cancer of the colon.
One night he came in a panic state. He said, 'I'm getting crazy. I saw another case and this is....'
and then I saw doing this, in that state you
know? His facial (muscles), they were torturing, chorea.
He didn't have the chorea but I saw the activity on the nervous system with the muscles.
It's so terrifying, the fear is overwhelming.
He says, what shall I do? I'm finished,
my life is finished. I'm dying from cancer.
Agaricus CM.
I telephone next day and I said, how are you?
He says 'I don't know after this crisis I had last night, I decided that I should never again be influenced
by patients and by all this kind of cancer and all this'. I said, good decision.
What is the remedy you gave me? I said, I will not tell you the remedy.
He used to call me once the day and three times the day 'I have cancer, I have cancer, I have cancer'.
Three times the day for two years, he was one of my students. I mean you cannot cure your student, it's very bad.
Finally I told him the remedy but for years now he has not telephoned once. Maybe he took the remedy himself, I don't know.
But to give you the idea of the intensity that there is no logic behind, there is no logic behind that fear. There is no control.
Of course, these are extreme cases, you may find less extreme but still you see the fear of cancer.
You see the activity on the nervous system and the muscular then immediately you put these two things together.
Now I try to describe in a word what I told you.
Their anxiety is such that they may drive you crazy with their complains that they may end up with cancer.
I've seen another case, a woman is pressing
her breast trying to find the cancer. She is sure she has cancer.
She presses and presses, one time maybe a little knob will appear after so many times pressing.
I mean if you press 20 times the day, most probably an inflammation will start and you will see something.
That is the kind of fear.
And there is a connection in their understanding between death and graves, funerals, grave yards
always connecting everything with death from cancer.
There is an element of....I will try to explain: how a person who looks something and says, now this looks to me like a grave.
The mind goes to the grave, she goes to bed and says, this looks like my grave I don't want to lie down here.
You laugh but the suffering is tremendous.
Better during sleep, in this nervous activity it is better when they lie down, the chorea stops when they sleep.
They will have no problems and worse
from coition. Sexual intercourse.
If they have sexual intercourse,
afterwards they feel very bad.
So fear of cancer and worse after coition in general, this combination gives again Agaricus.
Pains that exhibited diagonally is another symptom that you have to remember.
Left shoulder, right hip, left elbow, right knee.
Children after chorea which develops after you punish a child. The child develops chorea, Agaricus.
What impresses us in this remedy? Involuntary or unnoticed stool on passing flatus, resulting in shame and irritability.
Little ones will drop all over the carpet, yellow drops of mucus and stool, you can imagine.
Dissatisfied and angry with themselves especially when the process of digestion starts.
Alternating states, hypochondriac, consider life a burden in the morning and in the evening they are content and happy.
What you have to remember here is that
they suffer after eating, when the process of digestion starts
that means 1/2 an hour, 1 hour after
eating they start suffering.
If they have this symptom plus involuntary stool on passing flatus, the remedy is Aloe.
They feel very bad because they cannot retain, they don't have to pass real stool, it is some kind of liquid
or a little bit of liquid which makes the rectum always dirty.
Diarrhea, 5-6 a.m. is a characteristic of
Aloe and also of another remedy, Sulphur.
But these people they suffer this time, during
the process of digestion and they have this
on passing flatus, they have involuntary stool.
They suffer usually with hemorrhoids which come out and they look like a bunch of grapes, ameliorated by cold bathing.
Cold applications in general ameliorate
this remedy, whatever it might be.
It might be a headache ameliorated by cold application. Hemorrhoids, ameliorated by cold application.
It might be a pain in the abdomen, ameliorated by cold application.
Which is another remedy which
is ameliorated by cold application?
Ledum and Pulsatilla. Pulsatilla is a warm remedy. This is not a warm remedy; it doesn't have to be a warm remedy.
It has to have digestive problems with hemorrhoids and amelioration with cold applications.
Headache across forehead
ameliorated by cold application.
Lumbago alternating with headache and hemorrhoids is typical, esp. lumbago alternating with hemorrhoids.
They have pain here and then the pain
goes away and hemorrhoids appear
and the hemorrhoids go back and
the pain in the waist comes back.
Mental symptoms of Aloe are not pronounced as to differentiate. They are people who are weary
people who do not have the joy of life who are anxious about their healthy with a hypochondriac tendency.
All the time dealing with their stool, with their digestion, I do not have good digestion, you know this type.
What I want on that state is to remember a few things. If we go expand, expand, expand, in the end
you will not remember anything. What I want you is to grasp characteristics of each remedy
so your mind will go there when you see these characteristics.
What I told you about hypochondriacal state is too many remedies which have that. And you will not be able to differentiate.
But if you see that, your mind immediately will differentiate. So I don't want you to have a lot of information at this stage.
If you learn that and make it your own, then you can add and build the different other symptomatology.
I give you the basis on which you can stand quite well and be able to treat most of your cases, not all.
Nobody can treat all of the cases in any case.
What makes you impressed? Slowness of body and mind, severe constipation and inactivity of rectum.
Slowness of body and mind.
Progressing into a state of paralysis, paralysis of rectum, of extremities paralysis of mind, of emotions, answers slowly,
time passes very slowly for them confusion of mind, cannot express their feelings.
This is a whole syndrome where you get a person who cannot express their symptoms.
They come in front of you and then they stay almost without being able to express how they feel.
You say, how do you feel? And you see they make an effort to think how they feel. It is very difficult for them
the mind is very slow to express, to bring out. In the same way that the rectum is unable to bring out
to express, it is a feeling of paralysis.
Paralyzed feeling which ends up in actual paralysis sometimes. Alumina is indicated in Multiple Sclerosis
is indicated in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Myopathy.
Severe constipation, inactivity of rectum
even soft stool requires great straining.
This is a very characteristic thing.
No urging for many days, has to aid with the fingers. This is characteristic, the constipation is
so severe that they have to help with their fingers to bring out the stool.
In Alumina they come to you for severe constipation. You say, what do you have? Severe constipation.
Then you ask, what else?
How do you feel? And then you see immediately that their mind is slow, not comprehending, you feel that
they don't understand the question. They stay and stare at you. They wait before answering.
And then this can go very far as to appear to have a mental case.
Mentally you feel they are retarded, very slow. They cannot answer, in answering they say 'am I speaking?'
Can you imagine? You have to use your imagination with Materia Medica you have to use a lot your imagination.
How a person feels, that cannot think, cannot answer; tries very hard to express an idea, to bring out the stool
and then the idea comes and says who is talking now? Am I talking, they hear their voice and they don't realize that they are talking.
It's very difficult to perceive these things. You have to be really sensitive and imagine how a person can feel.
They feel like they are going crazy but it's not the fear of insanity which prevails but if the fear of insanity prevails
then the remedy is different. What prevails is the difficulty to express, to bring out; that prevails.
That is the whole issue with Alumina.
They have of course fear of insanity because in that state in which they are, it's natural to think that I'm going crazy.
But they are not bothered by it, the bothering is the difficulty to think, the slowness of mind.
Everything seems unreal, fear of knives, impulse to kill themselves when they see a knife of blood.
When they see a knife the idea comes, 'shall I, oh I'm afraid I will take it and kill myself or kill somebody'.
There is another remedy which has that, which one?
Mercury has that but Mercury shall it have constipation? No. Mercury will have salivation for instance.
The combination is different.
Here, we have constipation with the fear of knife and severe constipation, Alumina.
Dryness of mucus membranes and skin, itching without eruption.
It's a dry person and see the peculiarity. Dryness of skin, dryness of mucus membranes, yet desire for dry food.
You will think that the person who has such dryness, would require a lot of liquid food.
No, they don't like it, they like the dry food.
They have an aversion and aggravation from potatoes. Itching without eruption also is a characteristic.
Dryness of skin, itching without eruption, constipation, Alumina.
Itching without eruption, dryness if skin with difficulty to express ideas,  the state of slowness of the mind, Alumina.
And of course paralysis, M.S., Alzheimer.
I mean you can understand we are describing a state of mind which is the beginning of Alzheimer's disease.
The idea is to pinpoint the pathology of each remedy. Where is the pathology?
Around the mind
and what turn this pathology takes?
Around the digestive system and what
modalities around the digestive system?
Within heart and what modalities? There are remedies which affect the heart, the guts, the stomach, the mind.
So what I'm trying to give you here is the primary seat of action of each remedy.
Mucus membranes, skin, dry mucus membranes, dryness of skin, dryness of mind.
You see if the mind is liquid then it runs out. Which is the remedy who has liquid mind?
Lachesis, loquacity they cannot stop. The ideas come fast, like Coffea, Lachesis, Nux-vomica.
Now this, it's the opposite, dryness.
When somebody is dehydrated, tired in mind and body, they will go like that and you wait, they try to give you an answer.
The same idea is with the stool they try
very hard, nothing comes out.
They have energy. It's not a matter of great tiredness.
I don't intensify the idea of tiredness because all the remedies can be tired, all. But there are some remedies
on which we shall focus on the idea of tiredness. Alumina is not one of them.
Alumina has this dryness and difficulty of expulsion, of ideas, of stool etc.
I'm going to give you some cases which you will study and then, you can use your Repertory of course to get some ideas.
What mostly I want is if you can spot the main remedy that you would give first because of this information.
I want you to use this information and find out and you will tell me, in this case I would prescribe first that remedy.
Because these cases I'm going to give you are not typical of one remedy.
Usually they contain the possibility
of 2, 3 or 4 remedies.
Which one you would give first and for what reason is very important, so we synchronize our thinking.
In order to solve such cases you need to remember this. That's why you will have to study today these remedies
read them again and again because on Wednesday when I will give you the cases
I will give you enough remedies,
maybe one of them will be.