Anacardium means in Greek 'one without heart'.
One without a heart is a hard person.
Cruelty, hardness, malicious is a characteristic of this remedy. It's very interesting that in ancient Greece already
I don't know how they found out, that people who ate this drug became heartless, became hard.
Most probably they have noticed that this
remedy was bringing about a state of cruelty.
But what is characteristic of this you see
internal conflict, contradiction inside
two things are contradicting inside me.
And the idea is, the one is good and the other is bad.
Thinks he is possessed of two wills opposing each other.
This contradiction can be on any level and on anything. If they cannot decide really what is their best way
of going about, if they cannot decide, they
are vacillating between this and the opposite.
Most probably this is going to be an Anacardium case.
Vacillating, not being able to take decision, great lack of self-confidence with feelings of inferiority and emotional hardness.
Feelings of inferiority is very severe, lack of self-confidence. People who are really suffering with this idea.
'I'm not good, I do not know anything',
even if they are very good at their work.
I've seen a doctor working for years
in his laboratory, doing very well,
he was in charge of the department with tremendous lack of self-confidence.
He thought he was not able to perform anything. He thought that he was worse than the first young doctor who came in.
And he was given the half of the Materia Medica, he was in America.
That element was so strong, nice man, sweet. They can be very sweet. The emotional hardness we say here,
you will always hear they are beating their wife or they are killing animals and things like that.
This can happen of course but not in all cases.
Especially the cases that do not have self confidence are very sweet, very nice.
A person who has inferiority complex, I am worse than anybody.
If you see a case where the suffering comes primarily from lack of self confidence then the remedy is
either Anacardium or Baryta Carbonica.
If at the same time they are tormented by thoughts which are opposing each other, Anacardium.
You see here I've put either cruel, sadistic and malicious or helpless, hopeless, pleading, needy and insecure.
It can be either.
But all of them, all these types they will have
lack of self confidence and internal conflict.
Another characteristic of Anacardium is that the people who need Anacardium, they need to say swear words.
Go to hell, bastard. In their vocabulary such words slowly they come. If you observe a case and you observe
the developing of these traits you see a person who never sworn before neither his education nor his social status
justifies this kind of language.
They suddenly need to express themselves,
to express their anger with such words.
That is the time where the Anacardium
picture is starting, is developing.
Both types will have the same tendency.
The question is, both these types, the cruel and sadistic and the helpless and hopeless, do both have this tendency?
I said, yes. Both have the tendency for swearing words.
Another is sudden loss of memory. As if the mind is blocked. This is very characteristic again.
Anacardium will be a case where he leaves this room to go inside and bring the water from inside.
He reaches this room and he says, why did I come here?
Oh my God everybody needs Anacardium!
And there is a block, total block, sudden loss of memory.
He remembers everything and suddenly, even in young people, there is a block and then they say... 'oh water!'
So sudden loss of memory together with either lack of self confidence or internal conflict or
sensation of a band around a single part.
Like the knee, elbow.
You put a band here and you put it tight, how it feels?
In different parts, joints they have the feeling of a tight band. The pain always has this feeling as if something is tight around.
This is really a characteristic if it goes with
sudden loss of memory or it goes with
the need to swear or with the conflict.
People also who are heartless, they can treat humans or animals as if they don't have feelings.
There is something peculiar happening which I will try to describe. If I lose my feelings, I don't have feelings or I have
a hardness inside me, there is a block on my feelings, the feelings are usually fluid, they run they never stop.
You imagine some person whose feelings
are stopped and become hard.
Now such a person needs a shock to move his feelings.
The Anacardium is led to do malice, to do bad, to hurt somebody else to move his feelings.
If Anacardium gets irritated and angry, the tendency is that he wants really to do something very malicious, very hard.
You see you get angry, you shout a little bit and it's finished. The Anacardium needs to go all the way, to really hurt you
but in such a way you say, my god he does not have feelings this man or this woman?
He can be so harsh with animals. He has an animal and the animal is doing something bad and then
the punishment is extreme. He hits the animal and there is a kind of emotions inside, the emotions are very hard.
It's very difficult to make you imagine the situation, the emotions are hard so nothing
satisfies my anger unless I kill the dog.
And then there is the opposite state. Once the emotions are released, comes a state of tremendous
sensitivity on the emotions. It's the opposite state.
Let us say, a woman has a relationship with a man and she feels insecure, she has no self confidence.
Therefore she can be hurt very easily because of that state. If you have next to you somebody who is inferior
feels that you are powerful she can be
hurt very easily. Now what happens?
She's hurt very easily  and the
emotions become hard, harsh.
And then the tendency will be what?
Either she will tell you the relationship is
finished because there is no emotions.
The emotions are harsh, dead. So under this pain she feels, she will say 'go away'.
And you maybe pleading saying why,
why she has been hurt by little things
that you cannot imagine for what little reason but the sensitivity and the lack of self confidence is so great.
'You did not phone me, 3 hours passed and did not phone'. That is enough to make the emotions hard
and then once they are hard, she is very harsh.
Go away, I don't like you, it's finished.
She does not feel anything, she can hurt more and more until such time
when that emotions have been satisfied with their cruelty and then she turns back to become again vulnerable etc.
This conflict state: I'm so bad and then
another idea comes she says, I'm so good.
Because the emotions when they come
they are very vulnerable, very sensitive.
Opposing states, the harshness and the super sensitivity like somebody who says, 'I've hurt you'.
'But no, you didn't hurt me'. 'No I know I've hurt you so badly'. Remembers something she has done and exaggerates this.
And there are also skin eruptions. Anacardium is a remedy which is indicated a lot in skin eruptions.
The main thing that you have to remember is that there are eruptions with intolerable itching and
the more she scratches the more the itching.
You can't imagine how much it can go.
It can lead the person to almost spasms. It can lead to a hysterical state where the person
scratches and goes up and down, it takes a brush, scratches with brush, with towel.
They scream! Then there is a climax and then they may calm.
They tell you, I know that if I start scratching I had it'. So if you hear that, ah we go for Anacardium.
And then what happens? I scratch more and more until I go crazy. Anacardium.
Agaricus and Anacardium you will need them quite frequently actually in our times.
Because the beginning of mental derangement in our societies take this kind of picture, Agaricus or Anacardium so far.
There is a regeneration, a rearrangement
in the mind and the body, a different attitude
does not need to swear,
does not need to do this.
Does not need. It's gone.
-I would like to know if we should remember at Anacardium humiliation as a trigger point.
-No, who said it's humiliation, did I say humiliation?
-No. Because you talked about sensitivity and if somebody decides to do something because of some small event.
-No, Anacardium has nothing to do with humiliation. Actually Anacardium can take a lot of humiliation without
really having the results of other remedies, like Ignatia, Natrum Muriaticum.
If you humiliate them, there is a big problem. With Anacardium you can humiliate them because
they feel humiliated themselves, it doesn't matter.
Is it possible that Anacardium will be harsh on himself and be nice outside? I said, no.
The remedy who is harsh to himself and nice outside is Aurum for instance. It can be very harsh and cruel to himself.
When I say no at that stage, things are absolutely cut and dry. But what I'm driving at is to give you the initial
the basic idea. If you mix this idea, you dilute, you dilute and when it comes to the point, you don't recognize it.
So lack of self confidence, sudden loss of memory and conflict, malicious the one, very sensitive the other.
That's it. That's Anacardium. What are the words?
I'm not interested on the words because
they are written down in all Materia Medicas.
You don't need another on top of this. What you need is to make a few points, write them down in big letters.
Fear of cancer, half a page, Agaricus. If fear of cancer is so small, Calcarea carbonica, it also has fear of cancer.
But big fear of cancer overwhelming fear
of cancer....you have to get this idea
words do not convey the idea, the intensity, the picture.
When a person sits down in front of you and says the first words, if you have this basic knowledge your mind will go
to a small group of remedies immediately. And then from there you choose, you differentiate. But if you are lost
in all this information which comes with thousands and thousands of symptoms then you are lost entirely.
You don't know where to search, where to look, what to do. This is the idea.
What do you see here?
What impresses you here?
Edema, spelt in American way. In English is spelt with oe.
Edema, swelling of the extremities. When we talk about swelling of the extremities they become really swell hard.
Due to the dysfunction of the kidneys.
Puffy swelling especially under the eyes.
It is interesting that the pains of Apis are stinging pains as if stung  by a bee and then the swelling comes like urticaria
or swelling of ankles and hard swelling.
Worse from heat. People who are suffering with heat and people who do have a sharp tongue, they sting you with their words.
They are people with strong emotions, jealous, passionate, sexually quite active and easily excited but also very awkward.
What is awkward?
-Unusual?
- It is clumsy. I am awkward if I walk here and I fall down. There is a state of passion, if somebody is
usually involved with his emotions, does not pay attention to the people around, so he either pushes, throws things
falls down, you know clumsy.
This is another remedy which is better with cold applications.
It is a warm remedy, it has burning pains and it is better with cold applications.
Which is another remedy which is better with cold applications that we talked about?
-Aloe. This is what I want, the whole class, Aloe! You got the idea?
Fear of cancer? Agaricus! You never forget this.
Once we come to the 20th remedy then we start wobbling, being awkward, very clumsy.
So kidney problems, swelling under the eyes, around the face, swellings in general, swelling which is burning
better with cold applications swellings of ankles
of the extremities, clumsiness, falls down,
throws things around, he doesn't pay attention.
And then they cry and cry without any cause. Despondency.
Something is not good inside and they cry and cry. They don't know why. Dissatisfied.
And this remedy which is hot and burning and which is better with cold applications, is it natural to have thirst?
-Yes.
- It does not. Remember this. It does
not have thirst. Usually is thirstless.
But when it has a chill during fever, then it becomes thirsty.
The remedy is thirstless but when there is fever and chill, the moment it feels cold, then it's thirsty,
the moment it feels warm then it's not thirsty.
This peculiarity you remember is Apis.
Diarrhea, loses stool with motion.
Which is the other remedy that loses stool?
-Aloe.
-Aloe with flatus, with wind. This loses stool on motion.
You don't use your imagination.
Intermittent fever. Chill with thirst at 3 pm.
At 3 pm there is an aggravation or there is a fever which comes
and has its peak at 3 pm, this is Apis.
I don't need anything more.
Extreme anxiety about health. Fear of death.
Which is the other remedy we said anxiety about health?
-Agaricus.
-Which was the fear of death?
-Aconite. Now, this has both anxiety about health and fear of death. Combines these two.
It's not that he is afraid he is going to die from cancer or whatever. He's just afraid to die, from heart, from cancer etc.
So Argentum nitricum is one of the main remedies that we use for this syndrome that we see very frequently today
where people esp. people who have lived a nice life, they have enjoyed very much there is a point where they get
into that stage. They are afraid they are going
to die and that their health is threatened.
But with this fear and anxiety what do we have together with this? The main impact is on impulsiveness.
He is impulsive. It's a person that he will speak out in a very impulsive way.
A person whose mind will stick on certain ideas which have danger and they are attracted by this idea.
The idea that I will put my fingers or a wire on the plug. And the person sits here and studies and the idea is there
what will happen if I put two wires in this plug? And he tries, and then the idea comes again
he tries to concentrate and the idea comes again. And then he gets up, this is a little bit extreme,
then he gets up and goes up to the point to stick the wires on that plug, to see what happens.
And the last minute he says, my god.
They are in a high place, they look down and they imagine what would happen if I just fall down.
They say, 'go away from there' and then they go back again, what would happen, how would I feel.
And the idea comes again and again and at a certain moment they imagine they are falling down
their head is crushed on the ground, they imagine the whole scene, and then they come back to themselves.
The mind is attracted by such idea. You understand that a mind that works in this way, the quality
of the mind is not good. It has a lot of problems.
It's very strange how it's attracted to do things though the anxiety about health is so great,
the fear of death is so great; yet they put there their hands.
A very characteristic case, I have said it many times. I was fishing with a friend and we got a fish, a dragon fish.
If you touch that fish you can die from pain. So I got one fish like that, put it in the basket and said to him.
This is a dragon fish, do you see it? Yes. Don't touch it. I put it in the basket and I continue fishing.
Then as I turn around and I see he is putting his hand in the basket to move it. I said 'for God's sake if this hits you
and you suddenly go like this, then we have to go back immediately'. Then I turn around fishing and
again his hand
he is not fishing, just trying....I say 'for God's sake don't touch!'. Then I turn around and again.
And then I thought, oh my God!
We have been treating him for anxiety about health, fear of death, he was a nice man, very communicative, Phosphorus.
We gave Phos again and again saying a little bit be better.
Then it's like an enlightenment, this is a case
of Arg-n. We gave Arg-n, finished.
He was on the telephone all the time, I have my heart, then I have cancer then he had the head, then...
and just an observation like this, is finished.
They walk here and say, 'if I touch one line, I am finished'. And they can walk like this for hours not being able to
touch a line because if I touch a line... They go around and they say 'if I turn in that corner
something bad will happen' and they turn around all this way from the other side.
They are stuck with certain ideas. The idea is to understand the quality of the mind, that you have to have in mind.
And there is also a problem if they have to meet somebody, to meet with an appointment. They get very anxious inside
and they have to run to the bathroom several times before they can go to the appointment.
Sometimes they reach to the point where they have diarrhea before the appointment is approaching
they have to run to the bathroom and
then quickly rush to the appointment.
They come to be treated for colitis or others, it doesn't matter. What it matters is to have this unique characteristics of the remedy.
That is the whole secret in Homeopathy. We will be talking about 200 remedies and not one will look like another.
Each one will have its own personality, its own characteristics. Yet, if you look upon superficially you say
oh he has anxiety about his health, oh he has fear of death.
Yes but this coupled with this kind of mind, it makes it Arg-n. coupled with the fear that he soon dies
it makes it Aconite, coupled with the overwhelming fear of cancer, makes it Agaricus.
It is a matter of combination of 2-3 symptoms together which you are expecting to see in an Arg-n case.
Another characteristic is aggravation, desire for sweets, desire for salt, strong desire but if he eats the sweets
then he has aggravation he has flatulence, burning in the stomach, bad feelings, bad condition.
Diarrhea after eating sugar. Sugar is like poison for him, though he desires sweets very much.
And then another characteristic on the digestion is that their abdomen is bloated with gas, with air.
And there are eructations which are very loud. You hear eructations of Arg-n, they cannot hide it
neither they will try to hide it. It's like a machine gun.
Gas from down and up in a forceful way.
You see the bloatness, you see the gas
but is it Lyc., is it Carb-v another one, is it Chin, or it is Arg-n? In order to be Arg-n  you need
these loud, machine gun eructations.
And they are worse from heat, who else is worse from heat?
Apis, very good.
Aggravation from heat, from sweets.
Another characteristic is what is called granular conjunctivitis. I will explain to you.
In the white of the eye, there is a spot like raw meat, a very red spot on the conjunctiva.
You just see that sign, immediately your mind should go to two remedies, one is Arg-n and the other is Medorrhinum.
Red spot but not red eyes, this is different. When the whole of the eye is red and inflammed is different
it's Euphrasia, Clematis, Graphites, different remedies.
This is the eye here, it looks like this. If this is much bigger, most probably is Medorrhinum.
I had a friend of mine, he was suffering with asthma. Though he knew me, he never asked me for a remedy.
One time he asked me for something very mild, I can't remember now. He had that spot and I knew.
Also I've seen him, he ate a lot of sweets I had observed and one time he asked for something very minute.
He says, do you have something for this? He was a pharmacist. I'm talking about 1969 when I first went to Greece.
As he was a pharmacist he used to take for his asthma, his medication, he didn't believe.
I said, yes take this and I gave him a dose of Arg-n. He comes after few days and says, 'you know I had asthma
and after the remedy I don't feel the asthma anymore. Has anything to do with the remedy?'
I said, 'yes this is Homeopathy. You don't believe, you are a pharmacist, now you better believe'.
Maybe it was this spot here, I can't remember now but it was something irrelevant.
His whole organism changed.
Out of a little observation like that.
It is so important because it is unique. It is only this remedy which has that kind.
Because if the whole conjunctiva becomes red, lots of remedies but that so strong is Argentum.
Everybody knows Arnica.
This is a remedy that does not like others to come near her. Why? Because of the fear they may hurt them.
They say don't touch me.
There are people who say, don't touch me,
I don't like to be touched.
And this is a remedy which produces ailments after injuries from blunt instruments.
You hit like this and then all this becomes blue.
And it's very painful. If it blue but not painful, Arnica is not indicated. That's why Arnica will not act all the time.
Arnica has to be very painful. The idea is not only when they are under injury, when they are hurt.
They don't like to be approached, to be touched, to be squeezed as a constitution without being hurt.
It says, the pain of the head is such that the pillow feels very hard. The pillow how hard it can be?
But for them it is like stone, like lying on a stone. You understand the sensitivity?
This fear of being touched, approached, I have seen it in women that they cannot have sexual intercourse.
Women who cannot even think of having full sexual intercourse. It is impossible for them to have the idea
of being penetrated. The idea is as if they are hurt through sexual intercourse; so much that they will avoid totally.
Not that they have aversion to sex. They have desire for sex but they cannot have full sexual intercourse.
I've met a woman of 35 years old. She never had any sexual intercourse though she had tremendous desire.
She said, the idea of being penetrated for me is totally out of question.
She became pregnant after 9 months, after Arnica. I said how? By accident. I said yes, accidents happen also.
This traumatic experience can be in premature birth. In premature birth, you may have some trauma, you may
have some injury to the head or to the body and then this will remain as a memory of trauma and then of course
it may develop eventually into a case of Arnica.
The most dramatic cure I have seen
with Arnica it was with one cock.
Who died with a brain injury.
He was totally dead, he looked totally dead because he was hitting his head against the glass, trying to get
to the other cock who was to the other side and he was hitting, hitting and then he collapsed.
And the cock was given to me by my neighbor and I thought oh my god, I took the cock and told them that he died
most probably today because he was ok yesterday and whether they would like to cook him.
She said 'a dead cock? Never!'
I said 'either you like to eat him or I can survive him, what do you prefer?'
She said 'you are joking?', I said 'why, he just died, you can eat him'.
So I brought some Arnica, I put some water and I gave the cock a little bit of a drop, put it in his mouth like this.
The moment I put it there was a jerk. I said to her, keep on giving this water. Next day, the cock was jumping.
It is a remedy that is indicated in head injuries with hematoma in the head even if the hematoma
has stayed for years and has caused severe problems. The hematoma can be absorbed back after years.
This was very interesting case I just remembered.
He came to me to be treated but he was deaf  and we had to shout very much.
'How are you?', 'I have this pain'. 'What about the pain?', 'It's ok, take Arnica'.
He gave me some characteristics, I don't remember now, I'm talking back in 1970. I gave a dose of Arnica
and then after 2 months he comes back,
he was from a village and I said 'how are you?'
He said 'don't shout'. I said 'what?', 'I can hear and I don't know how it happened because I was deaf for 15 years. I can hear'.
His deafness was because of a head injury which had affected the acoustic nerve. Miraculous, in 2 months this was reduced.
He said, don't shout. His hearing was back to 85-90 %, we could talk like this, no problem.
Another characteristic is that if you get a patient in semi-coma and you see he is in a such a deep state
and you ask a question and immediately responds and gives you an answer and then goes back into coma.
It's very interesting, it's like stimulating this person with some sock, he comes back
gives you the answer and goes back to coma. This is characteristic of Arnica.
But if a person is in a coma and comes out of the coma and he starts giving you the answer, this is Baptisia.
If during the giving of the answer cannot finish his words and goes back into coma, that's Baptisia.
You just remember this, that first of all you have to have injuries, not injuries that cut the skin open.
You have usually injuries which they were blunt, a concussion not open, then there was a problem afterwards.
If the head was open, 99 % will not be Arnica indicated.
If the head was not open, was concussed and after this you have dilatation of pupils, you have headaches
you have vertigos, you have fears, you have injuries, then Arnica will be indicated.
Many many times in concussions, if you give Arnica immediately you dispense with all the problems
that the patient may have for years.
You just clear it.
Because in the beginning the extravasation of blood starts, you give Arnica immediately stops the blood coming out
and absorbs the blood which is outside and clears the case.
But you have to give high potency in such case. 10M, 50M, CM. 50M is a good potency.
Once I was going on a bus, I was getting up in a bus quickly and somebody else was coming with a steal frame
and she was going down with the steel frame,
I was going down and she hit me on my knee.
I got into the bus and I was fainting from pain; I asked the bus driver to stop.
I stayed in the street there and I tried to get a taxi because I was fainting all the time. I was trying not to faint.
And the taxi brought me outside of my home and I just managed to get inside my home with this severe pain, unbearable.
And I grasped a dose of Arnica 50M. I put it there and in a minute  like miracle, the pain disappeared.
Then you need Arnica. But it is wrong if with little injuries, you take Arnica.
This is not correct. If you have a strong injury you use these potencies. If you have a small injury, forget it.
Symmetrical eruptions, Arnica is famous but there are a lot of other remedies that have this symmetrical eruption.
Heart infraction, we use Arnica in brain stroke, in heart infarction especially when the patient does not want
to be approached by others, fear of coming near.
So the pillow feels hard, eructation and diarrhoea smell of spoiled eggs very characteristic
and of course after injuries with blunt instrument.
Sometimes people use this, homeopaths, use Arnica they say, you go to the dentist take Arnica to prevent the pain. This is wrong.
Take Arnica as a preventive. This is wrong. There is no indication for Arnica. When the tooth is extracted
always there is blood running out. The blood has to stay inside enclosed and then the severe pain  starts
and then Arnica is indicated.
The same after extraction of tooth, Arnica is not indicated. They say, 'oh it did me good'.
Of course it will be good whether
you took Arnica of did not take Arnica.
No before operation. Arnica in order to act has to have its own symptoms. Otherwise don't give it.
You spoil the remedy. By giving too many homeopathic remedies for little reasons, you spoil the possibility
of that person to react correctly in the correct remedy. There is no need to give remedy for little things, especially little injuries.
Don't use Arnica for little things, use Arnica for real problems. When there is a concussion and the person is in a coma,
you speak to him and you see he answered and then back, 50M Arnica, he will come out of the coma within minutes.
What about Arnica after birth?
After birth there is a possibility of a rupture of the perineum. In this case, no Arnica is indicated.
Maybe if the symptoms of Arnica are there, yes. If there is no rupture and there is severe pain left over, Arnica can be indicated.
But if there is rupture and then pain, no Arnica.