So here we come to a very interesting remedy: Arsenicum album.
What we see here the combination that gives Arsenicum album is a feeling of insecurity coupled with anxiety about health, fear of death, fear of being alone, restlessness and prostration.
Can you imagine this individual?
The idea is that inside him, he feels that he has no support, that he is alone, that he does not have enough security.
Nevermind the security, how much security he may have. He may have a lot of security, a lot of money, a lot of friends, wife, children, whatever, it doesn't matter; still the insecurity is there and wants always somebody next to him.
An individual who wants everything to be in order. Every disorder brings a kind of anxiety
and a kind of insecurity.
He wants to know what belongs to him  that is his own.
So the fear of death, the restlessness and the anxiety together with the desire for order and cleanliness.
He is a person who dresses absolutely meticulously, absolutely well. The best clothes, the best buttons; the buttons are very important.
This has to be exactly on the spot. It can take half an hour to bring this exactly into order.
You know the laces if they are not equal, he will not be happy. He will not tie them.
I have watched one time one of the doctors of the center. We've been in the sea to swim. Then I said, ok we finished, let's go.
In 3 minutes I dressed and I was waiting for him to finish dressing. He put this, he put that, very slowly.
And then he reached the point of the laces. And I was watching and I said, god what is he doing?
He was pulling out and then he was pulling a little more and then he was pulling the other way.
And I said, 'oh my god come on let's finish. We're half an hour here'. He says, 'I'm coming' until he brought them
exactly to the size and then he tied them. I said, now I know your remedy.
A child with fever is concerned with the blankets. Minding the blankets, they are too much down here
pulls the blankets so they fall both sides equally.
The child was in fever and the mother says,
she told me to pull the blankets to the exact size. She could not rest. You see the restlessness.
Once I had an assistant professor in the University in Athens and he said, 'I would like to know what's Homeopathy'.
I said, very good. And I had a doctor with me by this time, she was my student, who was his student as well.
So we invited him and he sits in one place with his overcoat; it's winter. He has his overcoat, we talk.
After a while he gets up, he goes and sits in another place.
After a while he sits in another place. In the meantime we speak.
For 1 hour and a half I explained to him what is Homeopathy. He said in the end, ok this is all theoretical.
\I have a cold, can you give me something for my cold to go away?'. I said, now it's a good time.
I did not ask any question. I only saw that his nose was a little bit red.
Without asking any question I said to my student, bring Arsenicum 200. So she brings Arsenicum, gives to him and he leaves.
Before he says good bye I said, wait a moment. Because the cold was going down and his throat was painful.
He said usually my colds are going down.
Tomorrow my cold will be there and I' start coughing and for 15 days I will be coughing.
I said, ok take this and what is going to happen by tomorrow evening, your nose will be running.
And by the next day, you will be all right. He left.
Next day in the evening, he picks up the telephone and says, 'my nose is running'. Close the telephone.
I heard his voice, he didn't even say his name. 'George, my nose is running'.
He is a strange character. You just met somebody. I'm talking about 1967 in Greece.
The other day he says, 'you told me that by today I will be alright'. A small pause.
'I'm ok'. Closed the telephone.
About 20 days later, because I knew what I had done. I had given him actually his constitutional remedy
by observing this, the feeling of the coldness which he had, the restlessness.
20 days later he picks up the telephone, he says, 'you know something I have been suffering for the last 15-20 years with gastritis.
So I have to have Maalox, it's an antacid drug to counteract the acidity of the stomach. I have Maalox everywhere
in my pockets, in my drawers, in my car, in my house, in my office. I had to take all the time this, my stomach was burning.
Now since you gave me the remedy, I do not have that burning. Has anything to do with the remedy?', 'yes'.
You know 1967 in Greece, a professor of the University talking with a "charlatan" you know, telling him some
strange things he never heard before and now not only the cold went but now the gastritis is cured. Now what is this?
Well about a few months later, he says 'can you teach me?', I said yes, 'but nobody will ever know that I'm coming for lessons'.
This man became the first President of the Hellenic Homeopathic Medical Association.
What is this knowledge? Only believing that a person who is restless, who is cold, who has anxiety;
of course he did not express his anxiety but he knew himself how much anxiety, how much fear of death he had.
Later on he confessed. What made me give me Arsenicum? It was of course the acid discharge from the nose.
There is acid discharge which makes the nose red.
Fastidious, critical about others and about himself. This is a characteristic, very critical.
They don't leave anything in chance, they
will criticize everybody and everything.
Of course it has burning pains.
Ameliorated by heat, hot drinks, hot applications.
So this remedy is a very cold remedy which
is ameliorated by heat in every form.
Feels the cold very much and wants to be covered with many blankets except for the head which he wants exposed to fresh air.
This is another characteristic while in most acute cases, you will find Arsenicum freezing but the head is hot
and wants fresh air. Wants to be fanned.
Restless in bed, anxious in bed and fanning the head while he has five blankets. I remember one case in India
in the hospital, with kidney colic, lying in bed and being very restless. We went up to see the patient
very restless, the nurse was there and says, air, air, air in the head. He was covered in India with the heat
with 4 blankets, they put one after another. She could not get warm enough. And the head had to be fanned.
And he called for water, the nurse was fanning and giving him sips of water.
Arsenicum wants water, he feels thirsty but cannot drink a whole bottle. He wants this and again and again
the more the fever, the more frequent.
In chronic cases, he has a water cup and he can drink it in one hour, two hours, just sip by sip.
Actually if you remember this picture for Arsenicum is enough. The prostration, the restlessness, the coldness,
the heat of the face, the anxiety and in acute cases you will also see the prostration quite strong.
They get up though they are prostrated, they get up from bed because they cannot sit in one place
and they go and lie down in the sofa. And they get from the sofa and go and lie down to the chair.
They get up from the chair and they lie down to the bed.
All this time this restlessness and prostration and the fever and the coldness and the air and then the water in sips.
In diarrhea after food poisoning with coldness and prostration, it's almost a specific. Together with specific kind of thirst.
Prostration, weakness, tiredness. Prostration is stronger than tiredness, am I correct Mr. English?
Total exhaustion.
And asthmatic breathing which is worse lying down. With the head low, Arsenicum forget it.
They say, we have to prop up, they stay in a place like this.
And the time for aggravation starts after midnight and then it goes more and more, 1 o'clock is very aggravated
2 o'clock more aggravation and then slowly subsides and they go back to amelioration.
So from midnight to 12 o'clock usually is their worse time. For asthma, for colics, for pains, whatever and in general.
So the idea is you may have with Arsenicum a lot of symptoms. If you have within 30,40,50 symptoms
these symptoms that's a case of Arsenicum.
Hypochondriac is anxiety about health. It can reach the point where he is hypochondriac.
Yes the anxiety is quite strong but usually is an anxiety because he is going to die. Fear of death.
It's connected with fear of death. Here we have fear of cancer, in Agaricus, but we don't have fear of death.
They will say, I'm not afraid to die; I'm scared to death to get cancer not because I will die.
Because of the idea of ugliness, the cancer reminds you of death all the time; death is on me and I'm going to go in a grave.
This kind of mentality is Agaricus.
Here, we have a different mentality all together.
Order. This is mine. The possessiveness is strong with Arsenicum. They like what they possess.
They like to have it. They like to keep it. And that is why when they come to the state of anxiety and neurosis
they usually cannot go outside in the market, without having somebody next to them.
To accompany them, to feel secure that if something happens to them, this person whom they trust
they don't take anybody, they take those people who they trust.
This person will take me to the hospital, so I can be saved. I will not die.
It's very strange how the chemistry on the brain can produce some thoughts. You give Arsenicum and the fear of death is gone.
They don't think about it anymore. How is that the chemistry can produce a thought like this?
How is that the chemistry of the brain
changes and produces fear of heart disease?
In Lachesis we shall see heart disease. In Aurum we will see heart disease.
'I have learned from other teachers that Arsenicum has a strong fear of cancer. In the Repertory also I see that
Arsenicum is indicated one of the two remedies which have in the 3rd degree'.
This comes from a misunderstanding of my teaching.
Most probably it's somebody who listened to me teaching and then he brought his own idea.
What happened? In the way I said, anxiety, anxiety about health, it means fear of cancer etc. I could have said that.
But this is not the symptom. Now if somebody hears it and takes it as the symptom, is not my problem.
That's why such mistakes have gone through because this must be an addition.
If you look through, you will see it's an addition. From who?
Fear of cancer it has to be 3 times there, it has to be Agaricus. It's 1 there.
What they did? Somebody listened to my tapes or teaching, heard this fear and put it 3 times.
Great anxiety about health. I have raised Arsenicum to the 3rd degree in the anxiety about health.
Because originally it was on the 2d degree in Kent's Repertory.
The original Kent's Repertory, see anxiety about health. Arsenicum is 1st or 2d degree?
It's 1st.
This is what I say, in my experience the anxiety about health of Arsenicum is very strong
and it should be raised to the 3rd degree.
Not the fear of cancer specifically.
Anxiety about health. They feel anxious that something will happen to their health whether it will be
heart attack, whether it will be brain stroke, whether it will be cancer.
But the fear of cancer is not specifically fear of cancer. It is anxiety about health.
-What do you recommend for fear of cancer?
-What I recommend?
-First or second degree?
-If this has fear of cancer, Agaricus on the 3rd degree, this should go on the 2d, Arsenicum.
But if you have the Repertory and you can correct, you raise Agaricus to the 3rd degree.
Fear of cancer also is Calcarea carbonica, it has to be on the 2d degree.
Usually the Arsenicum album is very cold and does not tolerate cold water.
But for instance a German Arsenicum, may discipline himself into going into cold water in spite of the fact he does not like it.
As a result of going into cold water, he may eventually become accustomed to that.
You can change all these symptoms. For instance a Nat-m who has desire for salt, may have no desire for salt
by using the mind saying it's not good for you to have salt. Eventually he feels no desire for salt.
In the same way, Lycopodium may not have desire for sweets, or Arg-n desires sweets.
But if he hears sweets are not good, make you ill then they persuade themselves they are not good.
In this way yes, you can have the Arsenicum dipping into 15 degrees of Celsius.
I, myself used to be cold person. Now I'm not so cold. I carry on swimming in the winter here. And I was blue.
I was coming out after 1 minute in the sea and I was blue. But I still say it's good for you, do it. It doesn't matter.
So the next remedy that you are learning is Aurum metallicum. Severe depression, relieved only by thoughts of suicide.
Constantly dwelling on suicide. That's it. You don't have to remember anything else.
Hopeless, despondent. Profound melancholy with a history of attempted suicide, loathing of life.
Here what we have to remember in Aurum is profound despondency.
Anxiety of conscience as if they are guilty of some crime.
How would you feel if you had committed a murder and you have kept it inside? The sub-conscious will be
always in an upheaval with feelings of guilt. You will never be happy, you will be despondent.
Melancholy, depressed.
Aurum has this particular symptom of wanting to commit suicide by jumping from a high place.
You will ask, 'how are you thinking of committing suicide?' He will say, 'by jumping'.
They will not give you the information immediately. You have to understand he's Aurum and you have to ask him
how many times you think of suicide everyday? 20, 30, 50 times is the answer. How? By what means? By jumping.
I remember the case of a patient who managed to survive a suicide. She said, 'I was in the terrace of a house'.
Here in Greece we have these terraces on the roof, straight, with little protection.
She said, 'I found myself in that position and I was telling myself, now is your time, jump, jump and I said that
if I would jump, I would be relieved from all this tremendous sadness and depression that I was carrying myself'.
So these beautiful descriptions are very valid because they point out exactly how an Aurum feels, at the moment before jumping.
Aurum the gold. How many people jumped, committed suicide in the financial depression in 1929
how many people jumped from the balcony because they lost their gold?
They lost the gold and down ! The gold goes up and down. The more up, the more down.
This is the idea with the gold. People like to be the first.
Like to be in a high position. They enjoy being in a high position, why?
Because actually they do not have feelings. The feelings are hardened and being in a high position and getting
the admiration of people from lower down, it makes them feel good.
The moment they lose that high position, they lose everything. They want to finish their life.
You see a very successful financial man. He thinks he lost not all his money but a lot of his money
and the first thing they think is, nobody loves me, I have no friends, my wife does not love me, my children have left me,
I don't have connection with anybody, I don't see anything to look forward. I lost also the position and now I have to jump.
It's the impulse inside, the feeling is from inside.
It is different between having courage and between, when they think of doing it they just do it.
With Aurum be careful because they are people who really commit suicide.
Not that they have courage, it's a different thing. I have courage to stay alive. I don't have courage to jump.
-Normally they are people with courage in other things?
-No, not specifically. On the contrary, they lose courage immediately. They lose heart, they lose courage
if they lose what they think is their position in life.
They value very much the position. I have to be on the top.
The idea is there. Once they are not on the top, then nothing is worth. I better jump and kill myself. This is the idea.
Of course by teaching, by saying things, students listen and then they transfer their understanding of what I have said.
So Aurum really jumps, that's what I have said. Not courage, it's madness. The moment they do it
they are crazy, they are mad, they are gone.
Another point you may see quite frequently is the Aurum, as I said, feel they lost everything. So nothing
keeps them in this earth. So it's better they kill themselves.
But one thing they feel that may keep them here and it is God. As they are inside them depressed, there is darkness inside
the idea of steel, iron, like you have iron instead of emotions.
And they feel they're going down, they're going to jump, there is no hope, there is nothing. And at that moment
they start praying. And by praying inside, God help me, God help me, they can pray for 1-2 hours before they can feel
a little bit of release from this depression. So praying Aurum, it says in the Repertory 'praying'
Like here it says, desires to pray. These are words. What you have to perceive is the state which makes you do this.
That is interesting, that you recognize in a human being and then you can save this person.
And neither they will tell you, 'I'm praying'. Very seldom. Praying is natural because human beings
we feel helpless many times. We all pray one way or another. But we don't stay for hours, in order to relieve
a little bit that tremendous depression to pray and pray and pray.
I remember in India, a boy came in the hostel where  I used to stay. He had a severe pain in his testes. Swelled up.
He tried to take different remedies because he was in the School and he has asked different remedies
from the other teachers there in the School. Then he came to me, he says 'I cannot live with this pain, it is too much
and can you do something?'. Then I enquired and I saw the depression in the boy, not strong. I said to him, do you pray?
He says, 'I pray, I get up in the morning'. 'For how long?'. 'Two hours, two and a half hours I pray'. It's very good, Aurum.
Pain in 3,4 days was finished. Swelling went down.
-You were talking about students who have problems during their studies. What do you suggest for students
before the final examinations, if they have diarrhea and insomnia and all this?
What would be the first remedy to think of?
-According to the symptoms. If they are terrified, trembling, I'm going to go to the examinations and they lose courage
and they are afraid, fearful, Gelsemium. But if they have diarrhea is different because it can be Arg-n.
And if they have total black out of the mind, the mind is so tired that they feel they cannot remember anything it's Picric Acid.
-I mean before the examinations. For example one week insomnia.
-One week insomnia before the examinations because of excitement, it might be either Nux Vomica or Coffea.
Because of excitement, you know they are so excited, reading, studying, the mind goes on continuously to think
then we have to think of Coffea or Nux Vomica. You see it depends how you give a question.
How you say a symptom and then I will give you the answer. Not me, Homeopathy has these answers.
Let's go to the next remedy.
Belladonna.
Do you know what the word Belladonna means?
Bella in Italian means beautiful, donna, lady. Beautiful lady. Why Belladonna was called a beautiful lady?
Because the ancients they have noticed that if a woman ate the berries of this plant, they used to have bright eyes and rosy cheeks.
It makes the face red and the eyes bright, they are shinning. And these are the characteristics of the remedy.
Redness of face and eyes, in fever the eyes are shining and red.
Glistening, shining. And the whole body radiates heat in the Belladonna, especially in the Belladonna fever cases.
Without that heat of the body, Belladonna will not be indicated.
You have to remember a very characteristic of Belladonna:
The head is very warm, burning warm, red and the extremities, the hands and especially the feet are cold.
This is the great keynote of Belladonna. Hardly any case of Belladonna has warm feet.
The feet are cold while at the same time the head is very warm, very red and redness in general.
If a skin eruption is very red, the main thing that impresses you in a skin eruption is redness, then most probably is a Belladonna case.
Radiating heat at the same time, definitely Belladonna. Warm head, cold feet this is a Belladonna situation.
Extremities in general cold, hands and feet.
And of course Belladonna is known for having a great intensity of symptoms.
Symptoms are coming like a storm and suddenly and they become very prominent.
The headache comes within half an hour. They want not to move at all, they want to lie down, they don't want
any movement, any light, nothing that will disturb them.
And the headache is usually on the right side.
Then during the Belladonna case, we have a characteristic that if they receive a jar like this, you go to the bed side
and you sit to look at the patient.
Wherever is the pain, in the abdomen, in the head, the jar makes the pain tremendous. This is very characteristic of Belladonna.
They are people with intense emotions and presence. They are strong, vital, self-confident.
These emotions strong all day they continue during the night. So they go to sleep and there you see the activity.
They start talking in their sleep very loudly. You can hear them.
Saying different things, conversations and the intensity is there.
Also the irritation on the meninges which is expressed with grinding of the teeth.
In the night. Which is the other remedy which has strong grinding of teeth?
-Tuberculinum. Usually when we see grinding of teeth, we think of Tuberculinum first and then we have to think of Belladonna.
There is another remedy of course, Cina, Stramonium also have grinding of the teeth, but that shows the activity
the irritation in the brain. Especially with the fever you see they're grinding their teeth, they're talking, the fever is very high
the headache is pounding, the redness in the face and the shining of the eyes. That makes the full picture of Belladonna.
And if you jerk them, they jump.
Of course cold applications ameliorate. I mean if you have somebody who is boiling, you put some cold applications and makes him better.
Desire for lemonade is very characteristic, during fever especially, squeezed lemon.
Not "Fanta". Real lemon, we're talking about lemonade. By the time we were doing these provings, we did not have "Fanta".
-But what if somebody likes "Fanta"?
-Maybe he likes it because of the fizzing.
-Can you use it for Belladonna?
-No. The lemon must be the sour because Belladonna likes lemon.
It can eat lemon. Arsenicum, Belladonna, Veratrum album they like lemon
and when we say lemonade, we mean natural juice.
Of course our taste today is degenerated and we may want "Fanta".
So what strikes you here is the irritability with the special, leave-me-alone, attitude.
Aggravated by any interference by any person. They lie down and the woman comes, she is concerned, how are you?
They don't answer. You want something? No answer. Why they don't answer? Because they feel so irritable inside
and if they talk it's such an effort and the headache will become worse. And everything will become worse,
so they just don't answer. If they do answer, it's going to be very rude answer. Leave me alone.
Once I examined somebody who is Bryonia and he was lying on the sofa, looking at the wall. And I was behind him
and the examination was all the time like this. Him, looking at the wall, answer me some questions
but he would not turn around to look at me. Why? Because it was very painful, he had a pneumonia.
And the coughing was so painful, every motion, everything makes it worse. So to turn around and talk to me
it was a great effort, he did not turn. So I did all the examination like this
and of course I prescribed Bryonia. He doesn't turn because he is painful.
You can ask him, you don't turn because it's painful? He may nod, something like that but the aggravation
therefore from motion, is very characteristic of that remedy
Never mind what it is, it is a sciatica, a lumbago, a headache, a pain in the stomach, pain in the abdomen, whatever.
Worse from any motion.
And another characteristic is very thirsty for large quantity, frequently.
That means I take this, I drink it. After half an hour, I need another one. After half an hour, I need another one.
Very thirsty. It's one of the most thirsty remedies together with Phosphorus, Sulphur, Natrum muriaticum, very good.
For large quantities.
Strong fear of poverty.
You see these people, a constitutional Bryonia has lived as a loner. The "leave me alone attitude".
They are much happier if they are left alone. They are not the people who will socialize, who will communicate
they feel better if they are alone.  is me.
For instance like me. Here you laugh.
Likes to be alone.
It can be, it doesn't matter, they are people
who are duty bound, they will do their duty.
They will come and teach but they prefer to be alone. And they don't depend, they are people who do not like to depend.
If they want something, they will do it themselves.
This attitude, when you don't rely on somebody, you get fear of poverty. That means, if I don't have enough money, what shall I do?
Because if you don't have friends, if you don't rely on somebody, if you don't have associates and you rely
on your own money not in anything else, then you get strong fear of poverty. And Bryonia is one of the remedies
with Psorinum, Sulphur and Calcarea carbonica and Calcarea fluorica and different other remedies, that have fear of poverty.
And it's very interesting also in their delirium, if they are lying in delirium, they will say, let's go home.
I want to go home. They feel better alone in their own house.
It's very interesting one case I had in a hospital, in Athens, where I was treating this patient.
He was in a coma for 3 months, he came out of the coma and almost as soon as he came out of the coma
after Opium, Sulphur and Hyoscyamus, I think these 3 remedies brought him out of the coma and the 4th remedy was Bryonia.
He said, take me home; he did not know what he was saying.
He could talk now but still not clear. He said, take me home, take me home, let's go home.
But he could not recognize his daughter for instance. He looked and said, 'let's go home, let's go home'. Bryonia.
Coughing so painful that he has to hold his chest. I told you that. This movement of the chest is unbearable.
Headache on left side is characteristic and the pain goes to the left occipital protuberance.
Pain over the left eye that extends to the left occipital protuberance, is Bryonia alone. Worse, motion.
It's one of the few remedies that they like to sleep on left side.
But if they have gallbladder problems, they like to lie upon the painful part. They like to lie on the right side.
So it does not move. In a gallbladder inflammation, lying on the left side makes it worse.
They turn on the right side and they feel good. Belladonna, they don't like the pressure so they turn on the left side.
So Belladonna in a gallbladder inflammation, will be lying on the opposite side.
Bryonia will lie on the side where there is the inflammation.
It's one of the remedies that have severe constipation like,  which is the other remedy that we talked about
and it has severe constipation?
-Alumina.
-Alumina, severe constipation, it's similar. Bryonia and Alumina are similar in their constipation
and they sometimes complement each other in severe constipation.
You start with Bryonia and then you go to Alumina. Or you start with Alumina, it's completed with Bryonia.
Bryonia has dryness, it's a dry remedy, a remedy that needs water. Where is my water?
These remedies are dehydrated easily.
For whom this temperature is too much?
For whom it's pleasant?
For whom it's cold?
It's an organism that loses the water easily. The water goes away from the organism easily, that is general.
Of course you may get a case where the thirst is normal.
-My question was, I know they are always thirsty. Almost always. My question was, if the pain is very strong?
-If the pain is very strong?
-They are still drinking or not?
-They are drinking yes.
-Because I think I read, maybe something from you.
-Not from me.
-They avoid to drink because of the movement by drinking is so hard
in pneumonia or other illness so they avoid drinking.
-Not from me.
-Ok, thank you.
-You see the thirst for Bryonia is strong, they cannot avoid it. They cannot say, let me not drink or drink later.
It's strong thirst, need for water. They will drink.
The idea that they will have aggravation from motion and thirsty. Aggravation from motion and constipated.
Do you see the dryness?
Constipation with very hard and dry stool as if burnt. That means there is no mucus in the intestines.
Nausea and faintness from sitting up or rising in bed also is characteristic.
Especially in acute conditions, the moment they try to rise from bed they feel dizzy and they feel vomiting. They feel nauseous.
If you have a chronic case, whatever, which has that particular symptom, you have to be thinking of Bryonia.
One more remedy and we finish for today. Otherwise you will have nightmares. You will see remedies in your sleep.