Calc.is the most easy remedy.
I was in America and one of my best students there, presented to me a case. He has given about 20 remedies without effect.
I take the case. I say, this is a case of Calc.. He says, oh my God I can see now.
It's an easy remedy but sometimes difficult to recognize.
So in Calc. the first thing that we'll see in the mental-emotional, a lot of fears.
Fear of dark, fear of heights. Fear of insanity it's strong, of getting crazy.
Oh my God, am I getting crazy? How I feel like that? Fear of dark, fear of ghosts, fear of thunderstorms
fear of dogs, rats, fear of death, fear of disease, fear of cancer, fear of anxiety about health.
All kinds of fears you get with Calc.
And the great keynote is despair of recovery.
Shall I ever be better? Shall I ever recover?
This is something that it is almost ingrained in them, almost deep inside. Their belief that they are not going to get well.
That despair of recovery also you cannote in your notes of Arsenicum.
That has anxiety about health, fear about death, has despair of recovery as strong as Calc.
The two remedies are worse from cold, both Calc. and Arsenicum.
They are having despair of recovery but the Arsenicum is usually lean persons with good combustion
burning of the food where Calc. has bad combustion and therefore putting on weight easily.
They take little food but they pick up a lot of weight. Calc. is one of these remedies that we prescribe for obesity.
Easily putting on weight. Obesity and flabbiness. The muscles are flabby.
The tissues are soft and watery. The muscles are not strong. Children which are flabby with big bellies.
Sensitive to cold, cold hands and especially feet. Calc. usually will tell you, 90% of the cases
I sleep with a hot water bottle.
Or I sleep with my socks on. 90% of the cases.
And they are cold in their extremities and at the same time, sweat.
They say cold, sweat, immediately your mind goes to Calc.
I reduced the whole Materia Medica into 2 days.
You need to study and learn by heart very few points, but these points if you remember, I can guarantee
that you will be able to spot immediately the remedy.
Just remember it's not only one point. You have to combine three points of the remedy. 1,2,3 at least.
Sweat on the back of head and cervical region during sleep. Very good symptom for children who are perspiring
in this area cervical area and their pillow, you go in the night, in the child and you see the pillow is wet.
90% of the cases, this is a Calc. child. Just because he sweats around this area.
If there is a patient, I tell you another secret, who has strong desire for sweets and desire for soft
boiled eggs
these two things most probably you solved the case of cancer, he has a cancer, whatever.
This combination makes a case of Calc. If you ask a question like this, the next question that you will ask is what?
What do you like to eat? I love sweets and also I love soft boiled eggs. You said, thank God I finished the case.
But before I finished the case, I put one question. What will be this question?
It will be whether it is perspiring here. In the night during sleep, do you perspire? Yes. Where? Here. They will show here.
If they don't have this, then the next question is how do you react to the cold?
Calc. must say, I don't like cold.
Ok thank you. Calc., go.
You don't believe because I have been teaching, ok you have to take the case. I will teach you how to take the case.
I have asked one doctor from the center, in Thursday morning, they will teach you how to take the case, what to ask etc.
But if you don't know these points, you will be lost.
It doesn't matter how well you can take a case. These points are invaluable.
If you manage to remember them,
you'll be fantastic prescribers.
You will see no remedy looks like the other. So immediately you short out the situation.
Immediately you say, ok a lot of perspiration. Where? In the whole body.
Immediately your mind goes Tuberculinum, Ferrum, Sambucus.
You know these remedies are perspiring a lot. Perspire here, Calc., Lachesis, Phosphoric acid.
Unless you know this, you are lost in so many questions that we can ask a human being  in order to find the key.
And the key here it might be despair of recovery.
You ask, you ask and you're not knowing where you are going and suddenly the patient comes out with the idea
'forget about my case, I know I'm incurable'.
You are thinking of Calc., it is confirmed by this expression of the patient.
-But a very young baby, how do you prescribe? Is it true that a very big proportion of babies, a very big proportion of us
at the beginning of our life, are Calc.?
-Yes, and there is an explanation for that, I will tell you.
The baby needs a lot of Calcium to build up the skeleton.
It needs food from which to take easily Calcium, to build up the skeleton. What is this food?
Soft boiled eggs. So the baby what you give it, what he likes, soft boiled eggs. He likes it very much.
Perspires here, Calc. These two things, never mind what the baby has. The baby has upset in the stomach
it has diarrhea, it has an eczema, whatever. Just these two questions. You short it out in the baby.
And the babies usually need the Calc. because the Calcium is disturbed primarily.
They cannot absorb it and they have problems. The organism starts crying out. Give me Calcium, give me more soft eggs.
I need more and more. Never mind how much you give, they need more, why? Because they cannot absorb it.
You give Calc. and everything falls into place.
- Is it right that the metabolism would function better after Calc. in such a case?
-Yes. Metabolism also yes.
-Do you have the experience that a flabby child will become a small, tall after this remedy?
-Yes. Not immediately. Not after a week but as he grows up, you see the change.
There are things that you cannot expect to correct immediately. You have to wait quite a lot.
Also you don't change remedies.
Discontent is the key word for Calc-p.
A person who needs Calc-p. must be  discontent person.
Calc-p. from children to grown ups, they are discontent. The children will cry.
You say, what is wrong with you. They don't know.
They can drive the parents crazy.
This is one and the second keynote is an aggravation from weather. When there is cold and wet.
Especially this comes when there is the time when the snow melts; that period is very very bad for Calc-p.
They become full of pains, full of arthritic conditions and complaining all the time during such a period.
Complaining and moaning. In the night for instance you will hear if you sleep with somebody, they moan.
As if they are in deep pain. They sleep deeply, they cannot wake up easily and they moan.
There is always this attitude of I do not feel well but they do not know what is wrong with them.
You will never get a Calc-p. child to tell you what is wrong with him, whether he has pain, headache etc.
And another characteristic for Calc-p. is that they will get headaches, if they push themselves to study.
They don't want to study, they are not up to the point of study. They push themselves, especially the children, the mother
the father push them to study and they apply themselves and they try and here they come with a headache.
So children who go to school and start with headaches, usually they will need Calc-p.
Also it has an effect on the fontanelles. Where they remain open for long period of time.
Fontanelles remain open and they are soft.
You touch them here and still it's not closed.
They are 2 years old and it is not closed properly; that is a sign of Calc-p.
There is another point which is very strong in Calc-p., which is the sighing.
It is similar to Ignatia, that we'll learn later on, but does not come because of grief.
It comes because of a kind of difficulty in taking a deep breath.
It is organic; in Ignatia it is emotional, stress and grief that brings this difficulty. In Calc-p. is organic.
So there is a discontent individual, sighing, moaning. Children moan much more and then it is strange
that this remedy wants to go away and feel better when they go away from the place where they live.
Travelling, desires to travel. People who feel happy only if they travel. And they enjoy only the changes.
There is another remedy also which desires to travel, which is Tuberculinum, but for another reason.
I don't want to mix it now. I want you to establish yourself in the discontent, in the sighing, in the moaning.
No satisfaction, no joy for life and then the only outlet is to leave the place and travel and go and see other places.
That idea is quite strong.
There are individuals who are quite duty bound, that means Calc-p. wants to finish her studies.
Even if she is not up to the point, she wants to finish her studies, to do her homework. Therefore she's pushing herself
and therefore she's getting the headaches. Studying makes the headaches come.
Another point is the stiffness which comes on the cervical region.
Stiffness on cervical region is characteristic. We see people who are doing all the time this.
And then they go to climates where it's cold and wet and becomes very stiff and the mind seems to be
stuffed up and they are not happy.
The mind is dull and stuffy. It seems as if by contracting the muscles here, it prevents the circulation on the head.
That feeling again comes.
On the contrary they can be quite well and happy in an environment where it's warm and dry.
Though it comes from the Calcarea family, does not have much with Calcarea apart from aggravation from cold and wet.
Otherwise they are not obese, usually they are people who are quite lean and their desires are totally different
than the desires of Calc. We said, the desires are for Calc. sweets and eggs.
Here in Calc-p. they need something more tasty and especially they like smoked meat.
You will see Causticum, it's another remedy we shall be talking soon, it has similar symptomatology
but great difference in the weather reaction.
Also very frequently you will see scoliosis on the spine, why?
Because scoliosis comes when children are pushed to do things that they don't like.
And they are nice, soft children which are pushed to do or themselves feel that they must do certain things that they don't like.
So Calc-p. is one of those people who do something they don't like just because they have to do it.
And just because they have to do it, here comes the stiffness. They feel the responsibilities which they have and it is too much for them.
And then the stiffness appears here. Strange symptoms of strange human beings.
I have to make an observation.
The discontent on the remedy is because of no reason; there is no reason.
You say the child everything is ok, why you are like this?
There is no reason. But if the child loses his mother he will be discontent because his mother left him
and is gone for 20 days away. That is not a symptom. The symptoms is, without reason.
If you lose somebody and you cry is not a symptom.
Children are forced by themselves, by their sense of duty they are forced to do certain things.
'I have to do it. The mother says, I have to do it'. They are duty bound they can force themselves to study;
they will sit down and study quite a lot though they don't feel like doing it.
Because they are already in a state of discontent. If they do it, they develop headaches.
And these are the children that they will develop headaches every day.
From the moment they start the school, they have headaches. The school stops, the headaches stop.
Also if they are in the school and they do not study, they don't get headaches.
Everybody is to be blamed because we are living in an environment and everything that happens, can have an effect.
But we get the end result of all this. So usually when the parents will telephone you about the child, about a Calc-p. child
they will be totally out of their mind. They telephone you and say, 'what can I do with this child?
I don't know what is wrong. I ask him and all the time from morning till night is moaning and groaning'.
I've seen a case where the father took the child at 3 o'clock in the morning, out on the streets, to try to calm him down
because he was crying and moaning and living in an apartment, it was disturbing the neighbors.
So he took him at 3 o'clock. He says, 'I don't know what to do with this child'. That kind of discontent.
When you hear this story then you say, that's Calc-p.
But then I tried to give you a little bit of insight into the remedy and I say, well also these children that are discontent
not all these children will be so discontent.
But they will have some other symptoms. What are the other symptoms that they may have.
When they push themselves to study by the parents, by themselves, they develop headaches.
And what they want to do? They want to go in a warm, dry climate. And what else they want to do? They want to travel.
They want to change the place because they are not happy; they feel in the environment which they live, they are not happy.
So it seems the same with Ignatia. Ignatia who is also sighing, wants to travel. You get a colitis, even ulcerative colitis.
Ulcerative colitis in Ignatia. And they say, if I take the plane and I go, the moment I arrive in the new place, my colitis stops.
This is a symptom. You will hear these extreme things seldom but then you have a very strong symptom.
Now Calc-p. they will not say that. They say, I like to travel, I like to see but they are not better from travelling.
You see the difference?
They have desire to travel and they feel psychologically only that they are having some kind of enjoyment.
Otherwise there is lack of joy.
Complaining.
You say, what do you want?
If you see, there are other remedies that will react differently.
-I want to come back to my point. Would you say that psychologically there was not a good enough mother
or children may be born like that or you cannot say exactly this side or the other side?
-We cannot separate, neither we can blame the parents at these cases. At least to my understanding I have not seen it.
Because you give the remedy and the child becomes normal and everybody is happy. The parents and the child.
So I cannot say the child came to that position because the parents were mistreating the child or misguiding the child
or doing something to the child. I have not seen this because once they get the Calc-p. they come back
and all the family is happy.
-Can the headache be a chronic migraine or a periodically appearing migraine or it has to be directly and after the exertion?
-It has to be aggravated. Let us it's a chronic headache but it must be aggravated after studying.
That means using your eyes and your brain.
-It has to be mental exertion?
-Mental exertion.
But if there is mental exertion in general, I mean you run and then you have a headache because you run, this is different.
This is Calc.
-Fulfilling household duties?
-Yes, fulfilling household duties Calc.
The Calc-p. has to have this mental exertion together with study. Then we have the real symptoms of Calc-p.
Now the Calc-s. is a remedy you will need in cases where you will have situations where you have suppuration.
That means an inflammation which suppurates and keeps on discharging.
Whether this is an otitis, whether it is a fistula in the anus, whether it is acne.
And it's discharging, discharging. The acne of Calc-p. is terrible to look, why?
Because it is full of acne here and it's discharging all the time. What happens?
They come out liquid and pus will form crusts. So at any time when you have a look it's all this crusts, all these discharges
which have come out and if she washes of course, then it stays for some time only the acne.
But after an hour, two hours, three hours then it becomes full of pus, dry pus and crust.
And the look is really ugly though the situation might not be as bad.
You remember I told you about a Professor who became my student and eventually he let me see his patient.
He opened the door like this and said, 'look this is the patient'. So I looked, I don't appear.
I see his face. He thought, you know, I was a magician, I just look and I know the remedy.
Because that was his experience, he thought I can do everything.
But in this particular case, I look and I see that face. It was a girl 28, 29. And then I said, what other symptoms.
He gives me some nonsense symptoms.
And then I said, ok give Calc-s.
The people who are breeding bees, they are the most healthy. And I have found again and again that this is true.
And almost all of them invariably, they let the bees sting them. They push the bee to sting them.
And they keep a very good health by doing that, why? They bring out to the surface all the reactions.
And I have found out they are all very sweet people, sweet natures, very human, very compassionate and very healthy.
-In Israel it's called "apiterapia" and it's by bees stings and we've seen cancer patients that are treated.
During chemotherapy in order to take it better, they come before and 30-40 stings done to them and then their cells
are reacting so much better. And the immune system is taking it easier and their vitality is better and better.
-I believe it. That's why I brought the wasps here.
I said something wrong. I told a lie.
So, as I said, he telephoned, I think one month later, because every month would see the patient.
He says, 'do you remember this patient with the acne?' I said yes, the Calc-s. case.
He thought it was unbelievable that I could remember the remedies but for me it was very simple because
I would connect one with the other. The pathology, 'do you remember the case with rhinitis?'
I said yes Hecla Lava, I would remember. He said, 'do you remember? Yes the Calc-s.'. 'I kissed her'.
So what he meant of course, you understand, the face was so clean that he kissed her.
Now this remedy goes a little bit further than discontent and becomes nasty.
It's a good word, I just found it, nasty.
And also very jealous and also a little bit malicious.
There is maliciousness, there is jealousy.
There is this kind of discharge which is coming out. The idea is, pus is coming out, just get the idea.
Pus is coming out all the time, on a psychological level it is the same thing.
We describe it as nastiness, maliciousness, jealousy.
It loses the discontent element. It goes to something else which is deeper and which is worse actually.
It is more on the destructive side and then if you close these discharges, then the state which we describe
the maliciousness, it's all the time oozing out ill emotions, bad emotions.
If you let the discharge go on, then these kind of emotions will be subsiding.
Here we have again another keynote which is desire for fruits which are green, not ripe.
Sour fruits, green fruits, unripe fruits like Medorrhinum.
-Calc-s., the pus has a certain smell to it?
-No, it's not specific smell. If there is a smell on the discharge, then we have another remedy. If it is very offensive
we have Psorinum, Graphites. Now of course it may have some smell, it may have all kind of other symptoms
but I say when these symptoms are present, think of Calc-s.
You said, when the discharge closes then the oozing becomes internal. Is it that in the beginning stages
when the oozing is outside, the internal oozing is not there?
I say yes, it might be there but as a potential. You close it and then it comes the psychological state, it comes more and more.
Every remedy has or may have symptoms on mental, emotional and physical. If the force of the disease is on the
physical body, the mental and emotional becomes free. For all remedies. The same with Calc-s.
So when we talk about mental or physical does not mean that you will find all the symptoms, mental and physical.
You may have only mental, only physical or you may have a combination. Some mental and some physical.
If I have a case with symptoms on the mental-emotional level, does that mean if I give a treatment
that the disease will invariably come on the skin or on the physical body?
Not invariably but many times it will pass through the body. That means you may have development
of bodily symptoms and finally you may have the appearance on the skin.
Not always because if the disturbance on the mental-emotional is not really deep, then you may just
eliminate this without passing through the physical body.
Sometimes you can see symptoms of Sulphur and Calc. and almost equally, symptoms belonging to Calc.
symptoms belonging to Sulphur and then you may combine. And sometimes it works, not always.
We go now to another remedy which is a contemporary remedy for the young.
For the pleasure of the young and see what happens if you use this remedy very frequently.
The provings show that people who are using this Cann-i. very frequently, they go into all kinds of delusions.
So people who are using a lot of Cann-i., they develop a lot of delusions, all kinds of delusion.
You have a delusion, you name it, Cann-i. will have it.
So it confuses the mind actually while at the same time activating the mind.
It activates the mind and confuses it.
What happens in this case? What is the end result of such a state?
It's an individual who is thinking, thinking all the time but not in a coherent way.
Without clarity. With a lot of so called, creativity. He may have a lot of creative ideas, he may have a lot of
explanations why everything is happening. They find an explanation.
And the mind is very very creative but no coherence, no clarity. There is a confusion and in the end
they end up going into delusion. Delusional states.
Let's think of those people with this mind. The first thing that they feel is that they do not have control over their mind.
They lose the control over their mind. Just think for a moment that you may be losing control of your mind.
What will be the first fear that will develop within you? My mind goes by itself, I can't stop it. I'm getting crazy.
So under this condition, Cann-i. will present tremendous fear, tremendous panic, losing control and then losing their mind.
Therefore fear of insanity develops to such tremendous degree but they will not call it fear of insanity.
They will call it something different, losing control many times. At least in my experience, people say
'I feel I'm losing control'. What do you mean?In a panic state.
The panic state comes and they feel that they are going to lose control and something terrible will happen.
As I said in the beginning, we talked about the disconnectedness.
The Cann-i. state for a person who is sensitive to Cann-i., not if you take just one Cann-i. these things will happen.
But you have to be sensitive to it and you have to do it repeatedly.
Now if you do it, then you lose the connectedness and you have very easily disconnected
the etheric body from the physical body. And then they may feel that either they fly or they don't step down
or that one arm, for instance, is raising by itself. It's a terrifying experience because they cannot stop it.
The arm is raising, they feel my arm is going up, what is this? In a delusion state of course.
And that situation brings about such fear, such panic, I'm going crazy.
And that fastness of the mind, thinking, brings on another symptom, we see in other remedies
which is loquacity, extreme loquacity. It's a specific loquacity.
I will give you some differential diagnosis with Lachesis. Lachesis has a lot of loquacity and she starts like this:
You say, how are you? She comes there, what's your problem? And she says:
'all my life I have been suffering with headaches and flushes of heat. Also I have stomach problems
and shall I tell you the story? When I was in Thessaloniki I met somebody, he is the friend of a friend.
And we had to go for some period of time together and while we were travelling together, we met somebody
who was a known friend of my cousin.
So.... it goes on like this.
In the end you have no symptoms of course but you have this kind of going all around the world, all her life meeting people
talking to people and then jumping from one subject to another without any stop. In the end of one hour you say,
I had enough of your symptoms, Lachesis, go.
Next time she speaks a little bit less. Now Cann-i. also we says loquacity.
What kind of loquacity? It's totally different because you discuss with them. He brings the subject on Homeopathy
because you are a homeopath and he will make a nice theory of why the remedies are acting, what is the theoretical
basis of energy medicine and they have all kinds of explanation, how the remedy must be working.
'I think I have this feeling that the remedy must be affecting a level, rather the consciousness level I think.
And through that, it may affect your feelings. If the feelings are affected, then eventually you may have an effect
on the physical body but I'm not sure exactly about that'.
This is a loquacity, a theoretical, you say my God he has the answer for everything!
You can stay with him for hours and he will volunteer to give you his own opinion.
But in the end, the mind you feel is so confused!
He, himself, does not perceive. He will not say, my mind is confused.
You perceive that the mind is really confused. And he is theorizing and theorizing....
One case, he was describing why he was in that state and he attributed to the encounter he had with a woman.
And how the woman reacted and what he did and all the theory about the relation, the woman etc.
In the end you say, my God his mind is almost totally gone. There is also a very interesting element in them.
You do not feel, as we said in Calc-s., any sting, any hardness.
There is a kind of an acceptance. You tell Cann-i. that I feel that Sirius, Sirius is a star, is ascending some influence on the planet
trying to raise the consciousness of the planet. It's a great theory for him, he will believe it immediately
that most probably it is like that or he will bring himself, another theory to explain to you how...
You understand the mentality of the person? He is believing, he is gullible. No critique.
That is why the new generation which has been raised up with Cann-i., is the generation that accepts everything.
You tell them anything and the mind is not critical at all. They say, why not, it may happen.
It's not impossible, don't be closed minded, this can happen, that can happen, everything can happen.
And you sit back and you say, my God there is no critical mind? It breaks the critical faculty of the mind.
Cann-i. breaks the critical faculty of the mind.
He talks and talks and theories and you see behind there is no critique to say, what the hell I'm talking about?
There is no such a thing.
Where you have other remedies, they are very critical of course.
-The Cannabis will be mostly indicated to people that have been taking hashish in the youth?
-Many times yes.
-Would you give it to somebody that never took hashish?
-Yes, definitely.
Greeks by the time I was practicing back in 1970 where most of the American youth has tried Cann-i.
on a percentage like 95%, Greeks youngsters, very, very few had used it by this time. Yet the remedy was indicated
in spite of the fact, they never had Cann-i. themselves. But what I had observed all these years
is that people who used Cann-i. in a kind of regular way, they became not actually confused but there is
no clearness in their mind anymore. Even if they have stopped taking the drug 10 years ago.
So the young generation has to be careful.
Because it's not as simple as you think it is.
-To treat somebody with chronic Cann-i. intoxication, wouldn't that be isopathy if you give them
Cann-i. as a homeopathic remedy?
-No. You see isopathy in Homeopathy is just words. If you use, in a mechanical way, the substance
that produced some situation, this is isopathy and this is not correct.
But if the symptoms of Cann-i. are there after Cann-i., then you give Cann-i..
But you can take Cann-i. and you develop symptoms of Pulsatilla. You can take Cann-i. and develop symptoms of Calc.
You can take Cann-i. and develop symptoms of Mancinella. Different remedies.
But if you take Cann-i. and develop symptoms of Cann-i. then it's homeopathic, it's not isopathic.
Because the symptoms of the remedy are there. Is it clear?
-No, it's not clear. I expected the symptoms to disappear when I gave Cann-i. as a remedy.
-When to give Cann-i.? When you have that picture.
-When I have that picture and I give the remedy ...
-Then you can give the remedy Cann-i whether the person has taken Cann-i. or not.
But not because somebody has taken Cann-i., not because of that you just go and give Cann-i.
Because Cann-i. may have produced a state of Gelsemium, not Cann-i.
-I can just say the background. I have several toxicomanes, heroin addicted patients and some of them have the picture
of Cann-i. And I never dared to treat them as Cann-i. as homeopathic remedy. Because it was isopahy.
-You can. Sure you can. If they have that picture it doesn't matter if they are from heroin or cocaine or whatever.
Because all these are hallucinogenic drugs.