The remedies are like every living being.
Starts with an ovum and a fertilization.
A little bit of information, everything seems the same. Eventually develops more and more.
Then we have a certain period when we have information on symptomatology. We just have some symptoms.
Then these symptoms as we get experienced more and more, these flat symptoms develop into a living pathological entity.
And this is the final stage in the development of a remedy.
So Phos. is one of those remedies which we know quite a lot about and we have almost the final picture of its pathology.
And what is this final picture of the pathology of Phos.?
They are individuals who have opened up, they have been opened.
And if you open a box with different things, they are just spilled out all the things inside the box.
The Phos. is the individual who has no box, no protection, no skin to retain within the skin everything else.
The soul is coming out, the blood is oozing out. The soul is out.
And the mind also is out.
So what is this openess? They are open to receive impressions without the ability to resist.
If I...shout!
Each one received this shock in a different manner.
Some they did not even move. Some they moved a little bit. Some they did like this and some, 'ah! what it was that?'
Those who are Phos. indeed, the mind is out, is there. We've been talking on the first about the mental emotional body.
In the Phos. cases it comes out. It's like hovering outside of the body.
And when there is a shock outside, it comes back. That is what it says, startling easily.
It is this idea with Phos. which the mind is diffused outside. The feelings are diffused.
If the feelings come out and somebody is suffering, immediately they pick up the suffering from the person who suffers.
And they suffer themselves. It says sympathetic but actually what kind of sympathetic?
That person who has this tendency to come out and see 'what happens? Oh you suffer!'.
They do not have a resistance. Suffering goes right through to them.
They see suffering and they move it inside and they, themselves are suffering.
The same thing with thunderstorms. 'Fear of thunderstorms'. Phos. is like this, 'what's going to happen?'.
Eventually it says, 'something is going to happen'.
'Something bad is going to happen' and then it becomes strong anxiety; fear that something will happen.
Something will happen which has to do with what? It has to do with suffering either of himself or of others.
It's not fear that something will happen like an earthquake, like planetary catastrophe. These are other remedies which have this.
The anxiety and the fear of Phos. comes when they come into contact with suffering. They cannot tolerate suffering.
This is the main characteristic on the mental emotional level of Phos.
So Phos. are people who perceive easily the feelings of the others; because they are open.
They have no protection. Whatever you feel, they feel. Whatever you think sometimes, they think.
Sometimes they perceive the thoughts of others because they are so open.
And you say, this is a nice quality. It's not because this creates a suffering within the individual
which is sometimes unbearable. They cannot tolerate such strong suffering.
And of course they are good listeners because they will say 'what did you say, this happens to you? Tell me!'
They come to you as a doctor, he is the patient. He sees that today you don't feel well. He says 'do you have any problem?'
'Yes'. 'What it is?'. And then he starts examining the doctor. What's the problem with the doctor
he has to do something with this person who is suffering in front of him.
This is a little bit of exaggeration but this is the type that you will meet. A typical Phos. case.
They like to have somebody to talk to. These communicative people they have to have somebody.
It says 'desires company' in capital letters.The idea is that Phos. actually needs somebody to reassure him
that nothing bad is going to happen. What they do? They communicate, they talk with the idea that
their mind is taken away from their anxiety. The anxiety, the free floating anxiety is mostly about their own health
which is primary problem, and the anxiety about their loved ones. Their children, their wives, their husbands, mother, father.
If you get a Phos. case and the mother is sick, 'my God you have high blood pressure' and then the mother comes and says...
'what's happening? Stop, sit down', they will take care of the mother, they have to do something, why?
Because they themselves are suffering.
In the hospital you will see a case where they will say, please take me away from this room because this woman is suffering a lot.
Forget it, the Phos. cannot stay in that room. It's not possible but somebody else says OK.
So that is the structure of Phos., the sensitivities of the Phos. people.
They have anxiety about their health; the anxiety can be very hypochondriacal. With a little thing, this is cancer now.
This maybe cancer and then it is the type of the patient who will go to the doctor and he will be influenced by the doctor.
The doctor will say, no this is nothing, don't worry, you don't have cancer.
They calm down, they go away. Next day, two days later again they start but for a period of time
they are better with the evaluation of the doctor who says 'there is no problem with you'.
It is not the same with other remedies so you have to start according to the information you have already.
You have to compare this kind of anxiety with the anxiety of ....
Agar., Ars., Kali-ars. But you see the difference there.
You see the Ars. will be very critical to what you say. They don't believe you.
An Ars. comes there with an anxiety about their health, with fear of cancer, with fear of something is wrong with them
and you say to them, 'no problem, nothing'. They will not believe you. They will go and check it out, take examinations
go to another two doctors to see whether they have the same opinion. It is different.
The reaction is different, the presence of the people in front of you are different.
You see the openess. It's very nice to have Phos. because they are concerned about you.
Sometimes you give the wrong remedy, you don't recognize a Phos. case, you give Nit-ac.
They come and they want to say that they are better. They want to please because they will cause pain to you
if they say, 'I'm the same'. The Ars. or the Nit-ac. they are better. They will come there and say, 'I think I am the same'.
And unless you understand then you will be misguided to believe that they are the same or they are not the same.
On the contrary, the Phos. will say, I'm better. And you examine symptom by symptom and you don't see
much difference you say this is not better really. This is most probably a case of Phos.
The peculiar thing you have on the physical level, what you will need except of this oozing out, diffusion
bleeding easily, the blood is spilled out very naturally. The nose opens just for no reason. It runs blood.
The woman has metrorrhagias, the blood goes out.
Usually the days of the menses for a Phos. case are more than 5 and full of blood.
You know the blood starts a little, then it goes to a peak and then it goes down. With the Phos. is a lot of blood.
Every time they lose a lot of blood. They have a polypus, the polypus will bleed very easily.
So this bleeding on the physical level that we see, usually in the children. In the history of the children you ask
'this boy was bleeding in his first years?', 'Yes he was bleeding very much, we had to cauterize
the arteries and stop the bleeding by force.
Another characteristic that if you see then you think of Phos. is, except of the bleeding is
great thirst for cold water, big thirst. they drink a lot and the water has to be very cold. Why is this?
From physiology point of view? You have somebody who is bleeding from his stomach.
He has history of duodenal ulcer with a lot of bleedings, you think of Phos.
In order to stop the bleeding what do you order your patient to do? Cold drinks. Why?
Because it has to contract the arteries so the bleeding will be reduced.
Phos. by nature feels that he needs this coldness to sustain itself.
Another characteristic of Phos., we said the bleeding, we said the openness in the character, the desire for communication.
We said the sympathetic element, very much affected, then what else you need?
The fear on electrical changes of the atmosphere and the fear of thunderstorms. Extreme fear of thunderstorms,
grown ups they will go under the table. They will not be able to use their logical mind. The fear is overwhelming.
Also the Phos. cases have a specific sensitivity towards the change of the atmosphere.
Atmospheric changes when they are felt very much, they suffer a lot.
They call it the electrical changes in the atmosphere. That shows again the openess to the environment.
They are open to the influences of the environment.
Phos. has a similar symptom with Natrum Muriaticum. What it is?
Salt. They have a strong desire for salt. Fish also, correct.
Desire salt is one of the primary symptom, great thirst for cold water together with desire for salt makes for two remedies.
Nat-m and Phos. What is the difference?
The one is closed. Nothing affects Nat-m or at least they will not show it.
Phos. will be affected by everything on the environment and they will show it.
So it's not possible to confuse the one for the other.
Desire for fish also. Both these remedies have excessive desire for fish.
They have all these fears, these anxieties and what they want? They want to communicate, to go to a friend
and say in the telephone 'I have this and I have that' to talk about it. And they like to talk about their symptoms
they like therefore communication. And in this way they learn that they can communicate very easily.
As a result of this, Phos. cases communicate very easily, communicate with the opposite sex.
They have easily communication with the opposite sex. Where the Nat-m is very difficult to make a new approach.
For Phos., very easy. One girl left the Phos., next day Phos. has found another one. It's like this.
The Nat-m has a kind of love disappointment. It will take one year before it's over, two years.
For the Phos. a few days, a few weeks, it depends. Why? Because of this easy communication.
Another characteristic is the time of aggravation. It's the time that the sun goes down. Twilight.
And their great amelioration is after sleep.
Sleep makes them feel very good. It is like a medicine. It says, my medicine is to sleep.
Everything that they have after sleep it's gone and then of course as the day goes by, they have more and more problems.
And then in the twilight the anxiety rises and until they go to bed, they go to bed and sleep in 5 minutes.
And they go through the whole night sleeping very nicely, very peacefully and in the morning they wake up very refreshed.
This is one type of Phos. as we describe. But there is another type, the polarity. Another type of Phos.
which this sensitivity we have been talking about, sensitivity with the impressions, is so great
that eventually the Phos. may stay inside the house without being able to communicate with anybody
because they feel pain by communicating, by going out. It's a very severe state of border line insanity
where people will stay inside, without being able to communicate with anybody because they claim that 'if I go outside
to the supermarket to buy something, I see people suffering and I cannot stand it. If they talk to me,
I see they are suffering and I cannot stand it, so I stay in the house'.
So we have the opposite polarity where Phos. does not like company.
And also they will wake up in the morning unrefreshed.
In Phos. when the subconscious is not expressed, all these fears and they stay inside, they create a very
disturbed soul which wakes up in the morning very unrefreshed.
They see a lot of dreams, suffering through the subconscious, they wake up in the morning, they are terrible.
So you will find in the Repertory, 'sleep ameliorates': Phos. capital.
'Sleep aggravates', 'unrefreshed sleep': Phos. capital.
So it depends which type you are examining. And then you go to the main points and you ask about.
The suffering can be so much from the others that they cannot establish a relationship.
Of course the one type, the first type I'm talking about, sexually will feel what?
Very active, sexually active and easily aroused, easily performing but the other type, the closed type
is very difficult, almost impossible to have a contact.
I had one case, that she would be afraid so much - a woman of 35 - she could not have any sexual contact.
With the idea that she was afraid of the pain that she may experience by having sexual intercourse.
The same symptom, that symptom we have seen it also in another remedy we have talked about. Arnica, very good.
So in the study cases when we give you the symptoms, you just try to find which is...
You see the idea with Homeopathy always is to construct, out of the information, to construct this picture.
What picture are you constructing from this information? I construct a picture of Phos. or it doesn't look like Phos.