Cham. is a reactive remedy. Reaction immediately and the reaction is always a bad reaction.
Why? Because they feel the pain. The sense of pain for Cham. is very acute.
It seems that the organism does not produce the necessary opiates to calm down the pain.
You see some people can stand a lot of pain. And some others, less. Cham., the least.
The idea of pain makes them react.
And pain makes them also angry
it's much more than irritability. When you have a patient and the nurse goes to the patient and takes some tea
to the patient and the irritability is so much that he will find something wrong with the nurse to shout at her and throw a tantrum.
So the need is to express this irritability, this anger which is inside Cham.
The children are irritated in their gums when the teeth are coming out and are breaking through.
Some of the Cham. cases, they cry day and night, they don't know what is wrong with them and the only thing
that can calm them down is to take the child and carry it.
For the child this works like magic for Cham.
You have to move the child like this and walk. This calms them down, why?
We don't know the physiology, you can theorize. But we're interested in the fact. This is happening?
Yes, it's Cham. The mother will say, I have to take the child in my lap and walk around, lullaby it. It calms down.
You put it down, ouahh...
Very good translator!
-Not a question but a contribution. It has been demonstrated that rhythmic motions of the body produce an increase
of endorphins. This has been shown in mentally retarded.
You know that the Sufis have special rhythmic dances which they do before meditation or instead of meditation.
Most probably they have done the research and found out that this rhythmic movement produces it.
In the same way, you may say the rhythmic movement of the mind.
In the Greek Orthodox church when they pray, they say the prayer of the heart.
The prayer of the heart is the repetition of a specific phrase.
And then you can see in the teachings of other religions and especially in the Indian religions also they have the japa
the repetition of sacred words.
And most probably this rhythmic movement of the mind, it calms down the mind and more opiates are produced
and then the state of ecstasy comes. The state in which the individual feels really in contact with the higher forces
intelligence, God, whatever they do call it. It's very interesting contribution, thank you.
Is this a research done in a hospital?
-It's a research that was conducted with mentally retarded people because they do a lot of stereotypic movements
shaking the upper body by themselves.
- So it reduces, Hell. reduces most probably the level of anxiety by doing this.
-It is as well being researched in marathon, in jogging people, in a big study.
It's the same that the endorphin production goes up very high.
-But marathon runners do they do some repetition of words? I want to win, I want to win.
-Some of them run 100 km, it's a rhythm.
-Oh, the rhythmic movement by itself.
Also with Sepia, this can be explained by Sepia that needs a specific movement to feel better on which we shall be talking about.
Dissatisfaction is not the right world. They have dissatisfaction and malicious at the same time.
They are malicious, irritable, dissatisfied together. Nasty they are very nasty and strangely behaving.
Cham. persons will not be satisfied even for 5 minutes the whole day. There is something wrong all the time
and they have to express it, and they find the least reason to express and to explode.
So you see this peculiarity, how it is expressed in the face. It says, the one cheek is red and the other is pale.
The one is hot and the other is cold.
This is a peculiar symptom. One ear is red and the other is not.
Which is the other remedy which has also great sensitivity to pain? Hepar Sulphur.
Which is the remedy which feels least the pain? Opium.
You see Opium is heavy, sleep, ecstasy all the time.
In Opium you may get conditions that you don't believe that the people don't feel pain.
-Seven years ago I had this very bad car accident and all the legs were destroyed and everything was fractured.
I didn't feel any pain, I thought I was paralyzed. There was no pain.
-For how long? For 1 hour?
-No, for 2 days but they gave me Opium right away.
They said I wouldn't have survived without Opium.
-They gave you Opium, that's why you did not feel pain?
-No, I didn't feel any pain after this accident.
-Before Opium.
-Yes. He came to visit me and he saw the situation, he gave me Opium right away. I was unconscious.
Two hours I was conscious and that time I didn't feel any pain.
-You were given homeopathic Opium high potency. I see.
I have seen cases where the skin has gone out, the whole body is a bed sore, when they lie in the same position
the Opium snoring.
You feel the opiates. You say, 'how do you feel?'. They say, 'good! and you see legs are broken and he says good?
Now the Cham. is exactly the opposite.
You get a little child, he has some eczema here on the neck or on the face or somewhere and you try to just put this.
He makes like this.
They do it before you touch them. You say, do you feel pain? He looks because he cannot say if he feels pain.
That is aversion to be touched.
Also Cham. will be the remedy for dental pains of any type as long as they are strong, they look like nerve pains
and they are aggravated with any change of the temperature of the mouth. Worse with cold or warm.
They cannot stand any temperature in the mouth. The pain is unbearable.
Arn. and Cham. have this smell of rotten eggs in the stool, in the mouth, in the saliva, in the discharges.
Have you ever smelt rotten egg?
Who has not smelt rotten egg? Only 4 people.
The smell of sulphuric acid yes.
You're treating a case of bronchitis and the aggravation comes 9 in the morning.
You will be thinking of Bry. and Cham. How you can differentiate? Very easily.
The one is very quiet, the other is very noisy.
A Bry. child, the mother will say, such a good girl. She sits there, she doesn't talk, she doesn't move.
For this child the mother says, this is a devil.
Hot sweat on head. The sweat is always hot unless it is very peculiar which the sweat is cold and we have the Calc.
Usually the sweat is hot. There is no sweat which is cold, unless it is Calc.
But if it is very hot then it is impressive.
Stools like hot chopped eggs and spinach  is the sum of the diarrhea that you may see in the small ones, in the small children.
So what you have to see is the sensitivity to pain, the total denial of communication. He doesn't want to be told
he doesn't want to be touched or interfered. They don't know what is wrong with them. You may give them something
they throw it out and at 9 o'clock aggravation, in the morning or evening, severe reaction to pain. This is Cham.
These are the basic things of Cham. You don't have to remember anything else.
You'll recognize the Cham. immediately if you remember just that.
For Cham. you go to the Materia Medica, you have pages and pages and pages of symptoms. How can you remember it?
-Can you please give me any differentiation in the emotional plane with Cina?
-The main differentiation is that Cina is not so sensitive to pain. Cina will not react because of the pain.
Cina is the idea of the worms eating you up, eating your nervous system,
like you have worms that are touching your nervous system. How you would feel? You will never feel at ease.
You will feel some kind of irritation in the nervous system that makes you react in such a way. Capriciousness.
It is not so much the anger. It's the capriciousness there, and the sensitivity to pain. This remedy can have big outburst of anger.
For Kali-bi. you have to remember its main characteristic, stickiness.
The mind, the emotions and the physical discharges. Whatever comes out it's sticky.
Thoughts are sticky. Sticky thoughts is when somebody is explaining to you something and it takes long time
he repeats all the time and it's a sticky person. And then feelings are sticky. The person is expressing feelings
and then you have the impression that you have enough. OK, what do you want?
They don't say, they keep on expressing emotions and love and thoughts which are sticky. It's very difficult to explain.
You know in the physical level what you will see is for instance the pus from a tumor. You try to open a tumor
and you take it out and you see the pus is coming out like this, in a cord. Like a hair.
The pus is sticky, the discharge from the nose is sticky. And then it goes down.
You vomit and there are sticky matters that they go down.
Unbelievably sticky.
I remember one of my teachers in India was BK Bose. By the time I was there he was 85 and he was a direct pupil of Kent.
That's why I went to the Calcutta college. He was teaching there just to meet him and hear what he has to say.
He had to say very little because he was 85. Don't come to learn from me, if I'm still alive.
He had that story where Kent was examining a case of gangrene, where it was quite progressed and he lifted
the matter like that and he said ok Kali-bi. 10M. Without asking any questions. He said this man with active gangrene
will take Kali-bi. and the case was cured.
We all have seen such cases, gangrene cases expecially. Some of them develop after severe diabetes
long standing diabetes, or because of infections. And the homeopathic remedies help very much in this condition.
Another interesting case that I remember is about myself. One time I got up in the middle of the night with
severe pain in the stomach and the tendency to vomit and to faint. I tried to go to the kitchen from the bedroom
in the meantime my wife woke up, but I realized I couldn't reach the kitchen and I came back and said to my wife
'don't worry, I will faint for half and hour'.
It was 2-3 in the morning and I thought that if I faint for few minutes and won't come back my wife will start calling
all kinds of doctors and ambulance and I didn't want any ambulance and any of the doctors to come and give me what?
You never know. I said I'll faint for half and hour. I calculated it's not possible to stay for half and hour.
If she waits for half an hour I will be back and I know what to do. So I fainted, and after a few minutes I came back
and then I asked for a basin to throw up. As I was throwing up this cord was appearing and I said to her
bring me Kali-bi. 10M. I took the Kali-bi. and in 2-3 minutes I was asleep. The whole incident was over.
It was a food poisoning. I'm prone to food poisoning because I don't pay any attention what I drink what I take.
I had it several times with Coca cola esp. if I combine it with mince meat, sauce. I get such poisonous
conditions that I have fainted several times. One of these times it was this one.
You see I have so many experiences myself apart from seeing the patient that I say, I live because of Homeopathy.
There is no question about that. That's why I devoted my time into teaching because if you would see
pictures of me when I was 20, I was looking very ill, I was very sick as a child. Not as a small child but after the war
because we did not have anything to eat. We grew up with eating spinach, without anything else.
Anyhow I was with bad health and one of these people programmed to live 30-40 years, so I got a lease of another 25 already.
I am outlaw.
Another keynote for Kali-bi. is pain in small spots.
You get a spot like this in the back. It says 'here, here'. It doesn't reflect or extend. It is very painful and in one point.
You get it wherever you may get this kind of pain localized without extension the first remedy is Kali-bi.
Now you get here the wrong impression.
The small spot pain doesn't move. But if you get arthritic pains, these pains they move, they go along like which other remedy?
Like Berb. and like also Puls. and like Form.
These are the main remedies that we have to be thinking so it's not a small spot which goes here and then here, no.
These small spot pains remain on one place usually. They are pressure on the roots of the nerves.
It's very severe and very persistent problem. The problems of Kali's in general are persistent problems, are deep problems.
And here also we have a remedy which combines symptoms of arthritis and rheumatoarthritic pains
together with skin eruptions. And alternation of skin eruption or suppression of skin eruption and then rheumatic pains
Dulcamara and also this remedy should be considered.
Cracking in joints, rheumatic pains in joints.
And also all the Kali's are remedies which affect the respiratory system.
Kali-bi. is one of the main remedies for uppermost part of the respiratory which is the sinuses.
Sinusitis whether it's frontal sinusitis
or maxillary sinusitis, especially if there is a lot of discharge; it doesn't have to be sticky  as long as it is a lot.
A key question is 'when do you have this discharge, in the morning, in the afternoon, in the evening?'
He says, 'anytime I blow my nose I have discharge'. This is a typical answer for Kali-bi.
You can understand they are feeling full of mucus in this area and their nose  is almost always blocked
with mucus and they have to blow, to open and so they can breathe.
-Do they have postnasal discharge?
-A lot of postnasal discharge and Kali-bi. are chronic cases.
The sinusitis eventually they have to operate.
You get this proper sinusitis, chronic sinusitis case where the sinuses always congested with a lot of pus inside.
You take the X-rays, you see the inflammation for years and years and they're going like this.
Eventually you say they have to be operated. Of course after a few years starts again.
The sinusitis doesn't stop because you are operated.
-I'm sorry I didn't quite catch about the small spot pains. Do you say that it's wrong what is written?
-No. In the way it's written it says, small spot pains which shift rapidly, this is wrong. The small spot stay
but there are other pains that shift from here, there, there, arthritic pains, rheumatic pains yes.
-Also these Kali-bi. people stick to the family, they never go on vacation alone. Do you have this experience?
-Yes this is true. They are people who stick with the partner, they are not people that will play around
they are serious people, lawyers, managers of the banks, the establishment.
They stick where is the best and they like to have the best. Best food, they like beer but if they do drink beer they have problems.
They have colitis, dyspnea. This remedy when we says it affects the respiratory, mostly the sinusitis, it doesn't mean
that you will find it only in sinusitis. You will find it also in chronic bronchitis, in asthmatic bronchitis, you will find all these conditions
and the aggravation of Kali-bi. which is in the middle of the night.
They wake up at 2-3-4 o'clock, dyspnea.
-I wish to ask you about this shifting of the spot pains.
-Shifting on the pointed pain is wrong, it doesn't move. The pain stays.
-My question is, I saw many cases from Geukens with such pains and they wander. One day in this place,
the other day in another place. Not quickly but they are wandering these pains in small spots.
They were also abdominal pains, different kind of pains, muscular pains and so on.
- Mostly muscular pains which can be moving. These small spot pains which I mean are pains which are due to
pressure on the roots of the nerve. And these pains stay there, they are not superficial pains. They are severe pains
that will stay in one spot. They are other kind of pains which are muscular, which are on the muscle
and which are possible to move around.
-Is there any color of the discharge of the sinusitis?
-The color of the discharge preferably is yellowish but not necessary.
Somebody was telling the other day concerning Hyper. He says, I did not give Hyper. because the pains were not shooting up.
No, you don't have to have all these conditions. You have a trauma on the peripheral nervous system, Hyper. is indicated.
Of course you have an inflammation here which shoots up the pain, also Hyper. is indicated.
Yes but it's not the only remedy which has spots. Oxalic acid also has small spot pains. But you have to have some kind
of confirmation, at least the second or the third symptom.
Hair-like sensation in the back of the tongue. This is also characteristic to another remedy and it is Sil.
A sensation that hair is stuck in the back of the tongue. It's almost a constant sensation.
Little things like that make big difference in your prescription.
Usually it is a cold remedy, so it is better with warm but not very warm. Ars. can stand a lot of warm and she will not object.
Desire for beer but worse from beer.
-Did you see also warm type of Kali-bi.?
-I can't remember now but it is not impossible if the other things are there. Just because the person
is aggravated a little bit from warm.
And don't forget, as I have said, that most of the cases they have several layers.
This is Kali-bi. Here is sinusitis and here also is rheumatic conditions. But the underlying remedy from this, is Sulphur.
And Sulphur symptom comes up while the whole picture looks like Kali-bi. you have a Sulphur symptom here.
He says, I'm warm. You give Kali-bi. and then what happens?
It takes away that picture but it stays there and then you see how strong it appears that symptom?
The underlying symptom that was popping up in the first place now it has become quite strong in the next layer.
That means you have done your job.
But if you have given Sulphur on the beginning, the second layer, forget it.
You aggravate the whole situation without bringing about a cure.
- I don't understand how it is aggravated in summer if it is a cold remedy?
-If it is a cold remedy of course in summer they will not say, I feel cold but you ask them, how you feel in comparison with others?
A cold remedy will describe to you that they are wearing a jacket when others are wearing only a shirt.
-The aggravation of Kali-bi. with its rheumatic pains can be during summer time?
If it is a cold remedy why do they have an aggravation on summer which is usually warm?
-Because the reason for the aggravation it can be exertion, it can be any other reason.
Also in asthmatic conditions it doesn't matter whether it's cold or winter or summer, they will continue having
the aggravation in 2,3, 4 o'clock in the morning.
The amelioration does not mean that the symptomatology goes away totally because of an amelioration.
It is a very relative issue, amelioration from drinking cold water. It is momentary amelioration. Amelioration of the cough
when you eat something. It is a momentary amelioration.
After a while cough starts again and continues.
And sometimes we have aggravations and ameliorations in a whole season. This is different. Aggravation during spring.
Aggravation during autumn. During winter.
Which is aggravation during winter?
Petroleum. Aggravation during winter the first remedy you are thinking is Petroleum.
-I had a patient 3 weeks ago who suffered from a strong sinusitis.
Since 2 months she could not breath through the nose anymore
and the doctor constantly prescribed antibiotics.
She had developed a strong itching because of the penicillin and came to me in this state.
Then she had this stringy discharge which was running down her throat
and I gave her Kali-bi. and we kept on talking  for a short while and after 10 minutes she said, wait a minute it's all gone.
I had seen her that night around 8 p.m. and after she took the remedy that night at about 2 in the morning
she woke up with a strong rash in the face.
She went to the hospital because she did not know what to do and they gave her cortisone.
I had given her a C30 diluted in water and after 2 days it was better with her sinusitis.
My question is, was this reaction due to Kali-bi.?
-Yes sure. It was a very good reaction and it was because of the Kali-bi.
-But she could not had developed some kind of shock?
-No shock under homeopathic remedy. The shock is there but it is curative, it's a curative shock.
She could have had a reaction with her bronchi, a reaction like dyspnea between 2-3 and still the reaction is curative.