Ipecacuanha, you will need mostly this remedy in asthma of children where you see easy vomiting.
They cough a little bit and they bring up vomiting.
Asthma which is mostly in the age between 7 and 12.
That is the action of this remedy but this is not all of course.
It has very impressive effect in cases after radiation. The people are nauseated all the time and they have
bad feeling with nausea and sometimes with vomiting.
In this case, Ip. will ease this situation without of course curing the cancer or curing the situation.
Also you use it in hemorrhage that is coming in gushes.
The blood does not run all the time, on the same speed.
Like vomiting. Vomiting which comes in gushes.
And then there is a big amount of blood coming out and then less amount. Then suddenly a little bit more and then less again.
These are cases where they look like Carb-v. case where they feel exhausted, they feel white with
tremendous feeling  of nausea as if the soul is coming out.
I don't know how many of you have been in the sea when it's rough and it affects you. Who is affected by the rough sea?
So all of you know the feeling. This is the feeling.
Yes you can take Ipecacuanha during that time and it can help you.
Whooping cough where the child loses breath and vomits. And all coughs which bring out vomiting very easily.
It's not all children who  cough that have vomiting. It's easy vomiting with coughing.
You see the child coughs a little bit and then it's vomiting. And it is because of coughing that the vomiting comes.
Because if the vomiting comes without coughing, just like that and especially if the vomiting in small children
is because of milk, it's another remedy.
Now here we have a symptom which is 'stomach feels relaxed as if hanging down'.
I'll give you a medicine because you laugh involuntarily. What is the remedy?
Cann-i. and then Ignatia and Nat-m.
Nervous laughing in serious conditions and she is laughing. Nat-m.
There is a kind of rigid, inflexible, duty bound and then fearful that a disease is coming soon.
There are two things that don't go together.
When the fear comes, they fear that a disease is coming. 'I feel my cells are degenerating.
My tissues of the body are not doing well and I'm going to be struck by a disease'. This is a fearful condition
that does not go with the duty bound, rigid, inflexible individual.
So what is happening here is when you have that state, you do not have this.
Once he breaks down, when these people with all the composure, they're composed people, who not break down easily.
But once they break down, then the most difficult thing for them is to face the degeneration of their organism.
They feel that the organism is degenerating fast and a disease is going to overcome.
Sleeplessness, this is very strange. This medicine that is so rigid and duty bound will have sleeplessness so much.
It's one of the main remedies for sleeplessness, especially if the sleep comes for a few hours, then no more sleep.
Or they stay awake for 2-3 hours, from 2 - 4, from 2 - 5 and by 5 o'clock they doze again.
It is like if they have a clock. They say, 'it is as if I have a clock in my body that wakes me up'.
They look at the time, it's 2.00, 2.05, 1.55 every night. And when they fall asleep, they can fall asleep 11.00, 11.30, 12.00.
Then around 2 o'clock they wake up. It's a biological clock that wakes up Kali-c. I have not understood why.
Most probably people who are duty bound they always have a sense that they have not done their duty.
And if you have that, something underneath eats you up in the subconscious. That you did not do your duty.
Many times they have come to me and have said that the hours that they sleep, actually they don't .They are half awake.
That's why I say, their sleep is very superficial. Actually what happens is not exactly like that. They don't realize that
certain hours they go very deep, ex. for half an hour, and so they are able to relax, regenerate and continue with their sleep.
But they will come mostly to be consulted for insomnia, for sleeplessness. The next thing they complain is asthmatic respiration.
Asthma, the lungs are affected. It's the weak point of Kali-c.
Again the asthmatic respiration is worse between 2 and 4.
And all the Kali's actually they have an aggravation around this time, between 2,3,4,5.
Depending on what type of a Kali it is.
Worse from coition, why?
Because all the Kali's are people tired in general. They are very tired and they suffer with weakness, exhaustion.
So having sexual intercourse, does not refresh them.
Actually it is a matter of biological reasons that somebody is not refreshed  he's unrefreshed after sex.
The sexual intercourse should normally refresh both.
They should feel both very well after sexual intercourse, as long as it is done properly.
Now you'll ask what is properly. I'm not going to talk about it.
We have little girls here. They will never come back again.
I once treated a man who, every time he would have sex, for 3 days he would be out of order.
He says, 'I need to have sex but if I have, I'm lying in bed totally'. He was a medical doctor, a black man, an American.
And his life was totally upside down.
Of course he was intellectual and he was thinking all kinds of things. With sex you don't have to think, you do it.
If you start thinking, you're going to be unrefreshed.
Because you are leaving your life to the hands of the other person. So you don't do it just like this, lightly, if you want to really enjoy it.
Kali-c. is a closed remedy, it's a closed person that does not give in, does not give himself up.
As I said, not all police officers get Kali-c. but I have seen that this type fits the picture.
The picture is always the disciplined one, the one whose mind is here and not on top of the head and people
who will not open up and joke with you and make laugh. They are quite serious, rigid.
And you will see the kidney problems is the third problem on which they suffer.
And that is why you will see like bags under the eyes.
If the kidneys are not working properly, you will start having these bags underneath.
More especially the Kali-c. have bags here on the inner angle of they eyelids.
They have two bags here and full bags here.
Pain in the back, worse turning in bed. What it means? It means that they will say, 'it is impossible for me to turn'.
But if they get up, they can walk, they can do. They go to lie down and they try to turn, impossible.
There is lumbago which usually extends down both the sciatic nerves. Not going right down to the ankles but on the thighs.
Asthmatic respiration also which is worse lying down, with the head low, forget it. Like another remedy, we talked about this.
Arsenicum, very good.
Now this one has the same and these people have to get up and either sit in that position
or that position.
This is also a remedy which looks like Medorrhinum in this position of amelioration, which is the knee-elbow position.
The knee-elbow position in asthma or in children, they sleep in this position
and this position ameliorates their state, whatever it may be.
If they have a colic, they sit like that. If they have asthma, they will sit like this. Especially the children but sometimes
you will see it in grown ups. And this is a position which is known with Medorrhinum.
-In the Repertory we have found 3 remedies in the rubric 'too much sense of duty'. Can you make some additions for us please?
-Which remedies? Aur. also is another remedy, duty bound. Nat-m., the Kali's, most of the Kali's.
Except of the Kali-bi. Kali-i.You have to be careful. This is not a symptom unless it is exaggerated.
It has to be really exaggerated the sense of duty. I have not done my duty. It has to be exaggerated
to be a symptom because normally we accept responsibility and we accept duty.
I have to teach never mind whether I'm tired or not tired, I come and teach. I accept this. I'm not sick because I accept this.
But if I go back home and I say, I didn't do well, I neglected, I should have been doing this and that and then I cannot sleep
then there is a possibility for me needing Kali-c. By the way I think maybe I need it.
-It's written in Allen, Kali-c. never give it in a fever.
-I disagree because Kali-c. you will need it in that situation with dyspnea, the pain etc. You will see in pneumonia
in the later stage of pneumonia especially if it has reached hepatisation where the lung is full of mucus and liquid
then you will need absolutely Kali-c. The problem is that this is a deep remedy, like Sulphur, Calcarea etc.
So if you give it wrongly, you may have some aggravation without the amelioration of course.
And that is why you will see some people writing these kind of observations.
Another observation for instance, I don't remember now where it's written, is don't give Lyc. 200
because it brings out big reactions. This is nonsense, it doesn't exist such a thing.
You give and if it brings out a reaction, it's the best. No problem.
Actually the reaction is not possible to be predicted by us in all cases. You expect some case
you have some reaction and you don't have and in another case there is a huge reaction which you don't expect.
But this can happen with every remedy, it's not only with Lycopodium 200.
Depends on susceptibility, pathology, how deep is the pathology.
In Kali-c. for instance, Kent has written don't give it in arthritis, if it is progressed. If it is there for years and you have
some deformities in the joints. If you already have deformities in the joints he says, be careful
because you can have a big reaction.
But later on we shall be talking about these big reactions and about reactions which can bring a kind of catastrophe.
Kent's idea was, in one of his observations, he said: if you give and there is a big reaction, the patient may go...
He says, if you give a high potency in an incurable case, you will have an aggravation and the person will die.
He said this but he said also something else which is in contradiction to this.
It's very good when you have a patient dying - in the chapter of euthanasia - you may be giving a high potency
and the person gets ameliorated for a certain period of time and he dies peacefully.
Do you see the contradiction? Both cases are incurable. In one case, you give a remedy and what you observe is
an amelioration, the pain subsides, the person is better and in 2-3 days he dies.
On the other case you give a remedy and he says, because the case is incurable you have a big reaction and then he dies.
So the truth is somewhere in the middle or a little bit different.
A propos of the observation, different things that have been said by different masters, teachers.
Even Kent, don't misunderstand me because what I know, I know from Kent and I respect Kent as nobody else, after Hahnemann.
But all we make mistakes. I say a few things which later on I find out post not exactly like this but different.
So what I found out is that the observation of Kent when you have a severe case and you give a high potency
you may have a big reaction. But this big reaction, does not mean that the person is going to die.
It means that during the time of reaction, the picture of another remedy is developing and if you see it
and you give it, the person will go to recover. That means you push the organism very strongly, the organism is giving now
a lot of symptoms. You observe, without losing your mind and then you will see another picture developing.
You give it and there is fantastic amelioration.
So when there is an homeopathic aggravation, not proving, then there is a possibility for a cure.
When we have incurable cases, we observe an immediate amelioration and then the degeneration
and then death, whatever. So in treating a terminal cancer case, what is your observation what it can be.
You give Ip. and there is better, 2,3,5 days, then the symptoms of Bry. appear. There is pain, cannot move
give Bry. better 3-5 days, the symptoms of Rhus-t. Give Rhus-t, 5 days, 6 days, 1 day, very short amelioration
and then another remedy and you can take this person to death, dying with amelioration, amelioration and then
of course death because the case is incurable.
Then we have the observation of Kent of euthanasia. He says, you want your patient to die in peace?
Give him a high dose of the indicated remedy and he will be sedated, will feel calm, his pains will calm down and he will die.
They don't die always with one remedy. You have to give a few remedies before they die. But still what
we say is that we can ameliorate the last part of the life of a person who is in really incurable situation.
And when you have dealt with such cases, you have seen the difference. How much better they die with Homeopathy than Allopathy.
The problem is that they don't believe us. They will say if they had allopathic medication, he would have lived
more or something like that. Which of course is according to our experience, is nonsense.
-I had a case with an old man, he had liver cancer and he came out of the hospital because they couldn't do anything anymore.
He couldn't eat anymore and he had this food what they give them. He was in a terrible condition and I gave him Ars.
and 5 minutes later he asked for ice cream. It took more than 3 weeks when he was at home and he got constipation
and Bry. state came out, I gave him Bry. In 5 minutes they took him to the toilet, he was sitting
on the toilet for 3 hours, everything came out.
And he lived another 3 days and had hallucinate and got to Opium state. I gave him Opium 200 and within 3 hours he slept.
-That's the experience I'm talking about.
This  information, what I have here is in every book of Materia Medica. It is not different.
I have especially taken care not to write anything new. So when you have it in your hands, it will be useless.
You have to hear what I say which makes it a whole. Otherwise these are just words.
Because I know what is going to happen.
You know the little book which is essences? The stolen essences. I taught Bill Gray, he was here and we were talking about
Materia Medica and he kept notes, then he left, he went back home. I said to him these notes are for you because
I'm going to write the Materia Medica and don't circulate this because this is not the whole thing.
Most probably he had also mistakes inside etc. He went in 3 months after he returned, the whole world
was reading papers, the stolen essences. In England they printed. It says written by fairies, gnomes and I was
in America in a Congress and as I went out with all the other people somebody comes and says, 'do you like this book?'
I look, it was typed written. I said, 'how much is this?'. He said '30 dollars' in 1983.
I said 30 dollars for this? He said, 'I don't know who wrote it'. It looks like mine. I said to Bill Gray 'I told you not to'...
He said,'they stole my apartment, they stole my notes'.
What is the idea with Lach. if you get a Lach. case?
She says, suppressed sexuality.
-Suffocation.
-Whatever discharge comes out, makes her better.
The idea is with this remedy we have a passion inside.
Strong emotions that reach a strong emotional state.
People that are easily roused emotionally, with little stimulation  there is the need to express.
It is absolutely necessary for this remedy to bring out the emotions, the discharges.
If this passionate condition is choked out somewhere, problems start.
It can be choked here like the Nat-m and then the constriction is felt here very much.
The constriction for Lach. is different than the constriction for Nat-m.
Nat-m. imposes a constriction upon himself. It says almost consciously, I'm not going to feel again this way.
Lach. says, I want to feel this way but I cannot and there is a push from inside but the constriction
is there and there is a lump and the lump is felt almost like a ball which goes up and down.
They swallow and the ball is there and it goes down and comes up again, the constriction is there.
Here they cannot even touch this area. This area has to be free all the time, forget the tie.
If she has to wear zivago she has to pull it all the time.
The feelings or the emotions which are not going out, create a state in which you have the pathology
which we call hypertension. Hypertension, the blood raises, the pressure in the blood raises and we have
typical idiopathic hypertension. In both men and women but especially with men.
Women are more prone to express the emotions, to speak.
Men they don't speak so much. The loquacity that we said  in Lach., we see it in 80% and only 20% in men.
Loquacity which is such that is changing from one subject to the other, jumping from one theme to another theme.
And then it comes all the time, she has to talk about it and the picture comes to the mind. What is the problem with you?
You ask one question the Lach. and the whole interview for 1 hour, she talks constantly without you realizing.
She jumps, she connects constantly the one subject with the other. The moment that she talks about her menses
she will remember that her niece also has a problem with her menses and also there was a friend....
And you are amazed, in the end you sit back, you don't say anything. You just say Lach.
They say, do you have everything? After an hour? I say yes of course we have everything.
She has not given any symptom, she has talked about all her family, the friends of the family
she has talked about how she felt when she was there.
And you just ask one symptom, tell me you sleep well? What happens? It's a characteristic of Lach.
There is an arrested respiration, as they sleep or they go to sleep, the vagus nerve paralyses for a second and the respiration totally stops.
Then there is a feeling that they cannot breath and they jump in a terrible terror while they are going into the sleep.
It's a terrifying for them experience, they know it very well and they will describe it to you very much.
Jealous, loquacious, left sided complains usually, not always, worse before and after night sleep.
Arrested respiration during sleep that makes her jump with terror. Impossible lying on left side and cannot tolerate tight collars.
Ameliorated by discharges when the flow of menses starts. Worse by suppressing the discharges.
So a very characteristic thing for Lach. is to suffer during night. The whole night they struggle and they battle
but especially when they fall asleep and when they come out of sleep. These two times is the worse.
And if somebody says 'I get up in the morning and I'm feeling terrible, I feel rotten as if there is no need why I should live'.
In the first hours of the morning they are very depressed and they don't like to live. Their loathing of life.
Depression in the morning, this is a Lach. state especially if they tell you that I have been lying only
on my right side as if I turn to my left, I have palpitation. They have to turn back to the right.
Tight clothes or tightness in general they cannot tolerate. Even touching makes them worse, in every pain.
They have a headache, you touch 'oh!'. They have a pain in sciatica, you don't touch. They don't like touching.
They like sometimes to press the head.
Mostly we will see in Lach. it starts on the left side and then goes to the right the problem.
The same as Mercurius-iodine-ruber.
Lach. can have a right sided headache mostly and mostly right sided sciatica. Why do we say left sided?
Because many times the heart is involved. And there is a fear of the heart but the heart is really involved in the pathology of Lach.
It's one place where there is the seat of emotions. We say symbolically is the seat of emotions. Why?
Because when you have emotions, the heart is pumping a lot, palpitations etc.
Lach. is an individual who is very egotistical, who wants everything for himself, 'I'm great', they feel they are important.
They feel that life owes them to feel well and if somebody else if living well, this is not fair. They don't like it.
There is this cramp in the heart, the heart feels there is pain and the pain extends
they have a problem and they have fear of heart disease.
Lach. is pathologically jealous to the extent that a woman she was describing about the husband how he felt.
The woman goes to the grocery shop to buy something. The Lach. will come out of the window and watch.
She is delaying, I know now they do it.
The imagination is so much that they imagine that definitely now she is having an affair with the grocery man.
If the woman is unlucky and somebody is before her or 2 people are before her to buy and then she comes 3rd in line, she had it.
Because she will be back and Lach.
will go into a rage, they will make a big scene.
'I know I have seen you before, you are flirting..' All this is imagination!
The woman telephones: I'm going to go shopping. The woman takes a friend and they go shopping, a girlfriend.
The Lach. will say 'wait a moment. She went out, she did not tell me that she was going out together;
so they went together and they did it. Because I know this woman is of loose morals.
So the other woman becomes of loose moral, the woman who promotes the other one, his wife, took her out...
Until the woman says, 'forget it. Let's separate. I cannot stand it anymore'.
Because when we say jealousy, we mean a pathological jealousy. Everyone who has live emotions
and is connected with somebody romantic, erotic etc, they bound to be jealous. If they are not jealous, they are not healthy.
That means the emotions are somewhat dead.
But jealousy comes with a reason. They have a reason, they see it, it's true. Sometimes you can foresee
what is going to follow and that is the normal jealousy.
I'm talking about that kind of jealousy which is totally crazy. Totally out of the mind.
Then we have jealousy which is like Lach. or Hyos. It has similar jealousy with more suspicious behind.
Another characteristic for Lach. is when the menses are going to come, just the day before when the organism
is pressing out the blood but the blood, the flow has not started, this time woman feels rotten.
The day before menses, forget it, they are irritable, dissatisfied, they are crying, weeping, sad, depressed.
The flow starts and everything goes away like a cloud, as if it was a cloud and it was lift.
I describe is as if I have menses.
Is Lach. a person who is sexual or asexual?
You can say sexual of course. He wants a lot of sex. They are easily excited.
And the children also they have the sexual instinct quite strong and this drives them to masturbation.
A lot of masturbation in children where it leaves them exhausted because the other state of Lach. is an exhaustion state.
Waves come, pain comes in waves, heat waves, flushes of heat. That's why it's indicated during the climacteric period for a woman.
Also you can find Lach. who is not loquacious at all.
She is very quiet, not speaking a lot, especially if a Lach. is having normal sex.
If her sexual life is normal, she will not
need to express so much through verbal.
It's the communication, once the energy of communication goes in a natural channel there is no need to express.
Once the suppression comes in a sexual level, then it starts talking, talking.
It's a replacement for sexual dissatisfaction or no satisfaction.
In Lach. we have actually a great remedy for contemporary people because we see a lot of high blood pressure cases
we see the suppression of the sexual energy is quite a lot in our societies.
As I said Lach. is passionate and can be hurt quite easily like Nat-m.
Not as much but they can be hurt and this time they withhold the sexual energy and then the blood pressure
goes high, the headaches start and they need to talk about.
-Do we always have jealousy in cases of Lach.?
-No, we don't always see jealousy. There are cases that they don't have jealousy at all. Actually they will tell you
I'm not jealous at all but the jealousy takes another form.
For instance, the woman is not satisfied and she always complain and find something to keep the attention of the husband.
They don't feel jealousy, these cases they don't even have loquacity, they don't have jealousy but the husband will say
'she never seems satisfied. She will always find a fault with me', she will always state as if
there is a subconscious jealousy where they don't allow the husband to act freely.
Always finding something to draw his attention until they drive them crazy. It's another form of jealousy.
You ask them and they say no.
Does she make a jealousy scene? They say no.
Where the expressive Lach. makes a jealousy scene. They cannot retain, hold back themselves.
The energy is so much that they will attack and they will be very vicious with their tongue and they will tell things
that hurt and things which are totally crazy.
-What is the difference of jealousy in Anac. and the jealousy of Lach.?
-If the synthesis has Anac. in the same degree as Lach., is wrong.
Jealousy is not a big symptom of Anacardium.
Nux-v., Gal-ac also has jealousy quite strongly. Calc-s. you may raise it because originally in Kent's Repertory
either was not there or was first degree. You can raise it to the second degree.
Calc-s. has strong jealousy but Anac. no.