.d like to talk about Lac-c. I will give you some information about Lac-c.
What makes Lac-c. unique remedy, you see with our Materia Medica what we have to understand is that what is important, what is unique in every remedy.
Because if you take it literally, every remedy almost will have the same symptoms. And there is the emphasis and the accent on one part or another that makes the picture.
So what makes Lac-c. unique are 3 things.
The person usually has fears about snakes, spiders but fears which are tremendously strong.
He or she fears that snakes are inside her or the place is full of snakes. Dreams of snakes, delusions of snakes.
Emphasis on that point makes Lac-c. unique. If you see such a case then you don't need almost anything else. There is no other remedy that has this strong fear, delusion, sense of being surrounded by snakes.
Children will be terrified. Grown ups will say that we cannot see a snake on a piece of paper. If you draw a snake it gives them the creeps. They see in television a snake, they cannot stand it. They will close it.
This is the idea of fear of snakes. The second most important element is that symptoms go from one side of the body to the other and they return back.
That means a headache which is one week on the right side, next week on the left side, third week on the right side again.
Pain on the breast which is on the left side, right side, left again. It alternates sides. If that is the pattern, that again makes a case of Lac-c.
The third most important thing is that they seem to have a kind of heat in the extremities. Hands, arms and soles are burning and are sensitive to touch, they don't want to touch.
Even the fingers in between them, they will keep them spread apart. The legs, keep them spread apart, they don't want to touch each other.
This heat with the aversion to be touched or the aggravation to being touched belongs again to Lac-c.
From these hints you have to understand the character. Do you understand somebody who says, 'snakes!'. What about snakes?. 'I feel that they are around'. What is the imagination?
Strong. They have a strong imagination. The idea of having strong imagination, imagining so vividly that snakes are around, that idea becomes important. And excitable.
They will stay in the night and will think about different things in their imagination and all that excitability will keep them awake. Sleeplessness from excitability.
Why? Because of the imagination. They have thoughts that torment them in the night and they are excitable.
They think about it and they get more excited and they think more. Then they cannot sleep.
And then this imagination which is strong will run very easily into delusions. And then during fevers we shall have delusions, which will be around
snakes, spiders, cockroaches, that kind of creepy animals that the Lac-c. patient cannot tolerate, cannot stand.
They are people who have a very low kind of esteem about themselves. They are lacking self confidence.
And many times we'll see confusion in the mind, a kind of forgetfulness, memory which is quite weak.
It is a mind which becomes tired, the memory becomes weak and they start forgetting. They usually forget when they go to buy something. Every time they buy something, almost every time this is the story as they say, I leave it to the shop.
They don't take it with them so they have to go and get it back. Now the memory is also weak in remembering words. When they write, the word will not come. They will write another word instead of the word that they want to write.
Or they want to use one word and they use another in speaking.
The concentration is difficult.
And with that state of mind, concentration difficult, imagination strong, memory weak, they have the sense that everybody else is looking down upon them.
They have the sense that the others put them down. You are not good. This is the sense they are getting about themselves concerning others.
They are people that because they don't have strong self confidence, they will get irritated easily. But irritability will never last. It will be over very quickly. Irritability which is over very quickly.
And then we have an element which is strange. When you find them in an acute state, they have gone through a fever, they are now over the most of the acute and now they are exhausted.
During that time the exhaustion is so great that they don't want to live. That is the time where Lac-c. has a loathing of life. They don't want to live.
But in their chronic states they have fear of death. Strong fear of death and they develop different fears like fear of death which is strong.
Fear of diseases and they have a similar fear with Phos. Fear that something bad will happen. But that something bad concerns mostly the health.
Fear of having brain damage.
Fear also of heart disease.
And then we have again fear of thunderstorm not as strong as in Phos. but still there is fear of thunderstorm. Fear of earthquakes.
This is information which comes from Greek cases mostly.
And fear of the dark but only when they are alone.
As the pathology progresses, they may go into a manic depressive state and in this manic state, they become quite malicious, nasty. Shouting, cursing in a rage.
They are quite strong in their expression of rage with a maliciousness, a hatred, nastiness and all these elements.
And then after that state they go into depression and during the depression state, they will feel lack of self confidence that everybody else puts them down, they mistrust themselves.
They, for themselves have the delusion that whatever they say is a lie.
And also the element that everybody is looking down upon them. That is quite strong.
In children we have easy delusion of snakes and fear of snakes very much and also we have another type of child that becomes mischievous.
Shrieking especially in night time and in sleep. They start easily and they are very aggressive and cursing.
So Lac-c. is a tired remedy that due to imagination they have, there is a kind of imagination which is very strong and a physical body which is weak.
As a result of that is that within imagination they want to undertake a lot of things. I'll do this and I'll do that. They make a project and they never go through the project. They don't have the energy to carry through the project.
In general we can say the organism seems weak and if they get a common cold, they may go into coma almost.
It's a comatose state, it's a state which resembles remedies like Muriatic acid. Very tired and they just don't want to live.
There is a despondency, a state of dissatisfaction of suffering and they just don't want to live.
Lac-c. is usually worse cold but I have found at times that they feel better in cold crispy weather.
When there is snow and the weather is cold and crispy, they feel at their best many times.
Another characteristic is during sleep, they sleep in a position
the one leg forms an angle and the other is straight.
Or they sleep in another position that makes them feel better. It's when they sleep they bring so much the knees to the face, they almost touches the face, curled.
In that very curled up position, they feel best.
And we have burning of the soles and burning of the feet and he sticks his feet out of covers. This is usual with Lac-c.. They don't want the covers to touch the feet. It's almost painful and they are burning.
Another characteristic is that if they have complete darkness in the room, they may have delusions. The darkness makes them have delusions.
And the delusions can be of different type but many times are delusions of bad looking faces that make face to them and they are terrified by looking.
With Lac-c. I have seen also a high cholesterol level with high blood pressure.
In such cases we have some kind of sensations going on which are not vertigo exactly. Like lying in bed and at the same time feeling that he is not lying, he is not resting in bed, he is kind of floating.
Also when they walk they don't feel that they walk and touch the ground. They have the delusion as if gliding through the ground, floating.
And during these floating sensations and this kind of feelings which are not grounded, then they develop fear of insanity.
Fear that they may be going crazy. In this respect they resemble Cannabis indica.
And the floating sensation is very strong also with Calcarea arsenicosa, with Lachesis also, with Mancinella.
With the headaches we said that the main characteristic is that the headache goes from one side to the other.
Whether the headache is on the side, on the forehead, on the occiput is one side and then the other side. One temple, the other temple, one eye, the other eye and back again. This is very characteristic.
The headaches are like Belladonna type of headaches, throbbing usually. Ferrum also has this type of headaches and Glonoinum.
And if you get this kind of headaches, that start from the midnight onwards, then it becomes a characteristic.
You see now here how we differentiate from one remedy to another, if the headache starts at 3 o'clock in the afternoon, it becomes Belladonna.
If the headache starts 12 o'clock in the midnight and continues, it becomes Lac-c. and it's the same type throbbing headache, one sided headache, on the right or left.
The only difference is when you observe the headaches over a period of time, you see the alternation usually.
And the alternation does not have to be exact, one time this, one time that side. It might be two times the one side and then again left and then again right.
But the pattern more or less what the patient will describe, will be that kind of alternation. It's not going to be exact.
One day right temple, after 7 days left. You don't expect to see such kind of accuracy. You will have to get the general idea of the patient.
We have words to explain. I'm trying to give you the idea of the remedy. Now 500 people maybe you understand in 500 different ways what I'm saying.
So when you see a patient you apply this knowledge which I'm giving you in one way or another and that's why videos become important.
Because I have noticed, I did not know, I thought that everybody recognizes once I have spoken of a remedy, he recognizes the remedy and says, OK this is the remedy.
But giving cases on video where I play videos back, I noticed that I go to the class, I say OK now, this can be a case of Nat-m? And the class will say yes.
And I say no, it cannot be, this is not a case of Nat-m. And then I realized that what I have described with words is not a real experience. The real experience is something different. That's why I say, don't stick with the words.
I said vivid imagination. Just apply that principle of vivid imagination, can you imagine, even try to imagine that there are snakes around you. You cannot.
But the Lac-c. believes that they are here. You say, here is a snake, he looks like that, if there is a snake there.
And he knows that you are bluffing  and still the idea is so strong. Now that becomes a symptom.
Headache which comes to the occiput and it is by the time he wakes up. Again it becomes a characteristic of Lac-c.
Pain on the occiput on waking. It is as if the whole night is building up, by the moment he wakes the pain is very severe. Then it becomes a keynote for Lac-c.
Also another keynote is if this pain extends in the forehead and becomes very important for Lac-c. like also Gels. and Sang.
With Sang. what it becomes important is that we usually vomit with such headache. They will get up, go and vomit and they will feel better. That case becomes now Sang.
With Gels. this kind of headache the eyes will be involved and they will feel really the heaviness in the eyelids. The heaviness in the eyelids will become prominent
and then it becomes characteristic of Gels. We say Gels. has heaviness in the eyelids. It is a paralytic state which continues, which carries on which seals Gels.,
the paralysis and then when it appears mostly the paralysis? You see in the eyelids and the eyelids drop. It would be nice if I could sleep now.
You will see one eyelid is paralytic and it is completely done and the legs also will be. Paralysis.
You see Lac-c. will has this headache and his feet will stick out of cover like Sang..
Sang. also will have this kind of occipital headache, extents to the forehead,  feet warm, sticks out of covers.
What is the differentiation point? The vomiting. Lac-c. will not have vomiting. Sang. will have vomiting and vomiting ameliorates.
Also Lac-c. can have a headache which may in one day alternate sides. It can start in the morning on the right and goes on the left in the noontime. By the evening it returns to the right.
Lac-c. will never vomit with a headache, it vomit but it will not be the usual thing. With Sang., it will vomit usually. Sometimes it will not vomit.
Sang. will have headaches but it will not vomit. There will be other characteristics to describe but we say as a main characteristic what is happening is this.
With Lac-c. we have severe photophobia, sensitivity to light, especially the light of the sun. They don't care about artificial light.
In the ears they have a keynote which is, sounds feel as they come from very far. They do not have the exact sensation from where the noise is coming.
In the nose we have coldness and also alternating discharge. One nostril and then the other.
The discharge is green, it is profused discharge. It looks like Kali-bi.
In Lac-c. you may have sometimes as they swallow, there is some kind of liquids that may go back into the nose, because of wrong peristalsis that happens and the liquids come back to the nose.
Obstruction in nostrils. Again one time, one nostril, the other time, the other nostril.
In the mouth we have a characteristic that sometimes food does not taste good for Lac-c. No food will taste good but only salty food. Salty food will taste OK.
And also fish is a good food for them.
Also we have a lot of cracking in the jaws as he eats the food, which is a characteristic of some other remedies like Nit-ac and Rhus-t.
Again in the throat the same idea, the left side, the right side, the left side.
Lac-c. is strong in pain in the throat on swallowing the saliva.
I give you only the keynotes. In desires, what we have is a keynote, strong desires about salt with Lac-c.
And desires also what kind of drinks? Warm drinks. These two keynotes, desires salt and warm drinks.
In the ovaries we have pains which again alternate sides.
There is a characteristic here which is a keynote, that pains in the ovaries are ameliorated by stretching back the body.
And we have also for the woman flatus from the vagina, initial flatus from the vagina which is characteristic in Lyc. also.
Lyc. and Ph-ac. also has that.
Pain in the uterus also that extents upwards.
We have an increase in the desire for sex and easy orgasm.
But usually they are exhausted after sex.
Different pains, back pains, pains that change place in the back easily. With sciatica we have alternating sides. Alternating pains from hip to hip.
This is all you have to remember, there are 3 things.
In reality there are certain principles. If you go to all Materia Medicas you will find the same things repeated in different ways.
You grasp the idea of the remedy and then when you see a case, you say now this is case of Lac-c.
You say some peculiarity is there. And then you see it. And then you recognize. That is how you can become good prescribers in Homeopathy.
It is not if you try to go to the letter in the Repertory and try to find a phrase that the patient says.
Life is something multifaceted, too many levels, too many facets. It's something moving all the time.
You can't have cans with human life, you see? There is a human being there and you cannot reduce it to one phrase.
You get a Lac-c. and he will not have this fear of snakes. The imagination will be there, he will not be able to sleep in the night,  the anxiety is there, the anxiety about others.
The fear of the disease, the fear that he will have brain stroke, the cholesterol level is high, the blood pressure is high and this is a Lac-c. case. And there is no alternation.
One time you will see the alternation, the other time you will see the fear of snakes, the imagination is stong. The other thing is the loathing of life. At the same time does not want to die, he is afraid to die.
What kind of dreams he sees? What does his dream?
Snakes.
We're talking about alternating sides. It has been observed that the Lac-c. can be one day worse in the morning and the next day is worse in the evening.
That means whatever he has, he has a pain in the hip which is one day worse in the morning, the next day worse in the evening and again.
That is the idea of alternation. You don't have to have it one side to the other but you have to have it moving in a regular way.