The Lyc. pathology is such that makes an individual to be open and extrovert and making a big appearance
but inwardly he feels not secure, he feels weak and especially when he is facing authorities in general.
They become coward. So you have this double face of the Lyc. where he will feel very much at ease and flamboyant
and making jokes, the big guy.
Those people who are a little bit older, do you remember Mussolini? He was the dictator who makes a big speech
and he was bloated always.
A lot of gas, like a balloon. There is no power behind.
And especially this appearance is in front of the other sex. A man who is a womanizer. Do you know what is a womanizer ?
Every woman falls for Lyc. This is the idea, this is what they love. They love the lack of responsibility.
They don't like to carry responsibility. Therefore they will act in such a way that their actions will carry no responsibility,
It's a men's remedy mostly. It's a man who loves very much to have one woman, one night and finish with her.
And then next time another woman, one night, two nights, no responsibility, no attachment, not real, deep relationship.
Not for Lyc. If it happens that they establish a relationship, they go into a family situation and then suddenly
they find themselves with a wife, two children and a lot of responsibilities.
They get really fearful inside and sometimes they leave even the family. Not all Lyc's leave the family but the idea is behind.
The idea that now I have so much, it will be too much for me.
So to have pleasure and not to have responsibility are important for them.
And that's why it is known to be the remedy
for men who are looking for one night stand.
They come to the office and you will see
them flirting with your secretary there.
You have your secretary, usually is a young woman and they will be flirting, making themselves very big
and what's your telephone number and I'm this big guy.
When they enter inside, they have totally different attitude. They are afraid, coward.
I remember a case. I suspected this is a case of Lyc. He was a short man and then I asked the question 'are you coward?'
He said, 'ah! I will tell you a story so you make your own decision if I am coward'.
He said, 'I was in the Greek army and they were the rebels, the Communists and we were fighting the rebels in the woods
and he would belong to the army. He says, at one point we were encircled by the Communists and all the battalion
was captured, except me. He says, 'do you know why?'.
He said, 'when we found out that we were encircled, we all rushed to get away
but we reached a place where there was a big ridge, a very big ridge, very deep and high, about 5 meters apart'.
He said, 'I had all the things we carry as a soldier and he says, can you imagine that I was the only one that out of fear
I jumped from one place. The fear was so much that was impossible for me to stay. I jumped, nobody else did.
I reached now the rest of the army and the colonel presented me, he said this is the hero who was not captured.
And I knew why I was not captured'. Just to give you an idea of the intensity of the cowardice, which is inside the Lyc.
But bloated the ego in front of the inferior. That's why I say dictator children who are dictators in their own house
they act like dictators. They go to school, what a nice boy. He never talks, he never does anything wrong.
He is very quite, he is very obedient. He goes back where he feels his power and then he becomes a dictator.
This remedy affects primarily the digestive system and affects the gallbladder and produces a lot of gas.
They wake up in the morning and they are bloated but their worse time is between 4 - 8 p.m.
This is a very well established symptom between 4 - 8 p.m. in the afternoon they feel rotten, they feel very bad
they feel low, depressed, bloated. They have no energy, they are irritable, they don't want to do anything
their mind is not working.
The lungs are going wrong this time, the liver is going wrong this time etc.
It says here impotency due to sexual excesses. You imagine this man who tries to have this kind of relationship.
What happens is that he does not find anymore excitement unless it is something new.
They cannot be excited anymore so in the end when they are 35 they are going to marry. 36, 37, 38 they decide to marry
and 3 months after marriage they are totally impotent.
Or they will come to you and say, for the last 5 years I'm married, I do not have proper sexual intercourse with my wife.
Though they make like their wife, they are nice together but they cannot be excited sexually due to the fact that
they have lived a life of superficial sex. Superficial sex is killing the desire and that's why the young people of today
very young people like 16,17,18,19, 20 they are impotent. Because of this reason.
The sexual liberation allowed this generation to play with sex too much. At the age of 12,13 the girl must have a boyfriend
at least in America. I don't know so much in Germany, probably not yet and Romania, you see she is feeling
very embarrassed.
In Romania you don't have this kind of things.
But 12,13,14 they start. By the age of 19 they have lived everything. They know everything. They are fatal woman
who doesn't care about anything.
In India on the contrary where man and woman are not allowed to have sex, 95% of the marriage, they stay.
Because they marry and for the first time the man the and woman have sex while they are married.
Such couples, such relationships are going to stay. But if one of them or two of them, have a lot of encounters before marriage
they come to Lyc. and there are some other remedies. Impotency, indifference, they cannot be excited anymore.
And the marriage is soon breaking down because each one tries to find a partner that will excite them again and again.
So Lyc. together with Staph. and Agnus Castus are the 3 main remedies for impotency actually.
For different reasons each one of them. Lyc. we said for what reason they are impotent.
Staph., when we speak about it I will tell why Staph. becomes impotent.
Premature ejaculation, loss of erection during coition.
Why premature ejaculation, do you understand?
Because we said he is a womanizer, he gets therefore excited very much, in the first, second encounter
and then he cannot hold and there is orgasm very soon, before even the sexual act.
It is a remedy which is hungry at night. It's not so much. Appetite increases while eating.
They sit down to eat, they eat a little bit and appetite is gone, that's one thing. Or they sit down to eat
no appetite and they start eating and appetite comes. So they have both.
Desire for sweets is quite strong and desire for warm drinks also is quite strong element for Lyc.
If you think he is a Lyc., for instance, and he says I have thirst for cold drinks, you think twice before you give it.
That point is quite important for Lyc.
Another thing is emaciation of upper part of the body, they are emaciating here very much, losing flesh.
The bottom part becomes big and especially the belly.
It's bloated, mostly air, balloon.
You saw these strong wrinkles in her forehead? Lyc. is one of the remedies you will think when you have this
special kind of worry that produces this kind of wrinkles. Another very characteristic thing is heels cracked.
The heels are dry and with big cracks without much pain. There is another remedy that has that, it's Calc-f.
One foot hot and the other cold, that is another peculiar symptom. In bed they touch the feet and one is cold the other is hot.
Very strange, they have it Puls. and Chel. also have that.
Impossible to sleep on left side like Lach. Lach. and Lyc. and Phos. cannot sleep on left side.
-Are there special worries that makes this kind of wrinkles in the forehead? Do you know that ?
-I don't know. You see in fever especially the nostrils go in and out.
-Now we learn the Chel. and the Lyc. Do you think is now the time to learn the differential diagnosis between them?
-You must tell me. Aversion to cold drinks. Aversion for cheese, sometimes is also desire. Sometimes in the remedies
you have polarities. For instance in Nat-m you have desire for salt and you have aversion to salt also.
So they get polarities. Sometimes I have seen Calc. with aversion to eggs.
It means disturbance of the calcium but taking a lot of calcium doesn't need more. It says, no, no calcium I don't need.
They have diarrhea and then they have constipation some other people.
Lyc. they need company. They are afraid of the dark, afraid to be alone in the house in the night, this cowardice.
The Israelis are correcting me, the Maltese are correcting me, the Germans are correcting me and here is the English
who is not correcting me. Let me hear it once from the original.
Cowardice. Did I say it correctly? Say it in the American way. Cowardice, but I will forget it.
If you get it wrongly from the beginning, forget it.
A man 45, 50 stays in the house even little children are gone and he is alone. The mother took the children
and they are gone and he is going to sleep in the night. The night comes and...my God!
There is nobody in the house. It's not only that they are afraid of some spooky things
they are also afraid of ghosts and things like that. But this is a feeling inside, I'm alone in the night.
Not in my house where I live in the wilderness where you cannot see any house all around, but on a flat, on an apartment, next door.
Even if there is a child inside, they feel secure.
As long as there is somebody in the next room, if the child is sleeping in the next room, they feel secure.
The moment they feel alone, that gives you the idea of cowardice.
Mostly they are afraid of the dark and being alone. They want company.
-You said it's mostly a men's remedy. I have two women Lyc. and they have fear of men, they are afraid of men.
-You see if you get a case like this or a case like that, special cases where women have been harassed
they have been raped, abused and things like that, especially these cases are terrible.
You cannot expect to have desire for men.
-I had a woman that it was so high, I put it in the computer 4 times, fear of men. She was very bloated and I gave her 200.
She said nothing changed and I said, we go to the computer again. I said, fear of men is still so high?
She said, no, no I have a boyfriend now. This is gone. In 4 weeks with Lyc.
-It is true that fear of men as you put fear of people, they are afraid of people. You have this symptom as a fear with Lyc.,
the same way as with Hyos., fear of people. But at the same time, they need somebody to rely upon, they have anxiety
about health, they are hypochondriacs. They can become so anxious about their health, totally hypochondriac.
Many times I have seen cases that they have much less symptoms than I have and they come to be treated.
I have a little pain in here, I say forget it. Live with this little pain here and there but the anxiety is so much that they cannot live
it just simply is impossible for them to exist with this little bit of something.
There are a lot of differences. First of all the Chel. does not have this fear at all. These fears I mentioned, are not there.
On the contrary they are people down the earth without fears, having gallbladder problems but no bloated.
The problem is more inflammations of the gallbladder than the amount of bile that goes into the guts.
Lyc. has a disturbance of the bile that is going into the colon and then you have the zymosis and then you have the bloatness.
With Chel. the effect is more on the gallbladder and the liver. They are not coward, they are not sexually driven.
Lyc. is sexually driven.
You cannot confuse them actually.
Lyc. after treatment is taking more responsibility or it will stay with that trait afterwards?
Yes he can take more responsibility. The fear is gone. Of course there is a special type of person who shuns responsibility
to such an extent that he will just, one day, leave everything behind and disappear.
That is not going to change his character so much but they attain more self confidence.
Underneath is a lack of self confidence. That the woman will say, bye, bye or that you are impotent or this or that.
The Magnesias, the Chel., the Lyc. are affecting the digestive system primarily.
The Magnesias in general are people who do not like controversy, who do not like fighting.
They are the peace movement people, peace under any price.
Mag-c. and Mag-m. have this trait.
We don't know how the gallbladder is affecting the guts. We say this person does not have guts
and the other day we say, he has gall, he has power.
Mag-c does not have. Another characteristic of this remedy is the body smells sour.
Another characteristic is that milk brings on diarrhea, makes the person worse, brings constipation, anything.
Milk passes undigested.
Forsaken feeling, feels as if not loved by parents.
Children who feel they are forsaken. That means my mother loves better my brother. My father loves better my sister.
Who believe that, but they will not make a scene about that, will not fight to gain a position in the heart of the parents.
No controversy.
A great characteristic is that coryza starts before menses, the nose starts running the eyes start running as if she has a cold.
Then the menses go away and it's finished. That is just before menses, during menses and then, well.
If you have that, it's very characteristic.
Menses flow more profusely at night.
While lying menses are flowing; when they are getting up and walk menses are retracting.
Craving for meat even in children is strong and aversion to vegetables.
They almost will say, 'never I eat vegetables, I'm not interested'.
Aversion to vegetables you think it's nothing but it's very important symptom because everybody eats vegetables
like vegetables. If you find somebody who will say 'I never eat vegetables', then immediately your mind goes to Mag-c.
Unrefreshed sleep is common to all Magnesias, to Lyc. as well, to Lach. and Phos. Especially unrefreshing sleep
is connected with misfunction of the liver. Misfunction of the liver makes you feel very unrefreshed in the morning.