In Theory you will be judged more than the Materia Medica.
All this you can find easily in the Repertory. You just turn the Repertory and you find it.
In Theory you saw what happened. He does not know the Theory, spoiled the case, now she is suffering. She would be a happy girl.
Though he knows Materia Medica. What he does not know, Theory.
And I have seen that many many good homeopaths, my students, spoiled their cases. Why?
Because they have not attended a full course, they don't know everything. That's why I say, ask questions
and make sure you understand a theoretical point. This is very important for me to feel secure that you are going
to be good in the future. In the future you will be learning Materia Medica every day, by feedback.
Theory you will never know unless you get it all in your mind.
Do I lecture from paper in Theory? Everything is a concrete thing and that has to be transferred in you.
So you are secure with this knowledge.
This remedy is a remedy who is weak in general. Weak in physical.
Also they try to avoid any kind of aggression.
If two people fight in a room, Mag-m. will try to pacify, 'please, please, don't fight'. They cannot stand the aggression.
Somebody else can enjoy. Tarentula. He will come and hit one or the other. It depends how is each remedy.
Lycopodium will run away. People react differently.
This will try to pacify. 'Please don't fight'. And there is also another characteristic thing with this remedy
that they feel they are getting old.
Never mind what age, 30, 35. 'I feel I'm getting old'. It's the weakness, this feeling, the liver is not working properly.
The digestion is not good and it takes the turn. Liver affection, hepatitis, jaundice.
There is another characteristic which is they're restless and anxiety or lying down and closing eyes.
He has to get up and walk.
You can imagine especially when the respiratory system is affected, there is a blockage in the nose and they cannot breathe.
They become very restless and they have to get up and walk.
The moment they lie down is very strange.
They lie down; the anxiety and the restlessness comes. And they have to get up and walk.
They walk, they calm down, they go and lie down, after a while again, anxiety and restlessness.
Unrefreshing sleep as we said in, diarrhea from milk, which is the same with Mag-c. Aversion to milk
and diarrhea from milk. Regular headache crisis with vomiting and thirst.
What do we mean by that? Regular headache crisis with vomiting and thirst?
This is a severe syndrome which this remedy has concerning headaches, which comes in batches. For instance for 2 months
the headaches come every 5,10 days. Every 10 days, severe headache which totally exhausts them.
They go to bed and they have to vomit 1-2 times and then it calms down. But during the headache it develops strong thirst.
This is very important for this remedy.
All the remedies actually which have the muriatic element are aggravated in the sea. Mur-ac., Nat-m., Mag-m.
Also infancy constipation during dentition. It's very strange that during dentition Cham. will do all this kind of things
which we know Cham. children are doing and these children develop constipation.
Who else cannot digest milk?
There is another remedy which is Aethusa which cannot digest milk and vomits the milk. This has diarrhea from milk.
Aethusa has vomiting in pieces, from milk. It becomes sour, like sour milk and then it comes out.
Med. is a very frequently indicated remedy in Greece.
I don't know in other countries but here is quite frequent. I have not seen it so much in other European countries.
They  are passionate people, passion for everything. Whatever they do, they do it with passion.
They breed animals, they have passion, they love them, they breed flowers. They do it with passion. They have boats,
fishing, it's a hobby for Med. They feel very well because they are in the sea and they are calm and fishing is very good.
The amelioration by the sea is not amelioration, I see the sea from here and I see it's beautiful. Not this.
The amelioration has to be when they go inside the sea and they have a headache, they have a pain, they have a colic
they go out of the sea and the pains are gone. This is amelioration from the sea.
Because there is nobody who does not like the sea. Who does not like to see the sea beautiful?
Then it's the opposite, then maybe he is sick.
Amelioration by the sea is with children with asthma for instance, they are suffering a lot, they come down to the sea
and the asthma disappears within 1,2 days. It's like strong medication. Children who have to take bronchodilators
to exist, Med. children, they can go to the sea and they feel totally cured.
That is amelioration from the sea and then we have the night people who are better in the evening.
We see it with students who cannot study during the day. During the day they are restless, they waste their time
and the evening comes and the mind is more clear, there is more energy more concentrated and they can work until
3, 4 o'clock in the morning. This is a remedy which is ameliorated from the sunset to 3 o'clock in the morning.
If somebody is ameliorated from 12 onwards  then it is Lycopodium.
You will mix this remedy with Lyc. because Lyc. feels better after 8, 9 o'clock, they start feeling better.
10 o'clock, 11 o'clock better but from 12 o'clock onwards they say I feel much better.
And they can work at 1,2,3. The same with Med. Students work, the homework they do, everything they do
in the night and they have an effect in the night.
If they sit down to work during the day, forget it. There is no effect.
See also the desires, the combination of salt, fat, ice cubes, sour fruit, oranges, unripe green fruits, sweet alcoholic drinks.
They can have this combination of desires.
If the sour fruit is missing, the unripe green fruit is missing, you start doubting.
People who like the fruits, green because it's sour, this is the best they say, that is a Med. case and also it is another remedy
which we spoke about, having desire Calc-s.
About 2% of the class remembers.
Med.  in their sexual life are oversexed, they like sex, they enjoy sex but their relationships are lasting as long as the passion lasts.
Then they are bored. They lose interest but this can last 3, 4 years.
How long a passion can last? Not more. According to statistics no more than 3 years.
Med. is a remedy that will keep up relationship with passion, the longest.
It may reach up to 4 years, 5 years together with Lach. Lach. also has that. Plat., on the other hand
while it's so sexual and wants sex all the time, the passion does not last, it has to change.
So these people are passionate people with a lot of emotions, they are extroverts and sometimes you have the opposite type
where you have a very introvert person who is not able to express anything, to say anything, to go out. They cannot go out
they cannot express, they are very introvert. And they have to drink alcohol before go out and buy something from the store.
Mostly they like sweet alcoholic drinks.
You know this 'liqueur' ? Who likes liqueur?
Liqueur because it's sweet it's liked by many people but it has to be really a desire.
These people cannot become easily alcoholics.
Because they are interested in sex so much that all the excitement and the energy goes there. They don't need to drink.
Shakespeare says the wine brings the desire but takes away the result.
Med's know that very well and they like to be sober when they have to do this kind of business.
What is interesting is that sometimes it takes the turn of life savior. They are extroverts and if it takes that turn
where the individual goes towards religion, the religious people that go with passion to religion and they want to do something,
they want to save the world and then they become healers. Because there is a lot of energy, they can become healers.
I have seen it in America where you have all these healers who are healing people. They gather and all of them
they pray together and then somebody gets better. This type is the Med. type.
No Verat. is different.
I had a case once with a retired general of the army. He comes there and I'm taking his case with a lady doctor, next to me.
He talks, he comes for his rhinitis. And we talk more to understand.
He tells me how much is involved with a group where he is the leader.
And then the idea comes to my mind that he is Med. And now I want to confirm, is he really Med.?
He is excited, he tells about his accomplishment, how people are healed. He heals the people
we help people, we're doing so much for the people.
I say, god when he is going to stop? He was bragging. In the Repertory we see 'egotistical', the ego is
very much promoted in Lach., in Plat., in Med.,
in Sulph. Egotistical people.
So he makes all this performance and he doesn't give me a chance to ask him a question.
I said, if I ask him now 'did you get gonorrhea?', with all this excitement he will say 'no, never'. So I think something else.
I say to myself if I put a question out to him totally unprotected, he will give me the right answer.
So I said to him, not 'did you get gonorrhea?' I said 'at what age did you get gonorrhea, 20 or 21?'
He said '21'.
He felt very bad because 'all this and now I'm exposed, I had Gonorrhea'.
We talked a little bit more, I said Med., go because I had to see cases very fast. I didn't have time to examine for ever.
A quarter of an hour, 20 minutes I had to find the remedy.
He goes away, then he never came back to us. He never came back for a follow up.
But by that time we didn't care so much about follow up, who comes, who does not come, people were coming in hundreds.
So somebody comes and says, 'I am with this general, I belong to this group'. 'Oh, the general.
How is he?'. 'He is quite well'. I said, 'he never came back to tell us how he is'. 'Yes because he felt uncomfortable
because of some question you put to him'.
I said, 'yes I know'. I'm talking about years later. This conversation took place. The man remained well most probably by Med.
He had that characteristic symptom of Med.  where I will make you a little bit nauseated now but I have to perform it.
Med. wakes up in the morning and there is mucus stuck in the throat and the post nasal mucus stuck there
they feel it, they try to get it out and they cannot. In the morning the wife hears every morning...
Very strongly.
You will never forget that.
There is another remedy which also feels stuck, what remedy?
Caust., very good.
It's different. The other is really... I mean you ask the wife and it is terrible. I've see it in a woman also, she was infected
by her husband, she says 'it's antisocial but I have to go to the bathroom and try to get out the phlegm'.
Because it's bothering them very much and it has to come out to release and if it comes a little bit out, they feel released.
-Very often people who smoke for many years they have a lot of phlegm in the throat and they have to clear the throat
a lot especially after the night when they were lying down.
-If they clear their throat it can't be Med. The people who smoke usually have the bronchi affected
and they are coughing  in the morning. It's different.
But you have also to take into consideration that we don't really confess people to the point where it' s OK up to a certain extent
when you have the symptoms Med., it's enough.
But going to details...what we know is, the idea is: over excited, over sexual, desire for sex a lot
passion, loving passionately the flower, the animals, the woman, the boat etc. But now to the detail it will be not specific.
If you have a pathology, you have a tumor that tumor which is the end result of pathology, this end result of pathology
does not belong specifically to one or other remedy. It belongs to all remedies. All remedies can have the pathology.
You have remedies who are over sexed or they have perversions, Plat. and Lach., are the same kind.
-I heard and seen that when you take a very high potency of Med., I've seen some people are going a little bit crazy.
We had a student in our class, he was normal for two years and then one day he started disappearing
from the class and then I met him somewhere. What happened to you? I took a very high dose of Med. and now
I'm writing a new book on LM and he is talking with god. He is treating people just by seeing them and decides,
you know from up, he doesn't have to study anymore. He goes really crazy and he was a nice kid. He took about 50M or more.
-I don't know, I don't have that experience.
It might be because he took Cann-i. the day before, I don't know.
-If I remember correctly you said once in one of your discussions or seminars in Germany that it can be very dangerous
to give Med. to a person who is over 60 years old, is it correct?
-It is correct yes. You be careful always in older age not to go very high, with Med.  especially.
Because it's a powerful individual who has powerful reactions.
You may expect that you may have some powerful reactions, especially in people with heart problems.
You have to be careful. If the heart is involved one way or another, better go up to 200, not higher.
-If the amelioration by the sea is missing and instead you have fear of the sea because you had some incident
in your childhood, could it still be Med.? Let's say you're almost being drowning but you are better in the evening
and all the other things are right?
-Yes he can absolutely.
Also you remember this position? The knee-elbow position, a position which little children are taking frequently.
And a very characteristic is a red eruption around the gluteal region. Very red eruption. Around the perineum.
Where you use the napkin for the babies, all this area becomes very red, not because of the napkins
but because of the Med. state. Another thing is the soles of feet, very sensitive. This is also very strong.
They cannot walk on ground which is not even. It's painful.
And sticking their feet out in the night, feet are burning and they stick them out. Usually they sleep on abdomen.
I think that's it.
-Did you tell us that 20% of all people that have a suppressed Gonorrhea will die early because of a heart attack?
Between 50 and 55?
-No. There are different types of Gonorrhea. There is one type of Gonorrhea which is suppressing Gonorrhea
that means going inside. This is out of 1000, it is 100 people. Out of these people a quite big percentage
I may even say 20%, they may get a heart attack, not die. A heart attack early, that means from 40 to 55.
From those they had the Gonorrhea which is suppressed. From discharge in urethra went to condylomata
condylomata were suppressed. Then this you have to watch. Watch these people because a big percentage
of this kind of people may develop a heart attack early in life.