So we go to Nat-c.
We have this nice remedy.
It's a remedy you will give usually in cases where you will see a life long problem with stomach.
If there is a sensitive spot for Nat-c. this is the stomach.
Stomach troubles of any type. Mostly gastritis, duodenal ulcer and dyspepsia.
They eat little and this little they eat, they cannot digest.
Especially if the food contains some milk or they try to drink milk. For them it is difficult to digest milk and they have aversion to milk.
It is one of the main remedies that have aversion to milk. So stomach problems with aversion to milk, goes straight to Nat-c.
If you have these two symptoms, go straight to Nat-c. You don't need anything else.
Aversion to certain persons.
It is interesting that Nat-c. people are sensitive, like all Natrums but sensitive especially to the presence of certain people.
The cannot tolerate the vibrations, the presence. They don't have to say anything, the presence, they are sensitive
in receiving the impression of another person and say, I don't like you. And they will leave, they will go out.
Usually this happens with women. I have not seen this with men but with women I have seen they cannot
tolerate a specific person. 'They are two persons I cannot tolerate, if they come to the room, I leave'.
They can be relatives or whatever, they cannot tolerate. It is a kind of hysterical almost reaction.
They are the people also who will not demand for themselves things.
They will not say, me first. Always it is the other person first.
You will say, is this pathology? We said serving others is good, is healthy. Yes but in Nat-c. goes to the extreme
where she likes to serve others, she likes to be the servant of other people. Not servant meaning something lower
but it is their desire to provide protection, food, whatever the other persons are needing, without making themselves present, aware.
We have other remedies which manipulate others. One of them is for instance is?
Where they boss other people, it's Chel.
Lyc. is different. They are not interested in the other person. They say, 'give me this, give me that', they are dictators.
The Lyc. does not say, 'this is best for you, you have to do it. You have to dress like this and you have to go tomorrow
to see the minister, and do this and that'. No. These are the Chel., Dulc., other remedies. Lyc. will be dictator
'give me this! Why don't you give me this?'
They behave like little dictators in the family.
Nat-c. is not a person who manipulates, who tells you what to do.
It serves you like the wife who stays always in the background and what is your need, she provides.
Without making herself, neither they want to make themselves present.
I am a very important person and some people come. I have a Nat-c. wife, she will provide everything, she will leave.
The Lach. will stay there. The Dulc. will stay, the Chel. will stay to protect you.
They will tell you what to do. Not in a dictatorship, this is different with Lyc. Lyc. do not really care.
When we say Lyc. don't think that all Lyc. are of that type.
Because as I said, you may need Lyc.and you have only digestive problems. That's it. Mentally-emotionally you don't need Lyc.
You are normal. So don't confuse it. Sometimes we say she is Plat.or he is Nux-v.
To accuse somebody by the remedy he is supposed he has taken. He took Nux-v., we know what it's all about.
No you don't know because you don't know whether he took Nux-v. because of indigestion and Nux-v.
is one of the remedies that has indigestion.
We're talking about Nat-c.  still you have not seen the Nux-v. Both they have indigestion but totally different person.
They have to really pay attention to what they eat. They eat very simple food and they eat little amounts.
That is why they are lean usually, the stomach is inside and the shoulders are like this.
They are lean persons.
Nice persons with everybody except of certain individuals.
If you get this, indigestion with aversion to certain people, that's Nat-c.
Usually in 90% of the cases you will have to have the aversion to milk. 'Milk? No I don't like'.
From 'I don't like' to 'terrible for me'. Or if I drink any kind milk my stomach is very upset.
So sometimes we are lucky and with 3 words, the person sits there and says, 'I have stomach problems'.
You say, 'what about milk?', 'Don't even mention it to me'. The case is finished. Next.
Later on he says, 'I feel so well, this is gone, fears are gone'. You say, did I do it myself? You wonder.
Chronic effects of sunstroke is another. Nat-c. is the most sensitive to the sun out of the whole group.
Nat-m. is the second and Nat-p.  is the third. But this one is very much affected by the sun or the heat.
The sun is such a poison for them that even the sun falling on their head for seconds, it becomes unbearable.
They have to walk with a hat. They are people who are having a hat all the time and it they are going to pass
from one pavement to the other into the sun, they will go quickly. Not to be exposed too much into the sun,
very sensitive to the exposure of the sun. And therefore very easily having sunstrokes.
After effects of sunstrokes. I had a sunstroke and since that time I have stomach problems, headaches, whatever.
You give Nat-c.  after effects of sunstroke. The whole thing, my problems started after sunstroke.
Great debility caused by summer heat. We had some heat waves in Greece, 2-3 years ago and in the Center
we had a lot of cases of Nat-c. They said, 'after the sunstroke after that summer I have this problem or that problem'.
Different problems. You don't have to have only headaches.
Can anybody tell me why it's so much indicated?
Because of the sea? Sea is 75% of the earth.
Salt is a big element for the sea, an important element, a mineral which is easily disturbed in the body.
Especially disturbed when you feel insulted or even worse rejected.
Fear of rejection to the extent that the person will say 'I will never go to that situation again. Never again!'
And they can close so much that it becomes like a wound inside. Like no emotions. Esp. towards the situation
which brought them this grief. What is this situation? Usually it's a situation of rejection in a relationship.
Most of the cases of  Nat-m. will relate to you that their problems have started after a relationship in which they went
innocently. Giving themselves to the relationship and then being hurt deeply by the other person.
Like Ign., Nat-m., has strong emotions. They are not people without emotions. They're people with strong emotions.
When I say strong emotions, I mean intense. Emotionally they are not strong. They are weak people, that means
they don't have much resistance on the emotional level because you can hurt them so easily!
And then we have insomnia from grief. They cannot sleep because of grief. You get that suffer with insomnia for years.
They work in the office, they enter the office and some people are there, and somebody forgot to say goodmorning to them.
Then they immediately take notice of that and they start thinking 'what have I done? Did I do something wrong?
Why he didn't say goodmorning? Most probably yesterday I did something, I said something, that hurt this person.
And then they go to bed to sleep and they think of this kind of things. Next morning they go and ask.....
'No, I didn't see you. Did not say goodmorning? I'm sorry'.
But the impact of such little thing is exaggerated. Now if the thing instead of being small is big, then the reaction
is tremendous and usually brings out not problems with the stomach but with the head. Headaches.
And the headaches are headaches which start in sleep, after the end of the sleep. In the morning they wake up
and they have a headache. And the headache continues until the afternoon usually.
Another type of headache is the headache starts about 10 and continues until 2 or 3 in the afternoon.
Such a headache esp. if it has the character of being like hammers beating, it's only Nat-m.
Also the grief they will keep inside. They cannot express it. They will not talk it over. They cannot talk over
their grief even with their wives, husbands. Even with the closest person, they feel that if they tell this grief
they will be ridiculed. They are afraid also of the reaction they may have. They may have a terrible reaction
and become really ridiculous.
Being ridiculous is something that stops them from doing anything.
If they want to cry, if they need to cry and cannot resist it anymore, they will go into the room, close the door,
go to the bed and cry there. Cry totally to themselves so nobody can hear them crying.
The same like the Ign. Ign. and Nat-m. are complementaries. Sometimes you start with the Ign.
esp. if the grief has produced this sighing but the grief is deep and you have to complete the action with Nat-m.
Of course such individuals who are so sensitive, so much reacting it is natural that sometimes the reaction will be
towards the hysteria. Hysterical reaction.
If they break down, they cannot express emotions in
a normal way. The expression is so much, so intense that we have a hysterical kind of a reaction.
They cannot control anymore. They feel it and they protect themselves by not going into such situations.
But once they are in the situation, they cannot control anymore, they are acting hysterical, they make themselves
ridiculous and that is the end. Also in a romantic situation what happens usually with a Nat-m. is that once
they have done such a scene they feel that they have been ridiculed, fall in the eyes of the other person
that they cannot anymore come back to the relationship. They feel the other person has seen them
being so low, so ridiculus. And all this goes into their mind and they go to sleep and cannot sleep, all this comes
to their minds. 'I did this, I did that' and all bad things which happened, they happened in the time
when they lie in bed and they try to sleep. And then we have insomnia from grief. They cannot sleep because of grief.
You get people suffering from insomnia for years! With bad thoughts when going to bed.
Everything that happens, happens during the time of lying in bed. And that is Nat-m.
One question you are asking and the question is what?
This little secret here, desire for salt is a big secret for Nat-m.
You just ask 'how is your desire for salt?'. They  say, 'I take the salt and make it white'. That is Nat-m.
If they say, 'I take the salt and I put salt' is different. 'A lot of salt' is different remedy and 'I make it white
I put so much salt' is Nat-m.
-They don't have aversion to salt, does this exclude Nat-m.
-No, it does not exclude.
If they just put like this it's Carb-v. If they put a little bit more is Verat. and Phos. If they make it white, it's Nat-m.
So this is something also that you have to take into consideration. Many times I've seen in the analysis of a case we make
I say no this is not a case of Carb-v. They say why? There is desire for salt.
Yes but the desire for salt is the desire which Nat-m. has and not the desire of Phos. or the desire of this.
In the Repertory you have some kind of degrees but even between the same degree you have differences.
So you are learning slowly the type; is this the type with the desire for salt?
If there is somebody who comes to you and sits in front of the office, you're sitting there and he comes there and he is full of life.
He says, 'what do you want me to say. I'll tell everything'. 'Do you have desire for salt?'. 'Yes'.
That is Phosphorus. You cannot say, but he has headaches 10-2 or 10-4, I say yes but better be careful.
Because he is not the type of Nat-m.
And if you are not able to differentiate and to see this sage you will not be able to say what is. You will always be confused.
Is this going to be Caust., Ign., Nat-m. It's a lot of remedies that can be each case. How to differentiate?
You differentiate by seeing whether the combination of what he says in each totality.
Yesterday we spoke about Merc. You take the combination because if you take the pain after operation you are led to Staph.
But if you take the whole of the history of the person the combination, it's the combination which leads you to the solution.
-I have a patient who is the Natrum type and I've given this and it was a relief but it was very deep grief behind.
It's a very old person, I didn't dare to give more than 200 each time because she was so weak.
And now there is a big desire for sweets and she is more open now but still there is a lot of grief. I wish I could go on
with a higher potency but still I don't dare this.
-No. If the desire for salt is less and on the other hand the desire for sweets has increased, most probably she is shifting
to another remedy, most probably to Lyc. They are complementary; after Nat-m. Lyc. many times is indicated.
So you see if the digestion, the bloatness and the gas is there, it's developing, you don't have to have so much gas.
A little bit of gas, it's going towards the Lyc. situation.
They cannot urinate in presence of others.
Because of the same sense of being ridiculed. Others seeing themselves and they would make comments or say something.
That's why they cannot urinate in the presence of others.
Aversion to fat is another strong point for Nat-m.  If you have desire for fat, it will make you think twice before you give Nat-m.
All the other symptoms have to be very strong to overcome the desire for fat in a Nat-m. case.
Fat and slimy, like the white of the egg when it is not boiled, forget it, he says 'uh..take it away'.
Desire for fish also is quite strong and farinaceous food.
Chicken and more the internal parts of the chicken, the liver, the guts of the animals. These parts specifically
they don't like and also chicken, I found out many Nat-m., they cannot eat chicken.
Aversion to the sun and of course photophobia.
Sun usually will bring headaches. If they lie in the sun for 10-15 minutes, the headache starts.
That's why they say, 'I like to lie down but for 5 minutes, not more. Because if I stay longer, then the headache starts'.
Also they are people who are having, if they are affected in this level, a lot of anxiety, hypochondriacal anxiety.
'My blood pressure today is so much, I have a pimple here, I have some headache. Do I have cancer?'
They keep on telephoning you for a lot of little things, which you know they don't have but for them it is a source of worry.
They bring out very easily these herpetic eruptions here in the lips. Recurently.
So if they are not assured, they are worried about this which is nothing.
Also they can hear that this is some point where somebody started a cancer. He saw some mucus in the stool
and then immediately they can search and find mucus in the stool. And then they can telephone and say
'I have mucus in the stool'. 'What do you mean?'. 'Well I don't know'.
So usually we don't pay attention because they are not affected in this level but if they are affected
they are one of the most hypochondriac patients.
The organism that has taken a lot of remedies  I found out that becomes insensitive to the right remedy
and you may miss it, thinking it's not acting.
And that is why I'm in the habit, in such cases where they have taken a lot of remedies, I repeat 3-4 times.
Even high potency, in the beginning, the same potency every day, 3 days.
10001,10002,10003. If you can dilute it and succuss it a bit take one dose higher.
Nat-s. I have found out of the Natrums, is the most healthy one in mental-emotional level.
Usually you get no symptoms, very balanced people that they have either asthma, the lungs are weak
or the digestive system is weak. In this remedy we see an aggravation between 4-5 a.m. in the morning
which is very characteristic especially in asthma. Asthma which is aggravated between 4-5 a.m. usually indicates Nat-s.
In such cases you try to get symptoms of the mental-emotional and you do not get.
But if by chance you have a case of a grief and after grief you see the desire to die but serious desire to die
very serious suicidal tendency the person feels that he has to fight all the time to counteract this tendency and it says
'kill yourself, shoot' and then they say 'No. I must not do it because of my father, my mother, my children, my husband.'
They try to resist this tendency to kill this depression which brings immediately to the desire to shoot themselves.
But at the same time there is a resistance and a battle that they must not do it, because they will give great grief
to their people, whom they love.
And it is this idea of balance inside them that you see when this is not overthrown, you see a balance
in spite of the fact that they lost their children, their loved ones.
They keep a balance and when the balance is lost, the organism tries to bring a balance by counteracting
the tendency to suicide by saying, don't do it because you will give bad feelings to the people that you love.
And they are able to control it though they suffer quite a lot because of that tendency.
They are people who are balanced, who are healthy, who are successful. Whatever they do, they will do it correctly.
They are correct people. And when the grief comes is so much, they say 'why should I live now? There is no reason'.
But they have their children. I remember a very characteristic case of skin eruption.
I was called to see the man in Belgium while I was treating Krishnamurti.
And I saw him with his nurse and his doctor who also was a homeopath. I'm talking about 1966.
And he showed me the eruption, this is the eruption, you give a remedy.
And he was a very rich man, aluminum industrialist in Belgium, very proper and I tried to ask certain questions.
I could not get anything.
At a certain moment he told me, he lost
his wife. He had lost his wife about 2 years ago.
'How do you feel?', 'Well, what can I do? It's a matter of fact'.
Then I cannot remember he gave me something, I looked in the Repertory and the idea of Nat-s. came to my mind.
Now how shall I tell him 'do you have suicidal tendencies?'. And his daughter was in front. His daughter, his nurse and his doctor.
So you know the situation. Rather young in1966, that means I had only 6 years of experience in Homeopathy.
And I see this case, he showed me his eruption, I said God, give me one good symptom. But the idea of Nat-s.
came to my mind because he did not look like Nat-m. OK, he lost his wife but he said 'OK. I accepted, what can I do?'
But since the loss of the wife he had this skin eruption.
Some grief is there? No, Nat-m. is not Ign.
And I thought of Nat-s. and I said to him, 'do you perhaps have thoughts of suicide, which you're trying to control
because you don't want to hurt your daughter?'.
He goes like that to the doctor. 'This man is undressing me'.
I said, thank you very much. I say to the doctor, 'give him Nat-s'. In a few days the whole thing was disappearing.
You see, from this little information you can make a cure that looks miraculous where nobody else can do it.
I had not still that moment met exactly that situation. It was the first time I was meeting a Nat-s.
and these suicidal tendencies.
And the way he said it, 'this man is undressing me here', it means I described exactly how he felt inwardly.
Of course you will see this remedy develops in damp weather; it does not like damp weather.
If people stay in damp weather they develop either joint problems or lung problems, whatever. Then you may think of Nat-s.
Another characteristic is photophobia which is quite strong and this remedy is considered as a remedy which is sycotic.
They call it sycotic.
Why? Because we see a lot of condylomata and warts in its symptomatology. Increased sexual desire.
The sex desire usually is normal. With Nat-m. for instance, you have a characteristic, I go back because I did not mentioned this.
You get a characteristic deviation I would say. It's not exactly deviation but for Nat-m. who is so timid
you don't expect that during sex they talk shamelessly. They like to say words which excites them in sexual fashion.
And they become shameless. It says in the Repertory 'shameless during sex'.
Why? Because they need to be excited, they need to hear or to say these kind of words.
Because they are closed and do not allow themselves in real life anything of that type, when they become loose
then they can really become shameless. In the same way they cannot talk but if they drink they become very loquacious.
So you have in cases of mental aggravation, loquacity in Nat-m.  quite a lot or in order to speak, they have to drink.
So in Nat-m. you see this kind of disturbances where in Nat-s. I don't remember a case where usually
they will say I'm normal with sex and do not have fears.
Very seldom you will find a fear in Nat-s.
I mean I don't know the picture of a Nat-s. insanity. I've never seen it.
And there is a great characteristic which is 'cheerful after stool'. After stool they feel really good.
It is automatic. I don't know what is stimulated there.
Headaches also which are connected with liver problems or with liver dysfunction are covered by this remedy.
-One question to Nat-s. They have this feeling of duty. Would they have Aurum too? I mean concerning suicide?
-Yes you have similarities with Aurum. The difference is that the Aurum suicidal tendency does not have the element
of trying to control it. When they think of suicide, they think what a nice thing to happen. If I die, the Aurum says, it's very good.
They invite death, they like death. They think of death and they feel relieved.
These people they think of death and they say, 'oh what shall I cause to my children? What grief shall I cause to my wife?'
-There is a question to Nat-s. When somebody got a dose of Nat-s with asthmatic condition and after 2-3 days
the asthma disappeared but within 4 weeks it comes back, what does it mean?
-Either the potency was too low or you need a repetition.
-It was an M thousand.
-It can be low for them and you can try repeating the remedy, let us 6-7 times.
Because it means that either the potency is low or the pathology is quite strong and it comes back easily.
But if you have a general amelioration and asthma amelioration, that means the remedy is correct
you should not leave it. You should repeat it.
- Maybe there is a problem that people are taking drugs against asthma. You can give also C12, some homeopaths
are giving high potency and because of these drugs you can repeat for a long time C12.
-Definitely you can repeat in low potencies if people take cortisone. It's very difficult to treat homeopathically.
You will have a big problem unless you still have a clear picture of a remedy. If you have a clear picture
even with cortisone, you will see beautiful reaction. But cortisone masks the case, does not give you a clear picture
and therefore it's very difficult for you to find the right remedy. Therefore you go slowly reducing cortisone
while the patient is improving a little bit and if you are lucky in 2-3 years  you manage to take him away completely from drugs
and you manage to have
a clear picture. If you are lucky.
In the beginning of my practice when I came to Greece for the first time, I got all such cases. All cancers, epileptics
asthmatics with heavy drugs and I struggled with all these cases in the beginning, very much.
I have quite a lot of experience from such cases and that is why I give you now my experience.
You will waste a lot of time for a case, a lot of energy. For one case you may be dealing every day with problems
before you can bring them around.
Cortisone is a terribly powerful hormone which changes the whole defense mechanism totally.