It has that symptom, anxiety about health to a very great degree.
Anxiety about health, yet nihilistic. It doesn't believe in anything. Everything is a doubt for him.
Why? Because you do not find the remedy immediately and then you have these patients calling you
all the time because of their anxiety. You have given Calcarea, Agaricus, this or that remedy and you have Nitric acid
calling you all the time, I have this, I have that and what about this? And I have a pimple here, he comes and
he wants to see the pimple. You say, ok no problem. Next day they come with another pimple and then with another.
They take the shoes off and they show you in the end of the nail a little black spot starting perhaps some fungus.
What about this? I don't know. I'm not a medicine man, maybe this is quite serious. This type of a person.
A type of a person who does not give, he takes. He looks at you under suspicion and he will not give you credit.
You feel he is judging you, he is mistrusting you.
You say, you have nothing, you have no cancer.
Because they are afraid of some serious disease
What is a serious disease? Cancer.
They will leave you and go to another doctor. And tell them you have no cancer. And leave him and go to another doctor.
As if they try to find a doctor to tell them, yes you have cancer. If this happens with this patient
the anxiety goes so deep that overwhelms the patient. And really you have him all the time coming back to you.
20 doctors told him no problem. 1 doctor told him maybe that is cancer.
Then that is the truth. He said the truth. All the 20 others did not know what they were talking about.
That type of a person.
Before they reach this terrible anxiety state, there is an anxiety where they feel they have something serious.
And then they go to a state where you say, ok we're not eternal. We're going to die maybe I will die soon
and then lose the joy of life. They lose the joy of life and they become nihilistic.
One who believes everything is a zero.
-He believes in the worst.
-No, he doesn't believe in anything.
-A non believer with a negative side. Everything is zero. Everything is nothing. Nothing is worthy.
There are no good doctors, there are no good people.
Not even pessimist. He's something else.
In the morning, especially they have this attitude in the morning when they wake up, they wake up in such a bad mood,
'Don't talk to me in the morning'. That type of attitude.
They enter the office and somebody says, 'good morning'. They say 'morning'. Leave me alone. Is it possible to be a good morning?
It's a little bit of exaggeration but I'm talking about real cases which I have treated.
And typical cases where you get the real picture. They also think of suicide. With this attitude nothing is worth doing.
They have a suicide but at the same time there is the anxiety, fear of death, fear of anxiety and anxiety about health.
So they think of suicide all the time but they don't do it because they are afraid. Afraid of death, afraid of suicide.
-I have a question about fear of cancer. They go from one physician to the other.
And they are so happy when somebody just
hints about the possibility of a positive answer.
- They are not happy exactly. They are satisfied. I thought I had cancer, now they found it. Or the liver, whatever they find.
-Does this not mean that in the emotional level they do have something which is asking for definition?
And they might call it cancer but inside they have something which is calling all the time and ask for touch.
I mean I have to believe that there is something emotionally which drives them all the time to do it.
-Maybe you have a point but I cannot go so far analyzing. What I described is facts. I described the way
that I have seen them behaving. I cannot analyze why they behave this way.
I mean the anxiety which I have seen is really tremendous. When the anxiety you see is overwhelming
the first remedy you think is Nitric acid and then Kali arsenicum and then Argentum nitricum and then Phosphorus.
Also there is another attitude. I mean listen to this person who is like this.
Cannot forget. Unforgiving.
Something you have done.You have insulted him and he cannot forget, impossible. It stays, sticks inside.
And you ask: 'if they come and ask you excuse me I have hurt you, will you feel satisfied? Will you forget?'
They will say invariably, 'I say ok but inside me I cannot forget, I cannot forgive'.
Unrefreshed sleep, waking at 2 a.m. As I said they wake up in a terrible state and with irritability
with tiredness and the day starts very very bad always.
One of my very first cases was a terrible case of acne vulgaris. Terrible in a Greek salesman, he was in a shop
and I was frequenting the shop.
I had been studying 2-3 months already.
He says, can you do something for me? Or somebody else told him, ask George.
He said, why not. I did everything, I also drank my urine and nothing happened. He can give me.
I gave him a low potency because I was in the beginning, I did not know.
He had a big reaction. He felt dizzy, I have to leave the shop, go home for 1-2 days and in 40 days his face was clean.
So all the customers they were coming said, 'what you did?' because they knew him for years with this terrible acne.
So a lot of customers come because of that.
And I remember this characteristic, I asked the boss how he behaves and all that?
'He comes in the morning, we say good morning, he never answers.
And I tell him there are customers here, you have to laugh, he cannot do it. And also I tell you something, he says.
I have noticed that he bought a gun and he carries this gun and I asked him why and he answered me
in case... I need it.'
He says, 'I'm worried because if he commits suicide with that state of mind, my shop will be in trouble.'
He took Nitric acid and he sold his gun. He became another person all together. Very interesting.
-Is it possible that alcoholics can reach that state?
-Yes they can reach that state but in order to be Nitric acid they have to have this feeling that he hurt me
I cannot forgive, I cannot forget'.
-Revengeful.
-It is not revengeful actually. It is they cannot forget, this is very important for Nitric acid.
-Does this state of mind can be the cause for drinking?
- I said, no. Because they are afraid of their health and they are careful.
Some other things we have, the urine smell like horse urine. If you get that symptom also is a beautiful symptom for Nitric acid.
Many many you ask but some of these cases they will say, 'yes exactly'. And this is a beautiful confirmation for Nitric acid.
Also you have cracking in jaws while chewing and also cracks on the corners of the mouth.
Desires fat, salt and children indigestible things. Fat and salt, this combination if it is strong, esp. if fat...
You know the way we say fat here, he says:
'I look to the plates of the others and I take all the fat which is left by others and I eat it'.
That's really desire for fat, this remedy has really desire for fat.
He eats his fat in the plate but also the fat which is left in the plates of others.
The feet are perspiring and very offensive and the perspiration is acid. It can eat up the socks.
Splinter like pains which we saw also in Hepar sulphur. What other symptom of this remedy Hepar sulphur has?
Chilly yes.
Not offensive discharge. Hepar Sulphur has discharges like cheese, smelling like old cheese.
Also we said it has splinter like pains.
I want to go to the next remedy which is Nux vomica.
Before I start with Nux vomica, I want to give you some kind of advice of how to study.
I gave you too much information and it is stuffed now. Maybe you are confused in your head at this moment.
But what I want to say, if you go back and you try to see your notes and you also have the assistance of these points
try to establish the uniqueness of each remedy in your mind.
What is unique. These remedies they don't look alike. They are very much apart for one who knows.
Getting from the start the difference between the one and the other is the secret of success for Homeopathy.
When I read Homeopathy, the first book as you know it was this book.
I read this book right through if I remember well in 3 days or less. I read all the remedies, I was going one by one
and of course in the end you will think I could remember anything.
But what actually had impressed me during that time, it was some points from each remedy.
Oh, this is good for colds.
I did not know diseases by that time, I had no idea what disease is and how complicated it might be
and different types and then by reading this I'm reading all these diseases of the human race
I said, my God all this happens?
What they describe here?
But what it stayed was the essential things for each remedy.
So later on I would think, there was a remedy that is especially for the nails.
I would see the case and said that's the remedy, I read it. It was M....
Myristica. I read this... felons around the nail and strong inflammation.
So each remedy has a unique personality. If you manage to get these few unique things for the remedy,
you have 50 % of your success.
It is unbelievable but it is true.
The problem is that usually when they teach Homeopathy, they try to teach everything in a remedy.
Of course the teacher himself maybe he is not clear of what is important, what is not important.
So coming here and clarifying this, take advantage of that clarification.
Take advantage of this point and try to remember  the uniqueness of the combination of 3-4 symptoms.
Here what is the uniqueness in the combination? It's the irritability, tremendous irritability
easily anger and impatience and indigestion.
If you remember 3 i's, for instance. You make different combinations in your mind. Nux vomica is 3 i's.
Indigestion, irritability, impatience. So you see that the case has these 3.
Competitive. The Nux vomica you remember irritable and impatient and especially when they get tired
when they are confronted with a lot of issues, Nux vomicas they can just break the table of break this one here.
The telephone will go like this. It's exactly like that.
Especially when pressurized, why?  Because they are people who accept responsibility,
who are able, clever, quick to act and impatient.
Come on, come on, you didn't leave the place yet? He expects that you told him something and he is out.
What do you wait for? Many times you will see a Nux vomica from the way he behaves in the waiting room.
Many times it has happened that because you are many times late, you had a difficult case before
you couldn't calculate the time and he is late.
Then he comes like this, 5 minutes is ok. 10 minutes, 15 minutes he jumps.
He goes to the secretary and says, 'listen is the doctor going to take me, yes or not? I had an appointment at 4 and it's a 4.15'.
The secretary says, 'wait a moment'. She calls you and say, 'somebody is upset'. 'Yes, please tell him to wait'. 'He cannot wait'.
Then you have to go out yourself to say, please Mister so and so. I'm very sorry but I have a very difficult case inside
almost dying and I have to deal. Can you wait? Can you give me another 15 minutes?
You have to say exactly the minutes. If you don't go out and it is 25 min. he says, good bye, he goes.
Next time he comes, you know his remedy, if he comes. Maybe he will never come back.
That is the nerve, the irritability, the angriness which is with Nux vomica. And many times they have left the office.
And many times they try to find relief, they cannot and they come back.
And you explain to them. As soon as you explain, they go inside, they satisfy their ego, they calm down.
It's ok but next time don't do it to me.
They cannot wait, impatient.
Irritable and especially when they are overloaded and they are tired, there are two things
one they cannot sleep and second they cannot hold their anger back.
Immediately with the least provocation they will just shout.
So this is the Nux vomica and in a little bit exaggerated form but you will see different steps of that remedy.
What is an organism who works like that? Spasmodically?
Take this, he speaks on the telephone and in the other hand he signs. Go away.
What do you expect? Digestion going into pieces, duodenal ulcer will develop, cannot evacuate the stool.
The stool will not come out. So the urge is there, the stool will not come out or they will go many many times before they can go out.
Frequent urging with no effect is a typical constipation for Nux vomica and also the stool is usually dry and little balls together.
People who are suffering with constipation a lot.
I am like this and I have an obligation.
I have to be here 4 o'clock.
There is pressure, interviews etc. and I say, no I have to be at 4 o'clock, please make it quickly.
And I'm exhausted; so I need what? Stimulants. You need stimulants. What kind?
I drink coffee. Beer, alcohol, not the time of the work. They need stimulants to continue the work
because the work demands a lot of energy.
Now in the night, when you go back home, you cannot sleep. As I said, they have sleeplessness.
Now in order to calm down and to relax, you need your whisky, 1 does no relax, 2 whiskies do not relax
3 whiskies do not relax, 4 whiskies you fell unconscious. I don't know how many whiskies each one can tolerate.
I've never tasted actually the whisky. I don't even know the taste but unfortunately when I teach and I have
so many obligations, so many people asking things, my energy goes down and I have to drink coffee, as you see
and then I become very irritable. But I don't take a Nux-v immediately because this is a passing thing if you sleep.
Tomorrow I'm leaving the island totally and perhaps I sleep 12-14 hours and then I recover. And that's how I can continue.
Because immediately after your course, I have the Russian doctors who are coming from Moscow.
So sleeplessness and wakes 3-4 a.m. You will see a lot of remedies which have sleeplessness.
They sleep 1,2,3 hours and then they wake up. That's the time. 2,3,4 o'clock they wake up and then they cannot sleep anymore.
And Nux-v sleeps why? Because he stimulates himself and the organism is stimulated and cannot relax
and go back to full relaxation that requires for sleep.
And then you have the nervous bladder.
The same thing that happens with the colon, it happens with the bladder.
Urging to urinate, a little bit comes out, a few drops. And then urging all the time, the woman or the man
has to go to the toilet and only a few drops are coming. The same thing with constipation.
You see the nervousness behind the idea of constipation. It's a nervous, irritable colon, irritable urinary bladder.
And of course you expect increased sexual desire. Of course, with all this energy.
You stimulate the energy and then the sexual desire is increasing and also you will see the impotency as well.
And the impotency is not that there is no erection but the erection is lost the moment that you start the sexual intercourse.
Stimulants, desires, spices, fat, tasty, spicy things, with strong taste, alcohol, stimulants, coffee, tea, whatever.
Nux-v people reach a point where they are totally exhausted.
I've seen it in ministers when they are overwhelmed with the work.
And they go constantly without much sleep, in the end there is total exhaustion which looks like Calc.
Calc. is a remedy for total exhaustion and nervous breakdown. They give up and say, we cannot do anything, anymore.
Nux-v will continue even in break down will continue to try to work. Calc. will say, forget it. I have to leave the work.
And many times they leave the work. Worse exertion, as we say.
They have worse exertion, too much work and then nervous breakdown and they have to leave.
Businessmen they stop the business, they cannot sign a check. They do not know what they're signing.
It's a total exhaustion of the organism.
We exhausted the organism and the society is structured in such a way that we're entering patterns of unhealthy living.
You are making all these efforts, expenses, airplanes, running, ferryboats they are bringing you here
and then finally you come here and I'm involved with that. I know the responsibility of that, that you have to learn
that you don't have to do this, that you have to have so much information because your time and energy has to be repaid etc.
So I enter a pattern, you enter a pattern of not healthy living.
Because you came here and you should have been relaxing much more. And I don't give you this chance.
I make you work when you should be swimming during the morning hours. The lecture hours should be less
to be more healthy. So if it was a School every day for a year it would be much more easy. But we cannot do that.
And now we enter to that pattern and many of us we become Nux vomicas.
- Is it possible that Nux then can sleep 14h a night or is somebody who can sleep
14h after exhaustion, not Nux vomica anymore?
-You may be looking like Nux-v but you are not Nux-v, especially when this is something which is temporary, for a period of time.
You push the organism and then an organism who is not Nux-v can sleep 15-20 hours.
Then you are not Nux-v. Nux-v does not allow you to sleep. Continue to go on without sleep.
If you exert yourself for a week and you become irritable, you don't mean to take Nux-v, just because of that.
Because if you sleep and you can sleep in the weekend, you say in the weekend OK I will not do anything
and you manage to sleep, then your strength is recovered. And you don't need Nux-v.
But you can drive yourself to a Nux-v state by staying awake the weekend, by pushing yourself in the weekend
by doing things in the weekend.
Superficial Nux-v. It's like having a flu. It's the same thing.
Fastidious of course. Fastidiousness in Nux-v is different than Arsenicum. It's the desire to do the job perfect.
They have a project and you have to do this. The organization and the performance; in this part, they are fastidious
but they are not fastidious, as far as I know at least, with their clothing.
The Arsenicum has to be perfect in appearance. The Nux-v wants to be perfect in performance.
Arsenicum perfection in appearance.
For Nux-v it's OK to be like this.
For Arsenucum it's not OK the table to be like this. As long as there is a perfection in performance.
Therefore fastidious. They say, 'why didn't you do it? I told you to do this. I tell you to write the envelope
it's going to the Prime Minister, it has to be written this way, write it again'.
Maybe it will act but it has to be more towards the cold. Not absolutely cold but some people are very cold
some are less cold but towards the cold. And even if a person is warm and he is going to Nux-v state,
his temperature of the body will lower down. That means not so warm as I used to be, he will say.
Somebody is very irritable and this irritability comes from exertion, too much exhaustion
then they are tired, they become very irritable.
They even sometimes can break out crying from exhaustion, from tiredness, they break out crying.
-When I started to learn Homeopathy, I took Nux-v and I had a proving but it happened so that I was only shouting
and couldn't stop anymore. So somebody said, you have to antidote with camphor.
And I took camphor and I had a camphor proving within 20 minutes. What happened there? I thought I die.
-You are sensitive, you are a good prover. We need people like you in a proving of a remedy.
There are some people whose organism reacts very easily to homeopathic remedies.
Something else I will tell you because later on I will talk about provings and I will give the conditions
and the type of person that can make provings. She is the type, she is sensitive and she proves she is down to earth.
She will not use projections and imaginations and delusions and all kind of things.
Because in a proving you can imagine anything you like.
Especially if you are a little bit the type of person who says what is going to happen to me?
If you are that type, you better stay away from provings. You cannot do provings. You are not allowed to do provings
because you will give wrong information and this information will be written down by somebody else who thinks
it's a great proving and then we have misinformation.
And in Homeopathy we have suffered from misinformation, I can tell you.
The whole of our science has suffered from misinformation. It is so difficult to say, this remedy is like that
because you can be describing only the character of one person, of one patient.
Which has nothing to do with the remedy. You give a remedy and then you go and describe his character.
His character is different than mine, different than his.
Each one of us has a different personality. So if I give him Euphrasia, now he comes he is better.
Then I see and I say, Euphrasia is asking a lot of questions because he is asking a lot of questions.
That is describing his personality.
Euphrasia is very theoretical, by looking at him, it has baldness here.
Whatever I can see, then I attribute it to Euphrasia, is wrong.
I have to separate the pathology from the personality traits. One person is a thinker, he thinks a lot
it is his personality and he is Nux-v . Another one is much more alert and quick. Still he is Nux-v.
How is a Nux-v  in a farmer? In an intellectual? In a painter? How is in a scientific man? How is in a performer?
You don't get the same type but all of them they will have this easy arousal, all of them they will be impatient, constipated.
But if I have a case of a Nux-v artist, you know artists most of them they are not healthy people.
If you want to be a real artist, you have to be really sick. You don't agree, right.
You have to be somewhat sick to be an artist because you are a sensitive person.
You are a person who perceives the world in a different way and this is the artist.
He describes the new, perceives the new.
So this requires a sensitivity in the organism.
These people of course in their sexual life they will be totally different in their behavior than a scientist Nux-v.
So if you take their sexual life and describe it as general sexual behavior of Nux-v, you are going wrong.
You are going the wrong direction and this is what is happening today. And I say, this is misinformation, come back to basics.
But basics that you can put your feet down in the earth and say, I can base myself here.
In Nux-v I have seen a lot of perversions. Extra energy which is there, they have different kinds of imagination, sex.
It's not use describing to you all these details though it would make an interesting lesson of course.
But it's no use because if I do, I will be most probably describing the peculiarities of a personality
of an artist or a lawyer or a doctor.
Who should be a prover? Later on when we'll know more Homeopathy we'll do some provings all together
or those people who are interested and then I will tell you who can be and who cannot.
I don't advice you at this moment to do provings because you don't know when to start, when to finish
what to write down, what not to write down. It's no use.
-I once had a patient who was in a coma. I did not have any symptoms I could use, I only knew the cause.
He had received antibiotics, he was taking a lot of drugs and had a lot of alcohol. So I gave him Nux-v 10M
and he woke the same evening. I just wanted to ask, Nux-v is frequently given to people not only who like stimulants
but also for the ailments after stimulants?
-Yes it is true. The idea is this. You stimulate the body, you produce many times a kind of Nux-v.
That's why we say, he has taken a lot of drugs, give him Nux-v. Because he has taken a lot of drugs.
Generalization of that type is not accurate of course.
The question is why he was in a coma?
-His friends just told me that he had taken antibiotics, he had drunk a lot of alcohol and was taking a lot of drugs, that was all I knew.
-So therefore he was in a coma because of the drugs.
-I think so. Medication-drugs-alcohol.
-If you don't have anything else to go by and if the person has come back, in the older books
they used to describe cases with the word debaucher.
These high livers who lived with a lot of women, liquer, a lot of sex and then they go to bed
3 o'clock in the morning they have to get up at 7 and they feel terrible. They said, take a dose of Nux-v.
And sometimes it works of course because you have created a state of Nux-v like in his case and it works. Not always.
-I had a patient who was a Nux-v, very nervous and swearing at home and shouting and smoking very heavily.
I gave her 1M once and she could not get near the cigarette. The effect was so strong.
She said she has nauseated from cigarette from that moment and she quit smoking.
-That's very good effect. She became healthy very soon.
Smoking cigarettes and all kinds of stimulants, taking drugs, hashish. Now they are on free market.
We come to a remedy which is actually the opposite of Nux-v.
The typical Opium case is a case who is satisfied under all conditions. Satisfaction under all conditions.
What happened to the lady who took Apis? It's much better. Yesterday it was closed.
So perhaps those that have seen this case and looked like her case.
In this case Apis acted very well, in her case Ledum acted very well.
Though they look almost identical because they were bitten on the same place, yet not the same remedy.
The situation is the same. The remedy is totally different. People are infected by a specific virus and they develop 20 different pictures.
The virus is the same. But it was so identical, her case with her case, you couldn't differentiate. So you have to take a chance.
Still it's a little bit hot, maybe one more dose.
In the previous seminar with the Italian doctors suddenly I come and there is somebody who has collapsed
sitting there and 10 of other doctors, students did that and that. The one the rescue remedies, the other take this.
What happened? He said he had an accident because of the sun. He felt dizzy, he fell down and hit this.
Everyone was very excited.
Then I saw him, he was really exhausted. He said, 'I want to vomit'. I touched his forehead, it was cold and sweaty.
I told him to give a dose of Carb-v. The doctors said, we take him back to lie down.
I said, wait 2 minutes. He said, 'it's OK I will stay to see the class'. He attended the class.
In half an hour his temperature was
normal and next day he felt totally well.
So in all seminars we have some excitement.
I will take all the videos of the accidents during homeopathic seminars.
Happy under all conditions!
There is happiness and sleepiness.
You talk to him and suddenly, I have seen it honestly
there was a fat man, from the very first cases, I'm talking about 1960.
He said, my thyroid is affected. He was very very fat. We said a few words and then as he was sitting there, I hear hrrr....
No more taking of the case. You like these things because you learn, you remember.
Overpowering sleep even while talking, while reading. They take to read this.
Can you read? No I can read only 3 lines.
It comes after Nux-v who is so alert, so irritable, so impatient and the other one lies down and says, how you feel?
What's called this from lying down a lot? What's called the wounds from lying down? Bed sores.
Full of bed sores. 'How do you feel?', 'Quite well'.
It's very strange that you see the happiness in the face of this people.
There is a happiness which is almost earthy.
No problem. Sleep, wake up for a while, see the world, being happy and go back again.
Snoring.
Breathing stops on going to sleep. Which is the remedy which has that? Another remedy we spoke about?
Lachesis. You have to do a lot of study when you go back.
Breathing stops but what is this breathing that stops? It's different mechanism from Lachesis.
Lachesis is not connected with breathing. It's breathing, stops, jumps.
Narcolepsy. Do you know narcolepsy? Difficult, slow and intermittent respiration.
As if the respiration stops and then starts again.
They have this snoring. It is the state which we see in comas.
This deep breathing and there is earthy redness in the face, brown red faces with full lips.
Painless in usually painful conditions. We said that. Never mind the pains, the pains do not matter.
Complains of nothing. Wants nothing.
Seems to be in bliss though very sick.
Severe constipation, no desire for stool. You see here how the two remedies go opposite? The one says, urging constipation.
The other says, constipation and it's finished. No urging. This constipation looks like Alumina.
Ailments from fright is a very interesting development for Opium because Opium is one of the main remedies for epilepsy.
Especially epilepsy in children who have convulsions, they are not bothered by convulsions.
They continue and you see this tendency to sleep all the time. They can sleep for hours.
Opium people can sleep 14 hours the day.
Pure bliss!
And that is why people who wanted bliss took Opium and they went to heaven.
Who has taken Opium?
Only one. Not, it's not one. I can see 1,2,3,4.
Great flow of ideas, vivid imagination and they have they say, the opposite also.
It's there when Hahnemann speaks of primary and secondary effects of provings.
Find paragraphs where Hahnemann speaks of primary and secondary action of drugs. Which paragraphs?
-Can you give Opium to children that lie and steal?
-Lie is another good quality of Opium. They lie, children can lie, grown ups can lie very easily.
In this happiness state, they can borrow money, don't give them back.
It can have an irresponsibility quite strong.
Where Nux-v is very responsible, this remedy is irresponsible, with big letters.
-Is it also for stealing? For children?
-For stealing not so much, for lying yes.
-I don't understand if they are such happy sleepers, why they aggravate during and after sleep?
-No they are not aggravated after sleep.
-It says aggravated during and after.
-During the breathing stop suddenly. While they are sleeping.
They sleep deeply. Narcolepsy, falls into a heavy, stupid sleep. Which is the description also of a coma situation.
That's why it's a specific remedy for coma. When somebody is in coma really, with a brain stroke, with heart attack
coming out of the operation room without being recovering. And the breathing is of that type, the snoring is there
the redness is there, then Opium will bring out of the coma.
-I think of another case I have had. He was a very old man, 95 years old and normally very sleepy
sitting at the table and suddenly his son was calling me because he had hallucinations. He saw children who were
not there and when I came he invited us to drink wine and he presented us persons who were not there.
And he was very happy, talking with his hallucinations, would that be a state of Opium too?
-Yes it can be.
-I wish to ask you about the other side of Opium as this is the indolent side of Opium.
-Yes great indolence.
-But there is also the other side. Over sensitivity.
-But let us remember that side now. I don't give you all the Materia Medica of all the remedies. I give you the most
important and those that you will really see. If we start going into details, we could do at most one remedy in a day.
Now we reach 45 remedies. It's very strange that with the Italians we reached the same number exactly.
We could not make 50. 50 was not possible for me, for them.
In which potency can I give Opium?
In potency you can give any potency,
as long as you don't give the real Opium.
Give it in potency. We can give from 6C to CM. You know now what it means 6C.
To a 4 year child, shock during birth, painlessness, often sleeping, appear less than 3 years in articulation.
What you write here are characteristics of Opium and in such a case you can give it from 200 upwards, 1M, 10M.
Shock during birth, ailments from fright we say and you will find in the Repertory.
The child does not feel the pain and often sleeps much more and has a retardation. It feels  retarded, cannot articulate.
Have you given Opium in this case?
- Before I came here, I just got to know the child briefly because of a tooth problem.
They told me some details about the delivery and by this I got the idea of Opium.
I saw the child how retarded it was and my question is now what potency, how high the potency should be
which I can give to such a small child?
-At least 200 up to 50M.
-Last seminar I had asked you a case of sinusitis with a lot of sleepiness and I had prescribed Opium
because I did not know the sleepy element of Allium Cepa and you had asked me to give my patient a 10M.
In that patient sinusitis drastically improved, the hypertrophy in the airways was clear, the sleepiness was gone to 90%.
He broke out in an urticaria area which was way back in his past history and lasted for about 4 weeks
and his hypertension also came down slowly.