It is a remedy which is excitable.
Sensitive young girls, boys who are easily excited, easily expressing their excitement especially through dancing.
Movement always helps Sepia, whether it is in the first stage, where we have the excitement state
or whether it is on a second phase, where we have the collapse of the emotions collapse of the mind
collapse of the uterus, the intestines. Everything goes down, there is no stamina, there is stagnation.
Everything is heavy, the mind is heavy, the emotions are heavy, do not move.
And the people will complain that natural emotions that should be there, are not there anymore.
What is a natural emotion? A natural emotion is to love your children. Even that is going away.
These situations will come out of shocks, out of traumatic experiences of the emotions.
The idea is that emotions, mind, sexual instinct, they all drop together with prolapses of the uterus
prolapses of the intestines with a feeling that all the internal organs in the abdomen, will go out. All the time there is an
internal pressure, they feel that the internal organs will go out and that is why they will be better sitting, in what position?
Cross legged, they feel that supports better the feeling of the intestines.
Sepia is a remedy that you could say is pathologically detached from those she loves. There is no attachment really.
These feelings of love which connect two people. Love connects two people, but if you say 'I'm detached'....
I have to say a few things to understand the feelings of Sepia. I have to analyze a little bit love.
We love our dogs.
It means that we are attached to the dog. If there is attachment, there is no pleasure in love.
You love your wife, you are attached to your wife. Who can say I love my wife but if she feels she would like to go
with another man, I would still love her.
The one who says that, is loving with detachment. Who can do that? Nobody.
Sepia cannot love. Who can do that? Only ideal people who have spiritually gone very far, where nobody can be there.
So love is a natural feeling but it contains within itself the possibility of pain.
So what is the most dangerous thing that you can do? It is to love with attachment.
That entails the possibility of pain in a very great degree.
Sepia understands that and she does not do it. She prefers to sit back and look detached upon a relationship.
Eventually she cannot love.
-My question is, Sepia understands it because she went through that experience of love which was
disappointing in a very severe way?
-Yes. Most probably the pathology of Sepia is formed in an individual who has been disappointed.
This excitable and sensitive individual came in contact with this stress and regresses back, collapses.
It's a collapse of the emotional level which has as a sequence the collapse of the three levels. The idea of collapse.
The uterus loses its power of contraction.
When a woman has orgasm, there is contraction. Sepia cannot have the orgasm, there is no the power, there is no the desire.
Therefore it says enjoyment absent and to that extent it's connected; the hormonal system is affected.
There are no hormones to stimulate and the organ collapses. You will see the uterus of a Sepia woman
that it can protrude out from the vagina, you can see it from the vagina.
How many times you have seen this? None. The gynecologist sees it and the woman tells you.
I've never examined anybody physically. Say open this. You will be surprised about how much I know or you think I know.
Because some rumors are going on especially in previous years, how George knows all this? From personal experience?
It's not personal experience, from hearing the story.
And from observation but from far detached observation. Not attached observation.
-She is midwife, she is saying that she can assure this because several times she used Sepia and she remembers
one case of a Sepia woman after delivering her third child she had a prolapse of the uterus.
She gave Sepia in 200 potency and all the symptoms came back nicely and the uterus involuted nicely again
after giving the Sepia. She's never treated higher than 200. This is her experience she wanted to share.
Therefore Sepia will affect the emotions on this love level and will affect also the sexual organs, where love
is expressed and in its more material form.
So Sepia loses the possibility to enjoy. There is no enjoyment, it is disinterested, no interest in life.
The only thing that maybe makes her feel good is when she has to stimulate her organism to work fast and move the circulation.
Sepia would like jogging, some fast walking, fast movements, then instead of getting tired she feels more energy.
She says there is no energy and there is this heavy feeling, no feelings, no enjoyment, she says to the husband
forget it tonight I'm so tired. Next day she is tired, third day she is tired, 4th day tired, tired, one year tired, two years tired
she says let's go to a homeopath.
You see a beautiful woman and you think really hot stuff, she is going to be very ... then you enquire the husband
he says, forget it, nothing.
She will look like half asleep and things like that and you will think she is looking passionately at you.
She is sleeping actually, she is half asleep.
I'm terrible but I've seen these things and I've treated these cases
and they have done well. The husband says, thank you very much.
What brings such a state is, I will tell you it's very interesting; Sepia condition of course comes from today's society easy.
The fear of having exposed yourself, you get the feedback and you finish and then you have a Sepia case.
But there is another type which develops Sepia symptomatology and which comes from young people of today.
The young people of today because of doubting and searching for truth searching for spiritual awareness
searching for that which is the highest, which actually is secure.
They go to these spiritual people who are existing, especially from India and then they  hear 'you have to practice
abstinence and detachment', 'oh they say sex is very bad, I have to be detached'. And they try to be detached
and the more they try to be detached, the more Sepia state they bring upon themselves.
Detach, detach, don't have feelings, don't have sex, then they reach a state where they are without energy.
It says they drag themselves. Spiritual people who followed the guru, who followed an idea which never is going
to be fulfilled because this is not the way to ask for enlightenment. And these young people who have taken drugs,
who have destroyed their emotions and feelings, who have dealt very early with sexual matters 14,13, 16 years old
they go and have sex, 17 years old they don't feel anything. Then they search for god, then they search for truth
then they search for the guru and the guru says, detach. He says, it's very easy to detach for me because I have no urge,
no desires anymore, so it's OK. Then they bring themselves to the state of Sepia.
So it's very interesting for a homeopath to observe the creation of diseases, how diseases are created.
Out of 100 cases that you put inside there, 90% you ask when this disease has started and they will tell you
out of a traumatic experience, out of an inner conflict. And that inner conflict involves mostly the emotional side.
And then they can disease, they can progress, it can become from one stage to another. Eventually you may have
very deep pathology. Then you get the Sepia which has, I don't know physiology wise why it happens
instead of menses they have discharge, leucorrhea. They have menses but the menses are becoming less,
premenstrual syndrome is very strong, before menses they are disturbed especially with depression
and irritability and a lot of discharges from the vagina. You get a little girl 12 years old, she hardly has started
her menses and she says leucorrhea constantly. This is 95% of the cases is Sepia case.
The leucorrhea, the discharge is yellowish-white.
So the dropping in the sex energy, in the feelings and in the intensity of the feelings and the dropping in the mental acuity
it points out to Sepia.
If you have of course a prolapsus somewhere in the intestines, that confirms it.
Better with strong exercise. That's another confirmation.
Leucorrhea in women, constant leucorrhea, a lot of leucorrhea another confirmation.
There is something else also that you see it very much in the literature and I have not seen it so much in practice.
The saddle around the nose. You know the lupus erythematosus creates a saddle around the nose and the cheeks.
It creates a redness. In Sepia it can create a discoloration, a saddle,  they call it, on this area which is towards
the yellowish but it can be also the redness of the lupus.
When it is red, Sepia is one of the remedies, when it is yellow, the remedy is Sepia.
Also these Sepia cases are very tired individuals. Tired physically, mentally, emotionally.
A man who has been very active and then eventually becomes less and less active and less and less interested in sex.
In woman it arrives to aversion to sex. Anything to do with sexual matters makes her feel nauseous.
If she is married and during marriage she comes into a Sepia state, she has a terrible condition because she cannot handle it.
The husband of course wants sex and she finally pretends etc. and it is a torture.
I have seen women who have pretended for years, Sepia women pretending for years that they are enjoying sex
and they actually have aversion to sex.
'I cannot stand it', they say. If only caress, even that, caress I can stand it from the husband. But you put some
sexual connotation in the caressing...
If the caressing is fatherly it's OK.
Another thing they have is of course, as I said before, the detachment makes them very acute observers.
You stay a little while with a Sepia case and she knows all your weak points. Then in the books it says, she is spiteful.
All people are spiteful. Sometimes if you touch them they will say something bad for you  but Sepia will find exactly
the point where you feel the pain.
And she will hit you.
Sepia is a cold remedy.
Of course the sadness and the depression of Sepia is of such indescribable matter, like she does not know what she likes.
There is nothing that she likes. That if it becomes deeper, then comes a state where without knowing why
she cries and cries. And she does not know why she is crying.
But she will find a reason of course. My husband has left for a journey. The husband comes back.
My boy is going to go to the army. They find a reason. Why you cry? Because of a peculiar reason.
The idea is that unless they cry they feel that they have to commit suicide. Crying brings a kind of balance for Sepia.
Not all Sepias are like this. You have to understand the ideas.
You see in both Sepia cases that we had, you saw in the one case the sex is quite strong. I mean as a deeper remedy
you could say sex is quite strong. But sex is becoming less and less of a real issue.
And in the second case sex has become out of question.
After Sepia sex is not going to be out of question.
It will be freed of that frozen situation.
In women they call it frigidity, indifference to sex.
Fear of ghosts, of storms.
Sepia actually can enjoy storms because Sepia can be stimulated by something which has intensity.
Because it is so difficult to move her. She will be stimulated.
And if you stimulate a Sepia case and she has an intellectual discussion, they feel better. The mind goes faster.
The faster the mind, the better they feel. The faster the body, the better they feel.
If you can stimulate their emotions also, they will feel very well.
Stimulate their emotions for a while and then the collapse comes.
Also it's one of the main remedies for having these empty feelings in the stomach, better eating.
But Sepia is not a big eater. Phosphorus is a big eater and Sulphur is a big eater and Iodine is a big eater.
And they feel better eating, Sepia is not a big eater but is better eating.
Kent has described the Sepia woman as a woman of very lean body like men's body without the pelvis.
You know the natural woman pelvis to bear children is big. So women are bigger here. To be able to bear the children.
Sepia tend to be lean here, not to be really built up for bearing children. And that's why they have spontaneous abortions.
So a typical Sepia will have a difficulty bearing a child. In the 2nd month, 3rd, 4rth month the child is gone.
You give Sepia, she has five children. And then she curses because she says, I wanted only one.
It's a good remedy and quite frequently is indicated in the society today.
Who is a man Sepia, is anybody Sepia here?
-I was actually diagnosed as having systematic lupus erythematosus at one stage in my life. And Sepia was the first remedy
that was prescribed for me. I also had this exanthema in my face as a butterfly which is known for lupus
and this was really wonderful cure.
And it was prescribed for me because for years I had suffered from strong migraine headache, this was the leading symptom
that actually led to the prescription of Sepia.
-Sepia has a left sided migraine over the left eye mostly. Where it was your headache?
-It was in the forehead.
-Not more in the one side or the other?
-No.
-What I wanted to start saying is that this is described in the books, that you have such body but to find a typical Sepia
like this is not so easy. Most of the Sepias will not be lean and thin like this. Most of the Sepias can be anybody.
You don't have to have this typical thin body with no hips.
-I learned in my homeopathic teaching in my school, where I went that Sepia has got the strongest
erotic appearance about it. They can be the most erotic people. For instance as described by Georges Bizet
this figure of Carmen.  We learned that she was Sepia.
-Which Carmen, the opera?
-Yes.
-The woman.
-The main figure in Carmen was Sepia?
I don't know. Who said that?
-These are fantasies. I have started these many years ago in order to show examples, to take examples from different figures.
I would say for instance Mussolini but I would support it with historical facts. Carmen had a lot of boyfriends.
Mussolini was a dictator but actually he was weak. He was a Lyc., he was bloated, he was egoist, he was womanizer.
All these are elements of Lyc. You can say, taken all these elements together this is an idea of Lyc.
I made this mistake in describing some people, known personalities. I said for the President of the USA.
I will describe to you and you will find it. A man with a face with a beard, Lincoln.
I said, he was philosophical, he was tall, lean, stoop shouldered, looks dirty and I said OK. And then I heard all my students
started describing the cases putting a lot of imagination like Carmen of Bizet is Sepia, no. I said before when
I was describing you don't have to have a Sepia which is dry and lean and thin.
You may have Sepia who looks juicy and not dry and still it can be Sepia.
This is what I said.
-I have a Sepia woman that treated since March. She had bulgy eyes and it is a case I've never seen in the 7 years
of my practice and I have it with me, I want to give it to my files. If you allow I can show it.
The differential diagnosis to Apis was difficult. She had warts in the face and I decided in the end it was Sepia.
And it was gone in two weeks and she had it for two years.
30 of April and she came in March.
-Very good.
-We can show it on the camera.
-Yes, I don't think of practical matters, only women think of practical matters. It's very strange.
I said to my wife why is that if here is a table, so she puts the plate here. I don't push the plate here so I can eat.
I eat from there. Therefore I spill my food.
Why do I have to always do like this? It is so simple, it's very practical just pull this next to me and I can't think of that.
That is a very impressive picture. She got only Sepia?
Can you put your camera on and project the picture when she was treated?
You see the difference in her eyes. You see here the sadness and the anxiety, you see here the suffering in the soul?
Here there is some joy.
You see here she laughs but the eyes are showing emptiness and grief. On what symptoms did you prescribe Sepia?
-The warts on the face was one symptom but what made me decide Sepia was the red eyes, the burning
she had also rash in the nose when she came first.
She had prescriptions two years ago from the gynecologist for estrogen. She is 44 years old.
-What was the diagnosis for this case?
-The diagnosis was tiredness. She didn't like the grand children around her, she was dull.
-The allopathic diagnosis?
-I don't know. She went to several doctors, to dermatologist.
-What did they say?
-The dermatologist said, did they ever check your kidneys? That's what he asked her.
I said, were your kidneys checked? She said, never. I did nothing with the diagnosis of the school medicine
and I gave her Sepia.
-What is impressive here is the amelioration on the emotional level. Here is a woman who suffered a lot.
Did you ask her about sex?
-Yes she said that she has no sex, she has dry vagina.
With this picture she said, 'when I wake up in the morning and my husband wakes up, he only reaches out
with his arm and tries to touch my eyes to see if this is back'.
- How long? In one and a half month?
-One and a half month.
-You see the problem is that in your whole practice you will never see a similar case again.
Every time you have to individualize and you have to come back to the basics.
Otherwise you expect to find a case like this, forget it. And most probably if we do find it will be Kali-c. or Apis.
Apis here is the remedy you look, you say Apis. Unless you take the symptoms and you find out, Apis is so sexual
and here she is not looking sexual.
-I wish to ask you if it's possible to have Sepia also without irritability and without premenstrual syndrome
or menses problems?
-Yes sure. There is no symptom almost in the Materia Medica which says this symptom will exclude the remedy.
There is no symptom.
Even they will get sometimes where you will even have a cold remedy will be better by a hot remedy.
So there is no symptom that you can say if you are hot, you are excluded from these cold remedies. No.
The time of amelioration for Sepia is evening time. Evening time instead of being more tired, Sepia feels better.
Actually after moving around, she feels better.
The idea of Rhus-t. is that somebody who is stiff, what he wants to do?
He wants to move all the time.
-Can we give some feminine practical advice? Just an advice for this heat.
-What do you mean?
-Just for now, can I?
-Yes.
-OK. Everybody has the papers of this. They can hold it, you know it anyway. We can open the window and enjoy the class.
-Master of ceremonies, what do you say? No. The windows is better to have this because sun will come in and kill you.
That sun is very warm. In this weather he feels best, 'don't open the window, I feel comfortable'.
If a Rhus-t. is sitting there will have the window closed.
I feel comfortable. Why? Because Rhus-t. is always better with heat.
General heat and application of heat in the different parts.
The main points are worse cold, better heat, worse what weather?
That which brings the stiffness, the rheumatic stiffness, especially in the cervical region.
You have seen me doing all this time like this? It is because I need Rhus-t.
All the time you see them doing like this. It cracks.
And the back.
They have to move all the time lumbago and cervical region is very prominent symptomatology.
And there is what we call restlessness. You cannot see them sitting, there is a restlessness of the mind
restlessness of the emotions always.
The emotions are playful.
There is a boy's attitude. It's stiff and yet agile. How is that? You don't know.
They get stiff very easily. The moment a draft is open, they fell it immediately either in cervical region or here.
They're stiff and they have to move.
They go to bed with a lumbago. They cannot stay in one place. The moment they are staying in one place
one minute they have to move to another side, they turn. The restlessness on the lower limbs are very strong.
So you go to the bed side of somebody, you see he is sitting quietly, forget Rhus-t.
Even in the most severe pain Rhus-t. would love to move a little bit. And you see the more the pain, the less the movement
but the movement is there.
If you observe the body is moving all the time. It says if you stop, I will grab you.
Stiffness all over the body, especially the joints.
Desire for milk is a keynote I can tell you, an invaluable keynote. This strong desire for milk. We mean from 3-6 lt. the day.
It says '5 lt. I can drink constantly. If I was not afraid of cholesterol, I could drink 5 lt. a day'. There is no stop for this milk.
And that is a keynote which is absolutely 100%.
Not acute, in a chronic condition. You have kidney problems, asthma, arthritic conditions, skin eruptions.
Skin eruptions which are better with warm and better from heat and restlessness.
You cannot imagine the itching of Rhus-t., scratching and turning, scratching and turning, the whole night
may go scratching and turning. And if you suppress this, then the restlessness will come in the mind
and it will not allow him to sleep, though not itching anymore, he cannot sleep, restlessness and sleeplessness.