Asar. is a remedy that you will need in cases of nervous exhaustion.
The nervous system has been stressed and stressed and eventually breaks down and creates a super sensitivity
on the nervous system, especially on the auditory nerve.
But all the nervous system is in a state of excitement.
You feel that the person is going very soon to break down completely.
And the person himself will confess that 'maybe I'm jumping over to a new state' which is madness, craziness.
This situation can be caused by an individual pushing himself, especially today. I think Asar. was not indicated 100 years ago.
But today with the idea of pushing, pushing ourselves into attaining and attaining and using the mind.
You get a child for instance, and she is good at school, the father and the mother are ambitious.
They say why don't you do some piano lessons? OK I do some piano lessons. And German is a language which is
quite contemporary, would you like to learn? OK I take some German lessons also. And then she tries and tries and
there is a moment where the girl just gives up, the whole system is broken down and she cannot attend anymore anything.
How you will recognize that this is a case of Asar. and not a case of Calc.?
Calc. has similar state. They break down, they don't want to do anything anymore, they feel they are going crazy.
What will be the difference between Calc. and Asar.?
-That over sensitivity to noises. To the slightest noise.
-Very good. This is the difference. There is no Asar. case where she will not show sensitivity on the slightest noise.
And which is this noise?
Especially the noise of the board, the scratch, the metallic noise.
They will close their ears.
If I ring the bell and it's an Asar. case she has to close the ears, she cannot take it, it's too strong.
Then what you see it's another element that you see in Asar. in comparison with Calc.?
That Asar. is really a hysterical case.
Because you see the child is sitting there, playing with their fingers when they are talking.
They don't realize what they are doing. They sit there, they look at you and the fingers.
That shows the inner state of the child, the extreme anxiety, the extreme hyper sensitivity, what are you going to tell me now?
If you push the child, 'study!', this tone of voice it can destroy it.
You take the child to the bus, you are a little bit late and you tell the child 'hurry up', it is impossible.
This pushing, this little bit of extra energy which he needs, he cannot put.
The idea is that you understand this situation and you can recognize it in cases of nervous exhaustion.
You will see such cases with nervous diseases, with M.S., where there is this hypersensitivity and the nervous system is really affected.
It has now a damage done on the nervous system.
Then with this hypersensitivity of the
auditory nerve especially, that's the case.
This is very characteristic. The grownups will not do it like this but there is something called embarrassment.
You feel the person is embarrassed. He does not know whether this is right or what to say and you feel the reactions
which are coming from the outside, whatever the stresses cannot be handled.
I have a feeling, I have a fear or an anxiety.
This is the state, shivers from emotions but
you have to understand the whole situation.
It's not a coldness, it's the nervous system.
This excitement inside and the pressure which we have out of the different duties we have to do.
Excitement, pressure, inability as a result, an inner hurriedness but she cannot run, she cannot do something quickly.
There is a hurried feeling inside without being able to perform.
It says 'noise causes chills'. You understand?
The whole nervous system is bothered.
Their sensitivity reaches to the point sometimes, they think they're hearing noises.
This noise they cannot stand. Who cannot stand this noise? Nobody.
Another state in which I have seen Asar. is indicated is states of what the Americans call allergic conditions,
allergic to anything. The Americans are allergic to anything, they have been exposed to too much pollution.
A case of American student had to give up her studies in America because she could not enter any laboratory.
Any laboratory on the medical premises will make her go into shivering, tremendous anxiety state and almost collapse.
You could see she was so sensitive, the nervous system, I cannot enter this.
The idea only of entering a place would drive her crazy.
You could not find that she will have a skin eruption or she will have an edema but she was performing as if she had all that.
So it is a hysteria which exaggerates the sensitivity of the nervous system. The nervous system cannot take
the least pressure, the least aggression.
You understand with this kind of nervous system, with this kind of sensitivities, how she will behave in sexual matters.
Forget it.
The idea of kissing is impossible for her, even the child, even the parents to kiss the child. Leave me alone.
There is no energy on that level at all.
On the contrary they perceive or they are affected by close contact.
It says 'aversion to be touched', 'aversion to sex', 'aversion to be kissed'. Any contact which irritates the nervous system.
Strong light they cannot tolerate. Strong noises they cannot tolerate. Strong wind they cannot tolerate.
Everything causes problems for them. Every stress.
And of course when the auditory nerve is in such a state for many years, may break down totally in deafness.
Hearing starts coming down. You cannot stay very long under that stress.
That state of over reaction of the nervous system it can be seen sometimes with the alcoholics.
These people present that kind of sensitivity and Asar. sometimes may help. Though the problem of alcoholism
is not an easy problem to tackle with Homeopathy. They need constant support from around society.
Such support is very well given by the alcoholic anonymous because they create a society and within this society
each one supports each other. And they can get out of it.
With Homeopathy you can reduce a little bit the effect of the withdrawal syndrome but by giving a remedy, you cannot
take them away from alcohol.
These cases also can be confused with the Phos. state.
In the previous group I did a miracle cure.
A woman was lying in the room with tremendous anxiety state, her husband was next to it and a few doctors were there
and I came and saw her. She had a shock, she fell down and then she had tremendous anxiety, nobody knew what to do.
I just touched the extremities and I touched the knees. I saw the anxiety and I touched the knees.
In the cases of Phos. the knee area is very cold.
You touch a little bit down is warm, you touch the knee, very cold.
There were a few Italian doctors. I said you touch here, you touch there. Bring her Phos. Give Phos., she got up.
Not always but many times. It is a characteristic and it is in Asar. also. But Phos. has it.
And of course I felt she was in a very anxious state. She was hyperventilating and she was very very anxious.
Little things like that, because you don't ask any question. You just observe.
Yesterday it was amazing also with her case when I got out of the class, one hour after we had spoken
still she was lying down there without being able to move.
And one dose of 30, not one dose even. She didn't touch, by the smell and she jumps up.
She was lying down there for one hour and ten minutes unable to move. Just the smell.
Uta was giving the remedy and before the pills touched the mouth.
She just jumped up.
-It says here: excessive sickness during pregnancy. Also in those state you have to have
the over sensitivity against hearing. Why does it come in pregnancy, do you know?
-I don't know but if you give it without
the general state, it will not work.
What I'm trying to give you now here is always the main structure of the remedy which if you have it the effect is fantastic.
If you don't have it, it may still work the remedy like yesterday we gave on one symptom and a few other things, we gave him.
You are not happy.
If it acts the remedy, they say it's a placebo effect, it's not a placebo.
-Is it possible that Coff. would come in such a state like Asar. and except of nervous exhaustion what would be the difference then?
-The Coff.will have the trembling, will have the over excitement, ups and downs but the difference will be that
the mind produces constant ideas.
New ideas are coming, the mind is very very active. Here the mind is the opposite. It's almost inactive.
You see the fear, you have to understand. 'I don't know what is going on, it is vertigo, dizziness, chills
the mind is not working and I'm going crazy'.
That's why sometimes we say it looks like and I say no, no, there is nothing to do.
Because if you understand the essence of the remedy, then you cannot easily confuse the one with the other.
The other is talking, it will talk. The Coff. will talk to you in an excited state, very easy to be involved in a conversation.
These people they don't like conversation, they don't like to communicate.
Everything which is on the sphere of communication, forget it.
-George you mentioned M.S., what is your experience with Asar.?
- I had two cases with M.S. which was the first remedy which took the case from here to there. Not cure.
M.S. is not an easy disease to cure and many times you can reach them up to a certain extent and then you may be
treating for 10 years, they stay in the
same level. Be happy. They stay and they walk.
Unless you get them in the very beginning stages, then I have seen total cures, I mean 20 years
still I have cases which they have not relapsed in 20 years, you never know if they will still relapse.
But I have seen some cases in the beginning stages where they have gone very well.
But once the plaques are formed, the destruction of the nervous cells is there, forget it, they will not repair.
They will stay with the edema and the process of inflammation of the nerve cells and the edemas, that will stop.
But the damage will remain to the point where you caught them.
-Is there any difference in Caust. and Nat-m.  in these cases because you mentioned this and we had one case in Vienna
two years ago I think. Caust. case of M.S. which was quite far gone already. You mentioned that in the beginning
you could keep the persons on a certain level. Does this goes for Asar. as well?
-This is for any remedy in M.S. when it's indicated, it's the correct remedy but will take the case up to a certain level, no further.
-No difference between any of the 3 remedies?
-No difference between the remedy. The same with Calc. or Sulph. or Lyc.
But you have to have that excessive sensitivity mostly on the nervous system.
Asar. is a remedy that today you will see a lot of cases. This nervous sensitivity is becoming more and more prominent
due to stresses that we have in life and the conscious effort we make.
I don't like to say things before I'm sure about, that the cases I have seen are cases conscientious people.
That they voluntarily push themselves to the limit but I'm not sure that this is really so.
It can happen to somebody else also but when I have seen that I have seen, you can say, ambitious people
but it's not, if you write 'ambitious: Asar.' is wrong.
What you have to have is that state.
-Does the sensitivity to noise has to be in each and every case?
-The sensitivity to noise has to be there enough. It can be very extreme, like the one I described, or the patient will say
'I can't stand noises'.
There is a degree of course. But always in all cases yes I would say, it has to be that the auditory nerve is very sensitive.
-There is known a syndrome which is called Rett syndrome, that is autistic disease of children.
Rett is an Austrian psychiatrist and he described it. They are known about 20 children in Austria and Germany who have that.
It's an autistic disease very severe and you see that they have very much sensitivity against noise
and they have this always restless the hands on the body.
-These two signs are signs of Asar.
In autistic children of course I don't know how much you can improve but you can try, if you have a case like this
a lower potency, constantly 3 times a day,
12X, going up every week 1 point.
In a 6 months treatment, you can evaluate because what you are saying is very typical.
-I tried with Q potencies and the sensitivity against noise diminished, it was not there and also the
restlessness of the hands and the child becomes more open. Before it was only looking through you
and after some time you got contact.
-You gave it already, I thought you were asking.
-Yes I gave it and there are some development but not cure.
-I believe that C potencies are more powerful. Go to C potencies, give it 3 times the day and give it for long period of time
6 months every day and every week going up 1 step.
In 6 months observe the effect.
They are totally retarded.
Was anybody in Alonissos back 15 years ago when I saw this child totally retarded with epilepsy?
A child paralyzed 4 years old with epileptic fits, totally retarded, no contact at all and with Cic. it developed quite good
to a certain extent where he could walk, no epileptic fits, couldn't communicate and he was a mongol child also.
But these cases you can improve so far.
I have battled with such a case for 8 years in the beginning of my career where all cases of this type were coming to me.
Spastic children, autistic children, epileptic, cancer cases and neuro muscular diseases and I was battling with all these diseases.
With one child I battled, an autistic child. When he came he was 8 years old and pull down all my curtains.
Very aggressive. For 8 years. He brought out eventually bunches of warts. His whole legs were full of warts.
Eventually he was able to support himself. Even his mother at the age of 15 would give him some money and say go and buy this.
She would give a note, he would go there, give the money, take the thing and bring it to his mother.
No talking, no communication, only aggressiveness.
-On which symptoms did you give Cicuta on this child?
-You will see the video, so you have to recognize it.
-You said that you cannot cure alcoholics by Homeopathy. You were talking last seminars about cannabis
the using of hashish. Do you think that you can cure this mental state that is the result of long use of cannabis with Homeopathy?
-Yes, you can cure but again if cannabis has been used for long periods of time and in big quantity, it always leaves
a mark on the brain. Always the brain will be deficient after that. It will not be able to concentrate
the concentration span will be small. And you will not be able to bring the brain back to its normal condition.
According to my understanding and experience, I never took myself but the experience of seeing cases with cannabis
it is that cannabis can have a very damaging effect on the brain if it was used regularly.
I don't agree at all with the idea of be free, let's smoke cannabis, it is like cigarette. It's not like cigarette.
Cigarette definitely damages but not as much as cannabis. Equal smoking of cigarettes and marihuana will kill the person.
20 cigarettes the day of marihuana will kill the person. Total killing in less than 10 years.
They are discussing of letting free marihuana. The same way with alcohol. They let free the alcohol and we have
how many millions of alcoholics? With marihuana the whole population will be subdued. If somebody wants to be
the dictator of the world, he will say let give them marihuana and everyone will be happy.
It's a very easy way to subdue a population.
The critical faculties, especially the critical faculties, are gone.
There is no discrimination, the brain cannot discriminate between good and bad. What is good and what is bad
what is true and what is false.
I say this for these younger children that we have here, so they can listen very carefully because it's not a simple issue
as they want to present it. They smoke one cigarette of marihuana and say, nothing happened.
Use 20 cigarettes a day and see what happens and come with the anxiety and the fear and the madness
especially the fear we discussed it in Cann-i. The fear of insanity is something unbelievable, I'm going crazy.
Tarent. is a remedy, you can say it's a remedy which acts on the nervous system, producing a lot of energy, a lot of force.
Excess energy that has to be spent.
How do they spend it?
By motion and activity.
That's why it says restlessness is a tremendous issue and restlessness, hurriedness which is beyond belief.
You see a Tarent. case and they will do 7 things at one time. This is the idea, there is not enough time for me.
I have to do this, I have to do that.
They go make the bed, at the same time take the duster, it's a crazy situation.
Then they finish in half an hour, they don't have to do something more. Now what?
Of course there is energy there. They put the radio, the music and they start dancing by themselves.
'You dance by yourself?' He says 'yes, loud music'.
One time I asked a Tarent. case
just for the shake of the students.
I said 'how loud you put the music?', He said, 'I will give you an example. I have some wardrobes, the music
vibrates the wardrobes so they open'. Full decibel.
And the more loud the music, the better they feel and then the energy comes down.  It says 'better with music',
it's not only better, it's very much better. A headache with strong music, a depression with strong music, and dancing.
And of course with all this energy which is there they cannot sleep.
Their sleep may be 3 hours the day.
They get up and they don't know what to do. 3 o'clock in the morning they have to get up, what to do?
They say 'I go to the garden, I dig...etc'. They have to do things to expend the energy.
The main point with them is that they are bothered by others doing their job slowly.
In case somebody is in the same office and there is a Tarent. they look at him, taking this book, opening it slowly
putting it down and then he says 'I'm going crazy!'
Especially when they have employees. With a Tarent. boss nobody can stay because he wants to finish before
he has given the job. You have to finish the job.
And of course with all this energy aggression is there, very great aggression.
Just to give you an example, I remember a case.
A man working in a bank and you know in a bank in a big hall like this, there are different desks.
I said to him 'do you fight?'. Because with this energy and aggression they are quarelsome. It says in the book quarrelsome.
They go into a fight immediately, they quarrel.
'Do you quarrel sometimes?'. 'Sometimes? I will just give you an example. I work here and somebody
said something that irritated me, in the other side. So I did not have time to go through the corridors and I jumped
over the desks of the different people and I grabbed him there.
So fast and so irritable!
If you have a Tarent. case on a video, the energy which is emitted from such case is tremendous!
The whole class is recharged with the energy of the patient. It is fantastic, the way they talk.
There are of course manic depressive cases that will need Tarent. M.S. cases they need Tarent. and cases of alcoholism.
I remember a case, an alcoholic, and I touched his arms and I felt underneath all the nervous system was going like that.
He was in the last stage, he would see nightmares, just open his eyes. It was terrible state and he was going like that .
I prescribed Tarent. for him. He stopped drinking for a period of time, then he relapsed, he went back
and he didn't come back to us but his wife told us that for a few months he stopped.
Excess energy which is expanded in dancing, desire to dance, desire strong music etc. can be self-destructive also.
They will hit themselves on the wall, they will tear their clothes, mental cases. The energy in mental cases where we have
this excess energy exploding suddenly in severe mentally ill people, these are cases of Tarent.
M.S. yes.
Because of the nervous system. Once there is this hyperactivity of the person and you have the idea of Tarent.,
whatever it might be the neuro muscular disease, the nervous system is affected.
The nervous system not that they have specific symptom, they have to have this type of person.
They eat very fast, they talk fast and also symptoms will appear suddenly and they will go away also suddenly.
Headache will appear suddenly and it will go out suddenly.
-How do you differentiate Nux -v. from Tarent.? Because it is also in a hurry, explosive, tears things apart.
- Nux-v. will never have this hurriedness feeling, that's first. Also Nux -v. will not like this strong noise from music.
They cannot tolerate it. Nux-v. will not be so much extroverted. Tarent. is totally extroverted.
Nux-v. will keep inside, that's why they suffer with their stomach. The aggression and the anger is kept inside.
With Tarent. is not possible to keep it inside.
And of course in the sexual sphere you will have all this excess energy, this extrovert person.
They are almost in a state of mania constantly, the sexual energy is very strong and therefore they become very promiscuous.
They have to have sex. Suddenly the hormones come, we have to have sex.
What they can do is unbelievable.
I remember a mental case in France. They called me to treat. It was a girl of a very aristocratic family and she was crazy.
When I asked the mother about that area, sex, she said...
...'I can't believe it. Sometimes when she needs to have sex she will go out in the street and pick a man'.
It is not possible to control at all. Like the anger which cannot be controlled.
When the anger comes, the adrenaline is in the blood, then they have to expand it by violent act.
Tarentulas are people, they are in a hurry. They leave the car and they have to go upstairs. They will always run.
They will not walk properly. 2-3 steps each time, no reason. He has arrived home, he has to relax, it doesn't matter.
-I have one question concerning the remedy in the last line of the mental symptoms, it says extreme violence and desire to kill.
Does this violence mean physical violence injuring people or is it meant in a sense of intensity?
-Extreme violence and desire to kill is the peak of the anger.
It can reach such peak the anger that they want to do violence. They are not controlled.
You see we don't do violence, even if we are very mad, there is no violence for a person who is normal.
These people they can kill of course. If the Tarent. pathology is established and it is there for years, they are the people
who will take the gun and do violence.
It's very strange you hear it in the news, the newspapers. They say, suddenly this man, he was nice
he grabs somebody and kills him and shoots him.
All these are pathological cases. Stram., Tarent., Hyos.
If you have given the remedy before, I believe they would never committed these crimes.
It's a great pity that Homeopathy is kept so much to the background and it's not widely accepted and spread and practiced.
But time is coming, it will happen. Never mind the resistance.
The Russians were the revolutionists.
Eventually they developed a philosophy which was expressed with a proverb.
Somebody from the communists who have been to Russia, told me this story in Russia,  she says,
we say that a young man who does not fight the establishment, does not have heart, he is heartless.
And old men who fight the establishment do not have brains.
If you become old and you still fight the establishment, no brains. But a young man has to fight the establishment.
So it seems I have no brains.
According to this philosophy, I have no brains, finished.
-You are not Russian.
-I'm not Russian but I have found out it's very wise.
Because you get tired, you fight, you fight and you hit here, you hit there.
Then you say, I give up. I go with the establishment.
You need some stupid people also in this world.
Desire for sand. Tarent. children are taking sand and eat it.
Also there is another element in the face of Tarent. which is this cunning look.
I have to show you sometime on a case, to show you what I mean. There is a cunningness, there is
something which is playful and at the same time foxy.
But definitely in order to give Tarent. you have to have this excess energy which is ameliorated by rhythmic motion or strong music.
You see especially the Germans who like music it's not they are Tarentulas because everyone likes music, it's different.
With Tarent. the music has to be very strong and very rhythmic.
The rock music, this rythmic music which is played very fast.
A person who is cultivated in understanding music, they don't like this type of music.
It's very interesting they say in old times when somebody was bitten by Tarent., the cure was to call the band of the village
and play rhythmically while the person was lying down with convulsions and vomiting and spitting.
-I had one Tarent. case which I treated.
He had tumor of the testes, it was not painful,
I knew this young man  he was 30 years at that time.
For an entire night he told me his thoughts, what he is thinking and how sex appeals to him.
He had not only the desire to dance too extreme with loud music but from time to time he had to paint.
Large pictures. Besides that everything had to be extreme in his life, not only music and the large paintings but also travelling.
To make it short, this young man had an operation and received chemotherapy...
...he already had metastasis...
...and after that he received Tarent. and after that he fathered a child.
Eventhough before they had told him he would not be able to have children.
Today he does not have this violence anymore...
...but he did not return for treatment. 3 years ago.
-That's typical case. All this energy goes to the sexual sphere primarily with all these kind of perversions
promiscuity, they want to do all kinds of sex, double sex, triple sex, whatever you call it.
- I have two questions. Do we know why people get into Tarent. state, like in Asar. we said they press themselves?
The second is how do I, in a 4 old child having problems, differentiate Iod. from Tarent.?
-Restlessness in little children and aggressive. Fighting, attacking very easily, the restlessness will be prominent while
the fear of dark will not be there.
Between Iod? Iod. is not violent.  It will not show such violence. It will show restlessness and heat in the body.
The Tarent. is a warm remedy but not a very warm remedy. Iod. is very warm remedy.
- I wanted to add that the mother is also Tarent.
She was never treated. She developed breast cancer at the same time.
Would it be possible that very deep psychological disturbances which were present during the pregnancy, could be the cause?
-When we are talking about a constitutional like this, what we described here, the pure type, what we call the constitutional types,
these types they don't have to be produced by a certain stress.
Such patients can be from birth and stay on the Tarent. level for the rest of their lives.
Also Tarent. is because of the strength of the organism, these are strong organisms, they are doing very well
in whatever problem they may have.
It is also very strange, you know I brought the idea of not coffee, don't drink coffee because I found out that coffee
antidotes the homeopathic treatment. I had a Tarent. case and I told him also don't drink coffee.
He came with a relapse 9 months to 1 year later, if I remember well, and I asked him why?
He said, 'I had been drinking coffee constantly, I did not pay attention to what you said' but it lasted for 9 months
before he relapsed. Another case at the most one month, drinking coffee every day will relapse.
He lasted 9 months drinking coffee.
The organisms are very very strong.