Staph. is full of feelings.
Feelings that cannot be expressed.
It's a remedy which has been sensitized in its feelings...
that means the feelings are sensitive,
strong and therefore vulnerable.
If you have a lot of feelings, you feel for everything, then you are exposed to vulnerability.
You can be easily hurt. If you close
your feelings, then you can protect yourself.
Staph. therefore wants to protect
itself by not expressing the feelings.
Not that she does not have the feelings.
Nat-m. does not have the feelings.
Cuts down the feelings, no feelings.
Sepia no feelings but Ignatia is in between Nat-m. and Staph. and Staph. has feelings but they cannot be expressed.
Can you understand this? Cannot be expressed.
The reason is because she has been hurt repeatedly.
And then she decides that it is better not to have a confrontation because always she is the one who loses.
Never felt bad in a consultation.
I'll explain to you. Do you know why
you feel bad in a consultation?
Somebody comes and you feel bad, that means you feel tired and then you say, he sucked my energy and this and that.
What is happening actually is that there is no communication.
If a person is closed, no feelings, only brain is working  and talking and you try to get information
there is no real communication. You feel isolated.
A patient like that is a patient who belongs to a group of remedies, different than other group.
With Staph. she will never express her anger especially, she will sit there and she will have feelings.
That means there is going to be a communication, if you are open.
So you perceive only if your feelings are open. And you communicate and then you understand.
You will tell me, how can I be open to everybody? Everybody who comes there, first of all it's dangerous to be open.
Because you are exposed to a lot of dangers. The second thing is that it requires a lot of energy
to have feelings all the time for every patient who comes.
And then you are tired and exhausted. Feelings are gone. But at the same time see how you understand.
You have somebody with whom you live, your husband, your wife etc.
And she comes in the room,
you look and say what's the matter?
She has said nothing. What's the matter?
What happened?
Can anybody else understand these
little changes in the face of that woman?
Only the one who loves her, can understand. What happened? Something happened to you.
The others don't realize anything.
So you love, you have feelings,
you understand in depth.
Nobody can tell you lies. You say, 'you
are not feeling good today. Why?', 'Leave it'.
But the change, what you see is absolutely minimal in the face of the person and you can guarantee that
100, 200 people can see the person, cannot understand that this is happening in her, so inner feelings.
Only you can understand.
What are the changes? Minimal.
Why you understand? Because you are open to that person. There is a communication then you understand.
Now a person comes to be treated and you are going to try to perceive what has happened in her feelings...
...in her soul, in her mental condition and
the bodily feelings are easily described.
But this openess in communication is necessary. With Staph. you don't have a problem.
She will show you who she is. She is a sweet, sensitive person who will not ever be angry.
She will never be angry. It's a very nice feeling for you, for the husband, for anybody.
She is not going to demand...'I told you!'
Never from Staph. You will never get that reaction from Staph.
The anger is there, is inside but the more the anger, the more the trembling, the more the pressure
which develops inside but she will be controlled.
And she will withdraw the emotions but the emotions do not die with Staph. Emotions are there.
And in spite of the fact that the husband has many times insulted her, even in public.
If you do this with another remedy, with Sepia the feelings are gone very fast, with Nat-m. closed, finished, she insulted me.
With Nux-v, just closed and then it comes the anger back.
With Staph. you insult and then she gets it inside but the feelings do not die. That means she keeps on loving the husband.
She can make sex with him the same night.
With Nat-m. forget it, five days.
Don't' touch me.
Staph. she seems to forget, why? Because the feelings are there, alive and she can communicate.
You see why in one case the woman says no and the other says yes? Because if the feelings are alive...
...there is communication, there is understanding, there is no this emptiness, this feeling of enstrangement.
If the feelings are closed, you have sex with somebody? You feel, who is he, who is she?
This feelings of estrangement because there are no feelings.
Therefore Staph. will keep the anger inside but will keep the emotions as well.
As long as this can be tolerated. And she tolerates, she tolerates ...
...and that's why we say in Homeopathy ...
...before you give Staph. you must think of the possibility what is going to happen, especially in a marriage situation.
Because the moment you give Staph.  then Staph. cannot anymore tolerate inside.
And she will hit back.
You give Staph. and the husband is very much used to come home, make me some coffee, take the newspaper...
Then one day she takes Staph. he comes home he says, 'make me the coffee', she says, 'you do it yourself'.
You have said so many times, you are insensitive, you are this, you are that, Staph. comes out.
And there is a possibility of course he will be able to suppress again and then you repeat the potency, higher potency.
There are two things that may happen. One is that the husband decides to change his behavior or change woman.
There is no third solution. Sometimes the marriage becomes better, fuller, more complete and both are satisfied
but sometimes also Staph. realizes I can't take it anymore and she may divorce.
In Staph. situation you see the social repercussions of disease.
You see we are living in a society which each one is diseased and we are interrelated.
And disease plays a major part
in what we have created as a society today.
Who is the society today? What is doing? It's doing wars, killings....
...competition, anxiety. I want to attain more and more.
And then we lose the basics.
Staph. is a person who is close to health...
... because it's more diseased to close
the emotions and stop the emotions. That is
more diseased
than Staph. Staph. closes, keeps the anger inside  cannot express the anger but still it's a better situation.
She is in a better place because still Staph. enjoys.
If you don't have feelings, enjoyment goes away. In Sepia you remember we said, no feelings, she cannot even
enjoy her own children. No pleasure from looking at the children, playing, doing things, indifferent.
Sepia, no feelings.
That's why I said, when we see through Homeopathy, the feelings are reenergized, then that is very
very good to hear for Homeopathy.
For the progress of the person.
But the feelings may energize but maybe the heart is already in a bad condition, it breaks down or the liver
is in a bad condition or the thyroid.
And then you have to carry on treating.
Then Staph. can go into the other extreme. That means she cannot tolerate anything at all and she loses control
and she starts reacting too much.
That's why it says in the Repertory you will
see throwing things, Staph. capital.
When the anger is so much she has to take
this and just throw it; but with a difference.
I have seen a few acute insanity cases with Staph. They are all expressing this, throw the plates, throw the vase
just throw things as if she wants to take all
the anger out what it has been left inside.
She wants to take it out by throwing things. Still on this condition you will see a kind of sweetness
you will not see violence. It's very
interesting, you will not see violence.
I remember one man, I have seen in America, who was the most violent Staph.
He said, 'I drive with my car and
somebody does some unjust to me...
...he doesn't allow me to pass and things like that and then the other guy opens the window and throws an insult to him.
And he says, 'I go home and I'm trembling and I want to hit my head on the wall. Stupid, why didn't you also insult him?
Why didn't you get out of the car and just go and kill him?'
But he cannot do it, he just thinks about it but he cannot do it. When I gave Staph. to this man, he says Stram., Hyos.
I say, no, no.
Hyos. when he wants to kill, he means it. 'I want to kill', it is another feeling all together.
You get the coldness in the eyes, you don't get communication.
You get something but this belongs to the area of deep observation of very sensitive observation of course.
But in Hyos. you get in the eyes a feeling that she can really do it. She can kill at a certain moment, it's a coldness.
Staph. because it's expressing the anger, he describes different incidents where he wanted to.... but it was impossible.
He would go back home and hit his head on the wall saying you are so coward, you are so stupid. Gels., give me Gels. No, no.
The idea of I want to express anger and I cannot. And I want to throw things, I cannot. I want to kill, I cannot.
You have a constitutional Staph. that means the child is born Staph. a Staph. child that will not be able to express anger
but at the same time having that vulnerability. Feeling inside that sensitivity. The child is growing
and is protected by the mother especially. They create a good environment for the child Staph.
The child Staph. will develop most probably into a kind of...he cannot become a man.
You see a man is connected with the idea of conqueror. You want to conquer, you want to be the power.
Staph. is lacking that. It is rather giving because it has a lot of sensitive emotions.
So if the child is born like this, it has a problem
in having a relationship with somebody else.
A boy who is very sensitive, very shy, who looks, who observes, he knows, he feels but at the same time he feels he can be hurt.
If he tells me that, what shall  I say?
In Staph. the feelings are alive, also the sexual sphere is alive but they lack the power to express outside.
That is why you will see usually in men that desire for sex. The desire is alive, what is he going to do?
He is going to resort to masturbation.
Because he cannot have the normal sexual relationship.
Not all men will be like that, not at all but I say it might be the case.
I once treated a case a man of 38 years old and he had never had any relationship.
But he was masturbating since the age of 10,11 something like that.
He did not have homosexual tendencies or relations.
He got into the habit of masturbation and he was not able to communicate with the other sex.
You see the woman wants to feel that the man is  stronger, she can rely. Staph. is not stronger.
Staph. is the person who supports with the feeling the husband. That's why the husbands who have Staph. wives
they say, my wife is the best.
Because they go at home and they do whatever they like. Always the woman is there, available.
With all her feelings, with all her love. You insult her, 5 min., 15 min. she forgets it, again the feelings come.
In the night you want to have sex. OK have sex. It goes like this until all that builds up and one day she says, 'I had enough'.
But by herself actually is very difficult
that Staph. will say 'I had enough'.
That means she got out of the Staph. situation  and then even if she does this, from time to time actually
if you ask Staph. they say, yes from time to time I break out my anger quite violently.
I may throw things and do all kind of things but then it passes away.
Under the remedy, this does not go away.
The organism is lifted and the person understands that this makes me sick, I don't want it.
And that's why she goes into extremes like divorce sometimes.
In the Repertory it is expressed all that in words. But actually what you have to understand is the structure of the individual.
Feelings alive, anger is there, cannot be expressed but the feelings are alive, the sexual sphere is alive
very alive but difficult to bring it out.
It's typical when you examine a Staph. you give an example where she has to suppress her anger
and the most common is when you sit on a queue and there are a lot of people in front and you wait for half an hour there.
And somebody tries to get there.
The Nux-v. says, 'Mr. go back'.
Staph. never will be able to say one word.
She can sit there and observe that, the anger is there but forget it. No way you can make her say
'please why don't you go back?'
Even that she cannot.
You go with Tarentula, he will
grab him and just throw him back.
These ideas will give the right remedy, the in depth remedy.
You say styes a lot of styes this is a hint
for investigating the possibility of Staph.
If every time you see styes you give Staph. sometimes will be correct but this is not enough to understand.
And we have enough information today for Staph. to understand in depth what is going on.
And then we see the acute Staph. situation where she is going mad. She has an acute insanity
and then she will swear, she will say bad words and she will throw things.
She will get up in the morning and the husband suddenly sees the whole kitchen is down.
She is gone out, finished. Call the doctor. And then she tells different things expressing anger.
One of the doctors of the center, it was a Sunday evening, she managed to put the patient into her car
and brought the patient in my home.
She was in a terrible state. She would say this, she would say that, she would express.
She was mostly angry with her mother in law. Her mother in law had suppressed her too much
and until she was lead to insanity.
So this insanity case she was doing all that, she was so angry. You know the doctor did not know what to do.
I noticed that she was so sweet, doing
all that but sweetness was coming out.
While the action was violent, the words were violent, the eyes were producing sweetness.
You don't understand that but this is Staph.
You see anger can be killing.
You see anger with viciousness.
Nux-v., Aur., Lil-t., they are vicious in their anger.
With Staph.  no. It's anger but not vicious. You understand vicious?
Tell me another word for vicious. Malicious.
It's very interesting that in Staph. these cutting words of whoever is connected with, it is like cutting the soul
and leaving a mark in the soul.
The same thing that you see in the physical body a sharp instrument like the surgeon cuts the physical body
and then there it remains the pain.
The organism cannot get rid of that pain and we have after surgery pain that remains for very long time is treated.
You see injuries from sharp object. It's the same idea actually.
There is another characteristic of Staph.
We said she is full of feelings, she is full of sexual desire, energy but Staph. usually do not have
especially women, a lot of affairs. Therefore the woman may be just marry the man who has met, the first man
who met and they are married and then they try to have sex.
Now what happens with Staph.  There is an over excitement.
It means a lot of blood supply into the area where this becomes very sensitive.
And with the excitement and this and sexual intercourse immediately after you will have this cystitis
which begins from the first intercourse or
after intercourse. It is not after intercourse.
It's when the excitement is too much and after the excitement in Staph. it's not a matter of being infected.
It's a matter of over supply of blood. That means the organs becomes very stimulated and then the cystitis starts.
Where the same thing if it happens because of the husband, the woman is not over stimulated and then it's Med.
That means you need Med. It means that the husband has been infected and in continuation infects the woman
and then she starts with cystitis, after a few days.
Usually with a layer of Med. in a woman you can see that she has been infected during her marriage
and because of the infection she starts having cystitis, another cystitis, another cystitis.
Then eventually she comes to you.
This belongs to group 2 where you give a remedy and jumps to group 1 and then cystitis ceases.
Then she may have a cystitis once the year, once every two years.
This is the type that she can be infected by gonorrhea.
Lower lever 3 and 4 cannot be infected by gonorrhea.
If you are in that level, you can have free sex. Don't protect.
I don't advice you that but anyhow you understand I hope.
Also in Staph. children we see an over excitement, we observe early masturbation and we observe
only sometimes the teeth turn black.
You see a child and a lot of teeth are becoming black in the base of the dentine.
There are discolorations which they look black.
Dwells on sexual matters.
Do you know what it means that? I will tell you.
It means that, for instance, a man goes to bed to sleep. He is not married and fantasizes a lot of sexual activities.
And then eventually he goes to sleep.
Either he goes to sleep or to masturbation or whatever. The idea is that sex occupies a lot. It's very strong element
with this remedy, it occupies a lot on the thoughts of the person. So it lies down and likes to fantasize
sexual matters which are not violent sex. It is
not so much sexual, it's more romantic sex.
Why? The sensitivity of Staph. requires that element of tenderness. You treat Staph. with tenderness
with kindness, with respect and she will give you everything.
She has no resistance but start hurting her, she closes, closes and then finally the explosion comes.
Something else we have to say about Staph. which is again characteristic and in most of the cases you will see it.
It's a very strong keynote.
When they sleep in the night time and they wake up in the morning, it's very good but if they try to sleep in the afternoon
and especially if they stay for more than half an hour asleep, one hour in the afternoon, they get up and they cannot.
They feel so rotten from afternoon sleep.
They say, 'if I sleep 5 minutes it's OK but if I sleep more than half an hour I can't get up, can't wake.'
They sleep deep and the sleep is not refreshing.
-I wanted to ask about the sexual dwelling. I understand that Staph. cannot be someone who would rape
because he is too tender. He cannot do it by force.
Is there any situation that if a woman accepts him and wants him, he cannot resist?
Anything like showing of love or acceptance from woman he would not be able to resist her invitation?
Is it something which might be typical for Staph.
-What we have to understand also is that Staph. has an element of femininity, not homosexuality.
He can be homosexual, he can go to that direction but it's femininity.
Therefore a man who has femininity is not aggressive and usually is the woman who takes the first initiative to invite.
And Staph. can respond very nicely but as long as will feel secure.
Why the Staph.  don't make easy love affairs? They are not the type of people they will run away.
Who are that type? Med., Tarent., Nux-v., Lyc., yes. Staph. no. She is too sensitive to do that.
So if a man is invited, then he has to feel secure to go ahead. Otherwise resist.
-When Staph. sleeps in the afternoon they don't feel good the whole evening or for an hour ?
-They are not feeling well for an hour, not
for the whole evening. The most one hour.
There are a lot of other remedies which are doing that. Oversleeping and then not feeling well.
Nat-s., Sulph. etc. but this has to say, after sleep I avoid it because I feel terrible if I go into a nap in the afternoon.
-I got a bit confused. You start telling that people with little change in the face you will not notice, only very little change.
What picture is this?
-No, no. I said in order to understand somebody you have to love them, you have to care about them and
if you love and care, you will notice even little changes.
I said how you communicate. You communicate by loving, by feeling things. Staph. has feelings, therefore
you communicate, therefore you feel good.
Otherwise as a doctor you can feel isolated and tired. Not with Staph.
-What picture is this when you feel
isolated? Is this Nat-m.?
-This can be Nat-m., it can be Ign., closed remedies.
But in the Repertory it says ailments from grief, Staph. is capital, silent grief, Staph. is there.
But the feeling you get is different.
You don't get the feeling of isolation, you feel good. That is a sign that the person  is open in his emotions
and this you don't go to the wrong remedies.
Also I said that in order to understand a person who is sitting in front of you, you have to keep your feelings
open but that does not mean you have a love affair because then you cannot cure the person.
Because you don't see objectively anymore and that's finished. You send this patient to your colleague
you do whatever you like, forget about treating this person because you love him/her.
You don't see objectively anymore.
So you have to have open feelings but at the same time not get attached. Difficult.
Especially when there is communication. The patient has open feelings, you have open feelings
and then there is communication. You have to learn to withdraw.
I learn as much I want, thank you, not anymore, I don't want to hear. We don't' want to hear stories, we want to find the remedy.
We are not interested because if you are so much attracted to somebody, you want to know everything.
That is not Homeopathy. Homeopathy is to get enough information to get down to the picture.
You get the remedy, finished the interview. Otherwise it is dangerous, I'm telling you.
When I develop the case it is all this
that I said is perceived in a flash.
You get the feeling, maybe Staph.
You may ask one question.
How do you feel after afternoon sleep? You get immediately answer, I can't have it.
That's all you need, finished. Never mind the affairs and not affairs and things like that. That you are not interested.
We are not curing people because of the placebo effect. That means because we are nice.
When we talk like that and somebody is listening to us, they say you are so analytical but the moment you sit down
with the patient, you are not analytical, you are just an observer. But you are open observer.
The patient does not know what you are looking for. So the patient he may even go angry out
A Nat-m. she will go out of the consultation feeling totally bad, especially if she has said a little bit about her own state.
Confessing, saying what she is feeling.
She says goes out of the consultation and
says, 'I was ridiculous, I almost cried'
And then they start feeling bad.
They go to sleep and they cannot sleep.
Because they had a bad consultation. What was bad in consultation? She spoke about certain things which are a bit deeper.
So we don't have the placebo effect. It's all nonsense.
We have the placebo effect but
not as curing but as an amelioration.
In the center in Athens what I had noticed,
they were 30 doctors working.
2 of them they did not attend the classes,
they don't know Homeopathy.
So they pass all the cases to somebody
else or they prescribe wrongly.
But they are the doctors who have the most clients, no client will leave them.
So you get finally the case, after a year nothing has happened and you prescribe, finally you find the remedy.
But in the meantime, one year the patient comes why?
Because they have the knack to behave well with the patient.
They are nice with people, this is the placebo effect but the patient is not cured.
He says, maybe in this I'm better and they talk and they get out and their inside.
If you talk and if somebody is interested, yes you are going to have a rapport and if you are open
you are going to keep your patients.
Even if they are not getting better. But then you know that this is a placebo effect. You give the remedy
and he comes back and says, a little bit this and that, I'm better and then they continue.
Never mind what you give, they are better. But not really. In the end, when you take the sum results
of your treatment, you see nothing.
That means he never got the right remedy.
-Do you mean that all the things we say to our patients is a placebo ? When I talk to a patient, I think our voice
has a tone and a frequency like the homeopathic remedies. As the color has, I don't see it as a placebo.
-When you talk nicely and you are behaving nicely and the person is satisfied after the consultation
is a psychological interaction.
This is what they do in psychotherapy.
In psychotherapy, they claim they have results...
...and I have patients 10,15 years in psychotherapy being exactly the same as when they started.
The difference is that they depend on that conversation with the psychiatrist.
And if they visit every week or every 10 days or they telephone, I feel that, they explain.
Now in America for instance they find all kinds of insight things which have happened in the past, mother, father.
They interfere with everything.
Your father died and you were in excursion and you didn't see him dying, that has remained for the rest of your life
and that's why you have this guilt feelings.
And I said, OK now you know that, the guilt feelings they go away. Why they don't go away?
The psychiatrist told me, he found out that it is because I didn't see my father that I have these guilt feelings.
Very good, now you know let's see what happens. Nothing. It's the same.
The anxiety is the same, the guilt feelings are the same. And then they find another excuse.
After you go on with these feelings of not seeing the father the moment he died, then they find another one.
Because your mother did not give you enough whatever....
...and they say all this useless talking
but necessary because people are suffering and
they have
to have some kind of release.
This is one type of release, communicating.
If you have a good relationship in your life with a man or a woman do you need a psychiatrist?
Why do you need the psychiatrist. You have your woman, you say I'm terribly upset today
because this has happened and the woman understands, she suffers with you, then it's finished, it's over.
Then you don't need to go to the psychiatrist. Or if you don't have a good relationship, the woman comes
'every time you come home you bring all your problems, I don't want your problems at home'.
Then you need a psychiatrist.
Of course because you can't express anything in the house.
I will get a psychiatrist and go and tell I was so upset etc. The psychiatrist will say 'yes I understand you'.
Sometimes they sleep. By the time they talk, the psychiatrist sleeps, it doesn't matter, as long as the patient talks.
That's the idea. You have seen the films, you have seen psychiatrists sitting on the back and sleeping, and snoring.
But it is necessary because he cannot have
a natural outlet in the proper situation.
When I resist my anger, this anger is going to go inside and kill me. This is the idea with Staph.
It's going to go inside and kill her. What it does? What are the pathologies which Staph. develop?
One of the pathology it can be affecting the nervous system and producing chorea.
Chorea in children which have been reprimanded and they cannot take it, they are sensitive.
And the first time the father shouted so much and then they start with the chorea movements.
And so therefore Staph. becomes for pathology one of the main remedies in chorea in children.
Also it's one of the main remedies in psoriasis in children, especially when the psoriasis is generalized.
If the child is sensitive and they don't cry easily, they will keep inside and then psoriasis comes out.
And this psoriasis can stay for many many years of course and then it comes as grown ups.
I like also to hear when we lecture and we have an experience or a case, I would like to hear and the class would like to hear
instead of me telling because I may be telling whatever I like, I like to hear from you, your own experience concerning this remedy.
And I had a cases like this, I'm interested, I'm learning also. I'm open to learning all the time.
I don't say 'now that's it', no. I see something else one time, I keep it. I see it again, something is going on.
And then this becomes knowledge. Then you apply the new information, then it works, then it becomes knowledge.
That is how Homeopathy can develop really. And develop realistically, not by imagining things.
You were in the orphanage? You need Tuberculinum.
That was told to me and I said, what is this because you are an orphan? Yes. Who said that? I tried to trace this
and then they say, this person who
heard it from you. I say, forget it.
This is becoming projecting and distorting the information and finally reaching the information in totally different manner.
At the same time you have to have the sexual excitement. That means going in the night, fantasizing all the time
and ending up most of the time in masturbation. And what is happening with Staph. also?
It's not that he or she goes to masturbation and feels good, no.
They feel bad because they are sensitive. What am I doing? They feel it's not right but they do it next day
and it's not right and they suffer because of this.
In the same way they suffer after sexual intercourse.
I remember one case he said, I feel bad for 4 days, exhausted, low energy, depression for 4 days.
And it was a man, actually he was a black man in America, a doctor who said, I have a problem because
I need more but I cannot do it because of the after effect.
The after effect, that means releasing the sexual energy does not give satisfaction but a dissatisfaction.
-I had a case of a 40 years old woman who had desire to become pregnant, who after many years of marriage
and going to hospitals and fertility clinics was unsuccessful in bearing children.
At first I had given Nat-m. and within few weeks she became pregnant but there was a spontaneous abortion
and again I repeated the Nat-m. Again she became pregnant and a spontaneous abortion.
Finally I asked her because she was very lovely, very sophisticated, quiet, delightful person very demure
in her disposition and I said, 'how badly you want this child?' She says, 'I wanted this child all my life.'
I said, 'how would you raise your child?' She said, 'I would raise this child with all the love and affection that
every woman on the planet could give'. 'And how would your husband would raise the child?'
She said, 'I would never let that son of the bitch touch her'.
So many red flags went up and finally it came to pass that she finally acknowledged that she had been in abusive
relationship physically and emotionally for the last 12 years with her husband. And I gave her Staph. 10M
and within 4 months she was divorced. She was remarried within 6 months and then proceeded to have 3 children
without any additional remedy.
-This aggravation after coition goes also in women?
-Also in women yes.
They desire very much , the desire is there but the after effect is bad and it's bad physically
on the physical body but emotionally also.
The masturbation leaves not so much physical problems as much as psychological problems.
-I want to relate an experience with Staph. I had a man about 40 years old, he had terrible headache.
And what brought me to Staph. because he was an engineer, he didn't have any children, his wife was at home
all the time and he came in the evening, did the laundry. So I gave him Staph. and a week later the wife called and said
'what did you do with my husband? I had such a nice husband'. I said 'how's the headache?'
'The headache is better but he doesn't want to put the laundry anymore'.
-I want to stress also that we're describing here as Staph. is on group 1 level. We're describing the Staph.
here and we give the full picture.
You will ask me, you won't find Staph. in group 4? You will find but not as a full picture.
As you go down, the picture becomes smaller and smaller.
So here maybe the Staph. is there but the effect is not going to be clear, it's going to be mixed with other remedies.
You give the remedy, it clears up a little bit the ground, it has some effect but not the effect that you are describing
here in these cases where you give the Staph. and they divorce etc.
Don't expect this to happen in these cases, when you have the deep pathology here.
You just have a little bit of an effect
and then you proceed for the next remedy.
-I have 2 questions concerning Staph. One is I used to be a lawyer and from my practice as a lawyer
I can remember that I met several women
who were in very difficult relationships. They were beaten
by the husbands and I really got engaged for them and made sure that they can keep the apartment and so on.
Very often then I experienced that either they make peace again with the same man they had beaten them before
or they ended the relationship, got a divorce and then started the next relationship with a very similar type of man again.
-That's correct.
Yes this can be done by Staph. women.
What you are describing can be done by a Staph. woman. This is the psychology.
-It is masochistic a little bit.
-Well not exactly because masochism is different where you like to be hit. You like pain. Staph. does not like pain.
It takes it inside, the anger raises but this is up to here and then it doesn't come out. The anger is there.
You hit me. It's the pain and you feel if you are sensitive at all, you see it immediately in the feelings of the woman.
You brought pain! But she doesn't say, you brought pain, you hit me. You just see a little change on her face.
And she just turns around and leaves.
It's totally different.
You hit Tarentula or Nux-v., Graph.,
and you will see what happens.
-The second question is Staph. is the main remedy in the rubric 'cannot tolerate injustice'. So it's a main remedy
if you have a case you ask a patient who cannot tolerate injustice, you will always think of Caust.
Why do we not think at first Staph.
-The 'cannot tolerate injustice', first of all is a natural feeling. Everyone cannot tolerate.
What we say here as pathology it means
little injustice brings tremendous reaction.
This is pathology. Then they say, you are crazy. Why you do like this?
They have described to me, for instance, a Caust. they see in the street a man who goes with his donkey
and the donkey knows that it's going to get one in the back. And the man just hits it in the back  and the donkey
speeds up and Caust. sees that and wants to jump on this man who hit the donkey, and hit him.
This is over reaction. It is not an injustice, simply injustice which everyone has.
There are injustices which are made in the world. For instance the Turks are doing a lot of injustice to the Kurds.
They are the power, they go there and they hit them. We all hear it, we say poor men, we don't do anything.
A Causticum will think what can I do?
Thinks, thinks, sees the injustice and then he prepares to make a bomb and kill the Prime Minister of Turkey.
He will have to do that. Somebody says, you are crazy, they will catch you, they will kill you. He cannot resist.
That's Caust. Staph. is different in injustice.
Cannot tolerate injustice means, I take it inside and I suffer and I don't say anything.
So both you can say they cannot tolerate injustice but the one is revolutionary...
... he wants really to throw a bomb, he is revolutionary.
The other one will suffer inside because he cannot express, he cannot say, you have been unjust to me.
You give Staph. and then she will say it.
-I just wanted to tell you about a case I had many years ago and I didn't know very much about Homeopathy.
It was a lady that had really bad back. She couldn't sit down, she couldn't lie, she couldn't move at all.
So I gave her Bry. and she got a little bit better. And then she came back and we were working on it
and suddenly one day she had this terrible back pain and I asked her if something had happened.
She said, she had a discussion with her boss at work. So I thought about Staph. I asked her if she could tell him off
and she said, 'no I could never do that'.
So I gave her Staph. and the pain was gone.
Then after quite half a year she telephoned me and she said, 'I've been in bed for 3 days with a terrible backache'.
I said why? She said I've been watching a movie on the television about some boys that were abused.
I said why did that come so strong to you? And she said, you know it was just what my father did to me
when I was a young girl. And I didn't know before and I gave her Staph. again and it was gone.
-How do we differentiate in chorea in children who have been reprimanded between Staph. and Agar.?
-The Agar. will have more little muscles twitching. The Agar. also will have a different type, as we described.
The Agar. is somebody who is weak willed and anxious to the extreme.
You will have several points in which you may be differentiating...
...and the Staph. will not be prescribed on the movements. It will be prescribed on the type of the person.
Pall. also will have similar situations from reprimand.
But in the Pall. the main issue that you will see is he is not recognized. He does not get the recognition he needs.
They don't tell him, 'you are a good boy'.
They need to be told every time, every day, if it's possible, 'you are a very good boy'. It is like Puls.
It's a craving for recognition.
Not consolation. Puls. is similar, recognition. 'You are a good student. You are a good doctor'. This is not consolation.