Thuja
I will give you some keynotes of Thuja.
Thuja is a very interesting remedy because was used quite a lot in older times
when vaccination for smallpox was a general practice and side effects of vaccination appeared to be manageable with Thuja.
I don’t know why, I don’t understand, an old homeopath Burnett found
that whatever side effects were produced by smallpox vaccination were nullified by Thuja.
I remember myself being vaccinated as a child, usually the smallpox vaccination made a tumor and left always a mark.
I still have the mark in my thigh.
This tendency is a very characteristic of Thuja.
It has the tendency to produce warts, excrescences, moles, growths in general.
It affects the glands, produces swelling of the glands.
If you will see a person who is a typical Thuja person
and you look at him you will see all over big moles, warts, and growths.
It’s a pantheon of growths! It is true.
The skin is quite oily, greasy, hair is greasy but the hair itself is very dry.
Have you seen these youngsters today who put gel and make the hair like this?
This is almost typical of Thuja.
If you see them their hair stands and you touch their hair and it’s not soft. It’s hard.
If we go to physical characteristics for men we see very frequently
swelling of the prostate gland and many times cancer of the prostate.
I remember as I child all the children praying together, most of the children had these warts in the fingers.
Once these growths are out there is no danger for the organism.
The danger comes if they cauterize these growths.
I remember a case we had seen, a woman who had come for mental problems, almost psychotic woman.
She had been for years to a gynecologist who was cauterizing the growths in her vagina.
She told the story, cauterized again came out and so on, said ok give Thuja.
She became well and then the warts were out again!
She goes to visit the gynecologist and he calls us and told us that you gave a remedy
and the growths I’ve been cauterizing are back.
We said not to cauterize them. Don’t do anything anymore. You will see.
The gynecologist became a follower of Homeopathy because he was impressed
because the warts were gone without cauterization.
This impressed him.
Did not impress him that she was mad and she became well,
impressed him that the little growths there disappeared with Thuja.
He said give it to me to give to all his patients.
Actually this gynecologist had a house here in Alonnisos.
Excuse me but my trousers are falling down!
- Hyos.!
– Sulph.!
Totally shabby! I don’t think I am quite in that state yet.
Anyhow, the cauterization and the suppression of this kind of growths
are very dangerous for the psychological condition of the person.
Not only that, he can actually produce states like cancer etc.
How do we recognize apart from these characteristics, the oily skin, the dryness of the hair, the perspiration has a sweetish smell
also characteristic and something else which is very simple for you to remember is the aggravation from onions.
They cannot stand onions but some other case you may see desire for onions.
You can see both desire and aversion to onions but the characteristic really is the aggravation from onions.
They will tell you that if I eat a tomato salad where onions have been cut in the salad and
I take the tomato because onion had touched on it I have an upset system.
So sensitive they are to the onions!
These are the little things which can make your life much easier.
Going to the mental state of Thuja; it is very difficult for a homeopath to see a Thuja case from his character.
The reason is he’s not an open person.
Not only that but he is somebody that may give you misinformation just to check out if you can find out that this is misinformation.
They don’t realize it depends so much on the information that they give and has to be accurate.
What does this have to do with my case?
I do not see any connection, so why should I tell him?
So, he gives information which is wrong. In this way they hide, they are sneaking.
They are intelligent people, critical, people who take care of themselves quite a lot and take care of their pleasures.
They have a relationship and in this relationship they get some pleasure,
they will not show it to the other person so they will not depend on the relationship.
When you show that you have a kind of weakness towards that person you become dependent.
Thuja will protect himself and not show this kind of dependence.
They will not give information about their life, in general.
They will keep half of it in the dark.
Their sexual desire is quite strong but it is earthy, a sexual thing.
Med. need the erotic element, they flirt, say nice things. With Thuja there is sex.
The other is nonsense.
They will go easily in a relationship which has no emotions.
Therefore one understands that the emotional side is not really complete.
It is an individual who is lacking in flexibility in the emotions.
If somebody is very practical in sexual matters, in relationships, that means
the emotions are not playing a major part, is like a hardness of the emotions.
The emotions in their natural state are very flexible.
You feel joy, sorrow, change.
They have don’t have many changes.
They’re fixed, immobilized.
Because the emotions are the “weak” part of us.
Because if you love somebody you are weak towards that body because you don’t want to lose it.
There is a weakness. Vulnerability. Thuja doesn’t want to be vulnerable.
Cannot tolerate it. Therefore the emotions become hard.
So this idea of hardness, callous… In Greek we say you are “callos” because your mind is stuck, fixed.
You have tumor in your brain, a callous. It’s the same idea.
The soul makes callouses, hard growths underneath.
The same idea of callous, hardness is with the emotions.
This picture, this patient, this pathology eventually may lead to fixed ideas.
Obsessive or compulsive. He gets an idea and cannot get it out.
That is so. Whatever it might be.
And there is a peculiar state of mind which sometimes they go into a state where they feel that the body
is brittle and can break, it’s made of glass.
This is very interesting.
You see the hardness, the inflexibility and I am going to be broken!
This is an idea which comes because of a deeper weakness.
These people can be very hard with others. If he is in the army he can give orders.
Kill them!
They are hard but behind it it’s the fear they make break down and go crazy.
And this whole situation of growths, hardness comes as a secondary stage of gonorrhea.
This is not known in medicine, they are know the different
stages of syphilis;
Primary, secondary where we have the rosacea and tertiary syphilis, the neurosyphilis which affects the
neurological system and of course the circulatory system.
It’s not known that gonorrhea has a primary and a secondary stage.
Thuja is the secondary stage of a gonorrhea which is coming through ancestors or it has come due to the fact that the individual himself got gonorrhea,
mistreated and eventually as a secondary stage they develop condylomata.
All kind of condylomata can belong to Thuja because there are many other remedies; Dulc., Caust., Nit-ac., etc.
But mostly when you see in the ancestors or the prehistory gonorrhea and then you see condylomata the remedy will be Thuja 90%.
You examine a person and you suspect Thuja.
It’s not easy to pin it down.
Then you ask what about your father, is he still alive?
If the father had gonorrhea before conception of the
person the father most probably  has died between 50-60 years old.
You ask him, you got gonorrhea yourself, no,
your father is alive, no, he dies between 50-60.
Usually you are right. From heart disease?
Yes. In the prehistory of these people you see the father, usually, has dies from a heart attack at the age 55-62.
Quite young. Heart attack which is final.
The heart attacks which are final that means nobody can save them is about 25% of the cases.
The rest of the cases can be saved.
Those who die usually there is a prehistory of gonorrhea.
So gonorrhea has made the heart quite sensitive.
When they give this miasm to the children the possibility is Med. and the second possibility in Thuja
especially if they have growths, warts, condylomata etc.
Thuja will be indicated very frequently in cases where the patient
says a lot of condylomata were suppressed, cauterized, etc.
There is a metaphysical phenomenon almost transcendental,
I don’t understand but it true.
Because I have checked it again and again.
Many people who have come with these warts, I ask them where are the warts,
they are gone, how are they gone, many times they have given a story
that they told me to through them in the night when then moon is full to
throw them to the moon, and what happens, next day I did not have them.
Then one time a builder he said to me they told me to throw them in the sewers.
So I passing where the water fall down and I throw them there and the next day they disappeared.
You don’t know.
Who heard about that?
Mark Twain!
I can swear I have heard this story again and again.
It must be true.
What happens with it, if it is suppression or not I haven’t still understood.
Usually they take the children to the prayers and they pray but I don’t know how suddenly disappears.
– In Ireland they buy the warts.
A relative buys the warts of somebody and I know a friend of mine who had this and the mother gave 1 penny and the warts disappeared overnight.
But this girl had constitutional homeopathic treatment and the wart came back and she felt better and she got a dose of Thuja too.
– I want you to hear some other people with the experience.
In Portugal they offer olive oil with corn cobs and 3 days later it’s gone.
– They put olive oil?
– On corn they get from the field and they make it as an offering, they pray and then 3 days later it’s gone.
– It’s very interesting with this phenomenon.
– You make a circle around the wart and the next day is gone.
– You have the experience or you heard it?
– I heard it from several people. But it only works with a special kind of pen.
– You have to put the mucus of a frog on the warts and then it’s gone.
– Most probably of conditions amenable to self-suggestion.
That means once people believe this is going to happen, it happens.
– I had in my practice a few cases.
In 3 I made a contract that they are really giving it to me and I bought them and disappeared in 1 week.
I did them a self-hypnosis or self-suggestion and I told them to go into relaxation and then it disappeared.
– So self-suggestion is very important.
– But it seems to work only in warts on the hands; it doesn’t work with warts on the foot sole.
– That is another good observation!
– Tell me you experience.
– There is a notion in our country if you have a wart especially in children
that if you tie your own hair around the wart and then a few days or weeks later it will be gone. But I did not see any cure.
– But you heard that.
– I had a patient and he a lot of condylomata on his penis, it really looked horrible like a cauliflower
and he could not show it to any woman anymore and first he went to a surgeon and they were cut and
cauterized and they multiplied and then he went in laser therapy but it was very painful and then again
they multiplied and become more and more and through homeopathy they went away and he is thankful.
– Was Thuja one of the remedies you gave?
– I don’t remember if it was Thuja or Nit-ac.
– We have to take into consideration these facts because what we call placebo effect is always there in what I call minor things of course.
You have serious condition, rheumatoid arthritis, psoriasis, collagen diseases, you try to cure them with placebo… forget it.
If you have psychopathic problems placebo, forget it.
If you have little anxiety this can be amenable to placebo effect.
I do not know that is the connection between Thuja and placebo effect because it’s very difficult to persuade a Thuja case or to affect a Thuja person by just talking.
They don’t trust, they don’t pay attention, they don’t believe, they doubt there are always second thoughts; this is the type of individual that you will meet in such a case.
Do you remember the case the AIDS case in London?
We have to show this case perhaps. It is a very interesting case of Thuja.
He had AIDS. He was a homosexual.
He had AIDS in a quite progressed stage and I said you have to be careful after I treat you because if I treat you cannot get any more gonorrhea but if I treat your AIDS and you become better you can be infected with gonorrhea.
I told him but he didn’t believe. And he was doing quite well and of course he had contact without protection and he got gonorrhea again.
These people have multiple sexual contacts. I asked him are you steady or not?
Steady. I thought I had found one steady in California and I asked him how many partners he had a year?
He was thinking. I asked 10?
I thought maybe 10 is a big number so I encouraged him to say… No 10 but 8. 20?
He was thinking.
He said about 300. 300 he was considering himself going steady!
I said to him if you are not steady how many?
Over 1000 a year!
When I examined deeper to see what is happening they said it is such an excitement!
They have a contact in the morning, in the noon and in the evening they cannot sleep,
they have to go the communal baths and have sex again and then they can sleep.
I was working on a research project Cornel in N.Y. looking in the psychopathology in HIV patients
and my job was to interview the HIV (+) males and one man came in and I asked him about the number of sexual partners he had.
He said, well let’s put it this way I go down to the shop and get the newspaper
and by the time I got home after taking the newspaper I would have sex with maybe 15 or 17 men.
That kind of reports was there.
Back in 1983 when the whole thing came out and I was examining in America some of AIDS people,
very young, very healthy in the beginning and I would ask them how many times they had gonorrhea, maybe 5, how many times syphilis, 3 times.
They said that they had to take antibiotics constantly because we have all these contacts.
We take antibiotics for 2-3 years.
After having syphilis 3 times, 5 times gonorrhea and antibiotics then the immune system was totally gone.
Kaposi sarcoma, Pneumocystis carinii, end stages, not the AIDS related lymphadenopathy, we have total destruction of the immune system and that’s when I wrote
A New Model for Health and Disease I have my ideas during that time which I’ve inserted in that book.
Because this book was written back in 1985-1986 and my ideas came from talking with such people and what was happening, how it was spreading.
And since that time I have predicted almost the spread of AIDS within the black people. Because of a gene, most probably which they have.
They’re predisposed to the virus.
Be careful, I know! You know that you are in danger?
You’re celibate!
That’s the best!
It’s very interesting when we speak about Thuja and how many of such young individual needed that remedy where what it matters is not with whom I have this
very intimate contact, is whether I will have the pleasure.
So Thuja individual has actually become a product of our times and our civilization.
They don’t care about contact. Like we spoke Ign. they need emotional contact.
Thuja doesn’t need, it’s just pleasure, just myself. If I get pleasure I can forget you!
It’s very bad. It’s not always that a Thuja is affected in mental emotional level.
Because if you see a lot of growths as I said the mental emotional level is intact.
You can see individual with a lot of emotions, giving but the body is in big danger. You will see the growth.
They are going for cancer.
They are heading to cancer, growths in the physical body.
I was just wondering if someone gets rid of his warts by some of these mystery stories we heard in your experience is that a suppression
or it doesn’t do anything when the warts disappear through throwing them away or selling them?
– I cannot say, this is what I said before.
I was not able to establish whether it was suppression or not.
People were coming telling me I have this and
that and I had warts they are gone.
I could not relate the symptoms they tell me know are
related to the time when the warts were gone.
– George, is the pathology of Thuja in emotional organs?
What is the pathology of Thuja?
It can be from hardness, a hard individual who will hide
his hardness to becoming a psychotic person with different ideas.
Some people think I am the queen of England.
They have a fixed idea. In your mental asylums you will find some of them who believe they are corn.
You know the story.
Where the chicken eat the corn, manger.
He thinks he is a corn and the chicken will eat him.
They put him inside of course. I don’t know if it is true.
Psychotherapy again and again, giving medicine so finally they re-examine, are you corn?
No.
They give him the paper, take him out of the asylum and next day he comes in a very anxious state.
He says to the doctor, I know I am not a corn but do the chicken know?
That kind of craziness…
Secretive and the nails usually are brittle.
Perspiration oily, we said that.
There is a very interesting keynote if you find it; when they go for stool the nose runs watery mucus.
They consider it as a habit.
Usually they don’t say unless you suspect and ask them.
He may tell you every time I go to stool I have to wipe my nose because the nose’s running with watery mucus.
And another characteristic is that the urination is forked.
You have to be careful because this can happen for the wrong reasons.
In Thuja usually it happens to people who had gonorrhea before and now they have what is called non-specific-urethritis.
This is a secondary stage of gonorrhea.
Condylomata and non-specific-urethritis are secondary stages of gonorrhea.
The discharge in Thuja is quite sticky and the discharge sticks together
the penis and then the urination is forked.
It is actually a chronic discharge which is called morning drop, a Greek expression.
These people after they have gonorrhea mistreated every day in the day they little discharge.
This discharge can get very dry and sticks together in the exit of the penis and the urination is forked.
Sometimes there is hair that may be going there… Jews don’t have this kind of problem!
You have eliminated that problem but for all others there are many possibilities.
Thuja must be a kind of very sticky, dry discharge.
One more characteristic, this is quite good information because it is given easily;
when they are sleeping at a certain moment they see a dream that they are falling and they wake up.
Dreams of falling from high place. It’s very characteristic.
In which position do they sleep? Do they have a certain position?
–No, I don’t remember a certain position for them.
If you remember these you will spot most probably most of you Thuja cases.
But you have to remember everything I said, not half of it.
Questions?
You mentioned something about they can head towards insanity.
Is there a fear of insanity here with them?
– They might have fear of insanity but they are not fearful individuals.
In general they are individuals who are anxious, depressed but not fearful.
You will seldom see fears as primary problem with Thuja.
The feelings of worthlessness must be in what way?
– In social matters and in professional they may not take a big position.
They feel they are of an inferior type.
There’s no real lack of self-confidence but they have not a high idea about themselves.
In general they are not individuals with aspiration, vision.
They are down to earth.
There is no excitement in that respect and therefore their idea about themselves is quite low.
What we really believe of ourselves comes of what we are really doing, not what others think…
George is very good, no, what I think about myself is very important and if I do things which are wrong
and have better idea about myself they know it, they are sneaky, secretive.
With a woman, I’ll manage to take her to bed, that’s it now.
It’s not like Anac. Or Bar-c. which don’t believe in themselves at all and have total lack of self-confidence.
I have seen Anac. in a very nice medical doctor working in a laboratory,
knowing his job very well and he said every time I try to go the laboratory I tremble how I am going to do the examinations.
I feel I don’t know anything!
That’s the pathology.
Here it is maybe overstressed a little bit.
Low self-esteem is the right word here.
It’s a bad conscience but not in a conscious level.
They say ok I cheated somebody, I’m clever. I cheat somebody else, I’, clever.
George, can I just ask about the idea of guilt is that connected with that lack of self-esteem?
– Yes. Because they know they have done wrong
things. It’s not something untrue.
If you are hard you make things that transgress,
go beyond the moral and you don’t really care.
There is hardness. I have to survive, I have to do this,
this is the idea behind and then of course there is time when they feel guilt.
This idea on the paper; as if a strange person is by his side, is that a common delusion?
– It is in the books, I can’t remember now.
What I have seen is… animal living in abdomen.
This is true. Something alive is in the abdomen, like Croc.
Influence of a superior power, as if body is fragile/made of glass.
This is also typical.
Something alive in the abdomen and body made of glass and can break.
The idea is not only his body is made of glass but they have to say I fear it may break.
That’s the whole symptom.
Body and soul separated; I have not seen.
But M.M. is not what I have seen because I haven’t seen all the M.M., I would be a superman!
I put some of this information which comes from the books.
George did you see Thuja more in men in women?
– Yes, more in men and it’s interesting
that Thuja woman is menish, like a man.
Can be quite hard. A woman who
has testosterone quite a lot.
Make a comment. I like to you hear your comments.
This is about body being made of glass… I read somewhere Thuja patient as child was constantly told you are of no use, hopeless,
nothing and therefore he/she wants to be loved by peers or parents and puts on a persona which in the later stages
starts to believe in but deep down in the subconscious he know he is not what he projects out and therefore it comes like ok
I am not who I am therefore if somebody finds out I will break and has this idea
that my body is made of glass because glass breaks so fast.
– More or less this is the idea. They fear they may break down and the real thing will come out.
They have guilt because they are doing these things.
They put a persona or whatever but they have guilt and if the glass breaks,
symbolically, then everybody is going to see the real thing.
What we like to hear is exact expression otherwise the projection may lead us ashtray.
– Can we use Thuja for the aftereffects of vaccination?
– In general, no.
Side effects of smallpox vaccination only.
The idea of smallpox is similar to Thuja.
For instance, you’ll see if we have a breakout of smallpox Thuja would do quite a lot of job.
Because it breaks down in many volcanoes.
You have to go to the ideas behind the symptoms. Growths. Many times malignant.
– George I have 3 patients who did not tolerate the smallpox vaccination.
They got high fever and very bad reaction and they developed Thuja symptoms and Thuja helped them.
But I have not seen it antidoting the triple vaccination, hepatitis vaccination.
I have not seen Thuja acting in such cases.
Smallpox is considered eliminated by the WHO,
WHO thinks it’s abolished from the planet which is not true.
It’s going to come back because these things come in waves and we are not healthy enough to get smallpox.
That’s all. If the population was healthy enough we would have a breakout of smallpox.
But it will come in India, Africa, South America even though population is vaccinated.
When I was in India studying, there was an experiment going on.
One town was vaccinated for smallpox and the other was not.
The epidemic came and the victims were equal. I don’t know.
Vaccination is a serious matter and has to be dealt seriously by the medical establishment.
They have to pay much more attention; they are doing something which is a massive destruction without understanding.
They think they are protecting people but actually they are taking joy away from people,
making them depressed, anxious and sick.
– In the sheet it is written that perspiration has sweets smell.
Oily also. Face is oily and greasy.
– How we can differentiate it is sweet smelling?
– The patient will say it because he has been told.
He himself is going to tell you. You are not going to smell!
The moment the patient tells you he has sweetish smell the idea of Thuja comes to mind.
Then you start investigating about different things; warts, condylomata,
gonorrhea, onions and eventually you can to the conclusion whether it is this or that remedy.
In cases you will see that I am investigating in a different way than theoretically
because in theory we say we must be totally blank and let the patient talk and give all the information.
If we do that it will take 4 hours and
finally you will have only a confused case, so many symptoms and contradictory.
When I had the Center in Athens there were 30 medical doctors, was one pediatrician doing this;
at least 3 hours for every case and then she brought the case to me to prescribe.
It was impossible! There were so many things.
The gist of picture was not there.
You could give any remedy!
If you know M.M. and have the assistance of the repertory your mind goes there.
You investigate this area, then no, you give up this area, there is another hint,
you go and investigate another area and this is the reason why many times students will say what about this remedy.
And I thought this remedy never crossed my mind, because of this reason.
Any case can be Thuja because if you see Thuja symptomatology it’s about 5000 symptoms
so everybody will have some of these symptoms but has not any of these symptoms.
Therefore for me is out.
It has to have the characteristics.