This is the evolution from the presentation we had in Thessaloniki with the presence of about 15-20 authorities
of Medicine and general directors of clinics and professors of different specialties.
The professors of Internal Medicine were not there.
This is characteristic. They would like to stay with their prejudices. All of them they said, we were prejudiced
from what we could hear and these prejudices come actually from all the kinds of nonsense which is going on
with Homeopathy all over the world.
And some of this is imported in Greece. In Greece we don't have so much meditating around the tomato.
Or meditating on the wall. Giving it to those who want to divorce.
This kind of nonsense is heard and it circulates very fast making a lot of damage because the people who would
like to do damage, they hear only that. And they remember only that and when there is a discussion
they give out all the bad information. So we have to fight this kind of nonsense.
Anybody can do whatever he likes privately. When somebody comes publically and states such nonsense
he has to be criticized very strongly by everybody.
It's not only me that I have to do all the dirty work. It's everybody's responsibility to protect.
He says, we potentize a song, we potentize a song and they will give it to the people. This is absolutely crazy ideas.
An agent that can cause problem, can treat this problem but the first condition is that it can cause problems.
These are things which make me mad. Because these things they circulate not for the reason of improving the science
but for the reason of impressing some naive people, we have a special word in Greek, but it's not use to repeat it now.
It means vegetables, impressing vegetables, people who do not think.
And impressing for his or her own good.
Frederick was telling me, he was in a seminar and they were talking about the salivation of owl.
We potentize this, maybe the spirit is here!
I don't want to go into that because then everything goes into recording and it's not nice even to repeat these things.
But unfortunately they are going all along.
What I would like to do today is, as I promised you, to do a differential diagnosis of the remedies which have strong jealousy.
First of all what I want to say before we go into differential diagnosis is that this feeling of jealousy
is one of the natural feelings that everybody has.
It is not pathology as long as it does not go over the limits; that means it does not occupy and overwhelms the individual.
When you are in love with somebody and you don't have jealousy, be sure you are not in love.
That means you do not desire this 'object'.
There is no desire and therefore there is no jealousy and then you can be proud 'I am not jealous!'.
Well if you were never jealous, that means you did not have that feeling of desire for somebody which is...
...one of the reasons, I was telling on the first lessons, that your cells and your living cells become into
a state of quietness and a state of unification. That they have a possibility to unite with each other.
If you have two individualities they cannot unite, they clash. You have to disappear this to unite.
In a magical way this disappearance comes and then one merges into the other. This is the idea of creation...
...between the limitations in which we are living.
We cannot create, we cannot bring a new idea unless we lose our individuality, our ego. I'm going to bring an idea.
You will never going to bring an idea. If you are in that state where you feel I am going to bring a new idea to the world
you are not going to bring a new idea. This is for sure, why? Because you don't allow this merge between
yourself and the world of ideas, God, whatever.
Actually the people who deal with bees, if they are bitten by the bees they become more and more healthy.
It's very strange.
They are healthy and they like to be bitten by the bees.
I mean there is a little pain but on the long run it seems that the organism by mobilizing its defenses
in order to counteract something on the surface, it acts like a homeopathic remedy. It is true.
Unless of course in the case you are allergic and you may have an allergic shock of course which is totally different story.
That means there is a limitation, there is something lacking in your defenses and then it may come to this
direction and then they have the shock.
-I had a patient, he was a bees farmer and he came into the clinic and I asked him if he had some stitches
or anything or if he had tonsillitis and he told me that just yesterday he had 15 bees stings, there was nothing
to be seen all around his face. So it completely disappeared and he told me that all the bees farmers are like that.
So whenever they get bitten, nothing happens anymore.
-They get an immunity, the body knows, that's no problem, don't worry.
So we go back to the idea of jealousy.
Jealousy is because we are not complete individuals. We yearn to be complete by the mergings of the other side.
That is why there is a satisfaction in case there is real love, when there is the climax of love which is the sexual act
and there is orgasm. Then this feeling of completeness comes from the idea that you lost yourself.
You lost your ego, you are ready to merge with somebody else.
Otherwise when you have sex with somebody for the first time, you meet somebody, then you go out and have sex, be careful.
Not only that but you have a feeling of incompleteness if you do that.
This is not a good state.
You have done whatever you are doing. What I say is, the idea is when you advise your patients.
When the young people come and they are eager, I am 18 and I never had a friend, I never had sex.
In America this is a crime. If you are 18 and you don't go out?
This is craziness.
There is a time for a maturity and time for this magical moment in which conception comes and people are born
which are complete, not missing a hand, one finger or one feeling.
People are born but they will be missing parts, they will be missing a part not only on the body, the teratogenesis
is not only on physical, it's on mental and emotional, we have monsters.
Born monsters, born killer. He is born monster why? Because the parents who came together they produced
that child who is missing the feeling of sympathy. Who is missing an organ!
You cannot see that his eyes are blocked, where you see it in the physical body but actually he is missing a part
an organ or even a system.
That's why you see these little boys, can you imagine they take a gun and they come to the class and they kill everybody?
Something is missing. It is a part in them, in the emotional which is not functioning at all.
In the same way when this is missing, the other side takes over.
What I want to say is that in case of jealousy for instance, something is missing for those individuals
who show jealousy in such a degree as to become pathological.
What is missing? Then we look Hyos. and Lach., they are the prime remedies for jealousy.
And Nux-v. has been elevated I think.
Apis, Calc-s., Cench., Hyos., Ign. Ign. has to be raised, I will explain the jealousy of Ign.
Lach., Lyc., Med. yes it's correctly there, Nux-m, I don't know who put that. Nux-v. yes, Puls., Staph., Stram. correctly.
There are additions but they are correct. We have to differentiate between these remedies.
Gall-ac. also is a remedy for children. We'll speak about it.
For instance if you go through these remedies and you will see what is missing and why a part is missing
and another part becomes very strong.
Like the way when you miss your two hands, the legs attain more qualities and you can paint with your leg
and you can do a lot of things.
Other organs come to replace that which is missing.
In the same way, this is how this pathology is produced and if we want to go fast into what is missing in each remedy
I will tell you quickly. Apis, what is missing. Is...
somebody who jumps into the feelings. And stings in case she is threatened. She is missing quietness...
... is missing the element of self assurance and quietness. In Apis we can say impulsive jealousy.
Hyos., what is missing?
It's missing a feeling of sympathy and understanding.
At the same time the negative energy which is there, is coming out as a destructive force.
I will go back to say the complete picture. This is a new thought, I'm just developing now.
It just comes as I talk, it's not something which I have meditated upon specifically.
Lach. is the passion too much, the passion of possession is extreme where Hyos. is detached, Lach. is attached.
That' s why their jealousy is of a totally different type.
The jealousy comes from different aspects, not only from the partner whom you are in love.
It comes from everything which can cause jealousy. The other one is better than me.
like in Nux-v. In Nux-v. they want to be the best and they want to the first.
They are lacking this modesty.
The Med. is controlled by his sexual desires and passion.
The jealousy of Med. is for the partner because they feel the moment they desire somebody, all the energy is there
nothing else matters.
But of course in two months they can change the object of their desire. That's why they can have several
affairs within a short period of time and being quite passionate in all of them.
That means the hormonal imbalance is too much and that's why they become very egotistical in their love affairs.
If you go to the rubric egotism, you will see Med. is there. Egotism is why mostly in this specific partnership
between man and woman they like to be the masters of the game.
The jealousy of Stram., you can imagine.
Always comes with rage, uncontrollable rage, they are the people who hit, Hyos. and Stram. they will hit the partner.
Med. will not do it although the jealousy is very strong. Lach. will not do it.
But Hyos., Stram. and Nux-v. they will do violence during jealousy.
The jealousy of Hyos. is not only for the partner. It is jealousy between brother and sister.
Very strong jealousy which is not expressed openly.
Hyos. may be very jealous and you as a parent you have not understood it.
Because it is a remedy that cools down, that some of the human feelings are gone in Hyos.
You don't have these human feelings that if I hit you, you feel pain. So this will hold back.
They don't understand these feelings.
There is a coolness. It says this person is hard, it's not only hard, it's hard and detached.
When you will take the case of Hyos. you will see that while there is a lot of anger deep down, nothing is expressed overtly.
They will not come out and shout, fight verbally but when the time comes, they can kill in a very cool way.
Many times I have said this example. I was taking a case of Hyos. epilepsy and the woman was describing
how she killed her brother, when she was 6 and her brother was 3.
I asked about jealousy and she said yes but I never show it but what I did to my brother.
My brother was sitting in front of the swimming pool, he was 3 and I just passed and I just pushed him
and continued to walk.
And she looks there very cool she says and then I thought in the end, that's the end, then I called my mother.
Then she shouted to her mother that the brother was in the swimming pool. He fell into the swimming pool.
She said, I never said this to my mother of course because she will kill me.
This is an example of the coolness and the detachment of Hyos.
Hyos. will not make a scene, it has the jealousy but will not show it.
Constantly swallows what they feel is a betrayal of the other partner, they swallow it, they don't talk.
Even when there is something done overtly.
The people play games with each other, especially in these matters in order to create a kind of interest
one for the other. And one of the games is that if I flirt with somebody, my husband or boyfriend will get mad and they like it.
You try this with Hyos. to get a reaction, forget it. She will pretend she does not know.
In the meantime there is all the anger going deep down and disappears.
But then you do it several times.Then the idea of Hyos. is to kill you, I will kill you one day. I will cut your genitals.
It's something of that type. This is the Hyos. jealousy. This is the typical Hyos. jealousy.
It's not a jealousy that will make a scene. On the contrary with Apis is an impulsive. Apis is somebody who is awkward.
In the same way it's awkward in their relationship, in their contact with the other people.
They are awkward.
They will say things, they do things and they are not aware of their awkwardness.
Where does this awkwardness comes from? It comes from a state of feelings which are over flowing.
The feeling of - in the table- I want to take some bread. The bread is there and in front of the bread, there is a glass of water.
They don't see how they get the bread, they just push the water down to get the bread. This is the idea of awkwardness.
But this is Apis, what kind of awkward feelings they have inside.
They throw chairs down, they walk in the street and in a very straight and suddenly you see them down.
Just a little bit of objects that they hit and they are down. They have no balance; in the same way they behave
in their erotic life. They want something, get it quickly.
And this idea is with the jealousy also. When they come to the point, they explode.
And they will try to go away.
They will shout and then they leave. They say, 'I leave you, I cannot be with you'. 'No, I was wrong'.
Then they come back again and again until they leave and then from Apis they go to Nat-m.
That's how they become Nat-m. They close themselves. Then you have to give first Nat-m. and then Apis.
These two remedies are complementary.
Nat-m is in a low degree, why? Because the Nat-m. have closed themselves already and they don't allow
scenes of jealousy. You do not see jealousy of Nat-m. because there is dignity. They feel their dignity is threatened
if they come out and say a word and show their weaknesses.
In Nat-m. the idea of dignity is very strong and very well established and if they do anything which loses
their dignity, if other people feel they are ridiculous, this is tremendous for Nat-m.
If I was a Nat-m. I would not be able to perform anything because the idea of ridiculous, I would be self-conscious all the time.
In a Nat-m. state I may be spelling the same ideas but in a totally different way, not expressing them.
So Nat-m. is jealous but with dignity.
Dignity is important, 'I cannot let myself go into the state of fight, quarrel and let anybody see what I feel inside'.
Because I may look ridiculous or I may lose my dignity. This is the idea.
That's why when you take a case you have to understand when this is a problem. Where this lies?
In the area of Stram.?
I had a case, I said 'there was any of these girlfriends whom you did not hit?'
He tried to remember.
He had a lot of women, he was 40 years old, good looking. He said no. I said OK take Hyos.
He said, 'but I never show my jealousy because if I show my jealousy, then the other woman gets detached from me.
And that was the time when I hit them'.
Also he would hit them for different reasons. He would find another reason and hit them, Hyos. Not to show the jealousy.
If you open the Repertory, it says 'desires to kill'. The desire to kill is very strong with Hyos., all the time thinks
I would like to kill. I just go out and kill.
Such individuals who have been born in their DNA's with these kind of problems are born from parents
who were not having sexual intercourse at the right time with the right person.
They could not lose themselves into the process and the creation was a monster.
I am good, no you are not good. Nobody is good, nobody is really, totally complete.
So you have to be careful and you have to advice accordingly your patients. Love and let it go.
They will say, some people, the Nat-m's, the Ign's, the Sepias, cannot let it go.
This 'I cannot let it go' is a hold back of the soul.
When you fall in love, the part which takes from you is the soul, the feelings. The mind is sleeping.
And many times you say, when I fell in love I was so stupid because I thought he was a god.
I thought this man was a perfect man and I was so stupid. The mind does not take part in this process.
It's only the feelings, so therefore when a sexual act takes place...
Please comments. Just listen first and when you understand, then you pass comments.
Either about yourselves or others, do not think by the time I'm talking.
I can perceive what you are thinking and why and it disturbs my process of thinking.
I cannot complete the subject.
You don't believe me. This is not something special which I have.
Everyone understands the thoughts and the feelings of everybody else. The difference perhaps is that
you don't pay attention and I pay more attention to what I feel, what I see.
It's not that you don't see. You don't want to see. If you say, I don't feel it is because you don't want.
The human is born with 6th sense, what we call intuition.
The ancients used this feeling together with thinking in a merging and that's why they discovered
such beautiful places. You go to the places that they have built, these nice temples and you say, what a view
how fantastic. Also the monasteries. You go to some monasteries and you say, how did they choose this place?
It was through the 6th sense. They were left there and they said, 'God guide me' or something like
that and then they felt the atmosphere. They allowed themselves to merge and to perceive.
And when you go there, you say 'oh my God, this is fantastic'.
So when the sexual act takes place in a case, they participate only the soul, the feelings and the body.
Not the mind. Forget it.
The moment your mind interferes, forget the pleasure. What the hell I'm doing now?
You are observing yourself doing this, doing whatever you have to do.
You are not lost in the process, you just observe the process and of course there is no joy. The joy comes when?
The joy and the calmness comes in the time you lose yourself in the process.
Lose yourself means you don't see yourself at all. You are passionate, you are merging with the other person.
Hyos. can do that? No they  cannot. Why? Because something is missing in their feelings, a part is missing.
It's an organ on the soul which is missing. That' s why they cannot do it and they are born with this deficiency.
In the same way you are missing an eye or a finger or a leg.
Monsters, these are the monsters. The children they are Stram. and Hyos. who take the guns and kill their schoolmates.
And where you see more and more of these atrocities? This kind of behavior? In America.
Because in America the technology, the technological civilization has interfered so much as to make
robots out of humans.
When I see somebody giving lectures in America, first of all they speak very fast, they know what they have to do
and they say it in the same tone of voice.
In the end you look and you don't know whether a human being is talking with some kind of emotions
no emotions at all, the head separated from the feelings totally. And the head is talking.
This is pathology and this belongs to Nat-m., to all the closed remedies, to Kali's, to Ph-ac.
What is this? You don't have feelings? What are you saying? And therefore you can say any lie you like, in this way.
Because nobody will understand what you say is a lie or it is true.
You can tell any lie you like, you don't blush. You try to say a lie yourself, that you are not used to saying a lie
and you see immediately in front of others, you blush.
Somebody who will observe, immediately.
It's so easy to get somebody and then these people they have their conscience still intact which is controlling
what are you saying, it's a lie. You blush.
And this is complete. You have this organ inside which controls. If you take out this organ or you make this organ
of conscience, you make it blunt and then you start immediately going different directions, different deviations.
All this is connected together and as people of the West we are most responsible for the whole of the planet.
Because we are the examples and poor Africans, poor South Americans, poor Asians are trying to imitate the American culture.
Nobody is exempt. What is happening in America? If you analyze, it is a deep sickness in the population.
Which is spreading over Europe, quite a lot, first Northern Europe and then it comes down to us very fast.
To the South. We have more feelings resisting and then we can resist. We say, I don't like this.
You have one time sex in this manner, you didn't like it, your feelings are strong, you cannot do it again.
Forget it, I don't like it, I will not do it again because the feelings are strong. But if the feelings are not strong
then you cannot resist. You say, there was some kind of pleasure, let me repeat it.
If you do like this, you end up in deviations.
In comparison with Hyos. jealousy, let's see the Lach. jealousy.
The Lach. jealousy is exactly the opposite.
Every time they feel jealous, they have to express it, they have to say it.
They cannot keep it inside because first of all the feelings are strong, the passion and the desire for the other person is strong
and therefore the idea of losing the object of their desire is unbearable.
Yet they will not think of killing the other person.
But the feelings of jealousy are one of the primary pathology of Lach.
We say, does Lach. get fears? No, it doesn't get fears, it gets jealousy as pathology and it might get depression also.
But there are certain areas in which they are sensitive and the area of pathology of Lach., in psychological state
is jealousy which is overwhelming and totally out of control.
That means it's going to be expressed.
A Lach. neither will leave the partner
nor the partner will leave the Lach.
Not easily at least, why?
Because the one who can bear the jealousies of Lach., which they come every day, they feel secure.
Lach. will not go with another man.
She cannot cheat. Hyos. can cheat; while they have an affair, they can have another affair.
Nat-m. can cheat, why? Out of self-defense.
They feel they have to have another support before the other person is leaving them.
Let me develop another companionship or friendship in order to suffer less when my partner will leave me.
Lach. don't care about that. They just want that person, they are totally focused on that person and the jealousy
comes with the least provocation.
In a party you go with your wife and I'm Lach. and my wife greets somebody.
Can you imagine Lach., oh he is such a good looking man, all the Lach. attention is on these hands.
You get it one split of a second more.
And they feel it. What they feel?
The passion of Lach. which has been expressed during the sexual act, which I know it is so strong
is going now to be repeated with this handshake or what is going to follow after the handshake.
Even if it's a split of a second, they will say, 'do you like this person?'. 'Nice'.
And then they go to the party and sometimes you look at him or her or her and sometimes you look at the person also.
There is a big feeling around, he is looking now and that's it they have an affair.
How is it, we were together all this time. Yes but you went to the toilet.
This kind of jealousy, it's the pathological jealousy of Lach.
Because there is passion, there is attachment. With Lach. the attachment is a big thing.
They are very passionate, very attached, enjoying very much the sexual act but if you cannot stand these
jealousy scenes, they are too much.
They telephone you in the office and Mr. John is out. Immediately, you have gone to meet your girlfriend.
No, I went to buy a sandwich.
Forget it. Sandwich?
Why don't you ask me to prepare for you a sandwich? Why do you have to go out and get a sandwich?
They talk, how much and how fast.
They say Lach. does not spell out words.
Because the feelings don't wait to articulate and to be expressed.
That is why you get the expression of Kent.
He has a description of Lach. while talking. He describes exactly what I'm showing you now.
Another remedy which is jealous is Nux-v.
Nux-v. is the big cheater.
That means is a person who needs stimulation.
3 months, 4,5 months and the stimulation is gone, so he will be searching for another stimulation.
Like the idea with coffee, with stimulants, all kinds of stimulants. They take drugs, they cannot resist.
They need that stimulation.
Therefore they are the big cheaters. When you cheat many times you cheat with another person who is married
and that is not a proper thing to do, right?
Nux-v. has no problems with all that. The idea of stimulation, this idea stimulates him even better, why?
Because it is outlaw.
So the stimulation is even stronger. She is married, she is good looking and then he tries to flirt with another woman.
Now once they get this woman or they get this partnership, they become very jealous.
By projecting their own life into the life of the other person, they believe the others are behaving the same way.
And that's why the jealousy arises very
easily and they are very suspicious.
They will not say anything because they know the game of cheating very well.
I remember one patient was telling, he says 'I have devised all kinds of lies to cover up my cheating
which my wife for the last 20 years, she believes'.
And the idea was that as soon as he had a new affair, he was jealous that the other person will cheat
in the same way like they do.
And immediately they know the signs, they imagine that is a sign. And once they imagine it, they become
very jealous and they can become also very violent.
And once they are violent, they can strike, they can hit, not to kill but to show that they are the masters.
In the same way that Nux-v. wants to be the best and the first, in the same way in the partnership this feeling predominates.
I am better, I am the master and you have to be subordinate, you have to obey.
And once they obey, of course they leave them because there is no stimulation for them anymore.
You see how different these remedies are. It says jealousy, it is not jealousy only, it is the whole context
under which you put the jealousy.
And one very interesting remedy which is misunderstood or has not been talked about in jealousy, for instance is Ign..
Ign. can be paranoid in jealousy.
Maybe I have become Caust. or something.
What is the characteristic of jealousy of Ign.? You cannot imagine. The very characteristic is periodicity.
Jealousy in periodical periods, not constant.
There is a kind of stimulation, some things are observed which Ign. feels that this might be a sign.
From that moment onward they become the most tormenting partners you can ever imagine.
They will ask questions.
'And the person whom you met on the party, this was your ex-friend?'. 'Yes but now I feel nothing for him'.
'What have you done? And they pressure, and they pressure.
So much anxiety and insecurity comes that the issue stays in their mind day and night and if it is possible to have
the other people there, next to them, all the time examining them and asking them questions, after questions.
You go to the super market and there is a cashier and you ask the man, 'do you like this girl?'
'No I don't like, I just go there and I pay the money and I go'. 'Yes but the other time you delayed
are you sure you don't like her?'. 'No, I don't like her'. 'Yrs but......'. They try and try.
The other person in a state of Ign., most probably during these periods say, forget it, we separate.
It is not possible, you are crazy.
There is no violence, there is no passion involved but this feeling of betrayal of the other person.
They understand what they are doing, it's going to destroy my marriage and they cannot stop it.
They will go on and on and on until the other person says, forget it. I'm going right now.
That is the time when Ign. will stop.
But they have to reach the other person to their limits and be threatened, that's it. Then they will stop.
They will stop for a period of time, it goes away like nothing existed there until a month later, 2,3 months later.
Then there is another bulge that comes again and these people take Lach., Hyos., whatever you like, no effect.
But you see the refinement in these people.
If it is a man, even if it's a strong man, will not ever think of hitting though the impulse sometimes may be there.
Don't forget, Ign. and Nux-v. are similar in their chemical consistency.
But their behavior is totally different.
We have also another interesting remedy which we don't use it very frequently, it's Gall-ac.
This is a remedy which has jealousy expressed in children, straight away with violence.
Children that have personality problems, personality disorders; at the same time jealousy; at the same time
aggressiveness, in these children you have to think of Gall-ac.
If you don't have jealousy, you are not normal. If you have jealousy, you need a homeopathic remedy.
So there is a balance in all these feelings, in which somebody felt jealousy 1-2  times in their lives or 3, 5 times
this is not a matter where you write down jealousy. This type of jealousy has to stay all the time
and it has to be there overwhelming the patient and be a problem, a limitation.
Otherwise jealousy is nice, he has some jealousy.
I felt jealous because I thought, you know. This even to express it, to say it, it brings interesting conversations.
But to keep it inside, I'm jealous and I'll kill
you one day. This is a problem.
What about Puls.? Puls. is jealous, expressing jealousy but through expressing jealousy it demands attention.
For Puls. is easy to say, I'm jealous. Therefore hug me and pet me. Hug me, I'm jealous.
I exaggerate a little bit but this is the tendency and the intention of jealousy.
If they don't pay attention, they can become angry and want to show that they are strong.
The man is there and this goes quite away from his head. Never to hit.
The jealousy of Staph. is because it is a sexual individual. That means sexuality and erotic feelings are strong for Staph.
Therefore the attachment of Staph. is very strong, very great but without demand.
Somebody who is attached but never demands of his own what is due to the person.
Accepts, admits all kinds of atrocities, all kinds of misbehavior on the other person but the jealousy is felt inside
without being expressed.
Stram. and Nux-v. will attack immediately.
Hyos. will wait until such time that all these feelings of jealousy are kept inside and then they explode
and then they can kill.
Do you see the difference? The Med. will have an explosion, the explosion is going on and then have sex
after the explosion and everything is OK.
Next time. Next time until he finds another.
Med. makes the person say, I'm an admirer
of woman, let's say it simply.
Med. loves the idea of woman because the hormones are quite high and at the same time there is a kind
of artistic feelings.They will not go and say, 'I like you, would you like to sleep with me?'. They never do that.
The Plat. will do it, the Med. never. They will approach a woman, they will say you are so beautiful
they will find exactly what flatters the woman and they will tell it.
They create a situation where there is a kind of psychical closeness.
Even if it is from morning till night, they have to create that situation.
They cannot go coldly and have sex.
You understand the difference?
Therefore the jealousy is with passion for a certain person which does not last long.