I will give you the  essence of a very well known remedy, Sulph.
I'm going to talk to you, as I said, about Sulph., a very well known remedy.
Many times the patient comes and he is Sulph. and we miss it. Why?
Because there is some information that has been given which is not wrong, it is said in such a way...
For instance, Sulph. is worse from heat.
And you take it that this is absolutely so.
But you get a patient who is shivering
from cold and he needs Sulph.
In your mind the idea of Sulph. being a warm remedy has been stuck and you cannot get it out.
From Kent and from other Materia Medicas, it is said in our books that Sulph. is a tall, stooped shouldered person
dirty looking and philosophical.
You get the picture of an old man with beard, stooped shouldered and with philosophical ideas.
Where can you find such patient today?
Forget it. Not even once in your life, you
will come in contact with this description.
But this description remains in our minds.
So what is actually true for Sulph. is that
when this element is needed...
...the characteristic of such a person
today a contemporary Sulph. case...
...is a person who enquires a lot, who is a skeptic, he wants to know why about everything.
Nothing passes him unless he makes
an enquiry. I want to know why.
Not only he wants to know why but
eventually he can make a theory about it.
About the problem he was thinking.
Therefore if you take this type of person and you apply it today, you will see a kind of scientist who is involved
too much with his mind and his thinking processes.
And the occupation of the mind is so much that the outside environment has no importance at all.
He is enquiring and he is trying to find out the truth; so he reads a lot, journals, books etc.
But he will never take a book and read it and take the book back to the shelf. The book will be left there
he will take another book, read and leave it there.
In the end when you ask such a typical
person, how is your office?
They say, 'it is a mess but I know exactly where I have everything. If somebody comes and touches
something, I know somebody has entered the room'.
I remember the description of a person.
I said, how is your room?
He says, it looks like a bombarded place. If you want to walk, you have to find little empty spaces to walk in the room.
Everything, the newspapers, the journals,
the books are all over the place.
I want to slowly develop the idea of that person who is enquiring. In the book it says, 'critical'.
It is one of the main remedies for
being critical. What is critical with him?
It is that nothing passes by.
He wants to know the reason.
This is the idea behind because we have other remedies which we call critical but the basis of their criticism is different.
Ars. is very critical but Ars. is going to be very proper, the opposite of Sulph., very fastidious and his criticism
is always towards this disorder which is around him.
The one is with total disorder around him and he is critical.
The other needs absolute order and he is critical.
He's critical because people are not correct, people are not honest, people are this and that.
Sulph. is not interested. He is interested about the essence of things. The truth. It's philosophy behind.
Ars. is not philosophy. Ars. what he wants is a materialistic person. He wants material things to be in order.
When I come here for the class I do this, I put this, 2 times, my shoes will be ... Absolute order.
When I see disorder inside, I become very critical. Look at him.
Sulph. critical but in what?
When you take a case and you ask somebody 'are you critical?'. He says 'yes'.
You have to put it in context this critical.
What do you mean?
The real Sulph. patient will tell you a theory.
He will say, 'I don't accept ideas. I want to prove them myself. I want to know why the earth goes around the sun'.
They are real scientists.
The problem is, when they need Sulph.,
they have gone too far in that respect.
That means the mind cannot anymore control itself. They are thinking without them being able to stop thinking.
Eventually there is an anxiety which develops. How this anxiety manifests?
This anxiety manifests in mainly two ways. Anxiety about the children and what is going to happen to the children.
Tremendous anxiety, they have to know
what time are you coming back.
The daughter says about 12 o'clock. 12 o'clock, she is not back. 12:10, 12:30 she goes out of the house
wait to see what happened to the daughter or to the son.
This kind of anxiety which is beyond logic. That means the organism has gone astray already.
There is another type of anxiety that
develops also which concerns their health.
Sulph. is one of the main remedies with
anxiety about health but what kind of anxiety?
They have read between other things, Medicine also. They know quite a lot about Medicine.
They know when the urine makes froth
that means there is protein in the urine.
And it's tremendous anxiety.
Maybe his wife has put some soap before and the urine becomes frothy because of the soap.
But he sees the froth and goes out of his mind in anxiety. Tremendous anxiety with the least provocation.
They see little things, what is this pain?
What is this? Here it's the liver.
In the same way the enquiry about the truth goes too far.
You can enquire in your profession, you have some enquiries, you do some research but if this is gone too far
that means your mind keeps all the time occupied with these ideas so it does not allow you to fall asleep and relax.
You will see Sulph. waking up in the night, wide awake and immediately the mind starts thinking.
They fall asleep again, after an hour they are awake again. They wake up 3,4,5 times during the night.
You ask him how is your sleep. In the sleep it has this kind of pattern, waking frequently during the night
and the person is not groggy; as when you wake up you cannot open your eyes usually.
He is wide awake. And then comes again and again.
They are suffering quite a lot from sleeplessness. They have lost the balance already.
But you have to understand something else. With this mentality, with this enquiring mind they discover
a lot of things, they read a lot, they know a lot and as a result it comes a kind of egotism. I know everything.
A kind of all the truth. Egotism.
You are telling me? I know.
This is the time that he will deal with the issue because he has really enquired quite a lot, he read quite a lot
but this brings a state that if you doubt his knowledge, he will be angry.
With this mind which is working, with the feelings which are quite strong, the combustion of food is quite powerful.
That means the organism needs fat to work with this engine that goes all the time. It needs a lot of food.
The typical Sulph. will have a tremendous appetite, it will eat a lot and especially will eat sugar things and fat.
That means alcohol of all types, whisky, wine, sweets, sugar a lot.
They need it in order to give energy to the
brain.  Their brain needs a lot of energy.
And they have to take easy energy
which is from alcohol and sweets.
Sometimes a Sulph., you may ask, do you eat sweets and they will say no.
But if you ask him if he drinks, he will drink quite a lot of alcohol. Replacing sweets with alcohol.
Or vice versa, they stop alcohol and they go to sweets.
There is this type who is lean, they take a lot of food but they remain thin because of the energy which is produced
quite easily. This is the one type.
And this person has the tendency really to be a little bit stoop shouldered especially when they are scientists.
Scientists who are sitting all day and reading, they may take that posture.
But there is another type of Sulph. who is obese and the characteristic is that he has blood congestions in different parts.
The lips can be quite red, the eye can be congested, redness of eyes, the conjunctiva becomes slightly
inflamed becomes reddish and burning like sand.
It is characteristic the word that they will use if you ask them, what do you feel, they will say, 'I feel like I have
sand under my eyelids'.
It is peculiar but almost they use the same words exactly.
So energy is produced in this organism and how it manifests this energy, it has to go out. They feel very hot
they sweat a lot and most of the cases they bring out toxins through the perspiration and the perspiration is offensive.
How else they bring out the heat? The heat comes out from two places. One is the soles of the foot
which are burning hot and usually they sleep with feet out of covers, whether winter or spring or whatever.
That's the one place that heat is excessive. The other place, you remember, this is the down end and this is the high end.
They have a vertex which is burning hot.
Connect all this, this machine which works
and burns and needs food. It's a peculiar thing.
When is the time that the machine needs fuel?
About 11 to 12 o'clock in the noon time.
Usually they say I have a gone empty feeling
and I have to eat immediately something.
An empty feeling in the stomach and they have to eat, why? Because the glucose goes down.
They become hypoglycemic during this time, 11 o'clock. You say, about 11? Oh yes at 11 o'clock I have an empty feeling.
What I tell you, are absolute characteristics. If you combine them in a case, it doesn't matter whether he has
a liver cirrhosis or whether he has cancer of the colon, cancer of the breast. Never mind the pathology.
Once you get this kind of picture as clear as
I described it, the result will be amazing.
Also the characteristic pains are burning pains.
Something else that you have to connect with the digestion and the combustion which takes place.
There is a kind of a fastness inside  this organism, it burns, it burns, it takes in a lot of calories and burns them out.
What happens?
It goes to bed and sleeps, 1 hour wakes up,
2 hours wakes up, 3 hours wakes up.
At 5 o'clock in the morning, wakes up
with diarrhea and runs to the bathroom.
5-5.30-6 o'clock and will wake up and they have to rush with almost diarrheic stool, not complete diarrhea
it can be diarrhea sometimes but stool which is soft.
They are people who would like the cool
air, they don't like the heat.
They perspire, they like coolness but this is not the desire for fresh air we see in Puls., it is different.
This burning, this heat which is produced
within the body, needs some cooling down.
That's why they stick out their feet, out of covers. Sometimes they sleep totally uncovered.
Another characteristic will be that they
do not care about their appearance.
They can be very dirty and everybody else can see it, they don't care, they don't see it.
Cleanliness is not their priority.
They may even wash locally, why? Because they think if I take a bath, I will waste my time.
Go to the bath, prepare the water etc.,
so I wash locally and I go.
This is characteristic for them. They do not care.
I remember my gardener, a local man, whom I had here and I saw him, he was having Parkinson's.
One day he hurt his thumb because
he was digging and he hurt his thumb.
So he said to me, 'do you have a remedy because I have some pain in my thumb'.
In the meantime I have seen all this trembling, especially the trembling of the lower lip is characteristic
of Sulph. as well. But what I had observed it was that when he was coming in my place, he was so dirty
he was almost urinated his pants, he
wouldn't care. He was really dirty.
So I said OK I'll give you a good remedy
for your thumb, so I gave him Sulph.
You wouldn't believe that his Parkinson's
was almost disappeared.
The Parkinson's it was within 3-4 months I observed that he was not anymore trembling as before
and later on, almost not at all.
The interesting thing was that after some days
he comes to my house and his clothes are clean.
He has washed them and after that his clothes were really clean.
After a year or two, I can't remember, I see again... and I see also his pants again in a terrible state.
I said, that is the time and I said, 'don't you have pain in the thumb?'. I found a reason to give him the remedy, anyhow.
He was so anxious about his blood pressure, he would ask me to take his blood pressure. That was the big thing.
Usually I would say, I knew how anxious he was about his blood pressure and I would make it a little bit less.
But when I see the relapse was coming, I said 'blood pressure is coming up Costas, you may need a remedy'.
'Yes give me the remedy'.
It's very human, it's very interesting that out of such little observations you can save the life of the person.
Once you understand the nature of the remedies, you can recognize this in the patients and then it's beautiful.
Each one has its own peculiarities
and you are observant, you will see.
Another characteristic is that they cannot stand.
In Christian church they stand.
You go to the church, you stay in one place, you don't move. This is the worst thing for a Sulph. situation.
To sit still standing without moving. They cannot stand standing.
Sulph. is the king of the skin eruptions. It is the main remedy that we have for skin eruptions in general.
There is a characteristic that you have to be careful in a skin eruption. That the skin eruption must have itching.
If it does not have itching you better
think twice before you give Sulph.
You need the itching in the skin eruption and also you need to tell you that if water touches it makes it worse.
They don't like to wash and their eruptions do not like water.
If water comes in contact, the itching
is more, they are aggravated.
So eczemas mostly but even other types, neurodermatitis, psoriasis but with itching.
Psoriasis usually does not have itching.
The psoriasis of Sulph. has itching.
Sulph. will scratch and scratch and they have a kind of pleasure.
Once they scratch and scratch more and more and the pleasure becomes like an orgasm almost.
It's so much the pleasure of scratching.
That's characteristic of Sulph.
For food I told you, they desire very strongly sweets and they have strong aversion for eggs, for sour
for fish and sometimes for olives.
They desire meat with fat. If they order meat, they say please leave the fat on, don't cut off the fat.
Not as much as Nit-ac. In Nit-ac. is like a bulimia. He sees the fat in the other plate and goes and gets the other
person's fat from his plate.
But Sulph. enjoys it very much.
There are some peculiar things. Sulph. looks dirty, he is dirty; therefore his sweat is with a lot of toxins, it smells
he does not realize his own smells but he is very disgusted if he smells the sweat from other people.
They cannot stand it.
Also it is very strange that they have great disgust for things...like they go to a restaurant and if they see
the restaurant is not clean, they leave.
They go to another one. It's very strange.
How they perceive the uncleanliness in others and they don't perceive it in themselves, it's very strange.
Why? Because they are occupied
in their mind with questions.
That's why they say the real philosopher...
the one who makes discoveries...
In older times people who made discoveries were closed in a little room and there in a very dirty environment
they were connecting wires and things like that.
And with the beard, they never shave. Why they don't shave, do you know? Because they are lazy.
All this energy is for mental application.
They are very lazy.
You gave Lyc. and somebody is doing
better but he says, 'lately I feel lazy'.
The most probable is that he is entering a state of Sulph.
If the person himself realizes that he is entered a state of laziness, he is too lazy to do things, they're entering
a state of Sulph.
And in deep seated cases we see a rotation between Sulph., you may start, then go to Calc., then Lyc.
Good organisms that they have been stressed and been degenerated in their health can fall into that pattern.
But together with these ideas I gave you, don't forget that a Sulph. case can be very cold. Very cold.
Actually I remember a case where she came and said, what is your problem? She says, 'coldness I feel very cold, I can't live'.
I had one of my first students, I'm talking in about 68,69 sitting next to me who heard that Sulph. is a warm case.
So he was sitting, he would write
in the prescription pad, I said Sulph.
He turns around, he looks at me,
he doesn't write. I said, Sulph.
He writes, he gives the prescription. He says, 'his main problem was feeling cold and you give Sulph.?'
I said yes, sometimes this happens.
By that time in the Greek team I didn't want to appear as the teacher; so I let my first students become the teacher.
And they will say certain things and of course they forgot that I told them, sometimes Sulph. is cold.
So they have taught Sulph. is a very hot person, burning feet, burning vertex.
And he says, I don't write.
Since that time, a lot of cases that need Sulph., they were very cold patients who needed Sulph.
Sour also, lemon, vinegar, they
don't like. Spices they like.