We will talk about the last big remedy which is Sulph.
Everybody knows Sulph.
Tall, stoop shouldered, philosophical...
This is a type which you will see sometimes
not frequently in your practice.
This description is very nice but you will not see it in your practice, very seldom you get this idea.
What you will see in your practice really which will be very frequent, it will be the sloppiness of Sulph.
Sulph. is one of the most sloppy.
This is almost in 90% of the cases. 90% of the cases are sloppy but in a way which is impressive
because everything in the room of such person looks dirty, absolutely dirty, as if nobody has ever gone in the room
to clean it, the books, the papers, the rags, the food, you can open  the bag of a Sulph. case and you will see in the bag
the Organon, the notes, cutting papers and plus his breakfast.
And therefore of course the butter has gone into the notes, the marmalade has gone into the Organon
and you get this idea, you look and you say, my god.
And he knows exactly where everything is out of this chaos, he knows exactly where it is, in that corner of the house
is lying the second edition of the Organon. He will go and pick it up. People many times have described the room
of a Sulph., they say, we cannot walk through the room because you have to go like this, there is one empty little space...
Why is like this? Because we say he is theorizing. What is theorizing?
Actually it's not always theorizing. It is the idea I want to find out, the idea behind Sulph. is I want to know why.
So he takes that book, oh there is an interesting book concerning the energies of the cosmos.
He will go, grab it and start reading it.
There is another book which says how seed grows, the mechanism, he will grab it and he takes it
he reads it but once he reads it, then he puts it somewhere. There is no order.
This theorizing is without order, without system. This becomes the pathology of Sulph. in the same way
that the absolute organization of Ars. where everything is clean, meticulously put is again the opposite pathology.
I have heard saying 'I wish I could stand
some dirt'. The Ars. will say, 'I can't'.
There is a little piece here, they have to clean it, take it out, take the broom as to be everything meticulous.
Now you can imagine what happens
when a Sulph. and Ars. get married.
It is a disaster!
The Sulph. will try because he loves his wife, will try to be organized and then he forgets, he goes inside the room
his feet are full of dirt and goes inside and the
dirt goes inside, 'oh my god!' but it's too late. The wife is already behind.
And Sulph. of course is also very critical. You see there is a critical faculty over critical, criticizing everything.
'This course is no good, this man is not nice, this person is not so....'
Something brings him to the point where he has to criticize.
When he becomes a nuisance for others because if you are critical all the time, then they cannot stand you.
But this critical faculty, this idea of
theorizing and trying to understand why.
Unbelievable questions they have in
their mind. They create questions.
Questions that never strike your mind.
It will come to the mind of a Sulph. case.
You see a scientist who is like this, sloppy and dirty and not caring about any kind of cleanliness.
Yet it's very strange, such a person goes to a friend to eat and they are disgusted because the plates are not clean
or the glasses are not clean. He feels disgusted and may not eat. He will say 'I'm not hungry'.
Disgust is one of the main symptoms of
Sulph. as well as their tolerance for dirt.
The tolerance for their own dirt, in their own bodies and in their own surrounding is unbelievable.
Sometimes of course Sulph. has discharges which are offensive.
All the discharges are offensive, the perspiration, the menses, the discharge, the eczemas which they develop they are offensive.
And sometimes they are bothered by this offensiveness themselves.
Because they do not have time to wash, in their mind there is no time, it's a waste of time.
You just go to the bathroom and prepare the bathroom and start cleaning, all this it's a ceremony
not understood by Sulph. So what they do,
they wash locally.
They wash quickly locally a little bit and then they are going, 'I'm clean now. It's OK I don't need more
what's the problem? The main problem is that we have to discuss a philosophical matter', this is very important.
You tell Sulph. we're going to have philosophical discussions about finding the truth, they get very excited.
They will come and stay and discuss and put ideas forward etc.
The scientists, as I said, are so sloppy and if you go to more gross inventors like 'I'm going to invent an electric car'
you go to his workshop, the workshop is really in a mess, it's really dirty.
He, himself is always dirty. This is the idea of Sulph.
And then the organism gets a lot of heat and the heat is especially where? We said already, on top and on the soles.
These are typical Sulph. of course.
When we discuss about this, we're talking about a typical Sulph.
That means a Sulph. which is going to make a big difference.
The person is going to clean up its place, he finds the energy. Also there is no energy.
He says, I don't have the energy, I will clean it.
So one day it's so dirty, he has to put order. He starts putting some order a few hours, then it's finished. Then again next year.
Once the year he will put some order, this is the idea of Sulph.
And then because their system, they need energy, they need heat, they need also to take sweets.
They don't care about the consequences, they are totally oblivious until the time when they will have some real problem.
Then the anxiety about health of Sulph. starts and becomes very strong.
They are becoming hypochondriac.
'Doctor, examine me here, I feel something inside here'. It's OK, nothing.
They come next time and say, 'examine me there, now it's here definitely' and then you get this idea of anxiety
developing more and more.
Another keynote for Sulph. is that they need food. They burn out the food. They need a lot.
Sometimes they get up in the night and they have to eat and the feeling of emptiness comes at about
11,12,1 o'clock around that time. It's an empty feeling and they have to eat something immediately.
They go to the house, if they are in the house and the wife says, OK wait half an hour to prepare something.
He says, no, no, he grabs something to eat quickly and then he can eat two hours later.
Just to fill up this empty feeling which they feel.
In their desires and aversions we have primarily desire for sweets and aversion to two things, fish and eggs.
Fish and eggs they will almost never desire to eat.
Aversion to fat it's written here, it's very seldom to have aversion to fat. The desire for fat is strong.
They eat fatty food, food that contains calories to burn.
Amelioration by cold bathing, this is not correct.
In the books they are written like this. Actually what you get is an aggravation from cold bathing.
Especially if they are having some eruptions.
Sulph. is one of the main remedies for eruptions with one characteristic. They have itching which is voluptuous
It's pleasurable itching. They scratch and scratch and it's so pleasurable that a monk will think this is a sin.
Such pleasure.
Actually this is a case I had in a monastery. It is a very saintly man, he said I had to scratch and scratch and then I go
and pray, god forgive me, for this pleasure' he was feeling.
There is another weak point. It is that they cannot support standing. Standing makes them feel irritable.
For instance, people who go to church and they have to stand, the Greek church is 2-3 hours, standing in one place
for Sulph., he has to either sit or go out.
It's not possible. Standing is the worst position.
Another keynote is the sensation in the eyes that there is sand, also you will find it very frequently. Sand in the eyes
it is a slight conjunctivitis with sand in
the eyes. This is also characteristic.
Feet are perspiring, burning, hot perspiration, offensive and the feet are almost every day out, summer
and winter it doesn't matter. They are out of covers.
You get two things, emptiness in the stomach in the morning and feet out of covers and you finished.
And you look at the person, really he looks dirty. A Sulph. will come and will have oil here and there.
They also like to collect things. They don't throw away things like Merc.
Merc. likes to collect, collect, newspapers, whatever and they keep it there. Merc. is similar in their rooms
they are similar with Sulph. You can make a mistake but Sulph. is much more sloppy and dirty than Merc.
Mercury because they like to collect things, they put them there and there is no way to clean the room.
Because of the collections.
Also you will in the Repertories saying, 'egotistical' because they have read a lot, they thought a lot.
They have the idea that they know better. 'I'm telling you. I know'. They believe that they know.
And they get this attitude which is a little bit out of reality.
-They like spices, is there any special spice?
-No. They don't like actually acid things like oranges.
They are oranges which are sweet and oranges which are a little bit acid.
Sulph. says, 'ugh, acid' where the orange is not really acid, it's a little bit acid, they don't like it.
In the books you will find it. The important things are desires fat, desires sweets and aversion eggs, aversion fish.
These you can remember. You want to confirm.
A Sulph. who does not like sweets, you put a question mark. A Sulph. who has no warm feet, you put a question mark.
There are strong keynotes for Sulph.
- Sulph. doesn't come to the clinic as often as some homeopaths give Sulph. but can it be that there are more Sulph.
children than Sulph. grown ups?
Or does every Sulph. child turn into a Sulph. grown up?
I have relatively many Sulph. children and I do not have so many Sulph. grown ups.
So does the remedy pictures changes?
-No, no. It is just by chance that you may have seen it. I have not made this observation.
Actually I would say the opposite, not so many children and more grown ups.
Also don't forget, we say Sulph. has all kinds of eruptions.
Never mind what it is the eruption, Sulph. will have it, with itching.
If you see eruptions without itching, doubt very much whether this is a Sulph. case.
So it has to have the itching element. The itching, it itches the brain !
That nature is there and many times we have given when it's not indicated. It's going to bring about
an aggravation of the situation. To an eruption, you give Sulph. and it's not indicated, you'll start having
aggravation, aggravation and the eruption
will just grow and no effect.
The itching stays the same, worse, the aggravation is worse.
They like open air, they like coolness
because they are perspiring a lot.
-We had in the University when I studied a Professor who looks like this, with eruption on the face
with a horrible mess in his room and one thing which I learned about him is that if you were to pass an exam
with him around lunch, when he is hungry, it was horrible.
Nobody can pass the exam. Is it something like that with strong hunger?
-Exactly. We brought you a nice present,
swallow this, everybody will pass.
Another thing is also many times they cannot stand heights. Heights with looking down, it brings vertigo
and they don't like it.
These are the keynotes that you have to check out in a case of Sulph., if they are there.
It's very strange that in Homeopathy, many homeopaths prescribe Sulph. when not needed.
And they cannot recognize the Sulph., when it's needed. Why? Because they are missing the main points of Sulph.
And they have different ideas and projections. It's very difficult. You have to be very careful with projections
on the mental- emotional level.
You say, this person is not secure. It feels to me that it is insecure. Why? Because he said that when he goes
to get his car, he first looks back.
And then you make a projection, you make a story. You have to be very careful in projecting some ideas.
This person is dirty. Why? Because
I saw oil here, Sulph.
Not like this. He has to have all the other elements. It just happened by the time he was coming to drop
something and then you give him Sulph.? Because something dropped on his shirt? No.
-Are there also Sulph's who are proper, tidy and clean?
-Yes. There are some Sulph.s who are proper, tidy and clean and these are the cases where, as I explained again
there are degrees.
Somebody is cold, it's a cold person with some symptoms.
This is a pneumonia case. You start the pneumonia with Ars.
And then it's getting better but the person is getting warm.
It goes to Sulph.
Now in these cases where Sulph. is not the constitutional, it's just a matter of changing a little bit the temperature
from cold to I'm not so cold.
Wait, don't repeat Ars. I'm not so cold anymore, you search for a warm remedy.
In this case you will not find the symptom, as it's exaggerated in the relation which I do to you.
I relate these symptoms, I exaggerate so you get the idea.
There is another element which I forgot about, laziness. They feel lazy.
Just give him some ideas, give him something to occupy the mind and he is there but give him something
practical to do and he is lazy. Give him some work to do like you have to learn, to study and learn
some boring things, forget it.
He will stay for 3 years in the same class.
He is intelligent but he pays no attention.
So this person here, Ars., he will tell you 'I'm not so cold and lately I feel a little bit lazy'. These two words
indicate that he went into Sulph. state. It's not really lazy but for Ars. to be lazy is something he feels it already.
Also there are two types. It can be fat, it can be lean. She can be Sulph. There is no fixed.
Because you get tall, thin, stoop shouldered, philosophical, dirty, you get an idea. You fix your mind in this idea
then you see a patient and he is not there and you go away from the idea. This is wrong. The keynotes are deciding factor.
-I wish to know something about the mental pathological picture. Perhaps if somebody has several times
gonorrhea and then treated. And then he gets for 25 years loss of concentration and all these typical symptoms of Sulph.
like philosophical matters and reading one book in one night and in the other night, another subject
could it be like this?
What you have described so far is not typical
of Sulph. It can be Cann-i., Cann-s.
But if in this picture you add feet burning, takes them out of cover, then it becomes Sulph. You have to be careful.
The idea also in the mental sphere is the criticism and the theoretical.
If you combine the two, then you get the idea. A philosopher, he likes to discuss all philosophical matters.
He likes actually to criticize and to show
through this criticism, how intelligent he is.
If it's a Calc. child and goes into Sulph. state,
can still be obese? Yes it can be obese.
But to go from Calc. state to Sulph. state, usually it means that the child is burning more energy.
So it will be reducing in the weight. It will become a little bit thinner than before. Still it may be obese but thinner than before.
-In the past days we have heard so much about certain traumas which cause a certain pathology. What is the case in Sulph.?
-The same causes. When somebody suffers in his ego, that means his ego is affected or his emotions have been
suffering because of different events in their lives, then eventually they will develop the Sulph. symptomatology.
We have to be separating these few things.
This is a pneumonia case.
Ars., Sulph., Calc.. With Calc. you treated the pneumonia, it's finished.
In this case you will not see the
mental- emotional picture of Sulph.
It's a different case, when we have a chronic case, the case that we discuss, where Sulph. is the main
chronic remedy for this patient.
This is what we're describing here.
This picture of Sulph. will tend to be of that type. We'll have a tendency. The feet here for Ars. being so cold
you give Arsenicum and the feet are getting a little bit more warm than the other body.
That is an indication it's going towards the Sulph. state, the patient.
Because every symptom has a starting point and a climax. In between, all this time you have degrees of that symptom.
You get in the beginning stages a Sulph., the symptoms will be very subtle, not strong.
And as they go to a climax, then you have
the description that I'm doing.
What I'm doing is, I'm giving here the direction. This is the direction it's going but you don't have it all along of course.
These are very difficult things but these are the things that make the difference in prescribing.
When you have a typical case, everybody will give Puls., everybody will give Sulph., everybody will give Calc.
The difference is when you are able to perceive quickly the development of a remedy.
To say, that remedy is coming up and you give it  and then you see the difference, that's a miracle.
-I have heard that there are some remedies that are very deep acting, including Sulph., Calc., Lyc.
My question is now, if there are strong Sulph. keynotes and the patient might need another remedy
as an upper layer, how can we differentiate this?
- Old homeopaths have observed that there was a cycle that goes like that. You start with Sulph., it goes to Calc.
the patient and then it goes to Lyc.
And then again the cycle.
It is a matter of intensity of symptoms.
You started with this intensity, Sulph., Calc., Lyc. and comes to this intensity. Sulph., Calc., Lyc. and comes to
this intensity, Sulph.,Calc.,Lyc. so you may need 3 times to go through this cycle in a treatment of 3-4 years
before you bring about a cure in severe chronic conditions.
-I have a daughter for whom I searched for 10 years to find the correct homeopathic remedy for her.
A timid, withdrawn young girl, even in 12 or 14 years of age she did not have one girlfriend
and what I could very difficult tolerate, although I love her, is that she never answered to a question.
We went to restaurant and asked would you like to eat pizza or salad, she only moved her shoulders and kept quiet.
I gave her Ph-ac. and I don't know what kind of remedies until one day I discovered that between her books
I found a banana peel of last month.
Sulph. brought a certain amelioration.
Is it possible that in females, maybe more than in males, you can also find the Sulph. type who is very timid
very withdrawn, does not make contact easily, does not desire to answer and mostly reads?
-The case he describes looks to me, of course I cannot answer hypothetical questions like that. I don't have
all the information but it looks to me that Sulph. will do something and then another remedy has to be given.
You go to this timidity it's very high in climax, you start with Sulph. because you see some signs and the timidity will continue.
And she may need Sil. as a continuation, she may need Bar-c. and then comes back to Sulph.
and then Bar-c. and then Sulph.
And you take her out of that intense timidity because this is something like between timidity and closeness
being very closed and lack of self confidence. All these issues have to be taken in consideration in this case
because this is the crux of the matter here, this timidity.
Sulph. will open up the case.
In the books we read Sulph. sometimes will open up the case, when there is no reaction from other remedies
you give Sulph., it opens up the case and then the next remedy becomes more clear.
These are ideas which are not to be followed blindly. You have to have this indication like the banana in the book.
There are some indications of Sulph., then you give it, then you see some effect, then you have to follow it up
with another remedy.
-George, do Sulph. children have the same keynotes as the adults, of dirty and philosophical, do they have
unpleasant discharges, hot feet always put them out of covers?
-Yes, children usually because they have
strong mechanism, they will have eruptions.
Children will have eruptions, they will be lazy, they will not do their lessons.
'Do your lesson', 'No'. This type of person, 'oh I have to do now this'.
They have the laziness, the critical, not philosophical but the eruption, the dirtiness, the laziness.
And in desires they will have the desire for sweets and fish and eggs they will avoid.
Sometimes very strong aversion, sometimes
they never touch in their life eggs or fish.
-Are they always lazy?
-Laziness is very strong in children. That type of 'do I have to do that now?'. And they can be obese or thin children.
-George I want to relate a Sulph. case I have in my clinic. He is a high politician and he is one of the most elegant
persons which I even saw, completely tidy. And it took me a long time to find out that he is Sulph.
And he has high triglycerides.
His triglycerides are 4800.
When you take the blood and you put the syringe there, it turned white and then finally by talking with his wife
I found out he is Sulph. So with Sulph. the triglycerides are totally normal in spite of drinking alcohol.
-They are great alcohol drinkers.
-But the disturbance on this level is totally gone by Sulph., it was incredible.
-There is a kind of arteriosclerosis with Sulph. which comes early and you may see the trembling of arteriosclerosis.
It's not actually Parkinson.
The lower lip trembling and then the hand and it goes like this because of the early sclerosis of the arteries.
It's a kind of arteriosclerosis which comes early in life and produces this.
I like to observe very much and I had a case here of Sulph. He would come and he was as if he had urinated his pants
he was always like that and big blotches
of whatever, I don't know what it was.
And then you give the Sulph. and he goes to cut his hair, put things clean.
It's automatic, they don't realize the changes. They don't realize. If you tell him, are you different now?
He says, 'what is different? Ah this pain is better, yes'.
The desk is full of papers and he says, don't touch anything because they know where is each paper.
You go and change and put order, they will kill you because they lose everything.
-I have two questions. The one is, what about the mental stamina to perform work?
-If they are not interested, mentally if they are not excited about the project, forget it. If they are interested
they will go on working day and night.
-And the other is, what about the sexual drive?
-Sexually they are performing quite well.
It's not an area where they suffer. Of course, I don't say they have excessive sexual desires.
But because they're burning a lot of energy, they are producing a lot of energy, the sexual performance
is quite good and I've not seen complaining, either men or women.
Laziness comes from the fact that mentally
is not taking an interest in this subject.
Once they don't take interest, they cannot push themselves to do the work. This you have to do, this is
your homework, forget it. This is your task,
you have to do. Forget it.
But if there is an exciting thing which excites them, they can sit the whole night talking about which
philosophical system is bad, which political system is bad.
They become the theoreticians behind the politicians.
They have all these ideas, they bring ideas because the mind is active but the moment you put them to do
a task which is boring, the laziness comes.
And that's why they say, 'I'm lazy'.
-You said that the aversion to eggs is very strong. I know a patient who was the full picture of Sulph.
but he has craving for eggs. He eats eggs every day in big quantity. Eggs and milk actually.
-I think is because of that. The egg craving comes from underlined Calc. You watch it out.
You will see Sulph. will cure him to a certain extend, then Calc., then most probably he will go into that.
-Months ago I had an amazing case with a horse. A patient of mine is dealing with horses and some day
he phoned me and told me one of the horses had skin eruption and she described the horse very well.
She said, this horse is like a pig, very dirty.
All his stool is spread and very dirty. I gave Sulph. and the skin eruption went away.
It was amazing the horse became really clean. After this the stool was very proper, in one corner.
-It's very frequent that all discharges and stool is very offensive. Sulph. stool is very offensive.
One time I was in a Congress and the toilets were downstairs. Somebody went to the toilets and as I walked
downstairs the smell was coming all over.
Who went into this toilet?
Find him and give him Sulph. quickly.
It will change the offensiveness within one day because the fermentation is not correct.
The moment it is correct, the smell goes.