Bar-c. is a very interesting remedy which
is indicated very frequently in our times.
Immaturity, lack of self confidence.
Which is the other remedy that has lack
of self confidence strongly?
Anacardium. I don't hear the whole class, you have to study more.
Immediately your mind should go Anac., Bar-c. Otherwise you will have a problem.
Bar-c. problem, forget easily, the mind
is not strong, the memory is not strong.
What is the difference between the memory
of Bar-c. and the memory of Anac.?
The difference is that Bar-c. loses her memory, forgets names, people, forgets proper names, words.
it's a constant forgetfulness.
Anac. has sudden loss of memory.
In Anacardium it becomes chronic eventually, yes.
They feel, I forget too much, more and more. As the organism degenerates it becomes more and more.
Here in this remedy what we see? We see the resistance almost of the human being to mature,  to become an adult.
She says, I want to stay like a child.
I want the protection of my mother.
She may be a woman of 30 years old. She says, I need the protection of my mother. I need to be protected like a child.
I want to regress to my childhood, I want to regress to the uterus of my mother, where there is the most protection.
This is the idea behind Bar-c. I don't want to grow. I don't want responsibility, please don't give me responsibility.
They are wonderful people for companion because they never demand, as long as they feel protected
they will stick in a relationship.
Even if they are abused because the insecurity is so much that they are terrified to go away from the protection.
This is similar to another remedy that we shall
be talking later on which is Staphysagria.
It's a remedy that you will need a lot in children and in old age. Old people who become like children.
You hear usually the daughter who gives the case of her father. She says, my father has become like a baby.
This is typical expression for Bar-c. because she does not know what she is talking about.
But the description is exactly of Bar-c.
That means the brain has been reduced, the arteries have been sclerosed and the whole human being
is regressing, going back to babyhood.
The saliva is running, they feel no confident to go by themselves, they need protection, they forget everything.
They cry like children old people but it's not indicated only to old people; this is wrong impression
because most of the Bar-c's I have given, were to students and especially students of Medicine. Medical students.
This has an explanation because in Medicine you are requested to use your memory so much and to remember
so much that the brain is overwhelmed with information.
It gets tired and gives in.
It says, 'forget it, I don't want to learn anymore, I don't want to see anybody, I just want my mother.
I want to find a place where I feel comfortable.'
And then the insecurity comes and then the lack of self confidence and you get the same problem with the Anac.
where they feel they worth nothing. They can not accomplish anything, they will not be up to the point.
You give them a job and they feel, 'I cannot perform'.
In the children a characteristic is that their tonsils are so swollen that close up the entrance to esophagus.
They cannot swallow. The tonsils are
touching each other almost, like this.
Huge tonsils indicate Bar-c. possibility.
Also a characteristic is even children they lose their hair. The hair is falling and baldness in very young age
it may indicate, not always, Bar-c. Usually the pathology of Bar-c. is accompanied by falling of hair.
Strong falling of hair.
Aversion to fruit is another symptom to remember and this is a symptom which is also prominent
to which remedy that we will be talking about?
-Ignatia.
-Very good. You just learn these little
tips and you will see. Ignatia.