I want to talk a little bit about the Ign. state.
As keynotes for a remedy which is needed
so many times, in so many cases today.
How an Ign. state is made?
We can see certain individuals
who are rather closed people.
People who will not easily give up their own integrity.
Usually such people have an inborn sensitivity, let us say, they have artistic tendencies.
Their sensitivities, even if their profession is whatever, a constitutional Ign. has sensitivities, why?
Because they are people who were keeping themselves as an observer in life until certain age.
That means they protect themselves up to the time when suddenly they fall in love with somebody.
You have to realize that they are sensitive people, serious, they go to Universities, they play the piano, they are artistic.
Suddenly the erotic feeling arises and due to the hysterical element which is inborn inside them
they fall into a kind of unconditioned love affair.
But they have learned to be observers.
They have to be observing themselves. So by the time they fall in love so much, at the same time they see the danger.
That if the man leaves me, I'm finished.
All along there is resistance. 'I will not
subdue myself. I will not give up myself'.
But at the same time the yearning is, 'I need to see him'.
And many times in our societies, the western civilization -let's call it civilization- the involvement is with an illegal affair.
And Ign. woman can fall in love very easily, much more easily with a married man, who has experience
in love affairs and knows how to handle such an aggressive little animal because Ign. will behave in the beginning
in a very aggressive way, not hitting but by intellect.
They will not accept unless the man knows how to handle such a woman without experience.
And the sensitive, artistic, observing individual who is hysterical, who does not learn how to handle erotic situations
eventually she falls in love with such a person.
You can understand the kind of life she will have.
Because she will observe all the time.
The observation is there all the time.
The critical mind is all the time right there.
He assumes, he looks at you and can make a summary of you and say, this is good, this is bad.
Because she has learned to observe.
That is why Kent in his Materia Medica, in the end of his lecture he says, when you take the case of an Ign...
...finish as quickly as possible the interview, look wise, don't talk much, give the remedy and go.
Because he has realized once you start talking, Ign. will be assuming, 'he is like this, he is not like this....'
and he had realized how much he was criticized by Ign. people.
This is true but we have to understand in depth that kind of constitution, which is a person who has been trying
all along to keep her emotions in control.
Because she knows there is a feeling inside Ign., that once she will let all her emotions out, she can be
behaving in a ridiculous way. So she
tries to control her emotions. How?
By mental effort but the effort of controlling emotions passes through the thyroid gland.
And she feels this constriction. You say, 'do you feel a constriction in your neck?', 'Yes, I have this constriction'.
The constriction is nothing else but the effort that emotions will stay on this part and will not become
aware and overtake the individual.
The emotions should not overtake, this is the biggest struggle.
In the Repertory we have a rubric it says, 'silent grief'. Ign. is there, Nat-m. etc.
Silent grief means 'I will not show to the other people how much I suffer. I must not show how much I suffer'.
Of course this is stupid but she does not know it is stupid. Her concept is 'I must not look ridiculous'.
And the moment you take her case, for instance you touch upon the real painful spot and immediately
you see she will try to swallow it.
Not like other remedies that will cry immediately.
Ign., she will try even if you touch this very painful spot, she will try to control herself and not show you what is going on.
In children where the parents are fighting and the child perceives this fight, that something wrong is between the parents
what the child Ign. will do?
It's so much the pain that she cannot react.
She is paralyzed, she will keep inside silent grief and the parents they don't even understand what is going with the child.
They don't perceive that the child is in a state of grief.
That is why we say that with Ign. we have a hysterical element which affects the nervous system
and therefore we will have nervous system affections.
You have epilepsy, you have nervous system affections and the element of hysteria is there. That means once
they let themselves to have convulsions, they will overdo it.
There is an exaggeration. In the same way if they let their emotions out, they become really ridiculous.
They overdo it to the extent that the other person may even get frightened with the reaction they have.
Because they are not used in such overwhelming reaction.
There is such a change which is imprinted upon the organism after an emotional stress and the weak point of Ign.
is not money, not profession, not position in society.
The weak point is those she loves, the idea that she may lose them. This is the weak point of Ign.
Emotional attachment that was never revealed to the other person.
They don't have the possibility, the Ign's, to go and say 'My father! how are you?'. Kiss the father, kiss the mother...
They don't have that possibility. They are observing, their emotions are there, very powerful
but they will not let them out. Maybe I become ridiculous if I let my emotions. This is the idea.
So the moment they lose this, that destroys it, they cannot control it anymore.
And then the organism takes all the impact and then the disease starts.
Whatever is the predisposition in the organism.
They go into a state where they don't want to talk to anybody, they don't want to be consoled by anybody.
They feel that they are responsible and they, themselves must get out of this situation.
And with this grief there is a peculiar thing that comes in the organism. I cannot explain it with physiology
but this is definite and it is a point on which you can rely.
With the grief, with the silence, with keeping the emotions inside, with retraction of the person, he goes and closes himself
comes an aversion to fruits.
They don't like fruits anymore.
It is the beginning of a deep disturbance
that will show itself after a few years.
Because fruits have certain vitamins and since the organism is producing these vitamins in excess
but producing excess in losing something else.
I don't know the physiology, I can't explain it but this is a fact.
And little things like 'do you like fruits?', 'No, I don't'. 'Since when?', 'Since two years?', 'What happened in two years'?
Then you become a prophet and say,
how did he know Vithoulkas?
I said 'two year ago this happened'. He said 'yes' of course because I know the situation when this happens
something had affected the organism deeply.
And then I become a prophet, this is not a prophecy, this is mathematics.
Just because I know certain information
which comes from the Materia Medica.
These people are sensitive people and it is a wonderful thing also to see that sometimes where externally
you may have somebody who is quite strong or things like this but internally there is the element of weakness
on the emotional level.
Now how come that most of us we become
Ign's when we lose somebody we love?
It is one of the weakness of the human
race. We don't see this in the animals.
There is a cat and she has 3 kittens, you take the kittens away and the cat has no problem, she is happy.
The same with dogs.
From humans you take the children and see what happens.
Therefore we have, all of us, the privilege of being attached and we have the privilege to be happy
because of this attachment.
When you take away the child, it dies, accident...
then the pain is unbearable and we have
the development of diseases after that.
My child! Why?
Because of the attachment, because it was given you pleasure. When you are attached to somebody
you get pleasurey ou enjoy yourself.
So when you lose this, you are going into hell, from paradise.
From the paradise of living in an exalted, ecstatic way.
In Ign. because of this hysterical element, we call it hysterical, it's an excessive sensitivity of the nervous system
that can be stimulated.
In Ign. the brain in certain areas can be stimulated to a great extent and can live very ecstatic moments.
The more the moments of ecstasy, the worse will be the time when she will be in grief. They want to kill themselves.
Usually they don't, they think all this but they don't do it.
They may think, 'my life is finished,
I don't want to have anymore anything'.
The experience of Ign. is so painful that at a certain moment they decide 'I'll never let myself again be in love'.
The moment they make this decision, in the organism there is a deadening of an area in the brain
in the amygdale or wherever the emotions are sitting. It's like a calcification of the area.
Closed, finished.
The emotions were closed but what was the chain effect that this closing of emotions had on the organism?
The ovaries are big, the uterus becomes bigger, the heart is affected...
and then they come with this problem and you give the remedy and then the organism tries to rejuvenate itself.
And there is really a struggle, it's not easy, once this calcification has taken place of the emotional part.
If you manage to give a stimulation to the immune system, the emotions may be coming back
maybe being alive again and then
all the consequences will manifest.
What are the consequences? A series of side-effects which we call aggravation or bringing back old symptoms.