You will be happy that we have this remedy because at one stage or another almost everyone
will need Ign. to bring back the
grief of a disappointed love affair.
Ign's are sensitive people therefore. People who will fall in love once and this time is going to be very strong.
And if they get a disappointment they can
go into states which usually require Ign.
The most apparent symptom when it comes to that state is .... like this.
They try to get a deep breath and it's not possible. They feel the air does not satisfy their lungs.
Why they do this? Because their sensitivity does not allow them to speak out their great grief.
So they keep the grief inside very silently. Suffering inside but they will not say one word to anybody.
The only thing you can see is that the mind is always somewhere else; they are not present and from time
to time, they go like this.
If you see somebody in your family, especially the younger, between 20-50, they all get it.
Under 20, they go over, it's OK. But once they reach 20 and they decide this is good relation and let us say
one Ign. has a relation with a Phos.
The Ign. is going to have a problem with the Phos. case because Phos. is very communicative
he is very open. He can express his emotions.
The Ign. will stay, will watch, will admire but one time he will see that Phos.  is actually flirting with somebody
and she will not say anything. She will keep
a bit silent. We say silent grief.
You see silent grief how strong it is with Ign.?
The Ign. will watch. 'My God! He is flirting!'
But this 'flirting!' is inside, outside it's
integrity. It's not to say anything.
Maybe I made a mistake. We'll see next time. Again, second time. Then the third time....
This is within a period of 6 months, 9 months, the relationship is going very well because Ign. in the beginning
if she has not been in a real Ign. state, they
are sensitive people who express...
Now I tell you something so you
get some experience from life.
The more close a person is, the more
their emotions during an intimate relation.
A person who cannot express her/his emotionality in every day socializations keeps this emotionality
only for that particular person.
So all the emotions are concentrated and are expressed in that particular relation, in a very private manner
in a very intimate way.
Once Ign. decides that this is the relationship, this is what I like, she opens up, then the emotions
are very strong. The same with Nat-m.
Both Ign. and Nat-m. are very alive emotionally people.
Therefore the emotions they have great force and are directed towards one person. They concentrate on one person.
They don't care about anything else. They don't care to say, to express their emotions to somebody else.
They are interested very much to get the emotional expression when they are together.
So that is very powerful and when the disappointment comes, the disappointment is really a shock.
It shakes the organism and it can reach the organism, reduce the organism to nothing.
And you see it collapses. Emotional, not mental collapse and suffering and physical collapse.
In noon time, they come back from work and they lie down and they cannot talk, they cannot express anything.
They close themselves into the room and there from time to time seldom, they will go into spasmodic crying.
Putting the pillow, so they don't hear in the next room.
And then they cry, they go out, now it's the dinner. They go to the table, they sit, the mother, the father
whoever is in the room don't understand anything.
What has been half an hour ago, has been
a torture inside, by herself. This is the idea.
Nobody must see what I'm going through.
It is absolutely necessary. It's a silent grief. Everything is kept inside.
Only you can see the sighing.
So for us that we know, something is wrong.
And then you can be a prophet.
Because you see the lack of concentration. You talk to them and they are not present, they are not there.
They're thinking all the time; behind their mind is what happened to me.
He left me.
Actually he did not leave her but the sensitivity and the idea that immediately she perceives.
The book says, Ign. quick to perceive and quick in execution. They are very aware people.
So their awareness tells them very quickly, he is flirting. 1,2,3,5 times then everything is blocked inside
and then the vagus nerve, which is responsible for the normal function of the lungs, is cramped.
Why? Ign. has a specific action upon the vagus nerve, the nerve which is responsible for the breathing. It cramps it.
They say when they describe, I feel as if my chest is so heavy; I cannot lift it to breathe.
Did you have a grief? Did something happened to you? They will think before answering you.
They will think, is it necessary for me to tell all that experience again? And then they will say something.
And then you insist because you know exactly what is the situation and you insist.
The moment you insist more and more,
you see the crying comes to the eyes.
At the same time that tears come, there is the will to discipline themselves and not to show. They have to suffer by themselves.
This is my affair, it is something that
concerns only me and nobody else.
Why should I tell anybody else what I'm going through.
This is what is going on in the mind of an Ign. case.
Now this can be primarily because of a romantic disappointment.
The pathology develops because of that. But also the pathology can develop because you lost your mother, your father.
Because many times the relationship between our mother and father is romantic.
When a woman admires the father very much and she loses him, she can go to Ign. state.
Because it was almost an erotic relationship. The same with the boy who loses his mother. It was a kind of erotic relationship.
These cases will go into Ign. states.
-How is about children when the parents move to another place and they lose their environment?
-The same. Children they will say nothing but they will feel, I'm losing my mother....
And then Ign. will develop problems with the nervous system. That means convulsions, chorea.
-My question was if children are moved to another place? The parents decided to move from Germany
to Greece and they lose their
environment, friends or the house?
-Less. Mostly you will see it in little children 5,6 when they lost their parents because of divorce.
They have divorced and the child at this age doesn't know, where is my mother, where is my father?
But not for friends, at least I've not seen it.
But going away from one place to another, it can cause some grief to children, there is no question.
This grief can be counteracted by the organism.
The child is sad on a few weeks and it's over, they forget but the divorce they don't forget.
Because it is something more steady. Not all
the children of divorce will go into Ign. state.
But it can be and it can be quite severe. When I say Ign. states, I don't mean just feeling heavy.
I mean ulcers, colitis, heart problems, liver problems, neuro muscular problems can develop after grief.
Grief is something which gives to the system such a shock that the predispositions of this organism can flare.
Suddenly they just come out. And with predisposition for diabetes, diabetes.
Juvenile diabetes in children, that means they are going to get it. Some children they get it at the age of 7
some they get it at the age of 15 or 16.
And you get it at the age of 15,16 under stress.
That means if the child did not have stress, it could have gone over in a nice, protected environment.
It could have gone over without ever appearing the diabetes.
We'll speak tomorrow about the conditions under which symptomatology appears in an organism.
Which are the main causes for the manifestation of diseases? Exciting cause.
And you will have to answer and you can write it from today the question, when Hahnemann talks about maintaining
cause and exciting cause. In which paragraphs Hahnemann speaks about exciting cause and maintaining cause?
I don't know the German word which is in the Organon, but it's better not to have the exact word
so you can search more.
If you don't know the exact word, you may be reading the whole Organon to find what is this.
In Ign. of course we have, like in all remedies, two states.
One state is what we call the constitutional picture. That means somebody who needs as a remedy
the one remedy that covers all his symptomatology.
And then we have the superficial picture of a remedy, which is a remedy used only during in acute condition.
I will explain to you this which is very important because when we talk about the remedies, we speak about
the constitutional type of people.
Here we have the chronic condition of a remedy which is Sep.
Underneath Sep. is another condition, which is Nat-m.
We have that individual who has not received any of these remedies, who goes in a big love disappointment.
On top of this picture, we have the manifestation of this, which is Ign. You put here sighing.
And you put here, another thing that
was not there, lump in the throat.
And you put here chorea or whatever. Ticks.
You see the picture it doesn't look clear here.
It's intermingling with underneath.
This remedy is added upon the constitutional remedies of the person. This is his underlying background
it's not an Ign. and on top of that background, another picture is imprinted.
Which stays for 1 year, 2,3,5 years.
He comes after grief in 5 years and he has his ticks, his gastritis  his colitis, his problems and you give Ign.
and this goes away.
This is the same way as we see in an acute condition. In an acute condition, we have here, on a Sepia
Nat-m. background, this person gets an influenza.
You see Gels. picture is developing as the uppermost picture. So you see the picture of influenza
and you give Gels. then. It goes away and then underneath stays the picture of Sep. and Nat-m.
The same with this bronchitis and develops a picture of Bry. Sometimes two remedies are on top like
Bry. or Acon. and Sulph.
Acon. and Sulph. can be indicated in a case of bronchitis or pneumonia, on top of this underlying pictures.
So the acute states in order to cure really, you need Acon. and then Sulph. Or you need Ign. and perhaps
one more remedy, the Ph-ac.
And then you go back again to the original chronic symptomatology of the person.
Why we cannot say, when you see a patient try to find the deepest remedy? Why we cannot say that?
Because the deepest remedy here is Nat-m.
and he comes here with symptoms of Gels.
You cannot give Nat-m. and cure him. He comes with symptoms of Ign. You cannot replace with Nat-m.
You have to go step by step. First remedy.
And as I said before, it is possible that in a
case the uppermost remedy may go away...
...and there is a possibility that another remedy will appear before the underlying constitutional remedy appears.
That means you cannot say at any moment really, which is the constitutional remedy of the person.
Because that breaks down the idea,
what is your constitutional remedy?
There is no such thing as what is your constitutional remedy. There is such a thing as what remedy
did the most good for you?
The most good for me it has been by Nat-m.  But in order to reach Nat-m.  you had to give the Sepia.
You gave the Sepia and the person says,
there are changes but I'm not well.
But the Nat-m. has come up again, as clear picture.
You give it and then beautiful.
There is a case treated. This remedy, that remedy... A case that comes to a homeopath master
after that touch, it improves nevermind what.
Even if the remedy is incorrect or what they think is incorrect. It opens up the way, so even another practitioner
who is not a master, can see the next remedy very quickly.
And there is 'now I can see your remedy! Take Lachesis'.
I went to George, he gave me Sep., nothing happened and then somebody else gave me Lach. and beautiful.
Yes but why did not anybody give you Lach. all these years and now suddenly the Lach. picture is prominent?
For this reason. Because somebody took away the first layer and then the next made itself apparent
more clearly and then you feel the difference much deeper and much stronger.
This is the difference between confusing
a case and clearing up a case.
He says, take drainage remedies. Drainage remedy what is it? To clear up the way, I will give you first
in every case, Tub., Syph., Med. and Psor.
So if you take these 4 remedies, 4 times the day for the rest of the year, your case will become clear.
That is dangerous, that is nonsense, that does not exist. It will confuse more and more the case.
So more and drainage remedy, more drainage remedies, then they end up totally confused.
We have to learn what are the signs to recognize the first uppermost remedy. This is what we are learning.
Except from sighing and grief and silent grief, we have changeable moods. That means the Ign. never feels
at an equal state. Either too high or everything
is dark and then suddenly it comes up again.
That 's another possibility and then disappointment.
Changeable mood is therefore very strong.
And another idea which is very
strong is a lump in the throat.
The emotions are filtered through
the different parts of the body.
Here is a portion of the body, let us say the thyroid gland, this station which filters emotions.
And it says, you can pass so much emotions to my throat. If the emotions are more, they cannot pass.
I can only tolerate so much emotions.
With Ign. this portion is closed. That means she has either mentally or willingly, she has said, not too much
emotions because I cannot handle. If too much emotions come, I will become hysterical and I will lose...
...self-control. I will lose my self-image,
my integrity and I cannot stand that.
Therefore the emotions that can
go through here are so much.
But if the emotions
are too much what happens?
Here it's blocked and she feels a constriction here. This constriction is because the emotions do not go through
and are constricted there.
It says, 'no emotions, no emotions'
and the emotions say. we must release, we must go out, we must cry and he says, no emotions, no emotions.
Then you have this conflict which ends up with a feeling of constriction here.
The constriction sometimes is terrible, otherwise it is less terrible. But sometimes people have almost constantly
a constriction in the throat.
Because the emotions do not come out.
-Is it because mainly of their pride?
-Well, it is the make-up of the person. The make-up of the person is such, you cannot say pride because
you go and look 'haughty'. No, it's not like this.
They feel that if the emotions overtake
them, they will be ridiculous.
If you see an Ign. for first time
making a scene, in a romantic affair....
....try to say this is unfair, what you've
done to me  she cannot say it.
She will make a scene, she cannot talk, she goes into spasms. That is why you have convulsions.
And then we have the chorea states. Or she will do the scene, she will do all these things but at the same time
she perceives, I'm ridiculous, what am I doing now?
Then she cannot stop. She goes over and over.
It is the organism who does this, she cannot control it.
So she knows that if I go into that state where I'm not controlled anymore, I will be ridiculous and she is ridiculous
she does this, she becomes hysterical. She can even fall down and kick in a hysterical way
and then she knows that she lost the game.
That's why I wanted to say before that the Ign's are not sent away by the boyfriends. The Ign's send away
the boyfriend before they can be so
much suffering, if the boy rejects them.
So they cut the relationship before the boy says, 'I had enough'.
I said the example with the Phos. and the Ign.
The Phos. can tolerate 1,2,3,4,5. In the end he will say or the Ign. thinks the boy will say, 'I had enough
and I cannot tolerate you anymore'.
Because she becomes close. They go to the appointment, they are close. What's the problem?
Do you have something? No, no.
And then she goes all the whole afternoon. In the mind of the Ign. is, yesterday he was flirting with another one.
He says, what's the problem, you are not enjoying.
No, no I'm well. She will not say. She will keep it, she will keep it, it will start here. She will start sighing
blocked until such a time where she cannot hold it anymore. She says it and she says whatever she thinks.
-I wish to ask you if it's true that sometimes in chronic diseases by Ign., chronic cases I mean, they are suppressing
so much their feelings that maybe they
don't remember the origin of the silent grief?
Even if they turn the page and they are thinking that they are still needing this person and this person
is wonderful and it was a wonderful person?
-Not the Ign. This can happen with Nat-m.
This is another state.
They turn around and they live with their imagination. This is the Nat-m. that can do it.
When we speak about Nat-m. we'll say something similar of what you're saying.
-But Ign. not at all?
-Not at all you can never say.
I never say never with the remedies.
Never say never because even in some cases we say, for instance Ars. is cold remedy.
Calc. is a cold remedy.
Yet you will get some cases where the
case is Sulph. and you have given Sulph.
and it's very warm person and now it's gone to a state of Ars. Is it going to be freezing? No.
The thing that will tell you is, I'm not as hot as before. Still it's hot and yet it's Ars.
That is where people are confused many times. He says, now they tell us in the book that Ars. is cold
and I have found an Ars. who was warm.
Once the hot person started being
not so hot, then it can be a case of Ars.
Here what we have to find, we said about cramps, the spasmodic effect, the chorea, the convulsions.
I showed you how they are produced.
What we have is aversion to fruit. Aversion to fruit is characteristic of most of the Ign. cases.
Most of typical Ign. cases they stop eating fruits. Once they go into that grief, no fruits.
It is very interesting, no fruits.
And also they cannot tolerate smoke of the cigarettes. Somebody smokes .... Even themselves
they can smoke and they can go into
Ign. state and they can stop smoking.
But especially the others. If there is smoke in the room, Ign. will just walk out, she cannot tolerate it.
But not as frequent as aversion fruit. Aversion fruit with Ign., we have almost 80% of the cases aversion fruit.
It's very seldom you get such percentage in these remedies.
And aversion to consolation, which we have to remember is a symptom which shares with a few other remedies, Nat-m.
Don't tell Ign. 'Oh! you are a good girl, stop crying'.
It depends, if it's the mother, she will do like that. If it's somebody else, she says please leave me alone. Forget it, not for me.
-I have a question for the fruits. I often see that people don't realize I don't need fruits, I don't eat fruits
but it's not expressed as aversion.
They stop to eat fruits.
-Yes, they stop eat fruits and they don't realize, they don't remember exactly. I mean exactly this. Very well said.
When you ask this question, they sit back, sometimes they will say, 'I eat and then wait a moment...lately
...now I remember, I don't ask for fruits'.
That kind, if you are having the grief, the
sighing, the constriction it's all confirmation.
Also one of the earliest signs of being grief, the organism changes in such a way inside that fruits are like poison.
-One question more. This aversion of fruits it can be combined with a desire for sour apple, for example?
Because they have also desire for sour apples.
-Maybe yes. If they have aversion to all other fruits, yes it can be combined with some desire. But if the desire for
sour apples is very strong, then we may think
of some other remedies like Calc-s. etc.
They need green fruit and sour, it's
Verat. etc. We will be talking about it.
Also it's a remedy that is not, as I said, a communicative remedy.
If some of you encountered an Ign. case, in your first taking of the case, most probably you will not be able to recognize it.
Because she will give you symptoms not of the emotions, symptoms which she thinks 'it's OK if I say this.'
Even symptoms like constipation, she will feel uneasy to mention. She will give symptoms like 'yes sometimes
I have some headaches and the headaches
are this and that, desire for sweets yes. Then desire for salt, yes'.
She will answers your questions but when it comes to 'are you close or open?'
'I think sometimes I'm close, sometimes I'm open'.
That kind of feedback. We will be discussing some of the taking of the case in the afternoon.