Rapidly spread in ulcers but I do not put here
anything about the mental-emotional state of Mercury.
So we shall be talking a little bit about the mental-emotional state of Mercury.
Mercury is unpredictable. He can go this way or that way, he can go very fast up,
very fast down. You see how unpredictable is when you try to hold the Mercury?
It will go, so it can go both extremes. It's really a remedy which has a lot of anger
inside and becomes introverted once they are hurt.
Once they are hurt they close inside and they live only with their inner feelings and
thoughts. They do not want to share things and that's why they feel threatened by the
environment because the support group, everybody has a support team, the support
team around is broken down. So they come to the point where they feel that they are
threatened very much by outside people. They are so much threatened that they can
reach even a delusion that everybody wants to do harm to them.
This is a reason why also they cannot express their emotions and because they can not
express their emotions, they start stammering.
And I said stammering with Mercury is a sweet stammering, it's not an aggressive stammering.
But the most interesting thing for the mental picture of Mercury is that this aggression that
has been kept inside it comes in waves as impulses to do violent things.
Suddenly it comes a wave that ... and he described exactly that there comes a wave
and I just want to destroy everything.
And I want to do some violence and so much strong is this that sometimes they say I
need to go out almost and shout. They try to keep themselves not to shout, not to do
violence and there is a constant struggle, violence comes from inside and then the struggle
not to show it.
In this case, apart from the symptoms which Mercury has, he has these core feelings
of Mercury, the impulses to do violence but he has to resist.
And maybe one time or another when he feels secure, then if you put here, one more
symptom like feels everybody is his enemy, Mercury will shoot up.
Do you want me to show you how in this Repertory, if you put the right symptom, you will
get immediately Mercury first. I will tell her to do that to show you that of course
repertorisation depends on what you are taking for repertorisation.
And then if you take impulses, then again Mercury will be.
-How about the scars, the operation that he had and the pain.
It doesn't mention anything in Mercury about this.
-No, Mercury does not have that symptom.
-So would you ignore it when you prescribe?
-I would ignore it for the time being and maybe later on if that symptom remains,
maybe a Staphysagria can come as second. You could actually give first Staphysagria and
then Mercury but I see now that the Mercury symptoms are much more strong and over whelm
the idea of Staphysagria.
And it has really the history of Mercury symptoms. In the past also he has the Mercury
symptoms. So Mercury is running through from a period onwards. So maybe Mercury will
bring back all his lost energy and will cure all his physical problems.
Mercury you see he has the constipation, the cicatrices, salivation in the night, weakness
after stool, cutting pain, change of weather aggravates, desire for sweets, unrefreshing
sleep, pain stool, injuries operation.
-We didn't put any mind symptoms.
-OK, just put one mind symptom. I will tell you.
They have programmed my thinking. It's very obvious, if you take the right symptom.
Even if not taking the right symptoms, Mercury would come fourth, third, so you could
get the idea that somewhere there is Mercury. And then you go back...
Then the suppression, the impulses, Mercury feels unprotected, the defense mechanism
is weak. That's why the ulcers are spreading. There is an ulcer and the mechanism
instead of making the ulcer smaller and smaller, it allows the ulcer to be bigger and
bigger. There is no power behind the defense mechanism.
You see the weakness and the trembling because of the weakness.
The trembling and Mercury is one of the main remedies for Parkinson.
Hands are trembling, legs are trembling.
Now he gave me his case the other day, just superficially like that and I was thinking
some remedies but never Mercury. I was thinking some remedies but I was not happy.
I said I cannot give the remedy, I will give him the wrong remedy.
And really you have to put together the symptoms because there is also the possibility
of Alumina, of Silica, of Bryonia, Stramonium, Staphysagria, all these possibilities are
there but what is the right remedy that will make the trick. That will free, will take him out
of the jail. He is in a jail now.