We do some Materia Medica, one more remedy. Which is the next? Ah, it's Merc. yes.
It's good that we have to talk about Merc.
Excessive salivation, metallic taste and offensive breath are 3 symptoms that if you find is Merc.
So we have apthae, gums are bleeding, profuse perspiration.
With every complain but not only does not relieve, it also aggravates the patient.
Now this is another point in which you
have to ask to confirm Merc.
-Perspiration in German is correct.
-Sure, Germans are always correct.
Great weakness, pains worse on night,
worse both extremes of temperature.
Rapidly spreading ulcers... but I do not put here anything about the mental-emotional state of Merc.
So we shall be talking a little bit about the
mental and emotional state of Merc.
Merc. is unpredictable.
It can go this way or that way. Merc. can
go very fast up and very fast down.
You see how unpredictable he is when you try to hold the Merc.  it will go. It can go both extremes.
It's really a remedy which has a lot of anger inside and becomes introverted once they are hurt.
Once they are hurt, they close inside and they live only with their inner feelings and thoughts.
They do not want to share things. And that is why they feel threatened by the environment because
the support, everybody has a support team, a support group around, it's broken down.
They come to the point where they feel that they are threatened very much by outside people.
They are so much threatened that they can reach even a delusion that everybody wants to do harm to them.
This is a reason why also they cannot express their emotions.
And because they cannot express their emotions, they start stammering.
Stammering with Merc. is a sweet stammering. It's not an aggressive stammering.
'I want to express my feelings but I cannot'. Sweet.
But the most interesting thing for the mental picture of Merc. is that this aggression that has been kept inside
it comes in waves as impulses to do violent things.
Suddenly it comes a wave and he described exactly that. There comes a wave and I just want to destroy everything.
And I want to do some violence and so much is strong this, that sometimes they say I need to go out and almost shout.
They try to keep themselves not
to shout. Not to do violence.
There is a constant struggle, violence comes from inside and the struggle not to show it.
So in this case apart from the symptoms which Merc. has, it has these core feelings of Merc.
The impulses to do violence but he has to resist.
Then if you put here one more symptom like, he feels everybody is his enemy, Merc. will shoot up.
Do you want me to show you how in this Repertory if you put the right symptom, you will get immediately Merc. first?
I will tell her to do that to show you that of course repertorization depends on what you are taking for repertorization.
And then if you take impulses then again Merc. will be...