The person who needs Sil. is a person who is rather sensitive and at the same time refined.
You start with Calc-c., he is more down the earth, you go to Calc-p. who is more refined and then you go to Sil.
These remedies are similar.
With Sil. you have more refined individuals,
that means more unhealthy.
They can have problems.
Sil. is an individual who can perspire a lot and feels the cold very much and who has the nails affected.
Brittle with white spots. That's Sil. which looks like what? Another remedy that we did?
A lot of perspiration, very sensitive to cold?
A lot of perspiration, sensitive to cold, breaking the nails...
Psorinum..
Very offensive perspiration for Psor., offensive perspiration in the feet for Sil.
Sil. has acid and offensive perspiration
of the feet, tremendously acid.
Eating up the socks.
Offensive and acrid,especially the feet, nails brittle.
Another problem that we see many times with Sil. is scoliosis. Curvatures of the spine.
And Sil. is one of the main remedies for constipation.
You have somebody who is rather thin, who is very sensitive to cold, very sensitive to drafts of air and who is
constipated, then you go to Sil.
Then you say, show me your nails.
If they have a lot of white spots, it's a confirmation, if the nails are breaking it's a confirmation.
It is the remedy that will open up tumors and will drain the tumor.
You have a tumor somewhere, no matter
where it might be, inside or outside.
It will open it, it pushes the organism
to open the tumor and discharge.
That's why sometimes the old homeopaths who are dealing a lot with tuberculosis cases, they were careful with Sil.
in case the infection is spread in all the lungs
and then they had a big aggravation.
The same with Phos. They said, you have to be careful. The same with Sulph.  you have to be careful in tuberculosis.
But when Sil. is indicated in tuberculosis, there is no problem. You give it and it will not open up.
In the cases where it is dangerous is when it is not indicated, when it will have some proving, it will go to the
sensitive area where is the tumor,
it will open it up and that's all it will do.
Of course it is a remedy that you will give in all cases when there is suppuration because of the foreign thing
into your body, which is creating suppuration, Sil. will take quickly it out.
Sil. is a timid remedy and they get brain fatigue.
This brain fatigue comes after mental exertion, similar to Pic-ac. and then they have a difficulty in appearing
in the public. They feel their brain is not going to withstand the stress of having a public lecture.
Then they gather some mental power and like our friend whom we saw, she gathered all her mental power, she did well.
She said, 'finally I do well but I have
to push myself a lot to do that'.
It's not easy to make a public lecture, to speak when there is an audience because I feel my brain is not strong enough.
The spine is not strong enough,
the brain gets fatigued easily.
The toxins are coming out through perspiration. That's why it is offensive but not all perspiration is offensive.
Where in Psor. the whole person is really offensive.
In Sil. is the feet. Sil. people will say, we wash 3 times the day, otherwise my feet would be offensive
and some people will put borax or something like this, antiperspirant, very dangerous especially for Sil.
You put this antiperspirant in your feet and next time what you have? Stones in the kidneys.
In 2-3 years you develop stones in the kidneys. It's very dangerous to stop offensive perspiration by antiperspirant.
Sil. also is one of the remedies who is afraid of pins or needles, pointed things. In the same way as Spig.
Fear of pins and needles Spig., of course fear of injections is Hep.
Yielding is not so.
These points you have to have to prescribe Sil.
You don't prescribe Sil. because it's yielding, timid.
Somebody has seen a Sil. who is not affected in this mental level, strong woman, it says strong will power, Sil.
This is nonsense.
Strong will power is not a symptom,
it's the normal personality of the person.
And you have to have the points
that we're discussing to confirm.
Don't forget that it is very difficult many times, especially for young people coming into Homeopathy
to discriminate between personality
qualities and pathological qualities. It's very difficult.
And once they see it, they grab it and they give it as information and this is causing confusion.
We'll try to reduce all this confusion and take the real essentials, keep them there and stay with them, as much as possible.
Otherwise you will have problems. Of course Sil. wants her head covered like Psor. They are so sensitive to cold air
and to drafts that many times they have to sleep with a hat.
They put their hat and they sleep because they are so sensitive and then some, like Bernard Shaw...
... had written comedies where you had these old people wearing their hat to go to sleep.
Most probably they need Sil. or Psor.
-Somebody has broken his leg and usually they are operated on and these parts have been fit together
with nails and screws. Constantly
he is developing purulent abscesses.
All the symptoms point to Sil. then I would have very much the danger that the body would try to of the nails
and the screws, if I give it, correct?
What possibilities do I have then?
-This is a good legitimate question. What I imagine would happen in such a case, if the organism creates
around the foreign body, pus and inflammation. Inflammation, antibiotics, inflammation. If you give Sil.
you stop the inflammation. And what is going to happen? These are nailed, Sil. cannot push it out. What it will do
it will reduce the tendency to inflammation on the one hand and maybe it will open up a place from where the discharge
will come out and then it will heal.
I will not be afraid to give it in case Sil. symptoms are there.
If the person is Sil. definitely is going to help.
-You said Sil. is timid and gives in very easily. Isn't that a very superficial giving in? Isn't she very strong
behind because that is what I read about it?
-You see the yielding comes from Kent.
I don't pay much attention to that. That's why I say, it's yielding it's timid, you are not going to give Sil.
Most probably the person is normal in that respect and you don't have to say it has a strong will power
therefore he is not Sil. no.
Strong will power is a characteristic of his personality, you can give it.
I don't take it also that Sil. has strong will
power, as a symptom, No, I will not take it.
This most probably comes from people who have observed superficially and give out information on a superficial level.
You say, somebody has a will power strong or weak will power. It has to be really weak power, it has to be
confirmed again and again and has to be,
after the remedy, changed.
What is a will power? It is, am I going to be well? Yes, you are going to be well. Then he waits outside here...
...'Mr. Vithoulkas am I going to be well?' I said
'yes, you're going to be well, don't worry'.
Then next morning, he waits for me in the street. He says, 'Mr. Vithoulkas shall I get well?'. 'Yes you will get well'.
This is a weak will power.
He has a problem, he comes again and again. You give Agaricus and then he doesn't come back.
This is my observation. When I teach I say about these things.
If somebody comes and tells me, 'I have a weak will power', like this lady whom we saw yesterday she was saying
I have a weak will power. Everybody will believe it. I will not believe it.
I want to see what kind, the situations, what is a weak will power, where, how it's expressed.
It's so difficult to say it as a symptom.
We have Stram. when we have some type of aggression.
It is very seldom that Stram. will be indicated where there is no aggression. There is no violence.
When I say violence, I mean in the appearance of the symptoms, as well.
So Stram. is a remedy which can express that which is inside, which is on the subconscious and can express it
in a violent manner, in a violent way.
We realize that these persons have kept inside them a lot of dark element, what we say the dark element.
It's a heavy darkness.
And it is indicative that they cannot stand external darkness.
If you have a Stram. and you sleep in a dormitory and you switch off the light in the night, even if he is asleep
he will wake up in a terror and will jump to open the lights.
The fear of darkness is so much which indicates the condition in which the person is living.
Yet, in spite of this description which I make, you may imagine somebody who comes in front of you
and he is violent, no.
They are very controlled and very nice and can be very sweet when they are in the consultation room.
But then they will say from time to time or when time comes, the fit comes, the anger comes, the violence comes
and the violence is hitting, striking and killing.
It's not the desire only to kill, they kill. They
have to complete the action of violence.
Hyos., who is a similar remedy, has the desire to kill. It's very interesting because I cannot understand
desire to kill and kill, what is the difference? There is a difference.
Hyos. will tell you, 'I have the desire
to kill constantly'. 'Whom?'. 'Anybody'.
But they do not go ahead and detonate
their anger by doing some very violent thing.
Where Stram. will really take a knife and will charge and hit and then you see the aggression.
They hit children, the mother, the father.
They will attack, they are tremendously aggressive and violent in their fit of anger.
Children usually that develop Stram.
symptoms have been terrified by parents.
There is a little one here, 5 years old and he plays, he does this, they say, 'shut up!'. He continues.
The father grasp him and goes to the balcony and says, 'I'm going to throw you down now. You shall stop, yes or no?'
Great fright and then slowly that child develops symptoms of aggression. Eventually you enter the house
it doesn't matter who you are,
he looks at you and goes and hits you.
Ailments from fright. People who got a
fright will develop symptoms of Stram.
I have seen it also in women who
had an experience of incest.
This experience is so frightening,
that they go into convulsions.
So the convulsions of Stram. are very aggressive convulsions. If you look at these convulsions and what they do
and how the muscles are in spasm, all the muscles are in movement and in spasm, it's frightening.
They express all this subconscious fear which is underneath.
Violence, fear of the dark...
...and fear of animals, especially dogs.
The idea of a dog is so frightening to them.
It is like projecting their violence with the violence with which a dog can attack you. It becomes so terrifying.
And then the darkness is connected also with closed places, closed and dark is terrible. Going through tunnels
going through places which are dark and enclosed, forget it. They will go into panic attacks.
It's a remedy also that is given in
old times when we had rabies.
This idea of biting, you know the aggression
of rabies and the fear of the water.
In such cases they have tremendous fear of coming near the water. How is that, why is that  I don't know
physiology wise. But definitely
there is a great fear of water.
In their every day life they cannot
have water running over their heads.
To put the shower and the water runs here in front of the face, they think they will suffocate.
There is a fear of suffocation, especially if the water runs over their head. They say they cannot breath.
They are terrified, the children will scream and will just throw the shower, they will go out.
We have to understand Stram. as this subconscious darkness which is there and the violence which
comes out and expressing itself in fits
and then it becomes very sweet.
Of course they will be afraid of being alone, especially in the night. The night comes and they are alone, they don't like it.
It is not a matter of wanting company, it's a matter of being exposed to an element of which they are very terrified.
It's very interesting that this violent remedy, so violent that they can kill, they themselves are afraid of being injured.
Either the same person may have both the violence and the fear or they may have only the fear of being injured.
Fear of being injured and there is no violence.
Fear of being injured to the extent... The woman says 'I'm afraid to shake hands'
A strong German says 'I'm very glad to meet you', the Stram. 'ah...'
This handshake is an injury for them.
-Can you differentiate the violence of Merc. and of Stram.?
-Merc. is not a violent remedy.
It has violent impulses.
The impulse to do violent things,
to throw things to counter attack.
But there is not danger with a Merc. With a Stram. you are in danger, once he is in this violent mood
because in Stram. we have a remedy with which we are dealing with serious mental cases.
You can understand the convulsions, the intensity, the violence, the hitting, the grimaces, the whole thing
which comes out is a violent scenery.
- A patient after doing his A levels, he finished his school, he went to Turkey and came back with strong symptoms of mania.
After coming back he could not stop talking anymore.
He was talking constantly and he had strong dellusions he would be the best, the nicest, the best looking
the biggest in the world. I saw him after he had been treated in the hospital with tranquillizers like Lithium.
First he came in a severe depressive state and we actually take out Lithium. I gave him Nat-m. and fitted well.
After some weeks he developed some problems with his eyes. He always thought he was seeing everything in double
and he had a problem with the coordination of his muscles.
After giving him Stram. 1M, everything disappeared within 2 weeks.
And psychologically he was also very stable again.
-I have two questions about Stram. First is do they forget after having this violent states and second
what is the differential diagnosis with Anac. that can also have these two states, one violent phase
and one rather tender phase?
-Of course they remember. When you see such cases and I have some in video, you will see the child is sitting there
it's so sweet, so calm, answering the questions.
And the mother says, he rushes and describes the violence, the boy looks like an angel.
You don't perceive the violence in front of you.
This is what I said. We describe like this and you say, this is a case of Stram.? It's not possible!
No, no it's possible because Stram. comes in fits.
Unless of course is on the last stage of schizophrenia and he is in a state completely gone.
-How is the stammering of Stram.?
-Stammering also is very strong and
it has to be compared again with Merc.
But the Stram. stammering is much more violent than the Caust. or the Merc. stammering.
It is aggressive stammering.
You see the grimaces!
It is two forces that want to come out and say "mother".
Mother is a nice word and so violent behind, this stammering.
It's the same, the idea of violence is behind. The convulsions.
- I would like to share with you a personal experience we went through with my son, who broke
with epileptic fits and Sil. helped him
immediately when he got it the first time.
And then about a year later, he was attacked by a psychopath, very badly, and brought a fit and nothing could help.
8 months later he was given Stram. and it took all the epileptic fits at once. After 8 months of constant fit
and no other remedy allopathic or homeopathic helped and Stram. took it immediately away.
-My question is regarding the fear of water. Is it a fear of water itself or the fear of suffocation?
For example, we have some case where the mother explains that the daughter is very afraid of even slight wind.
When the wind is blowing at the face, she can't breath, she makes like this....
-That's not Stram. There are two things about water. The one is the claustrophobia. It seems that for them
they are closed, there is no air to breathe
but because of this water falling. And the other is the shiny surfaces.
They bring them this violence from the sub-conscious. They don't like to look at the mirrors or calm water,  shiny.
They have fear of water. They say, 'I don't like to go to the sea, to the swimming pool, I don't like to swim
I don't like to be with water'.
-From my experience, I've seen it frequently, patients who are taken away their heroin, who withdraw themselves
from heroin, they often come into a Stram. state.
-Yes, the withdrawal syndrome, it can be very aggressive and many times of course they can have the picture of Stram.
They go to the sea. If they can go to the sea at all, they will say they will never look at the bottom of the sea.
The moment you go there and the sea
becomes dark inside, they are terrified.
Face hot and red with cold hands reminds
you of Bell. Bell. also has the violence.
Something else also which I have mentioned many times in this course concerning Stram. are the fears again
from the subconscious which come with children.
Children are sleeping, they are very nice, the whole day no problem, they are sleeping and suddenly
in the night they will wake up with a terrifying nightmare.
And they wake up screaming and looking in terror and the mother goes and says, 'what's your problem?'
And the terror is there.
Almost every night they will go into that terror and of course many of these children will leave the bed
and go to sleep with the mother the rest of the night.
The terror is so much that they need to feel the contact. As soon as they are in contact with the mother
then they go back to sleep. But these nightmares, this kind of nightmares which are precursor (George said it)
of epileptic fits of convulsions if they are staying, they are coming many times out of vaccination and they are treated
very well in the beginning stages with Stram.
-In Alzheimer's disease sometimes we also see this violence. Can we give the Stram. then?
-Yes, if there is violence definitely.
Convulsions, distortions of the face.
And the fear of darkness is a primary element but the fear of darkness you have to understand as that fear
which comes from the unknown. The darkness is when you don't see, from these elements you don't see the monsters...
-George  I recognize in my grand child, she had a frightening experience, terrifying experience and then she developed nightmares.
Terrible nightmares and fear of dark but she was never violent. When she was conscious, she was never violent.
Do you recognize this also that they don't have to be violent?
-These children seldom are violent in their daily life. The violence comes with the fears when they arise
from the sub-conscious level. You enter the
sleep in order to relax. What do you do?
You take away the logical mind. The logical mind is finished, then the sub-conscious takes over.
Once the sub-conscious takes over...there are cases of nightmares for 20 years, especially after incest.
The child does not know what's going on and then finds out and that terror comes and the nights become
really nightmares.
-When you described the child, waking up at night, having nightmares, the next day when you ask the child...
-They don't remember. But you have to have the child waking up in terror, real terror because there are
a lot of other remedies that have nightmares.
Real terror and shout and they cannot wake up.
They see something, you are sure they see something there because they are so much engrossed in
that, that they see. Then it is Stram.
The woman will shout. The husband is terrified. He says, I had to sleep in the other room.
Every night? Every night the same thing, that's Stram. If he wakes up and says...it's not Stram. It's different.
-I had one Stram. case with an 9 year old boy some years ago but it was very impressive.
The mother came to me because she did not know what to do. She said, the boy is terrifying the whole family
and especially her. He always had to know where she is. So as an example, when he is at school he stands up
during the lesson and say, 'I now have to phone my mother to see where she is'. And he was very afraid
and he got very aggressive when he could not find the mother. That lasted  for half a year before she came
and I asked what happened? She told me she had missed the boy in the town, when she was shopping
and he was lost in a big shopping center
and they get back some hours later.
And since then it was like this. He had very much anxiety in the night and the light had to be on...
-And many times these children they
get up and they go with the mother.
-Yes, he doesn't want to be alone at all. He had very big, dark eyes, when he looked at me it was terrifying
and he told me that when he looks at his hands, he thought they are very big and that makes fear to him.
-It's very interesting what he says, which I had noticed and I have said it in other lectures, that there is
a darkness in the face. Very thick eyebrows, with dark eyes and it's very strange, not all of them.
It comes a woman with premenstrual syndrome, with severe, cramping pains and signs like that in the face, they will lead you.
I remember a case in the very beginning, premenstrual syndrome, what the hell is this now?
And I saw the face.
-In a very little child with terrible
nightmares must be the fear of dark?
-No, not necessarily. If these kind of terrors wake up, with that kind of terror, that is enough for Stram.
-I've got a relative in Germany that after a bomb attack in the war, during the war at age 3, she developed
this stammering with grimaces
in the face. And she had it for 45 years now.
Now the last 5 years, she has been going under psychotherapy, so the stammering came down a little bit.
But now she is rather in a depressive state, with hanging eyelids and she is not very well.
And she never had any signs of violence. Whether one could think of giving Stram. as there is no violence there?
-Yes, yes, yes.
-Do we have restlessness in Stram.?
-Yes, it's the violent movements than restlessness.
-Can the aggression also go towards oneself?
-You mean like suicidal or hitting yourself?
I don't know, I cannot answer this
question. I do not have cases like this.
-Stram. is also a big remedy for violence of drunkards and I remember a case of a person who regularly
when he was alcoholised, would come home, beat up his family, get all the furniture and mess everything up
and Stram. helped really a lot.
-Exactly, the idea is that the logical mind goes away and the sub-conscious takes over, whether it is in sleep
or in waking state, it's the same idea. Alcohol takes the logical mind away the sub-conscious takes over.
The idea is when the sub-conscious takes over and this sub-conscious is violent, then the idea of Stram. comes.
Darkness and violence.
-My question is, if you've got children of violent parents, can this evoke a violent state in the children also?
-Sure. One time, I had a very interesting phenomenon.
In a family, the father of the woman died and her husband did not have good relationship with his father in law.
Aggressive relationship.
After this death, it came this terrifying situation for this man, where he could find no rest at all.
After the death of his father in law. Could find no rest. Tremendous fear, he had to put on the lights  and to stay
the whole night awake. He could not rest,
could not sleep and it was going on.
Then it came the idea of Stram., I gave Stram.
Then what happened is that the wife who was very nice, sweet, no connection with Stram. at all, she started having
this fear of darkness and that irritability.
For a nice person to have irritability and anger, she says what is this? I have some anger, I want to hit my children.
And then Stram. calmed her down and
then the children developed ticks, Stram.
And then the other one Stram., the whole family.
I could never explained that phenomenon, I have never seen it again. What was it, something in the house?
I still do not understand this kind of phenomenon. The whole family had to be pacified out of an aggressive state with Stram.
Very interesting.