There are so many different
substances in the world.
How can it be that the
relatively small number of them
which are proved have the power
the cure a rather high percentage
of all diseases? Who put this question?
Very good question.
How long are you doing Homeopathy?
2 years? He is your son!
That's why he put this question.
This question is a question
of an expert Homeopath
who has lived quite long and has
seen a lot and experienced a lot.
Should I answer this question?
How come that so few remedies we
have can cure so many people?
If we claim that a remedy
is individually indicated.
Shall I answer this question? Who
wants me to answer this question?
This is a question which
I had many years ago.
And I tried to find an
answer to this question.
A question is valid when derives
from experience, not theoretical.
Experience says that yes
we have very few remedies
and we cure millions of
people with 500 remedies.
How come? If we need an
absolute individualized remedy.
My answer is that I have not given
yet an answer to this question.
But I have some
thoughts about it.
So if you want to
hear the thoughts?
Experience has shown that sometimes you
give a remedy, a very central remedy,
the exact Similimum, there was a special
word defining the real Similimum
and there is an explosion, aggravation
and then a fantastic cure.
Not all the cases are like that.
My explanation for this phenomenon
is that in all the other cases
we give a close enough
remedy to have an effect
which otherwise could exist another
remedy that would be even closer
and have a better effect.
Therefore in many cases we
may have to use 3-4 remedies
before we attain a final good
result instead of using 2 remedies
if we had all the information of all
the possibilities of all the remedies.
I'll take you to the
level of energy now.
It seems that all is a matter of matching
the vibrational rate of the organism.
You want to stimulate the
vibrational rate of an organism.
The more similar a remedy is
the more the vibration is.
You have the guitar, la, and
you have another guitar there
and you pinch the chord and the
other guitar in la vibrates.
So if you can imagine that there
are infinite vibrational waves
the remedy will move this existing
by coming closer and closer
to the vibrational rate.
So vibrational rate with one 1562
wave it can be moved by another
with either 1252 up to 2075.
All these vibrational energies
will touch the vibrational rate
of the organism. The closer
you get to the vibrational
the more the reaction
of the organism is.
If you approach very close with the
vibrational energy of the remedy
there is this big reaction.
But the organism can be moved
within a space which is quite wide.
How do we know it? Because in a case
we prescribe the remedy on 30CH
and there is an effect.
Then there is a relapse.
You repeat and there
is a relapse.
Then you go to 200CH and you
repeat and there is a relapse.
And you go to 1M and you
repeat, there is a relapse.
You go to 10M, you repeat, there is a
relapse, you go to 50M and remains well.
That means all these vibrational
rates of the several potencies
were touching the vibrational
frequency of the organism
though they were
quite far apart.
So there is a wide range of
frequencies that are matching,
that can be moved, stimulated.
Which country are you from?
- During the process of healing as
the resonance frequency changes...
- Yes it can change.
Just a moment, my
answer is not complete.
The vibrational rate of the person will
change if it has been the frequency
that was uppermost, it has been
eliminated, completed its action
after the repetition 3-4 potencies on
the first remedy. Then it changes.
When we say a jump from one level
to another it is nothing else
than the changing frequency.
If you have an organism on
level 7, you give a remedy
and the remedy is very close you may see
an organism had never had a high fever
for 5-10 years developing a
high fever, even one week later
after getting your remedy. That is
change of the vibrational frequency.
But on another case level 7 still,
you give one remedy, changes,
you give a second remedy,
changes again the frequency,
you give a third remedy and after the
third remedy jumps to another level.
If you study, I think I have given this
explanation in the book A New Model.
Let us say this is level 7.
Here is six and here is
8 and a patient comes
when his state of health
is on this frequency here.
That means on the lowest part of level 7.
He does not develop fevers.
Another patient
comes on level 7,
but he comes when his organism on
the uppermost part of level 7.
This man stimulated by the correct
remedy will jump to level 6 immediately.
This here will need some work.
That means after your first remedy
you will need a second remedy
now he has come here.
But still on level 7.
Then you give a second remedy.
Then he goes here.
Finally he reaches here, you
give the remedy and jumps.
So sometimes he is here, you give
a wrong remedy and he goes there.
It's clear.
- From what I understand how come we
have such a small number of remedies
and infinite number of patients.
George Vithoulkas said disease is an
inflammation of tissues of organs.
You said that disease is
an inflammatory process.
We are matching a remedy to the
process of pathology not the person
and the number of pathological
states is limited, not infinite.
So we have small amounts of drugs
and small amount of pathology
or a derangement of
the vital force.
That's what we are matching not
the organism that is vibrating.
It's a state of pathology
that has to be matched.
And another thing. When you use the
analogy of the electromagnetic field,
it's not infinite. It's discreet.
That's how it is in physics.
It's not like there is an
infinite number of frequencies...
- There is not infinite
number of frequencies?- No!
- Who said so? You?- No!
The physics!
- Wait because we differ
with the physics.
The physics say there is no infinite
number of frequencies? Are you sure?
- The quantum is the difference between
a frequency and another. It's discreet.
- But one frequency
with a particular form
and then you say there are limited
numbers of frequencies in the world...
- For example we see the
light in about 600 nm range.
And I don't remember exactly how
discreet the difference is.
Say 600 or 680 I can check it it's
not 600 and 600.9 and 600.92...
You are talking about a completely different
thing. The colors are what we perceive.
My point is there is a discreet, a
certain, limited amount of pathology
and we match that with the drug.
- That is quite a good idea though
when we talk of pathologies
in our sense of pathologies,
the pathologies are unlimited.
When you speak from conventional
medicine's point of view ok
there is a book of clinical medicine
which describes all the pathologies
but for me when I speak on pathologies
actually as I have said many times
you have a liver
cirrhosis, it a pathology,
but before it the liver has started
deteriorating 20 years before.
So there is a process during
which, as far as I am concerned,
the vibrational frequency of the organism
changes every now and then into another
and finally reaches the pathology
which we call liver cirrhosis.
But all along from the very
moment when there is hepatitis,
somebody is infected with
hepatitis B or C or A,
from that moment there is a change in
the frequency of the person in general.
Not of the liver only. And then from
that change that took place that time
of infection continues either to
deteriorate or go back to normal.
Because there might be a possibility
that you take a homeopathic remedy
and you are cured. But mostly what
happens is it has started with shock,
inflammation of the liver which ended
up after 20 years in liver cirrhosis.
All these are series
of pathologies.
If you catch the person instead
of coming 20 years later,
you catch the patient 10
years after the infection,
the vibrational frequency as far
as we are concerned is different
than the vibrational frequency of the
final stage, in which we receive.
Therefore the only way I can understand is
that the frequencies of the vital force,
the vital force is the energy,
is affected quite impressively
within a range of frequencies from substances
and this stimulation can go towards
the right direction or sometimes it can
go towards the wrong direction as well.
- The only explanation for
that is that the change
in the derangement of the vital force does
not continue by little bit but is abrupt...
- Quantum jump. The
electron changes...
- So there are more and more
cells in the liver that died.
But it doesn't mean they change in a
derangement of the vital force continuously.
Then we would have needed
a zillion of remedies...
- Let me ask another question
to the physicists who are here.
The vibrational rate of the human
body compared to the vibrational rate
of anything else which exists
compared to the vibrational rates
that can be modified or
produced by human inventions...
all these what we call vibrational
rates of electromagnetic fields
are limited or unlimited?
You say limited?
- No I just answered
this question first.
If you use equations of quantum mechanics
and apply to a large body of ours
the rate of the vibration is
very close to 0 as compared
to a molecule or whatever.
We don't really vibrate it's in
submolecular level that we vibrate.
I accept your ideas about
vibration as far as vital force
is concerned only as symbolic,
otherwise we can't.
A guitar vibrates mechanically which is
a totally different kind of vibration
from the electromagnetic. I am
not going to argue about that.
- Ok. This is just to
conclude the question.
This question at this moment
cannot be answered actually.
But we have some thoughts.
I told you my thoughts, you
have different other thoughts
and we will see what
actually happens.
I believe the changes which
take place either a change
towards the better or worse or
a change which is initiated
by the intervention of the homeopathic
remedy take place in subatomic level.
These are changes on a field which
we call the prana or the vital force
or the level of energies. I
have some ideas about that.
- In Organon paragraph 11 mentions there is
a spiritual mistuning of the vital force.
- That is different. We do not talk
about spirituality with that meaning.
Here spirit-like force has not the meaning
of a religious spiritual situation.
It has the meaning of a neutral
field that permeates everything
which exists in the Cosmos.
It's a neutral force and through
some workings of the nature
this force creates human forms or
any existing form we know about.
So between matter and energy,
it was Einstein who said
and therefore we can accept, that
what exists is only fields of energy.
The basic substance of our
existence is fields of energy
which have been transformed into
what all the existing things are.
If we want to enter this level of
discussion we are entering an area
which is not known even to the
most advance of the science today.
As I was saying, whether
this change happens abruptly
like from one millisecond
to another, it is a quantum
jump from one state to another,
we don't know how it happens.
I was suggesting that the electrons
that are around the nucleus
which are turning in their own
axis, are turning in one direction
like the earth is turning around the
sun but also turns around itself
in a particular direction, so what
might be happening is that the moment
we become sick out of a shock the
electrons change the direction
of turning around themselves.
When a biological
transmutation takes place,
that means the organism is able to
produce what is needed in the organism
from a simple food, for instance
during the German occupation,
when we had no money, which the German
did not feel uncomfortable with,
we had nothing, but
when we had nothing
we had only eating a
particular food, beans.
We were going with a cup like this,
I remember myself, 10 years,
they put you some and
then you eat it.
These beans which did not have calcium,
the calcium was produced by the organism
because they had a lot of magnesium,
so they got a lot of magnesium,
transformed it to calcium and then the
organism could built up the skeleton.
All the people are eating
that kind of food every day,
how come that one needs so much
calcium, the other needs much more,
the other doesn't need at all,
but how all this is balanced
though everyone eats the
same food every day.
So something happens within the
organism which transmutes,
it means making lead and
transmuted to gold,
this was the big
fantasy of the people.
This transmutation can take
place in nuclear fusion.
Then transforms uranium to energy
or to whatever is left over...
Then under such big hit can
transmute and within the body
then some people thought in cold fusion
that happens within the organism.
There is some energy.
In order to transmute uranium in to
this release of this tremendous energy
and what is left over is
the radioactive materials.
These rubbish they don't
know where to dump.
This is what is left out
of nuclear reactions.
In the body the same thing
is done, nuclear reactions
and the rubbish is the
urine and the stool.
From the nuclear
reaction in cold fusion.
What I want to say is that there are so
many things happening within the organism
which are unbelievable for us
to perceive and to control.
Can you say I can control my body
so it can absorb more calcium?
There is no way. The organism
will do whatever it likes.
You give too much calcium because
you think there is not much calcium
and because it cannot absorb it,
it poisons itself and dies.
This whole thing is so complicated
and is so complex for us
to be able to bring down to logical
information, it is very difficult, impossible.
We can have some ideas but we are very
little to understand the infinity.
We are finite. We have a
moment of birth and of death.
That is it, finished bye bye.
This little something which
we are... can we have an idea
that we can understand the
Cosmos and everything?
When you enter such a field and
you really want to go inside
then you stay in such a position
that you say Oh my God,
there is something else that is
going on beyond our comprehension
which is much more beyond us like
absolute knowledge, absolute existence.
You cannot approach. That
was a very good question.
- I would like to come to
the original question.
Just before the first
question from Germany.
You are talking about vibration of
the substances and then draw the...
being vibrational pathology
of the human body,
what I don't understand is that
we can use one remedy in level 7
and we can use the same remedy in
level 1, there will be a change...
- The same remedy will have a
different effect on every level.
Depending on what Hahnemann,
will bring the idea later on,
of the miasmatic
predisposition of the person.
If the miasmatic
predisposition is deep,
that means you come from a generation
of people who had a lot of syphilis,
gonorrhea, scabies, lepra, you
come from a heavy tradition
and then you have epilepsy.
What you see as level
7 here is epilepsy.
Needs the first remedy which will
reduce the effect of epilepsy.
Number 2 will reduce it even
more, number 3 will reduce it.
How was this epilepsy created? Because
the ancestors had skin eruption
that was suppressed and this
suppression went quite deep
and created a situation where
we say has a psoric miasm
and together with the syphilis
3-4-5 generation before,
together with gonorrhea that
was 2 generations before,
this suppressed eruption is now
coming as a form of epilepsy
which is going to be
difficult to be treated.
It really needs an expert
to unravel all that.
Because if you don't follow the
right direction that means here
when I say number 1 ,2 and 3
, I mean 3 correct remedies.
But what happens in real life, here
you have the first correct remedy,
the epilepsy stopped happening every
week, and will be once a month.
You prescribe once a month and you create
some confusion here, wrong remedies.
How can you come to the
next correct remedy?
If you prescribe 3-4-5
incorrect remedies.
Again there is some expert homeopath
who realizes the number 2 remedy
that you need. Then gives a further
boost and goes to number 3.
Again here wrong remedies... confusion.
Before you can get out of that.
What you say is in level
1, you can have epilepsy.
Due to stress the person can
go to epilepsy as well.
He has a very good predisposition a very
good organism coming from his parents.
This person with one remedy will
be cured from his epilepsy.
With the same remedy this one
just managed to go here.
Same remedy is given
Calcarea Carbonica.
That is why the Indians who are very
excited when they have a case cured
shout "we cure epilepsy!" You can
cure epilepsy of level 1 to 3.
You do not cure epilepsy
which is of level 7 or 8.
Not so easy, you may also cure this but it
is going to be another story altogether.
You cannot say we cure cancer. You
cure a cancer and yet their health
is currently in the first group,
level 1-2-3 and they get cancer.
Then they take 1 or 2 remedies and the
cancer is cured. So they get so excited.
But when it comes to the point you
where you have a heavy predisposition
then it is a different story.
Generations of syphilis... As I said there
was hair... how much hair they had.
It means they are free of syphilis,
in a huge scale. Easier cases.
It is not a joke but a fact.
Kent mentions this that syphilis
except of the other known pathology
which creates, like the
syphilis in the skin
then it goes deeper in the nervous
system, the neurosyphilis etc.,
creates to the next generations
falling of hair and alcoholism.
The tendency to alcoholism
and the falling of hair.
He had noticed for instance Syphilinum
to some people that as a reaction
that they had falling of their hair.
He describes all that and it is true.
People whom you see
with baldness indicate
that there is most probably a
heavy effect from syphilis.
That is why most of the people of the
west, especially English people,
who are bald, because they
practice sexual excesses etc.
But the Indians who were occupied by the
English were not coming near the English
because they had strong ethics.
They stayed together to their
families, they were protected.
Some Indian prostitutes were giving
syphilis to a lot of English soldiers.
This was the punishment of
the English occupying India.
Nobody actually knew
what was taking place,
but it was a punishment of the English
occupying force that all of them
came back to England with syphilis.
Treated with mercury etc.
Then you see all the distortions of
the syphilis in the mental sphere
because if you see people
thinking that we should go to war
and kill each other and
all that... Is this normal?
- I was thinking how sociopathic most of
the western presidents and everybody is.
That is syphilitic miasm? The Americans for
example are constantly at war with everyone.
- It is not only syphilitic
miasm but a mixture of miasms.
At this moment the West in general
are affected by a mixture miasms
and also together
with vaccinations
that have deeply affected the human race.
We just witnessed an action of cruelness.
I see in the western population great
difficulties in bringing back health.
The races that are going to control
eventually will be South Americans
and Asian races, Indians,
Pakistanis, Turks.
Turkey is coming with a lot of
punishment, with drugs and vaccinations.
You will get it.
- From your explanation Calcarea
in lower level 7 comes together
with a lot of noises then it will
be the next remedy number 2, 3.
While in level 1
Calcarea is pure.
Can we say that coming up to level 1
of health we actually come closer
to the pure resonance? That
means when we find the remedy
that it matches with the person.
Can we say that the remedy one
level 1 is actually a remedy
that characterizes a person
and we come very close ...?
- We say this person has a clear
remedy picture of Sulphur, Phosphorus,
once you see this, it is the greatest
luck for the patient and doctor.
But in this case, Calcarea
Carbonica or Phosphorus
will be in-between the
different other remedies.
You will have to analyze very well
to understand not a Calcarea,
not an Arsenicum, not a Lycopodium, not
a Phosphorus. But it will look like.
I get Calcarea carbonica
or this or that remedy
and then you have to analyze correctly
and to prescribe to have the effect.
- I have a paradox in my mind.
If we come very close in level
1 to the pure resonance
wouldn't we close very close to
the infinity of our differences
and we should see level 1 to
the infinity of who we are?
We are so different one from each other
and there are all these substances
that could be used... But still
in level 1 we see limited...
Calcarea, Sulphur... Very healthy.
- Why don't we see peculiar
remedies in the uppermost levels?
- Why don't we see a big variety?
- There must be a reason.
I don't know the reason. I can give
you some answer but I don't know.
The reason is that the
basic miasm is the psoric.
What is the psoric? Suppressed
scabies, originally.
What does it do? It has an effect
upon the skeleton primarily.
Upon the skeleton means upon
the absorption of calcium.
So whatever remedies are connected
with absorption of calcium
will be the basic remedies.
Calcarea carbonica, maybe Magnesias,
Ferrum, some other remedies
which are concerned... as I said
before transmutation takes place
with beans every day which
contain a lot of Ferrum,
the organisms transmutes Ferrum in
to Calcium. That is why I think.
We come back to the basic minerals
of the body which are needed.
The 12 tissue salts. Silica, Calcarea
Carbonica, Calcarea fluorica,
Calcarea phosphorica,
Magnesia phosphorica etc.
These are the main remedies
that we will finally need.
But I will tell you something that
even if you arrive at that stage
where you feel really good and you have
a person who is happy, full of life,
full of energy, who enjoys
life, such a person
should have the best
possibility for living long.
200 years.
300 years.
What doesn't he live long? Because
he has a choice all the time.
All the moment in his
life will have a choice
and the choice will
be shall I do this?
Not good, don't do it says the conscience.
But I am attracted.
So by choosing the actions
brings back disease.
Eventually the possibility which
a person had to live 120 years
comes down to 75 where he
says goodbye to the world.
Though very good and healthy people
that enjoyed life very much.
The choice that we are given
to do good or bad is ours
so we do whatever we like.
We live longer or shorter.
Here is Homeopathy for those who are
not so lucky as to be in level 1
that always supports... ok live
one more year... take the remedy.
- I would like to ask a question
about what you explained before.
I am also stuck to the
figure on the board.
There is the case on
level 7 who has epilepsy
because a lot of ancestors had
suppressions. This is easy to understand.
In the first group it's logic there can
be a case with the same pathology.
Also convulsions and so on.
But comes from
healthy ancestors.
How can such a child be born
without the severe predisposition?
- How can somebody be born healthy if
today we have gone through all these?
I don't believe that anybody which is
born in the western world is healthy,
to tell you the truth.
- Let's say hypothetical case who is
really healthy, let's say in India,
they had healthy ancestors. In group 1
still develop epilepsy but without injury.
Where does this
predisposition come from?
- Where does a predisposition of healthy
individuals come from in Group 1?
I'll tell you something.
In the North America, the
red Indians were living.
They were eliminated by the Europeans
transferring to them the TB, disease etc.
From this example we can understand
what actually is happening.
That means in an environment which
is unhealthy any healthy individual
can be affected
to a deep degree.
Because the immune system has
not learned to face situations
which are very
pathological, inimical.
Therefore if you bring somebody from
a family life with all the love,
all the good things which happen in a
nice environment which is full of love,
and you put him into a society
in which he feels alien,
this person is going to develop all kinds
of diseases without predisposition.
- It's not the disposition.
It's an acquired disease.
- Before I answer this question
I have to tell you also this.
In case an individual is coming
to you with a psychological state
which is quite pathological though you
cannot understand it at the moment.
He has depression, different mental/
emotional problems and he is in level 8.
But on the uppermost level.
You give a remedy and while he is coming
back in his psychological condition,
he develops epilepsy. And from there
on you have to continue to treat
in order to take him out.
You may give sometimes a remedy and while
the mental condition is better there
appears a pathology
which is in unexpected.
It comes from the predisposition
because he was in level 8
when he had the depression. He
was not on level 1 or 2 or 3.
- I have 2 questions. I have not
actually understood what do you mean
by unhealthy people in the west because
here I see people who are very happy,
nobody is depressed, I don't
understand what do you mean by that!
- You live constantly in
a happy state, in bliss.
Do you really live in
another world from us?
Her eyes are full of
energy and happiness.
What are you talking about? Of
course you don't understand
because in India it is a fact most
of the pathology is physical.
I remember when I was
in India I was asking
and they didn't even
understand what I was asking.
Life is so simple, we love each other,
we are happy, we live together.
They don't even
understand what we mean.
What we mean is something we
experience because of predisposition.
We are coming through ancestors
who had syphilis, gonorrhea, TB
and the pathology went through from
different levels into the deepest part
which is the brain. You
are happy, stay happy!
- One more regarding
predisposition.
I'll ask with an example.
Suppose in my family none
had history of diabetes
and my father was the first to get diabetes
at the age of 36 after I was born.
Will I get the predisposition
of diabetes or not?
- Yes.
- But he got it after I was born
and no history of diabetes.
- It doesn't matter.
What it means is that your father had
a predisposition to get diabetes.
Diabetes is a disease of
influent people, who are rich,
have enough to eat and
actually overeat.
I remember when I was in India back in the
1960s most of the people were so thin
and if somebody was little bit fat,
it was considered a great beauty.
So everybody wanted to marry a
woman who was a little bit fat.
That was the model by that time.
Now diabetes comes because
you eat too much sweets
and eventually there is diabetes and the
diabetes is going to be transferred
to the new generation.
Be careful!
- You are talking
about predisposition.
What is different between
predisposition and miasm?
- Miasm creates predisposition.
It is the miasm that creates it.
One miasm which creates a certain
predisposition for certain diseases.
You had 2 miasms you have more
predisposition for more disease.
3 miasms even more.
To what degree you have
this miasm in your body
it will be shown in the
manifestation of the pathology
whether it will be
malignant or not.
A lot predisposition for syphilis,
that means your father had syphilis
or your grandfather, will
be in the nervous system.
If you had gonorrhea it will be on
producing tumors, explosions, condylomata
and in general tumors which are manifesting
if the predisposition is close.
So you have a predisposition of
syphilis out of 5 generations behind,
a predisposition of psora 10 generation
behind and a predisposition of sycosis
one generation behind then most probably
the first manifestation will be tumors.
- One comment on the
diabetes issue.
There is a new kind of diabetes
in India in particular
where thin people do get diabetes and
it is very tricky kind of diabetes
because it is hidden in thin people and
people who, when their mothers were pregnant
and they didn't have all the
nutrients it's a paradox
the children got diabetes, it's not
because of overindulgence to excess food.
That is one comment on that. It's
a little bit more complicated
but I have one question regarding the
predisposition in families with many children
where the parents have the same
predispositions themselves and they have...
- Wait a moment. In a family of
5 children the predisposition
is not going to be equal for everyone.
It is going to be different.
We say predisposition and we
get a general idea but in fact
when a baby is conceived depending
on the state of the parents
the predisposition will be better or worse
according to the state of the 2 parents
when the conception took place.
- I was expecting this answer.
- So one child is diabetic and
the second child has no problem.
- You have commented in your book
that the children who come from love
they have the biggest potential
to become healthy people.
But there are children conceived from
parents who really wanted to have a child,
were really in love with each other
and had a very bad genetic syndrome
and when they were born they couldn't
live or the mother had a miscarriage
because of this very
strong syndrome.
After that they may have had
other kids which were normal.
There are the same set of genes
and predisposition from a couple
who love each other a lot but...
- I am sorry I have not been
able to conceive your question.
Can you make it more concrete?
- Why a couple who love
each other have a child...
- Which is sick and
another which is not.
- They love each
other all the time.
- If 2 people who are married
and they love each other
and they continue to love each other
why one child is not so healthy
and the other is? Is
that the question?
I'll tell you something. What I
mean when I say in love is this.
When 2 people meet and they become
infatuated in a relationship
in which they feel I have found the right
person that moment is a special moment
which has special meaning for both
of them and gives them a feeling
of great completeness
when they are together.
So this feeling of completeness
when they are together,
that means I don't need anything once I
am with you I feel I don't need anything.
The whole world
is under my feet.
That is a state of love which
comes only unfortunately once.
I will explain more.
That situation in which you felt that
that everything you wanted in life
has been fulfilled
through this contact,
this completeness is going
to produce a complete child.
That child is going to get all the
best genes of you and your partner.
Because by the moment you
are in that exalted state
all the cells perceive this completeness.
They become complete.
It means all the elements and the
structures are in complete harmony.
The child which is going to be born it is
going to be a child which feels complete.
That child will be happy. Will not be
ambitious, a scientist of great attainment.
He is not interested because he has the
completeness inside, the happiness.
The child will be like this.
What is going to happen later on with
life whether the child will meet
with an equal child... The
real question starts here.
If I continue to be in
love with my husband
why my second child was not
as good as the first one?
Because the people who are really in
love for the first time it is something
which is so powerful that nothing
can be compared with that
and the only thing that can compare this
state is the state of the saint people
in certain moments in the
effort to approach God
where the click is made and they say my God
now I feel full of absolute knowledge,
existence, bliss, complete.
That state comes only once and it
is given only to young people.
Young people can have the power and they
should have also the cultural background
to wait until they found
their real partner.
If they did not wait they
want to try to experiment
and to have another
partner... it's finished.
They can never come to
that state of love.
The moment they indulge in a lot of
partners forget about that situation.
The child is going to be
born with limitations.
I come back to the case where
you are still in love.
You think you are still in love.
The first time of two
people being in love
and having sex unprotected in having
a child, that is very rare today,
that child is going to be
a child of love, wisdom,
a child who has everything.
Except from ambition.
I want to become
a scientist etc.
They are complete and whatever
they do they do it in moderation.
Now you feel you are still in love but
you are not in that exciting state.
It has fallen quite a lot.
In the second conception the
child starts having limitation.
That child will become ambitious,
jealous, will have limitations.
Will try to catch up because
it's absolutely impossible.
This is a law of nature in order
to rejuvenate the human race
and to make possible to the human
to reach spiritually higher states.
Whoever has arranged that says if you
wait and you meet the right partner
then your child will be in
better health than you.
Because the child that will
be born under this condition
will be healthier
than the parent.
So you can imagine if that
continues then we have a new race
which is going to be
another type of people.
Full of love, they can never
become generals, kill people.
Simple people but at
the same time wise.
The have love and
wisdom together.
Can these people become
general who has to kill?
Can these people become scientists
who manipulate the virus
so he can send it over to eliminate a
few millions of people? Of course not!
These people will never
become prominent in society.
And this is the way that regeneration
of the human race can take place.
That means the children of
love should stay alive.
Today the children of love are aborted.
You are too young to have a child.
Out! First abortion, second
abortion, after the third abortion
I cannot have a child anymore.
Go to a homeopath!
She told I have 500 sterile women... 400
women with sterility cannot have a child
because most of them they would
have abortions one after another.
And the endometrium
is destroyed.
It's the worst thing that
can happen to a woman.
What I mean by real love, completeness is
very difficult thing to happen really.
Very seldom. Very lucky people.
The man is 25 still he could control
his urges he did not go out
and play around and the woman the
same she is 21-22 they meet suddenly
there is explosion and the best genes are
transferred to the young generation.
One time, second a little bit less, the
third after 5 years of marriage... less.
In 7 years of
marriage is goodbye!
Still the love is there,
of course you care,
but what is missing is the spark that
made that magic thing come into reality.