I did not make it clear therefore I wanted
to present it again so it can be made clear.
I will read it again.
"In those older prescriptions of the
often dangerous effects of medicines
ingested in excessively large doses we
notice certain states that were produced".
He means the doctors who had written down
the symptoms of the people who were dying.
Keep in mind in those older
prescriptions of those
who ingested in large doses
some states were produced.
"not at the commencement" these states
that they recorded the last state
where they were dying. Not at the
commencement, they did not know
how the whole thing started.
"but towards the termination
of these sad events"
they noted down only when they were
dying, so he was dying, he was in a coma,
grinding his teeth,
they recorded.
"and which were of an exactly opposite
nature to those that first appeared"
He sais those records describing
the last stages of poisoning
are the exact opposite of the
first symptoms that started.
That means you ingest a poison and you get
nausea, chills, vomiting, diarrhea etc.
The pathology progresses
more and more.
We are interested in the functional,
primary symptomatology.
We are not interested in the end
stages when it crosses the red line.
Once the line is
crossed it is useless.
Let us see whether Hahnemann means the
same with what I have said or not.
"These symptoms, the very reverse
of the primary action (par. 63)"
that means completely different,
do not take it into consideration.
"or proper action of the medicines" he
considers proper action of the medicine
only the primary symptoms,
that means the symptoms
before the organism crosses
the redline and goes dying.
"on the vital force are the reaction
of the vital force of the organism,
its secondary action (par.par. 62-67), of which,
however, there is seldom or hardly ever
the least trace from experiments with
moderate doses on healthy bodies"
in these last stages hardly any
of the symptoms are similar
to the original
functional symptoms.
The last stages where the person
dies which have been recorded
by the toxicologists of the time, who did not
record the primary symptoms, are useless.
This is what I was saying. I will
continue because it is very important.
"However, there is seldom or hardly ever the
least trace from experiments with moderate doses
on healthy bodies and from small doses"
in these records there is nothing
which we use when we give a small dose and we
have a primary reaction of the vital force.
He is not correct when he says
that but we will discuss it later.
He is not absolutely correct.
"In the homoeopathic curative operation"
listen to this because it is important
because it supports another
mistake that he has made
concerning the explanation of the reaction of
the organism after the homeopathic remedy.
"In the homoeopathic curative operation
the living organism reacts from these
only so much as is requisite"  That
means correct homeopathic remedy.
"The living organism reacts from
these only so much as is requisite
to raise the health again to the
normal healthy state (par. 67)."
That means the action of the curative remedy
makes the organism raise its response
to the extent that is needed
to bring a curative reaction.
So with this phrase he nullifies the
idea of a stronger medicinal action
to suppress weaker natural disease. Here he
says exactly what I have explained before.
The homeopathic remedy raises the
reaction of the organism so much
as it is needed, no more, in
order to overcome the disease.
But this is what I have been
saying when I said that
when the homeopathic remedy is prescribed
then there is an aggravation of the symptoms
to the extent that is needed
to bring about a cure.
I see in your eyes
some doubts still.
Anyhow, let me recapitulate
and take the essence of this.
The symptoms which are useful for us come
from primary reaction of the vital force.
Once these symptoms have reached a stage
which he calls "a sad event" meaning death,
what you record in these last
stage conditions is not useful.
Therefore secondary symptoms, which he
means the last ending symptoms of the life
of the person, are of no use.
He says many time the primary symptoms are
the exact opposite of the last symptoms.
I'll give you an example
to make it very clear.
In an epileptic fit, convulsions
are the primary symptoms,
a great activity of the body
and then passes the red line
and we have status epilepticus. There
is no action, there is a paralysis.
In status epilepticus there is
no more the convulsive activity
which was originally present.
And there is the opposite.
When the organism has reached the
secondary stage the symptoms of it
are the opposite actually
of the primary stage.
What we are interested in is the
primary stage and not the secondary.
Let me give you another example.
- I am not a neurologist but from my knowledge,
status epilepticus is an epileptic fit
that lasts more than 30 minutes
so there are still convulsions
and after that post-status there
is this complete paralysis.
But when it is status epilepticus
we still have the epileptic fits.
- Don't play with the words.
What I mean that as long as there is
activity, we call it primary stage.
When it reaches the other part then
we call it the status epilepticus
where he has been paralyzed.
That second stage, the paralysis, is
of no use to record, homeopathically.
What is homeopathically useful is the
first part which shows the symptoms.
Once the vital force has given up
then there is a comatose state.
- I don't know if it is good
for me to intervene now.
Another example came to my mind. When there
is paroxysmal disturbance of the heart.
The heart continues pumping. If it
progresses it gets fibrillated,
there is electrical activity
which is completely chaotic,
but it is not pumping anything anymore. The
patient collapses, there is still function
but is completely chaotic.
- Exactly.
These are the stages where Hahnemann separates
between primary and secondary action.
You get a very high fever, tremendous
headache, stiffness, meningoencephalitis
but there is a lot of activity.
At a certain moment the activity stops
and the person falls into coma.
That state crosses the line. That
state he calls secondary action.
This secondary stages are not
useful for homeopathic prescribing.
Is it clear? You can ask as many question
as you like until this becomes clear.
Otherwise a kind of confusion
will remain in your mind.
- It's clear to me but maybe the
confusion is caused by the fact
that Hahnemann in paragraph
62 and 67 means something...
- Ok let's go to
these paragraphs.
We go to paragraph 62
to see what he says.
"But on what this pernicious result of
the palliative, antipathic treatment
and the efficacy of the reverse, the
homoeopathic treatment, depend,
is explained by the following facts,
deduced from manifold observations,
which no one before me perceived, though they
are so very palpable and so very evident,
and are of such infinite
importance to the healing art.
Every agent that acts upon the
vitality, every medicine,
deranges more or less the vital force,
and causes a certain alteration
in the health of the individual
for a longer or a shorter period.
This is termed primary action.
Although a product of the medicinal
and vital powers conjointly,
it is principally due
to the former power.
To its action our vital force
endeavors to oppose its own energy.
This resistant action is a property, is indeed an
automatic action of our life-preserving power,
which goes by the name of secondary
action or counteraction."
Here secondary action means that the moment
that there is an intrusion in the body
the organism always will
oppose with a symptomatology
and here he uses the word "secondary
action" in a completely different meaning
than what he uses there.
What he says here is not correct but I
will explain to you the whole process.
From the moment there is an ingestion in the
human organism of anything inimical to it,
either bacteria or microbes or
viruses or poisoning or bad food,
the moment they enter the
organism it scans the situation.
It says what is this? There is something
entering me which is not familiar.
It takes some time to decide
whether it will react or not.
This is called in medical
parlance incubation period.
After this period decides what chemicals
reaction have been done so far,
the 7 days of incubation period,
whatever I have done is not enough,
so he mobilizes the organism on a secondary
step which is vomiting, purging, fever.
This is a secondary reaction
of the organism.
Therefore from the very beginning
that something enters the organism
which is inimical there is a reaction of the
organism whether we understand it or not
is a different matter and that's why
they have said incubation period
in which we don't have symptoms... we do have
symptoms, we don't really realize them.
There are little things we
don't feel, mild symptoms.
The organism has been mobilized already.
But now it allows the problem grow.
The colonies of the bacteria are increasing very
fast so the organism reacts more violently.
But actually calling this primary
or secondary is not correct.
All the time it's the reaction of the vital
force against an agent which endangers life.
From the very beginning there
is reaction of the vital force.
What he say in paragraph
111 is different.
He says those old prescribers, old
people who saved the life of the people
who were poisoned, recorded the last stages,
but instead of saying "the last stages"
he says secondary action of the drug. And
then it was confused with this other.
But further down will explain exactly what he
says. And you will understand even better.
There are 2 stages.
One primary in which we have the fighting
of the vital force producing symptoms.
Secondary stage, where the vital force
has given up, there is no fight anymore,
the person has fallen into coma or the last
stages of his life and he passes away.
That is not useful for us to record.
We cannot use it.
What we are interested in is whatever
happens after some moderate doses.
Some new people.
- Your saying is very beautifully reflected
in our basic reaction to stress.
The first reaction to stress
is sympathetic, fight or flee.
This is the primary reaction which produces
fast heartbeat, the blood goes to the muscles,
to the periphery, less blood
going to the digestive system...
In the moment when the body decides
that the stress is too much
then the reaction is completely opposite.
It's parasympathetic, freeze or fold.
And then the blood is taken from the
periphery, the heart rate decreases...
- I understand.
The problem with this explanation
is that whether it is sympathetic
or parasympathetic reaction,
it's still a reaction.
There is still a functional
disturbance which we have recorded.
May be the opposite, maybe
alternating as I said before.
When giving a lot of opium first there
is diarrhea, then after a while
it causes a long state
of constipation.
But still these are to be
recorded in useful situations.
What he says in paragraph 112
is; crossing the red line,
those people who wrote down these symptoms of
the poisonings, they described only people
before death, 5 minutes before death
and these stages are not useful for us.
When we say sympathetic/ parasympathetic,
will still have functional symptoms...
I'll give you an example from the
hospital in India. Very characteristic.
I was in Calcutta college and
usually though I was a student
I was attending together with the attending
physician after the professor came around the wards
of the hospital watching, discussing the cases.
There was a case of acute typhoid fever.
The professors would come and ask
questions. Said give Gelsemium, he gave it.
I had taken the case and asking together
with the attending physician before them
and said he needs Hyoscyamus. Next
day he comes, is worse... Helleborus.
I said I said give him Hyoscyamus, he
is going to die. I cannot do it.
Don't tell them just give, he will die.
3rd day they gave another remedy.
With the 3rd remedy the fever drops and
he comes excited and said you were wrong.
The correct remedy was the last
one, I can't remember what it was.
I went to the patient and I felt the pulse.
The pulse was 200, I couldn't count actually.
I tell them do you think he is
doing better? Yes, no fever.
I said in few hours he will die. Why?
Because there is a perforation.
The guts have broken down and blood is coming
out very fast so the heart cannot tolerate.
In the afternoon he died. In that
stage you could do nothing anymore.
Whether you give Hyoscyamus in
that stage is not important
because the picture is not there.
There is no vital force to react.
The guts have broken, big arteries were
open and the blood was flowing out.
No fever, no symptoms. This
is what I am trying to say.
- As far as I understand and
please correct me if it's wrong,
as long as you can observe the effort of
the organism to get rid of the poison
or to overcome the disease, the
symptoms are important for us.
If you see a poisoning you have
to write it down and in a disease
these are the symptoms you have to
take in order to cure a patient.
At that moment you see the organism
giving up overcoming the poisoning.
The symptoms you see at this moment
are useless for us. Is this correct?
- If I understood well you say that
from the moment when the patient
is going in the last stage
symptoms are not useful.
- At the moment when you cannot see
an effort to come back to life.
You see no effort of the organism come
back to life or to overcome the poisoning.
At this moment it's useless.
- The vital force has given up.
I can't react anymore.
Because the actual pathology, that means
the heart is blocked in 5 places,
forget it, I give up, I
can't pass the blood.
The liver is cirrhosed and it blows up and it's
finished, the last stages of liver cirrhosis.
The last stages of typhoid fever, encephalitis
or whatever, they fall into coma.
This stage in paragraph 112 Hahnemann
calls secondary reaction.
"secondary action, of which, however, there
is seldom or hardly ever the least trace
from experiments with moderate doses" That
means the experiment with small doses
brings up 2 matters.
One is the fact that the doctors who have described
the poisonings describe the last stages.
And these last stages he said when
we try the remedy on moderate doses,
they gave out some symptoms, these symptoms
have nothing to do with the last stage
which was without
symptomatology.
- Yesterday you mentioned the
bipolar character of the remedies.
- Wait, the bipolar will come
later I think. My problem is that
before I come I
should have read it.
But I don't have time. Let
me read the other paragraph.
- I understand something slightly different
with primary and secondary action.
What I understand is that primary action
is when the organism gets insulted
by something and the vital force
reacts and it produces some symptoms
which are the primary action. Then the
organism tries to do a healing process.
The healing process
might be successful.
Sometimes you have an influenza
or not when you take a poison.
During this healing process you might have
some opposite symptoms to the primary action.
For example if you make a poison
which is poisonous to the kidneys
and at first you may have oliguria which means
you have scanty urine or not urination at all.
Then if the organism is successful
in overcoming this poisonous agent
then you have a
phase of polyuria.
The scanty urine which is attributed to the
poisonous agent, this is the primary action.
The polyuria is the secondary reaction.
The only problem when taking a poison
is when the secondary action is
not successful, then you die.
That's what I understand.
- No.
As long as there is a vital force
which is in a position to react
whether it is reacting one way or another
it is considered primary action,
it doesn't matter what can be
because when we give a remedy
there is many time severe aggravation.
This is not considered the opposite.
We may consider it as different
type of symptomatology
but not secondary reaction
in the meaning of Hahnemann.
The secondary action on this paragraph
is referred to the old prescribers.
He should say describers. Those who have
described the last stages of diseases.
He compares his experience
with moderate doses
with what the old prescribers have described
as the end result of poisoning and he says
that these contain hardly any useful symptom
of the original reaction of the organism.
- I would like to tell something about
primary action and secondary action.
When Hahnemann is explaining about primary
and secondary action from aphorism 63.
Hahnemann is explaining about the
operation of homeopathic medicine.
In aphorism 63 Hahnemann is telling the primary
action is the action of the agent on the body.
For example you have coffee. The action
of coffee in the body is sleeplessness.
That is primary action.
And secondary action of the vital force
which is sleepiness after 3 hours.
If you take coffee for 3
hours you don't have sleep
(that is the action of caffeine on
the body, that is primary action)
then the vital force reacts... The
primary action of coffee is no sleep...
- I understood now.
I have said that but this is not
what he means in this paragraph.
We will explain eventually that this cannot
be called primary but alternating symptoms.
That means in the beginning it causes sleeplessness
and in the end it causes sleepiness.
These are still useful symptoms. You
don't have to call them secondary.
Paragraph 115. "Among these symptoms, there
occur in the case of some medicines not a few
which are partially, or under certain
conditions, directly opposite to other symptoms
that have previously or
subsequently appeared,
but which are not therefore to be
regarded as actual secondary action
or the mere reaction of the vital force, but
which only represent the alternating state
of the various paroxysms of the primary
action; they are termed alternating actions."
This is very clear. Exactly
the coffee example.
It firstly brings sleeplessness
and then it gives sleepiness.
He says not to call
it secondary action.
Because he understands that George
and his students will be confused
with what I wrote and so I have to explain in
paragraph 115, don't call them secondary action,
call them "alternating actions".
- I just wanted to show something on the
board to confirm if I am right or not.
Just 1 minute.
- What are you going to write?
- I think that this is
the primary action.
And that's the turning point where there is
a secondary action and then comes death.
This is when the vital force is doing something
good to me, so it's trying to cure myself...
What I understood is when we give a medicine
to person who is diseased, the vital force...
- Once you give a remedy
is a different story.
We are talking no the provings of
the remedies and which are the provings
that we have to take
into consideration.
The proving we have to take into consideration
are those of the reaction of the vital force,
of the defense mechanism.
And these are valid.
Once this has happened...
There I don't understand.
- It's the turning point.
After that point the symptoms are 5 minutes
before death. These are of no use.
- If this is 5 minutes before death you
ignore it. No information from that part.
These are the most important here
that you will take into consideration
and once this happens that means the vital
force has given up we call it 'no reaction'
because there is an artery that has
been ruptured and the blood is flowing
until a certain moment
there is some reaction.
At a certain moment where the blood is
out there is a paucity of symptoms, faints,
if you touch the pulse
you will see 300bpm.
- What I said is ok?
- Yes.
This is what I have
been saying all along.
There is another paragraph
which I don't think anybody will be
able to understand what Hahnemann says.
Paragraph 113. You know the 13
number is always a difficult number.
"The only exceptions to this
are the narcotic medicines."
Opium, morphine, hashish
in big quantities etc.
"As they, in their primary action, take away
sometimes the sensibility and sensation,
sometimes the irritability, it frequently
happens that in their secondary action,
even from moderate experimental
doses on healthy bodies,
an increased sensibility (and a
greater irritability) is observable."
If anybody can tell me what this paragraph
is saying I will give him the 1st prize!
The problem is this is definitely a bad
translation but if somebody has the German...
Because I have another book here which
gives a little bit better translation.
115. If you can translate
it in your own words.
- If somebody takes narcotics and
makes a proving he has 2 stages.
In the first stage he gets some
symptoms like he is happier or duller
and the next day maybe he is more irritable.
It's like some kind of dependency.
I wouldn't call it secondary action. If
somebody takes narcotics symptoms are produced.
If the medicine is stopped then
he might have withdrawal symptoms
which are different from the symptoms
produced by opium or marijuana.
- I will read it now from
another translator Wesselhoeft.
"Only narcotic drugs should be
regarded as exceptions to this rule.
As these destroy sensibility and
sensation, as well as irritability,
in their primary effect, a
heightened state both of sensibility
and of irritability is frequently
observed in healthy persons,
as an after-effect following the
administration of narcotics"
Not as secondary action. After-effect.
Thank you.
Hahnemann wants to cover as many possibilities
as possible he even speaks about narcotics.
What he says; in the primary effect of
narcotics, you take opium, you are happy.
You don't have any symptoms. The sensibility
and sensitivity and irritability are gone.
This is the opposite with the usual
other whatever substance you may take.
Because immediately in other
substance the organism would react
and the person would
feel this reaction.
But in narcotics the sensitivity and sensibility
is destroyed, the person doesn't feel.
That why with opium we say
the patient feels fine.
And we take into consideration
not the symptoms
but the fact the person says I am fine though
he is lying down there with 40 C fever.
We take into consideration that the
person says I am feeling fine.
Because in narcotics the sensitivity and the
irritability of the organism has been destroyed.
But later on of course, after the effect, the
organism comes back with sensitivity, irritability,
as an aftereffect of the primary action. This
is what today we call withdrawal syndrome.
That means the real effect of the
drug does not appear immediately.
On the contrary, immediately appears
a kind of sedation, insensibility.
But once this is gone the vital force
comes back and reacts as an after-effect,
side-effects of people taking opium,
heroine. They have withdrawal syndrome.
But if you read it the way he
writes it nobody can understand.
Now is it clear? I don't believe
that anybody understood.
This Greek gastroenterologist
is a very inquisitive woman.
- He says that aftereffect in narcotic
comes even for moderate doses of the drug.
- Even a little bit of opium
may give you a sedation.
- But this doesn't happen
with other substances.
- It doesn't happen with other drugs because
if you take let's say 3 gr of Nux vomica
or strychnine the reaction will
be much stronger and immediate.
In narcotics first there is sedation, the
sensibility is gone, and you feel quite good.
This is why people
take these drugs.
Because as a primary action they feel
excellent, they have sometimes experiences
which are "spiritual". It's not spiritual
experiences, it experience of the spirit, alcohol.
Both give experiences but
not of the same quality.
- Because they are narcotics there is this
aftereffect where in other substances
there is only the primary
effect, no aftereffect.
- This is not secondary action.
This is aftereffect.
If you call it secondary action then
you are confused with the word.
Because you stuck with the
words and you are confused.
Because the translators were not
as careful as we are in analyzing.
This is the problem.
- Maybe you can explain people taking
a lot of alcohol as a narcotic
and they day after they have the after
effect. And they have to drink.
There are lots of drugs on
which people are addicted
because the aftereffect
was 'I need more'.
If I get a little more for a
short time I have a good feeling
and then they need
more and more.
- More and more to keep a state of
happiness. Artificial happiness.
- An understandable example from life that
comes to my mind is the sedation to animals.
When we use sedation they lose the
ability to feel pain and hear
but when they wake up they are much
more sensitive to noise and light.
- Exactly!
- Can you explain this theory with
the example allergic reaction?
For instance allergic reaction to penicillin if
there is skin reaction? Anaphylactic reaction.
- There are organisms who are more sensitive
to certain substances than others.
So there are people at this moment that are
so sensitive to penicillin as you mention
that by smelling penicillin
can go into coma.
Why they have become so
sensitive is another story.
Most probably the mother or the
father had taken a lot of penicillin
and the child is born with a
predisposition for this particular drug
and then this drug can bring
about a terrific reaction.
The same happens with
drugs, I believe.
People who are coming from parents
who are used to narcotics.
Such children will be much more sensitive
to the touch of the narcotics.
And I have seen cases that people who are
coming from parents who are alcoholics,
they themselves have never touched alcohol.
They say I don't like alcohol.
That means there is a relationship
between alcohol and themselves
which is of very
sensitive nature.
They feel if they touch alcohol
either they feel very bad
or maybe they will go into the
habit of drinking quite a lot.
I have noticed children of parents who
were alcoholics don't touch alcohol.
On the contrary those who touch
they go very fast into alcoholism.
- I would like to
come back to Organon.
In paragraph 112 where you can
read about the secondary action
and the original German
word is the after-action.
Even in paragraph 112 he writes about the
after-action. Not of the secondary action.
- In paragraph 62
what word is used?
- In paragraph 63 it's the after... opposite
acting, not the secondary acting.
The after action or
opposite action.
- When we use the narcotics as remedies,
do we take into consideration both
the primary and the
after-effects?
- The aftereffect of the narcotics is a
reaction of the vital force from small doses.
Therefore we take it as a symptoms
of the remedy we are examining.
- So we take both the irritability
and the loss of irritability.
- Yes. It is a series.
The fact that the vital force in the first by the
narcotic becomes sedated,
does not speak out with violence or anger,
is still a reaction of the vital force.
From the very moment the substance goes
into the human body the vital force
starts reacting and
evaluating, like scanning.
Evaluating; something has entered
me, can I deal with that easily?
If it is food I can, if it is
overeating I have a problem.
What is the problem?
I don't feel well.
I need to vomit now because of overeating.
Even simple food.
We don't take into consideration as
symptom after eating the problems
because if we overeat like that, we have
fish, soup, meat, fat meat, salad, fruits,
sweets, alcohol and then I say I don't
feel well now, I have to vomit.
Which is the cause of the vomiting? You
cannot say out of all these you have eaten.
We call it overeating. The organism reacts
but the organism to a certain point
when you put things inside
says ok I can deal with that.
After a certain point starts
saying I cannot deal with that.
Do not give me more. You
keep on drinking...
Once in my life I got drunk, 3 of us were
18, we went to Plaka under the Acropolis
to have some wine and eat... it was a big
thing the 3 of us... because we had no idea.
We had never drunk before so
we ordered wine, retsina.
Bring us 200 drams which
is about 1/3 of a kilo.
We ordered some meze you know some snack
but the snack took a long time to come
and we were drinking in the meantime we
were drinking the wine 300 grams of wine.
That means 100 and 100 and 100.
We finished the 300 gram and
we ordered another 300.
By the time the meze snack came we are
in the middle of the second bouts
which was about 150
grams to each one.
The meze snack came and by the
time we started eating the meze
because we were not used to drinking this
little wine made us all totally drunk.
I remember that when the waiter came
to be paid to make the account,
the bill was 38 drachmas. We
had a note of 100 drachmas.
The bill was less than 50 percent so we were
so drunk that one of us gives the 100 drachmas
and the waiter was about to give us the
change. One of us says keep the change.
In the meantime I wanted to say 'no it
is too much' but I was laughing so much
that I could not talk. The waiter
waited... this is my chance...
For a long time I could not say this
is too much, they could not realize.
I was the only one who could
realize but I could not speak.
It was impossible.
Anyhow the waiter understood that and he gave
the change and we took the bus to go home.
In the bus we keep on
laughing all the time.
Everybody was looking at us.
As you know I had no parents from the age
of 11 and was living with aunts and uncles.
I go home and I lie and my aunt looks at
me, where have you been, it's 11 o'clock?
I pretend that I don't understand and I
go to bed and lie and the moment I lie
all comes out and I rushed to the toilet.
I could not smell wine for 6 months.
Even today if I drink more than
2 glasses of wine I am out.
I cannot tolerate. But this was a
very interesting experience for me.
I think that with such a difficult
subject we have to say some stories.
- If I understood well. Hahnemann made a
confusion, he defines in paragraph 113
and in 63 in a way the primary and secondary
action and completely different way
he speaks and using the
same words in 112.
- This is actually
confusing the whole issue.
- We should take into consideration
that we are talking about provings.
- He mixes the provings he had done with the
description of toxic effects from the people
who have died and he says this is a secondary
action don't take it into consideration.
What you have to take into consideration
are symptoms from small doses
and some primary symptoms that were happening
in these people who died with poisoning,
they must have started with some
symptoms that are useful for us.
The symptoms which are useful for
us eventually were toxic symptoms
that have been described in cases that have
been poisoned by poisonous substances.
Like the Rhus tox, Nux vomica, Ignatia... most
probably these drugs containing strychnine.
They were used for poisoning.
I would like you to continue.
- In paragraph 105, he
calls it pharmacology.
He says we have to find out what happens
with the healing with our remedies...
We have in Germany, a doctor who has a
book that writes about the toxicology
and happened to people in older times with
Arsenicum and then he talks about the provings.
- So he combines the poisoning
with the proving symptoms
and completes the picture of the drug.
That is correct.
But in the way that these paragraphs
are written, confusion is caused.
Unless you really understand the spirit
of it, and not the letter of that.
Then it comes to mind.
If I give you 5 words, you look at
them ,do they have any meaning? No.
Now you connect these words with some
others and the 5 words make a meaning.
But the meaning of this
phrase is difficult.
Not everybody will
understand what it means.
20 people first read the words and they
mean nothing, then they are connected
and mean something
for everybody.
The real meaning of the phrase
was only understood only by few.
By whom was the meaning understood? By those who
had it already in their spirit, in their mind.
I will tell you a word, freedom.
Tell me, what it means for you.
For each one it has a meaning. I want
to be free to do whatever I like.
I want not to have my mother
or father say anything...
Each one understands the word
freedom in a different way.
Which is the real freedom? I
don't want dictatorships.
Is this the meaning of
freedom in its real sense?
Can anybody take away my freedom
because he is a dictator?
Yes they can, because if I speak
against them they will put me in jail.
That is one meaning.
If you think more about it
more, what is to be free?
These are the considerations that made
me write the definition of health
as freedom from pain,
passion, egoism ...
if you meditate upon these meanings you will
find out that my understanding of freedom
is different than from the
understanding of a freedom fighter.
Do they understand freedom
the way I do? No.
Who is right? Who has real freedom?
I'll give some examples.
You have an affair with a woman,
you are very attached to her,
your whole life depends on that woman, you
want her to be happy and always with you.
Do you believe that such
a person is free? No.
He depends entirely on what
the other person will say.
Even the least comment can make the
other person totally desperate
because the person you love said you are
this or that is enough to destroy you.
Therefore you depend your life,
happiness on that person.
The moment you are with the person you are
very happy as long as you are together.
When will you become free? When
you still love this person
but are not attached to it to that degree.
You can be free at the same time.
You have love for this person,
these are good feeling.
The moment that you are
attached that is a passion.
I want this woman
nobody will touch her.
Like all the Lachesis cases like
to keep their passion/relation,
not to be touched by
the other gender.
The moment Lachesis sees the husband
greeting a woman... looks at the hands
how much they touch... that is attachment.
Then you are not free.
If you love but at the same time you
can say she is free. She can go.
Then there is love and freedom.
The greatest freedom of all of course, nobody
has, is be free of the ego and the selfishness.
We can forget that. No one
can be free of the ego.
Some people have given up their ego
quite a lot but entirely? Forget it.
There is nobody.
Do not aspire to be free of egotism because
the moment you are totally free of egotism
you will be connected to the next world and you
will live in paradise but not in this world.
You will be in the next
world, it will be very nice.
So all spiritual attainments drive towards
the elimination of this ego centered sense.
That is the spiritual
driving of all persons.