I never thought that this job would
be as difficult as it appears to be,
to tell you the truth.
The difficulty is that I
perceive certain ideas
which I have to transmit and these
ideas which I have in my mind
have to comply with
what is written.
There are in some
instances where I can see
that Hahnemann either was a bit
uncertain or he was discussing things
according to his time and taking
into his mind his experiences.
All these have to be put together
in order to be transferred to you
and simplify the issues so it can
become easy for you to understand.
This is not so easy.
114. "With the exception of
these narcotic substances,
in experiments with moderate doses of
medicine on healthy bodies, we observe..."
Here is a point where you
have to be very careful.
"...we observe only their
primary action".
He says with the exception of
these narcotic substances,
in experiments what will do in proving
with moderate doses on healthy individuals
we observe only their
primary action.
This "only" means what? First of all it means
that this is what we are interested in.
We are interested only in this observation,
of what changes the moderate doses
have brought about on
healthy individuals.
By saying "with the exception of these narcotics"
means that moderate doses in narcotics
is different with moderate doses with all
other medicines. What is the difference?
Here he has actually made a mistake
which I have to point out.
He says that narcotics take out
the sensibility on the first part
and people do not
feel any bad symptoms
because it takes out the sensation and
the sensibility, the irritability.
Therefore in this case we
take the symptoms after,
when the vital force reacts back after the
suppression from the first dose of narcotics.
That is why he says
it is different.
In narcotics we take into consideration the
symptoms which come as a secondary action
or as an after effect action.
This is wrong. How do
we know it is wrong?
Because the vital force reacts
from the very beginning.
It doesn't matter that it
produces no aggressive symptoms.
It produces symptoms
which are pleasant.
The vital force still produces symptoms
and we know that these symptoms
that are produced by narcotics (opium)
are very useful for us in prescribing.
So the first part, where he says don't take
note of the repercussion of the vital,
this sedation, this feeling good of
with the opium, it is the main symptom,
the characteristic on
which we prescribe Opium.
We prescribe Opium in a case where there
is a terrible state and he says "I'm ok".
You see the patient there and say it is not
possible that he will be feeling good.
How do you feel? Nice, good!
It's impressive.
So you can prescribe opium on
that and have fantastic results.
Even in cases who are
progressed in pathology.
One of the main symptoms of Opium comes
from the first part of the proving.
When Opium was given and the
person felt everything is ok.
He did not have to make this distinction
and create a doubt in our minds
of what he wants to say.
The proving of the Opium is
first of all this feeling good
which is not justified
by the pathology.
The pathology is such that you don't
expect that he will say he feels good.
Don't prescribe Opium in every case
when the patient says "I feel good"!
But when you don't expect to say I feel good
then you say this may be a case of Opium.
I think we spoke about
paragraph 115 when he says
sometimes the same remedy has for a
period of time a set of symptoms
and then later on there is a repercussion
and the symptoms go to the opposite side.
The remedy can produce some
symptoms and then by reaction
because the substance is stimulating
he may get the opposite symptoms
and such symptoms are not called
secondary but alternating.
I would like you to tell me for paragraph
116... This is a very simple paragraph.
I would like you to tell me
if somebody understands it.
"Some symptoms are produced by the medicines
more frequently - that is to say,
in many individuals, others
more rarely or in few persons,
some only in very few
healthy bodies."
Who wants to comment on this?
- I think it depends on the
sensitivity of the provers.
The common symptoms will be
seen in most of the provers.
The more rare and peculiar will only
develop in very sensitive provers.
- It doesn't say that. It says something
else but what you say is correct.
But it is not said here
in this paragraph.
Some symptoms produced by the medicines
are more frequently manifesting.
- If you prove in low potency...-
It's not a matter of potency.
- Those symptoms who come more often
are more important for the medicine
that we give degrees 1-4 in the
repertory for every rubric.
One remedy is in the 1st degree which
means it has been seen very seldom
and one remedy in the 3rd degree
which means it has been seen
many times in the proving.
- Yes. This is the idea.
I'll give an example.
When you do a proving some symptoms of
the drug will appear in many cases.
Which are these symptoms? Some symptoms
which are more characteristic of the drug.
For instance if you prove
Belladonna out of the provers
a lot of them will get a
hot face with cold feet.
This is characteristic of the drug.
It will appear in many provers.
But other symptoms of that drug will
appear only in very few individuals.
Therefore if a remedy brings
many times a symptom,
we put it on the 3rd degree in the
repertory and then we have 2nd degree.
In the 1st degree
we have symptoms
who have been manifested
in 1-2 out of 100 people.
They are valid but we don't pay
so much attention to them.
The keynote of the drug will manifest to as
many provers as possible or to many provers.
If you prove Natrum muriaticum a headache
which comes around 10 a.m. to 3 p.m.,
which is characteristic, will
appear in quite a lot individuals.
Or the increase in the desire for salt
will come to quite a few individuals.
But some unimportant symptoms, a
pain in the left knee during sleep,
maybe it is there,
we will record it,
but very few individual brought
it out in the proving. Very good.
Now he will try to explain why this
happens in the next paragraph.
"To the latter category belong
the so-called idiosyncrasies,
by which are meant peculiar corporeal
constitutions which, although otherwise healthy,
possess a disposition to be brought into a
more or less morbid state by certain things
which seem to produce no impression and
no change in many other individuals."
He says there are some constitutions which
are affected very much by certain substances
and these certain substances appear
to have no effect on all others.
He drives the student
slowly to deeper ideas.
In this footnote he says "Some few persons
are apt to faint from the smell of roses
and to fall into many other morbid,
and sometimes dangerous states
from partaking of mussels, crabs
or the roe of the barbell"
I don't know what it is.
The caviar. Not the expensive one.
Eggs of the fish.
Those who are not vegetarians
they may have tasted barbouni.
It's very tasty food. He
says certain individuals
are affected very much by
certain things like a perfume.
They may even faint by a perfume. This
perfume will not affect everybody
but there is one person among us who
will faint if there is such a perfume.
He wants to say with this
that there are idiosyncrasies
that in these people there
is such a predisposition
for such reaction towards
a minute stimulation.
"But this inability to make an impression
on every one is only apparent".
What he means? Who will tell me?
Now you're stuck?
- Does he mean this is a matter of quantity
that if someone takes a minute dose
it will not be apparent but if he
takes a bigger dose then eventually
he will develop the symptoms?
- He had said in paragraph 35
or 36 that medicinal substances
have an effect upon the human
organism without exception.
In all individuals. All individuals
can be affected by a substance
as long as the dose is large enough.
He reminds this now here.
He says ok a person can faint, can
have some reaction from barbouni
and from the perfume because he is
sensitive. He may even die with penicillin.
But do not think that all others are not
affected. They can also be affected.
He will give the conditions under
which everyone can be affected.
"For as two things are required
for the production of these
as well as all other morbid
alterations in the health of man".
There are 2 conditions
which are needed
in order to produce an alteration
to the state of health, a proving.
"to wit., the inherent power
of the influencing substance".
That means if the power of the substance
which is influencing the organism is strong,
that is the one condition
and the second condition is "the
capability of the vital force
that animates the organism
to be influenced by it".
The expression here
is wrong again.
What should be the correct
expression in order to understand?
"and the capability of the vital
force [...] to be influenced"
It's not the capacity
of the vital force.
It is the predisposition of the organism
to be influenced by such substance.
Then it makes it clear.
But he says the capacity of the vital force
to be influenced it sidetracks the mind.
Does not give
directly the meaning.
The meaning is 2 conditions; one,
strong influence in conjunction
in relation to an organism who has a
predisposition to be affected by this substance.
He says further that the derangements of
the health depend on these 2 factors;
the predisposition and also the
power of the influencing factor.
"in which must lie the power of making the
same impressions on all human bodies,
yet in such a manner that but a small
number of healthy constitutions
have a tendency to
allow themselves
to be brought into such an obvious
morbid condition by them"
He has said in the beginning that every
substance will affect every human being.
Here he brings another factor.
Which are the factors?
First of all you have to have a powerful
agent and the second is the predisposition.
That means the vital force accepting
being influenced by this substance.
- Couldn't it be that he was speaking as
well about the capacity of the vital force
to move it all?
When we take weak patients, their vital
force is not so much affected anymore...
Know what I mean?- No.
- The vital force of the different
individuals is differently strong...
I was thinking that he was speaking
about that the vital force
of the different
individuals was different...
- The vital force being different
means...- Some weaker and some stronger.
- But the vital force
itself is an energy.
So you cannot say the
vital force is strong.
The organism is strong which
has a strong vital force.
The weak organism has a weak vital force.
You have to understand it in this way.
Now you tell me your question.
- In my mind he's talking
as well about some stages
where the vital force is not reacting anymore.
Even though he might be predisposed before.
- Give me some example of what you mean.
Are you reading German or English?
- Now I'm having the
English version as well.
- I go back. The idea is that we have
to be practical in order to understand
otherwise if you are caught in
the long sentences of Hahnemann
and the interjections between sentences
of another idea, then you are lost.
You have to be simple. And
the simplest is this.
He says do you think because not
everybody faints from the smell of roses
that the smell of roses
cannot effect anybody? No.
You give it to a big amount and then you
will see everybody will be affected.
He is driving to the same original
idea that he wants to apply
but now he makes
it more specific.
He says it is not only the strength of the
influence but also the predisposition
which manifests through
the vital force.
He has brought in the idea
that everyone is influenced
but still there are certain individuals
that are influenced more than others.
He has to explain this and I think he
will explain it later on even better.
"That these agents do
actually make this impression
on every healthy body
is shown by this"
He makes a jump here which is
really difficult to comprehend.
Does anybody understand this?
"...that when employed as remedies they
render effectual homoeopathic service
to all sick persons for morbid symptoms
similar to those they seem to be only capable
of producing in so-called idiosyncratic
individuals." Has anybody understood?
- It turns the
argumentation around.
Now he takes not the proving but the
application with the diseased person
who is in resonance with this special
substance because it produces the symptoms...
- His logic is quite difficult.
He says I will prove to you that all
substances can affect all organisms.
Then he says you have to
have a predisposition
and an equally strong
influence in order to be.
Now he wants to say all substances
can affect all individuals.
How do you prove that?
By the fact that when you give the correct
remedy the person is getting better.
Every time you give the remedy the person
gets better therefore the substance
can affect every individual
under all circumstances.
It is very difficult logic which only
Hahnemann can perceive and have.
- I have been confused a little
bit with the 2 terms that we use;
the context in
predisposition to disease
for instance predisposition
to eczema, epilepsy etc.
and the use of the term predisposition
to be affected by a certain stimulus.
- A predisposition can be a sensitivity of
an organism towards a certain stimulus.
You don't need more explanation.
There are 2 things.
The stimulus must be strong
enough and the sensitivity
should tally with this stimulus.
He says that but the
student if he is studious,
and has understood so
far what he has said,
he could say dear sir you have said
before that medicinal substances
affect everyone under
all conditions.
How you tell us now that you need a
sensitivity in order to be affected?
This is a contradiction in what
he had said in paragraph 35.
There he had said that
the dose must be large.
He has put this condition
which is quite strong.
Here he says even the smell of
a rose can make somebody faint
but this smell of rose
cannot affect everybody.
But this is only apparent,
it actually can.
What are the conditions?
2 conditions.
First, the stress must be strong and
the predisposition must be there.
He calls it vital
force sensitivity.
Which is the most innocent food?
The most innocent food is carrots.
If you eat carrots is the
least stimulating substance.
But he has said in paragraph 35 even
if you eat carrots in large doses
you are going to have
poisoning, symptoms developing.
One organism which is sensitive
will need 5 kg of carrots
before he has a reaction.
Another who is not sensitive,
he will need 20 kg of carrots.
You squeeze carrots and drink
and you will eventually
have a symptomatology
coming from the carrots
which are supposed to be the most
innocent food of all, as he himself says.
So by the strength of the influencing you can
overcome the resistance of the organism.
Even if he does not have a predisposition.
I am not sensitive to carrots at all.
If I am sensitive to carrots I eat a
carrot and my eyes are blown, my ears...
because I am sensitive to carrots.
But if I am not...
There are organisms who are
going to have a reaction
if they drink 4 glasses
of carrot juice.
For some others it will be 20 glasses
of carrot juice before they start...
So he wants to say now that all
remedies affect all organisms.
In his mind comes the
idea from his experience
that when he was giving the similar
remedy that means a remedy
to which the organism is
sensitive, there is always a cure.
He connects the stimulating factor with
the predisposition to show you that
since this phenomenon is
taking place every time,
therefore the influence of a stimulating factor
is always there for all cases.
I cannot explain more. Is it clear?
You tell me for whom is it clear?
- Every stimulus is effective
to every individual
if the individual produces the
appropriate symptoms, not in any case...
- No. The symptoms that an
individual produces are not the same
as the symptoms another
individual produces.
So we need 100
individuals to prove,
take the different symptoms
from all these 100 people,
put them all together
and form the M.M.
But if the substance is strong it will give
out in many provers the same symptoms.
So many provers will have common symptoms
but each will have different symptoms.
If you take the 20 symptoms of each one,
some will be common, what will be common?
What is strong element
in the substance.
If you collect all the symptoms
then you will have an idea
of the totality of the remedy.
Of what the remedy can do.
118. "Every medicine exhibits
peculiar actions on the human frame,
which are not produced in exactly the same
manner by any other medicinal substance
of a different kind."
That means that each remedy... The
problem they left me without tea!
That's why I have dryness of the mouth.
Talking too much!
Here he says something
very interesting.
He says every medicinal substance will
create different symptoms than the others.
No 2 substances will produce
exactly the same symptoms.
But in the repertories we know that a
symptom can be produced by 100 remedies...
When it comes to the peculiarity of a
substance having produced a singular symptom
which is belonging only to this substance,
that symptom becomes very important.
Opium produces symptom that when
somebody is in a terrible state
he can say I feel good.
Another remedy which has a similar
symptoms during the fever
when there are no symptoms and
the child feels perfectly well
but he has fever 40 C, then the
remedy is Ferrum phosphoricum.
High fever without symptoms, the child
is jumping around, there is no problem,
you don't give Opium, you give Ferrum
phosphoricum because it's a different context.
So he says no 2 remedies have
absolutely the same symptoms.
Some remedies share symptoms.
Headache on the right or the left
temple extending to the back.
You look the repertory.
Headache over the left eye
which are the remedies?
I don't remember,
Bryonia, Spigelia etc.
But if the pain extends to the left occipital
protuberance then it becomes Bryonia.
Medicines share common symptoms but when
it comes to very minute examination
of the symptoms you will find
in every remedy peculiarities
that do not exist
in other remedies.
In my effort giving the M.M. what
I was trying was to give you
the totality of a remedy
that has a personality.
This personality if different
than that personality
and try to recognize
these personalities.
By personalities I
mean disease states.
119. "As certainly as every species of
plant differs in its external form,
mode of life and growth, in its taste and smell
from every other species and genus of plant,
as certainly as every mineral and
salt differs from all others,
in its external as well as its internal
physical and chemical properties
so certainly do they all differ
and diverge among themselves
in their pathogenetic effects."
In the same way the plants are
different in color, in odor,
in appearance in the same way they are
differing when they are producing effects
in a healthy organism. Simple.
He repeats himself quite a lot.
"Each of these substances produces
alterations in the health of human beings
in a peculiar, different,
yet determinate manner,
so as to preclude the possibility
of confounding one with another".
If you study properly, he says, the
pathogenetic effect of each remedy
you will find out that they have peculiar,
different and yet determined symptoms.
Symptoms which are differing from one
another so you may not confuse them.
Paragraph 120. "Therefore medicines,
on which depend man's life and death,
disease and health, must be thoroughly and
most carefully distinguished from one another,
and for this purpose tested by careful,
pure experiments on the healthy body
for the purpose of ascertaining
their powers and real effects,
in order to obtain an accurate knowledge of
them, and to enable us to avoid any mistake
in their employment in diseases, for it
is only by correct selection of them
that the greatest of all earthly
blessings" There is no bigger blessing
than finding the correct remedy.
That is what he says.
On earth this is the greatest blessing for
a human being to have found the remedy
which he needs.
"...the health of the body and of the mind,
can be rapidly and permanently restored."
As long as you have found
the correct remedy.
If you really learn to
handle these energies,
what a blessing it will be for yourself
first and for the other people
who receive this possibility
to give them back health.
There is no bigger blessing on earth
and yet you see this has been...
You have these direction, you
are given these possibilities
you instead of doing that
you say should I sit down
and try to find the correct remedy?
Forget it.
So what can I do? More or less this condition
is covered by 3,4,5,6,7,8,10 remedies.
Take all of them and maybe one will
be correct and restore your health.
The problem is you
don't restore health.
Who started doing that? The
pharmaceutical industry.
They said we cannot sell one dose
because we will close down our factory.
If we follow your ideas Mr.
George we'll close our factories
and therefore we have to produce
drugs massively and specialties.
We put 10 drugs in a bottle and
we say this is for bronchitis.
This is for pneumonia, PMS...
There are people who do not
have either the possibility
or the mind or the energy or the enthusiasm
to sit down and with such meticulous,
like Hahnemann was doing proving
very carefully, and produce proving,
recognize this proving on the
pathology of the case and apply it
and then see the fantastic effect.
Sometime it is unbelievable.
One such impressive case
we saw three weeks ago
when the lady came flooding with blood
for 2 months. She had blood transfusion.
She was taking heavy medications,
hormones, the blood would not stop.
I gave one dose and before they reached
their countries the hemorrhage had stopped.
You expect when there is
such a big hemorrhage
that the arteries somewhere
have been opened quite a lot.
How could they close just like that
with a remedy? It looks like a miracle.
But you can imagine the
gratitude of these people.
They come back and say you
are god you saved me.
And if you believe that you are god forget
finding the remedy in the next case!
For this I can confirm it! The moment you
believe you are becoming the greatest
you will not be able to find the remedy
in the next case. It's very strange.
I don't know why it
happens but it happens!
Drinking like this what is the remedy?
Arsenicum. My dressing is like Arsenicum's?
My wife says put this out, put
something else, I am too tired,
no you have to take it out and put
this I am telling you, ok I'll put.
Every time I choose something to
put myself, every time I am wrong
because it is the
opposite of Arsenicum.
Arsenicum has a sense of well dressing
and proper colors fitting, cleanliness,
everything around has to be clean.
Me... Opposite. Philosopher...
Then what is my remedy? I know my remedy, I
know my fate I will never find my remedy!
You don't believe but it is true. I have
never found the deeper remedy which I need.
Of course I find the remedy
when I have an acute.
But as a child I had scabies and by
that time they put a yellow substance
that was smelling very badly, it was Sulphur
most probably with some other mixtures.
I'm talking before WWII, not WWI! I never
got it back. That means forget it...
That's why always people say, how is
your health? There are people like her!
I say this joke and immediately she thinks
he will be gone before the next seminar!
Don't worry. It's ok.
He has programmed, the time is exact,
when it arrives, nobody can do anything.
I remember when I was in India
and one of the school teachers,
heard that I was interested in
philosophy and spiritual people,
he told me of a story of a man, he was a
guru, he was attended by this doctor,
he says I go one day, his heart
was in a terrible condition,
so I have told him not to move
around etc, then I go one day
and saw him sitting in position like the yogis,
he got up and he was going somewhere else
and I shouted to him what are you doing?
You should not move you should stay there!
He then said to me, well you doctor
you have done your job quite good,
you kept me until now, let me do my job now.
So I followed him to where he was going.
He went to another spot, sat down in
the same position and left his body.
He knew that this was the time. He said
you did your job well till that time.
You kept my body with your remedies until
that moment. Let me do my job now.
I know what I am doing.
Don't worry.
He went to the spot, there was a
special spot he wanted to be.
Indians believe that if the die
in Ganges is very auspicious.
I will go to paradise which is not exactly
so but you don't go to the Ganges
and forget all you have done in your life.
No, but they believe it.
They go to a specific place. So he went
to a specific place, sat down and left.
These phenomena are usual. All these
people have heard several such cases.
So it is programmed. No matter I take my
remedies, keep my body as much as I can,
when the time comes bye bye. I
hope I will be happy before I go.
I will be happy only with one condition. Do
you know what it is? I will not tell you now.
119.
120.
121. "In proving medicines to ascertain
their effects on the healthy body,
it must be borne in mind that the strong,
heroic substances, as they are termed,
are liable even in small doses to produce
changes in the health even of robust persons."
He goes into more details
explaining what he had said before.
He said that strong substances
he calls them heroic,
a heroic substance is a substance that has
definitely an effect in all human organisms.
Which are the substances that have an effect in
all human organisms even in small quantities?
The poisons. All the poisons have an
influence upon the human organism.
Even if you give a small quantity it
is going to produce a lot of symptoms
even to the most robust people. "Those of milder
power must be given for these experiments
in more considerable quantities"
So as you need to prove substances
that are not so heroic,
so powerful you have to consider the
quantity that you are going to give.
So when the substance is not so
strong in relation to the human body
you must increase the dose.
In order to prove substances
which are very weak,
which have not so much effect upon the human
organism you have to find individuals
who will be "free from disease, and who
are delicate, irritable and sensitive."
In order to prove weak substances you
have to find sensitive individuals.
- When you say that the provings
can only be done on people
who are sensitive to that
particular remedy you actually mean
this is because they are given small doses?
Because you never mentioned that part.
- Yes. If the people do not take large
enough dose they cannot prove the remedies.
- I don't think you ever said that.
You always said that...
- Wait a moment. Later on he will say that
you can do provings with high potency.
Let's say beyond the Avogadro
number, without substance.
But you have to find specific individuals.
This is the original idea.
You have weak substances, find
individuals who are healthy
but at the same time they are delicate.
They are easily reacting.
Later on he will say you
have to find individuals
who are sensitive towards
that particular substance
in order to prove remedies
with high potencies.
The whole idea of proving with high
potencies is so misused by homeopaths.
They have no idea what they are doing.
They just come together and play around,
take a dose of 30CH or 200CH, talking
between them, then they collect symptoms...
It's nonsense. There is
preparation that has to be done.
There is protocol you have to follow.
He will give the protocol.
122. "In these experiments - on which depends
the exactitude of the whole medical art,
and the weal of all future
generations of mankind -
no other medicines should be employed
except such as are perfectly well known,
and of whose purity, genuineness and
energy we are thoroughly assured."
We had investigated properly, we are sure about
their properties, then we can apply them.
123. "Each of these
medicines must be taken.."
Listen to the precise
instructions he give.
"...must be taken in a perfectly simple, unadulterated form; the indigenous plants"
The plants of Alonissos... "...in the form of freshly
expressed juice, mixed with a little alcohol
to prevent it spoiling; exotic vegetable
substances, however, in the form of powder,
or tincture prepared with alcohol
when they were in the fresh state".
The exotic fruits you dry them, you crash
them and then with alcohol you prepare them
"and afterwards mingled with a certain
proportion of water; salts and gums,
however, should be dissolved in
water just before being taken.
If the plant can only be procured in its dry
state, and if its powers are naturally weak,
in that case there may be used for
the experiment an infusion of it,
made by cutting the herb into small
pieces and pouring boiling water on it,
so as to extract its
medicinal parts..."
You see how precise information he gives.
Everybody understands.
"...immediately after its preparation it
must be swallowed while still warm"
The weak plants. You put
them in boiling water
to extract the medicinal qualities
and drink it warm still.
"...as all expressed vegetable juices
and all aqueous infusions of herbs,
without the addition of spirit, pass rapidly
into fermentation and decomposition..."
So you have to maintain them
with a little bit of alcohol.
"...whereby all their medicinal
properties are lost."
124 will be the last paragraph.
"For these experiments every medicinal
substance must be employed quite alone
and perfectly pure, without the
admixture of any foreign substance,
and without taking anything else of
a medicinal nature the same day,
nor yet on the subsequent days,
nor during all the time we wish to
observe the effects of the medicine".
So you have to take the substance very
pure without any mixture of anything else
and you have to take
only that substance
and never take another medicinal substance
during the whole time the experiment lasts.
Dmitri these are instruction
you should follow.
You will see how difficult it is to
make a real homeopathic proving.
All these fanfare of
doing new provings...
In order to make one proving
you need one year of your life
and here they produce
proving after proving.
They write books.
And people believe.
He says I gave this remedy and the
person was cured. It was not cured!
It was a placebo
effect at the best!
The worst is that the person has
left the doctor and says goodbye.
In England the moment there was a
little bit of an attack by the press
half of homeopaths lost all their jobs
because their clientele left them
as they heard that perhaps
these people are bluffing you,
not giving you anything but sugar. They
try to do here in Greece, it didn't work.
They also try to do it in India also.
They attack. It didn't work.
Because in India there is a
tradition, they have 186 colleges...
They are medical doctors,
six years of studies.
By the time I was there the
homeopathic college was 3 years.
It was easy to pass. That's
why I have a diploma...!
I went to many colleges I never cared for
a diploma. The diploma means nothing.
The diploma must be here. If the diploma
is inside the brain then you cure...
If you have a paper and
here is empty... I am joking.
These things are really difficult. I appreciate
all this patience attending this turmoil.
Every person that I ever encounter in my life
from the beginning, especially the Germans,
have you read the Organon? No, I
try to read it, but I could not.
From time to time I meet somebody
who says yes, I have read it.
Very seldom to go through completely. To
understand completely is another story.
That's why I am thankful to you
because I had announced 30 years ago
I would write comments
on the Organon
but I would never have done it unless
I have thought maybe some people
will be interested,
so they will come,
so I will enjoy talking with them and
then I can do it. Otherwise forget it.
It's too dreary to sit down and write.
So you are participating in a project
which I always had in my mind and God
said ok, I'll bring the situation.