I searched for statistics in epilepsy.
I wanted to show you the statistics.
It will be very interesting
to see exactly what happens.
We have a comparison of our
successes and failures...
In the meantime we are
left with some questions.
-I have a question about the repetition
of medicines in allopathic drug dependent cases,
when for example we treat someone
with epilepsy, hypertension and we start
with medicine which we think it's the best and
though we try repeating it, this medicine
is not correct or it is but we
cannot know in the beginning.
But from the point of the start of this
medicine there is aggravation... in which point
we have to stop the repeating
until there is aggravation...
If there is an aggravation after starting
the homeopathic remedy. What do you mean?
An aggravation in epilepsy means... In epilepsy
it's not easy to say whether there is
an aggravation because you gave the remedy,
unless the person under drugs never
has an attack and then he takes it
and after 2 days there is an attack.
But for the last 5 years he did not
have any attack due to the remedy...
That you can say is an aggravation.
But it's not.
-And in such case we
have to continue...
-If this happens, it means that the
remedy overcame the suppression due
to the allopathic drugs and brought
out a reaction of the organism.
That shows a good reaction then you have
to reduce rather the allopathic drug
and continue to give once the epileptic
fit is over. You want to ask something?
-If we have such cases, not epilepsy, for
instance asthmatic cases on cortisone
and we give the medicine and after this
medicine there is an initial aggravation
can we continue with repeating the
medicine during the aggravation period or
is it better to stop
the medicine and wait?
-If the asthma is aggravated, that
means you have to stop immediately.
That's different. If due to the cortisone
he is taking, there is no aggravation,
no crisis of asthma and you give a remedy
and there is an asthmatic condition,
an aggravation, you stop. But
that means the remedy is correct.
The wrong remedy
will do nothing.
Neither in the epilepsy case,
nor in the asthma case.
The wrong remedy
will do nothing.
It has not the power to mobilize the defense
mechanism, unless it's very similar
to the condition. Then it can mobilize
and manifest the aggravation.
Many times people, even teachers, they
say we have never seen an aggravation.
My question is have they ever seen a cure?
It's doubtful.
The moment that there is an aggravation,
there is a possibility for a cure.
But not in all cases we have aggravation.
It's not possible.
Because not every case is curable. But
if there is aggravation, most probably
there is a cure. Of course sometimes
there is an aggravation without cure.
But this is under certain conditions, not
in the conditions you are talking about.
Ok, I want to show you some facts about
epilepsy. Let me see if you can read.
Epilepsy affects over 3 million American
of all ages - more than M.S., C.P., M.D.
and Parkinson's disease combined.
In America epilepsy is as common
as breast cancer and
takes as many lives.
Because he had a bad conscience
because one of the patients died.
Almost 500 new cases of epilepsy are
diagnosed every day in the U.S.
Epilepsy affects 50.000.000
people worldwide.
One in 100 people will develop epilepsy.
One in 100 of the population of the earth
will develop epilepsy.
1 in 10 people will suffer a
seizure in their lifetime.
This year another 200.000 will be
diagnosed with epilepsy in the U.S.
Each year over 125.000 to 150.000
are newly diagnosed with epilepsy.
30% of those diagnosed are children.
Epilepsy can develop at any age
and can be a result of genetics, stroke,
head injury and many other factors,
of course a side effect
of a brain tumor.
A brain tumor can many times cause
epilepsy. For many soldiers suffering
traumatic brain injury on the battlefield,
epilepsy will be a long term consequence.
In 2/3 of patients diagnosed with
epilepsy the cause is unknown.
That's very interesting. As if we
know the workings of the diseases.
The multiplicity of electrochemical
reaction within the body is so complex
that, how can we know. In over 30
percent of patients, seizures cannot be
controlled with treatment.
These are the patients that we
receive, they will come to us.
I have taken one drug, a second drug, a
third drug and still I can't control,
so could you please help. Such cases
are the ones that come to us.
Uncontrolled seizures may lead
to brain damage and death.
Up to 50.000 Americans die each year
from seizures and related causes.
The mortality rate among people with
epilepsy is 2 to 3 times higher than
the general population.
Risk of sudden death among those
with epilepsy is 24 times greater.
Epilepsy results in an estimated annual cost
of 15.5 billion dollars in medical costs
and lost or reduced
earnings and production.
Historically epilepsy research
has been under funded.
Each year NIH spends 30 billion dollars of
medical research ,30 billion is not enough
to find the cause of epilepsy.
If it was 50 billion, they would find
it and epilepsy would disappear.
These are unbelievable facts.
Just half or 1 percent is spent
on epilepsy. I was too excited.
The federal government spends much
less on epilepsy research compared
to other diseases, many of which affect
fewer people. That is quite interesting.
The overall picture of epilepsy is interesting
but if we want to see the history
of epilepsy, maybe we will see that even
in very old times the epileptics were
quite substantial number. There are
reasons for multiplying these cases
but I believe that this is a disease
...considered as the divine disease
or something like that.
You know Dostoyevsky, one of the greatest
writers, he was suffering from epilepsy
and they say a lot of epileptics before
the real convulsion starts, they perceive
a state of a divine awareness.
Which for this reason I was thinking
that epilepsy is connected somewhat
with the effort of humans
to approach the divine.
I have too progressive ideas but ... in the
effort of people to be aware of the divine
there is an electric charge which is
generated, which ends up into convulsions and
before the convulsions a
sense of divine awareness.
I don't know what more to say because I
didn't have so far an epileptic fit so ...
if I continue I don't know
what is going to happen.
I spoke about 94? No?
"While inquiring into the state of chronic
disease, the particular circumstances
of the patient with regard to his ordinary
occupations, his usual mode of living
and diet, his domestic situation and
so forth, must be well considered
and scrutinized" you have to examine
why this man/woman has these problems,
does anything happen that is abnormal?
Do you eat badly food?
Are you accustomed in bad habits? "to
ascertain what there is in them that
may tend to produce or to maintain
disease" he says you have to find out
" in order that by their removal
the recovery may be promoted".
You have to examine whether there
are some things he is doing
or he has circumstances around him which promote
and aggravates his situation.
So you have to advise
him not to do that.
"In chronic diseases of females it is
especially necessary to pay attention
to pregnancy" if somebody is pregnant
and she has nausea it is because
she is pregnant and don't
detach it from pregnancy...
"sterility, sexual
desire, accouchements"
Accouchements is talking about
sexual desire in a nice way.
Let's be practical, I started with one word
I said I don't know the word but finally
the meaning is, the sexual desire by
itself cannot be a kind of symptomatology.
What you do with sexual desire can
be a cause for symptomatology.
If you have to masturbate 3 times,
a day it is a kind of impediment.
And indulging in sexual desire can cause
symptoms. Then the doctor has to advise
the person, please stop it, don't
do it so frequently at least.
That is the practical thing of this,
otherwise there is no meaning.
Miscarriage, carrying baby ... I saw
by chance in Discovery a film,
before I go to sleep, I put science Discovery,
because the News in Greek are useless,
a women went with her husband in a
boat and found themselves in a storm,
they found themselves in a place to get
out of the storm, and suddenly the woman
started having tremendous pains in the
uterus, in the lower abdomen and suddenly
within the storm the woman started having
blood running out of her uterus and
she was screaming.
The husband was sleeping so heavily that
she could not wake him up by crying.
She was on the deck and he was sleeping
down. She was screaming ,something
is coming out the uterus... the husband
wakes up finally and sees something comes
out, an inner organ of the woman is
coming out. They called the ambulance.
The ambulance comes with a gynecologist
and support, they move her.
She tries to go to the bed and you
see the gynecologist and the midwife
were like this!!! There was a baby coming
out. She did not know she was pregnant.
I couldn't believe the story. In Discovery
they don't tell nonsense, they tell
very interesting stories but the woman did
not know that she was pregnant actually.
Otherwise she could imagine... something is
coming out, an inner organ is coming out.
I told you about a woman who had come
and I asked her how old are you?
She said allow me not to tell you, I said Ok,
I looked at her and I wrote in my notes 27.
Then she tells me the symptoms
and something is wrong.
I give the remedy, she comes the next time.
She says you asked me how old I am
so I told you a lie.
I said how old are you and she said 45.
She was on menopause.
Hahnemann being so detailed with everything,
he relates all the possibilities here
that you can go through.
"In chronic disease the investigation of
the signs of disease above mentioned,
and of all others, must be pursued as
carefully and circumstantially as possible,
and the most minute peculiarities must
be attended to, partly because in these
diseases they are the most characteristic
and least resemble those of acute diseases.
And if a cure is to be affected,
they cannot be too accurately noted;
partly because the patients become so used
to their long sufferings that they pay
little or no heed to the
lesser accessory symptoms"
We spoke about acute diseases before
and we said that in acute diseases
you do not need to take a full case
because the changes are so obvious that
the patient will give them
spontaneously to you.
But he says in chronic diseases you
have to be much more careful because
the patient except of his main pathological
condition, he may not pay attention
to the little minute details that are so
important for prescribing a homeopathic remedy.
"...partly because the patients become
so used to their long sufferings that
they pay little or no heed to the lesser
accessory symptoms, which are often very
pregnant with meaning (characteristic) [...]
and regard them almost as a necessary
part of their condition".
That means they have been used so
many years to be having a symptom
that they do not consider it anymore as
a symptom. For instance a woman where
she may have interrupted menses, all her
life she has 2 days, one day stops and
she is used to that. She comes now for chronic
headaches, she will not tell you that
I have an interruption of 1 day in my
menses, because she is used to that.
Another man has a nose that if he takes
onions, it will be terrible for him.
So he gives them up and for
20 years he never ate onions.
He will not come and tell you I don't eat
onions unless you ask him and that's why
he says be careful now on chronic conditions
because the symptoms which are going
to be given to you spontaneously, are
not going to be the symptoms we are
interested in.
We are interested in little details that
may be the person has been used to them
and consider as part of his
own self, not of his disease.
"...and regard them almost as a necessary
part of their condition, almost as health"
If I take this food, I will be having
heartburns so I never take it.
"...the real feeling of which they have
well-night forgotten in the sometimes fifteen
or twenty years of suffering" after 20 years
he never uses onion, he has forgotten
about it.
"and they can scarcely bring themselves
to believe that these accessory symptoms,
these greater or less deviations from the
healthy state, can have any connection
with their principal malady." They will not
mention it to you and that's why you have
to investigate and go back and ask the
different departments of health and find out
the little deviations. We base
our prescription on keynotes.
He is bringing up this idea of keynotes
on which we have to prescribe but these
keynotes sometimes are
ignored by the patient.
The patient says I have a swollen leg, a
swollen knee... whether I eat onions or not
has nothing to do
with my swollen knee.
So if the right knee is swollen and the
person does not like onions or is worse
from onion, the remedy
is... Lycopodium.
You cannot go so far but almost. But
you can see how important it is.
"Besides this, patients themselves differ
so much in their dispositions, that some,
especially the so-called hypochondriacs
and other persons of great sensitiveness
and impatient of suffering, portray their
symptoms in too vivid colors and in order
to induce the physician to give them relief,
describe their ailments in exaggerated
expression." Once I had
a case of an American.
I've never seen such an expression of
symptoms in such a vivid way as he was able
to express them to me. It was an enjoyment.
I was just listening to him.
How he suffered and cannot work and the
fears, I hate my mother and if I go to
the street I fight... It was
an explosion of symptoms.
I was just listening, I had
no chance to put a question.
I said have you taken remedies? He said yes
this and that. Did you take Stramonium?
He said no. Ok, take Stramonium now. For
1 hour he was relating symptoms in that
vivacity that I said to myself, if I had one
tenth of his energy, I would have changed
the world. What energy
was that, fantastic!
And Hahnemann makes a note, he says
the hypochondriac may exaggerate
their symptoms but actually they have the
symptoms and you can test it by giving
them placebo and
observe under it.
They will still continue to have the symptoms.
But out of all the symptoms they relate
what you have to take as definite is
the exaggerated way that they relate
the symptoms to you. Very
vivid, exaggerated way.
Which are mostly patients with a
psychological problem and usually the people
who are manic depressive during the
period of mania they will describe
their symptoms in this way.
"Other individuals of an opposite
character, however, partly from indolence,
partly from false modesty, partly from a
kind of mildness of disposition or weakness
of mind, refrain from mentioning a
number of their symptoms, describe them
in vague terms, or allege some of
them to be of no consequence."
They think why should I bother the
doctor with this and that which I have?
You have to realize that this is the type
of person and you have to encourage him
to talk and to tell yes I'm
interested and then they start.
Once you give them the space, you
are listening, they will talk.
Listen to this paragraph 98.
Very important paragraph.
"Now, as certainly as we should listen
particularly to the patient's description
of his sufferings and sensations, and attach
credence especially to his own expressions
wherewith he endeavors to make
us understand his pathology [...]
so certainly, on the other hand, in all
diseases, but especially in the chronic ones,
the investigation of the true, complete picture
and its peculiarities demands especial
circumspection, tact, knowledge of human
nature, caution in conducting the inquiry
and patience in an
eminent degree."
You have to be patient to be looking,
hearing him but at the same time you are
putting questions with tact and
understand the human nature.
Because the moment that you have a
patient and you start criticizing him
'he is so selfish, he talks about himself,
he thinks only himself, he is jealous'...
some of my students have done this. Wait
a moment. He's your patient you have
to look, observe, try to get all the
information but never be critical.
Understand human nature which means
that whatever deviations a human being
may have, it is understandable by the
doctor who has the ability to understand
human beings. It's not his
fault that he is jealous.
Jealousy is a symptom once
it is becoming excessive.
He's not in control of that, so you
cannot criticize him for having this.
A person who is oversexed and he needs to
go to prostitutes, a person who is born
with some problems in the hormonal area, is
not under his control, you cannot judge.
Sometimes I have spoken about those born
homosexual. It is like being born with
a predisposition for which
they have no control at all.
Therefore understanding the human nature
without judging them and listening
with special circumspection, the word means
all-around understanding
and patience in an eminent degree.
This is the most difficult I can tell you.
The moment that you have programmed to
see 20 cases, you cannot have patience,
I can tell you. 20 cases a day
for a homeopath is impossible.
So you are going to speed up the process
and you are going to make mistakes.
I remember when I was in Calcutta Homeopathic
College, an old student of Kent,
he was a teacher in the college and
people were coming to the outpatient
department, there was a big line of patients
and he was there with his big glasses,
he looks and writes, then the next...
He doesn't ask any questions.
He looked and asked 1 or 2 questions and he
gives a prescription and all the students
were behind looking what he was doing.
I could not understand at all.
The Indians were used to this.
So I asked somebody to explain.
So he saw me, that I was also interested and then there was a
little baby, looks, writes and as I tried to
look he closes, so I could not see
the prescription, what did I give.
I look at the baby and the saliva was
running out, most probably Mercury I said.
He did not say anything. He was unhappy.
He gave Mercury of course.
But this kind of Homeopathy is a necessary
situation in a country where there is no
money, no medicines, not enough doctors
etc. But Hahnemann is German, not Indian.
So he wants the
absolute and the most...
Paragraph 99. "On the whole, the investigation
of acute diseases, or of such as have
existed but a short time, is much the
easiest for the physician, because all
the phenomena and deviations from the
health that has been put recently lost
are still fresh in the memory of
the patient and his friends..."
In acute cases the patient knows how he
was feeling before and how he feels now.
So he is freshing his memory.. and his
friends. Here is very important that Hahnemann
based a lot of his decisions upon the
information from people around the patient.
Because these people who have lived around
somebody, know quite a lot of the habits,
their way of behaving etc. "...still
continue to be novel and striking.
The physician certainly requires to
know everything in such cases also;
but he has much less to inquire into..." In
acute conditions the homeopath does not
have to ask many questions. I have said
many times that you go to a person with
meningitis and there is severe pain,
there is high fever and you do not ask
'do you like sweets?'. You investigate
and you take the present symptoms
which are much less that
in chronic conditions.
"...they are for the most part
spontaneously detailed to him."
Paragraph 100. "In investigating the
totality of the symptoms of epidemic and
sporadic diseases it is quite immaterial
whether or not something similar has ever
appeared in the world before, under
the same or any other name."
Before we discussed here the new type of
influenza that has spread all over the world
and I related the symptoms of influenza
this time which are totally different than
the symptoms of usual
influenzas of the past years.
He says be careful these diseases you must
not think oh it's an influenza take this
or that remedy. It may be a
totally new kind of picture.
"...The novelty or peculiarity of a disease
of that kind makes no difference either in
the mode of examining or of treating it,
as the physician must any way regard
the pure picture of every prevailing
disease, as if it were something new and
unknown, and investigate it thoroughly for
itself, if he desires to practice medicine
in a real and radical manner. Never
substituting conjecture for actual observation"
If you want to practice real medicine, you
don't have to say oh yes I know this is
an epidemic of enterocolitis,
therefore take Arsenicum album.
He says at any given time in history an
acute disease may come with a new profile
of symptoms.
"...always carefully examining it in all its
phases; and this mode of procedure is all
the more requisite in such cases, as a
careful examination will show that every
prevailing disease is in many respects
a phenomenon of a unique character,
differing vastly from all previous epidemics,
to which certain names have been falsely
applied - with the exception of those epidemics
resulting from a contagious principle
that always remains the same,
such as smallpox, measles, etc."
By saying that he is like a prophet. He
says that certain contagious diseases
coming from a specific microbe may
remain in their overall picture steady.
But other acute conditions may
come every time in a changed form.
Every time you have to look a new case
like a common cold, bronchitis, influenza,
you have to look whether this type of
acute is different from the previous one
and do not immediately come to the
conclusion I know what it is.
Paragraph 101, "It may easily happen that
in the first case of an epidemic disease
that presents itself to the physician's
notice he does not at once obtain a knowledge
of its complete picture, as it is only by a
close observation of several cases of every
such collective disease that he can become
conversant with the totality of its signs
and symptoms."
He says in these influenza epidemics
don't come into conclusion immediately,
you have to see a lot of cases to understand
the overall picture of the epidemic.
"...The carefully observing physician can,
however, from the examination of even
the first and second patients, often arrive
so nearly at thr knowledge of the true state
as to have in his mind a characteristic
portrait of it, and even to succeed in finding
a suitable, homeopathically
adapted remedy for it."
That means the carefully observing physician,
he will see 1-2 cases, immediately
he gets a good picture of the
epidemic but it's not always so.
"In the course of writing down the
symptoms of several cases of this kind
the sketch of the disease picture becomes
ever more and more complete, not more
spun out and verbose, but more
significant [...] become precisely defined
as to their peculiarities..."
If you write down the symptoms in each case
that you take, eventually you will have
a whole picture, not fantasy, but
real picture of the epidemic.
"...and on the other, the more marked and
special symptoms which are peculiar to
but few diseases and of rarer occurrence,
at least in the same combination, become
prominent and constitute what is
characteristic of this malady...",
"The physician who has already, in the
first cases, been able to choose a remedy
approximating to the homoeopathic specific,
will, from the subsequence cases,
be enabled either to verify the suitableness
of the medicine chosen, or to discover
a more appropriate, the most
appropriate homoeopathic remedy."
That means he has seen one or two
cases, he has prescribed some remedies
but as he writes down carefully all the
symptoms of each case, he eventually may find
out yes I was correct prescribing these
remedies or may find out the real genius of
the epidemic is not what I thought it was;
Eupatorium perfoliatum but it is Rhus tox.
He may find out that he was not correct
and he prescribed Eupatorium perfoliatum
whether he should have
prescribed Rhus tox.
Why? Because he has seen a lot of
cases of Rhus tox symptomatology.
This case that I prescribed a similar
remedy or kind of correct remedy was not to
the point and I should have prescribed
another one, more appropriate.
Homeopathy is a real science
but it's a difficult one.
That is a fact but at the same time those who
learn it, I can assure you they can have
whatever they like in life.
I have 3 electric cars. 2 of
them have been given as present!
Apart from anything else which I wanted
it has been given by divine grace or
whatever... Not that I want crazy things
but what I feel is that this knowledge
has given me a satisfaction which if I did
not have it most probably I would have gone
to the next stage, as the Indians say, to
the next cycle of reincarnation, very early
in my life. I have programmed it already
quite early because I was suffering so much,
I said you suffer another 10 years, I
was 15 when I started with the pains.
10-12 years I came in contact with
Homeopathy. I owe all my life to Homeopathy.
I read this honestly one time in my life in
1960. Never again I opened it this book.
I read it right through but it is as if it
has remained every meaning of the book and
became my practice. You don't
believe that I never read this.
Maybe some things I overcame because
I thought they were not important.
This is the second time I'm reading it and I
said if I read it for a second time I may
record my comments, so they may
stay for the next generation.
For me it was the most pleasant and
easiest book I have ever read in my life.
That is also true. I was
so excited by that time.
Now I am reading again and I'm again
excited. After 53 years... it is ridiculous.
-Maybe in your next life you
won't need to read it anymore.
-I hope. But now I read it for your sake.
The first time I read it for my sake...
So whoever is present...
-When I started practicing Homeopathy with
your teachings, I used to find problems
in practice and in my town there is
nobody to whom I can ask questions.
I have a problem, please help me sir.
So I started reading this book.
From then till I came here. I
have completed Organon 232 times...
-You read Organon!
-Yes, back to back,
page to page.
-I believe you! The energy that you
present, that you have is unbelievable.
-Last year when I came here you have given
me a sign. At that time I had completed
Organon 150 times. And I believe this is
the best book I have ever read in my life.
-I can see you have read it. The
condition of the book is terrible.
You have been studying
it very thoroughly.
So I want to continue. Are you tired? I
can tell you stories, if you are tired.
The German people, they told me it's so
difficult reading this book. Is it true?
I said yes, it's very difficult to read
the Organon in the original German.
Hahnemann does not want to leave anything
out, so in one phrase which is very long,
he says everything but in order to follow
his thought you have to be himself.
Only himself could understand
what he was writing...
"...but the whole extent of such an epidemic
disease and the totality of its symptoms
cannot be learned from one single patient,
but is only to be perfectly deduced and
ascertained from the sufferings of several
patients of different constitutions."
He understands that an epidemic is not
engrafting a symptomatology which is typical
in every patient but every organism
reacts to this epidemic according
to its possibilities.
An organism has good possibilities, reacts
good, raising high fever and within a few
days it's gone, the other one cannot
raise a high fever and goes on and on.
Each patient reacts according to his
own individuality and constitution.
Par. 103, "In the same manner as has here
been taught relative to the epidemic
diseases, which are generally of an acute
character, the miasmatic chronic maladies,
which, as I have shown, always remain the
same in their essential nature, especially
the psora, must be investigated, as to
the whole sphere of their symptoms,
in a much more minute manner than has
ever been done before, for in them also
one patient only exhibits a
portion of their symptoms,
a second, a third, and so on, present
some other symptoms, which also are but
a portion of the totality of the symptoms
which constitute the entire extent
of this malady, so that the whole array
of the symptoms belonging to such
a miasmatic, chronic disease, and especially
to the psora, can only be ascertained
from the observation of very many single
patients affected with such a chronic disease,
and without a complete survey and
collective picture of these symptoms
the medicines capable of curing the
whole malady homeopathically cannot be
discovered..."
What he says is that, well I told you about
the epidemics, you have to see a lot of
patients before you understand the extent
of the epidemic and you form an idea of
what is the symptomatology
of the epidemic.
With psora, when it comes to the miasmatic
conditions, in chronic conditions,
you have a bigger problem before you
understand the whole extent of the effect
of psora, suppressed scabies... who
does not understand "scabies"?
Everybody understands. So to understand
he says the extent of the miasm psora,
you have to see a lot of patients and
eventually you understand the whole damage
that suppression of scabies
can have upon the human race.
Because one patient presents one part,
another patient presents another part and
then you have to put them all together to
find out the whole extent of the damage
that a miasm psora, has
done on the human race.
Who was in the previous?
Previously we had some cases that they
had the same causative factor but
they reacted in a
totally different way.
One came as symptoms of Anagallis, the
other came as Staphysagria symptoms and
the other came with symptoms
of Natrum muriaticum.
In the same way with the psora suppressed
each organism brings out different type
of symptomatology and you have to put all
this in order to understand the psora miasm.
So he is developing
the idea of the miasms.
"...without a complete survey and collective
picture of these symptoms the medicines
capable of curing the whole malady
homeopathically cannot be discovered".
That means if you don't have the whole picture,
you will not be able to find the correct
remedy. "...and these medicines are, at the
same time, the true remedies of the several
patients suffering from
such chronic affections."
Par. 104, "When the totality of the symptoms
that specially mark and distinguish
the case of disease or, in other words, when
the picture of the disease, whatever be
its kind, is once accurately sketched, the most
difficult part of the task is accomplished.
The physician has then the picture of the
disease, especially if it be a chronic one,
always before him to guide him in his treatment;
he can investigate it in all its parts
and can pick out the characteristic symptoms,
in order to oppose to these, that is
to say, to the whole malady itself, a very
similar artificial morbific force, in the shape
of a homeopathically chosen medicinal
substance, selected from the lists of symptoms
of all the medicines whose pure
effects have been ascertained."
He says once you write down the symptoms
in chronic conditions, then you are able
to find which of the remedies that have
been proven, have more similar symptoms
to this particular case. "And when, during
the treatment, he wishes to ascertain
what has been the effect of the medicine,
and what change has taken place in the
patient's state, at this fresh examination
of the patient he only needs to strike out
of the list of the symptoms noted down at
the first visit those that have become
ameliorated, to mark what still remain,
and add any new symptoms that may have
supervened."
Without knowing in the last seminar
I think I have said the same thing.
I said that we don't do a good job in taking
a case, what would be a good job would be
to note down the symptoms one by
one and ask the patient what about
that symptom? It's gone. What
about this symptom? Remains.
What about this symptom...? Do you have
new symptoms? Yes, I have 2 more new
symptoms, then you can go ahead
and find the next remedy.
I have said that without remembering at
all. He has mentioned even that detail.
Any question that
you want to ask?
-It's not only putting down the
symptoms and considering the new ones...
We have to see how the patient feels in
general and how his energy is because
what I saw for example in Indian hospitals,
they are doing that but sometimes
they are missing the point.
-That is true, I have said how you can
evaluate a case and this is different than
what Hahnemann says. He says that the
right thing is that you have written down
in detail all the symptoms and when the
patient comes back, go through the list and
ask him do you still have this symptom,
yes, do you still have this symptom, no,
are you thirsty, do you have
new symptoms and note down.
At this moment he does not say what are
parameters for knowing that a correct
remedy has been given. He just says because
he is very accurate, very detailed,
he says that you have to do that and this
is very important because if we want to do
research and find out what a remedy can
do further than the information we have,
we can find out only
through this way.
Because if we have cases where we have given
Pulsatilla and it has cured a symptom
which is not already recorded, then we have
a symptom for Pulsatilla, so we add to
the symptomatology of Pulsatilla. In the
same way when we have given a small remedy
and we have recorded the symptoms in
detail and we can see which symptoms have
changed. In a small remedy it's very important
because it augments the possibility
of that remedy. So what he says is a
practice which if I had done this when I was
starting in the 60s in Athens...
and I had assistance, people who could
write down and then the patient comes and
we see what has been cured, I would have
a wealth of information but it was not
possible for me to do it. Therefore
I relied only on my memory.
So I saw a Pulsatilla case, Pulsatilla aversion
fat, then I had a Pulsatilla which said
I desire pork, I said Ok I will give
you Pulsatilla, comes back, cured.
Thousands of such symptoms were gone
because I did not have the support team,
I was by myself.
I remember a film there was a battalion
that everybody was killed in a fortress and
there was one left and he put all
the soldiers looking through the...
so he was going around with his gun and he
was shooting as if everybody was alive,
so the other people thought they were
fighting with 50 people. There was only one.
I was feeling like this in the beginning. I
just explain why it was not possible for me
to have all this information but today you
have definitely, especially in India, you have
the structure that you may need
to get more and more information.
Because you have a lot of cases, you have a lot
of assistance, a lot of people are interested...
By that time I had converted medical doctors
to Homeopathy to prescribe for them
in order to have patients and be able to
prescribe themselves. I was prescribing
for everyone. How could I find the
time to go through the cases?
It's very nice but difficult.
-Sir, what message you wish to give us in
order to find all this information from what
we are getting in the practice?
-What he says exactly here, write in detail.
The patient has symptoms, write them
in detail and when he comes back you say
you said you had a headache that was
coming at 10 a.m. what happened with it?
It's not anymore. Ok, you had also
constipation what happened? I still have it.
You also said that if you eat sweets you had
an aggravation you had a heartburn,
what happened? This is better.
Do you have new symptoms? Yes. Write
them down. You give the second remedy,
he comes back, again you examine him
according to what you have written and you
examine him.
I remember an American who had been here
as patient she came and I said what
happened? She says I am the same.
Nothing happened, no change? No change.
I said Ok. I opened the computer because
in the computer we had all the symptoms.
I said what happened with this symptom? I
don't have it! What happened with this?
I don't have it! I went through the whole
list and she did not have any symptom left!
I had all these? You had all
these and now you don't have.
Thank you very much, I'm better. Now the
program keeps it and we can go through.
-A question about the totality of symptoms.
Hahnemann says that we have to write
down all the symptoms. Did
Hahnemann have an idea of layers?
Because sometimes we cannot prescribe
on totality. What do you think?
-I think Hahnemann
had everything.
I cannot tell you that now but what
they can say is most probably correct.
As we go along you will find it.
-I would like just to tell one thing, from
aphorism 172 to 183 Hahnemann has briefly
explained the strategy about the
Group 3 and 4 cases, how to go.
You give one remedy. You don't have
many symptoms in Group 4 and 3.
How do you explain Hahnemann had said
the same, if you don't have much
symptoms, just... then when you give the
remedy, that layer will go and then another
remedy will come, which the patient never
knew about it or might have said it I was
having the symptom and again you catch
that layer symptoms and give the remedy
and beneath another layer will come. Exactly
what you explain about Group 3 and 4
he has explained.
-I believe. Maybe you don't believe it but
in the process I thought I discovered this
and that. When I started teaching the Organon
again I found out he had already said it.
Most probably if we go further, we
will see even more from what Hahnemann
wanted to tell me.
-I used to know that we have found clinically
confirmed symptoms like Staphysagria
sleep on left side, Causticum sleeps on...
there are many confirmations which I have
seen in my practice but unfortunately I don't
have a way to send it in order to have
a proper edition. My question was how we
should proceed in order to make these
clinically confirmed symptoms into the
Repertory in a very authentic way.
-We'll discuss more about it and also we'll
discuss about provings of the remedies.
Dimitri was asking how to do
provings of small remedies from M.M.
We'll discuss it and I'll
give you my ideas about it.
-Because you say in your teachings that if
you are able to find a symptom clinically
for 3 times, then it's confirmed ... I have
a list of symptoms which I have confirmed
for more than 5-6 times,
more than 100 symptoms.
I have a record but I
don't know how to apply...
-Give them to me
and I will apply.
-Definitely yes. With pleasure. I also check
out to see. I will tell you how you can be
certain that a symptoms belongs to
the remedy and not to other things.
But we'll discuss in more
detail about that. Thank you!