We have spoken up to paragraph 90. The last paragraphs 82 up to 89 were speaking
about the taking of the case and what you have to pay attention to.
It's very interesting in paragraph 87, I don't remember if I commented on that,
he says "For instance the physician should not ask, was not this or that circumstance
present..." That means you should not suggest to the patient the condition.
Did you have a condition like this or that by the time... suggesting yourself to the mind
of the patient something which may not be there because the patient may accept
that this was so while this is not true.
"He should never be guilty of making such suggestions". Many times you are thinking
this is Calc. carbonica so you need that the patient will tell you that he has fear
of high places. So if you put it in this way "you have fear of high places" suggesting
to the patient, not asking but suggesting, the patient himself if he is of a weak
character, he may think maybe there was one time that I was in a high places
and...yes. So he gives you a positive answer because you suggested it, not because
the symptom exists. Hahnemann is very careful in these matters. "...which tend to
seduce the patient into giving a false answer and a false account of his symptoms."
So suggesting is to be avoided. He speaks of the details for which you have to get
information and in paragraph 89 just before the one that we are just to connect.
"For example, how often are his bowels moved? What is the exact character of
the stool? Did the whitish evacuation consist of mucus or feces?
Had he or had he not pains during the evacuation? What was their exact character
and where were they seated? What did the patient vomit? Is the bad taste in the
mouth putrid, or bitter, or sour, or what?"
If you read carefully the Organon, you will see that he leaves nothing to chance.
He takes all possibilities, all the mistakes we may make when we take a case
and he gives precise information. Later on he will give the qualities of
the homeopath who is doing the investigation and the qualities are quite high.
In order to take a real case the homeopath must be quite a wise man already.
That is a problem of course...
He goes on to paragraph 90. "When the physician has finished writing down
these particulars..." A lot of these particulars you can go and study in the notes
"he then makes a note of what he himself observes in the patient".
For example, how the patient behaved during the visit - whether he was morose,
quarrelsome, hasty, lachrymose, anxious, despairing or sad, or hopeful, calm etc."
The information has to be complete with the observation of the physician.
In paragraph 91. "The symptoms and feelings of the patient during a previous course
of medicine do not furnish the pure picture of the disease." Here is the case where
you have a patient coming to you and he has been taking allopathic drugs and
he comes under the drugs and Hahnemann says the symptoms that were before
taking the remedies do not give you the exact form of the disease you are going
to treat. He says be careful. Before taking the remedies what were the symptoms?
And you may come to the conclusion he says that this is the remedy.
He says not always.
"do not furnish the pure picture of the disease; but on the other hand,
those symptoms and ailments which he suffered from before the use of
the medicines, or after they had been discontinued for several days, give the true
fundamental idea of the original form of the disease", "but on the other hand,
those symptoms and ailments which he suffered from before the use of
the medicines, or after they had been discontinued" then you have the real picture.
What he says is you take the symptoms before, you discontinue his drugs and see
what is after. So what is after and what was before combined then you have a good
picture of the situation. There he speaks about usual cases that we have with
the modern drugs that people are taking.
Most of the people are taking allopathic drugs when they come to Homeopathy.
"and these especially the physician must take note of.
When the disease is of a chronic character, and the patient has been taking medicine
up to the time he is seen" until the day he comes to us he still takes the remedies
"the physician may with advantage leave him some days quite without medicine".
So he says that the best you can do if this case is chronic is tell him to stop the
medication for a few days and that will be to the advantage of your case, tell him
to stop the medication and now he suggests what to do "or in the meantime
administer something of unmedicinal nature". Give him some placebo.
Tell him take this now, stop the medicine and come after 15 days to see you.
Question.
-What shall I do with patient who is taking drugs for his high blood pressure,
for diabetes?
-I will speak about that. And send the patient on another period "and defer to a
subsequent period the more precise scrutiny...". Do not take details at that moment.
You take a few symptoms and you say OK I will give you a remedy now and in 15 days
I have to see you again. Take placebo. "...in order to be able to grasp in their purity
the permanent uncontaminated symptoms of the old affection and to form a faithful
picture of the disease". He says do not rely on the picture he had while taking
the remedy, this it is not enough, because the effect of the drugs may have changed
the nature of the disease. That means he has made the situation deeper and difficult
most probably. And that is why you should wait and see the changes that were made
by the drugs that he was taking.
Hahnemann speaks at the end of the 18th century.
What were the drugs he was taking by that time? They had not the type of drugs that
we have today which affect the organism much deeper and make an organism
to depend on such drugs.
Because when somebody is taking cortisone, they have discovered that
the suprarenal glands in cases of crisis they exude cortisone and therefore flowing
of cortisone in the blood is a link on a chain of the defense of the organism.
An important link, but it is only a link. If the person is taking cortisone, what happens?
The clever physician has given a replacement of what the organism should have done.
The organism should have raised the amount of cortisone into the blood up to
a certain extent. The physician does not know to what extent was necessary.
So he says take 20mg of cortisone. But maybe the organism needs only 3mg in order
to overcome. By giving 20mg it replaces the functions of the suprarenal glands and
they say oh my God there is too much cortisone into the blood, I stop.
So they nullify the function of the suprarenal glands because the organism knows
what is going on. You don't need to produce at all.
But if you do it for a long period of time the suprarenal glands cease to function.
So he comes to you and you say according to Hahnemann, stop the drug and
I will see you in 20 days but actually what is going to happen is that there is
no cortisone, the suprarenal glands will not start automatically producing because
they have ceased due to the use of cortisone from outside.
Therefore the conditions that we have to face as homeopaths at this moment
concerning the allopathic drugs is much more complicated than Hahnemann had
when he was writing the Organon.
We have managed to find drugs for high blood pressure.
But has anybody seen a cure by these drugs?
Now you take 50mg of this anti-hypertensive drug, after 2 years he needs 60mg and
then after 2 years 100mg. That means something is going on which we don't know.
What is that we don't know? Is that the organism has decided to raise the blood
pressure because of certain reasons. We come with the drug and say we don't allow
you to rise the blood pressure because it's dangerous for the patient he will have
a brain stroke.
And the patient believes it and he starts taking the anti-hypertensive drugs.
But what is the mechanism that brings down the organism?
We have to conclude that because there is no cure if one takes anti-hypertensive
drugs even for a long time. On the contrary they need more and more remedies
and sometimes the drug stops working and they need another drug, sometimes
they combine 2 drugs together to keep the blood pressure low...
He comes to us and we say stop the anti-hypertensive drugs because I want
to observe what is the real nature of your disease. "...to form a faithful picture of
the disease." Hahnemann could say that because there was no danger.
What they were doing was bloodletting, taking some herbs, things that were not
deforming the disease per se but the symptoms a little bit.
Here we deform the disease. That means before the allopathic drugs
there is a disease, after the allopathic drugs there is a disease plus.
the effect of the chemical drug.
So we have to be careful and understand the conditions under which Hahnemann
was working. But listen to this now it's very interesting...
Because Hahnemann never left anything out.
In paragraph 92 he says "But if it be a disease of a rapid course" that means a disease
which develops rapidly "and if its serious character admit of no delay, the physician
must content himself with observing the morbid condition, altered though it may be
by medicines". The physician cannot anymore say stop the medicine. He must accept
that the picture he has in front of him, that's it. He must be content with that.
Can you do something with this? You cannot stop the medication, it's dangerous.
The disease is going to develop. He speaks of another type of pathology which existed
by that time but if we had to transfer it to our contemporary situation,
what do we know is that when a person takes a drug,
especially on account of his cardiac situation, we better be careful
to not stop the drug but be content he takes now a drug for thinning the blood
and a drug for high blood pressure and a drug for this and that...
Just don't go and stop all these and take the placebo and I'll see you
in the next world... We meet on the next stage.
The Indians believe it is good if the physician helps a person go to the next stage,
has helped him to go quickly to one more cycle... This is accepted.
Death in Indian tradition, at least in the 1960s, this was accepted as a phenomenon
of the cycle of life in which a person through suffering in this life
becomes more and more spiritually evolved. The idea is to be similar with God.
But God is full of love, justice, energy, knowledge. Actually you have to be having
all these qualities to be in connection with God. How can you attain these qualities?
Only through reincarnation. Therefore if I give you a remedy and you die I helped you
to go quickly to the next cycle. Here it is different with western societies.
We consider life as the greatest thing. Somebody dies because of mistake of a M.D.
He's finished. He will never have again a chance. Just one mistake that comes to
the public. You see how the society is hypocritical.
Because there are at the same time millions of people dying because of wars,
of famine, of atrocities which the human mind has produced in order to kill each other
and because the M.D. made the mistake and he should have given this remedy
instead of that, then it becomes a big thing in the society.
We have to face it as homeopaths, this is the reality.
Because if you make a mistake as a homeopath, they will kill you.
Even as a M.D. where it is accepted to give remedies that kill the patient.
Actually there was a research in the American Medical Association Journal in 2000
which proved that the number 1 death situation was people who were taking
faithfully their allopathic drugs. Despite the fact they found they were getting
worse and worse, they kept on taking them... Bye bye! Finished!
2085 deaths from iatrogenic diseases. It means we gave you too much drugs and
we killed you.
Those of us who want to go according to the teachings of Hahnemann we have to be
sensible and understand that we are living in a society under certain conditions and
also in a time where the medical structure has found chemical drugs that can affect
very deeply the human body. Therefore we cannot do that very easily.
But in certain cases we can.
If we feel there is no danger of life of course we can do it.
But most of the times he says you have to give a remedy while the person
is under drugs. Because if you stop it, the disease is very rapid and he will go.
"if he cannot ascertain what symptoms were present before the employment of
the medicines, - in order that he may at least form a just apprehension of
the complete picture of the disease in its actual condition, that is to say,
of the conjoint malady formed by the medicinal and original diseases, which from
the use of inappropriate drugs is generally more serious and dangerous than was
the original disease."
That means by giving the drugs the condition has become more serious
and more dangerous. "and hence demands prompt and efficient aid"
immediately after you give the remedy... but your remedy has to be - if possible -
based on what symptoms he may had before the taking of the drugs.
In such a case you have no other option but to take the present situation.
What there is under the drugs. But also try to see if before taking the medicine
was a picture of a remedy and base it on that.
You most probably have heard a case of mine that I treated in Houston in America
with transplanted aorta and the patient went into coma in Houston.
He remained 3 months in a coma in Houston and they transferred him to
the Greek hospital in order to die in his country.
By that time his daughter came and said George can you do something?
I said no of course. But they insisted and I said Ok , let me go and see this guy in
the hospital. I went and saw him and I saw some signs and I could see the remedy.
In the meantime, I forgot to tell you, this woman together with her husband
who was a professor in the University , they went to the doctors and said
what is the situation.
The doctors said that it's a matter of 2-3 days, no more.
Everybody knew the patient is going to die in 3 days at most.
Ok then, if they agree to take out all medications, because there was a rejection
process of the implant, then I will prescribe. This professor said Ok Vithoulkas
will come to treat the case. But you have to take out all your medication.
The doctor said if I knew the situation was different, that means there was
any possibility the patient may survive, I would be very offended of what you are
telling me now but I will agree to withdraw all the medications.
In such a situation I took the chance of course but I knew they could do
nothing more.
The man lived ten more years, he was 72 he lived up to 82, he was driving his car,
he was happy and every year he was coming and giving me a present, because
he was still alive. Quite a lot of presents, he appreciated.
It was a tremendous situation I went through but I had to be very careful, and I made
a mistake in prescribing, at the moment I prescribed the wrong medication,
the blood pressure went up but he came out of the coma in 12 days.
This professor with his car took him home where I continue treating him.
All the doctors who were attending because his kidneys were breaking down,
the vascular system was so sclerosed and all that, he was in a terrible situation.
All these doctors disappeared, they never came back while I was treating him
for 12 days. Not one doctor came to see how this guy was doing
that Vithoulkas is treating, I am talking about '79.
After this all these doctors who attended, the nephrologist, the cardiologist,
the internist, there were 4 doctors attending the case before... none of them came
to ask what the hell have you done? Is there something that we don't know maybe?
Not one of them. A month later I played a trick, because the patient was feeling
quite good and some edema was in his ankles, I said please call the cardiologist
to tell us because I want to know why this edema continues.
The cardiologist comes, knocks the door and says I am cardiologist and I would like
to see the patient Mr... The patient says I am Mr...
From the state of coma, in which he was, could not recognize him now as a human
being standing in front of him. He said not you, the patient.
He said I am the patient. You are the patient? What can I do for you?
He said my doctor Mr. Vithoulkas wants to know why I still have this little edema
in my ankles. And he would like a report from you.
They have taken a lot of money until that moment when I interfered.
The poor doctor of course called me. I heard him saying well Mr. Vithoulkas
you have done a little miracle. I said yes a small miracle.
These edemas in the ankles is nothing, don't worry about that.
I said thank you for your advice.
Unless we do things like that, people will not realize the importance of what
we are doing. There is no possibility. They just go on...
I remember another case giving all kinds of medications for a case of constant fever.
She has been in Austria, has been in different hospitals.
Her husband was a lawyer in Areios Pagos, the supreme court.
They came to me in '71, I was 2-3 years in Greece and my husband is
in supreme court and I am taking cortisone and I am still having the fever.
What shall I do? Shall I stop the medication?
I felt there was no danger for her life so I said Ok you stop the medication and
I will treat you. She said there are 10 doctors who are attending me.
I was under attack already before starting the case.
I prescribed the remedy, in one month the fever disappeared.
What was the remedy? I think Ferrum phosphoricum. Just one remedy.
She came to me very happy and at the second month very happy and at the third
month no fever, very happy, the fourth month she says I will tell you a phenomenon
which I observed, I told all of them that you are going to treat me.
In the first ten days all of them, almost every day they would call me, how are you,
as I started telling them I am better the 10 became 9, the 9 became 8 and so on and
in the end remained only one who would like to call you.
Would you please talk to him? I said yes, of course.
He asked me what I did, what was your diagnosis? I told him I will not tell you
the diagnosis, I will tell you only the remedy. I gave Ferrum phosphoricum.
What is it? It doesn't matter, it's difficult for me to explain but this is the situation.
He says can I come to your lectures? I said of course every Monday I give lectures
to the Greek doctors, you can come.
He came 2-3 times and he said goodbye and never came back.
All these phenomena which are happening under homeopathic treatment and which
sometimes are really impressive are not being considered.
Such a callous situation that it's very difficult for us to deal with.
So Mr. Hahnemann was saying "...demands prompt and efficient aid; and by thus
tracing out the complete picture of the disease he will be enabled to combat it with
a suitable homoeopathic remedy, so that the patient shall not fall a sacrifice to
the injurious drugs he was swallowed."
He considered that the victim was actually a victim of the medical people.
Paragraph 93. "If the disease has been brought on a short time or, in the case of
a chronic affection, a considerable time previously, by some obvious cause,
then the patient - or his friends when questioned privately - will mention it either
spontaneously or when carefully interrogated".
"If the disease has been brought on a short time or, in the case of a chronic affection,
a considerable time previously, by some obvious cause..." That means if what you are
facing today is a chronic condition which was coming from a specific cause
you have to find out which the cause was that brought this condition.
Either the patient will say it spontaneously or when carefully interrogated.
"Any causes of a disgraceful character, which the patient or his friends do not like
to confess, at least not voluntarily, the physician must endeavor to elicit by skillfully
framing his questions, or by private information."
There is a couple that has come and the woman is having the problem and you
suspect that the woman has a problem because she falls in love with another man
and now she is in a great conflict what to do. Shall I divorce my husband who is so
nice or should I stay with him and forget the man with whom I feel Ok?
That is a disgraceful cause. You cannot elicit it in front of the husband.
Take the woman privately and ask. This problem is greater when I take a case
because everybody is listening. There is an extra difficulty for me to elicit such causes
but those who were previously attending the course they found out in 2 cases,
there was defamation, unjustly accused people who are destroyed by this defamation
and were able to discuss and to say what was actually happening.
Then you take into consideration this cause. You take it together with details of
the rest of the case. A cause can bring out on an individual a certain disease picture
and the same cause - defamation or jealousy- can bring out a different picture on
a different individual. You have to be careful of that.
It does not mean because you know the cause, you will always give Ignatia.
"...at least not voluntarily, the physician must endeavor to elicit by skilfully framing
his questions, or by private information. To these belong poisoning or attempted
suicide..." It's difficult for a person to say I have attempted suicide because I lost
my lover... These are difficult things to confess and people keep them for themselves.
And we have to be very skillful in eliciting this, in understanding what is going on
most probably. Sometimes the cause of the manifestation of a tumor in the breast of
a woman will be the conflict in her marriage.
Because during the marriage she fell in love with somebody else and the attraction
is so great that the hormones are changing completely. With her husband it was Ok.
But with this where the hormones are flooding the brain and stimulating it but
cannot be satisfied, the problem becomes tremendous within the organism and
the flooding of the hormones and the resistance of the person not to submit
to this new situation suddenly brings out a tumor in the breast.
The medicine that always knows everything they call it hormonally dependent cancer.
They like to have a name. But when there is a hormonally dependent cancer
you know that most probably there is a problem of not allowing the organism to
let out the extra hormones which are produced for one reason or another.
"...onanism, masturbation...indulgence [...] excess in wine [...], coffee [...] infection
with venereal disease..." The fact that somebody has been infected by venereal
disease, the doctor immediately will suppose that the man or the woman had been
gone in places not so clean to have sex.
That immediately brings a shame to the individual and will keep it inside.
So you have to elicit by skillfully preparing questions, otherwise...
I told you the case of a Greek general who was very religious and had a group
following him. He was a general in pension.
He had a rhinitis and the symptoms indicated definitely infection with gonorrhea.
He was saying for himself what a great person he is, followers are believing in him...
I said now I have to confirm. How shall I ask him? If I asked him directly, did you have
had a gonorrheal infection? He was in that exciting state he would say no of course.
You can never get a positive answer in such a situation. So I said to him,
did you get gonorrhea when you were 21 or 22? 21, he said!
He couldn't have time to think the question. Take Medorrhinum.
He was sending us cases after that. I said why didn't he come to tell us how he is.
He's very well said everyone of his friends that were coming.
I said to one of them why doesn't he come to tell us? Maybe he needs another remedy.
He says that you asked him some very peculiar questions he did not like.
I said I know, they were very peculiar. In his mind he could not believe that I could
know that this had taken place. The question was really beyond his comprehension.
Why suddenly somebody asked me did you get gonorrhea at 21 or 22?
Because I expected more or less the age, I am not a magician but I know the age
that the hormones are very strong and most probably he went to a prostitute
and he got gonorrhea.
And now he is a general, that means he's a strong person with a lot of testosterone.
People who want to put down others etc. All this was automatic.
He thought what the hell, what is this question? But afterwards he did not have time
at the moment to respond. He responded immediately.
And of course saved his life as well.
Because if somebody has a rhinitis, you do not give Medorrhinum.
I can't remember something else which I had found. Questions.
-If we have a case of tumor of the breast of a woman who is emotionally frustrated
in the marriage what could we expect to be done by the correct remedy?
-If the organism is not undermined a lot, you may expect to have a cure.
If the organism is a sensitive organism which has been undermined already quite
a lot, you may expect that the tumor will have a metastatic nature
and it will metastase.
Maybe with the correct remedy we will delay the metastasis instead of after
3 months, the metastasis may take 3 years. But still the metastasis will occur.
-When the situation continues, the woman is frustrated and the frustration continues
after the treatment, is there a possibility of frequent relapses because of that?
We gave the right remedy...
-If there is a possibility of relapse? Yes of course. Especially if the condition of the
conflict continues. The problem is the causative factor which is behind...
Usually this happens to women because husbands are usually unfaithful.
Apart from the Indians, I take them out, the percentage of the people being
unfaithful at least once in their married life is 85%. Maybe more. I don't know.
But this is a fact. So we are talking about a woman who is left dissatisfied at least
and the hormonal levels are not satisfied. You know that we use Conium
in cases of cancer and what is the main symptomatology?
Suppression of hormones in a woman, either because of the death of the husband
or because the husband has other affairs or because the husband has not the virility
to satisfy the woman. So the woman remains dissatisfied with the situation and
that is why a lot of times she develops cancer which responds to Conium.
The response to Conium is with women who are not so much in grief because
the husband is dead or because she has found out that the husband is unfaithful.
The cases of Conium in women will be because of the man being impotent
either totally or half-impotent or the loss of the husband or in any case the husband
cannot respond to the frequency of the desire of the woman.
These are difficult situations which may end into cancer in women and Conium will
be needed at a certain point of treatment with such women and will save her life.
One dose of Conium may bring back the tension which is created by suppressing
the hormones.
-About the example that you have given before of the woman cancer... if the woman
has conflict in her marriage, that means she has a lover but she does not take any
decision for her marriage because her marriage is nonexistent, they live together
but on the other hand she has her love, is it an incurable case?
-This is the husband syndrome in which the woman due to the lack of satisfaction
in sex, she will develop several symptomatologies.
One of the symptomatologies she may develop is cancer either in the breast or in the
uterus, but not always. She may develop all kinds of other pathologies but one of
the symptoms that she can develop under such circumstances is cancer.
If her organism is weak, it will be metastatic. You may know that cancer which is
hormone-dependent is more curable than the other cancer. Because usually they give
hormones to the woman and take out the pressure of the hormonal development.
-I have a question on patients under allopathic treatment.
When the patient is for long time under allopathic treatment, then the picture becomes
totally distorted and you might not consider anymore the previous symptoms...
-20 years ago he cannot remember what the symptoms were before...
He may remember some things, not the real picture. Actually if you cannot do
anything else and you cannot stop the medication because of a danger in his life,
then you have to act by giving a remedy which you think is good and reduce at the
same time, if he's improving, the drugs he is taking.
The more he is improving, the more you reduce the drugs.
In this case you have to remember repetition of the potency is necessary.
You have to repeat the remedy.
-In mental cases usually they do remember quite well. In psychotic cases for example
they can tell you what illusions and delusions they had but then they might have
been under treatment for 5-10 years and then they come to you.
Do you consider the original delusions?
-No. It's very difficult in such cases. You are talking about schizophrenics.
They have started 16-18 years with delusions, they took allopathic drugs,
now they are 35 and they come to you and say treat them.
Can you treat them? I have tried to treat such cases but I was not successful.
My gut answer is no, I can do nothing. But if somebody is schizophrenic and he comes
without much medication, then I will try to stop the medication.
And then I will have a full picture.
There was somebody who came here with his mother, a nice boy.
Stop the medication. In the place he was staying they said he destroyed all
the flowers. Broke all the glasses with the flowers.
I started treating him with a lot of success because the aggressiveness went low.
He could start talking, he found a girlfriend. He attached himself so the mother says
he is attaching himself to that girl. They wanted further treatment, they wanted to
take him to a clinic and now he is back in very bad situation.
But in some cases of that type which are not really zombies, because if the
schizophrenic comes after 35 years they are zombies, forget it we can do nothing.
How can you take out all these drugs they have taken, the sedatives can kill
somebody, they are dangerous for the society. In the civilized countries they detain
all these people that they must be in the asylum, take drugs and stay as zombie.
-I have several such cases this season.
People who stopped their medication by themselves because they don't want to and
they heard they could get help from me.
I was in very big dilemmas because they will come with pathology which is
very complex and they'll have very strong delusions and also very strong fears
and I will be in front of picture of very strong delusions which for example
would go with Mancinella and very strong fears that would go with Stramonium.
I know that the rules is that you go first for mental symptoms and you look
for delusions first and then the fears and my question is am I allowed to treat
very often such cases?
-In such cases you have to repeat the remedy. You search for the best remedy.
You decided this is the remedy. Which is very difficult but you have to repeat it
in order to see if there is an effect. By giving one dose, cases of that type
I have seen responding only in India.
People are strong, so if somebody goes in an acute psychotic episode
then with one remedy he can come back. It's different.
Here in the west if somebody starts with delusions and schizophrenia then it is going
to be very difficult to find the remedy. Because the organisms have been undermined
by generations of syphilis, gonorrhea etc. A mental hospital in India is totally different
than a mental hospital in the west. In a mental hospital... what was the percentage
that you had success?
-30% of the mental cases...
-The remedy is clearer. The organism is not so much undermined by syphilis and
gonorrhea. Something else I have noticed.
Kent has spoken about syphilis that drives people to become alcoholics and also
people are also losing their hair. If you take a picture of people of the west.
1000 people. See how many people are bald and you take 1000 people in India
you will hardly see any person with baldness. Which means that the syphilis that
was carried through the English occupying India, most of the English people had
syphilis when they were down there, because of the customs and morals
of the Indian race, they did not mix and were not infected much.
Because their morals were very strong within the family.
And that is how they survived to have better immune system than we have and
clearer picture. Best for prescribing.
-There are many cancer cases in India that we are curing with a single dose.
-Yet you cannot cure all the cases.
-Not all.
-But there is a bigger percentage than here. And with one remedy.
Because there are cases in Group 1, cancer cases which are responding.
-I would like to share a very bitter experience of my practice and I would like
to have your suggestion as well.
I had a case of child of 16 years old who was having epilepsy and she was
on strong anti-epileptic drugs. She was Silica by constitution.
After giving a remedy she was improving beautifully...
-Did you reduce the anti-epileptic?
-Yes, after giving Silica I was able to find the Similimum, so I started reducing
allopathic medicine very slowly.
She was very cooperative, the whole family was very cooperative.
During the treatment she had to pass exams and we know Silica has a lot
of examination fear and after that she went into so much stress,
that she developed strong convulsions and she expired...
Because of exam stress she was in status epilepticus and she expired.
It was a beautiful prescription and then there was a very bitter outcome...
I would like to have your opinion, during the treatment when we are reducing
the allopathic drugs, patient had stresses of life... so the exciting cause was playing
a role during the reduction of the allopathic medicine so the patient was in
a vulnerable state... can you suggest us something to do this in a much better way?
-It depends on the individual case. Every case is individual.
I cannot suggest a remedy or something like that.
-But giving the same remedy even in higher potency doesn't work in some cases.
Even when we evaluate the case sometimes the situation doesn't allow us to evaluate
in a better way.
-If you see that case is not responding, in case you have stopped the medication
and there is a crisis and does not respond then you may resort to allopathic drugs.
That means you cannot find at this moment the indicated remedy...
Here is Athena, she is a pediatrician and I have been treating a case exactly like yours,
an autistic child with severe epileptic condition. The girl stopped the allopathic drugs,
was taking only homeopathic, she was doing quite well, the parents took the child to
the beach, this child remained under the sun quite a lot most probably and
she started convulsions, so they brought the child here in convulsions.
I gave a remedy, no effect. I waited 5-10 minutes I gave another remedy, no effect.
She continued more and more severe epileptic fits, I gave a 4th remedy if I remember
well and then I saw she was going into status epilepticus (because it was 45 minutes).
I asked for a helicopter to take the case. So Athena being a pediatrician I asked her to
accompany the case in the helicopter. The child was carried to the hospital in Athens.
By the time the child arrived in the hospital, she was out of the fit.
That means the last remedy I had given was finally the correct one, it acted but did not
have time, so after half an hour of travelling the child recovered totally and since then
has become normal I believe because an American homeopath who took the case
later on said that he was treating the child with the last remedy I had prescribed here
and the child is quite in good condition.
A child that was autistic with epilepsy and now is not autistic and has no epilepsy but
as I said I saw the danger and said move it to the hospital to give the sedatives.
-That time it was at her home preparing for the examinations and because of stress
she developed the fit and she started going into status epilepticus.
Before her parents brought her into the allopathic hospital, she collapsed, she expired.
I had that experience 3 years ago. I have read the chapter number 17 on how to stop
allopathic medicines from Science of Homeopathy a book written by you.
I have read that chapter more than 50 times because for health one must not
experiment...
-One thing that you have to be careful when you cut the medication, one parameter
which you have to take care is whether the patient himself in all other respects
is feeling better. It's not only the symptomatology that is better, he has to be better
all-around and the previous history of the child that means when it started,
how severe were the crisis before the epilepsy...
-Actually it was not that kind of severe epileptic fit what she was having...
what I perceived is the withdrawal effect of the allopathic medicine coupled
with stress has ruined her life. Otherwise she was doing beautifully well with Silica
and I was very sure that I will be able to bring her out of the problem.
But this unfortunate event actually caused the whole incidence.
-Most probably the organism in a deeper level was not really... because epileptic
fits are not every day. That means if you let an epileptic person for a period of
6 months, he may not have anything at all. In 6 months he has an epileptic fit and
then again after 6 months and then maybe later on every 3 months, every 1 month...
If you observe the development of such cases you may assess the severity of epilepsy
because what you are saying is a problem also I have seen with other homeopaths...
A.G. one of the best prescribers he had his daughter in a state of coma from epileptic
fits, a semi-comatose state for years. You have to be very careful understanding
the severity of the disease by taking carefully the progress...
An epileptic attack which starts and then the next attack is after one month and then
the 3rd attack is after 15 days and then the next attack is after 10 days and then every
day there is a fit, if the progress is so fast you have to be very careful in prescribing
because you may expect at a certain moment he may go into status epilepticus.
You may say people are not going in status epilepticus. Of course they go
under allopathic drugs and also die under allopathic drugs.
You see one case tortured you for years because this happened but you did the best
you could actually, you let this child live for a period of time in a good condition.
But you have to be careful assessing the severity of disease by the progress that was
there before and be more aware. Do not feel comfortable when there is no repetition
of the epileptic fits... Ok, one year no epileptic fit, still you have to be aware.
That means attend the case, see whether the other symptomatology is presenting
another remedy, maybe you give it and a great confirmation is when you have acutes
with high fever during that and I have seen when treating epileptic cases immediately
after the right remedy, then high fever comes and that's a good sign.
The case is doing quite well. The case we saw of Crohn's disease, gave correct remedy
and fever was immediately there and that's why the child is curable.
It's almost already cured but what is left will be cured with Carbo vegetabilis and
then Medorrhinum. After Medorrhinum will be totally cured.