Here I have a question because
I spoke about hydrogen
and somebody write here what about North
Pole, South Pole, electricity, x-ray etc...?
It is true that in M.M. there are supposed
to be provings of North Pole and South Pole.
I consider them as
totally... wrong.
There is no question that we
cannot have any provings.
Hahnemann by himself... I don't know what
he meant and how this came to the M.M.
but it is not possible to have a
proving of the electromagnetic field
of the South or North Pole.
It doesn't matter what.
When a man has to do so much as Hahnemann
it's possible that he gives some information
which come from one of
his students or friends.
He incorporates but it is not
possible under any circumstances
that there can be a proving of the
electromagnetic field of South or North Pole.
Also Luna is in the M.M.
What is the proving of Luna?
Somebody was lying under the light of the
Luna for several nights. He became lunatic!
What else can I say? Am I to prove Luna
and to say these are the symptoms of Luna
and if somebody has these symptoms
you give Luna? It is lunatic!
It is a matter of you being out
of your mind! This is a science.
Of course people have great imagination
and their imagination is creative
and I understand all that but logic
also should prevail in our science.
Otherwise it is not going to be
accepted from anybody as science.
Because many times
people have said that.
How did you prove South Pole, Luna?
I said I did not prove it myself.
Some lunatics have proved it.
Do you believe that there is
somebody else living today
that believes more in what Hahnemann
has said, done or taught than me?
I don't believe
there is anybody.
If I who have seen applied all what
Hahnemann said and there are some point
to which I do not agree not
because I don't like it but
because experience had shown to me that.
Maybe I have seen much more cases than him.
It's natural because I practice more years
than him and I had a group of doctors.
I was getting a lot
of information.
If my information is such that is
contrary to what he says I have to tell.
Like this. South, North Pole etc.
Don't believe.
I will tell you the truth.
Before I said this many years ago when I had a
case where it showed the absolute symptoms,
it was a clear case, in spite of
logic I will give this remedy
because it looks so similar to what is
written in the books, so I gave the remedy
but there was almost no effect.
Came back.
Then I gave another remedy and
of course there was a cure.
But at a certain point I
tried it, against my logic.
There was a dispute because I criticized
these things with some other homeopaths.
So in the Journal "Links" it was written that
after all we don't have to prove a remedy,
we have to write the name of the
remedy with a glass of water over it,
leave it 10 minutes and then drink
it and then it is Lycopodium 10M.
You wrote Lycopodium 10M,
you drink Lycopodium 10M.
This is going as far as this.
Then I criticized this.
I criticized an experiment
which was supposed
to be done by the biggest allergiologist
of the world. Benveniste.
And he was in Bermuda and he said to 25
scientists of different types of professions,
not only medical, and said I have
found something extraordinary.
He said I found out that with the poison of
the bee there is degranulation of basophils.
And I saw something which I have
to tell you that is beyond belief.
That when I did not give the poison
itself but I gave a potency of 15CH,
that means much beyond the Avogadro
number and people were like this.
I said wait a moment. That is not possible
and he started a controversy after that.
As a result it was proved
that he could not show
that there is a degranulation
of basophils by 15CH.
It was not possible because he
was saying that high potency
could bring about a deep pathological
disturbance. It can destroy the cells.
If this was the case every wrong remedy
we'd give would destroy the organism.
He was saying
something outrageous.
Yet people still believe today
that he may be correct.
I don't understand how
they believe this.
You see the problem with Homeopathy
because it enters the area of energy,
a lot of craziness is injected
into the whole theory.
Another question says whether the vaccination
increases the possibility of homosexuality.
I do not know. I
cannot say that.
All I can say is that homosexuality has
increased tremendously in our times
but I do not know whether it is because of
the vaccination or the pollution or culture
or different other factors and people are
born with tendency to homosexuality.
They cannot help it.
If they are born
with that tendency,
that means with that imbalance in their
hormonal profile, they have no chance.
They have to suppress themselves,
go to the monastery or whatever
or they have to practice homosexuality
because they are attracting the same gender.
People I have spoken with,
a lot of times they said,
since childhood I could have
fantasies with the same sex.
Does it change? That means there is
somewhere some problems we are causing
that disturb the
hormonal profile.
Because it is the hormonal
profile I suspect that the drugs
which are used for cleaning the plants,
these substances which they spray,
contain hormones of the particular
insect which affects the fruit.
Because the hormone attracts the male
and is caught and killed in the trap.
I believe that the widely spread hormonal
substances for killing the insects of the trees
and fruits have affected
people hormonally.
This is an idea you
may take or leave.
You may investigate it if you
are interested to find out
which are the substances
exactly who have hormones.
But definitely there is a problem
and these people are suffering
because of this condition.
Any other question?
All these paragraphs concern
instructions for provings
and tell me after you have read
this paragraphs if there is anybody
who is supposed to do a proving
has taken not all these measures
but half of them of what he says? And the
way he says the proving must be conducted.
There are provings... take a potency... take
a remedy and tell us what happened.
Is that possible? If the enemies
wanted to destroy Homeopathy
that is the way they would do it.
Inject nonsense to the system.
Once you do that people will be confused
and the system will be finished
unless we stay pure of what is the correct
thing forget Homeopathy in 20 years.
Homeopathy will be diluted
with a lot of nonsense.
125."During all the time the experiment
lasts the diet must be strictly regulated..."
Who, is of these people who are
doing proving, regulating the diet?
"...it should be as much as
possible destitute of spices,
of a purely nutritious and simple
character, green vegetables...
Young green peas, green French
beans ('boiled potatoes')
and in all cases carrots are allowable,
as the least medicinal vegetables."
So precise information.
If you eat spice or food that excites the
organism it will interfere with the experiment.
And he mentions some food
that existed by that time.
"...drinks are to be those usually partaken
of, as little stimulating as possible".
Coca cola, not allowed. Retsina, not allowed.
Brandy, you know all these spiritual things.
In the note he says "The subject of
experiment must either be not in the habit
of taking pure wine,
brandy, coffee or tea,
or he must have totally abstained
for a considerable time previously
from the use of these injurious beverages, some
of which are stimulating, others medicinal."
Either you declare that I don't
drink coffee, tea, beer etc.
or you abstain for one month before
you can enter the experiment.
You see how serious
this science is.
That is exactly what should be followed if we
want to claim that we are applying a science.
Otherwise we apply hocus pocus.
I like to do this, I like to put
the water over the scriptures
and say you take now
the New Testament...
126."The person who is proving the medicine
must during the whole time of the experiment
avoid all over-exertion of mind and body, all
sorts of dissipation and disturbing passions;
he should have no urgent business
to distract his attention;
he must devote himself to careful self-observation
and not be disturbed while so engaged..."
If you read these instructions you
will understand that the people
who did the original provings were
entirely devoted to this task.
They had a vision, an enthusiasm, an
initiative inside them to discover.
By the time of Hahnemann they were discovering
the best possible tool for curing people.
They had the feeling I am
doing such a serious task.
All their mind, attention, everything
was devoted to this task to discover
and to unfold the medicinal
powers of the drugs.
Otherwise can anybody tell
me that you can apply this?
Find me a group of people to
apply all these instructions.
Only those who really believe that by
proving a remedy they will be discovering
one more possibility for
certain sick people.
That with this remedy it might be that
some people are going to be cured.
So we are going to give to the world a
new possibility for few more people
but it really is a possibility.
Not a fantasy.
It came slowly to believe that all
this is nonsense, Hahnemann is older,
forget him and now we have
the modern fantasy provings.
We reached the point where some homeopath
who followed my teaching for 10 years,
finally said you don't
need to prove a remedy.
You have to imagine what it can do
and this was accepted by people
which is pathetic for me.
My training is such, you know
I don't accept nonsense.
Because if you are 10 years
old and you have to survive,
you know what is right and what is wrong.
And you have to do what you have to do.
Not playing nonsense.
I was in that position, my parents left me
so you are alone, so you have to survive.
The same way I feel
with Homeopathy.
When I came to Homeopathy and saw the nonsense
that was going on I said you are alone,
Homeopathy must survive.
Then of course I started the fight
and the pharmaceutical industry
was the first one to
attack, we must kill you.
It's a big pharmaceutical company and they
come and say who needs George? Kill him.
I was going to meet the manager of a big
homeopathic pharmaceutical company,
and the other from the other pharmaceutical
company said I am going to meet George
and said just kill him! He told me.
Not directly.
He said to one of my students
and my student told me.
I'm testing my voice!
I had to fight against first
the pharmaceutical industry
and I said to them
what you do is wrong.
I also know that you cannot survive
if everybody takes only one dose,
one remedy or a few doses.
You cannot survive.
But what I do gives you prestige
to the world so you can survive
because people will still
believe in Homeopathy.
If you continue only with your system
Homeopathy will totally disappear.
In 1960 when I came into Homeopathy it was practiced
by very few people only with specialties.
It has already been out of the picture
as a medical therapeutic modality.
In few years it would finish,
nobody would know about Homeopathy.
One owner of a big company came to
meet me and said you must respect us.
We respect you and you
have to respect us.
I said to him respect is earned, if you
earn my respect I will give it to you
but don't ask my respect. I cannot give it.
I know you are doing wrong.
You are making specialties and you
say these will cure this and that
which is not true
and you know it.
He came to the meeting and told to my
secretary that George gave me a cold shower.
Of course! Later they said we must kill
you... This is the big argument that,
because of the miraculous cures
classical homeopaths are able to do,
the prestige of Homeopathy has
raised and these people can claim
we are producing homeopathic remedies.
Otherwise they would close down.
It's because of us.
"...he must devote himself to careful
self-observation and not be disturbed
while so engaged; his body must be in
what is for him a good state of health,
and he must possess a sufficient amount
of intelligence to be able to express
and describe his sensations
in accurate terms."
At least you have enough intelligence,
don't tell nonsense please!
I have bought it 15 years ago from an
airport, 10 euros and it's 1 degree.
Now I need the next generation!
Still it works but not very well.
This German makes good remarks.
I pay special attention
to her.- Thank you.
It's more a remark
than a question.
I've been to the center council
of homeopathic research
and they are doing a lot of drug provings
and they try to get the healthiest provers.
I have one remark.
They have different scales
for choosing the sensibility
which might not be good enough but
maybe you could get in touch with them
and tell them about the idea of not
giving high potencies to all of them
because I was sitting with
them and telling them...
- Where is this group?
- In Delhi.
But every homeopathic college
now has to do drug provings
and they have a format, guidelines to
follow... I saw how they perform it.
They do exactly that.
They have only students...
- With whom did you speak to
know that they are doing it?
- They head of the council
of homeopathic research.
And I attained the session of the drug proving
committee from all the place over India.
Not all of them but... Those who are
performing the drug proving in the colleges.
And I saw the format.
-What would be important is
to speak with the provers.
Because there is
the final truth.
When I went and spoke with a prover
I found out what was going on.
People were speaking to each other,
wake up and relate their experiences,
what dream did you see etc.
There was a report of a thing
like that with a control.
Half were the control and half were taking.
And they had seen dreams.
They take the dreams of the control
and the dreams of the provers.
They said we found out that
their dreams are similar.
How do you explain this? The drug
was influencing the placebo group
through electromagnetic fields,
so they got similar dreams.
Is this an explanation? I said I
will give another explanation.
The provers and also the
placebo felt nothing.
They had similar things because
none of them made a difference.
That's the explanation.
- They don't have
enough symptoms.
But are proving 12CH, 30CH and
200CH with a placebo line as well.
So it might interesting
to speak to them...
- They will not listen to me.
Just write them a letter and say why
don't you come in contact with me
and I will tell them my
opinion, what they should do.
- When I was doing my post-graduation this
law was implemented into the colleges
and I have seen one proving
being done in my college
where I was doing my post-graduation
and it was really the worst.
It has absolutely nothing to do what they do
in the colleges with what the council says.
Because the central council of Homeopathy
and the council of research in Homeopathy
are doing good work but the grass root level
the reality is something totally different.
9 out of 10 provings are done
either by juniors or seniors.
I saw all of them very closely and for a period
of 3 months it was absolutely non existing!
There was no day book, they used to smoke...
Only 10% was done according the guidelines.
- I feel the only way that a proving can
be done is only by idealistic people
who are devoted to this idea and can
really devote themselves to this task.
Unless this inner urge to do
this comes from the inside
to impose a proving to a
class like that, forget it.
That is why I am so furious when
I see every day a new proving.
Is it easy to make a proving...?
127."The medicines must be tested
on both males and females,
in order also to reveal the alterations of the
health they produce in the sexual sphere."
128."The most recent observations
have shown that medicinal substances,
when taken in their crude
state by the experimenter
for the purpose of testing
their peculiar effects,
do not exhibit nearly the full amount
of the powers that lie hidden in them
which they do when they are taken for the
same object in high dilutions potentized
by proper trituration and succussion,
by which simple operations the powers
which in their crude state lay
hidden, and, as it were, dormant,
are developed and roused into
activity to an incredible extent.
In this manner we now find it best
to investigate the medicinal powers
even of such substances as are deemed weak, and
the plan we adopt is to give to the experimenter,
on an empty stomach, daily from
four to six very small globules
of the thirtieth potentized dilution of such
a substance, moistened with a little water,
and let him continue this for several
days" What he says is very simple.
He says that if you take only the
crude form you will have symptoms
but not the full extent of the possibility
of that drug to produce symptoms.
The last years we have come to the habit
of proving a high potency up to the 30th
in order to get the more
subtle aspects of the drug.
129."If the effects that result
from such a dose are but slight,
a few more globules may be taken daily, until
they become more distinct and stronger
and the alterations of the
health more conspicuous;
for all persons are not effected by a
medicine in an equally great degree;
on the contrary, there is a
vast variety in this respect,
so that sometimes an apparently weak
individual may by scarcely at all
affected by moderate doses of a medicine
known to be of a powerful character,
while he is strongly enough acted
on by others of a much weaker kind."
There is here again a
misconception of Hahnemann.
He says if the dose that you take, one
dose of 30th potency, is not enough,
does not show enough, give a
little bit more globules.
Giving more globules is not giving
more remedy in the 30th potency.
For 30th potency you drink
globules of one cup
or you take 3 globules it
is the same, one dose.
In reality either you take
a whole bottle of 30th,
you have not taken a large dose, you have
taken just one dose of 30th potency.
Because there are no molecules
left in these dilutions.
Whether you take a few globules or
1000 globules it's the same, one dose.
Hahnemann still has this
material idea of remedies.
"If the effects that result from
such a dose are but slight,
a few more globules
may be taken daily".
And he says something
which is also true.
It's strange how he has noticed
that one dose of a weak remedy,
a weak remedy means that the
remedy comes from a substance
that does not affect the human organism, a
plant, that is considered a weak substance,
such a weak substance he says you
give a dose to a weak organism
and has no effect and you give it to a
strong organism and you may have an effect.
Which is true. But he confuses here the
action of the remedy with quantity...
It's not quantity, it's
quality of the drugs.
When you potentize beyond a
certain potency 12X I think,
chemistry know there is not
one molecule in the solvent.
Therefore what you are giving
after the 12X is pure energy.
The particular energy
structure of the drug.
You don't give
quantity but quality.
- I do not really get this.
If the remedy is an energy, there
is such a thing as too much energy
and little energy, so you speak of
quantity also in terms of energy.
- You see energy is supposed to be in
different types, we have electric etc.
Here we are talking about a new type
of energy, we don't know the energy
that comes from the plant.
Also we do not know exactly
the energy of the body.
So what we are dealing with here,
is an energy of substances
which have been processed and have arrived
at a state of becoming open energy
with certain qualities which is
going to affect another energy,
the nature which is
also not investigated.
I do not know if you confused the electric
energy for instance with that energy
or electromagnetic produced by a machine
where you can the amount of energy,
with these kinds of energies where
machines are producing electric energy,
electromagnetic fields etc.
out of machines can be
speaking about increasing
or decreasing the quantity of the
energy in a way. Not with this.
We do not have the possibility to
increase the energy with the meaning
we know we can do with
other types of energy.
What is really happening? We have to
investigate. It is a big subject.
What we are doing? We are matching an
energy of a body with the energy of a drug.
Here the opposite happens of what
usually happens in quantity.
We know that as we reduce the amount of
material substance the more we reduce it
the more active the
remedy becomes.
So a 10M potency is more
powerful than a 30CH.
But this 10M has been reduced more and
more as far as quantity is concerned.
That means the original material substance.
With this idea we enter another concept.
We have now to deal
with levels of energy.
Levels of subtle energy
and more and more subtle.
This is the idea here
with Homeopathy.
Ideally each one of us is performing
in a level of subtle energy .
The level my organism is functioning is on an
energy scale that we measure with potencies.
It is performing in 777 potency.
My performance, disturbance,
is functioning on 925 potency.
So when I get a 200 is too low, it is
going to last for a short period of time.
Then I go to 1M which is over
the 925 that I am functioning
and then I remain for a
longer period of time.
When I go to 1M still there is relapse.
I have to go higher.
Then 50000 or CM and
then you get a picture.
There is a level of energy on which
each one of us is functioning
and needs a particular potency.
Nobody ever can find the
exact potency that we need.
More or less we assume.
When we say 200CH will not
give big aggravation,
we mean if he is functioning
on 250CH and I give 200CH
is going to have an effect
but not entirely, not cured.
If I give a 50M it may be
too far with no effect.
If I give 10M still may
create a big aggravation.
That is why we avoid the big
aggravations in pathology stage.
We say go first to 200CH, 30CH
to find if the pathology is deep
and then proceed further
with a higher potency.
Sometimes I experiment with potencies
like 30CH, 34CH, 35CH sometimes
I see there is a relapse...
jump to 200CH, 250CH there
is still a relapse, 1M ok
there is a time when the person remains
steady and is supposed to be cured.
Is this clear or you still
have some questions?
- It seems to me that we
are speaking of something
that is very close to the border
between energy and information
and it is like a switch
on and off mechanism.
Once I reach the switching
on it's working,
if I don't reach the resonance
of switching is not working.
- But strangely enough there
is a limit that means
in a case this limit of
reacting is from 12 to 1000,
within this limit whatever you give is
going to react. But the best would be 1M.
In another person the limit
is between 30CH and 50M.
Whatever potency you give
between these is going to act
but again it will need a repetition
until you strike a potency
which is beyond the one which is
functioning. This is experience.
- In 128 the dilution of 3 or 4 globuli
maybe the quality of perception
is different when you get it in
water because the amount of nerves
that come in contact with
the information is bigger
or why does he mention
that water thing?
- "The most recent observations"
you see here what he says,
we have been doing experiments
with material doses.
Most of the information in Hahnemann's M.M.
come from provings from small material doses.
In the 6th edition he says "The
most recent observations have shown
that medicinal substances, when taken in
their crude state by the experimenter"
do not show all their
possibilities so we found out
that we can have some more
information about these drugs
by proving them in higher potency up to
the 30th. Your question is about water.
- It's about the end. Where
the 4 to 6 globuli appear.
He also continues that...- He gives
importance to the globuli.
- And to the water I think.
Make wet with water first, then it's
diluted with water, and drink it.
- What I wanted to point out
in your attention is the fact
that in spite the fact that Hahnemann
is talking about high potency provings
still he gives importance to the
quantity which does not exist.
The quantity does not exist when
you pass the 12X or 18X or 12CH.
once you pass this number quantity
is not of importance anymore.
But Hahnemann still having
proven all the time the remedies
with material doses he still believes
that if you give more globuli
even in higher potency
will have a better effect.
That means if I take a
whole bottle of globuli
it will have a more powerful effect than
if I take a few globuli. This is not true.
- I do understand that exactly but
he continues after these globuli
saying that he puts them
in water and I wonder...
- This is his experience,
the diluting in water.
My experience is when I take a few globuli
and you have the water up to here
and stir up these few globulis inside this
water and you take a sip of this water
it seems that all the molecules of the water
have absorbed the energy of the drug.
So it is a matter of an energy, a subtle
energy of an unknown type for us,
still nobody can know, but still
when a few globuli are diluted
and all the molecules of the water
become potent and you take one sip,
you have taken one dose. If drink the
whole water you have taken one dose.
If you sip the water
constantly you take one dose.
- I wonder if the perception
is different if you drink it
or if you take as a globuli.
I mean if you drink something
it gets everywhere in the mouth
and maybe there is a quality
difference in perception
of the information
of the remedy.
The perception, how you get it into you.
How you get the information.
- If somebody is in a coma state and as I
was saying the other day with the woman
who was lying in a coma and I said
take this water and put it over,
the moment the water comes in contact with
the mucus membrane then it has acted.
It needs some sensitive parts
of the body with nerve endings
because I believe the nervous system
is of great importance
because if you give it to the skin,
the skin protects, it will not act
but if you go to the skin
which is in the armpits
where the skin is quite sensitive and
between mucus membranes it may still act.
The interesting thing is somewhere
he says that you can smell a remedy
and still have an effect.
The remedy has to be in alcohol
and with the evaporation of
molecules from the alcohol
and smell it, then there is
the energy of the remedy.
So if you found a very close remedy or the
exact remedy you may smell the potency
and have quite a
strong reaction.
Aphorism 24. Read
- "Besides the tongue,
mouth and stomach,
which are most commonly affected
by the administration of medicine,
the nose and respiratory organs are receptive
of the action of medicines in fluid form
by means of olfaction and
inhalation through the mouth."
- You said that if we take many sips
from the cup it is still one dose.
- Every sip is one dose.
- So if I take 20 sips...
-You take 20 doses.
So in this case when you have
for instance an acute condition
where you have to repeat frequently
you ask the people to do that.
The problem is that if they are not
careful, if they don't do it properly,
if sometimes you have to hit quite
strongly in order to dissolve this pills.
It's not so easy.
But if you do it properly, each time
you take a sip you take a dose.
If you take 20 sips
it's 20 doses.
- At once?- Not at once.
I take one sip now. In the
afternoon I take another sip.
- How much have these
sips to be separated?
- It depends on the intensity
of the acute condition.
If you have very high fever
with spasm, fever convulsions
then every 5 or 10 minutes
you have to take it.
Wait 5 minutes and then take it, wait
another 5 minutes then take on more dose...
In dengue fever in India I
had to give it every 3 hours
because I could see if they
waited longer than 3 hours
then there was a relapse of the fever.
I told them to drink it every 3 hours.
Sometimes you have to repeat every
2 hours in order to control.
- I am treating many dengue fevers and
I was asking myself if I am wrong
with this but I never treated
so often like 3 hours.
- You are a little bit
shy and you speak.
- I said I see many dengue, chikungunya,
tropical fevers. In Thailand.
- In chikungunya you have
to give every 2 hours.
- I didn't know, thank you.
- Another question? Canada!
- You said that after
12X...- No 12X, 12CH.
I said 12X and then I
corrected it 12CH.
After 12CH it is going
beyond Avogadro number.
You see everyone is trying
to catch me in something...
- No George I was
trying to make sure.
- I am open to admit.
If I made mistake I am going to
say I made a mistake. No problem.
That's why I am not offended if
somebody tell me you are wrong.
We were discussing with another
doctor on the word of accouchement.
In my book there was not coma
so I read sexual accouchement.
Since Hahnemann was talking about
situations you have to be aware of
and if that is a situation it may
be natural to have a symptom,
a situation when somebody
is during menses etc.
I thought accouchement means
most probably indulgence in sex.
Indulgence in sex could give a
symptomatology that if you stop,
simply, symptoms go away. You
don't need to give a remedy.
This is what he says.
In some situations, wait, the
situation will pass or advise
and you don't need
to give a remedy.
I have explained this wrongly
as sexual indulgence.
I know none of you is doing
this, so there's no problem.
- You said before that for
example there can be a case
where any potency between 6C
and 10M will have an effect.
But the optimum will be 1M.
That means the beyond 10M there
will be no effect at all
or that any potency beyond
10M could be dangerous?
In old books like Kent says that
in certain cases it's dangerous
to start with high potencies.
That's my question.
- Experience has shown that sometimes
when you give a very high potency
there is no effect. You give
200CH and there is effect.
This is one experience.
Another experience has shown
that you give in a case 10M
and there is a big reaction,
perhaps unnecessary.
If you had given a lower potency the
reaction might have been better.
Therefore since we do not know
beforehand what is the optimum potency
we go carefully investigating
the organism. Take 1M.
Good reaction, I remain well
for 5 years, that was good.
But good reaction and after 2
months I am back. Ok go 10M.
So also the 200CH, 1M, 10M etc are
steps arbitrarily set by Kent.
Kent was the one who said
most probably after 1M
you need quite a higher potency
in order to have an effect.
So he said it but at the same time
the potencies during that time
were done not in a
very proper manner.
Because Hahnemann never
thought of such potencies.
It was impossible to think. He was
thinking of 30CH and that was the end.
I think maybe he tried one
or two time with 60CH.
But it was beyond any limit. Kent
experimented with much higher potencies.
The Fincke potencies
as he calls.
They were made by jets, by having
the substance potentized up to 30CH
and after that the tube with the
liquid goes in front of a machine
which injects with great force
an equal amount of water
that is already in the bottle. The water
will jump out new water is inside.
So even doing so there was a
possibility of transferring the energy
to the molecules of the water.
I don't understand how.
I consider it as not the
proper way of potentization.
Maybe some of you know that I have
given my ideas how to make a robot
so the robot could
potentize properly.
It would hit 10 times, empty, fill, again
potentize 10000 times, 50000 times...
In order to make a 50000 in
this way it needed 2 months.
The robot working day and night. That
would be very expensive potency.
The 50 potency. But once
they made 50000 potency.
From that they could make
as much as they wanted.
So after that they sell
and they can make profit.
So this company was a multinational
company that got involved
with machines of dialysis
and also saline solutions.
They were selling a lot for wars
in Iraq, Iran, became huge company
and most probably they wanted
to have a company in which...
I don't know how but they approached me.
They thought it's good business to make.
Tell us how to make good potencies. We have
the technology, we can build the robot.
I said ok bring me the people.
So a team of people came, we
discussed, they produced the robot,
at first the robot was breaking all
the glasses, they corrected it
and then after 9 months
they produced a real robot.
Then I told the students then the
students from different countries
started writing to this company
please I need this remedy. No answer.
Everyone was complaining, I will write
to Cziffra and there was no answer.
I asked them what happens and they
said that according to the Italian law
we are not allowed to sell outside
from Italy this potencies.
I don't know why but in any case
something was wrong with the company
and the chief men went to
jail, sold the company
and this company was bought by
somebody else and then somebody else...
And I am trying to trace who has
my robots and I can't find!
At least give me back the robots!
But I can reproduce the robots.
Now they approached me again.
Give us the parameters and we
will produce a robot again.
And I believe I will do it
before I leave this world.
I have to make sure that the remedies which are
prescribed are really potentized remedies.
We have to make sure.
Because you give a 10M
and there is no effect.
How do I know that this is not a well-prepared
remedy or a spoiled remedy or junk?
- I wanted to ask about your experience
in high potency of Hahnemannian method
or Korsakoff method.-
Korsakoff method is perfect.
You don't have to
do Hahnemann's.
Hahnemann means that you have
to empty and use another bottle
and take one drop from this bottle, put
it in the new, shake it, take it one,
empty, throw it away... That means you
will need thousands of little bottles
and would mean you need
double distilled water.
So this is not practical.
So the remedies I was using from
this company were really reliable
and were giving
very good results.
If a company say that they are doing
it by hand then I have a problem.
That they don't tell the truth.
These remedies cannot be done
in such high potencies by hand.
Because I have tried myself for a
certain person that I loved very much,
I could not find the remedy and I
tried to make the remedy myself.
And I reached up to 12CH and I broke
my arm because I was hitting too hard.
Can you imagine doing it 1000 times?
You hit 10 times
and you have done one time
and then... 1000 by 20 times
that you will have
to hit this 20000.
Then if your arm still remains in
your shoulder then... good luck!
So if they tell me this is a very good company
because it produces by hand. I say bye.
- In paragraph 269 and 270 Hahnemann describes
how you should do it by hand LM potencies.
And so those potencies in Germany
there are 2 or 3 factories.
- 269 and 270."Thus two drops of
the fresh vegetable juice mingled
with equal parts of alcohol are diluted
with ninety-eight drops of alcohol
and potentized by means of two succussions,
whereby the first development of power
is formed and this process is repeated
through twenty-nine more phials,
each of which is filled three-quarters
full with ninety-nine drops of alcohol,
and each succeeding phial is to be provided
with one drop from the preceding phial..."
This is what the call
Hahnemannian potency.
And there is story if you do the Hahnemannian
potency and you do it up to 12CH
then it is equal to 200CH.
The pharmacies say so in order to
sell the potencies. This is not true.
More or less the potency is the same
whether it is made by changing the phials
or by emptying and filling because when you
empty and you turn it back on the tube
there is one drop left of the sides so by
refilling it you have this mixture quite good,
not only that but according to a study that
we have done and published back in the 1980s,
you may find it in my website, we have
found out according to a theory in physics
which is for small clusters, when
the dilution of substance is done
then the molecules tend to stick
to the periphery of the vial.
They don't stay floating around.
They stick.
That was an idea which gave us that
the Korsakoff method is quite good.
Because in the periphery stuck on
the glass are the most clusters,
that means groups of molecules, in
the beginning and as it goes on
there are clathrates
that means a kind of...
Instead of the real molecules the clathrates
seems to have the structure of the molecule
without the molecule.
The molecule is now missing but what is left
is the clathrates that means... Hologram.
They call in
clathrates in physics.
This is what most probably happens in
potentizing with this kind of potentization.
This is one problem that I have
in my mind, we have to solve,
to have standardized quality
of the homeopathic remedies.
If everybody follows the same rules then
we have a standardized homeopathic remedy.
Otherwise each one following
his own rules... it's no good.
You may see an effect
with the one or the other
but still we don't have a
standardized type of medication.