109."I was the first that opened up this path,
which I have pursued with a perseverance
that could only arise and be kept up by a
perfect conviction of the great truth,
fraught with such blessings
to humanity, that it is only
by the homoeopathic
employment of medicines
that the certain cure of
human maladies is possible."
You see how certain he is only
on that point we discuss before.
Of course he mentions here another
German Albrecht von Haller
who actually had said the same thing,
he was earlier than Hahnemann,
that medicines should be
tested in healthy individuals.
"I saw, moreover, that the morbid lesions
which previous authors had observed
to result from medicinal substances when
taken into the stomach of healthy persons,
either in large doses
given by mistake
or in order to produce death
in themselves or others"
he has taken all the toxic effects from
suicides, people trying to kill each other
by giving a certain substance and then
there were reports of these accidents.
He says I have taken all "or
under other circumstances,
accorded very much with my own observations
when experimenting with the same substances
on myself and other
healthy individuals."
What he did was he read the reports from
the toxic effects of the substances
and then he took them himself and gave it
to his group as well in subtoxic doses
and he says what they recorded in
their reports in the people poisoned
by these substances are in
accordance to my observations
when I took these medications
myself and the other doctors.
"These authors give details of what
occurred as histories of poisoning
and as proofs of the pernicious
effects of these powerful substances,
chiefly in order to warn
others from their use".
These authors reported these effects to
prevent other from taking these drugs
in order not to be poisoned.
"partly also for the sake of
exalting their own skill"
they gave the report to prevent
others from taking the drugs
but also they wanted to present their
own skills to the scientific community.
He's very critical. He
leaves nothing out.
"partly also for the sake of exalting their own
skill, when, under the use of the remedies
they employed to combat these dangerous
accidents, health gradually returned;
but partly also, when the persons so
affected died under their treatment,
in order to seek their own justification in
the dangerous character of these substances"
Partly they wanted to save these people
from death because they were treating them
and of course some of them died and
then they named them poisonous.
It's the beginning
of the toxicology.
He gives his opinion about the
doctors who have treated such cases
and who gave reports of their
symptomatology before they die
or when they tried to save them most probably
giving some very primitive drugs, herbs
and finally if the people
who took the substance died
then they termed these
substances poisonous.
This is the beginning of the M.M.
as you all know.
"None of these observers ever
dreamed that the symptoms
they recorded merely as proofs of the noxious
and poisonous character of these substances
were sure revelations of
the power of these drugs
to extinguish curatively similar
symptoms occurring in natural disease".
They never imagined that these drugs
that were describing as symptoms
could be the drugs that would save
life eventually. They did not suspect.
"these drugs to extinguish curatively similar
symptoms occurring in natural disease,
that these their pathogenetic phenomena were
intimations of their homoeopathic curative action,
and that the only possible way to
ascertain their medicinal powers
is to observe those changes of health
medicines are capable of producing
in the healthy organism".
He repeats the same thing, these were the
possibilities through these symptoms
they produce that will
cure such symptoms.
"for the pure, peculiar powers of medicines
available for the cure of disease
are to be learned neither by any ingenious
a priori speculations" This is important.
For the pure, peculiar powers of
drugs which have the power to cure
cannot be learned a
priori by speculations.
Don't use your imagination
to say that this drug
is going to produce
this and that symptom.
There are some homeopaths who claim that
we don't have to prove the remedies.
We just have to imagine and
they have written M.M.
And they say this comes from the imagination
and just imagine what this remedy may do.
Let us say I give you a remedy and I say
to you this is the remedy Radium bromatum
so you hear Radium, radiation, bromatum
and I tell you can you imagine
and write down for me what
symptoms could be produced.
Even if you have some idea
what radiation can produce,
even then each one of you would
write a different story.
You take all these different stories and
you make a M.M. of an imaginary remedy.
So he seems to have predicted
how crazy we could be.
"and that the only possible way to
ascertain their medicinal powers
is to observe those changes of health
medicines are capable of producing"
this is the only way that you can
learn the action of the remedies.
And he says something else
that you learn the drug
"...for the pure, peculiar powers of [..]
[..] nor by the smell, taste or appearance of
the drugs, nor by their chemical analysis"
which is done with conventional
medicine actually.
"...nor yet by the employment of
several of them at one time
in a mixture (prescription) in
diseases; it was never suspected
that these histories
of medicinal diseases
would one day furnish the first rudiments
of the true, pure Materia Medica,
which from the earliest times until now
has consisted solely of false conjectures
and fictions of the imagination - that
is to say, did not exist at all."
He says that all the herbs that we have
been using so far in our medical practices
are coming purely imaginations,
myths, tales, smells,
because it smells like that you give this,
because it has that colour you give that,
this was the type of medicine that was
practised during his time so he criticized it
and he said the only way to learn
the action of a drug is to prove it
on healthy individuals. That is
the only way, there is no other.
No signatures, no
imagination, no nonsense.
"The agreement of my observations
on the pure effects of medicines
with these older ones - although
they were recorded without reference
to any therapeutic object, - and the
very concordance of these accounts
with others of the same kind by different
authors must easily convince us
that medicinal substances act in
the morbid changes they produce
in the healthy human body according
to fixed, eternal laws of nature".
I am convinced by these old
experiments that have been going on
and by my own experience that these drugs
are curing people according to fixed,
eternal laws of nature.
"...and by virtue of these are
enabled to produce certain,
reliable disease symptoms each according to its
own peculiar character." This is very simple.
"In those older prescriptions of the
often dangerous effects of medicines
ingested in excessively large doses we
notice certain states that were produced,
not at the commencement, but towards
the termination of these sad events,
and which were of an exactly opposite
nature to those that first appeared"
I'll read it all and then I will explain
you what it means in my own words
but if somebody claims that he understands
this paragraph please tell me.
"These symptoms, the very reverse
of the primary action (par. 63)
or proper action of the medicines on the vital
force are the reaction of the vital force
of the organism, its
secondary action (par.par. 62-67),
of which, however, there is seldom or hardly
ever the least trace from experiments
with moderate doses on healthy bodies,
and from small doses none whatever.
In the homoeopathic curative operation
the living organism reacts from these
only so much as is requisite to raise the health
again to the normal healthy state (par. 67)."
If anybody understands
this... you tell me.
- Here Dr.Hahnemann claims about the primary
action and the secondary action of the drug.
He said as explained in the
previous aphorism that a medicine
mostly given in higher doses as a poison
or for proving a drug the patient
used to get symptoms
of the medicines...
- No, don't get excited. Speak slowly
so we can understand what you are say.
You speak slowly
very good like this.
- Here Dr.Hahnemann wants to explain about the
primary and secondary action of the drug.
As he says in the aphorism 110 (the
previous one which you have explained)
about the high doses of drugs that people
used to take and got poisonous effects
he said those effects were the
primary action of those poisons.
- You explain it and then I will ask
the class if anybody has understood...
I will need a second opinion.
- When the poisons were
taken by the people,
or were given to the physicians
the effect that people
used to get is the primary
effect which everyone noted.
But at the majority of those cases
there were certain symptoms
which all the people ignored they
are actually the secondary reaction
which is the reaction of vital force.This is
very important for us homeopathic physicians
because primary action is of the medicine,
a poison which the person takes
and secondary reaction is the
reaction of the vital force.
I can explain it on the board.
- Come.
- In aphorism 101 we have learned
about the poisonous large doses.
Then when give it to the people,
people die and show many symptoms.
So Hahnemann has said these symptoms were
the primary action of these large doses.
For example if a person was given
acetic acid he had poisoned himself
with acetic acid and he got a set
of symptoms in the hospital.
He termed them as primary action.
But after the termination of this...
- The symptoms from which
he died are primary action?
- Primary action.
After acetic acid he got severe vomiting,
nausea, it is the primary action
and then after the termination of this
illness, after taking the high doses,
the persons get some symptoms at the
termination which were ignored by them,
the physicians, but he
said these symptoms
which they got after the termination of
this poisoning are the secondary action
of the poison. Because it is a
reaction of the vital force.
For example a person took the
poisoning, he got burning sensation
and it is the primary action and the reaction
of the vital force to the burns is vomiting.
Irritation of the throat.
So these are the heritage of the M.M.
what actually we put in M.M.
the reaction of the vital force.
- Good.
Did anybody understand? We
have to make it clearer.
- One last chance.
As we learned in aphorism 101 about
the poisoning with large doses
which you have explained
in this aphorism.
This is primary action of the poison
and a person for example is poisoned
with acetic acid so the reaction of the
body is vomiting, low blood pressure,
and nausea.
This is action of the acetic acid
which he termed as primary action.
But when the large doses went
into the body the vital force
started reacting because if he has taken
something the vital force reacts to it
and then produces a certain set
of symptoms which he termed
as secondary reaction of the vital force
which is actually symptoms of M.M.,
which we should put in the M.M.
and which help in knowing
the chemical drug ad hoc.
- I'll try to explain
what Hahnemann means.
Anything in excess is a poison.
Suppose table salt,
which we use daily.
But the normal quantity of table
salt does not produce symptoms.
But if we take a large quantity of table salt
we will be able to develop some symptoms
which if carefully recorded can
be used for curative purpose.
Now the aphorism says the older prescriptions
of the often dangerous effects of medicines,
this means those medicine which has
been taken in large forms initially
there is not any major kind of symptoms but
more dangerous symptoms are noticed in the end.
So primary action will be that
effect of the drug on vital
and the secondary action will be the
effect of the vital force on the drug.
By this if we risk to produce a
disease state in an individual,
we need to give a small dose of the
homeopathic medicine in order to is requisite
to raise the health again to
the normal healthy state.
This aphorism means primary action
and secondary curative action.
- This is something which I have
understood in a much simpler way.
When anything is inserted in
the body which has an effect
which is not normal like milk, bread,
there is no particular reaction,
but if you insert in your body
which your body does not accept
then your body is going
to have a reaction.
The first reaction that the body will
have will be the primary symptoms
which you can note down.
The beginning of the reaction,
for instance in a poisoning,
will give you some symptoms
which may be functional.
If this poisoning continues to affect the
body eventually it will produce symptoms
which the body will try to eliminate
the poisoning by a reaction
which can be such as
even to bring death.
That means the symptoms which
we should use for the M.M.
and for practical purposes are the primary
reaction. The functional symptoms.
All poisonous substance if
given in a very big quantity,
in the beginning they will have
particular symptoms but in the end
will all have the
same pathology.
That means all substances can
create pathological structures
which are will be considered as secondary
and which could not be used by us
in choosing the remedy. We cannot
choose the remedy on the pathology.
This is the idea.
A poison in small doses can
create a few symptoms.
If you keep on giving the poison the organism
is going to be more and more subdued
and eventually create a
pathological condition
which is going to be
quite deep and serious.
That kind of pathology can be created
by any substance that can be given once
it is in large doses.
What we have to understand is
that the remedy produces symptoms
which are useful for us
not in their end stages
when they bring the
organism towards death.
These symptoms are not useful for us
because all substances will bring death
by certain pathology.
They will have a diarrhea which will
cause bleeding and the person will die.
This is not useful.
What is useful is the primary
reaction of the organism.
I'll give you another example.
You get an influenza and it is a substance
which produces a reaction from the organism.
You have headaches,
muscle pains etc.
But the organism is not able to counteract
through this symptomatology and cure influenza.
So influenza proceeds, that means the
workings of the substance proceeds
and goes deeper to the organism.
There is a point where the body gives up
and the pathology becomes irreversible.
This reaction of the organism can be
considered as a secondary reaction
as long as the poison or
the disease is severe.
You can imagine an influenza
becoming a bronchitis, a pneumonia
and at a certain time the organism is not
able to counteract the pneumonia anymore
and the lungs are filling
quickly with liquid.
That is a reaction which can be considered as
a giving-up but still there is a reaction.
There is still liquid which
is flowing into the lungs.
That reaction which has come about
because the inflammation of the lungs
has become more and more and
there is a flow of liquid,
there is a time where the organism gives
up but still continues to have a reaction,
producing more and more flow, producing
a pathology which is leading to death.
This secondary reaction
which is a reaction
which came after a long struggle of the
organism, is not useful for Homeopathy.
That means that all poisonous substances
are going to have the same end,
the death of the patient
but there is a point until
which there is a possibility for recovery,
the organism is producing symptoms
and tell you I have this and that, save
me, through the symptoms I give you.
Until a time he gives up and says I'm
in coma or filled up with liquid
and it's finished.
That portion, from the portion of the
giving up of the organism further down
is not a useful information
for the homeopathic remedy.
You cannot say this homeopathic drug
can produce ulcerative colitis.
All drugs can produce ulcerative
colitis if given in big dose.
Therefore you cannot say this
drug is going to produce U.C.
which is dangerous for life
because the organism has given up
at certain moment the fight. I still
see some eyes which are not clear.
We have 2 stages.
One is with homeopathic remedies
and their proving symptoms.
The other we have the pathology.
Both the pathology can reach a very severe
state in which the person goes to death,
on the other hand the remedy if given
in big doses can finally reach a state
in which the organism
gives up and dies.
This end-stages, that means before the
turning point, the information is useful.
After the turning point the
information is useless.
What is the turning point in
pathology...is when there is no hope
and the person will die.
Why the person dies? For only one reason,
because the organism is not able to cope
with the pathology which has been created
by the disease or by the medicine.
There is a time when the pathology
cannot be dealt by the organism,
cannot be fought by the
defence mechanism.
I want you to see that point because there
is a lot of discussion about this matter.
Then I will tell you
a few more things.
Because Hahnemann was
not very clear himself
because when you give opium to somebody the
original reaction is to create diarrhea
but after the diarrhea a
secondary state is constipation.
So this is something that has given a
kind of confusion in this paragraph
because if the remedy is not poisonous
to the extent that will kill the patient
he may start with one set of symptoms
and then go to another set of symptoms.
But still the
organism is reacting.
If the poisoning is too much there
is a pushing up to a certain point
the organism fights then
the organism gives up.
Which of the 2 is ... what
Hahnemann means is not clear.
That is why it has been
in such a confusion.
You have to understand all diseases
end in the same pathology.
All poisonous substances end
in the same pathologies.
End stages can be created
by disease or by medicine.
But these end stages which are the
final pathology which a person dies from
is similar to all
diseases and to all remedies.
There is no
individualization any more.
There is no reaction of
the organism any more.
The organism gives up, so there
is no individualization.
It is going to die with certain
pathologies which exist.
Somebody wants to speak.
German.
- I don't think that he is
really talking about the fact
that when the organism comes to a
point where he can't react anymore
that there is a turning point it
is definitely going to death.
Of course every poisoning
can produce every symptom
but some poisons are more prone
to produce certain symptoms
that someone will rely on.
Concerning the Opium it
is the other way round.
The first reaction of the
organism to the example of Opium...
- Let me repeat.
Whether it is primary or secondary
reaction as long as the organism
is able to react, it's useful.
If the poisoning is too
much the person will die.
If the pathology is very
severe the person will die.
We are not interested in differentiating
between primary and secondary reaction.
What we are interested in only
is to know that at this moment
there is no hope anymore because
the organism does not react,
doesn't give symptoms anymore.
- If I understand this correctly
this point of no return is
when the organism is left
alone to fight the disease
so he can compensate the
symptoms up to this point
and when he reaches this point he cannot
compensate anymore but still reacts.
Is it true that if we come to this
point after the point of no return
with the right homeopathic remedy
there is no chance to go back?
- No. Something you
don't understand.
You remember I told you about a
man who was 3 months is a coma,
I went and said forget it he's gone
out of the possibility of Homeopathy.
Then I said ok since you are my
friends I am going to see him
and when I saw him I said I saw some signs
which indicated for me a remedy as a reaction.
And so therefore I felt here
there is a possibility.
On another occasion when I was
treating a rabbi in America in a coma.
I went there. I saw some
signs he could still react.
I gave the remedy
and lived 2 years.
At the age of 94 they called me from
America and they give me symptoms.
They said he was in an operating
room for his gallbladder
and he had his gallbladder out and he
fell into coma again, please come.
I said what are the symptoms? No symptoms.
I said I cannot come there is no reason.
They said please
come, I don't come.
They called again, I said ok then call
one of my students Roger Morrison
and tell him to come there
to give me the symptoms.
Roger Morrison goes there and calls me
and says George it's a matter of 2 days,
he will die. No symptoms. This
is the point of no return.
The first case he was
in coma there were symptoms.
The second time he is in coma
there are no symptoms, forget it.
You do not get the severity of the disease
of the disease by the name of it.
There are still reaction
from the organism.
- But you said that after the point
of no return the organism gives up
but still produces symptoms
which are not effective.
So there are still symptoms but the
organism cannot cope by itself.
- It depends. To have one symptom
which is coma is not good enough.
I told you I have been in the emergency
room with a woman who was operated
and I saw the woman
and I saw some signs.
And the surgeon who was very well known
and a professor of surgery said to me
what can you do in such a case?
I said yes.
What will you do? I said I will
not tell you what I will do
but I will tell you what you must not do.
Stop all the medication and then I will see.
All the Greek doctors know him.
I said to him do you still have hopes
that you will bring back this patient?
Because he operated this patient.
He was the responsible.
He said yes we have not
lost hope, I said goodbye.
If you say that you can bring back this
patient you don't need me. Bye bye.
After a few days he calls
me and says ok you come.
Now what must I do? Just
disappear you and your doctors,
take out all medications and
leave the patient to my care.
The head of the emergency was there
and he was asking different questions
what you are going to give,
we have to write it down,
this is the remedy I am going
to give, write it down.
I expect that she will slowly get out of the
coma, I expect that she will raise fever,
perhaps a high fever but you are not
supposed to give antibiotics or cortisone.
He said ok.
He said how are you going to give
the medication since she is coma?
I will have some water and cotton and the
nurse will put the cotton in the water
and put it in her mouth. He jumped
up and he said you don't tell me
that I studied for 10 years to
be a specialist in the I.U.
and now you tell me you come
with cotton to give the medicine
and the patient will come back.
He was out of his mind.
Never mind, the big boss said I should
take care this is what I have to do.
They started giving the water and
in the night at about 1 a.m.
the fever was raised to 39 C
and the son of this woman
who loved her very much and
I have told him in the I.U.
where everybody is in coma, they will
allow me to come and resurrect a patient
who is dying?
It was Christmas Eve at 1 a.m.
and I was awake.
He calls me and says the nurse
is going now to give antibiotics
because my mother
has fever 39 C.
I am 40km away from the place, even
if I was closer I could do nothing,
the nurse had decided to go and the man
who was sitting next to the mother,
he said to the nurse where are you going?
I have to give injections.
What injections? Cortisone
with antibiotics.
In the meantime she had unbelievable stool
and she started coming out of the coma,
moving hands.
It was from the morning they started the
remedy till 1 a.m. that this happened.
And they give the antibiotics. And of course
the next day she goes back into coma.
And Roger Morrison was studying with
me in Athens, he studied in I.U.
and I told him to go together.
The big professor came with
his 10 doctors following him
and I said to him we had agreed that you
don't give antibiotics and cortisone.
The head of the I.U. gave an order
to the nurse to give antibiotics
and the patient is back in coma.
He said well there was a misunderstanding
he tried to excuse himself
I didn't want to continue but
he pressurized me a lot.
He said try again. I
said ok, I'll try again.
The same scenario exactly.
They started 12 a.m.
The fever was high the nurse went there,
she gave antibiotics. Back to coma.
I went back and I said sir I
am sorry I leave the case.
So she died after a few days.
This case was still reacting.
We still have some information.
But the 3rd time there was
no information anymore.
There was no sign of anything I
could base my prescription on.
I believe that Hahnemann did not have a
clear picture of what we are facing today.
Today we are facing
these situations.
One situation is that the organism
can react to the medicine
or to the disease or the constant changes
within the body may bring the body
to a state where there is no return.
After this red line we can do nothing.
- About this red line.
I work in emergency for pets and
the patients arrive too late
and there is a point of no return,
there is nothing that we can do
because with Homeopathy they
die fast and without agony
and very often they die calmly with
no pain. It makes death easier.
- That is correct. Once they have passed the
red line the remedy will speed up the death.
The remedy will sooth the situation,
it will make it more calm.
In a case where there is no return,
all people who die from metastases,
they die with pain, agony, the homeopathic
remedy will sooth the suffering
but will speed up death. That's why we
never base our prescriptions on pathology.
It's almost useless. Very few
times you may strike the remedy.
What you need is primary
or secondary symptoms.
As long as the organism is reacting it's
ok, you take them into consideration.
But once this is gone
they are useless.
Whether you want to call
them secondary or whatever.
But my understanding is
what I am explaining.
You will see later that the symptoms
which are created by a remedy
can be opposing each other like the pendulum,
push the organism towards one side
then the organism goes to the other side
then the organism is in a good condition.
You make an organism which is very
cold, very hot and then will balance.
This information about the remedy is the
bipolar information from the remedies.
A remedy can be very cold
primarily but very hot also.
If you like to call it primary and
secondary symptoms you may do it
but still they are
useful symptoms
but the moment the pathology progresses beyond
the redline then the symptoms are useless.
You cannot use them.
Pulsatilla is very hot but
sometimes is quite chilly.
Arsenicum is quite cold remedy but
sometimes is either normal or hot.
There are primary and
secondary symptoms.
We call primary symptom for Pulsatilla
is heat the secondary is the coldness
but still has no special
importance for us.
These are symptoms that can
be used in prescribing.
We have bipolar symptoms of
many remedies and most probably
we don't know all the opposing
symptoms we may have.
Almost all remedies
have bipolar symptoms.
Natrum muriaticum has
desire for salt.
This is the primary reaction and the aversion
to salt can be called secondary reaction.
Ignatia has aversion to fruits but
has desire for fruits as well.
Hahnemann was trying to put this in
an order by giving this information.
He did not have the information that
we have today with all the pathologies
that are developing and
terrible situations.
- If I understood right, and please correct
me, concerning this point of no return,
before the redline the state belongs
to the 4th group but is very severe,
a few symptoms are presented,
one can prescribe a remedy,
see a slight aggravation have a next
picture and then maybe we have a chance.
Beyond the redline in the same 4th
group there are some symptoms
we give a remedy and you get a slight
amelioration, the case is lost.
- That is correct.
- I read an article recently.
There is a new branch of
medicine where they find
that dead people are not really dead and they
work for hours and hours develop technics
so they are alive again, they try to
change the idea of what is death...
- This is a well known situation.
It is called apparent death.
Where people for 3 days remain in
a state of death without pulse
or anything indicating death and after 3
days they get resurrected. Necrophania.
Nobody knows how this happens.
There are people who bury themselves for
15 days in a grave they put over soil
and stay there for 10 days and then
they dig them out and they are alive.
No oxygen no food. I do not
understand what happens.
The problem is you have to realize something
else in order to understand what I say.
The organism from the moment it is
on an attack whether by medicine
or by disease starts a reaction.
As the reaction is not enough to cure
to get rid of the disease the pathology
that is created increases.
You have to imagine yourself all the time
there is a new effort of the organism
to go on a second line of defense.
On a 3rd line of defense.
So when it starts with an influenza
which ends up in meningitis.
That is a third line of defense. The
organism still is struggling to survive.
He may pass the redline
and then finish.
The idea is with the remedy will
pass the redline sooner or later.
If we catch the organism during the time of
his reaction he gives us some information
then we help him to come back.
If it is over then you give the remedy
and see that it speeds up death.
You have to have in mind this idea because
as I said a cancer is not created
from one day to the other.
You had a shock and some reactions
started within the body.
And after 5 years
there is tumor.
A woman is pressurizing herself for years
before she brings out a tumor in the breast.
This tumor was all the
time organizing itself
because the organism did
not have another outlet.
Then the tumor is preparing until it
reaches a moment when the woman sees
that there is a tumor and goes to
examine it. This is cancer now.
Is it going to stop there?
No, why not? 2 reasons.
The organism is weak and the other
reason is why the cancer was created.
You have done something,
you had some shock.
The shock continues to be there.
It is very difficult to cure a case of
cancer in which the cause of cancer
is still within the
psyche of the person.
The moment that you realize that the
woman has a conflict and you solved it
if it was possible, that moment
the cancer is not needed anymore
and may stop the development.
A dissection in a woman who died many
times have found cancer that has stopped.
Which developed in the breast
but she died of old age.
This paragraph is not clear and
is not something we can rely on.
Hahnemann was very observant
and he had observed
that one time Opium causes diarrhea,
the next causes constipation.
So primary reaction is diarrhea,
secondary is constipation.
For a practical we need to write down
the primary or secondary of a proving
of a remedy within 20-30-100 people
who can give us information.
This was the point which I disagree
with all kinds of different discussions
and explanations and
things like that.
Most probably what he meant by primary
and secondary reaction is on a level
which is mostly of a
functional disorders.