How we proceed... you
had a question?
-After watching
the video before...
-I studied your case...so you are
responsible for me not sleeping.
You got the answer?
-And I have a difficult
question for you now.
After what you have
said in the video case
in order to be alive
the emotion must be alive.
My question is how these people,
who sell their countries, who do
not respect the other people,
who make such a catastrophe in their
families and the next generation...
What is the reason
of their sickness?
-I have written a whole
article about that.
As I said it I sent it to 3 medical
journals, they all refused it,
now there is a fourth one that may
accept it and the chapter of this...
I will not say
research but anyhow...
it says the role of conscience
in triggering disease.
The people you are talking about they
sold their conscience to the devil.
-Why?
-Because of money.
They believe more
in material gains.
Power and money.
This is the reason.
Once your conscience
is bought by money,
in order to do things
against your conscience,
you start to be deeply sick and then
you can commit crimes of all kinds.
The higher power the people
have, the bigger the crime...
Good morning little
one, why are you late?
The bigger the power, the greater
the crimes of the people
who have sold their
souls to the devil.
Symbolically I'm talking.
I don't believe in devils
but you know what I mean.
She has a question.
-I wanted you to tell me a bit about
giving a remedy to a nursing woman.
I took a case of a woman who has a
clear picture of Baryta carbonica
but she has a child
who is 2 months old.
I thought that maybe I
could give her 1M or 10M
but then it's not very clear to me
if the remedy passes to the child.
-This is very clear and I have
said it before. I will repeat it.
When a woman is pregnant and you take
her case and she needs a remedy,
that is the most lucky thing
that can happen to the child.
Because by the mother taking the remedy,
the child also becomes balanced.
To bring out a balanced
child is a fantastic thing.
Otherwise the child comes out with
predisposition ready to be sick etc.
Pregnant and nursing women must take
homeopathic remedy in all cases.
Of course if you have a woman who is nursing
and her heart is in terrible condition,
you must be careful with the potency
and don't give a very high one.
But give definitely the remedy.
The child will be saved.
It's the best thing that can happen
because the mother and the child
at the moment of nursing and during the
pregnancy are considered as the same organism,
there is no difference at all.
-It's a general question again.
Sometimes you treat a patient
and you see a partial improvement
that doesn't last for too long
and then there is a relapse
and then you have 2 options.
Sometimes you repeat the remedy that
has acted and other times you say
that the remedy was close, it wasn't
the Similimum but it was similar
and it has acted but it
hasn't cured the case.
How can we differentiate
between these 2 cases?
-On the first case, if the remedy was
correct, was based on certain keynotes
and you gave a low potency, it did not last
very long, in 2 months there is a relapse.
Once the keynotes are back, you may repeat
the remedy and this is the correct.
If the remedy was not
correct and it was close
and therefore it gave a kind of
amelioration in certain aspects
and then there is a relapse.
In such a case there is no
relapse, it is most probably,
because the remedy was not the
exact, the organism is coming back
to the original condition that
it was before the remedy.
Then search for another remedy.
The idea is that you have to make
sure that the remedy was acting.
That means during the time the organism was
better, the keynotes have disappeared.
There is a relapse, the
keynotes reappear.
The remedy was correct,
you repeat it,
first time the same potency,
later on higher potency.
The second possibility.
The remedy was close,
then the keynotes
on which you prescribed most probably
were not gone during the time
when the patient
was saying I am better.
You gave Nux vomica to a gastritis
case where there is a lot of heartburns
and it takes away the heartburn.
But the Nux vomica was chosen on certain
other symptoms, which are irritability,
offended easily etc.
While the gastritis is better,
the irritability is not better.
The "easily offended"
is not better.
That means the remedy was close.
There is a relapse, there is again
burning in the stomach after eating
or with the least eating etc.
You better find another remedy.
Which can be the other remedy?
A remedy that has burning in the
stomach and the irritability.
Maybe Robinia will be the remedy.
Then you give it.
Or Lilium tigrinum
may be the remedy.
It's like a tiger.
Woman with S tiger character.
-May I ask something on that? If
the keynotes of the physical level
and the patient on the mental/
emotional is doing better
but the relapse is on the physical
symptoms, is it still again valid to go...
-You give the remedy
on a gastritis case.
His gastritis is the same
but the irritability is better.
This is what you are saying.
That means most probably
the remedy was correct
but there is an underlying remedy
to cover the remaining symptoms.
What is the other remedy?
Natrum muriaticum or whatever.
Or you gave Natrum muriaticum
and the gastritis has remained,
I feel better psychologically
but I still have bloatedness.
Lycopodium, the second remedy.
-I have a case of a
child with asthma.
I took the case one year back and
the picture was clear Carcinosin.
I have given Carcinosin, the child has
improved very well on mental/ emotional level,
beautiful effect of Similimum.
Physically attacks have reduced, episodes
of acute asthma have also reduced
and all I can see an amelioration
of 60% on physical plane.
But now the case is stuck.
I cannot go further.
I have raised the
medicine to CM.
-Forget it.
He needs another remedy.
-Sir, there are no other findings which
I can enter with another remedy.
Best is to repeat the same
medicine with a potency of 2CM.
-If you gave Carcinosin
on certain keynotes.
Do you remember the keynotes?
-The child was
extremely fastidious...
-How old is the child?
-7 years.
Particularly sensitive to criticism,
fastidious, very emotional,
with a strong family history of
cancer, used to sleep on left side,
desire for milk... It was an
absolutely confirmed Carcinosin.
-Now all these keynotes are back?
-Much improved.
-Yes but are they back?
-No.
Therefore he needs
another remedy.
Still he keeps on being
fastidious I believe.
-No it's reduced.
The symptoms of Carcinosin on which
I have prescribed are reduced.
And there is a beautiful
amelioration with the Similimum
but I am unable to go
further more than 60%...
-He has asthma.
What kind of asthma?
-It was aggravated in the night and he was
being treated with allopathic medicine
since he was 3 years old.
He was in very bad state
of broken immune system
and when I gave the medicine, there was a
classic mental/ emotional amelioration...
-I understand all that.
But I am trying to help you by giving you
some suggestion about the second remedy.
He needs another remedy which comes
underneath, most probably Arsenicum.
Have you tried before
giving Arsenicum?
-It is the only medicine which...
-If the asthma comes in the night, if the
child needs in order to sleep a high pillow,
if the child is still fastidious, then
most probably he needs another remedy
most probably Arsenicum album.
But if the asthma comes at 4 a.m.
-Now there are no attacks
of asthma anymore.
-Then what do you
want to improve?
-There is wheezing inside the chest
and his mother is a gynecologist.
She has reported me that I am able to
hear wheezing inside almost every time
I auscultate his chest.
Wheezing is there.
-Now the symptom is wheezing. The
remedy now is Kali Sulphuricum.
It can be. Just examine the
possibility of Kali Sulphuricum.
-A few days ago you said commenting
on a case that both Veratrum (album)
and Phosphorus care and
try to help those around.
But you said Veratrum in a different
way but you did not comment more.
I want you to comment a little.
No, you did not comment
because it was late...
-They are totally different
one from the other.
Phosphorus is anxious when he sees
people suffering and he wants to help
because of his own
anxiety feelings.
These people are suffering, they
are not happy, I need to help.
Veratrum is different.
Veratrum is a leader that
wants to protect the others,
whoever they might be from being
suppressed, from suffering, whatever.
They both are caring about the other
people but the one is a leader
and says don't do this, it is not
correct, he will interfere with you
becoming unjust with somebody.
Phosphorus will go himself and try to help
as much as possible the person per se.
Veratrum album needs to show that
he is a protector of humans.
Needs to show it.
Phosphorus does not
need to show it.
It's caring but does
not need to show it.
Do you understand
the difference?
Both are bleeding from the nose, both need
cold water and cold things in the mouth,
ice cream and ice cubes but
they are quite different.
The one is a leader and a
prophet, repent... he goes out
and says to people "Repent! You
are sinners! I need to save you!"
Like me, I never took Veratrum.
Now it comes to my mind
I may need a dose of Veratrum! But I never
had nosebleed and I don't like cold water.
Anyhow I can take a dose... That is the
difference and these are the similarities.
-The last time with the German group you
gave an explanation in the Law of Similars,
how Hahnemann sees the artificial disease,
it has to be a stronger in order to cure
and you were explaining that this kind
of explanation would be a suppression.
It has not to be a
stronger suppression
because Hahnemann just finds
a way to explain the law.
But in a practical way this has some
difference between his explanation
and your explanation.
This has clinical consequences because
it is very delicate to interpret
every phrase of Hahnemann
particularly the Law of Similars...
You gave another
explanation, different.
-This is one of the first things
that concern me, his explanation.
The fact also, he was saying,
I am going to tell you how it
works (the homeopathic remedies),
what is the paragraph of this?
No, wait a moment,
I will remind you.
He says I can tell you how the similar
remedy acts but it's not important.
Paragraph 28, "As this natural
law of cure manifests itself
in every pure experiment and every
true observation in the world,
the fact is consequently
established..."
There is no question
about the Law of Cure.
"...it matters little what may be scientific
explanation of how it takes place (the cure)".
It's the first time that Hahnemann
has some doubts of what he says
and he says "and I do not attach much
importance to the attempts made to explain it.
But the following view seems to commend
itself as the most probable one,... "
He is full of doubts about the
explanation he was going to give.
"...as it is founded on premises
derived from experience. "
Hahnemann had some observations
with acute epidemic diseases.
He said if there is an acute disease
and there is at the same time
another epidemic disease
going on in the area,
if this new disease is stronger
than the one I already have
and I contract the second as well,
then most probably the stronger one
will suppress the previous one
which I have, will run its course
and afterwards the weaker one will
come and will also run its course.
But he says if I have a disease which
is stronger and another epidemic
which is weaker, I cannot
get it, cannot be affected.
If it happens that the 2 acute diseases are
similar in nature, one will cure the other.
On these ideas he was explaining
the action of the remedy
but you have to take into consideration that
these observations are not valid anymore
in our societies.
In our societies we do not
allow anymore epidemics.
We have eliminated the epidemics through
manipulation of the immune system
of the human organism.
We have made the human organism in
such a way as to not accept the acute.
Why?
Because we have created in us a subacute
condition which is stronger than the acute.
We are deeply sick and therefore the
acute which is around cannot touch me
because it protects me.
In the same way, the same observation
of Hahnemann, the difference is that
we do not allow anymore the acute
condition to play the game.
Because we suppress the acute conditions,
making the organism sick on a permanent,
chronic condition.
So we have permanently a
subacute condition going on.
And outside there is an acute
going around and there are people
who are going to sanatoriums
and are not affected.
There are people who go around sick
people with influenza, any epidemic
and are not affected.
This is not a good sign.
We learn from western medicine
that this is protection.
We protected the population.
We protected the population because
we made it sicker inside.
We are sick in a deep level.
Let us say schizophrenia...
Would you say that schizophrenia is an
inflammation of a part of the brain?
You would never say that. We do
not know what schizophrenia is.
Once I have said this theory that all chronic
diseases are of inflammatory nature,
ten years ago, some years
ago, I don't remember.
It was 3 years ago that one of my students
brought me a research from the U. S. A.
saying that they
have found out now
that schizophrenia is of an
inflammatory causative factor.
Thank you very much.
Now if the inflammation is in the brain
forget it, nothing can touch this person.
He is protected from all
diseases, even the worst.
I have said many times make the
experiment and let a schizophrenic
go with a person who has active
syphilis, have as much sex as he likes.
He will never contract syphilis,
gonorrhea , tuberculosis , Ebola virus.
I do not know. If there is any
substance, any nosological entity
that can overcome the resistance
from a psychotic person.
A psychotic person
cannot get any acute.
I bring bad news I know
but these are the facts.
So my difference on this
matter with Hahnemann
who says that the artificial
disease is stronger
and therefore it pushes the natural disease
and that is how a cure is accomplished,
we disagree because the most
logical and natural thing is this.
The immune system once it is
attacked responds with symptoms.
We do not know the
disease as such,
we know always the response of the
immune system in the form of symptoms.
There is high fever, coughing, headaches...
these form the response of the immune system
to counteract the disease.
So what is more logical then?
If we have a tool that if it is given to an
organism, it produces a similar set of symptoms.
So we give it and then because the organism
is already trying with these symptoms,
we give a remedy that produces
the same set of symptoms.
What is going to happen? It is
natural to increase the symptoms.
Because you have already an effort
of the organism producing symptoms,
you give a remedy that also produces
the symptoms, the organism augments,
aggravates the symptoms and then we
say we have the initial aggravation.
This is the way we say when there
is an initial aggravation,
it means that the organism is
strong and has reacted very well.
Because after the initial aggravation
there is an amelioration and a cure,
the disease is gone.
The fact that the organism suffering with
a chronic condition with the inflammation
which comes up and down
all the time inside,
so there is always a migraine coming
that lasts 2 days, then it goes away.
Then after 10 days the migraine is back or
the inflammation in the joints they come
and are stimulated, then subside
for a while then back again.
The organism all these years that
is sick with a chronic condition
is trying through these
inflammations from time to time
making a bigger inflammation to get
rid of the disease but cannot.
So we give him the extra energy he needs,
in order to overcome finally the disease.
Every effort, every headache is an
effort of the organism to cure itself.
Every symptom which exist is an effort of the
organism in order to get rid of the disease.
It cannot.
Why?
He does not have enough because he is prevented
by what we call the miasmatic layers.
He has like a blockage and
tries again and again.
That is why in simpler cases, we say you
rest, you eat better, don't get excited,
be calm and a
recovery can happen.
Don't spend your energy.
If you spend your energy,
you will be sick.
When do you get a coryza?
When you get a cold?
When you have exerted yourself and your
energy is low and then the microbes
find a way to come and then the organism
says STOP otherwise you will die.
No I don't stop.
You say I have a coryza and then
the coryza goes to the pharynx
and you get a pharyngitis...
then I have a pneumonia.
It says I told you,
you should lie down...
This is normal.
The homeopathic remedy gives
you the extra energy,
releases the energy which exists in the
organism but is blocked and cannot act.
The homeopathic remedy releases that
energy which the organism needs
in order to overcome
the disease.
So this is the most probable explanation of
how it is explained the Law of Similars.
The Law of Similars has to be
accepted as a universal law.
All the good things that happen
in the life of a person is
because of the Law of Similars.
You have a friend for who you say
we are thinking the same way,
we are feeling the
same things etc.
You come together and there
is energy, happiness.
This energy is the Law
of Similars working.
Because you found
somebody who is similar.
Now why do we need that?
Because we are limited and we need
to find that support in a friend,
in a relationship between men and women,
between women and women, men and men...
But you need that relationship to give
you the energy and you say I'm happy,
when I am with that person.
You cannot understand
anything from the outside.
It all happens on
an energy level.
This is the similarity
and then the Law of Similars becomes
universal and, as I have said,
all the people who are trying
to reach a state of enlightment
or a state of bliss or a state
of spiritual completeness,
all these are based on
the Law of Similars.
The problem is we understand
that in order to approach God
or whatever you call it in every religion,
you have to have certain qualities,
otherwise you cannot.
It's like a blockage.
Once these qualities on your conscience become
similar to the qualities of the divine nature,
then there is a possibility of
humans to approach the idea of God
and something happens inside
the brain at a certain moment,
a click that releases something which is,
some Orthodox say that is the grace of God,
some call it yoga...
but there is a click
in which you enter a new dimension in
understanding which is far beyond anything
you have lived before.
It is such a bliss,
such a completeness.
The saint people have described
it in different religions.
These states are real,
they are existing.
These people have tried very hard
to become similar to the divine.
It happens only to these people
who have attained the qualities.
Because we say yoga, you sit there
and... you can do that, it is an effort.
But you cannot ever have the click inside
unless you have attained the qualities...
Which are the qualities? Love, justice,
sincerity, honesty, helping others, love,
loving myself is not enough.
Love is to care about
others and to help others.
So the qualities more and more
similar to what we call the divine.
The Indian philosophy or spiritualism
has analyzed these things
and then they gave it to their
books... Very great analysis.
In the same way the Orthodox did it and gave
it to philokalia, books of the Fathers.
They gave the keys of their
understanding of what they needed to do
in order to have that click.
Unless this was a fact, the bliss that
comes, people could not live in a monastery.
They would say goodbye very soon, unless
they felt this total silence within yourself
and the feeling of bliss coming
a little bit in the beginning
until you have the big experience which
is described by the saints of our times.
This is the Law of Similars.
It is the same Law.
Yes, Carlos.
-I was about to
share a crazy idea.
Because many times in my mind I am struggling
with this subject, Homeopathy, Allopathy
and how to prove it.
I don't know if you know somebody
who is working to create a device
that can measure the vital energy,
that it would be very simple,
very cheap in order that
everybody can have this device.
Because in this way we will
prove the effect of Homeopathy
and the effect of
Allopathy, as well.
For example a measure of 100.
We give a remedy and if it's right it has to
increase the level of the electromagnetic fields.
Something that really
represents the state.
-Your idea is quite correct.
The correct remedy
organizes the field
and the wrong remedy or the
allopathic, confuses the field.
-Most probably the people who will
discover it, they will be killed
because for Allopathy, if the people have
this small device and they take this medicine
and the energy goes down, it's a
clean proof that something is wrong.
And it's a prove of Homeopathy as well,
if you give a remedy that is correct
and the energy organizes
the organism to be better.
-In the National Institute of Health
in the U. S. they found that box
in which you enter and measure your
energy field in Washington D. C.
One time they invited me also and said come,
we would like to ask you some questions.
I said I was very tired, I had
to come back here in Athens
and they sent one of the
doctors to discuss.
He was telling me they wanted to measure
the electromagnetic field actually.
We discussed quite a lot and I said to him
it's going to be very difficult to do that
because there are so many electromagnetic
fields interfering in the environment
and the box in which you could
measure purely, does not exist.
Actually they had experiments in
100m in a box under the earth.
Still the electromagnetic field
of the earth interferes.
So I don't know if they
will ever manage to do it.
But this is an old idea...
-We can measure and it can be
representing in a screen the real state.
It would be a great
proof, I think.
-One more question and
then we go ahead.
-Hello. I just wanted to tell
you how true your explanations
were regarding the Law of
Similars in relationships.
In India where there are
only arranged marriages...
-I will tell you something more.
I have said many times
that if people do not indulge in
sexual experience from early age,
they have the possibility to meet the person
with whom they have that great similarity.
So it's like one remedy
would do the trick.
One person will do the trick
also when coming in contact
which will be the exact opposite
pole of each other which they need
in order to be complete.
Therefore the energy which is given then
in a state of 2 individuals being together
and not be contaminated by
previous sexual experiences,
this couple can remain forever
together with a lot of pleasure.
Not only physical but
also spiritual pleasure.
Because it is like the correct remedy,
so if you find the correct person
there is a great explosion
of love and energy.
But this in order to happen you do not have
to confuse the case by trying this and that.
In our culture they say I
have to try a lot of cases,
so I will see which is finally the best.
Forget it.
You can never find the best.
The organ is confused.
They cannot recognize
the correct.
So when it comes even a person passing by in
front of the person will not recognize it.
Because it's damaged the organ
by experiences which are stupid.
They will kill me but it's Ok.
I don't mind.
That means you have done this?
No I have not! I have
done the wrong way also.
But realizing what I have
done, I have done wrong.
That's the difference.
Don't tell me if I experiment and I go with
this and that, have lots of experience,
then I get married.
Forget it.
You will get a divorce
sooner or later.
You cannot recognize your partner
really because the organ is confused.
You are not pure anymore.
How can you recognize?
I have to say this.
Maybe some people eventually they
realize that it is not good.
When I was in America they said
treat my son, how old is he?
He is 15, why treat him? Because he is still
stuck with the family, what do you mean?
He does not have girlfriend,
doesn't go out, he is sick!
According to American culture
a man or a woman who is 15
and has not gone yet to have
sex, is a sick individual.
I was there in the 80s 30 years ago
and I would take cases like that
and I could hear
things of that type.
Give a remedy, so he
can go with girls.
I said the child is normal,
why should I give?
Do you have other children?
I have 7.
Where are they?
They are all gone.
Where?
And then he was a naval
general in the submarines.
He says, some we know where they are,
some we don't know where they are,
one was caught and is in jail,
the other is in narcotics...
They were telling me, as
if it was very simple.
They got out, had
these experiences,
was caught, put in jail, the other is
in narcotics... I could not understand.
This was a cultural
shock for me.
I don't have any remedy
to give to your son.
-So in India when a boy and a girl get
married, before that they match the horoscope.
They match the horoscope and if they are
quite similar and if they are max similar,
that means they
have to be matched.
So if we have similar more than 25,
the marriage will be compatible.
And we have seen that if the
compatibility was less than 25,
they get married but
they get divorced.
-What she says, is
correct unfortunately.
We mock against astrology but their culture
is based on the astrological charts,
which the parents bring together
before the people have met.
Do they match? Yes,
bring them together.
And their marriages by the time I was
living in India were 95% constant.
Now they have
rejected this idea.
Marriages are breaking
much more frequently.
-In metropolitan cities...
-You experiment the same
way we have done it here.
They are not taught by what suffering
we have brought upon ourselves.
Nobody realizes the suffering.
-Even so with the horoscope we can
understand what was the past of the boy,
what will be the future of the
boy or girl, what is the character,
how many partners he may have had before
the marriage and after it... everything.
-Her father is an astrologist.
-My family, we have a temple and
my grandfather is a priest.
So we have a deep
knowledge about it.
-I said it as a joke... That's another
story, I don't want to talk about it
but what she says is true.
Their culture is based on the information
given by the astrologust when 2 people match.
And the fact that people remain together
for many, many years is a proof
that these people know
something we don't know.
That's all.
What was the paragraph?
105, "The second point of the
business of a true physician
related to acquiring a knowledge of
the instruments intended for the cure
of the natural diseases, investigating
the pathogenetic power of the medicines,
in order, when called on to cure, to
be able to select from among them one,
from the list of whose symptoms an
artificial disease may be constructed,
as similar as possible to the
totality of the principal symptoms
of the natural disease
sought to be cured. "
I don't like the word "business" and I
was wondering, you German can tell me,
what is the world in paragraph 105, "the
second point of the business" or the work
or the mission.
You cannot find it.
I thought you...
-I found it but it
is the same word.
It is the actual translation.
He doesn't use "purpose".
-Did it have a different
meaning during that time?
-No. It's actually
the word "business".
-"Business" actually
means my work.
-Occupation.
-Today it means I do something that I
earn money which maybe is not correct...
Good businessmen earn a lot of
money against others who do not.
-It has both
connotations in German.
-In German the word business like "Beschaft"
[also means "occupy"] if a dog pees
in front of your car, we say he did its
"Beschaft" or if he shits in front of your car...
Also has the meaning of "task".
-I would like to change
this word to "task".
Because if I were Hahnemann myself I
could have the right to change the word.
I change the word
"business" to "task".
The task that a homeopath has, is
to learn the provings of remedies,
what the remedies can produce as symptoms
and select the best possible remedy.
That is easy for
everyone to understand.
106, "The whole pathogenetic effect of
the several medicines must be known;
that is to say, all the morbid
symptoms and alterations in the health
that each of them is specially capable
of developing in the healthy individual
must first have been
observed as far as possible,
before we can hope to be able to find among them,
and to select, suitable homoeopathic remedies
for most of the
natural disease."
He says that the provings have
to be as complete as possible
to know all the possible alterations that the
remedy can bring about the human organism,
in order to be able to select
the most similar remedy.
We have to know not only that the remedy
produces diarrhea, that's not enough.
We have to know the complete
symptomatology of the remedy.
107, "If, in order to ascertain this,
medicines be given to sick persons only,
even though they be
administered singly and alone,
then little or nothing precise
is seen of their true effects."
This is very important for
provings of new remedies.
He says if a remedy is given to a sick
person, you will never get reliable symptoms
because he says "...as those
peculiar alterations of the health
to be expected from the medicine are mixed
up with the symptoms of the disease
and can seldom be
distinctly observed."
You see here why I
shout for many years.
The proving craziness is so
great all over the world.
Wait a moment you cannot prove
remedies just like that.
Because you can gather anybody who wants
to be part of a proving, take the remedy.
Usually 1 dose of 30CH of the remedy,
and then they collect the symptoms
from all of them and they have
now collected 2000 symptoms.
How did you collect 2000
symptoms from a dose of 30CH
which was given to a group of 10 people?
It must be the imagination of the people,
not the real proving.
It's not possible because in order
a remedy in 30CH or higher potency
can give symptoms it has to be very
close to the energy level of the person
otherwise it will
be like placebo.
I choose a substance and 2 of you
are sensitive to that substance,
only the 2 of you can have symptoms.
The rest 50 people won't get any.
It's not possible you get symptoms because
the remedy was chosen arbitrarily
but hit only 2 people who may be sensitive
to that substance, not everyone.
Here they make a proving and
everyone pours out symptoms.
These are the symptoms which everyone has
already as a chronic condition which all have.
Nobody of us today is really
healthy so we mix our own symptoms
with the symptoms of the remedy. We put down
2000 symptoms as symptoms of the remedy.
You may say yes but the remedy
did not have any symptoms?
Of course the remedy has some symptoms but
these few symptoms of the remedy were mixed
in 2000 symptoms which have
no relevance to the remedy.
- I want to ask something.
Has it ever been observed that a person
sensitive to a certain remedy of the proving
will in the future develop some kind of condition
which responds to this particular remedy?
- Yes.
- He's sensitive to this remedy from the proving
but will he develop a disease in the future
which responds to this remedy has
was sensitive to in the proving?
- Yes but you have to be aware that in
the provings we don't have pathologies,
we have response of the immune system,
functional symptoms which are not disease,
that means you give a remedy, you
prove Carcinosin and whether
the person can develop cancer...
- In the future he might
develop symptoms, pathology
which responds to the remedy he
was sensitive to in the proving
in which he has this
predisposition...
- My answer is no.
It may sometimes happen but Natrum muriaticum
what kind of pathology will develop?
We don't know. It
can be anything.
What kind of pathology Calcarea
carbonica may develop? Anything!
From cancer to Parkinson's
disease, colitis, anything.
The final pathology
belongs to all remedies.
That means all remedies in their end
stages can have all kinds of pathology.
That means the pathology that can be caused
by a remedy is never the end result.
That means before a person
dies with a pathology,
that kind of pathology cannot
be caused be a specific remedy,
it's caused by the organism
himself and his predisposition.
- I was wondering Hahnemann only says
that we have to find healthy individuals
to give them to. That's why
they are trying in India...
- I will speak about that.
- I think I know that you have the idea to
give the remedy to sensitive persons only...
- Later on I will tell you my idea
on the proving of the remedies.
Just wait a moment.
108."There is, therefore,
no other possible way
in which the peculiar effects of
medicines on the health of individuals
can be accurately ascertained
- there is no sure,
no more natural way of
accomplishing this object,
than to administer the several medicines
experimentally, in moderate doses..."
This is the catch phrase.
That means when you want to start an
experiment and if you want to have an effect,
you can start with posology
which is sub-toxic.
Not really toxic dose to kill the
person but sub-toxic. Moderate doses.
In paragraph 35 he says that medicines
have a power bigger that disease.
That means a disease can come to
you if you have a predisposition.
Medicines do not need you
to have a predisposition.
If I gave you large enough doses I
can poison anyone with any remedy
as long as I give it to you
in large enough doses.
32nd. "But it is quite otherwise
with the artificial morbific agents
which we term medicines"
Before he says you have to have a
sensitivity towards a disease.
Now he says it's "it is quite otherwise
with the artificial morbific agents
which we term medicines.
Every real medicine, namely, acts at
all times, under all circumstances,
on every living human being,
and produces in him its peculiar
symptoms (if the dose be large enough)"
You see in which case you can do a proving? You
can do a proving if you have some individuals
who agree to take in some
cases the mother tincture,
in some other cases a little bit more
attenuated and when you take hydrocyanic acid
try to attenuate enough so you
don't leave this world quite fast.
But you have to find what is the
sub-toxic dose that can produce reaction
from the organism.
- When we make a proving with potentized
medicine and we need sensitive people
for this medicine is
there any possibility...
- Later on he will say that.
Hahnemann has experimented
mostly in sub toxic doses.
In his Materia Medica there are
toxic, sub-toxic and finally
high potencies on
sensitive individuals.
So all this will come together finally
to produce the array of symptoms
that a remedy can produce.
But you have to find which are sensitive
first to a particular remedy.
And to find it when you start an
experiment and you give sub-toxic dose
to the whole class and one of you
comes and say today I have a headache
I never had in my life.
Ok with the 2 doses you got
you already get a headache.
You are a good subject for
proving a high potency
all the rest will give you some symptoms
if they continue taking the remedy
but these symptoms will
be gross symptoms.
But the most subtle symptoms
will be given by the people
who showed a specific sensitivity
to that specific drug.
- It means that for instance a
proving of Lac defloratum, milk,
all of us will drink a glass
of milk first and the person
who will vomit just
by the smell of it...
- This is the one
who is going to do.
People who just drink one sip and vomit
will be the one to prove a high potency.
- Could this person be considered as healthy
if there is such a big sensitivity?
- He's not considered healthy but
on the other hand there is a way
to get out of this by recording before
the experiment, at least for 1 month,
every day, very carefully
all your symptoms.
You write them in
a piece of paper.
I wake up unrefreshed at 11
a.m., I need to eat something,
they have to live in a particular way,
with the same kind of food, pure food,
no alcohol, no stimulants...
You write down all your symptoms
and once you have the full picture
of your own symptoms so you
don't mix them with the remedy,
so whatever beyond your
symptoms is recorded.
If a symptom is eliminated, also is
recorded, but as secondary possibility.
So if you have some new symptoms or symptoms
eliminated also recorded in separate group...
You want to prove a remedy and by chance
one happens to be allergic to that
that means it immediately brings out
a reaction then he's the best prover
for a high potency. If he is very allergic to
this most probably he is going to be cured.
It's going to be the
most similar remedy.
- If you do provings with toxic substance
and you talk about subtoxic doses,
variability in people...
- Every day you get 3 doses, 10-12-15
drops until you start feeling symptoms.
This is the process.
- You start from minute doses because the
toxicity is different to different people
depending on liver functions, how he
reacts to the particular substances,
the toxic level for someone may
differ from another person's...
- I believe he will give some
rules for instance exclude those
who are neurotics,
hysterics, hypochondriacs.
Such people could not participate
in such an experiment.
I don't remember if he writes
it but this is logical.
Maybe be he will write it.
Do you remember if he writes it?
- In Organon and you said it several
times over the years the real proving
has to be carried out in really healthy
individuals. Today almost nobody is healthy.
My question is; your final judgment, is
it worth trying making a proving today
or is it useless?
- What I have said in the past is...Boericke
Materia Medica has 780 remedies.
Out of them more than
half are small remedies.
There is some information there and it will
be interesting to prove the small remedies
to see if we can increase the symptomatology
which is there and is very little.
That will be a good idea but the idea
has to be according to a protocol.
And the protocol should be according to
what I have said starting with subtoxic,
see the effect and the people
who are doing the experiment
should not know
what the remedy is.
Actually I should know the remedy
and give it to your group, try it
and finally I will come down with a
conclusion how much of this is reliable
and how much is most probably
due to fantasy, hysteria...
- But it is not going to be again a combination
of the symptoms of the people as patients
and those of the remedy... Because
they are not really healthy.
- Before they start the experiment they have
to write down for a month all their symptoms.
So they cannot bring a symptom that is
written. Unless they do that... forget it.
In our state of health
it's impossible to get.
Perhaps in India you can get
some healthy individuals.
But the Indians have the problem
of not being systematic.
They are enthusiastic but system
is not going together with India.
They break the system very easily and they
get enthusiastic all cancers are cured!
We cure all cancers!
They get into this kind of enthusiasm due
to the fact they are very emotional people.
We need moderation between people
who has some emotions also
but some brains as well and control the brain,
control the emotions not to get overexcited.
The provers should never
speak with one another.
When I tried 2 times to do a proving I
failed. I could not get any symptoms.
[Name] tried to prove Hydrogen. I said
how is it possible? It's volatile.
I said how the hell
you have done it?
I asked him to send me the
preparation he used for hydrogen
and there was a group of Medical Doctors
in Italy who agreed to do the experiment
with a remedy I would
give them, without knowing.
So I gave it to them and of course they came
out with no effects. Nobody felt anything.
They said now you have the obligation
to tell us what you gave us.
I said I gave you hydrogen.
What? This is chemically not
possible to do pure hydrogen.
But did not tell these people that I
had asked the hydrogen from Jeremy
and he sent me the potencies and all that.
I lost these people completely.
He said George knows no chemistry,
has no idea of what is going on,
he gave us hydrogen to prove.
They were absolutely
irritated with the situation
but I didn't want to criticize without
having some proof of what I was thinking.
I sacrificed this group of medical doctors.
Because they did an effort.
I told them to write down
everything I tell you.
And then I gave them hydrogen because
it was a big racket by that time.
- Is there any source of provings
you would recommend as reliable?
- When I started, in the first group, I had a
case that I could not make out any remedy.
And the man had great allergy and
feeling indifferent about life,
just wanted to change world, go to the
next. Took lots of remedies, no effect.
The only thing that ameliorated me
was the spores of black cumin oil.
How did you find? I used to take
cakes that had these spores on top
and whenever I took I found out that
this helped me a lot with my allergy.
Why didn't you continue
taking cumin oil?
Because I found out that as it went along
I needed more and more quantities,
so I could not continue with such
big quantities of cumin oil.
I said, we well do an experiment and I
will give you high potency of cumin oil.
We tried to find out, I thought we don't
have it here, I ordered to prepare it,
found out it was prepared in England
I said to buy it from England
and I am waiting for the effect. I
have written down all his case.
I gave this high potency and if
this person is cured with cumin oil
then we have the first information about the
symptomatology that cumin oil can produce,
then eventually I can give it to others to see
whether they will develop similar symptoms.
So this kind of starting a
proving is also very interesting
when somebody by chance gives a
remedy that nobody has proved
but because of some thoughts that looks
like Rhus tox but it did not act
so I took another plant from this family,
gave it to him and he was cured.
If there is such a case, I
accept that may be cured.
And this is the beginning of a proving.
In this way we may have a remedy.