I'm going to show you a case on which we had the first problem
where she comes back and says no effect.
-This patient JK since 1983 she came in with complaints of neuralgia, headaches and
frequent colds. She has a history of syphilis 8 years ago from that time and she is treated bad.
She also had a stomach ulcer at age 16 and her mother died from stomach cancer
and had alcohol problem and depression.
She's had this neuralgia severely for 6 years.
-Where is the neuralgia, in which side?
-It is on the right side primarily
It began through canals, spreads on the eyes temples and she was very weak at the time.
I gave her Mercury 200 and she had brief aggravation, slight amelioration and
just relapsed completely.
Then the next visit I saw her she was so much worse cold, very chilly that I gave her...
-You gave her Magnesia phosphorica 1M.
-I gave her Magnesia phosphorica. Actually I consulted with Roger at the time about the
case and we decided that, that was the best choice. Then she had severe crisis.
It became very clear after that and the pain went right to the right eye and she felt a
sensation of something in the eye, all the time.
She actually described this pain in the right corner of the eye and she was moaning,
describing herself that she was crying desperately for the pain and
the feelings were so desperate that she didn't want to continue living.
When she came in it was amazing because she waited for the time for visit and then she
came in and she sat there and told me the story of how much pain she is been in.
I was just amazed why she didn't call me weeks before, she just waited, she is a very nice person.
What Roger has said is that Magnesia phosphorica would clear the case.
Then she made an aggravation and she was much better and we waited and a week later
she relapsed and we repeated the Aurum again.
Then she continued to get better.
-What potency?
-One of 50M...
Then she continued to get better gradually, she came in and all the time she was
complaining of cramps and I gave her Calcarea 20X and that seemed to help.
Then continued to do well, one time needing a repeated dose of the Aurum 50 M.
She came back in November 85 complaining of the neuralgia coming back very badly with
bone pain and worse in the right side of the face and at that time I changed remedies
because I was concerned that the Aurum 50M is been needed to repeat it so often and
I just felt that she would try something else. I don't know if that was a bad decision.
I gave her Colocynthis 200 and it seemed to help her quite a bit although it changed the
case somewhat and she came back complaining of being superstitious and praying
excessively and emotionally better, energy better and the neuralgic pain better also.
So we waited and she is been good for a long time but then she came in again last June
complaining of no neuralgia but the bone pain is back and from that she described it to
me as sinus pain and I'm the one who used the word bone pain...
It's a pressing around the bones in the sinus area, pressing out the pain,
as she describes, and it's deep aching pain.
-On the right side?
-Yes on the right side and around the eyes.
Her menses are much better from Colocynthis and she has got a chronic allergy type for
some time now and she is main functioning much better with doing her own shopping and
as the years went by she was quite disabled, she couldn't work, she couldn't go to school.
When symptoms began she was in College. She had to drop it.
So she is functioning but she still wants to go back to school and still she can't do that.
Also superstitiousness and praying is very strong, complaining of bones aching all over
and then she described this mental state of being feeling stupid as if her mind was really
deteriorating and has difficulty in concentrating and even felt what am I doing there?
She has just feelings like that sometimes, like her mind is just crumpling, as she described it.
At that time I thought she could go back to one of those remedies
but I really thought it could be good for you to see this case.
-What is this test?
-Epstein Barr virus. The virus is a mono-nucleosis virus and people are getting this condition
chronically.
They discovered it as a chronic condition with myalgias, with sore throats, colds and
sometimes chronic fever.
She had a titer of 1:60 which is moderate, it's not very high.
1:10 is normal and 1:60 or less indicates exposure to the virus and it goes way up to the thousands.
Again you see the same story here. She was better, worse, better, worse, better, worse
after 2-3 years of treatment, still the same state of health.
This is what I was talking about touching really the layers, treating the layers
which is a different sense all together.
Let's see.
-Do you have anything in your skin?
-Acne?
-No, I mean make-up.
-Yes, I do.
-Is it always very pale your skin?
-Yes I don't like the sun very much but it is naturally pale.
-You don't like the sun?
-No, I avoid the sun purposefully.
-You avoid the sun in order to?
What do you observe?
-Stiffness.
-It's very prominent the stiffness. It is a stiffness of what?
-Expression.
-Of expression mostly, an inner stiffness. Why? Why she is like that?
Because she is in pain? What is the reason for her being in this kind of stiffness?
-Certain insecurity.
-It's a symptom.
-Yes.
-She is holding herself up in a posture, in a position. Can you tell me why she is like that?
What she is afraid of? Like she is afraid of breaking the eggs? Why?
She is going to be like a mummy. Not the mother...
This is the impression she gives. Very important, why?
What is a mummy? Mummy is a human being who has everything else except what?
-Life.
-Life. You don't see life in her. It's not flowing the life.
Something has frozen her. She is frozen.
Why we are interested about this expression? For different reasons.
One is of course to give us an indication about the remedy and whether we can fit that
expression with what we know about the remedies.
The second thing we are interested about this expression is to know the actual depth of
the pathology.
This is a post-syphilitic condition? You may have these severe pains?
But how deep is the whole condition? It is depicted upon her appearance because there is
lack of life. There is tremendous lack of life, lack of vivacity.
What we are dealing with all the time, the element with which we are handling and we are
manipulating is this element of vitality, how much vitality is there, how much defenses are
there to stimulate.
In her it appears that everything has gone out, very little has been left in her. Let's see.
-But not that the sun bothers you?
-Not really.
-Do you like heat?
-I do, I can be very warm. I feel a kind of headache but virtually I like it.
-Do you want to describe how you feel?
-Right now OK. I have some pain today, sometimes it's been worse than today.
It feels like a bad cold or a flu, it's pretty much all over my body pains and aches but
sometimes it feels like pain in my head. Sometimes I have a really big pressure, like
headache.
It feels a kind of rock in here. It's usually around my eyes and my sinuses and my throat.
It's hard to describe exactly where it is .
-I'm sorry I don't understand you speak a little bit fast. That's my problem.
What did you say?
-A kind of in the roof of her mouth.
-As if it was something there?
-Like a sinus headache, it feels like over flesh between the roof of my mouth and behind
my nose and behind my eyes is so aching, it feels like a bad cold.
-What else do you feel?
-I have aches and pains especially in my upper body but also in my legs and arms and
shoulders, you know just aches.
-When did you develop all these pains?
-It started six years ago and before I had another kind of pain that has gradually got
better. That was a neuralgia.
That was like a toothache and sometimes it was in my eye. Now it is like a toothache and
sometimes it is in my eye.
-These pains now they are worse than what they used to be or they are better?
-They are better now.
-All these pains and the feelings in the head?
-Yes.
-What else do you have?
-It is really like a broken up especially the last six months, it's not too bad today but
usually my skin is all broken up here and here.
I find very hard to sleep at night, even if I'm tired and I sleep in midnight, I find it very hard
to get to sleep.
-What time do you finally go to sleep? It is late when you go to sleep?
Or you wake up in between?
-Sometimes I wake up in the night.
-What is the usual pattern?
-It's usually when I go to sleep 3,4,5 in the morning. Usually when I get to sleep, I can stay
asleep until I got an hour of sleep. Sometimes if I'm feeling particularly bad, it takes 10
hours to make me feel I have had enough sleep.
-When you go to sleep at 3 o' clock you continue until 11 o'clock in the morning?
-Usually yes.
-Why it takes you so long to go to sleep? You are excited, a lot of thinking?
What is the reason?
-I don't know, sometimes I'm thinking a lot but often even if I'm very sleepy it just feels that
my mind doesn't want to enter into sleep. It's like my mind and my body can't make me
adjust from being awake to being to sleep. I don't really know why.
I don't think it's particularly because I'm anxious, although sometimes but not usually.
The pain that I described to you is worse in the morning, when I first get up and at night
and sometimes it keeps me awake.
-How long it will take you before you are better with the pains? Five minutes,
three minutes or half an hour?
-More than half an hour and sometimes several hours.
-Before you could feel better.
-Yes.
-So you just wake up in the morning and what you do?
You walk in the house or you go out for a walk?
-Sometimes I walk and sometimes I have some place that I have to go but I if I don't have
to go anywhere then in half an hour I just fix myself something to eat and watch television
and I read.
-Do you like your life?
-It's OK except of the pains.
-What are your interests?
-I read.
-What are you reading?
-I read the newspapers a lot, I like to read many fictions and I have friends that
I'm interested in, I spend time talking to them on the phone and sometimes visiting them.
It's hard for me to get to them, so if they can they come to me.
-Are you religious?
-Yes.
-You are very religious?
-Yes, I pray a lot. I feel it very strongly.
-Is this praying a compulsion?
-Sometimes yes, you mean that I feel sorry for other creatures...
-No, that you have to do it, you have to pray.
-Yes sometimes it is.
-That you have to pray and you pray constantly.
-Often I do it, not to that point but often I do it because I feel fearful.
-What are you afraid of?
-I have a friend who has a heart condition, I worry about him, that's some reason to
worry and I worry about my father but sometimes it's irrational. I think of them and just
even thinking about their death...
I'm very superstitious.
-Very superstitious kind of thinking.
What symptoms are you looking now?
What kind of praying, what kind of person it is, what kind of life she is living?
-Stiffness, superstitious.
-Loneliness.
-Who sees loneliness in this case?
What do you see as her main characteristic? Why she is praying?
Because it is a pathology, it is a symptom, she is praying too much but why she is praying?
Can anybody tell me and analyze the case?
-Fear.
-Fear of her welfare.
-Fear of guilt.
-Why, because of syphilis?
-Consolating.
-It is consolating her the praying.
-She is fighting in herself.
-Fighting between what?
-To make contact with the outside world.
-Fear of getting insane.
-I'll give you a description and tell me if you don't agree, what I see in her.
She comes and she sits there lifeless. I see no life.
Then I get certain information about that person who is lifeless, that she has a lot of pains.
But the pains have been ameliorated but what I see is lifeless.
Then this person does not work. What she does? She sleeps.
From 3 o'clock till 11 or 12. What you do in the morning, I ask.
She says, I'm reading. What do you read? Newspapers.
What else you are doing? I'm talking to some friends in the telephone.
Now imagine her life. You have to imagine her life to understand.
It is important for us when we prescribe to go deep into the case and prescribe deep,
to change matters. Otherwise you will never change.
Give as much Aurum as you like and this case will not change,
it will become more and more depressed.
You have to find the remedy that fits the essence in this case, what we call the essence
now, here you have to prescribe on essence.
Unless you understand that essence and fit it with the remedy, as you know the remedy
to be, and what limitation this remedy  has, you will never succeed in this case.
Imagine this, why she doesn't move?
There are certain movements, what an individual does but there is another individual who
is careful about every motion, she appears to be very careful about every motion she
does. Is she dressed well?
-No.
-No, you don't like her dress?
I don't ask you whether you like the color of the dress etc. What I'm asking is whether you
get the impression whatever she wears, whether she is neat. Is she neat?
Is she neat?
-Yes.
-Is she clean?
-Her combing of the hair... Have you noticed the combing of the hair?
All the hair goes right through, not up and down, 3/4 of the hair in this side and 1/4 in that side.
She is sitting there and she looks very lifeless and she will not move, why?
She gives you the impression that if she moves she will spoil her hair, the hair perhaps
will go up and down, perhaps she will spoil the posture.
The posture is very important now for her, the appearance is very important.
But what is the life of this person? Living in a house without working.
She is unable to work, living in a house, opening the TV, reading the newspapers,
speaking in the phone and worrying. Worrying about whom?
About others, her father, a friend who has a heart problem and she is worrying about
others. Very limited life. Very lonely life.
You don't see the loneliness in this case?
When I asked you, only five people put up your hands.
You don't see loneliness? You don't see this lifeless person, living by herself,
completely isolated, gone inside?
She is gone completely inside, introverted without any life left to her, without any freedom.
She is restricted in a room. What she does? Just reading newspapers every day,
lookingbat the television, talk to some friends perhaps.
Not working, not doing anything, limited, lonely, tremendous loneliness and
now it comes the question of praying.
She is praying why? With so much loneliness inside, there is no contact.
She is dying, she is wasting away from life, going away.
Therefore she needs something to hold on, she needs some contact somewhere but
there is no human being to have contact with her.
It doesn't exist, she cannot form this kind of relationship, therefore she is holding with god.
She has to pray because it gives some kind of consolation, some kind of grip because of
the loneliness, tremendous loneliness, limitedness and restriction.
Imagine this person day after a day, what a pain, what a misery.
This is the impression I get and here she is standing there not to spoil her hair, it's very
important. She moves very slowly, otherwise her hair...
And I see her sitting neatly there and tremendous coldness.
The practitioner said she felt so cold after the remedy.
She gave her Mercury and then she was feeling so cold.
Syphilitic pains, those that they know the Materia Medica they get the idea.
What is the difference between you and me is that I take all the information inside,
I don't take what she says. What she says I don't even hear.
She says I have a pain here and there...It is not important. She is dying, there is no life.
What is happening? Now the pain here and there is that important?
Maybe, if you have a keynote of something but
what is important is the essence of this case.
What is the essence in this case, what appears to be?
After the analysis the whole class can say. What?
Look at praying.
What is the remedy?
-Veratrum.
-Veratrum? Veratrum is full of life and energy.
Feeling cold so much, dressed properly, meticulously.
Anxiety about others, look at anxiety about others.
Dressed very neatly, carefully, everything is very careful.
Freezing coldness.
What is your prescription now?
-Arsenicum.
-Who says Arsenicum?
I analyzed the facts. I didn't give you anything more than the facts.
I just constructed the facts.
Could anybody argue with the facts I gave you about this case? I projected a little with my
imagination, a little bit but not too much, because you can see she is doing nothing.
Can you imagine a person doing nothing every day?
Is it possible that this person is happy? No. Is it possible that she is lonely?
Yes she is very lonely, that is why she is praying.
It is not the praying of Aurum.
Aurum, I said it again and again. It is a compulsive praying for hours, no end.
It's a crazy situation, the same with the Veratrum album.
The praying of the Veratrum album has nothing to do with what she says.
Praying of the Veratrum album will be a person who goes out in the streets and say
repent, repent... a crazy person, who goes out and talks, he is crazy.
He is praying in front of others, he doesn't mind, he shouts. Have you seen this?
No, they close in the asylums all these cases.
This is not the case. She is praying in almost a logical way.
When praying is pathology because not everybody who prays is a nut but here we have pathology.
When we say Veratrum is praying, it prays in this way.
It prays very actively, it is shouting, it has the religious thing, it is the mental pathology in
Veratrum album.
In Aurum it will kneel down and pray for hours because the depression is so big.
It has to have an outlet of the depression, that's why Aurum is praying and
as soon as it stops praying, the depression overwhelms.
Here it is a person who needs some contact. She has to have something to hold on.
She has lost everything and if you don't reach that emotional state...you don't reach easily.
She has gone through big shocks.
What happened in her life we shall find out but
this is a situation where the person has gone through tremendous mental suffering to
arrive at that stage and we see it's terrible.
I've seen mental pathology and mental pathology is very deep.
-Why not Syphillinum? Superstitious, night aggravation, bone pains, tidy?
-Yes but the element of being dressed and being so proper, she will not even do a
movement that may be improper.
And also when we will put back the case you will hear the practitioner saying my god
she was freezing cold together with the anxiety about others, which she herself volunteers,
Arsenicum again.
Arsenicum freezing, Arsenicum anxiety about others, a praying, night aggravation yes
Arsenicum, syphilitic remedy yes Arsenicum. Why should you go away from Arsenicum?
You cannot.
This is a case of Arsenicum, as we said yesterday, I would like to show you a little bit more.
The idea is for this seminar to understand some aspects of Arsenicum.
What you have seen is a typical aspect of Arsenicum.
The way that an Arsenicum presents herself or himself is this way.
In this case it is a little bit accentuated, a little bit too much, this kind of perfection.
This kind of attitude which limits the individual who needs Arsenicum.
The individual who needs Arsenicum is limited by the appearances and what he sees and
what he wears and how he is. It's very limited.
Every Arsenicum will sit down like that.
It is in our Materia Medica, it is described the man or the woman who is very well dressed.
It is not very well dressed and is agile but he must not have creases.
An Arsenicum can wear the same clothes one week and you think he just put it on.
It says he little spoils his clothes, why? Because of that attitude.
He sits in that position, he will take of these things so much.
When an Arsenicum talks, he cannot talk like me, I cannot be Arsenicum. Never.
The Arsenicum will be talking like that, like that. This here, never.
It's an impulse, it's a compulsion for Arsenicum and you will see it again and again in
a different form, perhaps less or sometimes more but this is the aspect.
When I hear the practitioner I was impressed by the way she was feeling so much cold,
the syphilitic pains ...and there she comes. You don't need more, you can prescribe but
here the idea is not to prescribe, is to teach.
I would like to show you the aspects of Arsenicum. This case is so beautiful.
An Arsenicum has to be in order outside and inside.
A child sleeps, it is with fever and the mother comes to make the bed and the bed has to
be intact, immaculately, otherwise she is restless, she cannot tolerate the bed undone.
The person is limited, this is a symptom.
You may say order is a good thing, it is but up to a certain extend.
Once it is carried too far...
Why we say desire fruits is a symptom? Is it bad to eat fruits? No, but in order to have
desire fruits as a symptom, it has to be really gone very far because everybody likes fruits
except of Ignatia and Baryta carbonica and a few other remedies.
But in order to put it as desire fruits, it has to be real desire to say I have lived with fruits.
I can eat constantly fruits. Then you have a symptom.
Order, most people will like order, it doesn't mean that it's a symptom and you give
Arsenicum. He says I'm orderly, you don't give.
You give when the symptom becomes a limit, like this.
Now all her life she is limited. You will see the limitation of Arsenicum here.
She cannot go outside of her routine, she cannot communicate and interact.
Arsenicum cannot easily interact with others because this order prevents him.
It is easily disgusted, he wants order.
He wants time to fix his own things, putting up his clothes, it is a whole ceremony for him.
I told you a case of a doctor, we went to the sea to swim. So we finished swimming and I
dressed completely and he had just put on his...
And I was waiting and waiting to finish dressing. Now he goes to the shoes and I expect
he will take the lace and then he would take the two laces and measure them.
And the one was a little bit more than the other and then he would get it down and
measure it again and it was very little.
I was watching all this thing and I said my god he needs Arsenicum.
Then I said come on man, he said I'm coming, I'm coming. He wanted to be exact to be able
to tie his shoe laces. That kind of thing. This is the idea. Perfection.
It's impossible to be exactly the same thing here, what is there.
This idea you will perceive immediately in an Arsenicum case and when you see it,
it behaves like Arsenicum. The face is clean, even her hair...
I'll put 20 other women dressed in the same way and with the hair in front and you will see
the hair is not perfect and she is perfect.
Arsenicum is exhausted, the exhaustion of Arsenicum and at the same time restless.
Now you will say where is the restlessness here? There is no more life to be restless
here. It's so much lifeless.
I would like to see some other aspects of her.
-I happen not liking myself and feeling terrible and I don't feel like that.
-You enjoy life now?
-Yes I do. Sometimes I'm feeling absolutely the worse physically and
then sometimes I wonder how I can take it, I can go on.
-Then you feel that you want to end your life?
-I haven't really thought about that but I'm afraid that I would. It's really terrible.
Did you see a desire to commit suicide?
If you go to the Repertory suicidal disposition, you will see Aurum and you will see Natrum
sulphuricum and I have said about Arsenicum, when I did the differential diagnosis I said
Arsenicum, it is in italics? I think it is italics.
-Yes.
-I said that Arsenicum commits suicide, it is of those remedies that they can commit
suicide. They are other remedies that have the tendency, the impulse but
different other things prevent them.
Arsenicum is of the remedies that they really can commit suicide.
The idea behind Arsenicum is that she does not really enjoy life, it is too much for her and
she will decide to do it.
But she decides to do it, it's going to be almost a logical decision, I can't live.
What she says is, I'm enjoying life. This is not enjoying life you understand.
You will see more how she cannot enjoy life and she is not enjoying life.
Why this case cannot be Aurum? We differentiate now between Aurum and Arsenicum.
Because Aurum would have expressed...
If it does express the suicidal disposition, he says thinking of death is a very good
possibility, it is a very good outlet, this is the idea with Aurum.
It is a relief, if I could die, it would be a relief. Either this or it does not express it at all.
Therefore in this case, I would have taken that piece and I would say
what remedy can be this?
I would have extracted that piece where she says I don't really want but sometimes I have
been wanting to do it, this is not an expression of Aurum.
Aurum is deeper than this. It is a relief.
Aurum is somebody who all the time thinks about death.
On the background it is death. Whatever he does is death behind in his thinking.
-It all takes a little bit of relief...
-What is the history before? What else did you have before it started?
-I didn't have physically something.
-What did you feel that you had?
-I had a terrible experience in school, my parents transferred me into another school
because I had a fight with a teacher and that was terrible, I didn't have any friends for
almost three years and the other kids picked on me. I felt I can't ever go entirely over that
experience.
-What age that was?
-I was 10 when I went to that school and I was 13 when I went back to the public school.
-This was the first painful experience you had?
-I think so. I remember my parent fighting but that didn't bother me,
I don't remember being really terrible before that.
I did have a lot of colds when I was little and the doctor told my parents to...
sister and I used to get colds and respiratory infections and I was getting a lot of...
that stained my teeth but other I don't remember when I was young.
-Did you feel that you are a closed person or open?
-I'm closed.
-Very closed?
-I'm open to my friends.
-You have a lot of friends?
-Not a lot but I have a few very good friends.
-A few? Let's say 2-3?
-Three very, very good friends.
-You talk to them for what happens?
-Yes.
-Everything that happens in you, you will talk?
-There is nothing that you want to hide from them that you don't want to talk to anybody?
Is anything that bothers you inside that you don't want to talk to anybody?
-Nothing that bothers me. I have one or two secrets that I haven't talked to anybody but
most things I do discuss.
-About these two secrets do you feel that they have affected your life really?
-I don't think so, I think they are just things that are private. I don't think about them often.
-You were always have been a closed person?
-That was probably more when I went to the private school.
-Do you have a relationship, a boyfriend?
-No but I have an ex-boyfriend who is really my best friend, we are very close.
-How long before you have been together?
-About 10 years ago.
-For how long?
-For two years.
-Did you have full relationship? Did you have sexual relationship?
-When it was your first sexual experience?
-When I was 18.
-You were functioning OK in that respect?
-I think so.
-And now what do you feel?
-I'd like to have a boyfriend but I don't feel I suffer terribly from the lack of, I'd rather...
than to have somebody whom I don't go along with,
then I have to make a lot of painful compromises.
-At this moment would you say that you have an aversion for sex?
-No I don't think so, I'm a little afraid of getting involved but not an aversion.
What I'm driving at is I want to understand how she came into that psychological state.
What I perceive is that she had some very severe grief that was so much affected her life,
she has almost lost her life, she was withdrawn completely and
became like a mummy which she is now.
How a human being becomes like that unless there is a very powerful grief.
What kind of grief was that? I try to understand.
I try to see in the relationship what was happening.
Somebody must have said something terrible to her.
This is what I feel, like a boyfriend said something very nasty and then
she was hurt very much.
How one can become like that?
For me it is a very severe mental state.
-Are you a restless person?
-I'm pretty restless.
-Can you give an example of what you do?
-I find it hard to stand still like now that I'm sitting here I'm pretty tensed.
That is a very interesting comment, you see outside very little restlessness.
But inside she feels this restlessness, she describes it.
-I don't feel very comfortable sitting still.
But often I don't want to move, if I over exert myself and there is the pain on and I feel
tired in such a way that I just don't want to move.
Do you see the expression? Did you understand what she said?
She said if I move, if I exert, I feel such tiredness that finally I don't want to move, I try to
avoid moving because if I move, I feel very tired.
This is exactly what is the Arsenicum case.
If you go to the Materia Medica Kent describes it the person is restless, it is exhausted
and he has to move from one bed to the other, from one chair to the other until finally
he lies completely exhausted. This is what she describes.
She says if I keep on moving, I get so much exhausted that
I know I'm going to end up exhausted.
This is a very typical Arsenicum case, anxiety about others, praying, coldness,
this kind of fastidious appearance...
-I have weakness along with the pain like if I pick up a cloth and wear it,
it feels like a waste of time.
-So much? Do you do exercise?
-I just walk, I do some symmetric exercise.
-You complain about feeling in the mind that you cannot concentrate, you cannot understand.
Can you describe what is happening?
-If I'm reading a difficult paragraph, sometimes I read it several times and
I don't actually grasp, it's hard to concentrate.
Do you see? A remedy when it has a peculiar symptomatology, in one way or another,
you may perceive this peculiarity of the remedy in all three levels.
The restlessness, which is in the physical body can be perceived in the mental sphere
as well and an Arsenicum person cannot concentrate and his mind wonders.
There is a restlessness on the mind that it cannot sit still and concentrate in one point,
that's what she says.
Not that every Arsenicum will have affection on three levels but you may not find the
restlessness on the physical level and you find it on the mental level or the emotional level.
-Often I just wonder why trying to concentrate on something I get distracted.
-When you lie in bed...
-Usually when I'm tired and sleepy then I go to bed and then it starts getting worse.
-And in bed you are restless? You cannot keep a position for a long period of time?
You have to change positions?
-Yes constantly quite a bit. I think now I fall asleep but before...
-Do you have a special position where you want to sleep?
-usually lying on the one side
-what kind of food do you eat?
-Sardines and mustard. Salty things, very salty.
Do you see?
If you don't take into consideration all the other things that we have talked about
she says now what I like is sardines and salty things and you see grief and salty and
you take these two and you give Natrum muriaticum.
And you miss the case because this is not a case of Natrum muriaticum.
You see the fastidiousness in the appearance, this deadness, this attitude.
You don't have the Nat mur but also the praying, the freezing, the feeling of the coldness,
you will not find this in Nat mur.
There are a lot of points against Nat mur and in favor of Arsenicum.
There is desire for salt and finally you go to the Repertory and
you look is there any desire for salt for Arsenicum? No.
So it means either that Arsenicum has desire for salt but it is not recorded in the Repertory or
later after the Arsenicum you may have another remedy coming up that has
desire for salt and either Arsenicum will take away the desire for salt or it will remain and
it will be the characteristic of another underlined remedy.
-I do have bread and carbohydrates and sweets, definitely sweets.
-More salt or sweet?
-Both, equally.
And I get ferociously hungry before my period.
Weakness, I also feel that sometimes any effort is a big work,
just to get dressed sometimes is a huge task.
-You feel so tired?
-Yes very tired and weak and the pain makes it hard, just to get anything done,
just to walk around.
Sometimes I feel so exasperated, oh god it is a huge task just to do the simplest thing.
Sometimes I feel mentally that life is very hard and I feel overwhelmed by anything that
I have to do just to survive.
Sometimes I don't get the bills paid, my house doesn't get clean...
Look at your Repertory, 1419, 1418 look at the rubric weakness from pain.
Also she said I feel so exasperated because of that situation.
Translate it into the language of the Repertory.
Despair of what? Of recovery. That she will not get well.
Look at the page 36 for despair of recovery.
She is freezing, restless, praying, dressed as she is, weak from pain,
big effort to do anything, suicidal disposition.
You are a graduating class, so you should go away from the description of the letter,
as it is. Go to the essence of things.
From a description of a rubric like despair for recovery and weakness from pain,
construct a human being with your imagination.
Because what you are dealing is not a rubric, you are dealing with a human being on a
three dimensional size.
The rubrics are giving you hints but what you have to do is the suffering.
You understand the suffering? What kind of suffering, what type of suffering,
how it came to be that kind of suffering,
where is this leading, what kind of limitations are there?
She wants to die but she wants to die very well dressed. That is Arsenicum.
Immediately you have the perception. She wants to die but she has to be very...
What is there? What is so important that she wants to dress the moment she wants to
commit suicide tomorrow?
Then the pain and the exasperation and the exhaustion, she lies down and she says,
I can't do it, that's not a life, let me finish with life.
That is synthesis, synthesing and perceiving finally as a symptomatology,
you take here and there that kind of thing.
That is now the construction, you have this model and you see it once, twice, three, four,
five times and then you perceive this is the model, this is Nat mur.
I remember another case in London that was typical Staphysagria.
It didn't cross my mind that it might have been Nat mur at all.
So some students said we thought this is Nat mur, such grief and...
I said yes but it didn't cross my mind, why it crossed the mind of somebody else?
Because he takes the rubric ailments from grief and applies it there.
Ailments from grief Nat mur. Staphysagria is different in her mentality,
the way that she reacts towards grief than Nat mur.
This is Arsenicum, this is different. Now if I'm going because desire for salt.
Forget desire for salt here. This is the idea, forget it here. This is not a Nat mur case.
She was given Nat mur with no effect. It cannot have an effect Nat mur with this case.
What it has to do with Nat mur, it does not perform in this way.
Nat mur can be very introverted and can be very stiff but it's another type all together.
It's a very interesting case because we'll give Arsenicum and she will come back and
she will say nothing, I'm the same.
That's why I brought the case. I didn't bring you the case to say that we have cured it.
I brought you certain problems that you are going to face.
Now after you have done all this analysis and after you sat down for one hour,
you analyzed and said this is a typical case of Arsenicum, take Arsenicum 10M and
then she comes back and she says I'm the same.
No changed? No changed. Still the pain? The pain is there, everything is there.
If you don't know the laws in this game, she almost misled me,
if you don't know the laws in this game,
you will be completely mislead to believe that there was nothing there and
I will show you one point, of great interest. I will show you why.
The follow up here is very interesting but first I want to give you the idea.
I know you are tired, but she gives information and
this information try to perceive it like a piece of art because for us we understand, we perceive,
this is Arsenicum.
We recognize something special in a human being and then it becomes very important.
Unless you see it this way then it's boring information, desires salt, don't desire salt...
What is there? Just information that is thrown to you.
-I don't get depressed usually of how things go.
-When you wake up in the morning do you feel refreshed or unrefreshed?
-Usually somewhat refreshed.
-You said you are very superstitious,
can you give us an example of what you mean by that?
-If I think that something bad happened to my father, I'm afraid that
even just thinking about that I will make it happen,
I'm afraid to make certain thoughts and it can be one
thing or another. If I think something good could happen...
If I meet a man that I like, I'm afraid to tell my friends about it because
I'm afraid to tell them will make it not happen, although it is irrational.
If I'm talking about bad things, I'll make them happen, if I'm not talking about good things,
I'll make them not happen, this is just a general fear of thinking or saying...
I guess I feel that I have to pray, I'm afraid that something could happen.
-Do you cry easily?
-Not really easily. Sometimes I cry for sentimental things, a sentimental movie on TV.
But I don't cry very easily just for sadness, feeling sorry for myself and start crying.
What would you like more as a confirmation for Arsenicum? What you would like to have?
Just find me a more precise keynote for Arsenicum where
Arsenicum is almost alone capital with a few other remedies...
That is if you had this confirmation.
You would like to ask what?
-I thought about this anxiety in the morning.
-I'll tell you another characteristic of Arsenicum is that
they usually have an insecurity concerning financial matters.
Arsenicum needs to know that has money in the bank but
always the money in the bank must be more than what they need. That kind of attitude.
Arsenicum is not a person who spends money, it is a person who collects money,
who wants, who takes but it does not spend.
How do you find this in the Repertory?
Avarice!
You see Arsenicum is very strong because this trait of Arsenicum has been
pointed out by all homeopaths. It is a very strong trait of Arsenicum.
Avarice is the same idea of not letting things out, keeping things, clinging to persons,
holding the persons, fearing to face the challenges of the world unprepared.
They have to be very well prepared, very well done, meticulously.
Let's see a little bit more.
-Is there any time that you feel worse or best?
-I guess worse is when I first get up in the morning.
-And best?
-Best in the afternoon...