I would like to give you another case.
There is a case of recurrent herpes on the left hand.
It's a woman 31 years old.
She was married on 1980, she is happy with the marriage.
The date is 14th of April 1982.
She has great irritability, underlined 3 times.
If I let this irritability out, then I become calm. It's going away.
I'm very inside...
I don't take things easily. Everything I don't say never mind.
The word never mind does not occurs to me, this type of person.
If I have some kind of quarrel in my work, then that problem comes in my mind
and then it stays there all the time that I'm at home.
I can forgive but I do not forget.
She can forgive but cannot forget, underlined 2-3 times.
Fear of death, underlined 3 times.
She has metaphysical agonies, the night especially when she goes to bed.
Metaphysical questions.
Easily offended, underlined 3 times.
Jealous, underlined twice.
Wakes up unrefreshed, sleeps in all positions.
Worse in spring time, more irritability.
Sometimes I have the tendency to go away but I don't know what whould please me.
I like the sea but I'm afraid that I may drown myself.
Does not like tight clothes in the body, underlined twice.
Desires fish, fruits, underlined once.
Sweets normal, thirst normal, sex normal.
No reactions to temperature, neither she feels cold nor hot.
She has a duodenal ulcer also but at the moment she came she had no symptomatology.
That woman had come about 3 years ago and had taken the same remedy she received now
and she did well for 3 years, she took antibiotics.
But now the doctor takes a new case, it's as if it is new.
Anybody wants to do the analysis of the case?
-She has underlined 3 times the fear of death and with that there are several other keynotes.
Worse spring, dislikes tight clothing and great irretability.
When she discharges the emotions, she feels better ...
The metaphysical questions is again Lachesis, the can forgive
but can't forget... of Lachesis.
-Who agrees with that analysis?
-With some.
-Anybody else? Any other suggestion?
-The great irritability...and the fear of death...
-Nitric acid. Who agrees with that? Another?
-Nux vomica.
-Very good. Very well justified, especially the Lachesis is very well justified.
Ailments like reaction to temperature that's OK.
Now what I want to show you is...
Sometimes we prescribe on essence.
That's a case we rely mostly on essence because you see if you take it this way,
it comes out that, if you take it the other way, comes out another remedy.
Nux vomica is quite well justified also.
So here we are not sure about the essence.
If we are going to prescribe on essence here, we shall not be happy so far.
I would not be happy that this is the remedy or that is the remedy.
I'm not happy with Lachesis, I'm not happy with Nux vomica, I'm not happy with Nitric acid.
I'll give you one more information...
You will see what I mean the essence. Now everybody will say yes...
You see how you change your choice?
By completing the information how the choice changes
and everybody is sure that this the remedy?
She is very anxious about her husband, what is going to happen to him.
Nobody knows that? Don't open the Repertories.
Who knows that rubric?
You open the Repertory. Anxiety about her husband.
That's what she says, what is going to happen to him?
She is afraid about his situation. Health, security, that's general.
Has anybody found the rubric? Which page?
Page 7 on the right side.
Did anybody find page 7, column b, in the middle of that column.
-Anxiety for others?
-No, for husband.
-It's under fear.
I thought that you knew that but you thought anxiety about others.
Did you see now? What page is it?
-45.
-Second column in the middle.
Now what are you going to prescribe? I may be misleading you.
We go further. Look a little bit more fear of death.
Platina is there?
Now, I would want some more information.
She says I'm a big egoiste.
She has the tendency to put down everyone who doesn't agree with her.
She has sometimes the impression that people are very small.
You see what I mean prescribe on essence?
This is prescribe on essence.
You don't care about the herpes, weather it is on the left side,
whether the tight clothes is very much Platina or not. You don't even look.
You go to the essence, you say this is Platina, give 10M and it will be cured.
But you see how some lack of information can distort the whole picture
and can lead us to different other remedies?
You see how the picture develops eventually?
It comes out and becomes alive and then you are sure.
This is what we mean prescribing on essence.
You forget the totality here and you see the fear of death of course is there
and other little things that you will not find in Platina but that does not matter.
You prescribe on essence and it's going to work.
We have some more minutes, you can ask questions.
What it means in terms of layers the weak vital force?
I don't use the weak vital force, the defense mechanism?
This is confused sometimes with the vitality.
A weak defense mechanism does not imply a weak vitality.
What do I mean by that?
I mean that a mental case which is incurable, you may have tremendous vitality,
a hyper-activity, vitality that he will never sleep, he goes on for hours and hours
and the strength is increased and all this tremendous vitality.
But the defense is broken down, it is deteriorated the defense mechanism.
So I would like you to differentiate between that.
You see somebody with great vitality, it's not always a sign of very good health
or he will live to 100 years old.
Tremendous vitality...
You will see cases of cancer, people dying at the age of 38, 42, 45 with tremendous vitality.
He was very vital, full of life, enjoying this, that, the picture of a very healthy man
and then they tell you he was looking very healthy, he had nothing.
There is some kind of shock and the whole thing collapses.
The defenses behind are not in order and erupts the cancer...
And you see the person dies within a few months, no defenses at all.
So we must differentiate between the vitality and broken defense mechanism.
A defense, which is not in good order.
I didn't follow the argument.
-A person that had hay fever, who normally gets it from April to June, we treat him on April
so he had a month before he starts... what would you expect the reaction when the allergic season starts.
-If it is the right remedy, not to have the allergy.
-He wouldn't have it anymore?
-No.
I was thinking that you were enquiring on the same subject but you were talking on
a completely different thing.
He would have no more allergy or he would have very mild.
-What about an aggravation?
-She would an aggravation one month before. The aggravation might be a headache
or whatever it is after taking the remedy.
-...you expect when we give a remedy, if the remedy is correct those symptoms will disappear?
-Yes.
-Even if you think that there was amelioration but the herpes continue or skin eruption
or the allergies we would assume that the remedy was correct and ...
-Yes, a few symtpoms can be from a deeper layer but talking about allergies
and when he comes for his allergy, that is the thing that bothers him,
you cannot say that that comes from a deeper layer.
From a deeper layer can come a sensitivity to onions, you cannot tolerate onions at all.
That may not be covered by the first remedy and it remains
together with a few other symptoms perhaps that will develop later with the next remedy.
But when he comes for the headache, the headache will be the first to go.
What it may happen is that the person may come for something light,
where in reality something is very serious with him.
So that which is light and which is more external may be aggravated in the process
and the others which are deeper problems, they get better.
That may happen that the herpes may break out tremendously
by becoming better in her psychology, in her mental state.
-Another question about allergy.
People come in with acute and what I've been doing is I give them the remedy
that covers that and say come back in one month and I take again your case.
In the mean while you say that is not the right thing to do, did I understand you?
-Yes. It's not the right thing. Sometimes you don't have anything more to do
because the person does not give you symtpoms.
Even Kent comments on that particular question.
He says if you don't know what to do, you prescribe a remedy...
he will come back on each own and then search for a better solution.
That is a little portion of the whole thing, what we are talking.
-We were discussing acute (?) It seems to me that the discussion on acute (?)
could be on some circumstances an acute otitis media on each own
and at other circumstances could be an acute exacerbation.
-Sure.
-So you have to differentiate that in your mind.
-What can happen is an acute but I was talking about a case that has been suffering
with recurrent otitis. But this can happen, to complete isolate an episode.
Like cold that then develops as a complication and goes to the ears.
-In case of migraine and headaches where the patient is Natrum Mur and when they have a migraine headache, they produce a picture of Bry
you think you you can give Natrum mur because it is all in one layer?
-No. In a case of migraine, you have a layer of Bryonia how? By what process?
-Every week they get a headache...
-The local symptoms indicate Bryonia and the general symptoms indicate Nat mur?
You give Nat mur, don't give Bryonia.
-You don't have to wait for the headache to leave?
-No. That belongs to the same pattern. That is what I did.
You say this picture is Bryonia? It doesn't mean that it is.
When I say you, I mean me or whoever says it.
-In the epidermic genital herpes there is (?)
In my experience, which is not so much, it is difficult to treat homeopathically
on what seems to be better but it's not really cured
and I wonder if the generation makes it difficult?
-Also probably the remedy is not correct.
You touch on similar remedy because people have just local symptoms
and they don't give you anymore symtpoms and you sometimes touch on a similar remedy
but not the similimum, not exactly.
And there is an amelioration for a while and then it comes back.
-Under more experienced homeopath obviously I thought that I got the wrong remedy.
-It's not easy to treat, I accept but the reaction that you are telling me
is because of the wrong remedy. But it's difficult to treat.