-Your feet are better warm or cold?
-They are freezing always.
-Do you like milk?
-I like it with cookies and something sweet but
I don't just drink it usually unless I have something sweet.
It's hard to say, it's both the tiredness and the pain together.
The last 5-6 months my menstrual cramps have got very bad again,
they were dramatically better after the last remedy that you gave me the Colocynthis,
they almost cleaned up for 4-5 months.
That is another thing. She was given Colocynthis and
the menstrual cramps got much better.
What Colocynthis did?
It affected the person only on local aspect.
What you are aiming at this person is with your remedy to go very deep and
change the mental-emotional structure that has been crystallized for years.
You are aiming at changing the structure,
you don't care about the pains.
What you care is about the psychopathology which is there and
to see that this has been touched ,this untouchable situation.
Nothing can reach her to touch her, it has to break up, it has to break up.
Something is happening to that girl that she is crystallized almost.
You feel an element of crystallization is there, she is going to become a mummy,
she is going to develop the Raynaud's syndrome very soon.
This is the idea of Raynaud, the crystallization, the vessels lose their elasticity,
their possibility to carry the blood to the extremities and
the person dies from the extremities onwards in the physical body.
That is the idea of Raynaud's syndrome.
She is going to get it and then she will become arteriosclerotic completely.
Your remedy is not the menstrual cramps, you gave a remedy and
the menstrual cramps are better, thank you very much.
If you see it like that and then you see the same situation, you have done nothing.
That's why we have to learn to understand when the remedy is acting correctly and
deeply and when the remedy is acting superficially and affecting only little parts,
especially of the physical body.
That's why we can't say Homeopathy is this way or that way and
we can give 10-15 remedies and why you are fighting. We are not fighting.
We try to show that this kind of Homeopathy is much more rewarding first for
the patient and then for the practitioner.
Because you will see she will come and say nothing.
Nothing, no change, the pains are even worse.
Then I said now wait.
I received a telephone call just before I left Greece in May from America,
she said she has been without pains and
the pains have started to return after 6 or 7 months from the prescription of the remedy.
But you will see the follow up here and
you will see what happens. I'm sure you don't want to see any more of this case...
Later on I will ask you about the avarice element, can you go just to the end because
it is towards the end of the case, where I asked her about how careful she is with her money.
And you will see the answer how it comes. She says I'm very careful, I have to
calculate  every bit of money I spent and then I found a rubric which is very interesting.
Desires more things than he has, look at the page 35.
-It seems to me that you had some experiences in your life that have affected you very much and
you made some concrete beliefs in you, certain things you decided this is so.
-That is probably true.
-These experiences were very deep and very hurting but not overt, they were very subtle.
-You mean something that I'm not even aware?
-No, you are aware.
What I explained to her here that most probably you have some very painful experiences,
that made you feel that...
There is no love, there is no affection, there is no friendship,
some concrete conclusions she came about
and she has crystallized but to break through that it's very difficult.
There is a point where she talks about her avarice element,
this difficulty in spending the money.
-When did you take the remedy?
-Two weeks ago on Monday. Two weeks plus three days.
-It is 18 days. How do you feel it?
-I didn't get my sleep at all but yesterday I felt terrible. I felt like...
-I don't want to hear about on day, I want to hear in general.
Since you took the remedy what is the situation?
-It's been bad, physically terrible.
-You mean you felt worse.
-Yes.
-With the exception of today?
-Yes today I don't feel too bad but the other days very bad,
18 days that I didn't feel really terrible but most of the time I was pretty bad.
-How was the next day after you took the remedy?
-I think I felt pretty good.
-After the remedy. You felt exceptionally good?
-No, I think no difference from before I take the remedy and then
in a few days I started to feel worse.
-You felt that the remedy has done nothing?
-I may be having a reaction because I feel a little worse since I took it.
-In what respect?
-More pain.
-Where are your pains?
-My arms and hands, especially in my shoulders, the upper body but
especially in my head and my hands and arms.
-When you say head what do you mean?
-Sometimes I have a headache but it's all over my scalp but
I'm talking mainly about the pain which is in here behind my nose,
sore throat and my eyelids were very sore,
they felt like burning sensation.
-Out of these pains which are the most prominent?
-This pain around my eyes and behind my nose.
What really bothers me is the pain in my head.
-How was the insomnia?
What do you think so far?
-She has more grief?
-Who can tell me exactly? You see there is more grief, there is a change but
somebody else to define it differently??
-She is breaking down.
-More angry.
-She is exhausted.
-She is not so smooth.
-The face, yes.
Let us say she looks more tired and more old, isn't it an element of that?
As if she has aged too fast.
He says her hair is different. It is not. Actually it is exactly the same,
only the 3/4 here instead of lying here she has changed the style and put it over there.
This is the difference. Still her dress is very meticulous.
I know Americans they don't care about dress really.
For her being an American to be dressed in this way, old fashioned almost,
this is an old fashioned dressing for an American to be dressed at this moment.
It is typical of Arsenicum.
Now there are a few things we have to evaluate. She says I'm a little bit worse.
Can we take it as an aggravation? We can take it as an aggravation but there is one but.
If we take it as an aggravation on the physical level,
we have to see a similar amelioration on the mental-emotional level before
we can pronounce and say this is an aggravation.
If we don't see that the aggravation is undefined, it is not really strong to persuade and
to say this is really and aggravation.
So what I would like to see is an amelioration somewhere on the emotional side.
I can see this aging there. Something has happened. Some experience took place that
made her more alive, coming into contact. She was not into contact with life.
She gave me the impression that she was not in contact with real life,
she was just living in a world on her own, with her pains, limitations, misery, tragedies...
Now if she wakes up to the real world, she is 34... How old is she?
She is looking too young for her age.
When she wakes up and comes in contact with the world, she is going to age very fast.
This is one thing you will see with your mental cases.
The mental cases do not usually have the wrinkles or the signs in the face of the
experience in life because experience in life has gone over them.
Once you bring them back to real life, you see the lines in the face become prominent and
you see life going on.
If you look in the face of everybody of you, you will see the lines,
you will see the experiences of life and
that is why you can say you have been through this,
you have been through that, you have been through that...
Because you see the lines in the face and
something tells you a story because of the experience.
In mental cases you will see unbroken faces.
And you give the remedy and the remedy brings back the life,
as if the memory of the experiences is depicted upon the face and
the face becomes really expressive and
gives the experiences of life then.
This case I try to find out how much better she might have been emotionally or mentally.
Is she better? What happened inside in the very deep part of her.
I want to find out what is happening and she still has this attitude,
this unexpressive attitude that you cannot penetrate.
I'm going to be a little bit aggressive with her and you will see it,
because what I want to know is whether the remedy has acted.
Until now I'm not convinced that the remedy is acting.
I see a kind of aggravation but can I take it as an aggravation? I'm not sure at all.
-I wasn't too bad and then towards the end of this past week I got really bad and
I went to sleep at 4 o'clock in the morning for a number of days.
I took some pills, I lost my will power, they have antihistamine,
so they helped me sleeping. So for a couple of days I took that.
-This last night? For 2-3 nights?
-Yes for 3 nights.
-The previous nights you had been sleeping tolerably well?
-Before these 3 nights it has been about 4 nights that I haven't got to sleep but
at four o'clock in the morning and I got the feeling that I couldn't handle it anymore.
-How much of these pills you took?
-Two each night.
-And they are made especially for sleep or you made them yourself?
-No, it is for pain and I know that there is one other ingredient which is antihistamine and
it makes you sleepy.
-How was your psychological state during this time?
-Not bad most of the time, not as bad as the physical pain but as I said yesterday and
the day before I've been through really terrible psychological...
-The fact that you are feeling better psychologically and in yourself did not prevent you
from taking these other drugs, so you don't spoil the treatment?
-No.
-Because after you took it, you saw immediately the effect,
after you took it the last 2-3 days you are feeling rotten again psychologically.
-That is true but I don't really know.
-You didn't connect it. You take it every day the remedy?
-No, I just took two doses in one day. Just in one day.
-That's all.
So if I understand well your sleep was improved and
your psychological state was improved for 10-12 days and
after that because you couldn't sleep for 2-3 days,
you started taking again the antihistamine and then the pains were worse from the third day?
-I can't really say that the pains are any worse now.
-Yes but after the Tylenol the pains went back to the normal?
-I don't think so. I don't think that they are any worse for two weeks.
-No they are better.
You say now for a few days the pains are better where before they were stronger.
That is what you said, if you play back.
-That's what you said, the last few days you are feeling a little better but before that
it was terrible.
-About the pains.
-No I said today.
-Just today it's better.
-Several days before today I felt very bad physically and emotionally but
I don't think I felt worse physically,
I think I only felt worse emotionally the last couple days.
-What I say is that the couple few days you felt worse emotionally but
you felt better physically.
That means the pains the last 2-3 days are not as severe now as
they were 10-15 days ago.
-I'm not really sure.
-You are not sure because this is what you have been implying before.
-I'm sorry I'm confused. I don't remember what I said but it seems to me ...
You see the moment I try to get the facts there is an element in her that
she does not want to give the facts.
What she wants to say is that I'm worse and there is no problem and
no matter how I try to put into order the facts,
what really happened, she will not give the facts.
Either because she is not in the mental position to give the facts or
because there is a sub-conscious element of what? Can anybody tell me?
-Resistance.
-Resistance, there is a subconscious element of resistance. You don't feel it?
Your treatment has done nothing.
What she implied so far is that the first few days she felt good,
she slept but the pains started being more and
then because her sleep was disturbed and
the pains were strong she took Tylenol and the other thing.
The pains went down after Tylenol and now she felt bad psychologically again.
I tried to make sure that these facts are so and she will not confirm it.
What I perceive is that there is a resistance.
You have to be very aware of subtle things happening because in this particular case,
you realize that this person has crystallized, has taken a position in life that says,
here I am.
She has put her back on the wall and
says here I am.
You come to break down all this position, this philosophy,
whatever has brought this kind of attitude, you come to break it down and
you have to do it fast because the students in the class are waiting for you to make a mistake.
They say that is the wrong medicine, give another medicine.
I have to really find out did I give the wrong medicine? Is it the wrong medicine or
do I have to wait? Because if I make a mistake, the mistake will show later on.
So I'm very attentive of what I'm perceiving here. I'm perceiving a resistance.
And I say to myself now why this resistance? What she wants?
And then it clicks in my mind. This is what is happening and
you will hear what is happening.
-Physical pain has been pretty persistent throughout the 18 days. It's been the same.
-But you said it was worse.
-After I took the remedy?
-Yes, the pains were worse than before.
-Yes.
-Did you say that?
-The last three days are worse or as before?
-Oh, a little bit worse than before.
-But now it is worse than 10 days ago?
-I really don't remember how much better it was.
-The thing is that you stopped the action of the remedy by taking Tylenol.
-Really? I don't have much will power when it gets...
You see what she says here is I don't have much will power, so I took the Tylenol.
She has much will power as long as she feels things are going to be staying as
they are and suddenly she loses her will power and she takes the Tylenol.
She knows that if she takes another medicine because
she is under homeopathic treatment for the last 2-3 years,
if she takes another medicine she will spoil the treatment or will delay the treatment.
She knows that.
The third, fourth day of the treatment she goes and starts taking the medicine.
Again another point for me to confirm what I have been thinking about her.
What do you think it is happening? You will see.
-My will power is weak.
-By taking it you revert back the old pattern, that means less pains but insomnia strong,
psychologically bad, energy wise bad.
During the first 10 days, did you see any increase in your energy?
-No.
-If you don't speak honestly, we cannot help you.
-I know it exactly.
-You have to tell exactly and you have to realize that
you have to tell me exactly what happened before and after.
Before I was so much and now after the remedy I'm worse.
I don't care if you say I'm worse or I'm better, as long as you tell me the truth.
-I'm doing my best to remember exactly. I wouldn't try to mislead you.
-Because if you mislead me, there is no possibility that we will help you.
We rely completely on what you say, we don't have any measure whether
you tell the truth or you tell something to mislead us.
-I'm aware of that.
-Maybe out of your thoughts, you may think it is good if I say this or it is bad if I say that
and you intellectualize, you bring out the information, without giving the real information.
Yes the second day I was rotten, the third day I was much better...
I don't feel that coming from you. I feel that you think about it...
-I'm trying to remember, it's hard for me to remember.
-But you remember that you were worse. How do you remember when you were worse and
you remember you were better psychologically also.
-I think I was better psychologically. I'm very confused right now,
I can't remember whether I was or not.
What do you think it's happening inside her?
She says I'm very confused, I can't remember.
She actually imposes a kind of confusion upon her.
It is like somebody who is threatened.
Now a resolution has come very close, so he imposes a kind of confusion,
so we don't know what is happening and we are out of the situation.
This is my impression.
Therefore what is the conclusion? What is the natural thing for me to think about her?
What am I thinking about her now? Given the facts that she wants,
she does not want to give me the facts.
-She is improving.
-She feels emotion at this moment more than before.
-She does not want to improve.
She gives me the impression that she does not want to get well.
I suddenly perceived that what she is having at this moment,
the government security she receives, the disability things,
the life that has been limited she doesn't want to change that, she is afraid to change that.
-She had these complains for a long time and there is a certain order and
when things are changing becoming in this order then
that fits to the Arsenicum type because then
she wants to bring them back to order.
-Now she is confused.
-But these ideas are not strong enough for me to say, she is doing better.
Still she has confused me. Was she really better psychologically? I could not get it.
Is she really worse physically? I could not confirm it.
But what I perceive finally out of all this struggle between her and me to get the truth,
I perceive finally a resistance, she does not want to get well.
This realization comes to my mind, she does not want to change and
she feels now the change is too close and she resists. Now what shall I do if that is true?
-Reassurance for a new situation.
-Would you say before that she was lifeless, now she is still secure with anxiety,
would you say she was better than what she would like to?
-I can't because they are not clear facts, I cannot rely, I cannot tell you she is doing better
because there is insecurity now and therefore she is better.
I can't say to the students things like that because
it is too much imagination put into the case. I would imagine a lot.
What I perceive is there is definitely a resistance of getting better. What shall I do?
Let us you came to the realization that she does not want to get better?
How you proceed?
-Tell her.
We have the interval and you will hear the continuation.
Desires, aversions you said mustard and also Arsenicum has desire for olive oil fat.
I've seen Arsenicum cases where they drink olive oil. It is so much the desire.
Mustard also is there in your Repertory? Desire for olive oil you can add it as Arsenicum.
This was the situation we arrived.
As you saw, I could not make a decision whether the remedy had acted or not.
Then I realized that there is a resistance, so I'm thinking what shall I do?
But how to show it? You can't teach in the class and
say I think there is a resistance to treatment.
They will say we know all these excuses.
So I decided to put forward a question, to ask her straightaway to find out whether really
she didn't want to get well. Was it in her conscious mind?
Is it something that she perceives already or
is it something she does completely unconsciously?
That is one thing that may be lead me to believe that perhaps Arsenicum still is acting,
it is the right remedy etc. and we shall not change it but
what I still wanted to perceive is an
opening up, a breaking out on deep emotional level.
I wanted to see a tangible fact that Arsenicum has really started breaking down that
crystallization, which we see here.
And don't forget that some of the student remark while I was outside that
all of us have crystallizations.
When you come to a seminar of that type with preconceived ideas with
what is right, is the same resistance.
You may find it in yourself, inside, in breaking down preconceived thinking about
Homeopathy. So it is the inner struggle you have to go through also.
Let's see what happened.
-I'm asked whether I was better emotionally after taking the remedy?
I really can't remember. I know I felt physically worse but it seemed to me that my mood
went up and down and sometimes I felt very discouraged and sometimes I felt more
emotionally strong and I can't remember whether that emotional state sometimes good
and sometimes bad was any better or worse than before I took the remedy.
I'm only aware that the physical pain was worse.
-Did you say that you slept better up to a certain time. Is that true?
-Yes about a week. Then after that first week I started...
-After the first week or the first weeks?
-The first week, then it started being badly and
not being able to get to sleep until 4 o'clock in the morning.
-What potency?
-I think 200 and 1M.
-You are in the house most of the time?
-Yes, I go to do my own grocery shopping and sometimes I visit people but not very often.
They usually come to me and I read and I've writing some songs...
Sometimes I get a takeout dinner,  have dinner in my house,
I watch television usually in the evening.
-But your schedule continued to be the same during these two weeks.
-Pretty much the same. I was a little less physically active...
You see if the remedy had acted, it would have created some kind of urge for a human contact.
I expect it if the remedy had acted.
I ask questions that she does not understand whether she will give me the answers I want.
Whether she was going out more for instance,
whether she was calling a friend to come and have more intercourse with them.
Whether she started moving inside, having the need for a human contact because
she was so isolated, so alone before.
And if the remedy is breaking through, perhaps some kind of contact because that
isolation is the most hard thing in this case to break down.
She may give me an answer that she will not understand, then I will make sure that the
remedy is working, then I will be at ease and I will say placebo.
But until that time I'm not sure and still I'm not sure. Yet at this moment of the interview
I'm not sure whether the remedy has acted or not.
-You got out less?
-Yes.
-Your appetite was the same as before?
-I lost my appetite for about a week after taking the remedy.
-You lost completely your appetite?
-Not completely but I lost some weight. I lost two pounds.
-Did you like that?
-No.
-You want to pick up weight?
-I can give you a remedy that you can pick up weight very easily, is that OK with you?
-If you think it will do me good, yes OK.
You see the human nature? I said you lost weight.
What she tells me all the time is she remembers everything bad that happens.
She remembers the first week she lost weight, she remembers the first week she lost her
appetite, she remembers she lost two pounds the first week, she does not remember
anything positive that happened. She remembers all the negative.
What about your appetite? Oh my appetite yes, now I fix you.
I lost my appetite the first week.
She knows that is not a good symptom and to prove that she lost her appetite,
she says I lost two pounds in a week.
Did you like it? Then she backs up again.
All this play is to bring out the resistance. No, I don't like to lose weight.
That means you want to pick up weight.
We have a remedy I can give you to pick up weight.
She is afraid now, I may give her a remedy to pick up weight but it was bad that
she lost her appetite and she lost one kilo.
Now I tell her I give you a remedy to pick up weight,
no I don't want that.
She is projecting everything which is bad. The treatment is not successful, I'm not better,
I'm worse and I'm trying to give you this, I don't remember, confusion.
Everything that goes on in the case is for me a resistance to give me the facts.
More and more I confirm that really she does not want to get well.
She is set up in that situation and she is afraid, insecure to go into another state where
if she is well, the first thing which she has to do is to go out and work.
Back to work but back to work is back to this jungle of people, competitions,
she has to keep the job and she is very insecure, afraid of that.
-Do you really want to be well?
-Yes I do.
-Are you sure or you are quite set in this kind of situation where you say I'm unable,
I can't do anything and this environment feels secure for you and
you don't want to change it, to go out and seek a job?
Have you thought about that issue?
-Yes I thought and I feel familiar with the way I handle my life right now and I feel that
most of the time I'm able to deal with it and it is frightening for me to go out and work and I
don't really know how I'm going to do that but
that doesn't stop me from wanting to be well because I'm suffering and I don't want to.
-But if you are well, you are going to be forced to go out and work.
-That's true and that frightens me.
Do you see? She has thought about that issue, to go out and work is very frightening.
It is very difficult for her. She verbally says, well it doesn't stop me from wanting to be well
but it's really a frightening issue for me to think that I have to go out and work.
-Have you dealt with that matter intellectually? You said you thought about this,
what is your decision?
You have decided that I really want to get well and when I'm well
I can go out and work and deal with the issues of the world?
-I decided that I have to... that I'm doing and when I'm able to do more,
I will do more and tell that I really can take care of myself.
I'm trying not to be in anxiety about, I'm trying to think it's going to get better.
-When did you stop working?
-About 6 years ago I had a part time job but it was only once the week and
I didn't work for 2-3 years before that.
-What company?
-I was a cleaning lady.
-Did you make enough money?
-Yes it was enough.
Do you see the issue? Do you perceive what is happening inside her?
If I'm well, I'm not skilled, I have to go and work out as a cleaning lady.
Do you see with what you are battling now?
You have given a remedy and you are battling to break through this set up situation.
I asked her, are you happy with this set up? She said yes because
I learned how to deal now and my life is ordered and
I know what to do.
I'm frightened to think that if I'm well I have to go out and work.
Looking superficially in this case and not understanding,
would you change your remedy here? You would change your remedy.
You would say I made a mistake.
You expect other things to happen, they cannot happen in this case.
That's too deep crystallization, too hard things happening inside to break down so fast.
But still the remedy if it was correct, it has to produce that, what I expect to be a
break through in some area in her life.
That's why it takes me so long with the interview to try to understand what is happening.
In some area in her life a breakthrough must have happened if the remedy was correct.
-How much money do you take now? Is the same more or less with the cleaning?
-That's about the same.
-But would you like to make some more money, to be successful,
to do something that will really bring you out to the world.
-I would like to have more money but mainly...
I guess the main reason I want to work is to be able to take care of myself and
I want to feel that I'm not useless.
-You have been sighing where you are there now. I didn't hear you sighing the last time.
Do you feel you are in a stress, I put you in stress or do you feel comfortable?
Do you feel that I bring up issues that are a bit disturbing?
-Yes.
-How do you deal with them? Inside you now do you have anxiety?
-A little, not overwhelming.
-But that is an issue that you thought before yourself. It is not that I brought it up.
-No, no.
-So you are familiar with this issue and you ask yourself many times about that issue.
-Yes.
-You have been sighing even before and I'm asking whether you are aware of sighing.
-I was aware after you pointed out.
-Are you trying to control your sighing now?
-No.
-Be honest with me.
-I don't think I try to control it.
-Immediately the thought went to your mind, as soon as we discussed about it and
you were observing yourself.
-I wasn't consciously try to hold it down but I think I have an unconscious inhibition
when I'm upset not to show anything. I feel constraint.
-Tell me something. In your room, where you live, everything is in order?
-I like it in order but it's not always in order.
-Tell me something else. Do you have any fear of poverty or something like that?
-Yes I have some fear of that.
-And you are careful with your money, how to spend them?
-Yes and I realize that you are right about that, when you said if I'm avaricious, I first
didn't know about that because I thought that he is someone who thinks about money
all the time, not in that way but I'm a little avaricious and sometimes I'm generous but
sometimes I'm not.
-Do you like the money or you like the security?
-Yes I like to know that I have a little savings.
-You have a little savings, so you have some kind of security if something happens.
This is more or less what I perceived. Is that correct?
-Yes and I find it very disturbing to be in debt. If my savings were gone and
I had to borrow from somebody, I would be very insecure.
One of some other things that you said that I realized later that you are right about,
that I can't really think of the time like when I told you about the school and
later on you said if it was an experience that repeated that,
I couldn't think of anything but I remembered later on that at high school that
I went later, a certain group of kids teased me and
it wasn't cool like in the other school but it was mischievous.
They called me spook.
Do you hear that? The kids called her spook.
The first experience was in her school where the kids were teasing her badly and
she felt very much rejected and hurt by the teasing of the children.
Later on she changed the school, she went to another school and
I said did you have repeated experience?
In the first interview she said no. Now she says you are right I had again the experience
because I remembered again they called me spook.
The fact that I'm approaching a very burning issue for her, she seems a little bit more
open, she is admitting yes I'm avaricious or they called me spook, you are right.
Now we have established a contact. She understands that she cannot get away.
She understands that I'm going to get the facts and
she decides to volunteer some information. This is behind that interview.
She had resisted and resisted, I said OK you are resisting because most probably
you are afraid to go out in the world as a cured person and work again and
she said yes actually, I'm frightened. I'm set up here, I know what I'm doing,
it's nice and secure.
The other thing I don't know.
Do you see the sub-conscious resistance that comes up with the remedy?
That's why she took immediately Tylenol, to forget about the treatment,
I'm not going to get well.
-It wasn't malicious, it was more mischievious.
-What I feel is that you are a very nice person, very sensitive and
you felt unprotected in the world and having that sensitivity and
not being aggressive in going out to others like somebody steps on you,
having all that you eventually ended with a problem of syphilis that
came eight years ago.
-Yes.
-That undermined your constitution somewhat and all that together with the emotional
problems brought you in that state in which you feel subdued now,
you allow yourself to be subdued under the pressure of disease or whatever it is.
And that's why you try to protect yourself by isolating yourself almost in the house and
your environment where you feel secure, where in reality you have very good qualities
inside you, much better qualities than many other people that are successful outside.
You are correct, you are honest but you feel unprotected, completely insecure.
-Yes I do and there was a sensation that I want to describe to you...
In this particular case, you may say it's psychotherapy and all that.
It's not, it's human contact and common sense.
I was never trained as psychotherapist but it is my deepest desire that the people get well,
whether somebody has colitis or mental problems but every case has to be treated as
a specific individual case. That's what I'm doing. I will never praise anybody else.
Why should I praise? They are good enough, they have self-confidence, I don't want
to push their egos?
But in this particular case? That rejection that has gone inside her,
complete, total rejection by everybody and there she comes and give a remedy.
Let the remedy do everything but she needs a little bit of affection, you are good,
don't be afraid and it's true what I say, I don't tell a lie.
I do believe that these sensitive, unfortunate individuals are not the individuals who can
say she is sick and just reject it. It is because she has been so sensitive,
she came to that state.
Everybody has been hurt one or two times in life and we did not arrived in that state?
Why she arrived? Because she was too sensitive. Oh, I'm a spook.
But she became a spook and then life went away and now I give her some space to
breathe and as soon as I do that, she will volunteer the information.
Let's see what happened.
-In these last few days I felt like overwhelming burdens that have just been crashing me.
I have this problem with my car insurance, they don't want to renew my car insurance and
I don't know where else to go and it's nothing that I did wrong. My driving is perfect and
they don't tell me why they don't do and I felt that is completely unjustly.
This is happening to me and it's like a blow and it's knocking me down.
I don't feel like this all the time even when I'm in pain but when I feel it,
I can't fight things anymore,
I feel that arrows are running down on me from everywhere.
And often the pain feels like a burden on my head and on my shoulders, crashing.
-Why do you think the insurance people did that?
-I went to an agent and I was on a sign risk because I never had car insurance before and
he said a sign risk, why you are on a sign risk like you have a criminal record?
Then he said I don't know if I can set you an insurance, I have to submit an enquiry.
But I can't wait very long. Then he submitted an enquiry and it didn't go through and
I had to go elsewhere but
apparently he put the information into the system that
he did not sell me an insurance, he said that I was denied an insurance.
I don't know why they don't want to, maybe because I told him I was disable and
I get a pension.
-Did you tell them why you were disabled?
-Yes and I told them that it doesn't affect my driving but maybe they didn't believe that.
When I think about it, it's not that terrible because the worse it can happen is to go back
to the high risk and it will be more expensive, even if I have the stance I must progress in
my life, the worse it can happen is that I have to pay a couple of 100 more per year.
And it's only money but I feel bad when money have been taken from me and
I feel the injustice, I feel it like an injury to me,
they are doing something to me that is not right
and I feel almost the compulsion to take them to court.
I feel that I have to do something to stand up for myself and I don't know whether
I'm up to the task.
Do you see while she is talking now about something more intimate how
her voice has changed and it has some color,
some intonation showing that things are coming now from the heart.
There is more deep information which is coming from her speaking about her private
problem which they don't want to renew the assurance and what shall I do and
it was terrible, I feel the burden,
I feel they are sending me arrows from all over the world.
Now it is coming up on a different level.
Now maybe she will give the information, now the information may be true,
what she is giving.
I let her talk about herself, about the intimate things and she is prepared to talk.
Maybe I will get some information which is valuable.
-I worry about them and I cry.
-Do you cry frequently?
-I have been crying more since I took the remedy. I don't think I cry frequently.
-But you have been crying more, letting the emotions out.
-Yes and it was a time that I had a kind of religious...
I just now perceive that maybe the remedy is correct, from what she said I have been
crying more. I have not been crying before. For her case it becomes very important.
Whatever she has said before, I may disregard but this I cannot disregard.
Why she is crying more now? She is opening up to the pain, she feels the pain more now.
That's why she is crying more and you will hear now the experience she had.
-I have been praying a lot and reading the Bible a lot and one night I got an Irish song in
the television, picked it up and played it and it was so beautiful and I started to
cry and I felt...
Did you hear her voice breaking down?
She wants to cry, her voice is breaking down, now emotions are coming out.
She is opening now, in front of the camera, it doesn't matter. It is big emotional.
Like somebody has stayed in prison for years and first time goes out and
does not even believe it she is out.
-...I felt that feeling was god and I just felt so grateful and I felt close to god and
I felt grateful for that and I cried for a long time.
After the remedy she started crying, she cried and cried and
one day she had the song and that song reminded her of beauty,
she had an opening.
I said this is fantastic what is coming and she felt the presence of god.
She felt this connection, she cannot have a human connection but
she can have now connection with that which she calls god.
The urge to have some contact is breaking up and the contact is established.
She is crying, she is becoming again a human being with emotions, with feelings.
What has happened actually, this is what took place.
This is the important part after the remedy that was given but she broke down she had
emotions and she had the opening up and the religious experience.
That is the deep part that we expect in a cure.
Never mind the pains now, who cares about the pains.
I want to know whether my remedy is acting on a deep level.
Yes it is acting on a deeper level because of that.
Now I can be sure, I can go to the class and say don't worry after
20 days the pains will be gone. That is Homeopathy.
You see the struggle, you see what happens in this particular case?
How can you be sure from the beginning?
I showed this case to anybody until that point and they said we don't know,
the remedy maybe it is acting, maybe it is not acting.
Here I know the remedy is acting.
That opening up is what I expect from the remedy and it has happened and
she kept it secret, all these things,
until I pressed her and I found out what is really going on.
Now she understands, now I can talk and then she talks and said all that.
Further than that it's not important anymore. The remedy has acted.
The problem is now because she took some remedy...
As I told you, that is November and she got the remedy end of October and
in the beginning of May I received a telephone call from the practitioner saying,
she has been well with the pains and there seems to be a kind of relapse.
Seven months later she had a relapse. That's not a good sign.
With a remedy which you give and acts in deeper level, you expect this remedy to act
for a longer period of time, for one year, for two years before she has a relapse.
Now why she has a relapse? There are two possibilities for me.
I could not discuss all this in the telephone but this is what I think.
In this particular case the stresses of her life are too strong and
might have brought about a kind of relapse.
The second thing is that she took the remedy,
she has agreed now to cooperate with the treatment.
Actually this resistance after all these episodes has broken down.
In the end she will agree to cooperate and
she will agree not to take further the allopathic drugs.
By taking the allopathic drugs it might have hindered the action of the remedy and
I said to the class the relapse is going to be more soon that
what we expected from high potency.
Also there is a third possibility that the remedies were not properly potentised.
I gave her 1M, 10M, say 10M was the highest potency she took.
But I'm not sure any more about the real potentization of the remedies.
I have examples where again and again I've given a high potency where I expect for
this potency to act for a longer period of time and it acts like a small potency.
Before we have absolutely reliable medicines and medicines which are done in
a proper way, we cannot predict very much the time of relapse.
But I expect with a 10M potency in this case one and a half year to go without pains and
perhaps after one and a half year by stresses that
will be affecting her life to have a kind of relapse.
But seven months with such potency is not usual, the remedy should have hold longer.
So they are either too many stresses in her life or the Tylenol and the antihistamine she
took hindered the action or the potency was not really potentised.
The practitioner said the pains are exactly the same, she persuaded me that
it was a relapse. So we will see what happens.
-You repeated the remedy?
-Yes I repeated it now in May.
-Are you not afraid that she would commit suicide after the first remedy?
-No, I've never seen it happening.
I believe that with the right remedy they don't commit suicide.
It never happened to me. I've heard some stories.
It was in 1976 where Ortega gave a case.
He said I had a case, he was mentally ill and I prescribed Sulphur and
3 or 10 days after the Sulphur, I can't remember now, this man committed suicide.
So most probably I should not give him Sulphur,
I should give him some other remedy because Sulphur acted too deeply on the psoric element...
Different theorizing about this idea.
This is the only case that I've heard but can you be sure that
this was the action of Sulphur?
First of all Sulphur was indicated?
Maybe Sulphur was given without being indicated and the person accidentally committed
suicide after taking Sulphur but Sulphur was not indicated, maybe Arsenicum was
indicated or another remedy, how I'm sure that it was the really indicated remedy and
that remedy stirred that thing and made him commit suicide? How do I know that?
I had to know this case beforehand myself and to agree that this is a Sulphur case and
everybody agrees this is a typical Sulphur, we give Sulphur and
then he commits suicide, to be sure about it.
Who tells me he did not give the wrong remedy?
So it doesn't mean anything.
That was the only incident I had in my life about the question you are asking but
as I said I'm not sure it was the right remedy.
I've seen it with Aurum during the aggravation in the 24 hours after Aurum,
where the impulses for committing suicide can become very strong.
But in a real Aurum case, I have seen recovery after
the first 24 hours without any further depression.
During that time we usually say you have to be careful, we say to the other people,
just be careful for the first days.
Usually the person reports I have strong impulses for committing suicide but
they never do.
But if you give Aurum to a case where it is not Aurum, it is Arsenicum and
you give Aurum and after Aurum he commits suicide,
you cannot say you gave the right remedy and committed the suicide.
The right remedy will free the person into a deep level to the extent that
the desire to live is the first to come back, the desire to be alive.
It is the joy of life.
What she felt is a big relief from that experience. It is so joyful the experience,
it is a religious experience the feeling of the presence of god in her life.
It is so fulfilling.
She said I felt very well for a few days afterwards.
-I thought a religious, I felt much less anxiety about my situation to come and
it didn't last completely. I have had moments since then but
a lot of good feeling lasted.
-Would you be able to resist the Tylenol? This is a big issue.
-Yes.
-You don't have to work, even if you feel well. Only if you can't do otherwise or
you feel pleasure doing that.
Don't put yourself into a situation to say if I have to go to work...
Forget that issue.
Say that you will work, if you find real pleasure in doing something.
Not to put yourself into that conflict inside you. Forget about it completely. Let yourself.
Because you are such a nice person inside and
you have this spiritual relationship with god.
Even that is crowded by different fears and anxieties that are inside you,
they don't allow the freedom to connect and let your feelings acting.
If you want to cry, cry. It is a natural thing. If you want to pray, pray,
you want to talk to a friend, talk, if you don't want, don't.
But the big issue for us is not to take drugs. I'm sure the remedy underneath will act,
we will give some support.
-I will try harder.
-Thank you for coming.
-Thank you.
No more comments.