-Let us see the boy.
-First he had treatment from me in 1984 with two remedies, then there was a big gap on
the treatment and nothing else until 1986.
It was an acute state, when he came in with chronic earache. It started about 1.30 am in that day.
He is very frightened, he is trembling, throwing his head around and screaming,
feverish and chilly, I gave him Arsenicum 1M.
-That is November on which year?
-1986.
You see also in all the cases that have been taken previously that there is enough
justification for the prescription many times. Therefore where is the truth?
There is one truth. There is the right remedy and that is the truth.
How we go about to get this information and that is where it comes the evaluation of the
whole case, the analysis of the case. What do you understand by analysis?
By your analysis how many points you will take into consideration?
He takes.. worse cold, restlessness, drinks water, Arsenicum.
-I brought it back very quickly in 1M 24th of November, becoming again very exhausted...
He always complains about aches and pains, he collapses easily and he is worse when
his mother is around. He yells, kicks things but he miscalculates sometimes.
-Wait a moment. He came to you for what reason initially?
What is the problem with the child, just give us an overview of the case.
-He has trouble at school, this has come later but he never completes any work, he needs
a tremendous amount of reassurance and encouragement.
In what he says, he says in trouble in school, never finishes any of his work and then he
says he needs a lot of encouragement.
This "needs a lot of encouragement" is an assessment which he makes about the case.
Once you introduce an assessment of yours into the case, then you have mixed up the
case.
We find a logical thing. Why the child is not doing good at school?
Because he doesn't have a lot of encouragement.
But if you go and see the facts a lot of encouragement, the mother sits with him, she tries
to make him study, the father tries and the child still is not doing good at school.
The assessment is needs a lot of encouragement. Where it comes from?
Unless the child says encourage me, then you say it needs a lot of encouragement but
usually the assessment is the logical conclusion of something which explains, a logical
explanation.
-They sent him away in a different school.
-For retarded children?
-No, I think for difficult children, not retarded. He is also having trouble at home, he gets
into violence with his mother.
-What he does?
-He hits her, kicks.
-Swears?
-I don't know about swear.
-He becomes really violent?
-I'm not sure about that. He kicks doors and balcony.
-He can be really violent.
-Yes, his mother says if there is no real damage it is because he has miscalculated.
Do you see what we are doing? Explaining the symptoms away.
He breaks the doors, the idea is the force.
You don't see the explanation, you see the fact.
When I hear he broke the door, my god. To break a door by kicking the door, it's very
strong kick and you have to feel very strong.
Try to break one door, I challenge any of you to break one door by one kick, even if you
miscalculate. Nobody will be able to do it. Who can do it?
A person who is really mad, who is out of his mind and the power has arisen and so much
strong power that kicks the door and breaks it.
-How old is he now?
-14, I think but we may see it.
Also I would like to say that people who present a case are not my students.
You cannot say, oh this is your student, what he has done? No.
I consider my students only those who have the diploma of the School.
This is the diploma of the School.
If they have that, then you can blame me that they are my students but not otherwise.
This man is the first time I see him but it doesn't matter even if I see him for third time.
People present cases in which they have made mistakes and in which they have not
and I don't want to blame but the idea came about,
you see that my students are giving remedies this way.
Because I presented in the seminar. No it's not true.
-He has miscalculated. He tries to avoid really damaging things but sometimes he does.
-By putting too much force. Tell me what remedies you prescribed already?
-I prescribed unfortunately within two and a half weeks the Arsenicum.
-What about the first time, what was the remedy?
You gave something initially and then you prescribed another remedy before Arsenicum which was?
-Tuberculinum.
-And from your experience you have given three remedies,
there was any reaction from these remedies?
-No, I didn't find any reaction and
for the first remedy in 1984 I didn't see the patient again
until September, so I wasn't sure about any reaction.
And with Tuberculinum I didn't find any change.
-The child comes mostly because he has problems with his personality and also in the
school, where he cannot cope with the other children. His attention is slow or not at all?
-I think it is maybe OK, he needs encouragement, he is very easily discouraged by the
slightest thing going wrong.
-When he becomes violent it is only in his house with his mother and close persons or he
can become violent at school with the children?
-At school he can be slightly violent, he can hit the desk.
-But he never hits some of his colleagues?
-Not, as far as I know, I didn't ask about that.
-So he becomes violent exclusively with his mother or his father as well?
-No, they are separated. Mother and father are separated for 7 years.
His father is a very violent, angry personality and the child saw a lot of that anger.
-Was any time that the child was left handed?
-I don't know.
-You can add some information, as we are talking.
If you feel that you have some information that is not spoken about, you can say about
that it is this.
-OK. He doesn't like getting up in the morning and he doesn't like getting dressed.
You see he did not understand what I told him. I told him you can go now, bring the
patient and add any information. He does not listen.
If you don't listen, it's very difficult to become a homeopath.
-He didn't understand what you said.
-If he didn't understand me very well, he would say would you please tell me what exactly
you said?
-He doesn't have any close friends, he can't share his activities, he can't cope with the
responsibility having a friend playing, he is more like the gadget man, he can do tricks
with electronics and circuits.
-What do you mean?
-He invented a circuit when you put a battery or something like that.
-He seems he has a special time for electrical things.
-He seems to be happy when he is the oldest child in the group.
If he has asked to do anything and they demand this made, he reacts with tension and fear and
shaking of the head and tears, like homework or tidying up although he likes order but
he is incapable of doing it.
He twitches his fingers all the time and that's improved after Arsenicum.
This symptom it may be common to Arsenicum or to another 2,3 remedies, so the remedy
touches the symptom.
-He is sensitive to his mother new relationship with her boyfriend, which is somehow
difficult relationship and can't handle the boy very well.
The mother's new boyfriend finds it very difficult and the mother is very sensitive to having
a relationship with both.
He is critical to people in order to build himself up.
-He criticizes others in order to say I'm great?
-Yes.
Since 1M he has been quiet and playing with lego he has been very tired.
He moans and in good mood he is very charmy.
He likes chicken and rice dishes, sausages and butter, baked. He likes sweets, peanuts,
he dislikes fish and salad and ice cream.
He is very chilly, he comes down every night because he can't sleep, he comes down in
tears, he is afraid of not being able to sleep and he is better with a cup of tea.
He can't throw anything away, he collects junk and he invents things. He loves order but
he is frightened in trying to tide up. He can't get out if he is cuddled.
He can hit.
-Hard?
-I don't know how hard if somebody tries to cuddle him.
But he loves tickle. He has become more open to affection since the Arsenicum and less
restless. Now at the moment for three days he gave up eating or very little.
He wants to go to different schools because he is not part of the class, his writing is very
tight and he never finishes any of his work at school.
-Can you tell him to come in?
You like it? Being a film star?
-Yes.
-Yes he does, he wants to be acting.
-Do you like acting? Do you know what is acting? Tell me.
-To play out.
-In a theater. So you like to be in a theater?
-Yes I like to be.
He gives me some information and the information for me is a little bit unclear.
Where is the problem, how deep is the problem, how serious is the problem?
Definitely there are some personality disorders, some personality problems how deep and
how far are these problems?
He has given some contradictory information, as far as I'm concerned.
So immediately I try to find out the IQ of the child, how much he understands.
I'm asking whether he likes to act or not and he said yes.
Do you believe he likes to act?
No. He does not really understand at all what I'm asking. He understands the words
but he cannot make out why I'm asking all these questions. And what does it matter?
This is what is going on in him, it's not that I like acting.
Which are the remedies that they like acting?
There are remedies with good contact with others.
They enjoy contact with others. If you see remedies, which are extrovert and desire for
company and you combine all these elements, you will see the remedies, which are
mostly like to act.
Causticum is one of these remedies, Phosphorus more than Causticum. Argentum
nitricum quite a lot, Nux vomica yes and Lachesis quite a lot, Platina.
Palladium yes, not Aurum.
-Are you right handed or left handed?
-Right handed.
-He was left handed in the beginning?
-Yes.
-Very easy anger, explosiveness, wild, he gets very wild, he kicks.
-Usually kicks?
-Kicks and punches.
-What happens when you come to that moment? Can you tell us?
-My brother is irritating me so much and I hit him not too much.
-You don't want really to kill him.
-No.
-Do you like him in a way?
-Yes.
-In one way you like him and in another way you want to hit him, especially when he
provokes you. What kind of provocation he can do to you?
-A nasty word
-What happens inside you? Can you describe? Blood comes into your head? You feel
angry inside and then what you have to do? Attack him?
-Yes.
-And you kick him but not very hard. Do you try to control yourself?
-I can't really.
-Therefore you kick him but not very hard or you kick him as hard as you can?
-I kick him but not very hard.
-Then what he does? Is he older than you?
-He is younger.
-So he cannot fight against you.
-He is actually bigger.
-He fights back?
-Yes.
-So he kicks back sometimes?
-Who wins if they fight?
-I usually come and stop it.
-Does he attack you as well?
-Yes very hard. I get some very hard.
-Why do you do it to your mother? You can't control yourself?
-No.
What is important in this case is when you ask the mother and say what is the problem
with this child? The answer comes it is aggressiveness. The child is very aggressive.
After that you cannot say it is aggressive but needs encouragement.
It's aggressive but it does not have enough affection, it is aggressive but you minimize the
meaning of the aggressiveness. How much aggressive? It doesn't matter why.
The measure is that he kicks the door and breaks it, that's the measure of aggressiveness
and you have to take that into consideration in your prescription.
They are going to minimize it by explaining it their way; it is so nice child, so sweet.
You see how sweet he is? He is very sweet, very nice.
What is interesting in his character? I was impressed by one element in his character.
A nice kid that all of a sudden goes into explosion, no it's not that what I mean.
He looks at me. Why this should impress me? He looks when I'm asking.
-He said he can't control, so he is controlled.
-Most probably in one part of his mind he understands that he should not, in another part
he is unable to control and he does it.
Yes but what else do you observe? An element in his character.
-He is dreaming, he is somewhere else.
-It is a child which is not 100% present in the discussion. He has a dreamy state, as if he
is answering in one level and he is thinking of something else in another level.
Do you see that?
He is like a very wise grown up man who looks very objectively upon a situation and
assess the situation on another level.
He gives me the impression of a very wise man, his answers are amazing.
His contact, his behavior is really bizarre.
Talking to the child in this way, I would never imagine that this child could come to this
stage. Do you imagine it? Does it give you any hint that this child is violent?
-No.
-Sometimes you are good boy or always you are like that?
-Sometimes you are sweet, nice?
-No I'm not sweet.
-He is sweet but he won't admit it. Your teachers say about that.
-You don't care about these remarks, did you like these remarks?
You are pleased when your mother says you are sweet?
-Just.
-What do you like mostly to do?
You see this child is not behaving normally. The mother says he is sweet and the child
says why do you say that? It's not a normal reaction of a child. This is a question of a
grown up. Why do you say that? Am I really sweet?
-What do you like mostly playing?
-My lego.
-What is a lego?
-It is a plastic toy that fits together lots of pieces.
-Oh yes. He likes to play with that?
-In fact he likes to play with electrical stuff.
-You like electrical? You are good in that? Do you like to be an electrician or a television
repairer?
-Yes I like.
-He likes inventing things, he is always making things.
If you ask him to do something which he is not interested in, he won't do it or he does
it very withdrawn, not finish it. Lot of work he doesn't finish, he becomes very exhausted
and weak and he can't cope.
-Do you wake him up?
-Yes and take a cup of tea.
-Does he ever have any nightmares?
-Not very often. He wakes up in the night and he comes to me.
-He came to you?
He sleeps upstairs.
He came down in a terrified state?
-Yes.
-Why?
-He wouldn't tell me at the time but in the car he said he thought somebody was in the
other side of his room.
-And then he found out that nobody was there and then you were terrified?
-Yes.
-Does he leave the light on in his room or he sleeps in darkness?
-It's pretty dark now, for years we kept a light on but now not. He has some light coming
from the window.
-No.
-Yes that's true, I leave the light that comes up the stairs.
-And you leave the light until he is asleep?
-Yes.
-But if he wakes up in the night and there is darkness, he is not afraid?
-Not usually, he used to be until quite recently.
-When he first came one of the things you mentioned was the nightmares.
Used to be lot of them.
Here we have an important symptom but it changed.
We have to know whether it is a new picture or it is the same picture continuing without
that symptom.
-Can you describe what happened?
-When he was a baby, he would wake up and stay in terror throw himself on the left I couldn't
hold him because he was too strong and I put him on the floor and when he finished that
I picked him up because he was always very frightened.
-When he came out his eyes were very frightened?
-He was shaken.
-And you would put him back, he could have a second one during the night?
-No, I would stay with him until he sleeps.
When he was terrified, he tried to climb to the wall.
Do you hear that? The child had nightmares in which he would wake up with scream and
would throw himself left and right, his mother would take the child and put him on the floor
to calm down and after some time she was able to calm him down and go to sleep again.
But she said sometimes the irritation was so great that I would find him climbing walls,
trying to go through the walls.
Now I will try to confuse you.
If you are saying climbing walls and you had heard me saying the other day Belladonna
is climbing walls, I would mislead you by leading you there, like the patient is going to
mislead you.
He tells you a symptom which is Belladonna symptom. Let us say he said this.
In spite of that, that is the remedy.
I want you to understand eventually where is the key, the focus, the center of gravity of
the case?
-The core of the case.
-This is the picture of George. Now take this away, it is still the picture of George.
This is a little detail it doesn't matter, still it is the picture of George.
Little details will change but the whole remains the same.
You say now that, that is another remedy, no.
It looks like this man but he wears a hat and George never wears a hat.
It doesn't matter, that day he just put on this hat. This is the idea.
The child will give information about another remedy later on, is this the remedy? No.
Because the main picture is this remedy. We turn again and again.
He used to be afraid of the dark, used to want light, now he does not.
-When his brother was sick, he came down in the night and told me Mathew is sick, went
back to bed.
-How do you feel now? Calm inside or angry inside?
-Calm.
-Is it a good feeling or it is not a good feeling?
-In between.
-When you are in that state do you ever become suddenly, without any reason, angry?
-No, sometimes by a lesson.
-You don't like the lessons?
-No.
-You are divorced?
-Yes.
-In what age he was when you divorced?
-Five.
-Since he was one he had these nightmares. Did he hear some fights?
-Yes, his father...
Again the same story. The boy at the age of one starts with nightmares, it is not
accidental.
Most probably he saw a violent act in front of him taking place. His father is violent and in
the night he wakes up terrified with nightmares.
You see the remedy how it builds eventually up?
-Did he hear some fights?
-Yes, his father can get very angry and he was very angry.
In fact after the divorce his younger brother asked him why the father wasn't angry
anymore and he... at that age, he used to get very angry sometimes.
But they used to be a lot of his father anger in the beginning of the night and it was after
we finished and go back to sleep, then he would wake up screaming.
Very often the two things came together.
It is very interesting phenomena, I just draw your attention to the fact, so you can observe
it, the moment we will be taking about things that really concern him deeply, he would go
into sleep. He becomes sleepy more and more. That means he does not want to face
what he has faced consciously, he lets everybody to the subconscious.
The moment these things are coming up, I'm going to sleep, I'm going to hear now again
and to remember what took place, now I'm going to sleep.
The Stramonium has to do that in order to survive because what it stayed in the subconscious mind
so aggressively, they feel they can kill somebody easily.
They talk about him, about symptoms...
He says when his father left I was very angry, he said to his younger brother, the first
thing he said.
But this child is a unique child, I will tell you why.
-Are you sleepy now?
-Yes I'm a bit tired.
-Why?
-He always is when we talk about him.
You see the mother? "He always is when we talk about him".
That's how the remedy picture is coming out.
How George knows the remedy? It is not my imagination. It is what I see only, I see it
again and again and I see it, I don't dismiss it. I see the child is sleeping.
Why you are sleepy? What happened? I want to know, I have an idea but still I would like
to hear it.
What you see here you will never see in the Repertory.
-Even at school... He is very tired...
This was a few weeks ago I went to his teachers and so we expected him in school
Together... and after that I decided that... because it has been a suggestion that he should
leave that school and go away to a boarding school.
And I decided and I told him that I wouldn't send him away to another school.
And things got better after that.
Do you see where things have arrived with that school? They call and they say you better
take the boy away. This is a special school for problematic children. The child is not in a
normal school.
And from that school they call and say you have to take the child.
It cannot stay in the school. It is not a school for complete retarded children but for
children who are really having personality problems.
And the mother promised him whatever it happens, she will keep him at home, she will
not send him to another school for retarded children.
Because already the school in which he is, it is a school for children who are kind of
retarded.
-I didn't understand. Did you say that the sleepy is characteristic of Stramonium?
-Yes the sleepy is characteristic of Stramonium.
Not all Stramoniums will have that but we'll see it in several cases.
I said Stramonium are sweet children, they don't appear wild as they are described in our
books, the aggressiveness comes from time to time and it is uncontrollable.
But he says he tries to control. It doesn't matter what he says. Of course he tries to
control, of course he understands that if he kicks too hard, he may kill his mother and he
does not want to do that. Part of his mind knows it but he kicks too hard and this is
important.
And yet these children are sweet children, lovable, you love them.
Is he aggressive at all? Do you think he is aggressive? No.
He answers but he says problems in the school, they say they have to take the child
away, even in a school which is for problematic children.
-I wouldn't send him away to another school.
-So you are sleepy now. You want to go to sleep? Can you sleep while you sit there?
-No.
-When he became violent, at what age he started hitting others?
-In the second year at school.
-Does he fight with his classmates?
-He used to, didn't you?
-Yes.
-Did you ever hit somebody very hard?
-Yes I can hit but they hit twice as hard.
-They hit you back and then what you did? You became more cross?
-I became more cross.
-And you hit them back again?
-Yes.
-Did you ever hit anybody very badly?
-No.
-Did you ever hit anything, a door or a table, you broke anything?
-A couple of doors.
Do you see? I know the information whether he has broken doors.
I ask him and he does not know I know the information.
He says now this is gone too far. If I tell I broke doors, he may think I'm a bad boy now.
And then he hesitates to tell it. But this is the human being, this is where you reach a point
where you see the hesitation and you understand something is behind that.
-At home he actually does less damage. When he kicks the chairs, there is thought on
how he kicks them because he could damage them much worse.
So there is something in him...
-But what about his leg? Hitting a chair is not an easy thing. He does not complain about
his leg afterwards?
-No.
-He is very hard. Did you ever hit him?
-Yes I have done.
-He seems to feel the pain?
-Yes he does.
-His father hit him ever?
Now normally the child at that state when I say the father did he ever hit him, the child
normally is going to sleepy state. Not now maybe he will not do it but this is the idea
behind.
Also if you are very observant, you will see the change in the emotions.
There is some light in his eyes. Did his father hit him? The light goes away from his eyes
and becomes sad. Just put it backwards, watch that.
-Not when he was little. I remember one night when he was in a frightened state, he
shook him, for god shake stop this.
His father anger is against himself.
After we split up, his father hit other people but he didn't hit us.
Has he ever hit you when you stayed with him?
-No.
-When he is in this anger, does his face becomes very red or white?
-It doesn't get red now as it used to. One time at school, I gathered from the other children
he was actually...  he didn't say anything. He does not get so red now. Sometimes...
-Does he have a lot of problems with his ears?
-No.
-Does he get easily acutes?
-He gets weak and pain, it comes and goes.
-But not real acute?
-No.
Again this is the same idea. Once the child is disturbed emotionally, he will not get any
serious acute condition.
-What about his sleep, is it constant? He talks in his sleep, he laughs in his sleep?
-No, he doesn't seem anymore. He used to.
-Do you have any fears? Are you afraid of anything?
-No.
-You don't have fear of dogs or cats or thunderstorms?
-He used to be afraid to go upstairs on his own. But it's gone.
-To stay in the night alone?
-No, just even to go upstairs on his own. That stopped in the last year.
-Yes.
-So you don't like lesson in the school?
-Some I like.
Observe also the patterns. The child it seemed that the violence of the father came to
his subconscious fear, which appears during night. He wakes up in the night, throws
himself and all that and as the child becomes more and more violent in his waking state,
consciously, the other state in the subconscious subside.
The subconscious fears that in the night he will get up and he cannot stay in the dark and
he had nightmares etc. all this pattern subsides and then it comes real violence.
It's more to the conscious mind now but the remedy is the same.
The remedy has that first pattern and it has the second pattern of symptomatology.
Not because it changed the symptomatology we have another remedy now because we
see a certain symptomatology of the Stramonium child in the beginning, which develops
eventually into violence. It is a child which is going worse and worse.
-What do you like?
-Wood work.
-You don't have electrical things in the school?
-No.
-All his electrical stuff is at home.
-This redness around his...
-It is strong sometimes.
-He is very sleepy now. Are you very sleepy now?
-Yes.
-So you want to finish with that examination to go home?
-Mmmm.
He says yes in all that. He doesn't care, it is a cut off feeling, he does not feel
uncomfortable, it is a feeling of being cut off, a feeling of being in a sleepy state where
you don't want anything.
-He is coming down too much, too quite.
Do you want a little bit of fight?
-No.
-You feel very tired?
-Yes just about.
-Are you happy? Do you know happiness?
-Yes.
-Are you ever happy?
-Sometimes.
-When is these times?
-When I will do something good.
-And they praise you, they say very good. What you did was very good.
Then you feel very happy?
-Yes.
-Is he intolerant of heat or cold, things like that you have noticed?
-He feels the cold.
When he gets too hot, he gets a little bit depressed.
-When he is at home is he a talkative person or a quite person?
-It depends on what he is doing.
He goes on his own and makes things and he is upset if you can't see it immediately.
He comes when I'm cooking and he wants me to see it straight away.
-And then he becomes violent?
What about water? How is his relationship with water?
He washes himself frequently? He likes water?
-He likes to play with it.
-If he has a shower and you put water over his head?
-He used to get in a great state, if you would water his head, he would scream, he couldn't
bear it in his eyes.
He used to complain very violently about that but that it has gone better because now he
complains about doing it himself.
-Does he pour water over his head and the water would run over his face?
-Yes.
-You don't mind now?
-No.
-Has he ever broken any glassy thing, any window, anything which shines, like mirror?
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
Somebody throwed a shoe through a window but that was a mistake, he didn't want to go
through the window. Some years ago, that's the only time it happened.
-Does he like dancing? Music?
-He likes the music but he wouldn't dance.
-He is going to sleep, completely relaxed.
Do you like that we talk about you? Do you enjoy it?
-Not particularly.
-What we say about you do you feel embarrassing?
-No.
-But do you like that we are talking about so long you and we take a long time to sort out
what is going on inside you? Do you appreciate that?
-I don't mind.
-He has reacted strongly in the past. A lot of anger comes out later.
I think this time he is retreating.
-But the anger will come tomorrow most probably.
-Maybe yes.
Most probably what is happening with these children is that they are very impressionable.
Impressions can make a big event but they don't protect themselves during impression.
The let the impression come in without filtering... and then later on it creates disturbances.
-I'm tired.
-He is very sleepy. He is very nice after all this.
Something happens inside you that we cannot control. This adrenaline comes up and it is
too much and it has to...
-At school they are not so worried about that, they are more worried about the fact that he
is actually a bright child but he is not keeping up with the work at all.
As soon as he meets a problem, he can't' handle it, he is in panic, he becomes frightened
really and he becomes exhausted.
-He plays with his hands a lot now.
-He is relaxed actually. Some years ago he had a nervous cough, it wouldn't stop and
then he was doing that all the time, nonstop. He was writing and he puts the pen down to
do that and then stopped. Isn't it?
-Anything else?
-No. It's difficult to say.
-He is very nice. Everyone likes him?
-I think they do, at school the children want to know what is wrong with him.
He plays by himself quite a lot, he doesn't join the crowd very easily.
-Does he play with his genitals?
-No. They do it in the bath both of them.
-Not constantly?
-No.
-When he is angry does he swear?
-Yes a lot.
-He uses bad words. What words does he use?
-He calls me bitch and he tells everyone to fuck off.
-Yes?
-In acutes he becomes very frightened. He is very afraid of being ill any and over reacts to
any pain. He is afraid of pain and afraid of having temperature and that disorientated
feeling.
-He feels as if he is standing up, when he is lying in bed.
-Thank you.
I would like to make a remark now concerning Stramonium.
I would say that I find Stramonium in late years much more indicated than in my first years
of practice.
I don't know whether I learned to recognize it more easily or whether there is really a
development of aggressiveness in our societies and we have the appearance of more and
more of such remedies, as Stramonium, Hyoscyamus, Nux vomicas.
You see the Nux vomicas were always very prominent.
The aggression that creates problems in the human body were taken away mostly by
Nux vomica. Today we have much more aggressive remedies being indicated and also
we have remedies which cover pictures of drug abuse.
Also what I want to show you again is the time that you have to wait.
Remember Bill Gray left his cases for two years, returned and found them all cured.
Maybe there is a little bit of exaggeration in that but stick that in your mind.
You gave a good remedy, there was a good reaction, leave it alone, don't repeat it, don't
give other remedies. This is the idea.