-The case is male 36 years old and it concerns his memory.
Primary concerns memory, feeling of mental weakness, difficulty in memory,
concerns with being a homeopath and learning all these remedies and being able to recall them,
studying them, being in stress all my life, I'm a naturopath and the last couple of years I
have a lot of stress with finance and work and nothing seems easy,
nothing seems as it should be.
I had difficulty to come here, difficulty with memory that I start to write and
I get the letters wrong, peoples names that I should know well enough and
call them on their name and
I feel embarrassed about that, I feel stupid about that.
The last year some lack of sexual feeling, difficulty becoming aroused and
loose erections and things like that.
-Just say what you want to say and I will put some questions.
-This is observations about myself, claustrophobia.
No matter what kind of bedroom I have, I have the sensation that I'm sitting in the floor
and I'm going to disappear from the floor, I'm suffocating a bit.
-When do you have this feeling? By the moment you are lying in bed or
by the moment you are falling asleep?
-The moment that I'm in bed.
-Still while you are awake you have the impression that you are sinking through the bed?
-More that I'm attracted, maybe in the morning I can't get up again,
the sense of being towards the end.
The case we did on Sunday I felt like Sulphur, lack of will power under stress and tension,
I smoke with a pipe, the last 3-4 months I try to quit with very little will power.
The type of person that even when I'm advising other people about diet,
sometimes I never keep my diet.
For the last six months once the day close to where my office is, I go and have black tea
and sweet roll and a fish sandwich. I feel I need it to give me a lift.
-Is anybody that does not follow with this pronunciation?
-The memory thing just keeps coming up...
The last years I also have some muscle weakness, feeling lack of muscle tone,
at the summer I can take bicycle but I can't run because
I just don't have the strength and the energy.
I'm a night person, I rather stay up and work late at night.
If I had choice I would study and work at night and sleep in the morning.
If I'm doing paper work for instance I get stuck until the evening hours.
Some throat weakness, congestion this area, worse in high humid weather.
I have difficulty in making changes I need to get my life going. Lack of initiative.
Doing changes in my life.
In relationships with women I've been told that I try to remake people too much,
I think I've been giving all this helpful advice but it's not always taken that way and
generally relationships I don't feel I have a power. I feel women have a power.
In the relationships I've been in, it's usually women who left and I feel sometimes
confused and weak from that and... also a sense of lack of power.
-The women left you?
-Yes. Generally I feel I'm very shy, I feel it's difficult to reach out to people and
if it is a situation, maybe a class where I can talk to people and
I have a reason to be with people, I can do it then but in certain situations that
I would like to meet people,
I'm just in the corner, I don't do that.
Physically the sexual energy I have some fits [?] and a little rash...
Those are my big concerns.
Remedies I had five years ago was Nux vomica high potency, I've been seeing a homeopath and
I had Sulphur, Lycopodium which it seemed that it may have working but
I had dental appointment two days later and if it was working I wasn't quite sure.
It was repeated in high potency, it didn't do anything.
Since then I have Ignatia and for some reason I had Baryta carbonica.
-Did you have any effect from any of these remedies?
-I think I may have had some effect from Lycopodium, it was antidoted,
I don't know afterwards and I didn't take it the second time it was given.
-Ignatia?
-I had taken Ignatia 30 about a month before that for acute stress...
-You took it on a higher potency as well?
-I was given in high potency, I think 1M. No noticeable effect.
I have also concern with the sexual energy and I don't know whether this is a stress in
my life worrying me down or whether it has to do with the partner relationships I had which
is been hurtful to me and I had the feelings that it was dangerous to be involved.
I don't know which one of those it is.
-The memory, when did you first notice drop in your memory or it was always there?
-It's been always there and it's been worse the last 3 years.
I always had a feeling that I was inefficient computer, I was not stupid but the way I did
things was not the most efficient.
I also had that suffer tendency to do what I want to do, to study what I want to study,
which is maybe the most important at the moment. That is my background.
Difficulty in conflict situations, I do not get angry with people.
Very seldom, very seldom.
I was taught in so many classed that you have anger towards women and
I said yes I think I do but it was intellectualized. It's underneath there.
-Can you talk to us a little bit about your childhood?
-My parents were together,  my father never expressed his emotions,
there was always conflict between me and my father for things how to be done.
He never expressed his emotions unless he blew up, he never got the things out of him.
I had some conflict also when I was in my teenage years, I would make suggestions how
things should be done and 2-3 times he would try to bit me up.
The first time it happened I felt confused and unjustly attacked,
I felt I was a good person trying to do a good thing and
I've been smashed against the wall and that was confusing
to me and I felt hurt.
-What age it was that?
-12-13.
-That was the first time that you had a grief or stress or
it was before that you experienced anything?
-In the third grade I experienced it when I had difficulty in mathematics and I got moved
from the first group to the second group.
-What age was that?
-Eight years old.
-I remember the experience of going into a state of confusion and embarrassment
about not going properly and making mistakes and that changed me.
-Have you had any kind of psychotherapy?
-I don't believe so.
-What I'm asking is whether you had a psychotherapy session?
Or what has happened really is that you had been but for you it was not a session at all?
-When I was in the college to NY I went to a therapist trying to get valium from him but
it was not really sessions. Valium was a very good drug for me.
They thought it was addicting and they gave me another thing.
-Have you been using drugs at all, like marihuana, these light drugs?
-No.
-Or once, twice or three times all together?
-My whole life? I did some many years ago. I did it when I was in sociality program about
three weeks and everyone was doing.
-For how long you took it?
-Three weeks.
-Every day?
-Yes.
-What you consider as your main symptom?
-Two things, the memory problem and the sexual energy.
-The sexual energy I can understand there is no much desire for sex or there is desire but
when you are in a situation you have problem?
-There is mental desire but there is no feeling.
If I was with someone which I was very, very attracted to, it might be some but still I have
difficulty having ejaculation and I lose erection. I feel coldness.
-Before it was better?
-Yes.
-When did you have sex for the first time?
-16.
-There was a time when sexual function was good?
-Yes.
-And from one point onwards there is this blockage?
-Did you define it in your mind what it happened?
-I'm aware of about two years ago.
-After a particular relationship that you had?
-I can't say one particular, I don't know.
-How you are acting in a relationship? Can you describe?
You are over reacting emotionally or more logically?
-Too much logically.
-Since when did you realize that you are functioning with your mind?
It was always like that?
-It was always like that.
-You don't remember yourself functioning from the heart.
-I remember myself functioning from the heart but in a structured relationship there is too
much mental stuff that goes on, thinking too much and making plans and analyzing.
I've always done that but there was an emotional feeling that has been.
-There is a coldness inside concerning this area?
And sometimes this coldness becomes more?
-Yes, there is a mental desire but there is an emotional lack, when I go close to someone
maybe it will come up and maybe I will develop it but no there is coldness.
-Do you have brothers, sisters?
-Yes one brother and two sisters.
-Good relationship with them?
-Mediocre with my brother, now it's got a little bit better and
my sister is pretty good right now, I'm the oldest.
-What is the opinion of others about you, what they usually tell you?
-When I think of others you mean people I have relationship with?
-A general idea what you hear about yourself in relationships, from friends?
-Too critical, too perfectionistic, loving in some ways...
-What the girlfriends have said? That you are very critical or very cold or egotistical?
-They said that I'm very critical and very selfish and I try to change them too much and
I'm not satisfied the way they are.
-Have you been cheating them sometimes?
-I don't think so. Sometimes, yes. Yes I think so.
-What is according to your understanding his main, the most prominent as far as his
symptomatology is concerned?
-He is very hard to express.
-Very self-critical, too much.
-Somebody else?
-Lack of self-confidence.
-Do you think you have lack of self-confidence?
-Yes. I mean I believe in myself deep underneath but I think so.
People sometimes tell me that also.
-Somebody else?
-A kind of disconnection with life and feelings that is inside.
-Too much metalized.
-Yes and with people and feelings.
-Embarrassment.
-How did you understand that? What signs led you to that?
-He is blushing too much.
-His voice changes a lot.
-What did you hear from his voice? He says I have problems with my memory,
my memory is no good and then what I hear is another story.
His memory may be weak, I don't know if this is his natural because somebody has
more memory than somebody else.
Because he does not remember a time when he lost his memory from that moment
onwards which made it a pathological symptom.
What correlation with the voice?
-He is angry.
-I felt special when he was telling about his father, embarrassment and shame and
then the stress.
-The voice that comes out has a lot of embarrassment, distress and almost agony.
There is agony, almost anguish.
What I hear is anguish about what?
About problems that are not solved in his life.
Professionally, emotionally, he is not set and all this has created a state of
tremendous anguish.
The real thing is anguish. The memory maybe is not but the real thing is anguish.
We call it lack of self-confidence, still he has some doubts about himself but all this has
created an anguistic thing, an anxiety thing. Too strong anxiety.
It is not an anxiety about a job or about a woman or about sex.
It is an anguish beyond anxiety.
Why there is this anxiety?
The question that he is putting, is a question of memory that demands of himself
that which is beyond his own capacity and his nature or it is a pathology?
That means that at a certain point he lost his memory. This is pathological.
[bad sound]
It is a memory good for certain things. [bad sound]
The memory in him is, I believe, a natural state to have that capacity of memory,
he has not done this election. He has not decided I will remember all these things and
these I will forger and then the memory is weak.
But maybe there is a time where you felt that you lost your memory.
-Sensory short circuit things have been going around the last couple of years.
I don't know I remember some things and other things I'm not sure.
If I have a patient coming a week before, I feel I should remember who that person is
but sometimes I totally forget who they are. And sometimes I make mistakes in writing.
-What exactly are the mistakes?
-I think and it was...
-You replacing letters?
-Yes and it sounds like the nervous system does that.
-You lost control. How is your sleep?
-Sleep is generally very good.
-And also in day time, in siesta?
-I don't have time for siesta.
-Why?
-I work in the day time.
-Here you don't have a siesta?
-I did the other day.
-For how long?
-Two hours.
-Did you wake up refreshed or unrefreshed?
-I did from the siesta. I wake up in the morning, I never wake up refreshed the first hour.
-In the afternoon? You slept once here?
-I think I slept twice.
-And you woke up from that sleep refreshed?
-Yes I think so.
-The position that you sleep is steady?
-Right and left sides. Not back.
-Not in the abdomen.
Give us an idea of what you think about yourself, what kind of person you are?
-It's embarrassing to talk about myself.
-Do you have a tendency to cry? Do you cry easily?
-No.
-Is it that tears may come up to the eyes and they don't just come out or no tears?
-It comes seldom and they are repressed when they come.
I went through an est training about 4 years ago and
they have something I would get up on stage and I did cry there...
I cried a couple of times when a relationship broke up.
-What is your reaction to weather?
-I don't like the hot, humid weather. That's the most.
-Do you like being in the sun?
-Yes I do it here.
-For how long, for half an hour, an hour or two hours?
-Half an hour, one hour.
-Are you bothered by the sun?
-No, I don't think I am but when I'm for a couple of hours I get heat exhausted.
-...The feet are usually normal or very cold, very hot?
-They are normal. That's my feeling.
-Excessive perspiration?
-No.
-Other perspiration...
-I perspire excessive mostly in the axilla.
Thirsty.
-Cold water or not very cold?
-Not very cold.
-What other do you like? You like alcohol?
-I kind of had a problem with alcohol.
-You drink in order to relax?
-Yes before I came to Greece I've been drinking for years.
-You had some problems with drinking before?
-Yes.
-Beer or wine?
-Mostly strong beer.
-That seemed to relax you?
-Yes...[bad sound]
And also if I drink a lot I will have hangovers.
-Do you have any craving for food?
-No, I don't have craving for food, if I had myself go I would drink coca cola and potato chips...
so  salt and sweet. I don't particularly like fat.
-Do you have an aversion to fat?
-I think so. We have stuff with meat.
-You are vegetarian?
-I tried to be but no.
-How much salt do you take? Did you ever in your life had a craving for salt?
-I like salt but I don't have craving for it.
-You like salt when it's more salty than usual, like potato chips.
-That kind of stuff.
-Did you ever take salt and put extra salt in your food?
-If there is no salt I do it, in French fries I put salt on it.
-I like spicy food, I like vegetables, carrots, garlic.
Also using tobacco to relax stress started to be too much and I started smoking again.
I'm doing it because of habit, not of big desire sometimes. I'm upset about that.
-Are you anxious about your future?
-Yes.
-What is your greatest anxiety at the moment?
-My greatest anxiety is my health practice to become successful and work well,
which represents a carrier success.
Second from that to develop a relationship again. I'd like to marry.
-Do you sigh sometimes?
-Yes.
I don't know if it's an emotional fatigue sighing but yes I do.
-He has been doing this now?
-Yes.
-You have noticed that you have been doing that in the day?
-I know it's three times the day and it's a definite sighing.
-Do you ever talk to yourself?
-No. I'm driving and I talk to the other cars and do funny things but
not to myself very much.
-Do you have any kind of fear?
-Just a claustrophobia, a feeling of suffocation.
Fear of lack of memory and fear of lack of money.
That's a big issue in my family, they talk about money.
-It's a big fear with you?
-Yes, it's also in my family, it's like a sickness almost, we are talking about it too much
we are concerned about it, I also have fear of high places, a cliff on the ocean.
I want to jump, it's not committing suicide, it's jumping I want to merge, jumping in the
water in the sense of merging.
-Do you have any problems with time... growth?
-I don't know.
I do agree with you, it's anguish.
The last couple of years I feel is a good description of my life, yes.
-No inner calm.
-Very little.
-I was given Calcarea and Chilli also.
-Do you have anxiety about your health?
-About the muscular weakness and about the sexual energy mainly.
I know I have a weakness in the throat.
-You get colds easily? That's what you mean?
-Yes if I smoke a pipe I get irritation in the throat. If I smoke heavily it's not good for me.
-How much fish you take?
-I like fish.
-If I have weakness in my eyes?
-No weakness in the eyelids.
-More a feeling that I'm not able to spot things, like the muscles are losing tone or
losing capability.
-What is the problem with your eyes?
-I have stigmatism.
-Strong stigmatism?
-Yes and strong myopia.
I have a tense towards lower back and sciatic problems.
-Which side?
-Right. If I do something real strenuous like driving a car for many hours, I can't go out.
I also have stiffness in the fixation over the neck which doesn't bother me all the time.
I'm not thinking of them right now but when I'm thinking of them they are bothering me.
-What was the question?
-Has he ever become very angry?
-A kind of lose control?
-No, I know when I'm out of control and I want to do something which is inside.
Destroy people, buildings.
-Do you shout?
-I usually shout and I want to hit people, I don't usually.
And I still have this feeling of not being able... inside me. I do not throw things.
-Justice is an important issue for you?
-How many times you underline this information?
-In my mind it's only... I think so yes.
-How do you feel about your patients?
-About my patients I really like to get well and I feel that I help them and
it's probably about 20% which I don't appreciate and they don't appreciate me and
sometimes I just have difficulty with them.
-And emotionally as a healer?
-Emotionally as a healer I can put that aside...
-Do you feel a patient is there to attack you, to challenge your love or confidence?
-At a certain percentage yes I do.
-With all that is going on, do you feel inside that this is resolvable?
-I have my doubts. I'm a doctor two days a week, a farmer two days a week,
a businessman two days a week.
And that is a symptom of feeling somewhat overwhelmed.