I shall give you first the symptomatology; we try to study the symptomatology first.
And then because I've seen that case myself I shall describe to you the type of the person
and see whether what I describe if it comes with what it came down as a result
or maybe it will change all together our decision.
So this is what we call the essence of the case vs the totality of the symptoms
or the keynotes symptomatology.
And then we shall see, we will think together which is the best solution.
This is a girl of 22 years old, she is the fiancé of one of the medical students
that were interested in Homeopathy. That case came in 1977.
The case is a case of psoriasis.
Actually the real diagnosis is a psoriasis which is with very small...
Punctate. In this case is on the whole body.
This is better in the summer and worse grief underlined 3 times
and better when the emotions are positive.
Worse grief 3 times, better joy 2 times.
Worse in winter of course where the whole body is covered
and there is only one exception that in the head remains throughout the year.
It does not go away from the head.
That state of affairs started 6 years ago after a fright.
The fright was that she saw a snake in the country, where she had been.
And the fright was so much that the next day this state of rapid eruption started growing.
When these spots appeared, the first time that they appear, they break out,
they have itching. Otherwise the itching stops.
A tachycardia, which causes a kind of dyspnea, as if she cannot breathe...
She has claustrophobia. She is very much afraid of going into a lift,
where too many people are gathered and this is underlined 3 times.
She says, she has a fear for thunderstorm
because she had witnessed a thunder to go and hit an old man, almost in front of her
and since then she is afraid of thunderstorms.
Desires and aversions. There is desire for sweets.
First desire for chicken, which is underlined 3 times.
Then desire sweets, desire salt without any underline,
desire orange juice without underline, thirst is normal,
her reaction to temperature is normal, worse heat rather without underline.
She never sits in the sun without going constantly in the sea.
She goes in the sea to make herself wet and she goes out.
That means she cannot stay under the sun directly and constantly.
Intolerance of tight clothes and I have underlined at first 3 times.
Then on enquiry I found out that she could wear a turtleneck. She can wear that.
When I asked her about tight clothes, she said I cannot have tight clothes.
The reaction was such that I underlined 3 times but then on studying the case...
I have noted 3 remedies.
I first prescribe one remedy, I cross it out, then a second remedy, I close it down
and then I gave a third one from what I see from my notes here.
I went back and I checked how much that intolerance of tight clothes was
and I saw that she could wear that turtleneck.
She sleeps on the sides and abdomen.
She is very sympathetic.
The menses, the last few months, have become scanty,
where in older times she used to have menses 12 days in succession.
When I asked her about dreams, she said that she was very clairvoyant.
She could see very clearly incidents that were going to happen.
She has difficulty in concentration.
She does not sleep well.
Better in the sea, underlined once, feet cold, underlined twice biting her nails.
This is the case which we try to solve.
-How much she weights?
-She is a normal height and physique, not skinny, absolutely normal.
I gave you that whole information because it is very didactic to see what happens actually
when you take a case.
You get a symptom and you go to reexamine it and you have it in two or nothing
and the opposite is happening, you just bypass it and you go there
and you see it's very strong.
So cross examination is very good thing to do
in case you are going to base your prescription on that symptom. Always I do that.
If I shall rely on certain symptomatology, I go back
while I'm studying the case in front of the person, I go back and check it.
You said it is worse heat, what do you mean exactly?
How much heat do you have? To evaluate myself what is going on really.
I have given you some information to see the inside of this person through symptomatology.
Just to take a deeper look into her make-up.
What is this information which shows it?
-One thing is definitely the clairvoyant dreams, she has difficulty concentration
and all the reaction she shows when she happy, joyfull...
-I'm standing on that observation.
She said that she looks unstable, how your phrased it?
-Unstable.
-Being worse grief and better joy in her condition.
She calls that instability.
-Because it is suggestible.
-You call it suggestible?
-In other words most patients have a symptom and not a normal reaction.
So my question was really that reaction was and indication (?)
-I don't understand if you understood what I said.
I said that psoriasis is worse with grief 3 times and better joy 2 times.
That means if she had emotions in positive state, the psoriasis goes.
What that means actually?
-She is very open.
-She is very open but symptoms are changeable.
-I see a diffusion of emotions...
-Yes but here we have the pathology affected in a very amazing way by the emotions.
The emotions are strong or weak?
-Strong.
-Very strong. Emotions within the person must be very strong.
To affect the pathology, great emotion.
So that we take into consideration.
That the emotions are deep and strong in order to affect the pathology.
Who wants to make another analysis?
-I thought of Phosphorus because and that to change (?) with joy and grief as an openness.
-Now the biting of the nails with 2, does it go with openness or closed person?
-Closed.
-You have not seen these people? That state is open or close?
-Close.
-Who says close? Who says open?
A person who expresses and interacts openly would do that?
It is the absolute, outward sign that a person is closed, it does not express his emotions.
And especially when they are in agony...they bite their nails.
It's a sign of being closed definitely.
You don't agree?
-No I agree. I can see that the nervous energy...
-The nervous energy which is not expressing itself in a natural way.
It's not expressing, it's not coming out, it's not interacting with the outside world.
There are emotions going on inside there that cannot be held by the individual
and the last resort it is to do some nervous action,
where it releases that nervous tension, which is inside.
-Openess what do you mean?
-Openess of character. I'm angry with her and I tell her.
I don't have to bite my nails instead of telling her that I'm angry with her.
I'm expressing myself, I don't have to do it.
-In chicken...
-In chicken yes, Graphites is strong.
Who agrees with Phosphorus? It doesn't matter because it's closed
it cannot be Phosphorus.
So Graphites.
-Worse in grief and worse from (?)
-Who is in favor of Graphites?
-What you try to keep us away from Lachesis?
-Who is favor of Lachesis?
-Argentum nitricum.
-Phosphoric acid.
-I don't know enough on Phosphoric acid.
-This is not Phosphoric acid. Phosphoric acid we said yesterday you need to have...
If you take the diagram of the emotions of Phosphoric acid is this.
No emotions, emotions are dead.
This is actually a case where emotions are like that compared to the normal state.
In that case they are very strong and deep and not expressed.
Emotions, which are deep felt but not expressed, inhibited.
That is why I asked you whether you are familiar with the Theory.
Pascero in the theory of the miasms , which says that the 3 miasms.
He describes them...the psoric miasm as inhibition,
the syphilitic miasm describes it as distortion, pervesion
and the sycotic miasm as eruption, as an expression of big eruption.
Big emotions that are expressed, extrovert and it grows tumors etc.
According to this classification of Pascero, we said very grossly now
but the whole book comes down to these 3 points,
in which of the 3 you would put this girl?
-Psoric.
-Psoric and sycotic?
-Psoric is inhibition.
She inhibits the symptoms. That is a perfect case of inhibition.
-I thought of Aconite. The reason I thought it is because she was frightened
and she had highlighted the claustrophobia...
-Going on a superficial level to counteract the fright, we may give Aconitum
but also Aconitum has a picture of its own,
which has to be there before you can give it.
If you give Aconitum on the assumption that there is a fright, which causes the disease,
very few times you will succeed.
-Can you say something more about Aconitum?
-With Aconitum the expression is much bigger and more vital.
For instance palpitations.
But palpitations which are strong and will not cause dyspnea.
This is a palpitation where you see a problem with the heart really.
She is 22 years old and she has to lie down with dyspnea.
That's a case where emotions have been inhibited and have affected the heart.
The heart is quite affected, if you take in consideration
that there is already an eruption in the skin and the heart
in spite of the expression of that eruption being outside the heart is affected.
22 years old most probably she has an affection from inheritance concerning the heart
because she is too young.
The expression is on the skin of a very big eruption and yet the heart is affected.
That means it shows a predisposition with the heart already from the parents.
Usually when the heart is affected in the children,
we have the sycotic miasm coming through to the children.
The sycotic miasm produces a heart attack at the age of 40, 42, 45.
In younger age when the person is vital still, it produces a heart attack which is fatal.
These people who have children, the children have either problems with the kidneys
or with the heart.
You asked what age did your father died? Is your father alive? No, died.
When? Age 45. From what? Heart disease.
You are like prophet.
If you see the sycotic miasm, if you see the kidneys affected...
and that was the case actually with a doctor we had from Norway.
She was working for the government in Norway and she came to investigate
or to see what our Center is doing actually
because she is working for the government in security.
She came down and she talks to me and I have a kidney problem.
And what I look, what I said was that your father most probably died in a young age
from heart attack. She jumped, she said yes that's the case.
I did that to impress her and to show what we are doing here.
Do you know anything about Medicine? That impressed her much more
than the Theory I was trying to get through to her.
She was coming the next day. What did you say? How did you say it works?
Again I started all over. The third day again, how did you say it works?
Third time to explain. It won't go through the Theory.
When we became more friendly, then we started talking more.
She gave me some information. I said this most probably has happened.
This is because we have a line of thinking. She was impressed.
It's not something that you can do for sure every time.
You have to be absolutely sure what you are talking about, otherwise...
Many times he had survived the heart attack and he lived to the age of 70.
I have written down here Natrum muriaticum first 1M. I crossed it out.
Then I've written Phosphorus. I crossed it out.
Then I wrote the medicine in 200.
You see I talk with her more now. Nat. muriaticum? No, something is lacking.
There is this closed person but the emotions are inside in a state of much more strength
than the Nat muriaticum people.
The Nat muriaticum are like the English.
Somebody said yesterday, the English men who control all emotions.
They control emotions.
She could not control the emotions. The emotions were arising and affecting so much.
I said this does not go with the essence.
Then she was a very nice girl but so inhibited, so inside.
She had difficulty in communicating, in talking.
There is a biting of the nails, there is strong emotions that cannot be communicated.
I asked her whether she was going steady with that man.
That was the only man she was going out from much younger age
and she never thought of another man.
Lack of self-confidence was there, lack of self-confidence and embarrassment.
She felt embarrassment very easily.
Can anybody remember from my teaching of the remedies in which remedy
I referred to you as a polarity on a second type of person?
Do you know?
-What was the question?
-If anybody of you that listened to my lectures remembers the description
of such a type of case in one of the remedies which I have given?
That inhibited type, inhibited person that will not be able to communicate very well.
-Medorrhinum?
-Medorrhinum you remember?
What I had in front of me as essence is concerned, that strong emotions
which cannot be communicated? You don't remember?
When I give the lectures, of course you can't remember everything
but it is very helpful if you do remember.
You know Medorrhinum, we all know Medorrhinum as the extrovert who has sex,
who goes from woman to woman, he expresses himself.
But I have commented to you in Medorrhinum and I said be careful
there is another type, which is inhibited.
And I remember I had described a case where she could not talk.
She came in front of us with her boyfriend and it was impossible to talk.
She was taking a lot of alcohol to be able to talk and yet she was so inhibited,
she wouldn't talk. That state.
We miss many cases that we don't know that inside of how the remedy behaves
and we take the symptomatology and we cannot make it out.
And we miss many cases.
I remember cases, which later on when I came to the understanding of the remedies
I said my god that case was Medorrhinum or that case was Mercury.
Because Mercury also has that inhibition.
Mercury has a lot of inhibitions and cannot talk and will statter.
In this way he will talk.
-Lachesis also has that?
-Lachesis is inside.
She will say something to hurt you, she will present her case, she won't say I'm jealous
but she will say something to imply that.
It's a whole lecture if I give that and I don't want to go to it. You will be confused.
We have biting of the nails in the next rubric.
We have reasons to go with the Nat mur and Phosphorus definitely.
Other remedies I do not see.
An interesting thing is that in claustrophobia, Medorrhinum is not mentioned anywhere.
And claustrophobia has been totally eliminated by Medorrhinum here in this case.
If we have claustrophobia in Medorrhinum now, in your Repertories you may insert it.
We had the heart, which is affected and which shows the sycotic miasm.
We have the desire for orange juice, we have the biting of the nails, which is capital.
We have the whole character to go by, what is left?
There is nothing left that cannot tally with Medorrhinum.
-The clairvoyance?
-The clairvoyance dreams come a lot with Medorrhinum.
I don't think that Kent mentioned that.
Clairvoyance is not Medorrhinum?
-It is.
-Sure it affected my thinking because I put things together.
When I see that character, that girl...
The husband was in the medical school, I took the case myself
and I gave great favor to her and they wanted me so much to see her myself.
She had great respect for me and yet she won't talk, she was very inhibited.
You could see a person that the emotions were alive inside
and she gives the indication that the emotions are strong but not able to be expressed.
This is a case where it goes totally away from that theory.
When the theory is not really valid, it doesn't hold good.
This is a perfect case of psoriasis, of psoric miasm according to that theory
and then you give Medorrhinum, the number one sycotic.
And then the essence and you say this is the psoric side of Medorrhinum.
You can make anyhing but what is left from the miasms?
So the miasms are not that.
One day they might be able to speak about the miasms
and I shall give you some information concerning the miasms of how I evaluate them,
how I see recognize them and what value they play in prescribing.
They do not play such a tremendous value in prescribing.
They play a value in prescribing for long periods of time.
But they play very mild part in finding the first or the second remedy.
That's why novices who do not even know the theory of miasms,
can spot the remedy very quickly.
The understanding of the layers is the miasms and plus indications,
which I hope one day when these things will have been clarified,
then my thinking I shall give it out to you.
-Medorrhinum is not in the rubric ailments from fright.
-Yes. You can ignore that.
-Like Staphysagria where you see the emotions are too powerful.
-Yes, too strong for Staphysagria.
The first information she gives is better joy...
I could see a real connection between emotions and the pathology that was going on.
And I wanted a remedy which has that in essence.
I thought I had described to you quite clearly the essence of Medorrhinum
and that you would be able to spot it.
Of course in another case when you see it now, you may remember it better
because you met the problem.
Somebody wants to talk? Is anybody who does not understand why this is Medorrhinum?
Of course you said it before because otherwise you would have found it.
-The emotions are very strong, I was wondering if they are too strong to be inhibited.
-Exactly that's the idea. It's impulsive, she cannot inhibit.
Argentum nitricum lets it out.
It's not inhibition there, it's a restriction on the reaction.
That's inhibition, it's instinctive.
She does not think I must not say that because it's no good,
it's not right, they will criticize me.
It's an instinct which is there, she cannot handle it.
It's a very alive person, with very alive emotions. It's not dead.
Staphysagria is much more dull.
Everything was inside but cannot be expressed and embarrassment all the time
and concern about others.
-Lachesis?
-I said we cannot say that this is a description of Lachesis.
You know the other type of Lachesis I've spoken about? It's not that.
The other type of Lachesis is quite a lot of spite, malicious.
She wants to bite but she is compulsive. I'll give you an example.
I go in the street and the man has the child, the woman goes back.
She says give me the child because you don't protect it enough.
She takes the child and she goes and a few meters after the child falls down
and then Lachesis what will do?
It will put the whole responsibility on the husband.
You see I told you, you made me cross and that's why the child fell down.
So it's your fault. You have done it. It's always your fault.
It's you that you have done something and I have not done it.
She will not express jealousy, that other type.
There are two couples. One is the doctor and his wife, the other is the engineer
and his wife and they go together.
Then the doctor who knows them a lot and knows that the thyroid of the woman
of the engineer is having trouble, he says how is your thyroid, just out of curiosity
and friendliness and interest.
The Lachesis woman will observe that. She won't say a thing.
She will go back and she will think of it and she will say he definitely showed
much more interest than he should have done.
And then she will not say why did you show...?
But she will not say it exactly, she will say something to the effect that you paid
perhaps too much attention to her and this may have been interpreted by her husband.
It's not me that I'm jealous, force the fault to somebody else.
No, no, no I know you are talking...
The husband with the mother in law in the house and they talk and he communicates
naturally with her also and she would think that she is left out
and the husband is giving more attention to the mother in law or to his mother
than he is giving to her.
In a certain break of nervousness she will say something malicious to him
and then underneath that she would reveal that she had been put aside,
in the husband understanding.
This type is much more disciplined in her reaction than the other one.
Then you see the man he is at a certain job but he is jealous of the others
having a better job than he has.
What he will do is he will moan like I did not have the possibility to study like him
and much more possibilities were giving to him and this thing will eat him up
constantly all these thoughts. He will never say I'm jealous.
This is quite disguised in the second type and it's presented as a very disciplined
and very orderly person but emotions are rising to the extend
that they give rise to thoughts, which are completely if you analyse them deeper,
they are of the type of jealousy. But you will not see them in the beginning at all.
The desire for chicken also...
She came two months later to see me again, I have not written down the exact date.
This report is 8 months afterwards.
She said that she had an aggravation for 10 days and after that started amelioration.
The itching during the aggravation was much increased.
If you remember there was no itching apart from the first days. Now she had itching.
Then she describes it as an intense calm inside after the aggravation, joy.
The words she used often is 'psyhremia'.
It is interesting because she described exactly the coming down of that intensity.
She said joy and intense calmness and the clearness of the mind.
Previously she thought she was overtaken by a situation. Now she is cool.
It took away that condition, that inside intensity of the emotions
which she will not describe it. She will not say I have emotions.
She could not describe anything of what was going on.
What she said was that when I'm joyfull it's gone, when I'm in grief it's...
That was an observation but actually the same observation was not there.
She would not give me that.
What you had is to feel and understand what is going on inside.
But I give you a hint that they may give you to understand the inside of what is going on.
She confirmed it later on by giving the natural state, the healing state of things.
And she said you were right when you evaluated that situation in me.
I heard what she is saying by the description because I didn't tell her evaluation
and all that.
After that it started a period where she says sometimes I will go down and then up again.
Then going down and up but on the whole she was quite OK.
She had no tachycardia. Lately she says that she has some stitches in the heart
but if she lies down, immediately they go away.
She says that she started to see dreams of a nightmare style.
Sleeps on back now. The position of sleep which is on abdomen with Medorrhinum,
for Medorrhinum is normal to the back or to the sides.
No claustrophobia at all. She can enter a lift, she can go anywhere.
She said that is gone completely. No desire for chicken.
She eats the chicken but there is no special desire.
It was very accentuated in the first meeting.
And lately she says I've started biting my nails again.
So she has some ups and downs, bites her nails again. What shall we do?
-Wait.
-We can't wait, she comes from Thessaloniki very far and I have to make a decision.
-Stramonium.
-Stramonium?
No problem.
The symptoms in the skin, she says sometimes up, sometimes down.
But it seems it starts to appear and disappear.
You must remember that the whole body is covered with that situation and the head.
It has cleared up and then after a while it started coming up and down.
In the meantime she said I had this aggravation and I said wait, wait, wait.
Then wait, wait by the phone, she decided to come and see me.
By the time she comes to see me, I said continue it's all right.
Then it goes away, then it comes back.
That is the situation when she comes to see me and what did I do?
-Placebo.
-Generally she is better, mentally she is better...
All that is left is some fluctuations. In that phase I would not give her a remedy.
-Of course the prescription here is placebo.
Now she comes 3 years later on 8th of February 1980.
And now she is in a crisis, that means it's broken out the eruption.
Before that breaking out there was an allergic condition which came up.
She has eaten something, she did not know, there was an allergic condition went away
and the eruption broke out again.
It has intense itching now and the itching is worse in the afternoon.
It's interesting that the heart is still working OK, tachycardia has gone
and claustrophobia still remains.
Desire for chicken did not come back again, the desire for sweets is more
and the thirst is more. What has increased is the desire for orange juice.
Sweets and orange juice have increased in desire.
Now she dreams and many times she sees sweets in her dreams.
Biting of the nails is quite strong again and no other information.
1980 as we said, 8th of February. What did I do? What would you do?
200. You remember I wrote 2 remedies before Medorrhinum
and then I wrote Medorrhinum.
In this case I would have given 1M if it was a very clear cut case of Medorrhinum.
But that's not a very clear cut case of Medorrhinum.
So I gave 200. That was a small potency.
Now what did I do?
-1M.
-10M.
-I'm going to change the remedy because there are changes in the chicken,
claustrophobia and tachycardia?
-No.
-No. The constitutional symptoms which had come up more, desire for sweets
and desire for oranges are covered by the same previous remedy?
-Yes.
-They are covered.
Then the biting of the nails is characteristic of Medorrhinum as we saw.
Medorrhinum has helped her. She is in a relapse.
The itching is in the afternoon but it's not in the evening.
So I gave a dose of Medorrhinum 1M and she has not bothered me since then.
She used to telephone quite a lot when we had started.
When she was reassured, it took her 2 years before she came down.
I told her, I explained to her that you might have a real relapse
and you still wait for 15-20 days, one month before you see the relapse
it is really established that you come down again. And that was the case.
With that case we had 3 years going by from Medorrhinum 200 with a good reaction.
When the remedy is correct, you don't expect within 2-3 months to come back.
Also I would even say that 3 years is not a big time.
Some antidotal influences most probably have been on her to bring it back.
We've seen cases that after 5, after 6, after 10 years we see them again.
That means they remained well, in spite of antidotal influences.
This is the effect that we have when we find the correct remedy.
I'll tell you something about psoriasis.
From 5-6 years onwards to 10, 20 years psoriasis is a very difficult situation to treat.
If they come within the first 6 months, I found out that success is 100%.
Once you find the remedy is 100% success.
But if they have a lot of years behind their back with the psoriasis,
it becomes much more difficult.
I treated a case of generalized psoriasis, which was for about 10 years.
I treated for 5 years before I could make the skin tolerably well
and yet the skin is with redness.
And I have seen that case with 25 years, they get better but to a certain extend.
They don't progress further.
This is a case where she had the eruption almost 6 years.
But there is a difference here with the psoriasis, it is puncted.
This kind of psoriasis, in Greek is called puncted para-psoriasis.
I don't know if that's the whole name in English also.
In Greek is 'stagonoides' para-psoriasis, this is the diagnosis.
Have you got the English? Stagonoides para-psoriasis.
What you said punctate para-psoriasis.
There are two types of psoriasis.
The classical type which is more malignant than the para-psoriasis.
This para-psoriasis looks like it but it has small...
In psoriasis it becomes bigger and bigger and one spot can become within
25 years as big as that one.
It becomes a whole redness which has started from a spot like that
and then the thickness of the skin is quite thick and it falls out in big pieces.
In para-psoriasis it remains to that size and the scale
which is formed is much more thinner.
Also you don't have the cracks and the fissures that trigger in psoriasis proper.
They respond quickly, they don't go towards cure.
They respond quickly usually with a big reaction.
That means flare up of the situation.
Then it's gone up to a certain point and then they don't go further.
-Do you have any conjecture why psoriasis was the disease?
-Psoriasis is of an unknown origin and they classify it usually with the collagen diseases.
All collagen diseases are supposed to be quite obstinate and quite persistent.
And all diseases like lupus erythematosus are also of the same type,
of the same prognosis. Also rheumatoid arthritis.
What I said it holds good for all collagen diseases.
But strangely enough you have a condition the sarcoidosis.
That is supposed to be a more serious condition than lupus erythematosus.
How you identify?
How you say the intensity between these two diseases are?
What would you say?
Sarcoidosis verse lupus. Which is more great as a prognosis?
-I would say sarcoid is an equivalent. They are equivalent to each other.
-But for us, for treating cases of sarcoidosis I found out
that it is more easily manageable than lupus.
-...Can you probably say that they are not going to jump up to another level of health?
-Most probably in other words we can say that. They are not going to.
One more observation.
The same observation will apply for multiple sclerosis.
Multiple sclerosis will form a plaque and this will give out symptoms
which will be permanent.
Around the plaques there is an edema which causes the symptoms to appear and disappear,
when the edema goes away.
That's why it has a kind of recurrency.
When you treat homeopathically, you take away the edema
and the tendency to form edemas and plaques but what is before your treatment,
what damage is done before your treatment is going to be left there.
Do not expect that this will go away.
Therefore if you catch these cases very early in their development you have 100 % cures.
But if you let it develop within 2-3 years, the plaques becomes more and more
then the permanent damage will be left in spite of your treatment.
-Are you saying within the first year they are diagnosed or...
Because many people have for 2-3 years strange symptoms.
-That is a problem in diagnosis.
Mulptiple sclerosis may appear, the first signs might be of very different type.
It can appear as diplopia, it can appear as post bulbar neuritis as numbness in different parts,
as a difficulty, as a weakness on the extremities. It may have a lot of forms.
But there is a recurrence and you will see it after 6 months again.
With a similar episode and then it starts the numbness, the weakness.
At that stage are manageable and they are many cases
that they were diagnosed already.
I believe that if we had better diagnosis for multiple sclerosis,
we may be able to establish better our results.
-I wonder if this is same. I have a case of generalized psoriasis 15-20 years, very severe...
Now much better energy, the skin is exactly the same but it has an aggravation
the first week. I asked him what it was. An extreme pain.
But there was no change in the skin but since it was so much better
we didn't do anything but I wonder why the skin didn't change.
-Most probably. 20 years of psoriasis you don't expect much changes.
Actually we have battled with such cases and what I tell you now
is my experience of the last years and what you came down
to know after many years of battling.
In the beginning we battled with this and you try to do something really.
What you see is aggravations, ameliorations up to a certain extend
and then it stays there.
There is one more point to remember, that if you make mistakes with these cases,
later on you may bring back the whole situation as it was in the beginning.
After 2-3 years of treatment while the person is ameliorated to quite a good point
but not happy, not satisfied because the thing is not gone,
you try more and more and then you make mistakes.
One day you see the whole thing flares all over again and you say my god.
Then they get disappointed and they may leave you.
This is lack of knowledge of Theory, of what we can do.
In our books unfortunately nobody else spoke clearly about these things.
You get cases in literature. A scyzophrenia case is cured, an epilepsy case is cured,
a multiple sclerosis is cured but nobody spoke the truth, his experience.
And I tell you just to see the possibilities that exist with Homeopathy,
I'll give you an idea.
They brought me on 1968 a case of multiple sclerosis
which has been going on for the last 10 years. I did not know that at that time.
I prescribed. They stopped the cortisone.
She was walking with the cortisone, cut down the cortisone, in bed, paralyzed.
Once you cut down the cortisone in such heavy cases,
they lie in bed, paralysed completely.
I tried a treatment for 3 months but she was in bed constantly.
With cortisone she was walking. Without treatment she stayed in bed for 2,5 months.
I expected that I may have treated more and more and find what was the next remedy
but she had no patience to wait and she went back to cortisone.
She took some Russian remedies they give with snakes and some Bulgarian remedies
and on 1979, about 10 years later, they called me again to see the case.
But the case was in the last stage.
The medulla oblongata was affected, she had difficulty in swallowing,
difficulty in the heart, difficulty... That is the last stage that they get choked
and they die.
She was in bed now, for the last one year she was permanently in a chair.
Hands affected, all extremities were affected, heart was affected...
They called me and they said we decided finally to give up cortisone
and rely on the treatment completely.
They knew she was going to die.
I said Ok since she stopped the cortisone... that was the end of the cortisone.
I went to see her and I prescribed for her a series of remedies.
The symptoms of dyspnea, of not swallowing,
of not being able to speak they all went away.
She reached the point where she saw some signs of moving the big toe.
She was better psychologically, better in everything.
She was married to a young man at her age, that girl must be 35 years old.
Since 12 years old she is suffering with the disease and she became pregnant.
That becoming pregnant was after the second homeopathic treatment.
Then one day they telephoned me and said she is pregnant, what we should do?
I say my god, you have a big problem.
I said ask the gynecologist whom she was attending and ask what are the prognosis
and whether she should keep it. And if he says yes, keep it.
And he said yes.
This girl now has a child of 1,5 years old.
I'm not attending the child, some other doctor is attending.
I believe that being under homeopathic treatment we escape a lot of suffering
but the interesting thing is that this girl from 1979, we have 1983,
she goes now with her life. I consider that she would have died within a few months.
We just saved her from the last stage of the disease.
She was able to cope with the labor.
The heart was almost a heart failure during the labor time
and we kept on prescribing for her.
That is to give you an idea of how we cure multiple sclerosis
but we have to be quite accurate when we talk.
To know what we propose because some day they are going to ask us to do
double blind test for Homeopathy.
So we know what we can do and not claim what we cannot believe.