This case, she comes to the doctor and says...
The first thing she says is that mostly what I suffer from
is that I have the tendency to commit suicide.
What is this remedy?
-Aurum.
-Aurum, very good. But it's not.
Why it's wrong?
-It's too open.
-It's too open for an Aurum.
Aurum won't come and tell you from the very beginning you know my problem is
I want to commit suicide. Forget it, that's not Aurum.
It's a more open remedy, it's a more vital remedy that will say that.
Pulsatilla can say it, Sulphur can say it but not Aurum.
Because the type that we meet Aurum, it will one with sheer depression.
Aurum has decided to commit suicide. He may be come for his depression
but with the back of his mind he says I want to commit suicide.
This is not a symptom. It is a logical decision because he suffers so much.
He suffers so much, the depression is so...that he does not want to live anymore.
This is the state of Aurum.
Therefore he will not come and tell you my problem is that I want to commit suicide.
Immediately your mind should go to other remedies which are more open and vital.
A Natrum sulphuricum would it say so?
-No.
-Which are the remedies in the Repertory? Open the Repertory at suicidal disposition.
We have in capitals, Aurum, Aurum muriaticum and Natrum sulphuricum.
These are the three remedies. The two Aurums are similar in their way of facing the world.
The one is Aurum metallicum and the other is Aurum muriaticum, the underneath.
The Aurum muriaticum is not as deep as Aurum metallicum.
It is quite deep but not as deep as Aurum metallicum.
Aurum metallicum should be underlined in the Repertory
because it's the remedy that really commits suicide.
It's the number one remedy that really commits suicide.
It has to be elevated further from the other two.
Aurum muriaticum, the muriatica seems that pose down the tendency of Aurum to stop his life
and they will say this, I cannot live anymore etc.
Depression we see with Aurum metallicum.
Natrum sulphuricum now. We have what kind of depression?
There is a struggle inside in Natrum sulphuricum cases that it's really a struggle
that I should not live anymore, I want to die, I just want to go away from this world.
But they know that if they do it, their children, their brothers,
their sisters will suffer tremendously.
They know that and they want to bring that suffering to their relatives.
There is a constant struggle inside them. On the one hand wanted to go away from this world,
on the other hand they say if they do it, think of ... I don't know the Indian name...
I struggle inside, I must die, I can't live, a constant struggle inside.
This is the feeling inside. I want you to understand the real inside, what is going on.
Then do you think they will come and tell you I'm struggling inside? No.
Then what you get? You get a feeling, yes I want to die.
And then you feel something more is inside and you say why don't you die?
They say I'm thinking of my children, I'm thinking of my brothers,
I'm thinking of whomever he is connected. And then what?
Then I constantly have that struggle to pick up the information, almost force the information.
They are not open people who just tell that I want to commit suicide.
So neither Aurum Muriaticum, nor Natrum sulphuricum
or Aurum metallicum will use such an expression.
When I was in primary school I was first but when I went to the gymnasium
because they were better people than me, I thought of giving up gymnasium.
Also I have claustrophobia, intense fear, especially when I'm going through a tunnel.
The thought that the train may stop going through a tunnel cause great panic to me.
When I was in the primary school I was first but when I went to the gymnasium
because they were better people than me I thought of giving up gymnasium.
Who can say that? Which are the persons?
Can an Aurum say that?
-Yes.
-Yes, an Aurum can confess that. But it's not only Aurum.
It might be a remedy which has mental weakness as well.
Which are the remedies that have mental weakness?
Argentum nitricum, Phosphorus, Phosphoric acid, Picric acid, Anacardium, Aethusa,
Barytta carbonica, Agaricus... and many others.
Now I also have claustrophobia and intense fear, especially when I'm going through a tunnel.
Which are the remedies that have claustrophobia going through a tunnel, great panic?
How do you find claustrophobia in the Repertory?
-Fear of narrow places.
-Fear of narrow places. Find fear of narrow places in the Repertory.
Other remedies that have that are Lycopodium, Natrum muriaticum, Calcarea carbonica.
Sometimes she wants to press the heart region and at the same time to take a deep breath
because she feels a kind of discomfort there and she is afraid that the heart will burst out.
How do you find this symptom in the Repertory?
Has anybody found this symptom? No.
Feeling of bursting in the heart.
Suddenly as I'm working I have a sudden tendency to faint.
Where do you find this symptom?
I have a great, sudden weakness.
Sudden weakness where do you see? In the generalities, weakness sudden.
This is how you look in the Repertory, how you study a case.
You try to see what is the remedy which covers mostly the symptomatology of the patient.
You go and look and search in the Repertory and you will always find eitherthe exact symptom
or something similar. And then you get some ideas about it.
Then the final decision will be made by your knowledge of Materia Medica.
How much knowledge of Materia Medica do you have?
Eventually you will say is this a case of Phosphorus? Is this a case of Sepia?
Is this a case of Aconite? Is this a case of Argentum nitricum?
Then after you study a case in this way, you have a lot of remedies.
You come down with 5 or 6 remedies that they may be possible in such a case.
In this particular case, you may be coming with different remedies
like Aconite, Argentum nitricum, Phosphorus, Arsenicum, Sepia.
And then you have to decide which of these remedies that came through repertorization
is the right one.
Let us say that the remedy is within those remedies which is indicated here...
Which of these remedies fits mostly this particular case? This is the question.
Out of repertorization we came down...
You saw frequently Aconite, Argentum nitricum, Phosphorus, Arsenicum and Sepia.
Which of these remedies is mostly fitting to this case
and how logically you can say this is the remedy?
Here now comes the knowledge of Materia Medica.
How much Materia Medica do you know to be able to differentiate really?
If you don't know enough Materia Medica, what you will do?
Can anybody tell me what you will do?
-Totality.
-But you worked on the totality and more remedies come through.
What are you going to do?
-Find the essence.
-Say you don't know the essence of all these remedies to be able to differentiate.
What can you do further?
You may try to see the causative factor, it is giving you a clue.
What was the causative factor in this case?
-There was an earthquake.
-There was an earthquake and people were dying.
You don't know the remedy. I know the remedy but I try to teach you how to think.
This state came after a fright that this man had because of the earthquake
and because also of some death that took place next to that.
Then what is next? What I'm going to do next?
Which are the remedies that they may have symptoms after fright?
Here in Greece that we have a lot of earthquakes, I give you a remedy
that has symptomatology after this fright.
-Opium.
-Opium, Aconite, Stramonium, Ignatia concerning...
and this person has 2-3 symptoms that are very underlined.
What are the symptoms that are 3 times underlined?
Great, sudden weakness, I don't want anybody to contradict me, time seems endless if I wait,
I cannot hear bad news, I become panicky, claustrophobia, fear of being in a crowd,
she cannot go out, then she becomes panicky.
There is a day where she cannot go out and then she becomes claustrophobic.
I cannot even think of going in an airplane and fear of being alone in the house
in case there is an earthquake.
These are the symptoms that have been intensively underlined.
From the Materia Medica we know that after fright from this remedy, Aconite should be one
that is mostly indicated.
From this remedy, the one that is mostly indicated after fright is Aconite.
Which is the remedy which has fear in a crowd and claustrophobia?
Fear of narrow places, we read it before, it was Aconite.
See fear in a crowd, see in your Repertory.
You see how strongly is Aconite there?
If you go and read now the Materia Medica, especially our Materia Medica on Aconite,
you will see the description of that very much,
you will see how the Aconite cannot go in an airplane, how he becomes panicky
and then they faint.
You will see all the description of what is happening here and also you will not be mislead
to prescribe here Aurum because the Aconite patient is an open patient, vital, strong,
will give this information immediately, I want to commit suicide.
It is not a closed person, it is an extrovert.
Out of these remedies if you go and study a little bit more,
you will see that Aconite is very prominently indicated.
Would you like to see what she said when she came? She got Aconite 50M.
When she came back after a month, she said that generally and mentally she is much better.
From the beginning when the doctor started enquiring about her symtpoms,
she says it crossed out all the bad symptomatology which I had.
I have nothing anymore from that.
I had an aggravation the seventh day. The seventh day she had a mental aggravation
and since that day, since the seventh day, that she was very irritable,
she wanted to kill her husband, after the seventh day everything is going well.
No tendency to commit suicide, no fear in the tunnel.
She has come actually by train, the day she came to consultation.
The chest symptoms are not there, no fainting, no weakness.
Buzzing in the ears if I'm pressed by some situation but even this is better.
She had not given in the beginning this symptom.
The feeling that something kicks the heart is better.
She wants to do the work in the house. No fear of brain stroke.
She managed to go and shop in the town, the claustrophobia is much better.
She can wait now, she goes on like that.
We see in the report because of that general amelioration
that the remedy has really acted deeply, in spite of being Aconite.
Aconite usually in our books, we have it for common colds.
When there is a common cold, we give Aconite.
And you see here a case which is quite disturbed mentally
and Aconite takes all the symptomatology
and gives us a beautiful cure on a chronic condition.