What is the issue that we will dicide for what remedy we will prescribe.
It will be, whether we have enough symptomatology to support a prescription clearly.
If we have enough symptomatology to support the Graphites prescription, then we know
that the constitutional remedy is needed.
But if we have enough evidence to support Ignatia, then we know we're achieving the
layer upon which came after the treatment.
So the next question in the analysis of the case is, is any constitutional remedy that goes
through his case?
Elements of Sulphur, elements of Medorrhinum, elements of Graphites,
elements of Natrum sulphuricum they are not strong, they don't have enough information
to prescribe with certainty and have an effect on this case.
Furthermore his case is not clear anyhow when we prescribe...
But since it is definite that the whole thing started
and from now on his health is decreasing.
I supposed we had to counteract that kind of shock and the problem is with what remedy?
-Natrum muriaticum?
-He presents certain symptoms of Natrum muriaticum, especially when he says that when
he drinks, he feels more relaxed
Then you communicate better with your wife?
That feeling does not present a picture of Natrum muriaticum.
He spoke quite in depth, there is a closeness, he does not supposed to be bothered with
his emotions, why?
Because his emotions are very strong.
And that means what? All the lack of energy he experiences now is a repercussion on the
suppression of the emotions. Why do I say that?
Because going into spiritual questions like impression of egotism, selfishness etc.
You remember when he said when he went to Brazil he was happy but it was an ego trip;
that means he is what it is to enjoy and to feel important
he was flirting with different women he was successful , his love affairs and his
ego was stimulated according to his intellectual rhythm.
Even that did not allow an expression of that portion in him suppressed.
So I feel that the lack of energy and the sudden lack of energy is because he has not
allowed the powerful emotions which are in him to take expression.
He will find himself when he will find an expression of these emotions.
Our remedy should be one that holds back the emotions.
Because of his constitution he is prone to philosophical thinking.
Philosophical thinking is a natural tendency to him. He did not mentioned anything on that,
I don't know if he knows that tendency but there are certain signs in his face that show
philosophical thinking.
He will be a philosopher. Eventually if he goes on with his life, he will be more and more
philosophically inclined.
It could be the nose that shows that and also the eyes which are white underneath,
together with the Impression that we get when we discussed.
So his energies have been blocked with questions about life that blocked his energy.
He is paralyzed, he does not know whether to do this or to do that. He does not know
whether it is right to express the emotions or not to express his emotions and how to do it.
Also he does not know how to do it. He has not learnt.
Also another point that I would say, he mentioned his liver and his spleen.
He feels maybe it's not functioning and the digestive system but here more I see an
affection functional, dysfunction of the suprarenal gland.
I feel that this impact has been taken in the suprarenal gland and that's why there is this
sudden drop of energy. Not that there is anything there. How is your blood pressure?
-It's not too high. It's not low.
-160 - 100.
-Oh, wait a moment. Is that what you mean? It's a bit high.
-But that's the highest.
-Diet should be very careful definitely.
-We are thinking of Staphysagria, is it Staphysagria?
Is it Phosphoric acid, is it Ignatia, is it Natrum muriaticum?
There are certain symptoms to support this.
Do you have a sighing at all?
-Yes.
-How many times you can do that in a day?
-It depends but I do it.
-Frequently?
-Once an hour or something like that.
-Can he be Sepia because also he has some symptoms of Sepia? He says he likes
dancing and he is stimulated by physical activity and also Rhus tox because the
symptoms that he presents
are symptoms of Rhus tox
-A lot of Sepia.
-You see now the problem? How to start a case because you like to be successful.
You don't want to give Sepia and then Ignatia and then Nat mur and then god knows
what. Because it may not just do anything finally.
So you like to strike the center.
-You had some ideas?
Who likes Nat mur in this case? Nobody.
Who likes Ignatia?
Who likes Phosphoric acid?
Who likes Thuja?
Fruits do you like? In general?
And perspiration mostly? Where do you perspire mostly?
-On my face.
-Only the face?
-The whole body, it starts with the face.
-Who likes Sepia? Who likes Staphysagria?
Is anybody that has any other idea? Natrum phosphoricum?
-China, because he is over-reserved, closed person, he is sensitive, he can have this
impulsive anger. He has these pains of the... his eyes sore too and he has a yellow
discoloration.
-China has a yellow discoloration, is it capital?
-No.
-Mercury and Natrum phosphoricum. China is italics?
-China is having some symptomatology also.
-Daydreaming.
-Daydreaming yes.
-What is your reason for Mercury?
-He is very sensitive, that kind of sensitive that you can see in Mercury.
They do not contact others unless they feel really warm, they cannot even talk if there is
no contact.
-Would you consider Aurum?
-Aurum sure.
What is the area which you have to treat in this case?
You feel this emotional area is very calm. This is your focus of attention now.
You have to find the remedy that concentrates, not only that concentrates on the liver or
China that concentrates on the gallbladder or Sepia that concentrates on the reproductive
system but really you need a remedy to touch the emotional side, to free the flow of
energy and then to produce more acute physical symptom.
Once you will touch this case emotionally, he will develop more clear, more acute physical
symptomatology.
Then is the time for Sepia, for China, for Graphites, for Sulphur, for Natrum sulphuricum.
All these possibilities are there but first you have to touch that.
-I think if you give the remedy we are talking to, you are touching other symptoms.
If for example you give Lycopodium 10M or 50M. It's not only for the liver.
-You touch the mind but when I say Lycopodium is mostly given for the digestive system.
It acts more on the digestive system but it acts also on mental-emotional.
But if the main problem is emotional, you will seldom think of Lycopodium,
if it is purely emotional.
-Nitric acid?
-Nitric acid and Argentum nitricum.
He does not have the anxiety of Nitric acid.
What are the remedies there? We have Causticum, we have Graphites, we have
Arum triphillum, Nitric acid and Silica.
-Can you consider Lachesis here?
-There are some points of Lachesis.
-The suppression of emotions.
-Yes, sure.
-I thought of Ignatia, then Sepia
-Do you take milk?
-Yes.
-The sun, how do you tolerate the sun? You can walk in the sun?
-Yes. The heat I don't like.
-Hot applications are tolerated?
-When the bath is too hot, then I think about hell or something like that
That makes me nervous when it's too hot. I don't like when it's too hot.
-Where to start? You see how many possibilities with good reasons?
He has lost his desire for sex also which is in favor of Sepia.
As we discuss we get a clearer understanding of this case.
That is what you have to do by yourself, thinking of the case because when we think of
the case, we have different ideas. We are concreting the ideas, why this and not that?
-What you would give?
-I would give Ignatia.
-Who would give Ignatia? Who would give Nat mur?
Who would give Sepia? Who would give Phosphoric acid?
The main feelings are indifference? Can you say indifference?
-I thought about it. Something neutral, all this neutrality
-Why the crisis came on?
He had a relationship with his wife and at a certain moment they felt that they are not
good for each other, they decided to separate but stay on the same house
-No, I changed house.
-I thought you said you stayed in the same house when you decided to separate.
-I said when we decided to divorce. It's a period we stayed together.
-For how long?
-One and a half year.
-During that one and a half year, she had a love affair with somebody else?
-I haven't seen it, I don't know.
-When you have seen it?
-I don't know, it was with divorce in February and the first time I came home she was with
another one and that was a shock to me because it was always like that, periods away
and then together again. Suddenly I saw that man and I got a lot of anger that time.
-Was there jealousy with this anger?
-Yes jealousy.
-There are a lot of problems with a relationship after a divorce.
-What are his feelings now for his first wife? At the moment?
-I don't have feelings. It's not good. I don't want to face it. The problem is not solved.
It's not hatred. There was a lot of problems with the divorce, we had to share what we own.
I don't care about my first girls. They come to me once the year. I don't call them and if
they don't call me, they don't come. It's something that (?)
-With that girl now you have a lot of emotions?
-Yes, I really love her.
With the first one I feel it's not working and I have so much anger.
-There is a big mortification and grief.
-Since he speaks so easily about his personal affair, would he be Nat mur or another
close remedy?
-He could, not a typical Nat mur.
The way he speaks is not a typical Nat mur but he could be.
Also we have to understand that Nat mur of today, especially in the intellectualized
countries like America especially, they can speak about anything, they don't feel.
They can speak about their feelings, they can speak about their relationships because
they train themselves to do it.
Here in Greece we get the more pure type of Nat mur, in America you have to understand.
He is a psychiatrist also. It's in psychological treatment, psychotherapy and they say
these things several times. So he maybe a Nat mur but sophisticated.
You see what I don't like about Nat mur is the condition which is inside, which is cut
emotionally, it is emotions strong but cut. That is Nat mur.
In his case it is Phosphoric acid and Sepia, he is indifferent.
The problem is here behind and affecting the emotions which are here but in a
subconscious way and paralyzing the emotions.
Paralyzing the emotions but some of the organs are taking the impact.
I feel as an example that more and more that this is very big.
And there is this state of depression he is in
but he is not the type, the depressed type, he is not prone to depression
but the problems is so big that has brought about a state of depression.
Therefore I would prescribe as the first remedy, Aurum.
Aurum until we free him on a certain level and then eventually
he may need some Sepia or Nat mur or Nat sulphuricum.
But this is a deep state of depression for him, he does not appear with the tendency to
commit suicide because he is not the depressed person, he is not the type that will go into
pure depression, that will make tendency for suicide.
But it's as serious as the Aurum state.
This deep closeness, this untouchable...The feelings are completely untouchable.
I feel that Aurum should be given first. If it does not act, then Sepia he will try.
If it does not act, then Nat mur. If it does not act, then Ignatia.
This is more or less the series of remedies.
Now if Aurum acts, he may still need Sepia as a second remedy or he may need another
remedy all together. If Aurum acts, it may change the situation.
I believe that the next stage tremendous anger will come out, it will be expressed that
anger that was held back it will be expressed during that period of healing, irritability,
tremendous irritability and then one should go through this period and then we will search
for the next remedy.
I'm sure that the suprarenal glands have been somewhat affected, that's why your blood
pressure...This blood pressure is ...
-What about Phosphoric acid?
-I would say that the weakness is Phosphoric acid.
There will be some mind, intellectual weakness and also the state in which he would have
been, it would have been is total indifference. But he said it's not indifference.
It is something that does not move. Not real indifference.
This state is what we describe in Sepia situations. Sepia is very possible.
Actually in the beginning I was more Sepia and then as the case it was developing I was
seeing more and more the deepness of depression and then the events that justify this and
then I chose Aurum.
-Why did you think about Aurum?
-A few symptoms, like  better in evening is characteristic of Aurum and mostly the intensity of
the depression and the fact of being his type, he said sometimes he is thinking about the
idea of suicide.
You were a good case because you gave us a lot of intellectual exercise.
What we are doing in Homeopathy in prescribing?
We have two basic kinds of prescribing.
The one is prescribing for a layer
and the second type of prescribing is prescribing upon a layer.
What do we mean by that?
Prescribing for a layer is prescribing deep constitutionally and taking away a chronic
condition, a layer that will give the person a sense of well-being and will jump in health.
Prescribing for a layer will have as an effect a jump in the health of an individual,
will feel not only better but another level of health.
This kind of prescribing for a layer is what we may call also a constitutional prescribing
and it is obtained by prescribing either one, two, three or a series of remedies.
That means a layer will not go away always with one remedy but maybe with a second
and a third remedy and these are cases where you prescribe one remedy constitutionally.
It does changes, then you prescribe a second one, you prescribe Apis, then you prescribe
Nat mur, where the person feels even better but finally you come with Sepia, Sepia covers
the most. So it is Apis, Nat mur, Sepia that has created the lifting of a layer in a person.
This is a desirable prescribing that it cannot be done always.
So usually what we do in our prescribing is prescribing upon a layer.
That means there is a layer, underline a layer which is Sulphur, Calcarea and we
prescribe Rhus tox, Bryonia, Belladonna and all the time we prescribe for that individual
without touching his deeper, constitutional tendencies.
Prescribing upon a layer would mean several things.
The first is that you cannot touch the deeper layer, unless you prescribe upon the layer.
You have a case of Sulphur constitutional but unless you give Ignatia to counteract a state
of grief in which he is in or a Staphysagria state of grief or a Causticum state of grief or a
Nat mur state of grief that was there for the last 5-6 years, you will not be able to prescribe
for the layer.
So you see some elements of Sulphur underneath, you go and give Sulphur but it doesn't
do anything unless you prescribe upon a state which has come about after a stress, a
grief or whatever it is.
What happens in this case, this person constitutionally has this kind of graph, which is
Graphites. He is basically a Graphites patient with an underlined Sulphur to cover up a
psoric layer or you can say Nitric acid and Mercury.
This is his basic layer and now this person most of his life he does not find a homeopath,
he takes allopathic drugs, sometimes he comes into contact with a big stress and then
upon the Graphites layer is grafted an Ignatia layer.
So you see some similarities here of Graphites which still looks underneath but taking into
consideration this part, you will see Ignatia. Unless you give Ignatia, he will not answer.
The underlined Graphites state will not appear.
So here it is a remedy not born with, not constitutional but grafted upon certain
circumstances.
So a remedy can be grafted or the picture of a remedy can be grafted upon a constitution
and if that is left for years, a second graft can take place under different stresses.
So here you may have Ignatia and upon the Ignatia state it can be grafted a state of
Phosphoric acid or another remedy.
You may need two remedies before you reach the real constitutional.
What happens is that an individual who needs Graphites, meets with a stress, sleeping on
a wet place, he gets up in the morning and he is with a lumbago or a sciatica.
He comes to you with symptoms of sciatica, which indicates a perfect case of Bryonia.
You give Bryonia, he goes back, he is very happy, thank you.
Or if that is left, this lumbago, sciatica etc. he may develop another remedy, that means
Rhus tox and then Bryonia.
So you give Rhus tox and then Bryonia and then cure and then he goes away.
But what you are not touching the underline at all.
But what you are doing and you may be doing it for years with that individual without
understanding what really happens, now in such a case prescribing upon a layer,
the sense of well-being and jumping a level-as we call it- it will never come.
The individual is happy because you are a good prescriber and every time he comes with
a stress, he comes with Phosphoric acid because he is in a syndicate and he goes for
elections and he is humiliated, he comes back with a Phosphoric acid state.
Then you give Phosphoric acid, he is cured, thank you very much, he goes back.
Then later on he goes to India and he comes with a diarrhea etc.
All these prescribings are prescribings upon a layer, that means you prescribe correctly,
this is a correct prescribing but it won't give the chance to go deeper.
But maybe he likes to come for a deeper treatment or you may not even explain to him
but you must know what you are doing.
You must know that I have touched this individual on a superficial level, which is correct.
It is not incorrect, it is correct but you have not touched him deeply.
That is a big difference.
The person is satisfied, you are satisfied, it won't seem to be (?) of what is going on
without any reason.
It is this knowledge that made me yesterday going away from remedies that may be
constitutional for him and I said this is a big shock, the organism is under that stress,
under that grief, then I have to see what is indicated for that state first and then actually
thinking about going into constitutional prescribing.
What happens in our prescribing actually, that sometimes we do that and it is correct.
What you will usually, well not usually, it depends in our experience but many times even
an experienced homeopath will do, is to prescribe upon this symptomatology, which is
Graphites, which is underneath.
That pushes a little bit the case and changes the case without producing real effect.
Then because of the change we prescribe another remedy and a little bit more change, a
little bit more change...
You remember the case I gave you with Ranunculus bulbosus?
You think that you are doing something; actually no remedy was correct except of
Ranunculus bulbosus and that was left, was not recognized and other remedies were
prescribed further to let the person stay in the Ranunculus bulbosus state.
So what we do is we prescribe and we change symptomatology without touching deeper,
without bringing out order into the case.
Order is a great thing to realize because we have a knowledge.
Order in this case it means that our knowledge is sufficient to recognize the harmonics,
which are appearing every time in the individual and to evaluate these harmonics and say
this is important harmonic now, I have to treat that.
This comes with experience and cases after cases and mistakes after mistakes.
I do not say that I have not made mistakes. I have done a lot of mistakes that's why
But I was very responsible.
And you know why I was very responsible? Because I was practicing medicine in a
country where you are not allowed to practice Medicine unless you are a medical doctor;
So I had to be absolutely correct. I had to be very correct and I was very anxious.
That's why most probably led me to the observation and to know more.
Other medical doctors say we can kill a few and then a few more.
In certain hospitals they call it, you know when they play football and the make a goal, one
doctor says to the other who comes on duty, we have two goals, that means we score two
points, there are two persons dead.
This is the attitude in hospitals. I could not have that attitude, I could not afford it.
Therefore I had to be very careful of what I was doing.
A clarity eventually comes upon and then you recognize that this is a case where you do
not prescribe constitutionally, you have to antidote first the upper layer, what we call the
upper layer.
And once this is gone, then you may be dealing with that layer.
So prescribing upon a layer can be correct and can be wrong
because you may be all your life prescribe upon a layer on an individual
when he needs Bryonia, you prescribe Graphites,
when he comes to Ranunculus bulbosus, you prescribe Rhus tox,
when he comes finally to Dulcamara influenza, you prescribe Dulcamara and he is better
but back to the previous layer and you can't find it
Another layer is coming because of another epidemic and you give correct, you give
correct, you give wrong, you give correct, you give wrong, wrong, wrong, one correct
This is more or less what is going on without knowing what you are doing.
When you prescribe a remedy, think it very seriously, decide that this the remedy, give it
and don't haphazardly go and change your remedies, give another. This is no good.
In his case I would like to comment a little bit more and then later I shall read you from the
Materia Medica I'm writing on Aurum to show you why I have decided on Aurum.
Why I didn't prescribed Ignatia?
Because Ignatia is a state which is much more mild and it is not as deep as I would see
that state in which he is.
Ignatia in spite of appearing there somewhat, it will not touch this case.
The hysterical element of Ignatia is not there.
It is rather a deep, philosophical attitude, thinking deeper.
He thinks a lot, he didn't disclose all his thinking of course, but it is not the hysterical
element of Ignatia
Ignatia is light in spite of her hysterias, in spite of her reactions.
You say something, she answers immediately.
You do something, immediately she can react.
There is a lightness. Here there is not that lightness.
There is a deeper, solid state.
I will read you from page 8, from Aurum just to show you.
Even Aurum is one of the main remedies with complaints from grief and rejection,
the patient seems almost to invite isolation, by his action he isolates himself.
He has a cool, calculating manner in his emotional life.
He seems to think, well I said good morning to my wife, that's enough.
What else she needs?
He feels an intolerable pressure from any sort of emotional demand made on him.
Do you understand?
He feels an intolerable pressure inside from demands on emotional level made on him.
The demands lead him to fits of anger and then self-reproach.
He is full of passions but seems to lack or being incapable of giving affection.
Though he has passions inside, he is unable to give affection.
On the other hand he requires a great deal of love and appreciation.
On a deeper level there is this need for affection and for love and for protection
but it is so deep. Even here he finds it difficulty in accepting affection.
Though in a deeper level he demands affection, he demands what he said about his
mother, the love, the breast, he wants to be safe
but even in this case he finds difficulty in accepting affection.
If his wife becomes over emotional or if her affection becomes too overt, it fills him with a
type of repulsion. An Aurum cannot take it, repulsion.
He seems to need a refined, almost elegant approach from the others.
Not over emotional things.
Thus he tends to cut down all warmth from his family and the ridiculous, when that is
expressed. Finally he becomes more and more isolated.
He looks at a distance in his relationships and finally he begins to blame himself.
He has been generous with his money but not with himself.
Then someone in his family criticizes him and calls him cold; he looks deeply into himself
thinking he is right, it's all my fault.
This element of not accepting affection, not being able to accept affection is very strong in
his case and depression is there and that is the type that we prescribe upon a layer now.
It is not a constitutional Aurum that you will find every little detail of Aurum but you will find
the essence of Aurum in his depression.
Though he says I do not want to commit suicide, he says I'm flirting sometimes with the
idea because he is not a constitutional Aurum.
I don't prescribe constitutionally Aurum, I prescribe in order to counteract the deep grief
that came upon during that period and also Aurum is philosophical.
It is much more deeper thinker than Phosphoric acid, Ignatia, Staphysagria, etc. from
these remedies.
So you are thinking not this, not that and then eventually, as the case unfolds, you say
that's Aurum.
In the constitutional type, when the child is Aurum, we see the high ideals
to be the best, to shine the gold.
The Aurum people need that reassurance from others, you are the best,
they need that in order to go on.
And as they go on with this reassurance, there comes the shock, the grief, the failure,
whatever it is and everything is lost. Absolute darkness, it cuts down the gold all together.
Then you need to eject some gold to be shining again.
Describing with words situations it is very difficult.
I've been thinking a lot when we are writing with Roger, you can ask him when you need,
I will give a lecture like this, I will talk about Aurum to him, he will write it down and he will
bring it back and half of what he writes it is misunderstanding, not this, not this, this word
is not right.
I mean to express the right thing is so difficult because you may have been reading
Aurum and yet not recognize that state, where he was saying almost the same words that
I was writing.
Here we prescribe mostly on what we call prescribing on essence, in his case.
We have the confirmation better in the evening, open your Repertory in generalities,
evening ameliorates and see which are the remedies that are ameliorated in the evening.
We will not go for Medorrhinum in his case.
You see how one could go on, desire for sour things, amelioration in the evening makes a
Medorrhinum case, where a Medorrhinum may be later on, it will be Sepia-Medorrhinum
or Medorrhinum-Sepia.
Then Medorrhinum is going to act but first this.
There are some people who are teaching today Homeopathy
and then what they have seen?
They have seen some cases who need Sulphur and a relapse, again Sulphur and again a
relapse and Sulphur does very good to them for almost every situation.
So they teach and they say there must be one remedy for every individual that is going to
help him right through.
You ask them, have you found this? For how many patients of yours have you found this?
Very few. But since they have seen that, that means every patient should have one
remedy that will cover everything...That is nonsense.
If you try for that, you go deeper and deeper, you go to the childhood area and you give
Staphysagria, you give Ignatia, you give this and that, nothing.
Unless we use our logic and our experience also.
Go and find deeper in there, yes sometimes you have to do that but in particular situations
where what symptomatology appears to be now is on the childhood as well.
He is not an Aurum childhood.
Aurum came after a grief.
That's why he is not a typical.
He will not have all the typical symptoms of Aurum.