-When I come home I still was very distended, the same as before, even more.
Every day I had the same constipation, nothing happened with that
but I have in the middle of July I had very little menses and that was the first time
since nearly 2 years because the menses had stopped.
It was about that time that I fax to you, I think I got a fax back.
-What did you say in the fax?
-I just said that I was very bad because I was very bad.
The summer in Norway was very good, hot, sunny, it was relaxing for me
and I went on vacation. Everything should be very good but this distention goes on,
every day.
I feel very tight sometimes but it was more tight when I started working again.
In August no more vacation. The tightness is still there, especially in the evening.
It goes with the bloatedness, I'm sure of that, I feel  that. I don't sleep so good either.
I sleep bad than before China, more restless, more sub-conscious in a way,
lots of dream every night but I dream about the usual things, what happens in the day
or I mix it with things before, people from the past in my life.
I take the Silica 200 12 of August and it didn't happen so much.
After Pulsatilla I had not so much desire for soft boiled eggs, I always had desire
for soft boiled eggs. It was less after Pulsatilla, with the Silica it comes back again.
I'm still quite thirsty, maybe a little less. After Pulsatilla I noticed that
in the evening at home, it could be chilly and before I never noticed.
I just sit there and people say aren't you cold? Now I more notice and I put
some more clothes but I'm still more warm than cold person and I still need
the fresh air for my head and all that stuff. It's the same.
But little changed, always here in Alonissos, I can go to the toilet, I have stool every day.
But this time for some days nothing, so this changed.
-But you said last time, here you had constipation.
-No, in past, 7 years ago always when I travel, I go more worse but in Greece it's better.
The last 5-6 years Greece is better, it's always better here.
But I tried the same at home to eat Greek salad with olives but it doesn't work.
So I feel it's something to do with the bacteria. It's another bacteria here than home,
I'm not sure about it.
But after Silica I have more perspiration in the groin again because I never perspire here.
I took away this many years ago, I told you.
But sometimes I can perspire in the groin and that's worse after Silica.
I still have bad concentration when I'm studying, when I'm reading a book to study
after work, half an hour and I'm tired.
But I'm still more relaxed than before, I do less things and I work little less,
I can stay a week by myself because I don't need company.
That had been better for a long time, I think I' m not sure if it's after Pulsatilla.
Maybe before.
-Here you had said last time you were in a hurry, you wanted to do a lot of things.
Now you say...
-I still do things but...
-But I see a big change in your face, I see much relaxation, you got a new boyfriend
or something?
-It's from 1 year, little more but we have a little...
-You seem more satisfied.
-Yes, I am.
-Can you tell us why?
-Yes, I moved in his house very soon, very fast. I don't do that.
I use to be with a person for at least 2-3 years, so I take a big challenge
and it works very good. Just sometimes...
but I think that's natural because we didn't' t know each other so well,
so I feel quite well about that.
He is very relaxing man, he is very kind man, spoiled me in a way.
-Tell me in the morning how you wake in the morning?
-If I slept good, the best for me is in the morning but before I could go to 5 or 6 sometimes
but now I hate that. I don't want to go before 7 o'clock.
If I have a good night I can stand up to 7 o'clock, I'm quite refreshed
but if I have this restless sleep, subconscious and all that, I'm not so awake.
So during the day my best time is before noon but after noon is going more and more down
and in the evening I'm very tired but it's a little better than the other time.
So I'm a little better because I can stay up more to 10.30, 11.00 instead
of being so tired at 9 and want to go to bed.
This summer I eat sausages because I never eat that because of the pork and that fat.
I take the chance and I eat some and I think I'm sensitive to everything,
so it doesn't matter, so I eat them 2 times.
-It makes no difference the pork sausages.
-I try to eat something else too but I never eat something with wheat,
some fine cakes with the wheat.
I don't eat that stuff because I cant' handle it so well.
-What about the potatoes? Did you eat potatoes?
-No, I try to avoid them, just a couple of times but I can see so much difference because
I feel I'm more, every day it's the distention now.
From morning before eating and then it goes on, in the evening sometimes it's very big,
sometimes not big, it depends on what I eat, I'm not sure.
-What time is the distention.
-I would say 7-8 and I always have to eat regularly. If I don't do that, I have distention too
and that can be earlier in the day. If it goes for 4-5 hours, it's very big.
-But tell me, you said potatoes you ate twice?
-Yes 2 times.
-What was the effect of potatoes?
-I'm not sure because before I was investigating more what I could have.
-Why?
-Because I knew I couldn't have milk products, I couldn't take potatoes,
but that was more lately, 2 years ago and fruits also.
-How is your reaction to this now?
-I think I react on everything, it's difficult to tell because I feel it's every day.
-Your distention is more.
-Yes it's more often.
Before I could have some days, it was OK and before that again some years ago,
I could have weeks. Some weeks was good and then it started again and I always notice
because if I eat milk products I was worse but now I can't tell
because I feel everything in a way makes me that.
If I eat very little, maybe it's little, if not mix too much.
So in the morning I eat eggs, sardines, maybe some tuna fish.
-Sardines in the morning?
-Yes I like them very much.
-You like the fish?
-I like fish.
-What about sweets?
-Not so much, I feel sometimes for it but I can't.
I know that's bad, a little bit of chocolate and sweets and it's bad for me
but I like chocolates.
I have no big desire, I never had that, maybe when I was 14 but not now.
I more feel for strong spice or food with taste, olives, caviar, smoked lamb.
-Can you tell me psychologically more differences between what you feel now
and before the treatment? Can you make an evaluation? What do you think?
-After November last year I sold my house.
That house was very big trouble for me for long time because it was lots of accidents there,
lots of stuff and I lived together with another, all these troubles.
But I was alone last year in summer, I meet this man and I was intending to sell my house
before I met him and I had investigated to have an apartment but he said, why you rush,
can't you live here and relax?
In the beginning I think that's stupid because we knew each other very little
but after a while I think why not, I can try and I feel very relaxed in this place.
It's very quite place, very small cozy house, I don't have much to do there
because he does so much.
-So therefore you feel better?
-I feel better after Pulsatilla I'm not sure.
-So you sold the house because it was a big problem for you, you felt much release after
selling and then you met this man with whom you are doing quite well together,
as I understand.
-Yes.
-Therefore you feel better.
-Yes I feel better.
-Why don't you say it?
-Yes I feel better, mentally I feel good for a while.
-But why when I ask you to say how you are, you don't say it? You are afraid to say it?
-No, still we know each other for 13 months, I 'm a little bit,
I always feel insecurity in relationships.
-Have they found amoebas in your stool?
-What do you mean? Salmonella?
-Not Salmonella, it's something else.
-I don't know.
-Have you been to Africa at all as holiday?
-No.
-To East?
-I was to Mexico one time.
-How long?
-Just one week.
-Then you got something?
-Yes because I had diarrhea.
-And he gave you some medicine.
-Yes.
-When it was this Mexican story?
-I think it's 10 years ago.
-You have not mentioned vegetables? Do you take vegetables?
-Yes. I like it very much but it's better cooked than raw.
-If you eat raw vegetables?
-A distention is a lot but I love vegetables, so I eat them.
-Do you remember how many years is the distention?
-Many years. Aggravation started after that trip to Spain, in 1978, 20 years ago.
I had the diarrhea and I had this salmonella worm.
-And you were treated for that in Spain?
-No.
-How do you know it was salmonella?
-Because when I came back the doctor in Norway...
I had diarrhea there and when I came home after 2 days I had no diarrhea
and after that constipation and a distention very much.
I had been constipated since I was a small child 2-3 years old but the distention...
-Started at 1978.
-Yes, after that comes and goes and I travel many times in the States
and it's always worse the constipation, it's very bad there because of the food.
If I don't take clesma [enema] I can go 14 days.
2 years ago I could alternate, 2-3-4 days constipated and then go one day but not anymore,
not since Pulsatilla. So I had to use clesmatic [enema] after one week.
But if it's a party, not too often, if I take alcohol some days I can go several times.
-Do you take some laxatives to help?
-No.
-So when you say constipation you mean you go every second day?
-No, I don't go. I can go a week without and then ...
-And then what you do?
-Clysmatic.
-You use only water?
-And some herbs that belong to the machine.
-How frequently you had to use this? How many times the month?
-I just use it since last time. Before that I could use after a long time
because I could go after some days and I could go one day several times.
It's just now I started to use it again.
-How frequently?
-Not so many times, I think 4.
-For the past 2 months how many times you used it?
-Not much, 5-6 I'm not sure. If I had a party, if I drink alcohol, I can go.
I can drink alcohol every day, that will function but if I drink alcohol in the weekend
I can go to the toilet the day after. But I thought that was usual for people to do that.
-No, it's not. It's only for you.
In the previous interview you have said that alcohol makes you worse,
is that what you call worse?
-No.
-What is the worse?
-That I had to take very little, otherwise I got very tired in the same evening.
Everybody gets tired the day after, me too but I get tired already after a couple of hours.
It makes me like a jelly. I need very little.
-Before?
-Some years ago I could have a lot more.
-Before Pulsatilla you could drink and have stool or this appeared after?
-This has been for many years, if I drink alcohol...
-If you drink you go.
-Yes but if I drink seldom, once the week, not every day, if I take a cup of glass every day...
-OK, now you drank some wine. The last 2 months you drank 1 or 2 times?
-In the summertime we drink a little wine every day, it's vacations.
-So now you drink every day.
-Not now but in the summer I do that.
-In the summer did you feel the same reaction from alcohol?
-No, if I drink every day it's not the same reaction.
-So you don't feel tired?
-Yes, tiredness yes.
I had to take a little bit. If I take more, I feel very tired.
-And if you take more, you will have a stool now? If you have a party you said,
you will drink some alcohol and then you will have stool, is that correct?
-Yes, so wine with some other little something.
Because we have a party on Saturday and before that I haven't drink something before,
for a couple of weeks and then it  function. It's like coffee.
If I take usual coffee now, I think it will function too.
-Do you drink any coffee in this time?
-No, just decaffeinated.
-Do you have any tendency, any urge to go for stool or no urge?
-For a while before Silica I feel very little urge. After Silica maybe more urge.
So I have urge and I can have a little bit sometimes. Before I'm going in here it was
a little bit because it was anticipation and that has been before too.
If I had anticipation but I think that's usual.
-In your country do you have zucchini?
-I'm not sure about it.
-You don't know zucchini?
Now, what I want to understand, the distention is as big, strong as before
or it is not so strong but every day?
-I think it's nearly the same because before it was 2-3 days it was better and then
it was very, very big sometimes.
And now it's very big sometimes and not so big but it's every day.
Maybe it has been 1 or 2 mornings that I fell notthing because it was always
little beginning in the morning before the evening.
-Your diet is the same as before or you changed your diet?
-No, I don't change, I start eating wheat again, I had a little bit of wheat before too
but I started eating a little bit more.
Because the doctor say they want to take a new sample, a new blood test because
when they did it the last time, that was not sure.
The wheat was on the limit, the wheat flour.
-I don't understand.
-Allergy test.
-Yes they told me to eat more wheat again but it doesn't matter because I was worse
before I eat more wheat and then I stopped it again.
-So it makes no difference.
-No difference.
-Potatoes also make no difference? Milk, did you drink milk?
-I never drink it but I think sometimes because I feel like it but if I take little more,
I feel it's no good.
-What about fruits? Do you take fruits now?
-I take some fruits but it makes distention.
I don't take apple because I know that's the worse but I take grapes, I love them so much
but distention too.
-There is a desire for soft eggs, real desire?
-Yes, I nearly eat them every morning and I have 2 soft boiled eggs, really every morning.
Sometimes I don't do it but I have something else.
-Very well, I see you have lost weight.
-I don't think so. I have no scale.
-From the first time I saw you, you have the same weight you think?
-I think, nearly the same. This summer I put some weight. I know because I feel it.
After Pulsatilla I think I eat more and this summer it was so relaxing and we had
a lot more food in a way than I'm used to, so I eat more.
Maybe I went a little bit down again after Silica but I think I'm nearly the same since May.
-Not May, in the beginning I say.
-I changed very little because I nearly have the same way since I was 16,
maybe 2 kilos up and down. I'm between 53,55, 58 kilos.
You remember in the first interview the psychological state in which was and all this?
Together with a chronic cough. She forgot to say, she says the cough is totally gone.
We just complain. Now the fact is that still she has a digestive problem
but in order to be able to predict or to make a good prognosis we have
to understand the pathology, as I said, and we here we have some kind of a pathology which is,
in a way, persistent and it is localized of course in lower part of the digestive track.
Now what is the problem? Can anybody tell me? Do we have an enterologist,
gastroenterologist in the class?
The symptoms which she has and the aggravation from certain food indicate
a particular pathology, which is in the Mediterranean mostly.
-She told me several times I was so good in China, my stomach problems were so much better
and the cough was gone.
She felt so much better that after this holiday in Tenerife there were problems again
and these problems she told you about in May and you gave her Pulsatilla for this problem.
But the problems came back, the distention was much more worse than before
after this holiday in Tenerife.
-I see. So don't go to Spain. Twice you went to Spain and you got it.
So conclusion, don't go to Spain again.
What I think is that happens here is that there is some kind of a deeper pathology
which is aggravated by a certain situation and now the whole story came out that
she most probably ate some food which upset the digestion and then she started again.
That's interesting.
When the aggravation comes from 2 sources, mostly green vegetables and milk and
there is distention because of such food, there is a possibility of having amoebiasis.
You know what amoeba is? What is the German word?
Amöbe, I got it!
This comes together with some pain. Usually there are little pains
which are going on together with distention, if they eat green stuff, fruits, green stuff
and milk are no good for this type of problem.
This type of problem is a severe and insisting little bugs which they stay into the body
and nobody can get rid of them ever. It can be reduced to a considerable degree with Homeopathy
but you will not really get them out, especially if there are many years of standing there.
And I wonder if she has not been examined ever for this disease. No.
The second possibility which is a syndrome, called malabsorption syndrome,
it is a symptom in which gluten is not tolerated and creates a lot of similar problems,
the ones that she is talking about.
I think the other name is, if I remember well, it is called Coeliace [celiac]  sprue.
The symptoms that she relates and the type of food which aggravate her indicates
either the one or the other.
Both of these conditions are conditions which are quite insistent I would say
and we have to be a little bit patient.
Now unfortunately the situation was aggravated as it appears to be in Spain
and what shall we do?
-It has the distention yet but in almost all cases it goes together with diarrhea
and not with constipation.
The patients are emaciated due to this massive diarrheas that sometimes are like explosions.
-Maybe what happens here is not a typical or a severe case of Coeliace sprue
but this can be quite a severe case, intolerance of gluten.
-The last years they found out that there is constipation too, constipation and tightness,
so it is not right. It's new.
-As far as I remember, there is not so much the syndrome in the diarrhea
but malabsorption syndrome means a general bad condition, it is like eating poison
when you take food which contains gluten.
I don't say it is the mal absorption syndrome, neither I say it is amoebiasis
but what I say is we have to examine these 2 possibilities, in which case we have to be
a little bit patient in waiting to see the effect of the remedy
and not expecting immediate results.
Because both of these cases are cases which are insistent, they are hard to treat.
What she says is when she eats certain food, which she used to eat certain food,
she has this type of stool, which she described several times.
-I didn't get what she said but I will mention something.
I've been to Spain one time 6 weeks and before I go I get the gamma globulin injection.
-Where?
-In Norway.
-Wait a moment, you get the gamma globulin now this summer?
-No, many years ago. I think 12 years ago but for 3 weeks I was so good after gamma globulin,
I was very good. Go to toilet every day, distention, everything was good.
And [doctor's name] she has a machine and some years ago she tested something like amoeba,
I don't remember, I have the paper at home.
-But you have been suffering for years with this problem, so how is that you knew
about the Coeliace sprue? How did you know? Your doctors suspected?
-Coeliace intolerance they suspected but not sure.
-It is not a severe case, if it is a case like that but now we go to the treatment,
what shall we do? Who says wait?
Who says give a remedy? Who says give Lycopodium?
Which remedy, this is the problem.
Those who put up their hands, do you know which remedy?
I want them to tell me which is the remedy.
-We know you know.
-I know?
Who wants to give a remedy and what remedy?
-My understanding, maybe I misunderstood, was that the last remedy she received was Silica
and not Pulsatilla, right?
-Yes correct.
-And I understood, maybe I misunderstood, that she is not feeling well,
she complains every day now.
-She has distention and constipation every day.
-And with China she felt better, she said.
-She felt better all around but she went to holidays and then she got bloated again
and then we prescribed Pulsatilla, for which she described how she felt.
At this moment she feels very well, as far as coughing is concerned, and her mental-emotional state
is quite good.She has a physical complain, which is constipation and also bloatedness.
Is the bloatedness severe? She was not able to confirm that it is severe.
She says it's every day but I did not get the impression it is really severe bloatedness.
-You can't go like that she said. It's terrible. When it's worse it's really worse
and he can't understand why I can bloat so much.
-He is a doctor?
-No he is not a doctor, I try to eat carefully and then this bloatedness in the evening.
I can't have usual trousers, I have to have a jogging and... so it is worse.
-I would like to say that this is severe because when I see her in the evening,
she looks pregnant and this is not what she looks in the morning, so it's much worse in the evening.
-She did not say that.
-No and she is very tender, it's like she can't have any clothes on that is tight, not at all.
She can't stand tight clothes around this bloated abdomen, so I think it's severe.
-And definitely she confirms that in the evening is much worse. What time is the worse time for you,
I want to ask you.
-After 8 maybe, 7-8.
-I like to add something more. I also think that her tiredness is very special.
We can sit and work together and suddenly she can't take it anymore.
She has to lay down, relax a little and in the evening she is very tired but she can stay awake
and this I think it's special.
-What is the remedy?
-I don't know but I know her for a while and I think after the got the China
something else started to happen, very, very positive.
I think that she is-not only in the physical state but also in the mental state-
she is not that confused anymore, she is more clear and the tightness is still there
but something positive happened with her.
And she is much more happy, much more alive and I think we all agree on that and her distention too
was much better and the cough was totally gone and when we spoke with her she was very happy.
And of course this was at the same time that she got this new boyfriend and everything in her life
was getting better, so we don't know exactly if it was the remedy or if it was the situation,
we don't know.
But we experience that the time of the China was a very good time for her.
After this trip to Tenerife she told me on the telephone many times, I don't get well again
after this happening in Tenerife.
-I was better from China before that last boyfriend. I met him after.
I start getting better, we went on vacation together in Cyprus and I started getting better
but I stopped gluten, I stopped eating bread at the same time, as I told you.
I was so good for half a year, very good, nearly every day I would go to the toilet,
no distention, it was perfect.
-Do you have the original case? Can you show the original symptomatology?
Stool bloody, she had bloody stool also. Also sleeplessness. Sadness on waking in the morning,
chill after anger.
-Yes but the bloody stool was not often. But this summer I had it 2 times again.
-No other symptoms. Sweets aggravates, desire for company, desire for traveling, hurry.
Show me what symptoms China was covering. Coughing...
Stool bloody, flatulence... This acute smell you still have it?
-Very little, I can be sensitive very seldom to tobacco smoke but perfumes and strong odors
is much better.
-Do you eat fruits now?
-I try to eat some fruits.
-And it does not give you this intense flatulence that it gave you?
-Not flatulence, never flatulence, only distention. Very seldom flatulence,
maybe when I eat something special that I don't know.
-So actually you don't have flatulence.
-No, sometimes maybe in the evening but not amelioration, very little amelioration.
In the evening if I lay down in bed, maybe a little bit, very seldom.
-Last time we had a keynote of Medorrhinum and I was just wondering what happened on it.
-Sleeping on abdomen?
-No, leaning back for stool, I wonder what happened to that.
-Leaning backwards when she has to pass stool.
-If I had urging, it helps to do that. That's quite strong.
-Show me this rubric. Only Medorrhinum.
You like sour fruits, unripe fruits?
-Very much before, when I was a child I was only eating sour fruits, fruits that
were not ready at all and if I eat an orange, I need to eat 9 more.
-If you started eating.
-So I asked my mother if I could have the whole pack.
-She would never put it all in front of you.
-I just had Medorrhinum once.
-Was any effect?
-It was 10M and after I had very stiff legs, walking upstairs very stiff legs.
I don't remember so much because the homeopath changed the remedy after a month.
-You still sleep on your abdomen?
-Yes.
-And you are better in the sea.
-I'm so tired with Medorrhinum, in the evening but maybe it's the opposite, I don't know.
-She had gonorrhea. When you got the Medorrhinum what year it was?
-I think 5,6 years ago.
-There are 2 possibilities according to me for the new remedies.
The one is Medorrhinum and the other is Lycopodium. My question is shall we repeat China
or shall we go to 1 or the 2 remedies which is Medorrhinum first
or Lycopodium second possibility?
-I intend to ask you but I didn't. Why didn't you give me China higher because I think about it myself.
I wonder but I didn't ask you.
-For me there was no anymore the China sensitivity and irritability
and the whole nervous system which you presented the first time.
If I show you the first interview together with this interview, you will see a tremendous difference
in the presentation.
The one was really the nervous system really in a state of great stress and excitement.
I didn't see this, then most probably you told me there was less desire for sweets and
different other things which are changed, now I can't remember.
-I never had desire for sweets.
-Most probably you did not give me the keynotes of China.
-Loss of fluid.
-Yes but in the first interview you have said that sometimes you had bloody stool.
-I think it was just for some days, maybe it's my English. She said something more,
I said it in there now but she said maybe I didn't say it clear enough. I had to eat quite often.
I have to eat every 4 hours, I prefer to eat after 3 hours but I try to wait 1 more hour.
If I don't eat, I get so tired.
I had done that as long as I can remember and I had to eat regular food,
no cakes, no sweets, real food.
-And very frequently.
-Yes real food, some protein with food the same with my aunt it's like that.
It's always the same, he had to eat regularly but they had not the other trouble I have.
-If I remember you had taken before Lycopodium and you felt good on Lycopodium.
Is that correct?
-Yes I was better but it was definitely that the China took the cough.
I took it by myself the first time.
-As we have said we prescribe a remedy after a remedy.
So the first remedy you should have taken it was China.
Now we are trying to find the second remedy.
The second remedy was Pulsatilla but I do not understand whether Pulsatilla has acted or not.
The way that you describe as if it gave you only an aggravation without amelioration.
-That stayed too long I think.
-So I'm not sure but on the other hand I see your psychological state is quite good.
I don't know whether this is because of Pulsatilla or for what?
Still you had your boyfriend last May, no big change from May until today, I see in your face
there are certain signs.
I will teach you some physiognomy, some signs.
When a person is satisfied and she has this sign, she has the sign of a person
who is finally satisfied and there is no satisfaction, there is an inner peace.
We have to show to see it if you can see it on the video because it is a very little sign on the lids.
The lids become relaxed and they open a little bit more.
I don't know if I can show you this sign on video.
Her lower lids are relaxed and they are more open. Now that for me together with the
quality of the skin, the skin takes a juicy quality, it's not dry. It's very difficult to describe
but this is juicy. Juicy means not dry.
Your organism is better, so your report says I was aggravated by Pulsatilla.
My observation says she is better but anyhow, it doesn't matter.
Now we're dealing with your situation and we decide that you take a dose of Medorrhinum again,
but not too high, just 200, Medorrhinum 200.
Let me ask you one more question.
You remember you had this reaction after the remedy where you lie down inside?
You were present together with her. We two managed to calm her down,
was it after China this reaction?
-The same day.
-You have not seen this reaction and it is interesting that you get some information
where she was really feeling bad psychologically. I would like you to describe
because you were in the same room with me.
-I was there.
-So you will see the reaction and don't get panicky after the reactions of the homeopathic remedy.
She was lying down there and she was in a terrible state and if you lose your heart,
you start giving different remedies to bring her back.
You should describe as dramatic as it was the case.
Don't try to be a Norwegian but rather a Greek describing a Norwegian case.
-Well I can make a try. Just some minutes after she took the remedy, she had this reaction.
Very fast after she took the remedy. She had to go out from the class and I went after
and she was nearly collapsing and she would lie down on the bench in your office
and on her stomach and she started to cry, really cry.
-She couldn't stop.
-She couldn't stop and it was like her body was trembling really.
I don't know the expression in English, shaking, a deep cry like something was coming out.
Sobbing, OK thank you.
And after Roger came I remember and he drove with his car back to the place where we stayed
and after a little while she got much better.
It was like can this happen? She was so bad but after half an hour maybe,
she was much, much better and we could communicate.
-Not half an hour because half an hour I was with her trying to hold her
because it was really coming out from very deep all the grief, I would say all the grief
she had been all the years.
It was coming out in that particular hour, it was 1 hour, 1 and a half hour.
Half an hour after you returned...
-Let's say 2 hours after she took the remedy she was much better again
and then we  went on the beach and she was sleeping on this beach for some hours.
She did not communicate with us, she was lying there, sleeping but it was very cool,
very normal, very good, everything but she felt much better the same evening after China.
Can I add something more?
-Yes.
-We went before China in the mountain in Norway together, just me and her,
we were walking in the mountain.
On this trip she has a reaction, she had something emotional coming up, it was after she had
an accident with her knee but this accident led to that we had to sit down. We had to sit down,
we couldn't walk anymore, we had to relax and I don't know what was happening
but she was very angry, she was very angry with everything that was happening in her life,
before years ago.
I remember she was throwing stones, it was nobody there, just us, so don't misunderstand it
was just fine, it was not a crazy thing to do, it was OK but she was throwing stones
and she was very angry and she told about several things back in her past and I think after China
I haven't seen this anger anymore, it's gone. So something must have happened with China.
-Anyhow what is important is when you give a remedy and you will have this kind of reactions,
to never interfere with that reaction, don't try to stop such reaction.
Don't get panicky because such reactions are always curative and never dangerous,
especially if they concern emotional crisis. We all have kept a lot of emotional traumas.
Different reasons for each one of us and when the remedy hits really deep these traumas
they become conscious.
You become conscious in way, they come up to the memory and you relieve all that.
And this is a very good catharsis, a very good process in clearing up all these dramas
which stayed inside and if you give a remedy at the moment, even if you think there are
dangerous symptoms, don't stop the reaction.
It is absolutely necessary for this to happen.
-How much time is allowed to pass between taking the remedy and such a reaction.
I mean if it happens a couple of minutes after somebody takes the remedy it's clear but
what if such a reaction takes place maybe 2 or 3 weeks after taking the remedy,
is it still OK then?
-Still OK, if the reaction is on an emotional level it is OK because it maybe a slow process
and then you have this outlet which is a big catharsis and the important thing is that after
this crisis the person must feel much better.
Don't confuse it with a hysterical reaction which may happen during the taking of the remedy,
this is different.
If a person has a hysterical reaction after your remedy, it doesn't mean it is a curative
reaction. The curative reaction where you will see that after this crisis,
the person feels much better. Then you say, this was a curative process.
-Does that also counts of the patients afterwards developing a severe depression?
-It depends what? She is suffering with a depression already? You are talking about a case?
You have a case of depression or no depression, you give the remedy and she has depression?
You give the remedy and she has depression and she was not suffering before with depression.
Only in the case that you have personality disorders or you have a case of fixed ideas
or you have a case mentally quite disturbed. You go to depression yes.
Once the mental is more clear and more understanding, then this is a curative reaction.
We have that also in psychiatry. In psychiatry, those experienced in psychiatry afraid
the time that the person feels better in his mental confusion.
When he comes out of the mental confusions many times they are afraid of suicide
because the person goes into depression and the remedies have acted, even the psychotropic drugs
have acted correctly, bringing down the mental confusion into depression.
But they are afraid during that time that the person may commit suicide.
The moment they realize this, they go into depression and they can commit suicide.
-I have to add something to that question.
If it is a patient who had had a depression, maybe 3 years ago and now he receives the remedy
and after 1 week he goes back into that depression, is that still a curative reaction?
-It is a curative reaction in case of a cancer. You have a cancer of uterus, you treat.
And the cancer it is the result of a depression 10 years before, there was a breaking down
of a strong relation and the woman going into depression and from depression
develops cancer of the uterus.
Now you treat cancer of the uterus and she is doing well, she will go back to relive the state
in which she was before.
I went back to Harrison and I read a little bit the syndrome we had been discussing,
the Coeliace sprue for the case of the Norwegian lady and it is true that we can have this condition
without the diarrhea. But in this case what I said, it might be that syndrome.
Why? Because if you remember when she was eating gluten containing foods, she had a reaction
and when she took it out of her diet, she did better.
This is a typical diagnostic about this syndrome. What happens now there is no the diarrhea.
That means it's improving, the syndrome is improving because the diarrhea was before.
She said, if I eat these opposite foods then I will have a stool.
But this case also is interesting from another point of view which I think I have
to point out to you that there were...
In her case it is this kind of things. You have China and there is Pulsatilla
and there is Medorrhinum but you see the Medorrhinum symptoms were from the very beginning.
The Medorrhinum symptoms from the fact that she got gonorrhea etc.
Yet we choose the China as the first prescription. Now what happens is that then what belongs
to the Pulsatilla symptomatology, it remained.
The China symptom went away and the Pulsatilla with the Medorrhinum symptoms remained.
Then you give Pulsatilla, then this layer goes and then the Medorrhinum layer remains
and if you give the Medorrhinum now after China and Pulsatilla,
now most probably the Medorrhinum will act.
Where previously she had taken Medorrhinum and there was only a little aggravation in the feet.
This is the difficulty with this confused case because what is this?
How can you read this? It is confused but still there are guiding symptoms
and the guiding symptoms are the ones that are keynotes for the case.
Also it is interesting what her friend remarked. Why you didn't give a China again?
Why didn't I give? Why I did not consider a China again?
It is better if we make an experiment, so you realize in actual practice what happens.
You have a case, there is an aggravation, then there is an amelioration, then there is starting
a relapse here. What you will do? Wait? You better wait.
It's a complete relapse but what do we mean by complete relapse?
All the symptoms, OK. I will give you an example so you understand what do we mean
when we say relapse because this is the teaching and I presume that you understand the teaching.
Now I will give you an example to realize that here you have to wait,
most probably you have to wait but there are conditions on which you can prescribe.
The same remedy.
What are the conditions? I will give you a case. You write down.
There is a case with asthma which is worse, the asthmatic attack is worse during the night,
without a specific time.
It can be in the beginning of the sleep, it can be later, it can be towards the morning.
What is the remedy?
You see, you say I can't make a decision. Then you continue to ask the patient
and you say do you have some modalities? Yes, when I cough, then I bring up sputum and
coughing up sputum makes the coughing and the asthma better. What is the remedy?
Can anybody tell the remedy?
With these 2 symptoms can you tell the remedy? Can you be sure for the remedy?
-No.
-No, who can prescribe on this? Nobody.
You can tell any remedy Sambucus nigra and Natrum sulph and Kalis, everything.
Then you ask for more modalities and he says that I can not sleep in a position which is flat.
I have to have 3-4 pillows for the night, which is the remedy?
Kali carbonicum, Pulsatilla, Arsenicum... which is the remedy?
You don't know the remedy, correct?
Then you ask further information and she says that the asthma is better in the open air.
What is the remedy?
-Pulsatilla.
-Pulsatilla, are you sure?
-No.
-And then you think of Pulsatilla and then you ask do you feel cold or do you feel hot?
And says my god I'm very cold. What is the remedy?
Who dares say the remedy is going to take a chance, you don't know the remedy yet.
Then you proceed and you ask a bit more information. Are you thirsty? Yes, I'm thirsty.
Are you thirsty for cold or for warm? For big quantities? Big quantities. For cold or warm?
For cold. Thirsty for big quantities for cold, what is the remedy?
-Phosphorus.
-Phosphorus, are you sure? No.
Then you are examining more the case and you say, do you have any fears?
Yes, I'm afraid of dying, fear of death. Which is the remedy?
You don't know the remedy. Then you investigate further and you discover that she is a person
who is very cold really, she covers herself with 3 blankets even in summer but
she says the head is hot, my head is hot, my body is cold but my head is hot.
I need freshair in my head actually where my body is very cold.
What you suspect mostly will be the remedy?
You start suspecting that the remedy is Arsenicum. You say, are you by chance restless?
And the patient says, I'm tremendously restless, I can't stay in one place, I have to get up
and go there and I'm exhausted and still I have to get up and change the place
and go from place to place, what is the remedy?
-Arsenicum.
-You confirm now Arsenicum.
-Better in open air, Arsenicum is not better in open air. It's strong.
-Yes it's strong but this is the case where you have to start with a remedy with these symptoms.
I told you, which remedy you will start, tell me. Which is the remedy with these symptoms so far?
When  the person is very cold but the head is hot, is warm and needs air, fanning,
when there is great thirst, when there is restlessness and exhaustion, when needs to sit up
with 3 pillows, can not go down, which is the remedy?
All these symptoms, fear of death, these symptoms now become symptoms of Arsenicum.
OK, to make it more clear I changed the thirst from cold but in sips.
You have thirst which is frequent in sips, which is the remedy? Arsenicum.
Now you give Arsenicum and this happens, there is an aggravation, there is an amelioration
and after some time it starts a relapse.
Now the persons comes back and he says I started again having dyspnea and coughing, when?
Mostly I started in the early morning hours but also during the night from time to time
I have some dyspnea, I cough, I have some mucus, then I go back.
I'll take several possibilities. The one possibility is, she tells now,
the modalities of the asthma, a little bit different.
She still needs to prop up, she starts needing to put up her head in the night with 3 pillows
where before during this amelioration period, she was sleeping without 3 pillows,
she was sleeping with 1 pillow. Now she starts putting up the pillows again.
Are you going to give the remedy? Are you allowed to give the remedy?
-No.
-You are not allowed to give the remedy. Now you investigate and you say that
how is your coldness in the body?
Coldness in the body starts again where it was quite normal now I start feeling the cold again,
are you going to give the remedy?
-No.
-No. How is your fear of death? Fear of death is gone actually,
are you going to give the remedy?
-No.
-No, do we agree? You must not give the remedy, it's not shall I give or shall I not, you
must not give the remedy at this moment of the investigation and let us say now, you
continue the investigation and you say, what about the thirst?
She says, my thirst was reduced, I did not have to take all the time sips of water but since
15 days I'm starting again taking sips of water, are you going to give the remedy?
Who is going to give the remedy at that stage?
Then you still investigate and you say that what about restlessness?
Since 2 weeks restlessness has started.
Do you remember when you started thinking of Arsenicum?
That moment when you started thinking of Arsenicum till the moment you confirmed Arsenicum
by several keynotes is the crucial points in which we call complete return of the case.
The asthma is not the return of the case. The return of the case, in order to prescribe,
are the keynotes on which you base your prescription.
If the keynotes, on which you based your initial prescriptions, are back even here
you can prescribe the remedy but even here you can not prescribe if the person says,
yes I have sips of water but I don't have the restlessness and then you ask,
did you start having some bloatedness? Oh yes.
What time do you have the bloatedness? In the afternoon, 4,5,6,8.
So therefore under the Arsenicum was Lycopodium and in spite of the fact
you have some keynotes but you don't have all the keynotes.
In the first case, in spite of the fact one keynote is missing, like fear of death is missing,
still there are enough keynotes, can not lie flat one keynote, second keynote thirst
for sips of water, third keynote coldness of the body, fourth keynote restlessness with exhaustion.
You can give it, you can give it even here.
When you don't have a full relapse because the asthma is not so bad, it only comes towards
the morning hours and sometimes comes but the keynotes are back.
The keynotes on which you prescribe, you are allowed to prescribe the remedy here.
But you have to be careful because some keynotes they belong to 2,3,5 or 10 remedies.
So if you are not careful, you are going to repeat the remedy with one keynote,
thirst for sips of water, good OK.
But the coldness is not so much, then there is bloatedness, then the aggravation is
in the afternoon, it has changed the picture and that means you have to prescribe
the second remedy, not the first.
And in her case like in every case which is difficult case, it's a case which is confused,
it's a case when we say difficult case it's from many points of view, it's not only pathology.
A difficult case can become a case of mild symptomatology, I just feel this and that,
let me go to Homeopathy because sometimes I feel tired and I get a little headache
and sometimes this and sometimes that, little symptomatology.
You go there, you can not find the remedy and you start prescribing different remedies. You see?
A change of symptoms only. Not a progress in the case.
So in this case it is important to observe how the Medorrhinum symptoms remained constant,
the underneath symptoms remained constant and there is a time when we will need Medorrhinum
but not yet.
Perhaps now its' the time, we never know unless we see the reaction of the case,
we never know if the remedy we prescribed is correct.
Especially in cases that are confused but I can tell you I have seen cases where they look
absolutely like Natrum muriaticum. You give Nat mur and doesn't act at all.
So even if you think the case is clear, the remedy may not act,
maybe missing something in the case, which if you put it together, like if missing the bloatedness.
You forgot to ask about the bloatedness and the time of aggravation, you miss this
and you prescribe different other remedies instead of Lycopodium.
-In the past I've been told and I think you told this that when you give a remedy and there is
a good reaction, the patient improves but then after a time the patient gets worse again
that this is a good reaction of the first remedy and the first thing that you should do
is to repeat the first remedy.
-This is what I meant. Now I explain because there was a misunderstanding between.
This is what I said. When the case is relapsing, you can give the remedy in case there is
a full relapse.
I call it a full relapse. A full relapse, I explain, it might be that the pathology might be different
but the keynotes on which you prescribed initially are back.
This is what you are interested in order to repeat the remedy, a full relapse I mean
actually the coming back of the keynotes on which you prescribed originally.
But you have to be careful because in headaches, you have to have the experience
to understand what I say.
A case of severe migraines, you have started treatment of she has taken treatment
for the last 20 years, taking drugs etc. she has shifted the original symptoms without even
herself to remember how was originally.
When you start treating and you see at this point there are symptoms of Ignatia, give Ignatia
and the headache?
What happens to the headache? Nothing but the headaches start shifting a little bit and
becoming more clear and eventually the headaches sit on the right side, damping,
bursting headache and says, oh my god, my eyes will come out and say Belladonna now
and then the headaches are affected.
So you give a remedy for the headaches and the headaches do not change but this is the remedy
you have to give first to go deeper into the next layer. You can not avoid that but
if you have given Belladonna, Belladonna has acted very well and then your Belladonna
was decided upon the headache symptoms, then these headache symptoms had to be back
but in Arsenicum case you did not prescribe upon the asthma condition.
You prescribed upon the generalities and upon the peculiarities.
So when we say coming back we mean these symptoms on which originally we based our prescription. Clear?
-I just want to tell you something. When I walked down here the stairs last night,
somebody smoked and that little smoke made me cough. And after that I had so much mucus coming out
all down the way and you remember before I never had mucus.
I had to vomit 2 times, it was terrible, it was disgusting, she goes besides me and...
-She can confirm it.
-And it continued after I came home, I was so tired but I had to go to bed and I take something with me
to spit in it.
I was so tired when I come home, so I must go to bed but after a while, after I laid down it stopped.
But then I start thinking about all things and I got so angry that I want to throw all the furniture out
of the balcony but I could not do that.
-You could not do that? Why not? You pay to buy new furniture and...
-Yes it OK but I think about the other person sitting there out eating and...
So I had to do something else and I woke out to ask for help.
So we talked about so many things and I cried and it goes better.
-How you feel now?
-Very tired, I was very tired before I go down here too and I had the same feeling that in the beginning
after China it started a heavy feeling between the shoulders.
-Heavy feeling between the shoulders.
-Yes it pressed me down and that feeling started again. We saw a movie here and it started again
and I feel very exhausted.
-Very good. Medorrhinum she forgot to say, yes of course she took Medorrhinum that's why she says
how she reacted. She reacted after Medorrhinum, she took Medorrhinum and then
she had all this reaction.
-So tell me what happened again after taking Medorrhinum 200?
-The same evening, very short after, when I go down the stairs here I start coughing and
I get lots of mucus, all the way home, mucus, mucus, I had to vomit 2 times.
-So you went home, you still brought out mucus?
-I still brought out for a while but I was so tired which I had to lay down
and take something with me to spit in it. And then these thoughts are starting from past.
-Some thoughts from the past which made you very angry and you wanted to throw everything
out of the window, correct?
-Yes.
-Then?
-I was not so much better in my distention, not so good, it continued for quite a while
and the constipation too but the knee began hurting.
This right knee I had trouble before and this started again and this has continued very long.
I was really tired after the remedy. I don't sleep much better, I still sleep very little.
For long time I could sleep only 2-3 hours in the night and I think before Christmas
I sent you a fax because I was not better, I was constipated, distention, everything,
I was not very good but you said no other remedy.
In the end of December I went to Thailand on holiday and 2 times after food it was shellfish
I get very sick.
-With diarrhea?
-Yes vomiting, diarrhea very sick, so I had to take Arsenicum.
And I got better very fast, I was just tired for some days but then I eat something again
and a new vomiting and diarrhea started again.
And I took one dose Arsenicum and one dose the other time and one dose now and I got better very fast.
After a day or something I could eat.
It has been several things happened to me because when I come home I was still very constipated
and distended and last year on July I got something.
I had to tell you because I take a sample from the spit and from a year ago I got this
but I didn't take them.
-Spit examination.
-From the sputum examination.
-This an American man.
-And you got Syphilinum and Chlamydiosinum and Ergocinum.  enterobacteria...
-I just start in the first stage in February and I nearly... now and after that very slowly better.
So I'm now a little frustrated because I'm not sure if it's Medorrhinum or this
but I'm very good now.
The last 4-5 weeks I nearly go every day to the toilet, very little distention, here in Alonissos
I have distention 2-3 times very little, very fast went away again but I broke my arm too in March
and my friend had Arnica in her pocket. I take it immediately for 3 days and then Symphytum.
-Why Symphytum, you broke it?
-I broke it here. It was really broken and here too, after 10 days this broke here was very good,
you could hardly see it on the photos. One more thing because I was skiing in February.
it was before this and this knee was nearly good again. It was better but still painful
and then I do ski and I fell and it was so bad, it has been really bad for months before that
and I do nothing but after that the whole night I couldn't sleep.
It was so painful. The next day I think I take Rhus tox.
-And it helped?
-Immediately.
After that I have some pain but it's getting better and better.
It's quite good. So just to confirm all things I have done.
-At this moment which is the biggest problem you would say?
-The biggest problem because my stomach is so good, the biggest problem is that I told you
when I come here.
-Wait a moment. What is the biggest problem at this moment?
It's the problem that you told me in the beginning privately?
-Yes but I can say that before full moon I always am worse on everything, more tired,
difficult to concentrate, clumsy. It's not so much... because this was a big problem.
So if I get rid of this in the mind, it would be perfect. But I will say I 'm also thirsty,
so that's better, I 'm not so hot, I'm less hot. Sometimes I'm quite chilly, after Medorrhinum
sometimes I was quite chilly. I had to put on sweaters, here in Alonissos.
And my sleep is quite good too.
Sometimes when I think about examination or something is a little bad but it's very good
for the last 3-4 weeks.
Before that it was no one day, sleepless.
-Tell me how is at this moment do you have a relationship? Are with a man, the same man?
-Yes, the same man.
-How is your sexual desire?
-I think it's quite normal.
-You are sexual type or you are really romantic type?
-More the romantic type.
-You are not really sexually very interested?
-No, not that interested.
-But you need in order to have sex, you need to have some nice environment and things like that,
more romantic?
-More before, not so much now but yes I like it.
-The irritability in you is normal? Now you are not irritable?
-I'm less irritable but I'm a little bit irritable if things go too slow, I'm impatient.
Still I like things to go fast but not as fast as before, I'm more relaxed, I'm not bored so much,
before I was bored, I had to do something all the time.
-So you enjoy more now things you are doing.
-Yes and be by myself because the man I live with, he works in another place,
so he is away for a couple of weeks and I like that. I think it's OK to be by myself relaxed
but I'm still quite tired in a way in the evening, quite early, it's difficult to study in the evening
because I'm so tired. But I'm a little better and that's the reason I sleep better.
A little bit better on this tiredness in the evening.
-In general how you feel, how you are?
-In general I feel much better.
-You better say it.
-In general I'm much better, I'm very satisfied because the stomach problem has been solved,
it's like a new life when this functions.
-It was quite a severe problem but anyhow thank you We go inside.
No medicine.
-No medicine? OK.