-Tell us what happened after Calcarea. You took Calc. carbonica.
-Yes while we were here in May, about 14 of May.
-What potency?
-10M.
I took it in the afternoon and a few hours later my feet got warmer, more comfortable.
I got a bit tired and a bit irritable, I just wanted to be by myself, do things on my way,
they made worse 3 days later and from then on I got better and better by day.
I had throat pains, stitching pains on swallowing for about a month, slowly decreasing.
After a week of emotional aggravation, I got better and better and I had a great time.
For a month and a half, two months, lots of energy, no problem in the work.
Everything was just easy and good and I felt so good.
Then I spent quite some time by myself, I spent a lot of time by myself
and slowly I felt I had less energy but still when I went to see people
it was OK immediately. I didn't need some time to warm up and feel OK.
-Why did you spend time by yourself?
-Something happened during the vacation and things were not planned.
-Did this upset you?
-It didn't upset me, it brought me down, I got less energy but still I had some days
that I went to see some people and at that time immediately still I felt very good
and I could speak easily, felt very much at ease, it was all right.
Then later on I just felt that my energy dropped in a couple of days.
-Without reason?
-Without reason, I didn't take any coffee, no drugs, nothing.
-No antidoting and no some grief, some upset?
-Not really but being alone for me is really difficult.
It upsets me very badly, even if I look forward to be alone,
that's the way it's been for a long time. That's the way it is.
I felt deep, I felt quite low and it's like my situation was back to where it was.
-It was really back?
-Yes, that's how it feels.
-You know now how important it is to really evaluate the situation? Very critical.
-Since then on, this was in the end of July, then I waited a few days and I sent a fax.
You see other times when I get a remedy, you know I gave you a list of remedies
and the fact is that I got very good responses, I got very good reactions to those remedies
but it just lasted a short while.
Also emotionally-mentally I felt a lot better but then when I repeat it
just doesn't do anything. So I thought the same thing is happening this time.
-So you repeated?
-I didn't do anything.
-So your energy went down or your emotional?
-Both, energy and emotional and then it picked up again a little bit to where it was
before the remedy, I would say. But maybe I am a little more centered, more grounded.
-Self-centered?
-Yes.
Now I have a small cold now, it started on Monday.
Always when I have a cold, I feel more at ease emotionally.
Maybe not the first few days but when it starts coming out, I feel more at ease.
-Now this cold that you have now, it is strong or mild?
-It's mild. I didn't sleep too good last night.
-How is your memory?
-My memory was much better in the first period, now it's about back to where it was.
It's not good, although maybe perhaps is a little better than before the remedy.
That's possible.
-Now if you put your problems into perspective, what would you say
is the most difficult problem for you? What would you complain at this moment?
Let's say we take your case at this moment, what you would complain?
-If you asked me yesterday or the day before, I would say I'm not at ease with people,
I feel uneasy.
-Why? There is a reason or there is an incident that took place?
-Recently you mean or long time ago?
-An incident.
-Not now.
-Feel unease with people, next what you would say?
-The problem to be alone, just to be alone for a few hours even if I decide to be alone,
I look forward to be alone, even so after a few hours being by myself, brings me down.
That's a really big problem and then it takes time when I'm back with people to feel at ease again.
And I want to be around people but I don't want to talk. I just want to be there,
don't ask me any questions and then slowly I feel it's all right
and slowly I can also take part to a discussion.
-You have said that you had a chill at night in bed. It's still the case now?
-Yes absolutely it is. It was better for a while, for 1-2 months but now I'd say
it's back to where it was.
-You had that sadness in the morning on waking, is this still there?
-Not so strong. That is not very strong now.
-Also you had said that in the morning you had aversion to company.
You didn't want anybody in the morning.
-Aversion to talk, especially to several people. I feel I don't have energy to expand.
-How is that aspect now after the remedy?
-I'd say it's not much different.
If there is one person whom I know very well and I feel at ease with, it's no problem.
It's more when there is quite a few people.
-Now you stay by yourself here in a room?
-Yes.
-How is your thirst?
-I'm thirsty.
-For cold water?
-Preferably cold but not ice cold.
-In the morning also you had glue in the eyes.
-Yes, mostly in the night when I wake up.
Sometimes I have to open with my fingers my eyes.
-This symptom is always there or it comes and goes?
-Very often, I'm up every night to go to the bathroom once or twice. It's every second night.
-But it's still there?
-Yes.
-Was a time where you did not have this?
-There have been periods after certain remedies and it could have been OK.
And now when I had a good period in that month and a half, it might not have been there.
I don't recall.
-What about your desire for eggs? Is it still there? Soft boiled eggs?
-I like eggs, it may not be the great desire but I like eggs.
-You had some perspiration in the back, cold perspiration in the back you have said.
-Yes at night. It's not so much now, it's more like cold. Sometimes a little bit clammy,
very cold, I have to have some comforts and clothing.
-Your feet are again cold?
-Yes they are back to where they were, cold and clammy. Definitely very clammy.
-Your fears? Fear of poverty?
-They were gone, now I'm not so very much concerned with it.
-Fear of being observed?
-That fear is still there but it's not being provoked so easily. It's just in situations.
It's very strong when it's there and I felt it a few times.
-So it's less but still there.
-I would say it's changed after the remedy, I don't know.
-You say, it's still there.
-Yes.
-The thirst is while eating still? That still is there.
-Yes absolutely.
-The desire for chocolate?
-That decreased after Calcarea.
I could have chocolate and eat a little bit and it was OK.
But now it's back. I have to have the whole.
-Anxiety about the future was quite strong. How is that?
-It's not really very bad but I don't know. It's not a big problem.
-You remember you had said that there was discoloration of your tongue.
Usually it was grey.
-Yes, that's the same. Usually worse in the morning. Worse when I get a cold.
-Can I see it?
-As soon as my feet get wet, very often my tonsils get red.
-You have something else to add?
-No, you have the faxes I sent you. That's OK.
-But you did not take any other potency, any other remedy?
-No.
-OK very good. Let's go inside and discuss your case.
What shall we do in this case?
I would like to hear who says wait? Who says repeat?
Who says give another remedy?
Do we have new symptoms which have developed after the prescription?
We don't have new symptoms.
Actually all the symptoms are the same except of some mild changes
in some mental symptomatology, which even that is not important.
There is the fact that he said, he had a reaction in the beginning and then he felt better
but for a 10M potency, what he got, he seems to be very short time to have the amelioration.
He says, 2 months amelioration and then I'm back, it is very strange
unless some stress has happened. It seems he is very sensitive to the fact that he is alone.
He likes to be with people. He likes to have company.
If he is alone, his energy goes down and then perhaps this creates a situation
where he feels himself isolated and his energy goes down.
Therefore his remedy is "find some company".
Also what he says, that in every remedy he takes, the reaction is the same,
it's a little bit strange. It can not be possible.
So he has an impression or he doesn't care very much or he is not observant
but it is not possible with every remedy, he has the same reaction.
If he says, with any remedy he has the same reaction, first an aggravation,
then amelioration for a short period of time, then we can be thinking about the placebo effect.
Do we have here a placebo effect? We have to examine that possibility,
if he says with every remedy, I feel better. Do we have here the possibility of placebo?
It is possible except for one little detail. Which is this detail?
-The aggravation?
-The aggravation happened with other remedies?
-Not really.
-With the other remedies you had just the amelioration.
There is another detail which made me think, most probably this is not a placebo,
which is that detail?
-The feet became very warm.
-This is typical, the feet are typically cold with Calcarea carbonica.
The time that you take Calcarea carb. you can not say that the placebo is I feel my feet are warm, no.
The placebo effect is I feel better.
But to say that I have an aggravation but my feet got immediately warm,
it means there is an action of the remedy. If there is an action of the remedy and the
remedy has acted correctly, first aggravation, then amelioration, what is the conclusion?
The conclusion is that the potency of the remedy is not strong enough, is not the correct
and therefore we have to change the potency or to change the repetition of the remedy,
if we don't change the potency.
Also the fact that he took a lot of remedies, if you remember he had a list of 30 remedies
he had taken, high potencies.
Therefore this kind of treatment by having an organism with too many potencies,
we see that the reactions are not as should be expected.
That's why, in such cases, I usually repeat. I did not repeat in his case
but I remember I suggested a higher potency in his case. I suggested 10M or 50M.
-10M and then 50M you said.
-That's it. But you got only 10M because we could not find the 50M. Is that correct?
You see how much a science it is?
I said something is wrong, it's not possible to remember all details in all cases,
as you can understand, but it is definite that I said this case needs to go higher.
Now I gave 10M in this case? I had doubts. And actually I said 10M and 50M
to be sure that he gets a high potency.
So this time you are going to get 50M every day for the rest of your life!
You get 50M. The problem is I don't know if...here I don't have 50M in my medicines.
Otherwise I would have given it to you.
-There is a pharmacy, they can bring it Kostas.
-Yes, there is a pharmacy, they can bring 50M. And you take it for a few days every day.
If you have a reaction, even with the first remedy, you stop.
But if there is no reaction, you continue. You can continue up to 10 days, taking 50M.
-What happened?
-I took 4 intakes of Calcarea 50M. The first morning I woke up in good spirit, it felt just great.
But I kept on taking it another 3 intakes because I wanted to make sure.
Then I got more and more tired and I stopped and then slowly I recovered. It took me a month.
It was a slow, good recovery. It felt very good. And all the autumn, it went fine.
It went better and better.
Then during Christmas I had some difficult days, being with my family, it felt very painful.
I was where I grew up and they were very nice, they wanted to do the best for me
but I felt very alone. It was very difficult.
So I thought I have a real relapse but then after a few days, I have some very good friends there.
I stayed with them and I recovered. But not back to where I was.
I felt I was a little more tense, not the same. Then in January I had a real bad relapse.
That took me about a month to recover.
-Did you repeat the remedy?
-No.
-Why in January, there was a reason?
-I over worked, I wasn't careful. I have to be quite careful eating regularly during the day.
I wasn't careful enough and I pushed myself.
-Did you drink some coffee?
-No.
I got really down and then slowly I recovered again but a little lower, I didn't go back.
-Did you take any marihuana?
-No, nothing.
-No other medication.
-Then two months later, mid March also, it's a kind of a relapse but recovered again quite quickly.
But I noticed that I can not stay so well alone, as I could in the autumn.
I need to be more careful eating regularly. My feet start to perspire again quite heavily
since the beginning of April, clammy feet.
-Cold and perspiring.
-Yes. I still am quite cold at night, in bed.
-Lately you felt more the cold?
-It was better in the autumn but now during the winter it's been more cold.
But it hasn't been back to where it was before.
-Also you had mentioned a chill in bed in the night. That is still coming?
-Yes it's still coming but not so strong.
-The perspiration in bed in the night?
-Occasionally yes, it can happen but not so often.
-Desire for chocolate is still there?
-Yes.
-Desire for eggs?
-Yes, yes definitely.
-Even more than before?
-Not more.
-For soft boiled or hard boiled?
-Soft boiled.
-You had thirst while eating? You still have?
-Yes a lot.
-Only while eating?
-Not only while eating, over all, quite big thirst.
-The water has to be cold?
-Not icy cold, normal.
-What about ice cream?
-I like it very much.
-Your color has changed. You became more red, because of the sun here or what?
-I haven't been in the sun here. I arrived yesterday afternoon.
-You are more red.
-I don't know why.
-How is your timidity?
-It's much better.
It's not really a problem, especially in meetings I have no problems
but lately I've been a little more nervous and timid in some situations.
Not so relaxed, as I used to be but then in important meetings, it's no problem at all.
It's almost that I get too excited about things.
-And communicative?
-Yes.
-I don't remember you are married?
-No.
-And still you are not married?
-No, I'm alone, I'm single for a year and a half.
-You don't know now? You are thinking?
-We'll see. Possible something it's happening now.
-You had a tongue which was coated grey.
-Still coated, particularly in the morning.
-What about vertigo from high places?
-I think it might be better. I haven't try but I feel it might be better.
But I remember leaving here on the plane, just looking down from the plane, I was feeling...
-Nervous.
-Yes but now I think it's better.
I still when I get up at night to go to the toilet, I have to drink cold water
because I feel so dry inside. Just one sip.
-The thirst has increased lastly or you say it's more or less the same?
-I'm more physically active now, so maybe I drink a little more.
-We have to decide whether you take another dose.
-Right.
-What do you think? Should you take a dose?
-I think so.
-You waited a long time?
-I waited a long time.
-It's not usual for you. How many remedies you had taken before?
-I have taken 24 remedies.
-That's all right. Let's go inside.
-Thank you very much. It's been great.
You see on this case that we just saw, only the computer was thinking is Cal. carbonica.
Nobody else, if you remember. We all had doubts about this case.
What shall we do now? Shall we give another dose, yes or no?
-It's a miracle he didn't take one yet.
-Sure. This is interesting also for you to see, many times we have said
that the cure will go like this.
Sometimes will go down but never down like this when it's started.
It will go up and then down and then up again and you have to take into consideration this
and not jump into the picture and prescribe.
You see how difficult it is to judge, when is the time to repeat.
If I put to you the same questions for 1,2,3,4, as I put the previous one,
1 wait, 2 repeat, 3 higher, 4 another, which one of these is for him?
Who says 1? Who says 2? Who says 3?
Who says 4? You better don't raise your hand in 4.
None of these answers is correct for him.
Let's say 5, lower potency. Who is for lower potency?
None of these is correct.
I'll tell you, it's very simple.
-You have to marry!
-Yes, give Calc. carbonica everybody will marry.
In this case what we see, he is doing quite well. He, himself realizes that finally.
He says, I'm starting going down and most of you said, wait.
This is correct wait for the time being. That means we're not absolutely sure at this moment.
At this moment he comes for consultation. His next possibility will be after 6 months.
Shall we let him wait for 6 months or we give him another direction?
The direction for me will be that if he continues really to be going down,
then he can repeat the 50M.
At this moment it is in the border, though the key symptoms are there
and especially what is the key symptom for him to say that we can go ahead and repeat,
what is the one symptom he said?
One symptom he gave us, makes us almost certain that he needs a repetition.
Which is this symptom?
-Clammy feet.
-The clammy feet being typical of Cal. carbonica, when he says
I lately started having clammy feet, then he gives us the right to prescribe.
It is almost certain that he will need the Cal. carbonica.
Also the fact that he still feels the cold, the fact that he perspires in the night.
The fact that he likes the eggs, as much as he used to like, that means that still the
Cal. carbonica layer is there and not only is there and it's coming back.
We'll give him a margin of one month more to wait.
After the month the right answer is, wait here, if still the symptoms are continuing to go down
and you have your clammy feet, then
take a repetition of Cal. carbonica. This is the right answer.
24 remedies you see the problem we all have? We have to find the correct remedy.
-Then take another dose of 50M.
-Did you take?
-Yes, what happened was, I didn't tell you while I was here.
I had a bad hay fever. So it developed and got worse day by day.
So I felt it was going down to my chest.
It was raining and I felt it was going down to my chest and I had cold perspiration
all over the body, I went to bed, I had to get up immediately, I was just all sweat.
So I took the remedy then and immediately I felt like I was warmer in the body and also in my head.
From then, it was Wednesday and by next Sunday the whole thing was gone, more or less.
-Since then what happened?
-Since then I went home, I had one bad dream after 1-2 weeks. This dream was about my mother,
I had the dream that it was me and her and another person between us,
we were looking straight ahead forward and I was just standing there and she was about to leave.
She knew I was there but she didn't want to see me, she just ignored me.
There was a person, I don't remember who it was, we were standing really close to one another
and she was gonna leave for good. I knew it was for good.
The feeling was, I never felt that thing so bad in my life. I can not...
You have to be a child to understand the pain somehow. I woke up and as soon as I woke up,
the pain was gone, I was out of it immediately.
I didn't do anything, I didn't act, I was there. My mother is dead. That's OK.
-Very interesting. Do you realize what is this dream?
-The pain reappearing again I suppose. But being a kind solved or not quite perhaps, I'm not sure.
-Then after that what happened?
-Things were developing slowly, gradually went better and things were doing fine
until the end of July, 24th of July I went for the wedding of my brother
and I was doing a lot of driving and I had a relapse on that time.
I felt depressed and I couldn't get over it.
-You said you were going to the wedding of your brother.
For first time?
-Yes.
-And while you were going you got depressed?
-Not while. During that period of time it was also my vacation and it was a time
where I spent some time alone.
Also there was another thing happening, in this wedding was a woman that I was very fond of
but it was very much my imagination.
I build great things out of little signs.
-So you suddenly realized that this was your own thing and then you just got depressed
and you started going down?
-Yes slowly.
It always happen quite suddenly, in a couple of days I'm down.
Not to where I was, I've never been down to where I was before I started the Calcarea, not close.
But still it's down. But I said I wait, sometimes it comes up by itself.
So I waited a month but it didn't change.
So I repeated in 20th of August, I repeated Calcarea 50M for 2 intakes and it was very good.
-You came out of the depression?
-Yes next day.
I guess I didn't tell before when I get a relapse I immediately feel that
I don't want to see people, I want to hide, I don't want them see how I am
and also I feel so worried that I'll never get back, I'll never get OK.
Always it will be like this. Those two things are so strong.
-Despair of recover and you don't want anybody to see how you feel.
-No, like they can see through me and it's so painful. This is something I had all along.
But I still feel I could defend myself more.
It's not like I am so vulnerable like I used to be but it's still painful.
But then I recovered slowly, I had a headache for some days and it was very good.
In general I feel very good. My life is going very well, I'm very happy with things.
-OK, we are also happy.
-Just one thing I want to say here because while I'm here, studying I just realized
that I can't make a case.
When I'm unable I just think so deep, it can take me 1-2 days to recover
just from not making a case
and I make very haste decisions but then I'm quite sure this must be it
and then I realized it's not.
-And you get disappointed?
-Deeply and I have to be careful not to. My feelings go so much up and down.
I have to protect myself more, if I can and I can most of the time.
This is an interesting dream; can anybody tell me what signifies this dream?
-Maybe I'm getting into dangerous waters but I think it's finally growing up for good
and letting the mother go.
-Letting go. The idea of holding the relationship and holding the attachment to the mother
which was very, very strong, finally on a sub-conscious level he decides to let it go.
That's it what it is.
It is very clear, very interesting and shows how deep the homeopathic remedy will act.
It goes to the sub-conscious mind and releases it.
Another thing also which is interesting, talking about the project of confirming,
in his case you will confirm despair of recovery which we have it in black letters
and also you will confirm this fear of others, they can see how you feel,
if you are a Calcarea carbonica. Your fear that the others will see me.
But what is interesting also is that from a disappointment Calcarea goes into depression.
Depression after disappointment.
And not love disappointment necessarily, any kind of disappointment.
You have to be able to see the progress in a case.
If you can not see, you have a problem and this is very serious
because the moment that you don't understand whether a case has progressed or not,
you are tending to give a remedy untimely.
You did not see the difference between the Pulsatilla?
You saw that also.
What you are saying is when one remedy is indicated, then I can see the difference.
This is what you are saying.
What I say is that you have to be careful because in case we have cases more complicated
belonging to the second or third group, then you will have a problem recognizing the progress.
Then that is very bad because you are going to spoil your case very easily.
-Don't you think since the second relapse already that came after 6 -8 weeks,
don't you think that maybe we should raise the potency?
-I think we should be careful to have better potentization of remedies.
I don't know how much is this due to the not good effective potentisation of the remedy.
We may have a problem on that level when the remedy is not potentized properly.
When we say 50.000 times, can you imagine? A robot will take one month to prepare one remedy.
So if any pharmacy stops after 2.000 times instead of 50.000 times, still you will not be able
to recognize it and that's the problem.
Another problem is the pollution in which we live today.
The pollution in which we live can lead us very easily to relapses.
I'll give you an example.
During the war in Kosovo we saw very frequent relapses of the people
who stayed in the North of Greece.
The Thessaloniki area and the Greek North, the relapses were much more than usual.
So the pollution and what is going on with the expansion of this radiation from the handies,
you see the antennas all over, we are bombarded with radio waves, TV waves, antennas,
we're just sent signals all the time.
How much this is affecting us and how much the body can resist I don't know.
So the relapse is a fact of several factors, not only one.
Not only bad constitution or bad preparation of the remedy.