-Where you will start? I see you've been through a lot.
-Maybe I will start with the physical problems
but then I think the emotional problem is the main problem.
I have dermoi cyst in my right ovary, it's a kind of tumor which is there for a long time.
I know about it for 8 years already and the doctors want to operate it
but I had two children since I know about it and I don't want to operate,
especially not before I finish with the children and I'm pregnant now.
That's one thing that wasn't change by Homeopathy until now.
-What remedies did you have so far?
-When I first got to know for Homeopathy, it was French Homeopathy
and it was in my second pregnancy, I had severe headaches and I got few remedies,
I don't know exactly what. I know that one of them was Sepia and it helped with the headaches.
But then I got a lot of Sepia, every time I had a headache and then I was depressed,
so I got a lot of Platina from the French homeopath and I don't know if this didn't complicate
because I had a lot. I got Apis for the tumor for few months, very low potencies.
-6X?
-About and then 2 years ago I started with classical Homeopathy,
so the first remedy was Stramonium and I got this for the impression of the homeopath
that I was very inside death and she found me in the middle between life and death.
I felt that this did something; I'm not in the same situation that I was before,
I will just tell you the occasions.
When I was 22 I had a boyfriend, we were living together like a couple for 4 years already
and he had cancer in his bones and for 2 years he was very difficult sick
and I was with him all the time. Mainly me, I was with him all over the world with operations.
He died when we were 24 and it was a big trauma for me. Then I got married
and I had children but it was still very much inside me, still now I feel it.
-Did you cry after his death or you kept it inside?
-I think I cried and I was talking about it but it was a drama that I didn't finish with it
because it was like a surprise for me when he died; I was not prepared,
he was sick for so much time and I was in the hospital and everybody was talking about it
and I couldn't realize that, that would happen.
It was a shock and I feel that still I'm trying to understand what it is that somebody is dead.
-You are afraid of death now?
-About myself no.
-About your children?
-Yes, I feel anxious about my children's health.
-Very anxious?
-I think so, yes.
It's like I feel that I'm not sure that life will keep going.
But I don't feel afraid of death myself, I think this is part of my depression
that if I die, I die.
-Tell me except from Stramonium you took something else?
-Yes, afterwards I got twice Sepia, once with 200 and the second with 1000
but I'm not sure about the potency.
-And then after Sepia? Sepia had an effect?
-I don't feel that it had an effect.
-After Sepia?
-That's it.
-You remember receiving Nat. mur.?
-I think that the French gave me Nat. mur. maybe it was one day Sepia, one day Natrum..
-After the death of your friend, did you get any Nat. mur?
-No, I wasn't involved with Homeopathy at all.
-So it was years after when you went to Homeopathy.
Now your physical problem except of the tumor in the cyst...
-I have a kind of allergy, it was very strong, I had it every spring from many things
and I feel it's better, Homeopathy did a bit good with it but it's still going on.
Before I came here I touched some clothe with dust, things that I kept for long time
they make me sneeze a lot and maybe after one hour of sneezing, I feel it like a flu.
All the mucus membranes become inflamed and I feel a bit fever.
-And your nose is running like water?
-Mostly it's blocked but also it's running and I'm always with a tissue in my pocket,
it's always a bit running.
-Like water or mucus?
-More like water but at the same time it's blocked, it's never open completely.
Also I have yeast infection in the vagina, itching.
-With leucorrhea?
-It's not so much coming out but it's inside, white and it tastes sour
and it makes me have problems with the sexual intercourse because it feels pain
and it's not comfortable.
It's not so common but it comes from time to time and mainly it comes
when I'm tensed and also the allergy.
If I'm calm, I can touch things and I won't have it but if I'm tensed
I will have it and also the infection.
I remember having it very strong before I had my first child.
I was trying to get pregnant for 3 years and it didn't go easily,
so the doctors gave me hormones and I had to make sex at certain day.
So I had it all the time because I was under stress.
-During that time did you have discharge, like leucorrhea?
-Not so much.
Only itching and there is white discharge but it's not coming out.
It feels dry but it's not dry.
-When you have sexual intercourse, you feel dryness in the vagina?
-Not always, only when I have stress. I have headaches since I was teenager,
it was very strong and also I told you in the second pregnancy I couldn't do anything
for few days or two weeks and now I have it from time to time
and always at the beginning of the menses.
Sometimes it starts here above the teeth and I feel it like congestion here and it goes up,
above the eyes, especially the right eye and then it covers the head around.
And also at the same time I feel very much tense here.
-And it starts before menses?
-About one day.
When I have the headache, I know tomorrow I'll have it.
-And the headache is so strong that you have to lie down in bed or you function?
-Sometimes I function but I had times in my life that I couldn't function at all
and what aggravates the headache is when I sneeze. If I sneeze, it's so strong...
I have pains in my legs, especially the soles, it feels dry and burning
and when it gets worse, then it goes up to the leg. Of course it was in pregnancy
and during menses.
I wanted to say that I don't have any nausea while I'm pregnant.
I was in the flying dolphin, nothing. That's it about the physical.
-Now what are your real problems?
-There are a few things. I don't know how to start.
-I'll tell you how to start. Was any time where you felt good, normal
or there was no time that you felt that? Age wise.
When you are 10,11, 7,8 was a time that you felt good no problems
and then problems started? Or you can't remember?
-It's hard to say, I don't really remember a very good time.
-You were born where?
-In Jerusalem.
-By Jewish parents?
-Yes.
-You had a hard time?
-No, no.
I think my childhood was OK but I was not happy.
-Why? You wanted to do things that your parents did not allow?
-No, I think I was very serious and I was trying to be good and to do the things
that were accepted and I have this problem now which is one of the problems
that I want to talk about.
I have two children and I feel that I can not be very happy with them,
I can not play with them and I think that maybe I didn't play,
I can not be like a child with them, I can not feel alive...
It makes me very sad.
-That you can not feel joy. What you say is I don't feel joy.
-The joy is coming from outside, from them, from my husband.
When you asked me before when it was good time, I had good times
when I got in love with my husband or friends before. This time was very good.
-That means when you had sexual and emotional relationship,
that moment you were getting some joy and then you were falling back into indifference
or apathy or depression?
-It's not indifference I think.
There is a kind of sadness inside and I feel like the vitality the liveness,
the joy is coming from other people, they can give it to me
and I can not give it to myself and not to others.
-You are crying easily?
-I was crying easily when I was young and last years I'm not crying easily
but if I'm excited like now ...
Very small things, my voice is trembling like crying, it's not real crying.
If I read books for the children and it's emotional.
-Do you get a chock here in the throat like constriction?
-I did have an Ignatia experience. It was not with Homeopathy
but it was very strong much before I get to know Homeopathy.
I don't know exactly what it was, it was the death of my friend or problems with my husband;
at the beginning it was difficult, I was jealous and I started art therapy
and I had an experience like something was here and I had to take it out in visualization
and then I got pregnant. I couldn't get pregnant before.
-After you felt these emotions coming out.
-Yes.
-Do you remember yourself suppressing your emotions when you were a child?
Consciously? That means you liked somebody and there is a friend of yours
who got him and you tried to close your heart, things like that.
-I remember two things. Once I remember I was about 8 years
and I had to go to an operation to take out my tonsils because in my childhood
I had many times tonsillitis.
I remember I was in the hospital and my father was walking outside
and I remember myself worried about him that he is outside worrying about me
and also when I was a teenager, the man who is my husband now we were friends,
in the same neighborhood and I was in love with him and he had other friends
and I had to live with it.
It's not a suppression but I have to live with it and when we were together
and I was older I felt like I won. Something that I couldn't gain when I was a child.
-What year was that? When you were 18 or 19 or 20?
-After the death of my other friend, it was when I was 24-25.
-You told him that you liked him?
-This time no, it just happened.
-But you said then I decided I won him and...
-No, no it just happened. I was so depressed after what happened to me with the death.
It's not that I wanted something, we just came together.
-And then you were crying for the other man and he tried to console you?
-We were trying to console each other.
-Because he lost his girlfriend also.
-Yes.
-What about consolation? Do you like being consoled?
-It's not easy for me when I'm consoled. I think I want the affection,
I think I can not be consoled, it doesn't help. It's like it does the opposite.
I wanted to say another thing.
With my husband I always had the feeling that he may leave me sometime
and it combined with the feeling that I don't have inside something to give.
Generally and with the children at home I feel so not available,
it's not only that I don't play with them but I don't have the patience,
I'm in something else and I'm very much duty conscious, I have to do this...
-You work at the same time or you look after your children only?
-I work yes.
-What is your work?
-Now I work like a teacher. I teach computers and movement.
-Alexander technique?
-No.
And sometimes I'm also angry with them and that makes me feel very guilty
when I'm angry with the children.
I'm angry and I can shout at them and if I have to do something and they are in the middle,
I don't have time for them and I feel very guilty about it, I want to be ...
-Loving and affectionate and you can not.
-It's never enough.
-But tell me your children are with you now or you left them in Israel?
-I left them, it was very difficult.
-The first time you left them?
-No, it's the third time.
-When you leave them do you fell home sick immediately after a day or two?
-This time I feel it very strong, I think it's also because of the pregnancy.
I feel that my place is there now but other times it's very difficult to leave them
and then I'm OK.
I'm here and OK.
-But this time what do you feel in this respect? Strong home sickness?
-No I don't think that it's home sickness.
-It's worrying about?
-Worrying, guilt feelings and worrying if something happens to me or to them
and now I just heard that my child has fever, so I feel anxious.
-How is your memory?
-Very bad.
-What do you forget, can you give us examples?
-Sometimes I forget something that I was about to do.
So I feel that I can not be trusted, I don't feel responsible
because if I have to call... you will tell me call me at 4 and now it's 2
and I will forget to call you at 4, it's gone and I make lists
but I forget to look at the lists and I forget names. It's very difficult
with the students in school, I don't remember names and I completely forget the past,
I don't remember my childhood I don't remember my teenage, I have hints but not...
-Not real live experiences of memory, like you are empty.
-Yes, I feel sometimes maybe its' something that I'm doing to start every time from the beginning.
Because if I get to remember, I don't like myself like it was,
so maybe it's better for me to forget and to be someone else all the time.
-Medically have you checked your blood pressure?
-I checked my blood pressure when I'm pregnant and they say it's OK.
My mother has very high blood pressure, she takes medication.
-You are sighing. Do you know it?
-I know yes, sometimes it's a lot.
-And sometimes you go... as if you don't have enough and you make a noise like this
or it is not with noise.
-It's not with noise, it's to feel.
-But not that you have to do like this.
-No and one thing very important is that I can not decide, it's very strong.
It's not that I can not decide, I don't know what I want.
-Even small things?
-Even small things, in big and in small things. Like I had to decide to come here or not
it was very big, very difficult and I had to decide if to take this sweater or not,
it was very difficult. And when I have to decide, I have to sigh a lot.
In shopping it is so difficult for me.
-Do you eat fruits?
-Yes, I like fruits.
-All kinds of fruits?
-All kinds of fruits.
-You feel you don't have enough energy or you have enough energy?
-Not enough.
-You feel physically tired? Your physical body?
Do you feel that you need a lot of protection from your husband, your parents
or you can manage or you feel I can not, I can not?
-It's both.
I feel that I can not but also I think that there is a big difference in what I feel
and what people see from outside. People think that I'm very strong
and that I don't need protection and I have it also. I know that I can manage, I know it,
I know that I'm talented and that I can do things but inside I feel very low.
-Very weak.
-Yes and sometimes I feel that I'm tight, like I don't have the energy to do things that I want.
It takes so much time to move and to get out and I'm always late.
It's both also that the energy is not working very well to move
and also that I don't have time because all the time I have to do things
and I don't have time to get from one place to another.
I go out of home and the minute that I have to be there and I am in a hurry all the time.
-Do you feel that you are in a constant state like that or you feel ups and downs?
One moment you are very happy, the other .. or you are in a steady state like this?
-Yes steady.
-Mostly how would you describe your inner state? As sadness, as indifference,
apathy, depression, anxiety, fear, guilt, which is the main, if you can...?
-It's very hard to say. I have strong guilt feelings and also I think strong sadness.
-But this sadness is like you don't want to live, you want to die?
-No, it's like something that covers everything.
-Your real emotions are covered by that sadness and nothing can come out.
-Yes. I'm not sure because maybe what covers everything is maybe a depression.
-You have anxiety you said about your children. What about your husband.
Do you have anxiety about your husband also?
-No, mostly is my children.
-Do you have any fears, are you afraid of anything? Dark, thunderstorms, bombs, wars.
-Everybody is afraid of wars. Yes maybe that something very terrible will happen
and that people will suffer a lot and I will have to see it.
Sometimes they have the pictures but in our reality...
-Yes you have that reality.
-But sometimes also when I see in television earthquakes that people suffer so much.
-That makes you what? Anxious or sympathetic?
If somebody is suffering and you look at somebody who has pains and you are sympathetic,
you suffer together or you can face it normally?
-I can face it unless it's a relative, with my children, a relative or someone
that I have to take care about him, then I become very anxious and I'm very much involved
and I want to help and to do.
It's all the time in my mind, like my life stops and I'm into this situation.
If somebody dies, then I have to be with the relatives.
-But then you have feelings or still that sadness, that cover is there or the feelings
then start coming out during that time?
-I think in myself it's all the time.
-When you had this first relationship with the boy, 4 years, you were in love with him?
-Yes.
-So you had emotions?
-Very strong.
-And erotic emotions, sexual and you were in love with him?
-Yes.
-When is the time that these emotions were lost, immediately after his death, after a month,
after 5 months, after 5 years or slowly?
-He was sick for a long time?
-Two years.
We were four years before he had the cancer and then we were two years with the cancer.
So during these two years things happened.
I think that my feelings instead of being like a lover with him,
I became like a mother with him, something like this and my feelings then were complicated already.
-And there you lost your feelings during that period?
-It's hard to say because I think so that it is so but also I remember times
when I was teenager that I had this kind of depression also.
It was not something completely new. It was very strong then.
-But when you met him your feelings opened up and you enjoyed being with him.
You were living in the same house?
-Yes.
-But no children with him.
-No.
-Why? Because he could not have a child?
-We were still young, we were in the army.
-You were protecting yourselves.
-Yes.
-He was faithful to you this first boy?
-I think he was faithful, I'm not sure. I'm very faithful and while he already had the cancer
at this time of course he was faithful but he told me that one girl that he met in the hospital,
she fall in love with him and it was so strange for me that he is sick
and he got involved with things, I'm so much faithful all the time.
-So it was a shock for you?
-No, it wasn't a sock because he didn't love her, he didn't leave me, he told me about it.
-It was not his feeling, it was her feeling.
-But this affected your feelings? You felt jealous?
-No. I think I was already in this stage. It didn't matter so much.
-Did you feel jealous while you were with him? When he was looking at another girl,
he was speaking?
-Yes.
-What you were saying? You were saying something
or you just suppressed this jealousy you said, it's not good to talk about it.
-Mainly I suppressed these feelings. Also now with my husband I have this fear...
-That he may leave you but...
-But we have very good relationship, we love each other but still I have this fear.
I have the jealousy and I won't talk about it unless I feel that I have to talk about it.
-To make sure, you want to clear the ground and to clarify.
-Yes.
-When you talk, you talk very strongly?
-I can talk strongly.
-And then he tells you what? You are crazy, nothing happens.
-What's difficult with my husband is that he is not like this, that he will say it's nothing
and you are crazy, he says this is life, I can not promise you anything,
I don't know what will happen.
-He leaves you in the air as something may happen.
-Yes. He is very anxious as well for me. I don't why but he is.
-Because he has his experience. Can you close your clothes around your neck?
-I can but I don't like it.
-You always want open your neck?
If you have to wear a turtleneck, can you wear it or you have to pull it all the time?
-I don't like it, I will pull it.
-In bed, what side do you sleep?
-On the right side.
-You don't like to sleep on your left side?
-It's much less comfortable.
-And if you turn for a while, then you feel palpitation?
-No.
-Just it doesn't feel comfortable.
-Yes.
-Is there any time happened that while you fall asleep,
during that time you feel your breathing has stopped and you wake up to take some breath?
-No.
-When you wake up in the morning you feel good, relaxed from sleep?
-No, it takes time.
-How much? One hour or five minutes.
-Not five minutes. Two hours maybe.
-Before you are really awake. So you wake up unrefreshed.
-I'm not a morning person, I can not wake very early.
-What is your best time for you?
-It was always the evening and the nights but now with the children, I'm very tired.
I can not enjoy this time but this is a good time for me.
-Is there any time where you feel, because you forget so easily, oh I'm going crazy
I may go crazy and you have the fear I may go crazy?
-No, I don't feel that I will become crazy but I feel that I may become useless,
that I may not succeed.
It's also difficult for me to read for a long time, I become tired.
This feeling makes me feel that I'm not useful.
-You have dreams?
-Yes.
-You remember your dreams?
-Yes sometimes.
The last months I got some dreams. Regularly I don't remember my dreams
but I tried to write them so I saw something that is coming again and again
and it's something like irresponsibility that I forget to go to take my children.
-Or you forget to go to work.
-Or I become very late, I hesitate about something and I forget the time of the flight.
Suddenly I realized that it's coming and I'm not prepared.
-Do you tolerate more easily cold weather? Do you like cold, fresh weather or you like warm weather?
-When I was young I liked warm weather and I suffered from the winter
and now it's too difficult for me to tolerate both and it's also difficult to tolerate heat and warm.
-Do you ever get any flashes of heat?
-I used to have but now not.
-Your menses are regular?
-Yes it is regular.
-And you have any premenstrual syndrome? Any depression, irritability?
-I had very strong, I think about this it did improve by Homeopathy.
Now I have it but not so strong.
I can be more depressed and irritable for two days but it's not very strong.
-If you remember by the time it was too strong, this depression or the situation it was before
would go away by the flow, when the flow started then you felt released
or it kept going on during menses?
-The hard time is before and at the beginning and then it goes away.
-The flow of blood in the beginning is little and then next day is full flow?
-It doesn't take a whole day. In the beginning it's a little but then in a few hours the flow.
-But not that as soon as the flow becomes full, this premenstrual syndrome is going.
-No, when the flow comes, I feel the pains, I'm still not recovering.
I also wanted to say that I feel very not easy with communication with other people.
It's difficult for me to express, to talk, to find what about to talk.
I don't have anything to talk about, also with my children.
-There is no ideas coming.
-No ideas, with the children I'm trying to find stories to tell them and nothing comes in.
And with other people I' m also embarrassed to start talking, I never start talking.
-When you go to bed and try to sleep, sleep comes easily?
-Easily. Sleep is something very easy for me.
-But in the morning you are not rejuvenated.
-No.
-In the afternoon do you sleep?
-I like to sleep in the afternoon.
-When you wake up from the afternoon sleep?
-It takes time.
-Again takes time to recover.
-I'm very tired at noon, I have to sleep even for 5 minutes. Then it takes time to recover.
-In sleep do you see any saliva running?
-Very seldom.
-Your nails are strong?
-Yes.
-You perspire a lot?
-No.
-Do you take normal salt or more?
-I take more salt, I always add salt.
-The salt you add is in any place? You go to a restaurant, they bring you the food,
you take the salt and you put?
-No. I first taste and then.
-Water how much you drink?
-I'm thirsty.
-Cold or room temperature?
-I don't care. Also at night, if I wake up at night, I have to drink water.
And the water helps me with the headache and if I'm very hungry I feel that I have to eat something
or to drink. So I drink water.
-Do you like ice cream?
-Not so much. I don't like sweets.
-You prefer the salty?
-Yes.
-If there is no salt, you will leave the food?
-If I'm very hungry I have to eat it.
-But you don't enjoy it.
-Yes, I don't enjoy it.
-In the sea do you go swimming, you like the sea very much, you feel good in the sea
or you feel tired or more tired near the sea?
-I feel good.
-And you would say, if you have a headache and you go to the sea and swim with the heasache
your headache goes?
-I don't know, I didn't try but it feels good to swim.
I don't take very cold water because if I take very cold water, it makes the headache.
-Can you lie in the sun?
-Not anymore.
-What do you feel? That the sun will give you a headache?
-Yes and I can not tolerate the heat.
-You eat meat or you are vegetarian?
-I eat it but I don't like it so much.
-If the meat has some fat, you like it better to have some fat or you take it out the fat?
-If I take it out is because I know it's not healthy but I can eat it.
-You like it as a taste?
-Yes, maybe to take it with the bread, if it's salty yes.
-Fish you like?
-Now in pregnancy I don't like the smell but I don't care.
-Is any food that you don't like at all?
-No.
-Is any food which makes you sick?
-You eat tomatoes, onions, raw onions in the salad?
-I can eat, no problem. If I drink orange juice, I feel in the abdomen distention.
-Fresh orange juice gives you gas.
-Yes.
-Milk you take?
-We don't take so much milk because of health reasons but I like milk.
Also in your notes put that she got Ignatia 30, she felt no effect from Ignatia 30.
Put it in your notes.
Here, in this case, we have to consider Phosphoric acid, Nat. mur., Ignatia,
Lachesis, Medorrhinum.
-Aurum?
-Baryta carb., show the analysis, Graphites, Sepia, Platina...
In this case the remedy on which we will decide must be an uppermost layer, I would say.
Why?
-Totality of symptoms is not covered by one remedy.
-That's one reason. Another reason?
She said she had sadness before, after, so it was there all the time.
I said with a difference. Big difference. Who can say what is this difference?
-Emotions are the difference. Less emotions now.
-Yes but she said before I used to be also sad. I said yes before but with a difference.
What is the difference?
If you find this, then you find the remedy.
-Before in the past she was getting into relationships and feel close and feel comfortable
within those relationships from an external outside source
and now that she has additional outside sources like husband and children,
she doesn't have the capacity and it's that lack of capacity that prevents her
from being more complete.
-Correct. The sadness was maybe there.
-I could not understand what he said.
-OK, he said before she had sadness but once she had a relationship,
this sadness was breaking down and the feelings were coming up.
Now feelings do not come, in spite of the fact that she has husband, she has children,
where is the joy? She says, I have no joy.
That means there is a sadness but the intensity of the sadness during these times
is much less than this type of sadness. This type of sadness now is deeper
and can not break through joyful things, like having a husband, children, she feels no joy at all.
Before she could break this sadness. She was a sad child yes but she could break this.
Therefore that is one point. The other point on which we are thinking
that this is an upper layer we have to prescribe, what is it? Can anybody tell me?
All the remedies have sadness. In the past she might had a remedy indicated that had sadness.
Now she may have another remedy indicated for that sadness. It doesn't mean that this remedy
has to be right through and I say that the remedy which is indicated now most probably
is a different one that the one which was indicated 10-15 years ago.
In spite of the fact she says, I also had sadness back there. Now the remedy is different.
Why do I say that? Can anybody tell me why do I say that?
-She now can't tolerate the sun and the warmth.
-She used to be a cold person. Now she says I can not tolerate warmth and the sun.
That alone means she has changed because it's a general symptom
and when we have a general symptom, like this, we are thinking of the remedy must have changed
and it has become a warm remedy now and the intolerance of the sun can not stand in heat
and when we do the repertorisation, we take into consideration that factor.
We prefer a remedy that has intolerance to sun together with the other symptoms.
Therefore Sepia may have been indicated in the past, because Sepia is a remedy
which is worse cold but maybe not anymore now. Sepia will not do anything for her now.
So we go to the repertorisation and you see... explain Nat. mur. 21 out of 30.
Irresolution, weakness on memory for proper names, consolation aggravates, sadness,
desire for salt have you put?
-Yes it's here.
-There was a time where the case looked as if she was going towards Lachesis.
The reason for Lachesis was not only the jealousy but also Lachesis
in its state of indifference or sadness, the emotions are killed in the way that she describes
but the sexual area is quite powerful and it remains alive.
So sexually she is alive but she has...
What has happened to her? We start to analyze what has happened to her.
She had this boyfriend whom she loved, she was enjoying and she suddenly felt I'm losing him
and he is gone. She said during that time the emotions changed.
She felt a deep sense of helplessness that in front of facts of life, you are helpless,
you can do nothing and that gave her a protection.
The indifference is a way of protecting the emotional part.
You become indifferent, you close up, you have no feelings and you don't suffer
and Nat. mur. has that strongly the same way that has it in Lachesis, in Phosphoric acid.
Why not Phosp. acid? Desires fruits, Phosp. acid is there, she is tired Phos. acid,
she forgets Phos. acid, she is quite indifferent Phos. acid.
What is that you don't like about Phos. acid?
-The strong desire for salt.
-And also?
-The feeling of guilt.
-Feeling of guilt and also?
-The remaining emotions and the home sickness which she is totally feeling,
that's the character of Phosphoric.
-Yes, Phos. acid. You remember I asked her about home sickness,
she said it's not home sickness, I'm just worrying maybe they are having fever,
it's not real home sickness.
Therefore Phos. acid does not have.
Let's see Phos. acid how many of her symptoms has?
-11 symptoms.
-Ailments from grief, anxiety...
But if in this case we had a strong case of home sickness, that would be a case of Phos. acid.
Now what about the potency? What potency you will chose for this case?
Who wants to speak about the potency? Who would prescribe 200?
Who would prescribe 1M? 10M? 50M? CM?
This is a case for very high potency.
-But the child?
-No problem. The child will be much more healthy. This case is not easy to move
because she has taken a lot of other remedies and it's not easy to move.
So this case let us she was coming to me for first time in Homeopathy,
I would prescribe 50M, CM one dose.
Now I would like to give a lower potency but repeatedly to move this organism.
These cases end up in deep depression.
They are quite serious cases though it doesn't look very serious.
When the memory is dropping so much, the inability to express any emotions is so strong,
she describes ... she is not here.
It can go into deeper things. Therefore I would like to start with 200 and give for a few days
and watch what is happening every day and then if there is a reaction, we stop.
If that does not give any effect, then we go to 10M, just give one dose,
if this does not have an effect we give 50M. With the next possibility
being Lachesis and Phos. acid., Lachesis first.
If this does not work. I will stick with Nat. mur. in different potencies.
Nat. mur. 200, 10M, 50M in case there is no effect.
And in case there is no effect at all, then you go back to Lachesis 200.
-Nat. mur. is a slowly acting remedy. How long would you wait?
-Who told you it's a slow acting? No. It can act immediately in depressions.
There are no slow acting remedies. There are slow acting organisms, not remedies.
-I want once again to ask for Phos. acid.
Is it against Phos. acid that she does not want to be alone?
That she misses her children because Phosp. acid has this tendency to want to be alone.
-It's not against Phos. acid. If she had home sickness that case would be
a Phos. acid case but home sickness had to be strong, because she is tired, no emotions,
memory weak, then you go to Phos. acid, you go to the basics.
She is leaving the children and she is alone.
-Yes, so it suits Phos. acid.
-That's what I said also.
-So why doesn't she get Phos. acid?
-Because her symptoms are not enough, she has symptoms on the other hand
of Nat. mur. much stronger.
-I'm talking about Lachesis, why not Phos. acid before Lachesis.
-Because I think that this is a case of a volcano, she does not really realize
the intensity of her emotions.
I don't want to say more because she is in the class and you are gossiping
and you are going to tell. Leave things like that, it's OK.
We don't have to know everything.
Very strong emotions that are inside. This is not the idea of Phosp. acid.
Of course in a extreme case you can take it but this is not typical Phos. acid.
Phos. acid is dead, is finished, no emotions really. She says no emotions
but I can tell you there are so many emotions that she is afraid of her own emotions herself.
So it is different.
-I realized liveliness while she was talking about this business with the first boy,
having something in the hospital. Then she was very lively, then I thought it must be
a lot of jealousy inside her, was that right?
-Yes, most probably there was and she admits even today she is jealous of her husband.
She says, I'm today jealous so I could see emotions, no emotions, emotions, no emotions.
Phos. acid I have told you, I'm tired, just leave me alone, tired, tired, it cannot give
and she described I have nothing to give, this is Phos. acid but there are stages of that.
One person says, I can not give and is really dead emotionally, the other one says
I can not give because all emotions are covered and she said, my emotions are covered,
I feel my emotions are underneath and there is a kind of cover. This is not typical Phos. acid.
-I think we could see her emotions but she couldn't feel them in a way
because she didn't look emotionless at all to me. There were emotions hidden.
-Yes, if I pushed her a little bit she would break out crying, just a little bit and then she...
But Phos. acid? Phos. acid says I forget words, I didn't feel ...
The problem with the memory of Phos. acid is, it wants to say something,
it wants to say glasses, he looks at the glasses and says.... glasses,
it takes so long to find the word.
I didn't see that. Still the expression on a superficial level it looks like
because she says I have no emotions, I express no emotions, I have nothing to give.
The eyes are lifeless also in Phos. acid.