-Very short after I feel very weak, tired...
-Just a moment what happened? Last time you had what?
-You mean after the remedy.
-You took China 200 and then after that?
-After a quarter, 20 minutes I had a reaction, very strong reaction.
-Can you describe?
-Yes. It's starting in the back and something happened and then I feel very tired,
exhausted and it gets worse and worse like I nearly fell asleep. It was like getting a
drawing sensation, forward that I had to lay on the table and I think I would prefer to go
out but I was afraid if I couldn't walk. So I waited and in the end I tried to go out.
I felt like I was drunk and outside I had to sit down because I don't feel to stand and
after that I came in here.
-After that we pick you up from there and we put you in bed here.
-I feel the same sensation, I lie on my stomach and it feels like I was drawing down
all the time and so heavy feeling that I had to move to get out from here but in a way I couldn't.
-You could not move.
-So weak and so helpless.
-Then what happened?
-I cried in here I think.
-You think, you cried a lot.
-I was like this for 20 min, half an hour, I'm not sure about that.
-At least half an hour you cried there and slowly you started coming back.
-Yes and somebody was driving me back to the hotel and I was very exhausted
the rest of the day.
When I came back home I was very tired, exhausted feeling for a couple of weeks,
3-4 weeks, very little energy, very tired, feel like I don't want to go to work at all.
-Did you sleep all the time?
-No. I don't sleep.
The sleep is not better. I had the same at night time, I wake up the same time
between 3.30 and 4.
Sometimes I could sleep 5 hours but mostly it was 3.5-4 hours and I was very bloated
more than before.
I always have been that for 20 years but it is more.
From the morning a little bit and worse after eating and worse and worse during the day.
Then I go to Cyprus, it was very hot there and I have noticed that before,
in very hot summer my sleep is better. I could sleep in the morning to 11 o'clock,
if I want to and I do that.
-You went there for holidays?
-For 2 weeks and I sleep there.
-What exactly the time was there?
-20th of July and there I can sleep.
-And there you slept quite a lot.
-But at the same time, the same day we went back and I stop eating farinaceous food.
No bread, no potatoes and feel much better, slowly better in the stomach.
-And what did you eat?
-I eat vegetables and I could eat fruits, before I couldn't I was so bloated from it.
But because I don't take the other stuff, I could eat fruit and I eat some meat but meat
and vegetables, fish and vegetables, no rice, potato, bread.
-You avoided farinaceous food.
-Yes but all this time my constipation is no better. I have it from my childhood
and it's thesame, even worse here in Alonissos because always in Alonissos it's better
but not this time.
I always had it from very small.
-But you didn't say after that what happened?
-I drink much less too but if I eat a little bit more heavy I'm more thirsty again.
-During eating?
-After eating because it always is aggravating about eating much and eating heavy.
If I eat very little, very light food, no. The stomach is good but not the constipation.
If I drink alcohol, then I drink a lot. One glass or two glasses of water
and one little sweet I need a whole glass of water and I'm more stiff in my shoulders.
I've been this for many years too, especially the right, on the right side of the neck
and down on the right arm. So I can hardly write, aggravates very much writing
and to carry just a little bottle or something...
-It's painful?
-It's painful and very stiff.
And I have pain on the right knee, I had it before, if I go upstairs I have that for many years.
It's the same but I've always been allergic to metal and for some years, any metal.
-You have been allergic if you touch it?
-Yes I get an eruption very much and I had to avoid it but for some years I noticed
it was a little bit better but now it's worse again.
I noticed because I get a new thing and I put it on, it was very beautiful and I couldn't have it.
It was very much the skin eruption.
In Cyprus I get ulcers in the right side here, I get that for many many years too,
always in the summer but for some years it has been a little bit better, not so much
but it grows faster.
But this time it would not grow and I had to take it, to do something or going into a big part
if it was so terrible and I put Mercury D13.
-You took Mercurius.
-Yes, it didn't help for 2-3 days, nothing and I took 200 and in 2 days it was gone.
But I don't know when, I think it was in the beginning of August but I'm not sure about
something that happened after that but I can't sleep at home too.
That is important I nearly forget it.
After Cyprus I sleep or maybe after Mercurius because I took it in the end of the vacation
or in the beginning coming home, so I sleep very good.
I had noticed that if, sometimes I take a little bread, if I'm in a party and eat a little bit
of farinaceous I notice that I sleep and I wake again in the middle of the night.
-Potatoes you can not take?
-No, I don't think so, I feel that's bad too.
-How is that you did not mention that before?
-I had tried several years to avoid milk products and that helped me.
-No, you have said you have flatulence from milk and flatulence from fruit also.
-Yes but not flatulence but bloated.
-But you did not mention any problems with farinaceous food before.
So you found out after China that you were?
-I've always mistaken it but the tests you take with the doctor didn't show anything wrong
with wheat or something.
-I'm asking you, forget the doctors, before you had problems with farinaceous food
or you don't know?
-I know because all that stuff, pancakes, all that things always aggravating
but I wasn't sure about it, if it was the milk or the farina, the wheat.
Because that kind of food I didn't eat, I can't eat it since I was in the 20,
I couldn't eat that. I like it very much as a child but I try to avoid it.
I'm a little more relaxed, a little more concentrated but I need more relaxing
and more concentrating because it is very bad, really very bad.
I can concentrate for a while and then my thought is completely far away
and I try to get in it again and I miss.
I think I'm too hurry and restless, always have to be occupied, I don't like to sit down,
I can't really relax.
-Any other complains?
-I have not so many fears but I have a little bit of claustrophobia.
For many years I have desire diving but I haven't done it. Before July now in Cyprus, I do it.
I take a course and  the last time you had to dive in caves, very small and I did it.
-So it is better.
-Yes I think it's a little better.
I'm more relaxed in the mountain, always in a mountain and on a boat, in the sea.
And I'm still mostly warm but sometimes could freeze a little bit more and if I exercise
I always perspire very much, lots of perspiring.
-Lots of perspiration with exercise.
-But I get very easily chilly again, if the other in the group want to open the window
because they are perspiring, I get chilly very easily again, I have to put on clothes.
-But you remember a symptom that you have said that you are chilly after anger?
-Yes. But I haven't been angry so I don't know.
-But you did not say anything about your main complain that was cough.
-It's gone.
-It's gone. Why don't you mention it? You think it's ...?
-I think it's the first thing.
-You take it for granted.
-No, it's very, very good.
-You say one good thing also for your follow up, otherwise I was prepared to give you
the wrong medicine.
-Oh no but of course this season now, the autumn, winter is always worse
but it has been a little bit cold here and I haven't cough.
I used to do that, so I think that's very, very much better.
-Also you have said that your stool was bloody sometimes.
-Yes at that time, the last time here it was for some days.
-You never had it again?
-No, it has gone away.
-But you forgot to mention this also. It was not important.
-I have a little about bit. I got a little lump air induration here, I had it the last time too.
-But what has to do with the blood in stool, do you think it comes from that?
-No, I have no blood in stool.
-You sleep is good? Just give me an idea. You go to bed, you fall asleep and
you wake up in the morning, you don't wake up in between at all?
-Sometimes very seldom.
-And when you wake up in the morning you feel refreshed from sleep?
It's good that you have slept.
-If I have slept 8 hours, I feel refreshed.
-Your energy is good, you are happy with your energy that you have now or you want more energy?
-In the evening I can't do mental work at all, mentally no energy.
-Which is the worse hours for you?
-I don't have time to feel so much during the day time, if I sit in course here
I feel tired about.
No, I think it's about 2 o'clock but I'm not in course here, so I didn't notice so much.
I'm on the beach here and at home when I work but in the evening it comes when I sit
down. After 9 when I sit down, then...
-OK, also you had said that in the morning on waking you had a kind of depression.
-Yes I had very much depression.
-Now?
-No.
If very seldom I wake on 3 or 4 I can have a little thing but it's very little.
So that's very much better and quite energy physical, I exercise more than the last time.
-Do you still like sweets?
-I didn't like sweets.
-You had aggravation from sweets?
-Yes.
-You still say you have aggravation from sweets?
-Yes I have.
-And also from warm covering of the head you had aggravation. Do you still have that?
-I think it's a little bit better but I still don't want.
I bought a cabriolet this June because I want my head not warm.
I want fresh air for the head but I think it's a little bit better maybe, I'm not sure.
Warm cars is terrible.
-Do you have any salivation during sleep?
-No.
-OK, let's go inside.
I want to say about the follow up that you have to be careful because many times
I have made mistakes because you don't go thoroughly through the case or you don't remember
what was the problem and the patient comes and has several complains,
which he gives you the complains and then you tend to give a prescription for the complains
and then the confusion starts.
This could be exactly that type of case where they don't give the overall picture,
they don't know what is going on where lots of others symptoms are going on
and you don't know really what the remedy has done.
Anyhow we clarified that, that is one thing. The second thing, I took care of the reaction
which she had. It was one of the most quick and most dramatic reactions from a remedy of 200
where she was really collapsing, from one moment to the other. She took the remedy
and then we put her on the table and then she was crying and crying,
I didn't know why of course.
This was a quick reaction, I said OK very good, things are doing well.
When you see this reaction always the remedy is going to act, there is no way.
Unless of course it is a hysterical reaction, which is different.
Maybe a hysteria is coming because they also may be crying and acting in a hysteric way
but she is down to earth actually too much.
She was even coming more down with the remedy.
She is not the hysteric one and the reaction it was quick and quite strong and I said OK,
that's going to be very good.
Coming out to the situation, what shall we do at this moment?
She has a sensitivity towards the farinaceous food, she says.
Before, what happened with the Mercury?
I don't like it because the general idea is one is starting breaking out, you will be surprised
how much relief can bring out a blister. I have seen terrible headache, chronic headache
being relieved with Dulcamara when Dulcamara brought a herpes on the lips.
For years, she took Dulcamara, in a few days the lips were full of herpes, which they broke up
and she was a woman, she was quite good looking and she did not like this idea and of course
I would not do anything. She says, do something about that, I don't like it and I say, I like it.
She says, I don't like it, OK I can not do anything.
She went to the pharmacy and put some cream there. As soon as it has gone,
the headache was back.
I said, OK now you want it? Yes I want it. Take again the remedy, it broke out again.
So you don't want suppressed these things and if you suppress them even
with homeopathic remedy, this is even worse.
You have to be lucky not to spoil the case. The patient may tell you, I have to go to a party,
you say this is what I can do.
This is the law, I can't break the law because you have to go to a party, you break the law
and you break it yourself. You go to the pharmacy, put whatever you like and then it's gone
and then OK. But I will not do it.
The fact that she sleeps is not because she went to Cyprus.
It's because the remedy started acting and she was sleeping normally.
Simply Mercury did not spoil the case and she would start again not sleeping,
which would be unfortunate.
Therefore now at this moment, she gives certain symptoms which produce the picture of a remedy,
yes or no?
The symptoms she gives at the moment is flatulence from farinaceous food.
We look at this and we see 6 remedies there.
We see this is still a point where it will take a little bit more time before it is corrected.
So it may take to correct this point, to digest better farinaceous food, it may take let us
say another year, it doesn't matter.
The moment that you see she is better all around, you don't give Mercury or Natrum Carbonicum
because she had... she has aggravation from milk, flatulence and I can not imagine,
I'm going to find this rubric, perhaps I'm going in my Repertory and I'll find it.
I can not imagine this is not here.
I have to find it, I go especially for that in the interval.
So no remedy, she has to continue not to take any remedy and not to take any coffee of course.
-A year ago you got China, what potency?
-C200.
-And you had a big reaction.
-And I was very exhausted after for a long time, very tired and the cough much better.
But now it's better to talk about now. The cough is very good, it's not there.
A few times just by cigarette smoke but nothing, so it's another problem that I have,
I told you about before, that's my stomach.
-Your stomach.
-Very much bloatedness and constipation.
Constipation started when I was a child but the bloatedness started 20 years ago, I was 27,
after a holiday in Spain.
In some samples they found salmonella, the other 6 was OK but after that it started and
I was in a school situation at that time and from 10 o'clock every day I couldn't
lock my trousers I had them open. I had to wear sweater and it was for months and months.
Sometimes it's better, if I try some diet and that goes on for many years.
But last summer I mistake gluten, I'm allergic to gluten, it's in wheat, in flour.
So I avoided and nearly stopped. I got is sometimes in restaurant and I get very good.
I was so good and so happy, I thought I would continue.
I thought I found a solution in a way and one month ago I get the test and they said,
I'm allergic to gluten.
But before that I was in Tenerife in March and I seek for some food, I eat some sea food
and I get sick and vomiting and I get it sometimes before I go on holiday too.
I eat some snails and after a while I was not good, so I stopped eating but I get very sick.
After that it started again, bloatedness every day. A little bit from morning,
worse and worse during the day and in the evening very, very big.
And the constipation for several days and then may be one day I can go several times,
it gets softening, the stool. If I go several times one day.
I'm constipated for many days and then I can go for one day.
-You mean 3-4 days no stool, then you go for stool, then it's better the day after?
-Yes 1-2 days and then it starts again.
-What about the gluten? You said you avoided the gluten but you avoided and you still
avoid? So why you attribute the better in the avoiding of the gluten, I don't understand.
-I was very good but after the holiday in March it started again but I'm still avoid gluten.
-So you didn't change this, you don't take gluten now.
-No.
-And the constipation is the same as before? The same type?
-Yes the same. It can change a little bit but many years ago I was constipated
for 1 or 2 weeks but I try to take something for it and not school medicines, but from herbs.
-Now you don't take herbs?
-No.
-Before you took laxatives herbs but after China you stopped taking herbs
or after a few months after China? When did you stop taking herbs?
-From last summer when I stopped gluten.
-From last summer you did not take anymore herbs and you had some bloody stool.
Now still you have?
-No, it was just some days, it was nothing special.
-What about sleeplessness.
-I sleep very good, after last summer I went away from gluten, I sleep every night 8 hours.
-Gluten again.
-I tried to take after this vacation because I was so bad and feel it  was some bacteria
I tried to take Arsenicum C200, do nothing and then I wait for 6 days
and I try to take China C200 again, do nothing.
-What else you took?
-Nothing else.
-Do you still take sweets?
-I need a little bit after meal, more than before.
-Do you have an aggravation?
-Yes, so I try to avoid it.
-What kind of aggravation?
-I feel without energy and then very tired.
And the same with alcohol, in very short time I get tired.
-When you wake up in the morning, you feel good?
-No, I feel tired.
I can sleep 8 hours but I feel still tired, not refreshed.
Sometimes but mostly not refreshed and I get very tired if I study.
We have a group in Norway, we study together, the other can go for hours and hours but
I'm exhausted after a few hours, really exhausted, I have to lie down, I can't think,
I'm very tired and in the evening I'm very tired, after 8 o'clock, 8.30 so tired that
I can go to bed.
-Which is the worst time for you?
-It can be in the middle of the day too but if you work you can't notice it like that
but in the evening when I sit down.
-What time is this?
-Usually before 8 I do something always exercise or work. After 8.
-You have mentioned a symptom that if you get angry you have a chill.
-Yes that's true.
-It's still there?
-It's still there.
But I think I put a little more clothes now because I'm nearly warm.
-Are you very angry? Are you irritable?
-No, I think I was much more before Tuberculinum. I think Tuberculinum took away
some of it but I can be more impatient, if things are very slowly. I'm quite hurry.
I have energy if I exercise, if I work, move, I have energy very much and I'm always warm,
I want to do lots of several things, skiing, roll blade, everything, I want to do things.
So sometimes I avoid studying because I always get tired on studing.
-You do too much?
-Yes better physical things.
-Are you still in a hurry inside you?
-It's better.
I think China has to do a lot with that, so I'm very glad of that, besides the cough
I'm very glad of that.
-So psychologically you feel better?
-In what respect? Can you describe how it was before, what is now?
How is the difference?
-I didn't think so much about what the others said and mean about me.
I'm more organized and not that hurried. I can be more by myself, I like it,
so for many days it's OK, I feel I need it because I'm so tired, I'm exhausted,
I feel I need it. I feel I need a year free from work and everything
because I feel so exhausted in a way. I feel to dosomething else.
-You like really to be by yourself now?
-Not by myself all the time, I want love in my life but I will try to go away to another
country and do something else. I'm planning for it, so we will see.
-Energy you have more than before, now?
-No.
-Same or less?
-I think I have less energy the whole of me because I always do things but now
I can't do so much anymore and I have to sit down or lie down. But just for a short time.
-I don't remember, are you married?
-No.
-You are divorced?
-No, the first time I lived together with a man I quit it. I'm not married.
-You were living with a man. What do you mean the first time? The first time you came here?
-No, it was ended before I come here. I told you about it. He was much younger than me
and I told you a little bit about that.
-But before you had not been married?
-Yes, two times.
-And then you had an affair that it broke out when you came here and after this
you have some new?
-I had been alone until this summer, so I have...
-This summer you mean the previous.
-Yes.
-Then since that summer you have somebody that you are together.
-Yes we are together, I sell my house in December because I didn't want to own anything more,
so I wonder what shall I do, so I looked at apartments and think what shall I do
but I didn't want to do anything but I couldn't live in the street.
So in the end this boyfriend, he said to me why can't you live in my house, I travel so much,
you can be by yourself for a long time, so you can live, you don't need to press the situation
to buy something. And that is the situation now.
I feel very good in this house because I'm born in this area and I love the area
and I feel comfortable, he is very kind, he spoiled me but in a way I feel that I had to
do something before I decide what to do.
I live there but it's not the meaning that I should live there for ever,
it's a temporary situation until I decide what to do.
-How is your sexual desire?
-I think it's normal, 2-3 times the week, in vacation maybe more, free time.
-It's OK. Do you have any leucorrhea?
-No. I had when I was 14,15 very much but not now.
-When you were young did you have a sexual desire or the desire came much later?
-No I don't think the sexual desire was so much more but I feel more kissing
and other stuff, yes always.
-Always it was like this or afterwards?
-Yes always it was like this but not so sexual desire.
-When did you have your fist boyfriend?
-The first, if you call it a boyfriend, it could be 11, that's kids.
-I don't mean this, I mean when you had complete sex.
-The first time I was 14 and I didn't want it.
-You didn't like it.
-No, I didn't like it, I didn't want it but he was a little bit too strong for me,
he was much older than me and ...
-When it was the first time that you enjoyed sex, what age?
-27 I think. I really enjoyed it and relaxed in a way.
-As a young girl you were interested very much in boys going out or not really?
-Yes, I was going out quite much but I had very much to do because my mother was sick
and she died when I was 15.I had to do the house, it was my father and me.
I work in the shop, I go to school, so I had not so much time but I was a lot of time out.
I like to be out yes.
-Did you like to dance?
-I like very much to dance, I love to dance, everything and very much quiet music,
all kind of music.
-Do you remember when this leucorrhea stopped, at what age?
Did you take some medicine to stop the leucorrhea?
-Yes I will tell you because when I was 14 in this first intercourse, he was a sea man.
He gave me the gonorrhea, I think after that and I had a bladder infection 5 times after
that in very short intervals and I got antibiotics all these times.
That was in very short time.
-You took antibiotics a lot?
-Penicillin and some antibiotics.
I'm allergic to penicillin. I noticed when I was 27.
-What about the flatulence from milk, you have said if you drink milk it's much.
-Not flatulence, it's bloatedness.
-Also from fruit is still there?
-Yes because I think it's a cross allergic. I'm with hay fever, allergic to most grass and
things, so I can't eat pears, apples, peach.
-What it does to you?
-It gives me bloatedness, always bloatedness.
-Without gas?
-Very little coming out, it stays there and I can't eat potatoes I have notices, too.
Farinaceous food and potatoes too. I got very thirsty from sweets and very thirsty from alcohol.
One glass of wine, I have to have two glasses of water and one little chocolate bite
I need a glass or two of water.
-The pork you say also it gives you some aggravation?
-Yes some aggravation and fat.
-You still like spicy things?
-Yes I like spicy, I like very much shrimps with garlic and chili, that's very good.
In a way if I'm bloated I feel for something strong, alcohol too, bitter.
Because I feel it does something to relax in a way.
-The smell of food you like or it gives you some nausea?
-No. Smell of pork maybe, I don't like.
Because one time when I was 16 I ate so much of this crispy in Christmas evening that
I vomit the whole night and after that I can't stand it and I feel it's swelling fingers.
-With pork is this?
In the night when you wake up you still feel bloated?
-Not in the night but in the morning I'm bloated.
-When you wake up?
-Yes, sometimes very little, sometimes a little more and it gets worse and worse during the day,
so in the evening it's very much sometimes. It looks like I'm pregnant.
-Which is the worse hour about 5-6 o'clock in the afternoon or 8 o'clock or you can not say?
-No, it's goes on, I get worse and worse. Most in the evening and if it's very bad I had
some nausea too and some heaviness in head, not pain but heaviness that I feel it goes together
with the bloated stomach.
-Do you still have your menses?
-No, it's one and a half year since the last one. But I have no trouble.
It's the same as before, less trouble, not the pre-menstrual.
-When you come here to Alonissos this time do you swim in the sea?
-Yes, I love to swim. I swim in Norway 2 weeks ago and it was 8 degrees, so here...
-You like swimming and do you feel good?
-Very good, I love to be in the sea on a boat. I love to be in the sea from most time.
-Do you like oranges?
-I like them but I don't eat them because they are bad for the kidneys.
-For the kidneys?
-Yes.
-Why?
-They damage them.
It's very difficult to clean the orange out of the kidneys, I have learned that.
-When?
-I learn reflex therapy under the feet. But I love them, when I was a small kid
if I get one orange I wanted 7-8 more.
-You desire.
-Yes, very big desire.
-Yes.
-But now you don't take them at all.
-Yes because I know they are not healthy for me.
They said don't take anything but I can take some lemon sometimes and eat lemon directly.
-Eat pure lemon?
-Yes.
-In the sea if you are, let us say swimming all day, will you avoid the bloatedness, you
don't feel the bloatedness?
-I don't know but I think I feel a little better if I'm much in the sea.
I feel it with the whole me, the skin and everything, that is most good.
-Have you ever taken Sepia?
-Yes, I think a homeopath in Norway gave me one dose but it did not do nothing.
-It did not disturb.
-No, because I see my journal I go and pick it up from his office to see what he gave me
and I saw the Sepia one time, what he wrote, do nothing and then I was on Tuberculinum
again I think. It's many years ago.
-Medorrhinum you took?
-Yes and maybe it worked for very short time because he changed it and I think it was right
but I get some heavy legs from it. If I walk upstairs I feel that my legs of wood.
So I'm not really sure about what happens with this Medorrhinum.
-In general you say you are hot person?
-Yes, in general I'm hot.
I can be very sensitive to changes sometimes easily cold but I easily get warm again.
-Do you need fresh air all the time?
-Yes always, I told you I bought a car without a roof.
-You also took Pulsatilla before?
-Yes, many times.
-And it did not do anything for you?
-I'm not sure, yes the first time it did very much and I think I told you before
it was my first remedy.
It helped me for one year for the stomach. I was good for one year after this remedy.
I think it was 17,18 years ago.
I hate warm room, I need fresh air and in the cars I open windows but I have this strange thing,
if I come in a very, very warm room or warm bath I can have gooseflesh and then it's over again.
It's strange because I don't like this heat.
And I noticed when I have stool very often I have to lean back.
-To pass the stool?
-Yes to pass the stool.
-You sleep on what position?
-Stomach always.
-This last year you have been crying or you didn't cry very much.
-Not so much.
But I can easily cry in a way. That was better than before. I was crying very easily before
but if I argue with somebody, especially boyfriend I can cry, yes.
And if somebody goes deep in talking to me about me, I cry.
-You like consolation?
-Yes.
-You have said that warm covering of head made you worse. It's still there?
-Oh yes.
-Very much?
-Yes.
What your computers have made?
-Medorrhinum, Pulsatilla, Sepia.
-I see that the class is divided into 3 groups. The one is the Pulsatilla group,
the other is the Sepia group and the other is the Medorrhinum group.
Some of the questions, as you understood, referred to the underline layer when I hear
I had a lot of leucorrhea as a child, immediately brings the mind to the idea of Sepia.
Then Sepia investigation concerning sex and then it came out this experience
which was not very good, so either she is Sepia and she can not enjoy until
she goes out of Sepia.
That's why she stays long time or because of the bad experience itself,
it may not been able to enjoy but the infection also complicated matters.
So it's not a simple matter of Sepia layer and then the idea of Medorrhinum of course came up
and she confirms, she actually by saying as a child I like very much eating the oranges,
you may most probably think that the layer with which she came, the first layer was Medorrhinum.
And then due to antibiotics, penicillin etc. the organism changed and other layers were added.
Until we reached the layer of China and China brought about a change of course which
is quite substantial, like the cough, which was the recent problem together
with the correction of the sleeplessness. The sleeplessness was quite strong and went away.
It took away some other symptoms as well, as she described, and now the question is
since China has acted quite well and China has this bloatedness very much,
China is one of the most bloated remedies. The most bloated remedies
are the first one is Colchicum.
In intensity of bloatedness without being able to bring out this is Colchicum.
Then the second one still is not Lycopodium, it is China and the third one
is Argentum nitricum and then is Lycopodium and Carbo vegetabilis.
The Colchicum is the highest, very bloated without being able to bring out any gas.
Is this case of Colchicum, of China or what is the case and we have to decide whether
we shall give China again or we shall give Pulsatilla, Sepia or Medorrhinum or even Lycopodium.
-She said already that she repeated China and it didn't work.
The last few months she took Arsenicum and then she took China and it didn't work.
-But maybe in a higher potency.
She took Medorrhinum, she took Pulsatilla, she took Sepia, she took the remedies and
yet she was in that state in what she found, why? Do you know why?
Because she did not follow the right order of remedies. There was an order of remedies.
The uppermost is, let us say, Pulsatilla. The second is Tuberculinum, the third is Lycopodium
the fourth is whatever.
If you don't follow in a case the right order, you see this kind of mess.
You remember when we saw originally the case it was not clear at all, what was the remedy.
Now it's becoming clear, the remedy is more clear.
What is this clear remedy after all this analysis? This is good for examination paper.
You have to put together. First things, first. There is a possibility for Medorrhinum
because she says so much she likes the sea.
She sleeps on the abdomen, she doesn't orange or you don't know whether she likes
or doesn't like but anyhow there are some arguments and you can say
the possibility of Medorrhinum is there.
The question you have to ask is the time of Medorrhinum has arrived?
It may arrive but it is now or we have a better choice than Medorrhinum
and what is the better choice?
If this is a Sepia choice, a Sepia choice for this moment you have to hear not only
I like dancing, this is not enough.
You have to hear that, OK forget the leucorrhea, but at least you have to hear
that you have the libido very much down.
You don't hear that. On the other hand Sepia is a cold remedy.
She is warm, ameliorated in the cold air, she goes and baths at 8 degrees.
I don't know how many they will bath at 8 degrees.
So if your computers have said either first, second, third, fourth... the mind should say
if this person is still aggravated by pork, if the pork aggravates,
if aversion to fat is still there after China, if the heat aggravates this person,
if the open air ameliorates, she said it very strongly.
You know these remedies and you battle with these remedies like you know they are bloated remedies
and you forget that if you go and see distention in the abdomen, you will have 325 remedies,
it's not only these 5, it's another 320 remedies, between them it's also Pulsatilla.
Do you like consolation, oh yes you hear how she said consolation.
Oh yes I like consolation. So the case for me and for you also is clear. It's becoming clear.
The idea is as you go along, year after year, you have your patient getting better and better.
The idea is not back, forth, back, forth. So here she has said I was given Pulsatilla
and I was not cured but I believe you have a different idea of what cure is today than
the idea you had when you started this course.
When you started this course you had the idea that somebody takes a remedy and he is cured.
This is not the majority, this is the minority. This is a small minority,
very small minority today I will say, that will just take one remedy and everything will be going.
So in most of the cases today you need to find the "mitos of Ariadne",
how it is called from the Minotaur.
-Did I understand right that you said she has constipation which is only ameliorated
by leaning backwards?
-Yes, that's another for Medorrhinum.
-It's only Medorrhinum and it's very peculiar symptom.
-That is correct, I forgot to mention this. If you look there, she has amelioration in the sea
and she has also this leaning back ameliorates.
-I don't quite understand, do you think she changed so much also on mental-emotional level?
You think of Pulsatilla because of the food modalities and so on?
Because the sleeplessness went away which I think it's very important symptom.
I thought China has done so good that I would have tried to give it higher first
and then to look if it goes to Pulsatilla.
-China is a rather cold remedy, that's the first one.
The second is that certain symptoms on which China was prescribed are not there anymore.
On the other hand the uppermost symptoms of the present situation, which they come out quite clearly,
are Pulsatilla symptoms. And most probably you will see that Pulsatilla will take away
quite a lot of this bloatedness, will give more energy, will have more strong
and underneath that most probably your Medorrhinum will be popping up.
In what way we are still to see.
The symptomatology was mixed in the beginning, very mixed from different remedies and
now it's becoming more clear. It's becoming between Pulsatilla and Medorrhinum.
Pulsatilla is more prominent because of the general condition, general symptoms and
also the fact that she says, when I first took it, the bloatedness went away.
So that means in her case the bloatedness is covered by Pulsatilla. It's a Pulsatilla bloatedness
and not a bloatedness of Colchicum, China or Argentum nitricum.
-Which potency?
-Which potency you like to give? Let me see. 30, 200, 1M, 10M, 50M.
-OK give 50M. No, she doesn't need 50M. 1M or 10M is good enough. 10M.
You will eventually get this feeling for the potency, it's not so tangible. It is intangible.
It is an intangible in the homeopathic prescribing, we can not put rules,
very concrete rules, we can not.
Why I said to the child, Veratrum 50M and we couldn't get it here anywhere
but I needed Veratrum 50M.
It is the experience to see the depth etc.
I think even 1M will be good enough, even 200 will act but maybe we miss time,
30 willstill act but we miss time because we may need to repeat more frequently
and where can we find her. So take a big sigh and continue the effort. What can you do?