-Feedback.
-You wanted me to tell you what happened after the Sulphur?
-Yes.
-After the Sulphur I had this pain and you gave me the Latrodectus Mactans.
Actually after the Sulphur the same evening I felt euphoria, I felt good and I had loquacity.
I didn't stop, Alexander she had to suffer because I was talking to her and next day
I still was in a good mood and only at 10 o'clock the pain started and went worse and worse.
Then in the evening you gave me the Latrodectus Mactans which gave me a hot flash in the face
immediately and the pain started going down.
Then it started with taking ECG and the blood pressure
and suddenly everybody put me in the corner of the sick people and I did not like that.
-You did not like it? Everybody knows that also. Tell us what happened after you left.
-Mentally was very bad. I was very cross.
-Especially with certain people?
-No, because everybody looked at me like this. I didn't like to be, the main thing that I have to know.
-To be in control.
-It's not so much in control but to know what is going on.
In the minute that I have the knowledge I can cope. If I don't have the knowledge, forget it,
I go nuts, I just go crazy. It's not in this incident. It happens all the time.
-Next time we will tell you exactly and see whether you can cope.
-I can cope with it, I'm not worried but the thing is that I have the feeling that, because
you've been hiding I thought it was worse than it was actually.
When I went home I still felt very sick. I was very tired, I had pain in my hands,
I couldn't breathe, every word I said took a lot of energy. A little word was coming like
I was losing energy and breath. It was very funny, I never had something like this in my life.
Every word I wanted to say by the time I finished the word, it was here.
The same was with the anger. The anger came like this up to my ears. A lot of anger.
-Did you go for a check up?
-Yes I did.
-How many days after you returned?
-I returned I did a blood test, that was the quickest way I could do and I asked for a check up
by a specialist, a cardiologist. It took time, I had two big fights to get it so I went after a week
and then the check up was again later. By the beginning of July I finished all the checks ups
which was a normal ECG again by a doctor, a heart echo and ergometrics.
Everything was fine.
-Do you have it?
-I have it, I have it here. Now when she told me everything is fine with you, first with the
echo everything is fine, a big stone came out, I felt better mentally.
Then in the ergometrics. when she said it's fine then I was so happy, I was really free.
I felt like a sick person and I don't like to feel that way. I had enough in my life. I don't want.
I want to be able to do everything, I can't feel sick. The worse point was my memory which is still now.
It is diminished, it's gone. I forget my bag and I have very big fear of robbers,
so it's very funny that I leave my bag with my money everywhere; I just forget it
and even to the ergometrics I came in another date. I had to convince them to do it.
-But what exactly happens? You forget appointments?
-Everything.
-No, wait a moment. You forget words while you are speaking?
-That I had before also. I want to say a word and I say this, I don't get the word.
I had that also the last year. My husband laughs at me. It takes time till I get the word.
Sometimes it takes the whole day till the next day.
-Do you forget by going from one room to the other what you have to do?
-Of course. All my follow up I lost. I did a beautiful follow up and I don't know where I put it.
I had to recall now from little pieces of papers that I found at home but everything with the doctors'
echo I put in an envelop, I put it in a place where I could find it
and it took me 2 weeks and I couldn't find it and I had to go and take extra papers
from the clinics from the computer, the blood test and everything 2 days before I came.
-The enzymes, everything in your blood examination was perfect also?
-Triglycerides very high which I never had high before, 6 months before I never had it.
Cholesterol is on the top like 148 and she looked at it and I said, it's not good
and she said don't worry you make a diet, everything will be fine, your blood pressure will be fine
all this will go out and I showed the ECG that we had here, she said it's nothing,
it comes when you have a high blood pressure. It's normal. That's what she told me.
I said thank you and I went, for me it was enough. I was happy.
-But I told you about the diet myself. I told you, you have to follow.
-Yes I know. I stopped cigarettes which is very hard, I never took any cigarettes since then
to my mouth. My family is sending thanks finally. Finally I stopped smoking.
I promised you then and I didn't start. It was hard enough and making a diet I felt so bad
the last months that I couldn't think of having a diet. I need strict diet. I tried with meat
I ate more bread because everything else gave me problem to my stomach.
-Fish also you can eat.
-I ate fish in the grill. I hardly ate any fish and I felt sick, the fish smell I didn't like it and
the meat was too heavy for me. Since I took the Sulphur my stomach is... I have to tell you
something. I don't know if it is the Sulphur or the Latrodectus but it seems like it cleaned everything
good that any remedy did. It just stripped me from all the remedies that I had before and
brought me back to 5 years ago with all the problems.
I'm talking about stomach problems, cramps, everything, especially the stomach
and the memory. I never had something like this before.
-Not so strong.
-The memory is impossible. I'm angry.
-You checked in your arteries by a specialist, looking at your arteries through the eyes?
-No. If you give me a list I'll fight for it but if I don't know what to do
I can't go to my doctor and push her.
If I'll push her she'll give me papers but normally they don't suggest nothing.
-It is important to know the degree of the sclerosis of the arteries.
Normally there is a degree of sclerosis.
-Through the eye?
-Through the eye the eye specialist can dilate the pupil and can look to the condition of the arteries.
So because you are a little bit over weight
and because you have been eating very well all your life...
-No, since I studied Homeopathy, in 6 years I put 30 kilos.
-We try to prevent, it's not nice for you to say everything is all right. You are not the type
because you just go alone, you just forget about it, smoking, eating...
The moment we are absolutely sure that everything is OK, you will start smoking, I promise you.
-No, I'm not. I told you I'm not stating to smoke. I had cigarettes in my bag all this time.
Only I had and on purpose I left it. I'm not smoking
because I don't want to smoke not because I don't have.
-Except of the memory you are doing like this, like Ignatia.
-I don't have air.
-You feel you need air.
-Since I stopped smoking my capacity of the lung maybe grew, I don't know I need air.
-You said you need air blowing in your face actually.
-Look at me now, I'm sweating all the time, my old grand mother used to.
If the air is blowing a little bit, then it's fine.
But even if it's not so hot outside but if the air doesn't move I feel horrible, I don't have air.
At home I use and I sleep with an air conditioner and two fans, with a full air conditioner.
-You are very hot.
-Since May. Before I was hot also but not to this degree. It's getting worse and worse every day.
-I can see that. Bread and butter you are eating a lot?
-I try not to. Here in Alonissos yes because there is plenty for breakfast.
I eat in the morning but I try not to.
-Eggs?
-Eggs I like them also but I don't eat.
-Soft?
-I like them soft, mixed, scrambled.
-What about crying, weeping?
-All the time. That is the worse thing that happened to me since I was here.
Again a sensitivity came, like it cleaned the Phos away. With the Phos I had a shield,
I didn't take it in and in the minute you gave me this... I was crying here all the time,
for every little word, every little look, I cried. It's terrible, it's embarrassing,
it's horrible and if somebody comes to me and tells oh this and that, how do you feel? It comes out.
It's terrible, it's not nice and I cried from anger most of the time,
if I'm angry and frustrated, if I'm angry about something immediately the tears come.
It's like frustration, I don't knowI cant' explain it.
I tried to write symptoms which are very obvious this time, not messy. The mouth, the dryness
I used to have before at night, now I have all day long. The burning, I have very strong burning
from here up to my ears. It's so strong that it comes up to my ears.
-When the pain is coming?
-All the time, anytime. At night I involuntarily vomit bile, I found myself wake up for choking
and the head up with bile, very burning from the stomach that comes up like burning
the whole esophagus. I used to have it before that time that I told you that I took Nux vomica
and it went away? Now I have again but burning sensation is with very strong pain.
-Tell me in the past you have taken Pulsatilla?
-No, you told me to take if the Phosphorus doesn't work.
-No, before me.
-Never. My daughter took now Pulsatilla. I never took Pulsatilla.
The feet is numbness and sometimes ticklish and a lot of cramps.
-Cramps in the toes or in the sole?
-The sole becomes like a cramp and the toes stand. The cramp comes here and then
it turns the whole sole and I have to stand or something and it comes if I sit like this.
There was a very funny thing which is special, I never had it before. I was sitting on the floor
trying to reach something and I felt that my intestines inside made a loop like this.
That's very funny, I never had this before. It happened a few time for about a week all the time.
This one I told you. The memory is... I have to do things at work
and if I just distract to do something else I forgot
and I skip and I'm talking about very important things that can cost me my office.
Suddenly after 2 days I remember that I didn't send a letter here or there to solve things.
And I found out that everything that I get angry or offended, everything goes
immediately to the physical. I get upset and immediately something wrong,
the blood pressure goes high, I get hot. I had an incident before I came here.
My husband left the country with my daughter.
-While you are here did you check your blood pressure?
-Yes, on the one hand it 200 over 120 and on the left hand was 180 over 110. And I think
now it's even more, I feel it. Every movement, every exertion makes me sweat.
This one, do you know what is that? Since I have the high blood pressure I have this swelling here
and I have also sometimes if I lie on my back, I have cramp in the back.
-Only on the right side?
-It's closer to the spine but on the right side, a little bit higher than the waist.
And I always have to turn immediately, otherwise the whole back is in a cramp.
Most terrible was the stomach problems.
-What you described.
-No, I didn't describe you yet. Since I took the Sulphur I used to wake up at 5.30 to the toilet,
7.30 to the toilet. If I woke up not with an urge to run to the toilet, after 2 minutes
I run to the toilet and gas and diarrhea and urine, everything like a war. It was terrible.
-In the morning?
-In the morning and it took me at least 5 times until I go to work within an hour. It was not formed.
-When it was that?
-All the last 4 months. Some days during the day too. When I came here, only the last 3 days
the stool is formed.
-Let me understand. You wake up in the morning, early in the morning from a pain in the
abdomen, an urge and then you go and you have diarrhea ...
-Gas, urine, everything it goes out and it takes at least 5 times until I finish.
-This happens 5 times.
-At least 5 times, I used to run. I told myself stop it, don't think about it, its' the Sulphur.
Forget it because I was afraid I'm getting my ulcerative colitis again, it's not funny.
Because it was with pain.
-When you had the ulcerative colitis was very severe?
-Very very severe. This kid is healthy next to what I was. You said 20 times?
I used to do 60 buckets of blood the day. Blood here, blood in the hospital for a few months.
42 kilos less than half of I'm now, with 5 hemoglobin. Very very sick.
I'm very happy to see that she is more out because that helped me, just open her mouth and say.
Don't hold in but I was afraid that I get it but it's 30 years now, I don't think I should get it.
When I had this pain in my stomach I was afraid that something was going on,
I had cancer in my colon or something because all the time they are sending me
letters to come and check. I never checked it I don't want to put nothing in.
But the last 3 days here it's OK.
-Where did you attribute that fact? Did you change your diet drastically?
-No, I thought it was aggravation from the remedy.
-And it stopped, you feel that it stopped the aggravation?
-I don't know. It stopped 3 days ago. Now I'm going twice, 3 times the day but not that's horrible feeling.
-I'm afraid it's not the aggravation, it's something more than the aggravation.
-Maybe it's proving, I don't know. I had the same thing when I took Sulphur last time
that's why I was afraid to take it.
-It's not a proving. It's the colitis which is coming back.
-No it's not.
-Not exactly.
-I had these years but for a very short time.
It seems upset with everything I put in my mouth, it wants to go out again very quick.
-But you say this happens only in the morning.
-No, during the day also, all day. It started in the morning and then few times during the day.
-Every day?
-Yes but then it continued when I went in the last week of August we went to Italy.
One day before we went to Italy I think I had a virus or something because I had a pain here
which I never have, a pain in the pit of the stomach here.
Very severe pain and weakness all over, I think it was some kind of a virus,
I couldn't pack, I couldn't do nothing, it was terrible.
-You took some medicine?
-I didn't take anything and then when I was in Italy my husband and my daughter said
that something is wrong with you. The smell was terrible. Everything I ate I had to run to the toilet.
It was impossible for them because I had to be near toilets all the time.
I had to find restaurants all the time, put them to sit so I can go to the toilet. It was terrible.
-The diarrhea makes you get up from bed or after you get up?
-Sometimes at the beginning it made me get up. I wrote it down and most of the days
was that I woke with it, 5.30, 6.30, 7.30 and then it calmed down and only after I woke up.
At the beginning most of the time was waking me up and then it evens up and then it
started also whenever I ate something but I always have been very sensitive in the
stomach. If I go and eat in a restaurant and something is not completely fresh within 15
minutes that goes in I have a terrible pain.
-Where?
-In my stomach and I have to run, within half an hour if I eat something rotten or little bit
old, it doesn't do anything to anybody, it does to me.
-The stool comes out with gas, like an explosion?
-Yes like an explosion till 3 days ago.
-Now it's more formed and once or twice?
-No also twice in the morning, one day I didn't have at all in the morning and then once
in the evening or twice, but that's normal for me to have 3 the day.
I never had any constipation in my life but I'm bloated.
-You have a lot of gas.
-And now I started also swollen in the ankles which I lost after Phosphorus,
I didn't have it anymore and I wanted to tell you, I heard that everybody saying about the ticklish
of the soles, I never thought it was important to say. The most ticklish and sensitive place
in my body is my soles, I never ever walk without shoes, even not in the house.
-You had Medorrhinum before?
-But now it's a bit numbed the last year. Water that comes on my face when I shower
and I have water I look for air.
-You can not breathe.
-Yes and the same in the dentist, when I have to go the dentist I don't go
because I just drown there, he uses water.
-The stool has a peculiar color like green or brown, yellow?
-Sometimes it's yellow if I eat a lot, when I'm on diet and I eat a lot of cheese is yellow like baby.
It depends what I eat but normally is not black and when I have diarrhea you see all the food in.
The blood pressure was funny after the Sulphur.
In the end of May I found myself in the afternoon very dizzy like losing conscious
and I checked the blood pressure and then I found out that it's dropping to 17 in the afternoon.
I used to wake up with a very high blood pressure and by noon, afternoon it used to drop to 7.
120 over 70.Then starting go up again and I never used to this low one and I walked like this,
so I checked it morning, noon, I checked it for a few days to see when it's going up
and when it's going down, it's a cycle.
Here I wrote down strong stomachache with diarrhea, it used to wake me up in the morning
and it was like undigested food.
-How you wake up in the morning?
-Tired.
-Very tired?
-I feel like having another hour, especially here, I need the hours in the morning to rest.
-Do you have times where you feel better or worse?
-I think I feel better at night.
-After sunset?
-It could be.
-But not clear.
-I remember once that I was sick and it was in the afternoon...
-Desire for fresh air put 3 times.
-Not only fresh, fanning air, that will move not stand.
-The main important thing was this burning that was unbearable and the heat and the stomach,
now the stomach is OK. I had burns, I had also little ones that grow.
You see here, this grows here and around the bra.
-Little warts, they just came out?
-They came out after May, I had few before but more or them came and I had one
which was very big that I got few years ago and this one shrinked here.
The things that I got rid of which amel. this burning is the soda water, that what I'm living on now.
Soda and lemon and everything I put lemon, it's refreshing.
-You feel that you need lemon?
-Yes because I can't drink water, it's bitter, I hate water so I drink soda.
-You don't like water?
-Never, I never liked and cold I don't drink at all because I have pain here from the cold
and also from ice cream. I wait to melt. There is a pain that goes up here between the eyes.
Also in the cold weather I have this.
-Put headache from cold or ice cream.
-Also if I'm in Europe in the winter I have a problem because I have a pain here.
And if I'm going on snow I have pain in my legs.
I have something very unique with this sweat. For instance in Israel or here I found out
that if I go and the street is very hot, I go outside and I'm hot and I sweat a little bit
but in the minute that I go into a shop which is air conditioned and which is nice and cool
then I start sweating like a shower. Suddenly it comes down piles of water,
especially from the head, the forehead, leg. It's very funny because I don't sweat that much
in the heat as I sweat when I get into a cooler place. Normally it used to be ameliorate the sweat,
now it makes it worse. Sometimes if it's really hot I sweat here.
-In the inguinal region.
-And sometimes it smells like semen,  a sperm, I had it the first time when I was pregnant
with my first daughter 20 years ago. I was walking in the street and suddenly I was so wet
and I thought that the water came out because it smelled funny and since then now and
then in the summer I have it.
-Your thirst is normal or less than normal?
-I'm not thirsty, I never was thirsty. I hardly drink, my daughter pushes 2 glasses per
day for me. If you let me drink as I want it would be 1 glass or 2 the day
but I'm very dry now, maybe the blood sugar went up.
-Enough information.
What shall we do?
Wait, repeat, give another remedy?
-Yes.
-You are getting too good.
Why? There are changes and these changes point to a remedy and the remedy is clear
you can say it is quite clear because there are a lot of symptoms supporting that remedy.
Everybody is thinking of the same remedy? You don't know.
She was sighing a lot, shall we give Ignatia?
-No.
-You are getting good I told you.
It was very nice what she said, everything good has happened to me,
it was taking out she was left with the bad things. It's very nice to hear.
You give a remedy, everything is going to pieces. She is not in good condition
and she likes to be more happy. The bloodpressure is very strange also, up and down, what is this?
-Something new, "Sulphatilla".
-Very good, why Sulphatilla? Why? On this particular symptom of going up and down?
-Changing symptoms.
-Yes, it's very strange. Especially in blood pressure. We know moods are changing,
you are up and down, the color of menses maybe changing but to change the blood pressure
from so high to so low is the first time I hear it.
-Every day.
-So the whole class seems to me that agrees on a remedy...
Let the cardiologist speak and I have to put some questions to you.
-I have to say that the examinations which have been made in Israel, I have to evaluate as to be not complete.
The examination of just the cholesterol without examining what is
the high cholesterol and the low cholesterol, this doctor can't really call himself
to be a good cardiologist. I've looked at the ergometric examination, she practically
broke down after 3 minutes in 25 seconds. That means they gave a too high exertion
from the very beginning on, the heartbeat without any exertion was 76 per minute.
At the end of this test was 168. That means that the volume per minute was going up very much
and the blood pressure stayed 160 over 70.
This is either wrong or pathological or it is not taken in the correct way.
She has 8 ventricular extra systoles per minute without any comment of which kind they were.
We can't really take such an examination into consideration nor we have really
examined the back of her eye bulb, as you have already mentioned, no examination of the kidney,
no examinations of the blood sugar, nothing.
-It started at around 23rd of May. In the morning I used to wake up with 16 over 11 or 16 over 9
and then by the afternoon it used to go to 12-7 or 10-8 but it took about 2 weeks
and it was all up again. For 2 weeks it was like this.
-When it was up, it stayed up all the time?
-You are talking about afterwards? It stayed up around the top when it used to be between 15 and 13
and the low one used to the lowest 9, between 11 and 9 but not that low as 7 or 8.
-I want to ask you what is your opinion concerning this swelling she says
that she has developed here on the sternum.
-We only see such a symptom with the emphysema. I've spoken to her because she came up to me
and asked about this. He has a history of bronchial asthma and if you do an auscultation of the lung,
you can't really call it emphysema.
I really you should make a thorough pulmonological examination to make a clear statement.
-Do you have any coughing while lying in bed in the evening?
-No.
-Anyhow we agree on the remedy, the remedy at this moment is quite clear. It is
Pulsatilla. The problem is with the potency. 10M, 50M, 200, 30, 12.
What potency you will give to her? Who will give 50M? None. 10M? One.
1M? One. 200? 33. 30? 28. 12? 13.
I will also prefer to go slowly and to start with 12C and she can take twice the day 12C
until she has a reaction. You have a reaction, then you stop and then will go slowly higher accordingly.
If you are better, you repeat 12, no good, then you go 13, 14,15 and
every 10 days you can raise one potency. But sometimes what happens in this schema
sometimes the patient will tell you the number 15 is very good, so you don't keep it 10 days,
you continue to keep it for 1-2 months. As long as the patient feels good, you keep it to this potency.
There is a potency is which they respond much more satisfactorily and you leave it there
-But if I get aggravation after 2 days?
-Then you stop.
-And I never go up anyway.
-You don't go up. You wait. You see what happens after the aggravation.
After the aggravation, you must have an amelioration.
The amelioration may last 10 days, 15 days, then you will start going down.
Once you start going down, then you start repeating again.
-The same potency?
-The same potency.
-I have a problem with Pulsatilla. I see symptoms that contradict to the remedy.
She was perspirating very much during the interview, she was perspirating a lot on her face
and on her neck and she said that she would sweat a lot with any short of exertion.
The rubric sweat with the slightest exertion, we don't find any Pulsatilla
and we don't find any Pulsatilla with sweat on walking.
-It is wrong. Pulsatilla sweats a lot. Pulsatilla is one of the remedies
that we use in flashes of heat, in climacteric. A lot of sweat, a lot of heat, no problem.
The sweat is like Calc carbo. Calc carbo will perspire in the way she describes.
Also if I remember wellCalc carbo will perspire in the cold air, as she says. I come to the cool air,
in a cool room and then I perspire. Can you find this in the Repertory? Perspiration air cool.
What are the remedies?
-Pulsatilla second degree.
-Calcarea carbonica is there?
-No, Veratrum Argentum nitricum.
-Yes but I'm not perspiring in the cool air. Unless I've been outside in the heat,
I stand a little bit, then I go into a cooler place, then the most perspiring starts.
-Show the remedy, perspiration in cold air, you see the Calc carbo is strong
but Pulsatillais on perspiration, what is exactly the rubric?
-Perspiration during coldness.
-No. But it's not what I meant.
-This, what you have is not possible to find exactly in the Repertory.
We don't' have a problem with this. Why? Because first of all I know that Pulsatilla perspires,
as we could see, secondly the symptoms are so strong for Pulsatilla.
She is so warm, she wants the air to blow, she cries so easily, she says it's a big problem,
desires bread and butter and all the other symptoms. Show me the repertorisation.
She has strong Pulsatilla symptoms, you like consolation also?
-Yes.
-Yes but it aggravates also. If I have consolation, I cry.
-She cries more.
-I want you to see the repertorisation because all her symptoms are there.
-I don't think that Pulsatilla is a good choice.
Concerning to my opinion she said very often that she has this terrible perspiration
and she has these stools and she says whenshe can pass stool, she feels better
and the swelling up here and I would think of Lachesis ecause she looks as she has emphysema.
-No. Lachesis will be a kind of a dangerous remedy to give because if she is not Lachesis
it will bring the blood pressure even higher, so we don't go. It is interesting what she says
also apart from other symptoms, which is interesting. I don't drink and if I drink cold or
ice cream, I get a headache. That is a symptom of Pulsatilla almost alone.
Arsenicum maybe has this sometimes but Pulsatilla has it very strongly
and it is a strange symptom because Pulsatilla should like cold, should be ameliorated by cold.
It is ameliorated by cold externally but if she eats ice cream, it has be proven that
Pulsatilla ice cream, just because it cools down the buccal cavity, it brings up the pain in head.
After ice cream, Arsenicum and Pulsatilla.
-In the rubric headaches after cold drinks you find Sulphur and not Pulsatilla.
-After cold drinks?
-You have to look a little bit further down in the Repertory and then you have cold drinks aggravate
and then you have Pulsatilla in it.
-Very good. You better be careful next time because I wanted to say, add it.
Show me the repertorisation.
-You mean the columns.
-Yes the columns and show me why Pulsatilla. It has 14 symptoms or more?
14 out of 20 and Nat mur? There was at a certain point there was a possibility of Podophyllum
when it comes to the point where she may... fear of robbers, weakness of memory...
How much salt you want?
-No.
-Is she Nat mur?
-Forget it, you take it out immediately. That is why many times I said I will not even consider that remedy.
Nat mur do not come into consideration for her case.