-You can tell what happened. Last time you were here, it was two years ago.
-Two years ago, in 1998.
-And you had received initially Nat. mur. 200.
-It was the third month of pregnancy and 5 months later, at the end of 8th month
of pregnancy I wrote you a letter and you prescribed Sepia 50M,
which I was afraid to take but I did took it and the reaction was beautiful.
I had very difficult pregnancy and the 9th month was very easy,
I had good feeling again towards the embryo and the children and my husband
and everything changed wonderfully and then the delivery was tremendously easy,
very easy, very quick.
I almost didn't feel anything and afterwards with the baby I had very good feelings
and I had a lot of milk and the baby was good and this kept for about a year.
Then I wrote you a letter, it was September 1999, there was no clear picture yet.
-I wrote back and I said it's no clear picture.
-Yes, I had few symptoms from the beginning, like depression again and irresolution
and all the things, forgetfulness, hurriedness but then the picture was not clear,
then in November 1999, Smedar and Tamar took my case in Israel and Tamar wrote you the letter
and you prescribed Phosphorus 200, which I didn't understand from my point of view
but it reduces the depression and I have a symptom which I didn't' t have before,
pain in the stomach, very sharp pain the whole night but then it's gone.
I tried to eat more and my baby started to be sick a lot, to have lungs problems
and I wonder whether it was connected to Phosphorus, I didn't know
but it was difficult time for me, for a few months.
Then I wrote you a fax again and you prescribed Sepia 10M.
I took the remedy in February this year.
This remedy acted for about a week or 10 days, I had much more sexual desire
and I had good feelings but then after really short time, I remember quarrelling with my husband,
a kind of disappointment from him and then I felt that it's all gone.
For about a month I was depressed and a symptom started to come again,
the allergy hay-fever which I suffered from it and it was gone with the Sepia during the pregnancy,
headaches, backaches, pain in my legs, everything that was completely disappeared,
started to come back.
I was asking myself what is happening, I was so confused
and then I think I did a very big mistake and I took another dose.
-You repeated the Sepia?
-I repeated the Sepia, I knew it was a mistake the same day
but it was like I don't know why I did. I was so disappointed and in despair.
-What happened after Sepia?
-After Sepia the same day I got high fever and for about few days I had strong flu,
I couldn't get up from bed and then for a month I have every day another symptom.
All it was from the past. I knew the symptoms, nothing it was new
but it was coming day after day, symptom, symptom and I knew this was my mistake,
I have to wait and you also told me to wait and it's gone, after a month
I felt clean from this artificial thing on me.
I think that now about 3 months after it's a bit more clear.
I think what happened with the Nat. mur. is that the grief that I've told you
about from when I was 20 years, this is something that is now gone from life.
It's not influencing anymore.
I'm a person of grief like a sad person but these incidents are not living in here all the time,
I'm just free of it.
And I think the Sepia made a tremendous affection on me being a mother,
with the children, I think I had very good contact with my baby and with my other children
is not the way I wanted to be but it's not like I felt before.
I felt much more in communication  with them and good feelings.
Now I think it's a lower layer coming.
The main complain I think is emotional, I told you from the beginning
that I have a cyst in my right ovary.
-You checked it lately?
-I checked it and it's the same.
-The same size?
-Yes.
Also I have pains in legs, so I have to change shoes every day
but I don't suffer from it so much and another thing that I was complaining about
which still I think I have to keep myself from it, is leucorrhea, the yeast infection
which I think I keep myself from it and I don't have it.
-You don't have it now?
-Yes but I think I have to keep sexual relationship normal but you know in Judaism
there are rules for sexual relationship.
We keep during the menses period and then one week after we don't...
And I feel that if I keep the rules, then it's OK because during this week I have the itching
and then it's gone.
-I see.
-I'm coming to now. The main thing is this irresolution that I can not decide anything.
I feel that it has influenced all over my life and my family and everybody is influenced
from this because I hesitate on everything, like when I go to bed if I have time
I want to take a book with me and then I take 3 books because...
-You cannot decide which one.
-And when I look at them it takes time and then I fall asleep because I don't have more time
to read and that happens all the time.
For example here in Alonissos, I'm here with my family
because I couldn't leave the children at home, it was a very big problem to separate
from the children and especially from the baby, so they all came with me
and we were looking for a house. We were on vacation and I couldn't relax,
just looking which house would be better and now we chose one
and to take the upper floor or the down?
All the time thinking and changing.
-You can not decide.
-Even when I decide something I still think whether it was the right decision or not.
-This happens also for big decisions, did you take any big decision?
-We are trying to buy a house in Israel and we don't do it,
I think we both have problems in this but my problem is in making decision and I can not do it.
Or whether to come to Alonissos or not for me it's a big decision and it takes months on thinking
and until the very last moment all the time I worry about.
-So this is your main problem at this moment?
-I think in it there is everything connected to it.
-Can you give me what else is connected?
-Like I never have time, I'm trying to do many things and I don't have time
for really doing something because I'm surrounded like trying to decide and organizing
but not in the thing and also with my children...
-Would you say you are in a hurry inside you?
-I'm very much in a hurry, I'm always in a hurry and all the time organizing things
and trying to chose, trying to think what is the right thing to do, what is better for me to do.
Like packing the bags to come to Alonissos I did it for a long time, to take this or this
and I'm exhausted but still I'm doing it and also since I don't decide from the beginning
then I don't have time because until the very last moment I'm still working in my mind
and it makes me feel tense because I know that I won't be prepared, I'm going to be late,
not ready and if I do something then I regret, I think I made a mistake.
And also I feel that I don't enjoy life, it's also connected I think to the grief
and this attitude of sadness but more now it's this that I don't experience what happens
and I'm far out thinking what to do and what is right.
Sometimes I think I don't really listen to my child because I'm in the next thing
or in the prior but not in the present.
-Your mind is racing all the time.
-Yes and also this is another thing which is coming now from the past.
I have a very low feeling about myself comparing to others.
I feel like I don't have anything inside like I don't have anything in my life.
I'm 40 years old and like I don't know anything and how come?
I have my life, I have my children but my feeling is that nothing exists,
all these years I didn't learn anything.
-Have you been in the army?
-Yes, I was in the army and I was in computer.
-What is your skills? You have computer skills, in high school you did mathematics?
You were medium, how you were in school?
-Mathematics yes, very high.
-And still you were not believing into yourself?
-Not then but I was very high and I think there were a lot of expectations
from my parents, from myself and now I feel that I didn't accomplish anything.
-But do you now feel that you don't have any skills, you don't know what to do?
-It's not that I don't have skills but when it comes to the point, then I feel that I don't know.
-This is what I say. You don't know what to do with the child...
-But also whether to chose a remedy, when it comes to the point it's like I don't know anything,
like I didn't study anything and I feel that I have this year very big conflict
in myself because I had again expectation to make a big progress in Homeopathy
but I had the baby and it was difficult to separate from her and also in my mind
I thought it's better to be with her.
But then I didn't do neither of them because I also tried to do this and this
but I didn't make this progress.
-But you didn't feel that you lack in self-confidence?
-Yes.
-Very much?
-I don't know, I think it's a change now because first I did have this irresolution before.
My husband knows what he wants, so I wanted to do what he wants and to give up myself
and I was frustrated and angry and this was, I think, Sepia.
And now I don't know so it's better to take his way.
-But do you need also his protection? You feel that you need to be protected by him?
-I feel that I want reassurance from him because if he criticizes me, then I'm lost
because I can not stand on my own because I don't know what I want.
I don't know what I'm doing.
-How is your memory?
-Not good.
-But not very bad either?
-I think it's getting worse.
When I came here I thought it was connected to the grief because this time
I don't remember a period of time but also I don't remember my childhood
but now I feel that I don't remember my past at all and also little things
like where I put something or what I said or what I wanted to do.
-Tell me something else. Do you have this where you wanted to go
and find something in the next room and then you go to the next room
and you forgot why you were there?
-Rarely but it happens and then I'm thinking and I don't remember
and then I'm in another thing and then I remember.
-You talked about that grief, there was a big grief that you had
and you said now it's over it's not anymore in your head?
But this grief I believe was concerning emotional relationship, right?
-Yes.
-Now you are not disappointed that you did not continue with that?
-This grief was about a boyfriend of mine from the age of 20 and he died from cancer.
-And now with the husband that you have sexually you feel good, connected?
-It's much better now, I have my desire but it's not for every day, it's not frequent.
-With the other boy that he died you had much more desire?
-No, it was before I had children and also with my husband before we had children...
-So you were careful?
-No, it was the beginning, falling in love, much more sexual and now
I'm not looking for it, my husband wants it much more and now when we have it, I enjoy it.
I don't need it so much.
-Your parents are both alive?
-Yes.
-Is anybody suffering?
-My mother suffers from high blood pressure and palpitation.
My father has skin problems but I always tell him this is good.
-There is cancer in your family at all? Brothers, sisters, uncles?
-No. I want to tell about my parents that during this year and maybe the last years
it became much stronger, I feel that I want them to support me studing Homeopathy
and make a progress, I feel I want them to support me for doing what I didn't do
when I was 20 with this problem, I didn't accomplish things.
-Have you ever been wild child?
-No, I was always very good girl.
-You never took hashish, marihuana?
-I tried few times but I didn't like it.
-Are you sure? Difficult question. I have not yet found a young person
who has not taken these drugs. Who did not try. But my question is how much?
-Very little. I think I can count 5-10 times, no more.
-Did you ever have a bad reaction from that? You remember any bad experience?
-I remember that I didn't like it, I didn't like being dizzy and being out.
I liked to be in control and when I felt it's not control, I didn't like it at all.
My friends did like it but I don't.
-Did you ever have any skin eruption yourself in the past, as a child?
-I don't remember.
-You have in your report here, you have said that you did not like the smell of fish.
-During the pregnancy. I can eat fish, still I don't like the smell so much.
-But you can eat fish, you like fish? You cannot say.
What about sweets?
-I like sweets now  more than before.
-Salt?
-Still.
-You like salt, more than usual or medium?
-It's medium but if it's no salt I don't like the food. Maybe less than before.
-You have any hair fall?
-Yes.
-Strongly?
-It's always after giving birth for about a year.
-How many children you have?
-Three.
-With the same husband?
-Yes.
And I had one abortion before I had the kids, with the same husband
and I told you in the fax that this was another grief of my life.
-You did not want?
-It was like an instinct that I didn't want to do it but all the circumstances
was like doing it and my husband was not my husband then
and it was just after the death of my prior friend and I really didn't feel good about it
and I still I regret about it and like I have this child in my mind sometimes.
I wanted to tell you about my parents that I want them to support me and during this year
I tried a few times to tell them that I need their support emotionally and money wise
but I didn't dare to talk to them about it and it's so strange for me, why I don't say it.
I need your support but they don't really like Homeopathy, they are in the other side
and also maybe they don't want to give money for this, I don't know.
I have to speak about it and to open myself but I don't, I remain close
and this influence my relationship with them because ...
-You are in distance.
-Yes and a few times I was sitting in front of my father and I said,
now I speak but I can not.
It's a kind of fear and also I have this fear that something bad will happen to the children
or to us or to me and all concerning the children.
Sometimes I see visions, like I go with the car and it falls
or my husband is now with the children at the beach and that something will happen.
And then I clear my mind but it comes.
-Do you feel very much the heat or the cold?
-I think it's even.
-Your nails are strong?
-It's OK.
-How much thirst?
-It was very high while I was nursing but now I think it's normal and I drink much warm drinks.
-What about fruits?
-I like fruits.
There was time in my life that I really loved fruits.
Now it's not that I'm looking for it but I eat fruits.
And there is another thing in the morning, this is continuing,
when I just wake up and open my eyes I have gloomy feeling.
I remember times that it was a depression. Now it's not a depression but I'm not happy.
I'm looking towards the day and thinking what I have to do and then I'm tensed.
-You feel the responsibility is too much for you or what? You can not handle it.
-I have to wake up the children to go to school and they want to go on sleeping
and I don't want to wake them, why to do this to them and I'm sad about it
and I don't feel that I can make them happy because I'm not happy myself.
I don't feel easy, it's heavy.
-Anything else? OK.
Since you don't know the follow up that came through the fax,
I have to read you the follow up to see why I prescribed Sepia. She says, I got Nat. mur.
and I'm not sure that the picture at this moment is clear now but I don't feel good.
I'm depressed and I think that the remedy is not working anymore. I feel completely powerless,
physically and emotionally and mentally.
I have ne joy, no happiness, no smile and I'm not nice to the people around me.
You see how she describes the case of Sepia, it's unbelievable
because you were surprised why I prescribed 50M.
I don't feel myself, I'm tensed, I feel and think negative
and I try to think positive but no success.
My thoughts and dreams are bothersome and full of worries.
I don't have any positive feelings towards the embryo.
I'm worried that there might be something wrong with it, I don't feel connected to it at all.
You see how she describes the Sepia state exactly.
The same way I don't feel connected to my other children and husband.
I don't feel the love and happiness, only the duties.
I pity them for having me as a mother and wife.
Also I feel bitter and angry with others.
I feel that things are happening against my will and that I blame others for that.
It's terribly difficult for me to make decisions, I'm afraid to make the wrong choice
and even when the time is over, I still don't make up my mind and if I'm ignoring reality,
then I feel disconnected and bitter.
Physically I feel very heavy and limited. Every physical exertion is difficult,
climbing stairs is a big effort, I can't stand, I have to sit. Mainly I can't lift things.
My back cant' stand it. The middle back is weak and painful and can't hold the effort.
Also pains in the bones around vagina. My lower back feels as if broken, I have varicose veins,
swollen legs, I have to wear elastic socks.
Also I have to wear something tight to hold the belly, otherwise it feels uncomfortable.
You see all the symptoms...
Still the urine doesn't come out in strong stream.
Afterwards there is some more urine coming out involuntarily. I have to wear pad all the time.
The yeast infection in the vagina is better but I have no sexual desire and no attraction,
what makes the distance with my husband even bigger.
I feel generally warm, when someone touches me, it hits me, so I don't' want to be touched.
I'm less thirsty and there is less desire to eat.
No special desires. I have aversion to fish smell and to chicken.
When I lie down on the back lifting my legs, I feel pressure on the chest.
And then she makes a post script here.
You remember she has taken initially Nat. mur.
She says, a month ago I had to take an antideimmunisation, I don't know what it is.
What is this?
-It's for rhesus.
-Yes that's true... since my blood type is rhesus negative. Could it antidote the remedy?
It's very interesting because it's very instructive case. Then I said, take Sepia 50M
because we have a perfect picture of Sepia. It could not be more perfect, she has everything.
What antideimmunisation did, it brought out, most probably, the next layer.
That is very interesting. Here we have a case of grief, uppermost.
With an underline layer which comes up a little bit, which is Nat. mur. and then Sepia
and then we have underline this.
So there is a symptom which comes from a deeper layer, which is the irresolution as you hear.
She describes here everything else went away except of that symptom.
That means that symptom, which is irresolution, that was popping out belonged
to an underline layer.
And that is why also when she repeated untimely Sepia, she had a very bad time,
after repeated Sepia wrongly.
She bothered me quite a lot, she sent faxes, what shall I do, I made a mistake, I'm stupid,
I feel very bad and blah, blah, blah. I said wait. No give me a remedy.
No I don't give you a remedy unless you come here. When you come, then we discuss.
So this is what I was trying to persuade you not to do. Just before.
I didn't know the case was coming, just now. She is a very good example of what I said before.
It is like synchronicity.
A perfect case of Sepia, she did so well and she repeated it untimely and she goes down like this.
So now what do we have to do is to find this underline layer which is there very much.
We have the symptoms.  Give me the symptoms.
Cyst in the ovary, the three first are one symptom and then the three seconds
are another one symptom, weakness of memory, desires, anxiety for others,
waking in the morning sadness, in a hurry and the remedy ...
-Baryta carbonica.
-The remedy is Baryta carbonica. I tried to differentiate between Graphites
because the aversion fish was not exactly aversion fish and she confirmed Bar. carb.
by talking about her memory and also talking about fruits. Baryta carb. does not like fruits.
Finally when she says yes I like fruits, she says I don't like them as much as before.
You see this becomes important because of less desire for fruits.
So that is the third remedy for her so she can speak to her parents and tell them
what they have to hear.
What potency? Who says 30? Who says 200? Who says 1M? 10M? 50M? CM?
OK, CM. No, 1M is enough.
-There is a question George. She said she had her fall but the peculiarity was aggravated
after pregnancy and in this rubric...
So if you put it together with the low self-esteem desire sweets, right sided, desire warm drinks
and together with the fact that Lycopodium is complementary to Sepia?
-You deviated from the right line of thinking. Here you can not ignore...
Always you go to the strange, rare and peculiar and take this and base your prescription on that
and what is really at the moment bothering the person and what bothers her at  the moment
is lack of decision.
Irresolution, you have to find a remedy that really is irresolution.
Irresolution, we have 72 remedies. Which one?
That remedy which has at the same time lack of self-confidence, that she needs protection,
that she can not speak to her parents.
I have these needs. That forms together with the memory and together with the lack
of desire for fruits, as it was before, makes a case of Baryta carbonica.
When the indecision is so strong, you have to find a remedy that has very strong indecision
and we know that the remedy which has strong indecision in everything big or small things
is Baryta carbonica.
Not only that but Pulsatilla will not describe the need for protection like this.
I feel I don't have, my mind is empty, I don't have anything to say,
so I better leave it to my husband I better leave it to somebody else who makes the decision.
So this description fits the Baryta carbonica description, not Pulsatilla.