-OK we can start with her story.
-I started homeopathic treatment in January and the reasons are that I have a
depression and the other is that I suffer from psoriasis.
-The remedy she has taken so far is Kali-c.?
-Yes.
-And the reason she went in the homeopath in January was because of depression or
now the depression has arised?
-No, the depression started already about 3/4 of the year before I went to the homeopath.
-That's what I say. She went to the homeopath to be treated for the depression,
not for something else.
-I developed some symptoms here, in the last few days. One of them is that I feel
a pressure on my heart and I know it's not the organ itself. I can't take a deep breath
I can't breathe down into my abdomen as if there is a blockage.
-As if there is a blockage in her breathing?
-Yes. I have the feeling I only can just barely breathe superficially.
If I'm down at the beach and really relaxing, I feel that it softens and that I can breathe
deeper but for instance now again is like that and the pressure on my heart is permanent
these past days, there is no change in it.
-And the pressure in the heart is recent? It's only here?
-I know it, I used to have it once in a while, for a few days but it always went away and
now since few days here, it's staying.
Since I heard yesterday that I'm going to be a live case here today, I'm quite nauseous.
And I know that from many years in my childhood, strong feeling of nauseousness
without vomiting.
That was what I wanted to say in the beginning and now I would like to tell you
some parts of my life.
When my mother was pregnant with me, she tried to abort the pregnancy by letting an
ultra sound device put into the uterus but luckily enough that thing fell out and
I was born a couple of months later.
My memory I had very happy childhood because I was always speaking with the animals
and the flowers and the wind and sometimes even with things which were not visible.
But I always had a strong longing that my mother should love me which never did.
I never felt that she loved me.
And for two years, I remember in my childhood, that I woke up every night screaming
because I had anxiety dreams and I couldn't get up. My mother had to come and fetch me
and take me into their bed and then they continued sleeping and I was lying there
in the middle and still couldn't sleep because I actually still had anxiety.
-How old she was by that time?
-Between 4-6 years.
My sister and I, she is 6 years old, we didn't have that good relationship,
our father was very strict and sometimes also beat us, but what was much more prominent,
he had a kind of aura, which always made the day not happy anymore when he was coming home.
I always felt that something threatening was coming from him.
-Her father was an army man?
-No.
From many years I remember wishing for their love and their recognition which I never got.
Probably I was too lively for them, I had too much vivid imagination and phantasy and they
somehow couldn't deal with it. So this longing just remained but on the other hand
I did have the flowers and the trees and the animals and everything outside.
I met my husband when I was 17,5 and he also was the first man I ever kissed.
Before, I had no experience whatsoever, I haven't even flirt or anything before.
And this marriage separated 2,5 years ago. I was the one who walked out of the
relationship, even though this man was a person who loved me very much.
But the last years of our relationship were such that we both developed into different
directions and it just was not possible to work it out anymore.
We have one child together, a boy, he is turning 20 now and it was so that before I met
my husband I already saw him and I also saw my son before he was born.
Meaning I had pictures of them already before they were there.
I was born in the eastern part of Berlin and we built a house there during our marriage.
-She was eastern Berliner?
-Not anymore.
-But she was living in east Berlin?
-Yes.
We built a house at that time and I had years of working very hard, I was working 3 jobs
at the same time and also building up the house. At that time I had a lot of energy
and liked physical work, physical exertion and I just loved watching what comes out from
the work of your hands, what you can create.
-But it was allowed to have their own house in east Berlin?
-It was allowed.
I forgot one thing. The psoriasis developed when I had sexual intercourse with my
husband for the very first time.
-It was unpleasant for her? Pleasant?
-Yes, I wanted it.
-But she had a shock? She said she developed psoriasis after the first intercourse.
She had a pleasant shock? It was a big experience for her, something which changed
her inner world?
-Not in anyway you put it, the only thing I could think is that maybe I was afraid of my
father because I was doing something he would not approve but if there is an
explanation it could be that, otherwise I don't know.
-And she became pregnant after this intercourse?
-No. I have the psoriasis across my entire abdomen and also my legs, my arms and
later on also my head.
-She developed that immediately after the intercourse?
-4 days later.
-The feelings she had were feelings of happiness inside or feelings of fear?
-No, mostly feelings of happiness, maybe feeling of fear not to lose this person but
mostly I was happy.
-How is that she does not have psoriasis now?
-For many years I treated psoriasis with tar preparations and I also have psoriasis now only
not as strong as it used to. And before, in times when it was really bad,
I also used cortisone.
I was very thankful and very happy at that time that this man did not leave me in spite
the fact that I didn't feel very beautiful anymore, I felt more ugly and that he took me as
I was and I was very thankful for it.
-What was her husband?
-Electrician.
During the time when we were building the house, I was working a lot physically and
I was very exhausted in the evenings because I was doing a lot, I only weight 50 kilos
myself but I was able to carry cement bags weighing 50 kilos themselves and I
remember always being very proud about my physical strength and also my persistence.
Whatever I planned, I could carry through.
Suddenly enough, exactly at this time, when I was physically working so hard,
so exhausting very often, my husband betrayed me and I felt it and I asked him and
he admitted it was the truth.
And after that I developed another strong push of the psoriasis and as I did also in my
childhood, I didn't talk to anybody about that.
In my childhood I also had many years when I didn't talk, I was used into keeping things
inside, I wrote a lot into my diary but I didn't talk to anybody.
I remember those were the years where I had to fight with this constant nauseousness
in the years I didn't talk.
Next to my husband I always felt like the little girl, even though my friends were saying
you are not, you are the power woman, you are doing everything, you are managing
everything and it was the truth, I was doing all these things but I never felt like it.
I always felt like a little girl.
When the house was almost finished, I talked to my husband very much, very long and
told him that I felt I could not live any longer in this state, in this system, it was a
suppressing system and already in school I never joined any of the usual organizations
where most of people went already in school.
I was a kind of an outsider concerning this
and I told him even in the most beautiful house, in a golden cage a nightingale would not
sing and so I felt I could not live there any longer.
We talked about this issue for more than a year and my husband was not very happy
about it but through the years before this entire process of building the house and
realizing whatever I plan or try, I can manage and I can go through with it, I felt the
strength and I had this experience in my background now and I knew, if I really wanted
something, it could happen.
And so I also had this feeling there is a way out of this system.
-What she meant, she was planning to defect, to go out to the West?
-Yes, I planned to leave the country but officially. At that time you could apply for
leaving the country and we did that, very officially and I was also the one who quickly
connected with other people who also wanted to leave and I was active in this movement
and carried a lot of these services, Sunday services in church.
-She got a job on Sunday services?
-No, this peace movement, the activists in Eastern Germany.
-After the fall of the system?
-No, before.
-Before it was not allowed to go out.
-You could, you could apply before, it depended whether they would allow you or not
you could fill the application. You could apply, of course you had to wait 6,7 even
10 years until you got permission but you could apply. It was like dancing on a wire
you could go this way or that way. If you were too official and getting too uncomfortable
for them, you would end up in jail or if you carried through with it and you were very
active and very known publically, they couldn't do that.
So you got more and more uncomfortable until finally they wanted to get rid of you.
I had a lot of encounters with the Stasi and the service system there and I was afraid
and shaking and trembling very often but I just felt I had to carry through and I would
carry through and that's why I got so connected with all these organizations and
developed a lot of energy in this matter.
Then we got a 24 hour notice that we were permitted to leave the country, meaning we
had to give our house to the State, even though we had given it to our parents but they
wouldn't accept it, so we had to write it over to the State and then we just had time to
take one suitcase and one bag and leave, that was the usual way at that time.
-And with her husband they left.
-Yes and child.
When we were in west Berlin I worked as a nurse, which is my profession and I also
worked almost round the clock and after 2 years I started my education as a practitioner.
These two things I also did parallel at the same time and I also attended many seminars
and all together I was very active again.
Then the time came when the Wall came down and my husband couldn't deal with the
fact that he had lost the house.
So at that time I was busy with all the new things I was doing and the courses and very
happy with it and that I had content in my life and I was going on with it but he couldn't.
He was very sad because he had lost the house and he couldn't get out of that and that
was the time when we started developing in separate ways.
-He wanted to go back at the house?
-It wasn't possible at all but it was probably the fact that he developed a depression at
that time and I couldn't go back to that point and stick with it and so that's where we
started going apart.
-So her husband went back to east Germany?
-No.
It was most that I had started to practice physical therapies and many things in
a very energetic level and I had been training my awareness and perception and I felt
he was getting heavier and heavier in his energy and lower and lower and I couldn't
take that anymore with the sensitivity I had. I couldn't go on living and working like that.
Then I told him that I did not want to continue the relationship.
And he then moved and went to live in Bavaria.
I have to say that I always felt this relationship for him giving me a lot of security, he was
like my piece of ground, my piece of earth even though I was the one who was
developing activity and working and powering and so on.
He was something that maybe centered me, kept me on the ground and although I was the one
who wanted the separation, I knew it was going to be a big step to an unknown world.
-She developed in the meantime an affair?
-Quite quickly after the separation I had a relationship with another man for 1,5 year.
That was a man who, himself also was in a spiritual search, spiritual path.
And since I already had a child, I always asked a lot of questions about what's going on
and read many books and was very interested in looking myself. I was very happy to
have met such a person.
This man together with other people and a group, which was in a process of a therapy
took drugs to be able to perceive certain things more clearly and ...
-For spiritual search?
-Yes and go back to some things and release them.
-She took also?
-Yes.
-What kind?
-It's called MDMA.
-Chemical?
-For example one of my issues I was working on was find out why I constantly have
the feeling my parents don't love me.
And for me was very important because I had the possibility or I was allowed to look at
feelings I used to have as a child, from a different perspective and I also this way I was
able to understand how the life of my mother had been before, I was there and which
feelings my father had at that time and so on.
And later on I asked my parents about it and said, was that the case, did you feel this
and this way and was the situation so and so and both said, yes that what it was.
I always felt that for my mother I was too much, I was in the way, I was not wanted and
actually she had wanted to separate from my father, which then was not possible
anymore because I was under way.
My father was very happy when I was under way because he hoped that, that would save
the marriage and they are still together today but at that point the marriage was very critical.
And I, as a child, always felt their frustration, his and hers, it was always poured out
on my back, even though actually I couldn't tell it but both of them had frustration that
had to go out and they kept going on to me.
All of this situation I could re-live or feel again under the influence of this drug and later
I asked them about it and found out how it was.
-Is she clairvoyant in other things like foreseen things that happen?
-That's more the way that I've trained to do that. I've trained this ability, I will tell you
more about it, what I worked.
The experience with this drug was very valuable for me because I could understand
what was happening with my parents but also after that I never got rid of this feeling
of being unwanted, not loved.
And I realized especially since I felt into this depression that I can't get this contact to
myself, nothing is in flow, everything is blocked and I always feel as if a part of me was
not there, I'm always in effort. I always have to try to be good enough, to satisfy
everybody and it's a constant strain I'm under, to satisfy.
This feeling I have almost my entire life, I have to be something, I must be something
else, something better, I just can't be the way I am, I can't be myself.
My mother always used to say, you are tough, you can take anything and so when I
fell I hardly ever cried, she always said, you manage and so I always try to be the strong
one and the tough one and in my entire life I'm strong but I was never permitted to also
show the weak side in me.
There were many things that hurt me and when I cried or said I didn't like it, they said
come on don't be so sensitive and don't take everything in the bad part.
It was like they never took me seriously and so today when I'm together with other people
and I feel that something hurt my feelings, it's very difficult for me to articulate it at all.
What I also forgot to mention is that while my mother was pregnant with me, my father
was in the hospital for lung patients with tuberculosis.
And I tell you a little bit about the kind of work I do.
I'm doing a craniosacral body therapy and then with a couple of Indian people I learned
another kind of therapy which is called inner reading, meaning to go inside yourself and
read yourself.
Over the years I developed quite some sensitivity, while I treat the patients I feel pictures
arising in me, I can see things about their life or about their childhood and I also
developed the ability to feel organs of the body.
I sit on the foot of the bed and I imagine the body and I get a certain feeling and my
thinking is that you should have this and this check. I don't want to scare them, I just
give them hints of what they could do.
I can't do it immediately like if you push a button, I need some minutes to enter this
and there is also days where I see nothing. That's also possible.
-I have not understood yet. The depression has started about a year ago?
What she calls depression?
-I had this drug experience together with this man and right after that, he told me I don't
love you and left. And that was the one relationship I had after my marriage.
-And then started the depression or after a few months?
-It was pretty much right after he walked out of me but what came into the picture too
was that, that was actually the point where I started feeling what was going on.
All these feelings about my marriage started coming up and the realization that I was
alone and that I had nobody around me anymore.
The whole feelings of the whole story came up then and all that together.
-And that feeling of being rejected by her parents also became more strong?
-And a feeling of loss also. That she had a loss, even though she was the one who
walked out from marriage.
The feeling concerning my parents I had during this drug therapy. After that I personally
decided for myself that I love my parents and that I will go and visit them, no matter how
they behaved towards me, I will go to them, take them in the arms and show them my love.
And after that the relationship really improved which had been difficult until my 38th
year but after that it improved.
-Does she grind her teeth during sleep?
-I used to do it for a while but that was a time where I had many amalgam fillings
which actually were too high and by grinding at night, I would lower them and when they
fit, I stopped it again.
-How much salt she takes?
-Hardly any, less than normal.
-If it is a little bit than normal, she will leave the food, she will not eat it?
-I don't like it. I like to eat olives, they are supposed to be quite salty but
that's practically the only thing.
-Fruits she takes?
-Yes, I like very much.
-All kinds of fruits or sour or sweet fruits?
-All, I used to prefer more the sour and now I prefer more the ripe and sweet fruits.
-How much water she drinks?
-At least 1,5-2 lit.
-So she is thirsty. For cold water?
-No. Here I do drink water but at home I drink tea and I drink eat lukewarm.
-She prefers warm or cold drinks in general?
-Warm, not hot but warm.
-Her menses are normal?
-Yes but scanty.
-Before menses she is more depressed, more anxious, more crying?
-Not anymore. I used to have premenstrual syndrome with swelling of the breast but not anymore.
-Is she calm now as she gives her case?
Because she was very anxious before, she didn't want to do it. How is that she is so calm now?
-It's like that quite often with me. If I deal with something, with a situation or something
coming and I decide this is what you are going to do now, then I can go through this.
It's OK now.
The only thing I must think is that there is the entire class sitting there next door.
-She must not think about the class.
-She may not think of this that the entire class is sitting next door.
-What about if somebody consoles her, if he shows her tenderness, she likes it?
-I like it very much. I didn't use to, before when somebody was coming like that I didn't
want to accept it, I didn't believe him. But that's different now. I like it very much and I
actually have a longing for it now.
I've got still some short things.
I'm scared and frightened easily, if something happens.
-Startle. I've always had that.
I have a small myoma in my uterus and a couple of years ago I had a mastitis
which was operated.
And I had an operation on my thyroid, in German it's called the "cold knot" I don't know
the expression in English.
During that time I also had slight depression but after the operation I felt much better.
-Now with the depression, what she feels? She feels she wants to stay by herself, she
wants to isolate, she wants to cry, she wants to die and whether this has an hour which
is better or worse?
-Yes, there are times when it's better or when it's worse.
-What does she mean? Daytime or just a few days?
-Always a few days. The worst thing about the depression is that I couldn't get out of bed.
I had no energy whatsoever and I just told myself OK, just stay in bed, relax, maybe
you've been doing too much these past years and just stay and wait and it will go by.
The bad thing was that it did not go by, it stayed and often when I wake up in the
mornings I can just turn around and go back to bed again.
The worse part about that is that actually I want to open up my own practice and I want
to learn so much, I want to do so much and I actually can't.
Then the feeling is that if I can't do this, then I don't want to continue anymore and then
I also had thoughts of jumping from a skyscraper of something. From a high building.
Because I have no energy.
What I forgot to say is that there is no more energy and what she likes most she can't do.
That creates a deep sadness.
And what makes me so said is what I love most, which I used to love most, nature and
everything outside, is as if there is a veil between myself and nature and I can't get in
contact and I can't just open my heart, as I used to, and feel everything.
-When she was trying to get to see her, she was crying a lot.
They were telling me that she was crying.
Is she crying now? Or it just happened that she cried two days ago?
-I could say in the past two years, after I've started dealing with myself it's got a bit
easier, which does not mean it's easy.
For many years it was not possible at all but now
in these past few days in Alonissos, I have had states where I could cry.
I often had situations where I felt like crying and I wanted to cry but the feeling was as if
it was all cramped inside and it was difficult and then I immediately also told myself
come on stop self-pitting of yourself.
-Is she affected by heat or cold?
-I would never go to any winter holidays because I freeze.
After Kali carb. I did get a bit warmed, that was the reaction and I was very happy about that.
-What about her extremities? Feet?
-Icy cold.
-When she has meat with fat in it, she will eat it or not?
-I don't eat meat, very rarely.
-Is she vegetarian?
-Yes.
-Does she belong to a spiritual group?
-No. I just don't get anything from meat.
-But does she pray ever to god?
-Yes. For example before I begin a treatment but it's not like praying in a sense of
kneel down, it's just something I do.
-Is she constipated?
-No.
-She will be going 3 days without having outlet?
-Her nails are soft? Break easily?
-No, they have ridges.
-She perspires a lot?
-No but the odor of my perspiration has changed since Kali carbon.
-What it was and what it has become?
-Before it was more odorless and now I can sense when I'm perspiring but I can't
really tell you what it smells like.
-Does she perspire mostly on axillae or face or...?
-Axillae, under the arms.
-She never liked meat or now she has become more vegetarian?
-It was when the psoriasis started, I dealt with the issue and start reading and
thinking what could I do to improve it and one of the books said that it might not
be so good to eat meat.
-She used to like meat?
-I slowly left it away and now I have no desire at all.
-Eggs.
-Not at all. I don't eat eggs.
-Aversion to eggs. We got the symptom.
And if she sees somebody suffering, how she reacts?
She is affected or..? She is sympathetic?
-Yes, very. For example now when I work in the hospital and a child has to get an
infusion but I also work with my energies and often I succeed to calm the child down.
When I was a child, I was always carrying the handbags of some old ladies and
I always got engaged.
It's somehow that I have to pay attention but I don't put too much of that on myself
because then I can get to a point where I not only sympathize but I suffer along with
the people and so I have to find a point to say stop.
-Does she have any fears?
-In the depression phases, not this time but last time when I was in Alonissos, I could
not go into the ocean because I had fear of this dark water.
And another thing after watching the Hitchcock movie where the girl is killed through the
shower curtain with a knife, for years and years I was not able to take a shower without
having my head sticking outside the shower curtain, all the time making sure that there is
nobody coming and approaching me.
And as a child I had these dreams when I woke at night and screaming because I always had
this feeling that somebody is coming and is going to kill me with a knife.
And I stopped watching television for years now already because all this kind of movies
I cant' bear, I get so excited and so restless, I can not watch them.
But on the other hand, if there is an accident somewhere, I have no problem running
there and helping. That's a completely different situation.
-Now she is afraid in the dark at all?
-Not anymore. When I was a child yes.
-She is afraid of thunderstorms?
-No, I like them.
-As a child?
-Yes, as a child I had some fear.
-As a child in the dark she would see ghosts with her imagination?
-Yes and not only seeing, I also had the impression that I had been touched which led
to panic attacks.
-Was any time when she was anxious about her own health?
What about the health of her own child?
She is anxious about him, what is going to happen?
-I was always fear about others. For many years I had that, I was afraid that something
would happen to my parents and when they wouldn't come home, I was sitting at home
crying and be anxious and for many years also with my husband and I had it for
several years also concerning my son but that has got better now. Always fear for others.
-Now she likes to be by herself or she likes to be with others to communicate?
-At the moment I prefer more to be alone but if there is a person with whom I can have
a good quite talk, with whom I feel I'm accepted and secure, I like to be with.
-Is she very orderly?
-In the meantime yes, as a child no.
-Now very orderly?
-Not very.
I like to have things in order but I'm not very fastidious about.
-Fear of death?
-Concerning my own death I can't really say. What I experience is in the hospital
when a child dies and I'm with it when it dies, it's OK but if I leave the room and
shut the door behind me, then I would have to go back because I forgot something
or so then I'm afraid.
This is another case of Ignatia.
She comes there and she has depression and she is sighing all the time.
Who saw her sighing? The others did not see sighing.
This is a case of Nat. mur. Why Nat. mur?
This is a case of Staphysagria. Because she was suppressing all the time herself
she was doing everything for the husband, the husband...
-No.
-Be careful. Is this a case of Aurum?
-What about Pulsatilla?
-No.
-What about Palladium?
-Palladium?
-You will be surprised. What is the essence of Palladium?
The essence of Palladium, we have not spoken about but there are individuals
primarily who want appreciation. Appreciation is the matter with them.
They need to be appreciated and to be told. My parents do not appreciate me.
My husband does not appreciate me, my teacher does not appreciate me.
If anybody of you, you were Palladium, just say good words, they wait.
You are good, the blood pressure can go down, just one word, it's so important.
They have to be appreciated.
So when the main issue is, she comes there, she has a depression, she is crying,
you must take this case and then I see her there and I realize that the main issue
for her is the appreciation from the parents. It's a big issue.
-This sounds strange to me because when a child wants the love of his parents, wants a
word of appreciation, a word of acceptance, this is a natural process, even if he needed
for a long time and she needed it for a long time, you still think this is pathological.
-In Palladium we are talking about pathological condition, that means beyond the normal.
What you say is correct. You are not Palladium, so I can praise you.
What you say is normal, every child needs somebody to say good words but if your whole life
depends on that few words and you are sick because of that, then you are Palladium.
So actually she is Palladium or she was Palladium in the beginning of the evolution of the
case. The evolution of the case showed me that most probably the remedy that she will
need is Palladium. As the case evolved, did I have reasons to go away from Palladium
and to think of another remedy?
There was the time when I could not really pinpoint to any remedy, the possibility of
Pulsatilla with what she said, great need for consolation.
How many times you have underlined consolation? 4 time? Ah, twice.
-Also in favor of Pulsatilla she said her mood was changing from some...
so I put the Pulsatilla.
-But she has other symptoms of Pulsatilla also.
Put it there to see how many symptoms of Pulsatilla she has. Only 12 symptoms?
18 out of 28. Very good Pulsatilla case. Aversion to salt, consolation ameliorates...
Put 4 times consolation ameliorates. The way she said, how many times you underline?
Who underlined 3 times consolation? Who underlined it twice? Much less.
Who underlined it once? Nobody. OK it is 3 times, she said it quite strongly, you are
justified to underline it 3 times. She said it very strongly and if you underline it
and you put it in your repertorisation, you give it value.
-If you put in all the symptoms, more or less you come up with Phosphorus and with
Pulsatilla and what I don't like about it is that looking at her case, she somewhat gives
the impression of certain hardness, the sensitivity inside and the hardness towards
the outside. Also her feeling during childhood of being separated from the world
startling easily and also suicidal tendency and especially the aggravation in the mornings
I thought of Anacardium. Anacardium also has skin eruptions on the abdomen.
-The skin eruptions of Anacardium are usually with severe itching, more they scratch
the more... I have seen hysteria, this kind. I could not imagine her. She did not mention.
Anacardium has skin eruptions and the skin eruptions are terrible and it's a remedy
together with Rhus tox and Rhus venenata but what she said, the idea of the plug she
did not press it.
I don't even remember it but let us say, you are right but you had to pursue this idea in
case this lady was telling us that she could not really accomplish anything because she
would have no confidence in herself.
On the contrary, what she said is I establish myself in West Germany. I did this, I did that
I took classes, I worked, I did another job and my husband...
Even if the plug idea is there, then you have to go away from this idea.
What you say is very correct that outside she looks like Nat. mur.
Her look or the way she handled the situation was quite like Nat. mur.
That is how the Nat.mur. will give a case.
Even if they feel the pain a lot, they will not show it, they will not cry.
That's why I was wondering at a certain moment she is a Nat. mur. case?
Because she doesn't give out this pain which is inside, she kept it, she closed.
But I will tell you also that I never fix my mind, saying this is the remedy. Never.
That is why I make less mistakes than others who fix. This is the case blah, blah, blah.
I say yes, most probably. I came to analyze her case thinking of Sulphur.
In the process I see they are right, I change, I have no problem because you cannot
go against the truth and say my truth.
It's not your truth, you don't have the truth. Who knows exactly what is the remedy?
This is almost god given. To give the correct remedy out of these thousands it is like
the biggest present you can give to somebody.
You always stand with awe against the case and don't insist. Sometimes I see you insist
you press the point, it's good to press the point but then you give up also.
-Aurum muriat. she has depression?
-Aurum muriat. we have individuals that they have attempted suicide. Aurum muriat.
is one of the main suicidal remedies. That's one thing. She has not attempted suicide.
She has thoughts of suicide. The second argument is that she is not praying
in a pathological way, neither she is religious.
She is a person who is interested in spiritual matters, so she finds somebody who asks about life,
about death, about this and that about spiritual matters and she follows and then when I ask her
do you pray she answers, yes but in my way. She has a way of praying. What is her way of praying?
It is to meditate and to think please god help me, help me in this case or something like
that, this is not pathological praying. What is the idea of Aurum in praying?
You are in deep depression, that means you see nothing around you that you can hold
on, nothing, it is dark, it is stillness, it's like your heart feels like a steel,
it doesn't move.
Your emotions do not exist, you feel almost pain from depression and during that time
you see no way out, you are in a dark, total darkness, there is no a ray of light anywhere.
You can not see any light and then the idea comes, I just want to die and then before you
do that, it's like you have the last chance you hold from god and then you say, god help
me, god help me, they pray for 2 hours and that releases them a bit.
The tremendous pain which is there it is released, so it is a context under which they
pray, it is this deep depression that leads them to pray.
So therefore in the Repertory you will see it in capital letters and there in capital letters
you will see praying is Veratrum also but it's a totally different situation with Veratrum.
Veratrum does not pray because of the depression, it prays because of madness.
The mind has gone already beyond the normal, it's going to pathology as a person who
wants to save the world. The idea behind is that idea of the savior, that is why it says
in the book it preaches repent, repent ! He will go in the streets of Munich, he is finished.
Before that state there is a state where they will pray to save the world, they will pray for
others, it's different situation, they are in a manic state and they pray in such a way as
to save the world. Aurum prays to save himself because he knows the next step is
jumping from a high place, there is no way out, there is no way out.
It's very strange. I told you the case with the man who telephones and says, tonight
I'm jumping from the cliff, there is no way out, he has decided it. You give Aurum and
next day he says, I changed my mind. That means he was in an Aurum state, he would
jump. In the way Aurum was the case that we saw, he took the car, smashed against
the tree, no way, at that moment this is Aurum.
I have been given information, people like the doctor who ...
If you talk with them and say, what did you feel? They have described several times
they found themselves in a cliff, higher than this, in the roof of the building and suddenly
comes the idea and says, now it's your time, jump, jump, jump... it goes into a crescendo
and they jump because there is nowhere from which they can hold and Aurum will pray
under these circumstances and I do not get this idea with her. Therefore it is I would say
a different depression, a depression together with a kind of complaining, why my parents
never loved me, what is wrong with me? That was the case.
-I would like to say that she did not mention the plug in the breast. She said she had a
blockage and a difficulty to take large breath.
-A deep breath yes, that is what I say sighing. She said I have a shallow breathing,
this shallow breathing is characteristic of Ignatia, they feel they can not take
a deep breath and they breath on a certain level and the breathing can not really go down
and relax the organism.
But whether she said plug or not still in analyzing the case you have to find other
supportive symptoms for the case.
-I completely understood when you say my parents didn't love me and what is wrong
with me and that is why I think I always try to be better, to be good, to perform.
And I think I struggled all my life and now I reach the point where I can't just go on
fighting, there is no energy left.
There are many people who know me who say, why do you always make it so difficult for yourself?
And I always answer, I can't do it differently.
And I think this is what you perceived that from the outside I make a hard impression but
inside I'm very soft and this is the conflict.
-I also wanted to ask you about Phosphorus. Is it so far? Because when she came she
said, I can not breathe deeply, so a Phosphorus would say and she said about
clairvoyance and she said when I was a child I could talk to animals and plants.
So the question is, is Phosphorus for you very outside?
-But now she feels separated from nature. She has a blockage and she is separated from nature.
-I had Carcinosin one week in Germany and the teacher told us that first remedy when
children from the parents are not loved.
-Perhaps all this comes from misinformation and perhaps I'm responsible for the
misinformation. There are two types. One is the one that wants to please the parents.
Like Staphysagria, they don't care about themselves, they care only about the will of
others. They will do anything to please the parents.
And the other type is the opposite. They will just against anything that the parents will
say, like a bulldozer.
The one type is really thin, the other type is really fat and strong.
Whatever it's proposed, they go against. There are these two types.
The one type who tries to please is very nice person and tries to please.
Usually these children are loved by the parents. Carcinosin children I have not seen
a few times I have given...
The parents speak very well about these children, they are very good children, in school
they are excellent, they will be meticulous, they sit and prepare everything,
the parents do nothing, they are amazed, they say it's such a good child.
I say, I'll give a remedy and your child will not be so good anymore, have it in mind.
It doesn't matter because they feel something is wrong in this behavior.
So if I say children want to please the parents, then somebody may take it as that
the child wants to be appreciated, the child wants to be loved but the child is loved.
Here we have not the case. It is not this case.
I believe she did not do everything possible to please the parents, especially when she went
at the age of 17 and she had this affair her father as she said, now my father will kill me.
The Carcinosin child will not do that, will not do anything to displease the parents.
Anything. They will do things to please and the parents love these children because the
Carcinosin children are very high IQ. It's like the cancer, it's starting speeding up matters.
They are very intelligent.
The idea of Carcinosin was coming in the Repertory at a certain moment quite strongly
but I pushed it out for this reason, I did not see the predisposition in the family,
she did not mention, everybody dying in the family from cancer.
-Just to open the discussion a bit more. I have also seen that Carcinosin children do many things
to please their parents, almost like Nat. mur. has this fear of being rejecting
if they do not please. At the same time in her particular instance that I've seen this before,
if the parents are not forthcoming and responding to the child's desire to love because she has
such a strong experience and develops an independence, since there is no availability
on the part of the parents to give anything to the child, they become independent
and also dependent, depending which way it goes, on the parents or to respond in their
desire to please, then they will go off on their own independent way.
-But don't forget we are talking about pathology here and in these instances pathology
and natural reactions are intermingled. What I say, the child does anything to please
and not to be in stress in the environment. It's pathology, the parents perceive it
actually they say, the child is very nice. They give some direction to the child, the child
will follow the directions. This becomes pathology. The other one starts to be natural.
The child needs to react for a certain period of time, it needs to go out, you can't close
a child. The last case I remember it was a woman 17 years old, she never went out with
a boyfriend, only first in school, doing everything correctly, never had a boyfriend, never felt...
The mother was saying, she is too good. So you give the remedy and then the child
starts reacting, that is natural. It starts to be independent, yes of course.
Any child that will be suppressed in this way, naturally it will react, it will leave the house.
Especially in America, you know. Nobody stays. I went to a family with 6-7 children and
they were 2 left in the family, 1 was 11 and the other was 16 or 17 and as we discussed
I have this child, I have this child, what happened to the child? Gone, gone, gone all the 5
children were gone, 2 were staying. 1 was 11, very small and the other one and then I
hear the mother saying, I don' t know what is wrong. She wanted me to treat the child.
It was 17 years old and hasn't left the house. By that time it's not conceivable, 17 years
old you leave the house?
And she was complaining that something is wrong with this
child because it has not left the house. The others left it by the age of 14, 15, 16.
What happened to the others? The one got into jail because of drugs.
The other had 2 years without communication, the other...
That kind of society is creating some problems. You don't know where is the right and
where is the wrong. The child must stay with the family, this is correct, until it feels
naturally he must go out and work and support himself. But that's natural, the father
naturally helps the child and the child goes away.
In her case the pathology is that she has a wound because she felt my parents do not
want me and that is a real trauma in her life and there comes a time where she decides
I will do my part. I will love them, I will give them, I will hug them, see what happens.
And then she says, now I've done this, my parents respond better. This is not the
pathology of Carcinosin. She should have done this, as a Carcinosin child, long time ago
but now she is maturing and she does it out of maturity and out of mental decision.
That is not Carcinosin state.
Aurum, Nux vomica... Nux vomica is third in this repertorization. Is she Nux vomica?
How many symptoms she has? 20, Nux vomica has 20 symptoms.
Fear of water...she said dark water, don't put fear of water, it's not correct.
-I want to ask you if this that the extremities are cold, does this exclude Pulsatilla
from this case?
-No. She is freezing cold, she said I freeze, it's a very cold remedy, you have to find
a cold remedy. Pulsatilla sometimes is chilly but not in this way, not so strong.
The spiritual, we didn't go to these issues because they are difficult issues to be
discussed in public but I will tell you my perception from her, what was happening.
She goes into a spiritual group, she found some people interested in spiritual matters
and somebody suggests that if you go inside yourself, if you take that drug and you
discover things...
She has been suffering because of the life, parents and then the husband and she is
in a time of sensitivity where she tries to find a solution for her inner suffering.
Why do I suffer inertly? Why do I have that need that my parents will love me?
What is this? The hell with you...This is more or less the situation I perceive she is in.
The somebody says, take this and you will understand. It's like psychotherapists will
say, take lithium or valium and calm down your anxiety.
Instead of taking a drug of that type, valium, tavor, lithium or whatever, she takes this
drug. I don't consider it as pathology at this moment, that means a pathological drive
towards the spiritual and I consider it why?
Because when I enquire a little bit into the issue, she said this is gone, this is past.
I'm involved so much anymore. A person who has pathology, a Sepia will follow and
lose the energy, she will go into that, the idea of detachment, I want to detach, I don't
want to love anybody, I don't want to be connected and that is how it is produced the
state of detachment of Sepia, which I have been talking about.
With her feelings are strong and that's why the suffering is strong and with her also
we see the opposite, I want to love my parents in spite of that because she fought inside
herself to come to the point to say, in spite of the fact you have rejected me, you didn't
love me, you didn't give me tenderness, attention, I have to love you, I must love you,
I love you.
She has done some inner work inside to be able to reach that point where she can hug
the parents, I forgive you, it doesn't matter. Am I correct? She says, yes.
And then sexually, we didn't discuss her sexual desire but I can see it is OK, normal.
I would say normal, I didn't say anything.
-I was sitting yesterday for hours thinking about this case and turning it and looking at it
from different directions and I kept stumbling over this one symptom. She told that she
had been afraid of knives for years after watching the psycho film by Hitchcock
where the woman was stabbed through the shower curtain and now my question is
how do you judge this symptom in the whole context?
-Before let us see the evaluation of your understanding.
-What I had as a child also, it's more the fear of being murdered, I was always afraid
that somebody would come and murder me.
-And these dreams continued after that time but only the intervals got a lot larger.
They came like twice the year. It's more this maddening fear that somebody is going
to kill me, to murder me.
-But also she said that she can not see violence. When I ask her how much sympathetic
she was, she brought as an example the fact that she will not see television because
what she sees in television comes in her and affects her. The violence, she feels it inside.
-What I'm missing most is a kind of a place which is secure, which I'm looking in myself
and I can't find it, a place where I experience security.
People often have the impression that I have a lot of self-confidence which is probably
true to a certain extend but I, myself inside do not feel it.
And concerning the other question which emotions I like and feel strongest, I can only
answer all, I can feel everything from up and down, the whole range, I can feel very strong.
-OK, we analyzed this case as we do and we think about all these matters. We think as
the case goes by. You think is this? No. Is that? No, no, no, yes. This is how more or less
you are doing the inner repertorization, helped by the repertorization of course of the
Repertory. From time to time you look at the Repertory, fear of being murdered, I want
to look or different other symptoms and then finally something brings together the case
and you say now, what do we need to do with this case?
This case used to be a case of Phosphorus, it's obvious. As a child she had the fears
she had the mentality of the child, she would go to the parents to sleep with the parents.
She could not stay alone, she go to the parents and then she still in between them and
still is not secure, she sees the ghosts. Then she goes through life needing that affection
which she did not receive from the parents, then she attaches herself to the man she
married and then there is this divorce and then there is this barrier that comes.
The only question that we have to put once the case has progressed, the only question
is, does she need now another remedy and then Phosphorus or shall we go and give
Phosphorus straight away?
Why don't we go and give straight away, immediately the whole class...
Do you know why? Who can tell me why the whole class did not say after this taking of the case,
this is a case of Phosphorus? Do you know why? What has gone through as information
in your mind that stopped you from saying Phosphorus? Do you know what it is?
-She likes thunderstorms, she likes to be alone in thunderstorms and not complain.
-When this depression comes on, she goes to bed and rather not get up from bed and
then she also feels very difficult if she gets hurt, to close up,
so I think it must be Ignatia.
-Unrefreshed sleep. She goes and sleeps, she is very tired, she just wants to go back.
So she has a sleep which is unrefreshed, find me unrefreshed sleep.
This should not put you out of Phosphorus, she wakes up, she is terrible, she is
unrefreshed, it can not put you out but what put you really out of Phosphorus was when
I asked her, do you want cold drinks or hot drinks?
And she said, temperature. She said but if I had a choice, I would prefer to have warm drinks.
So cold drinks and what else, what was the information that came?
She did not say she loves to be alone, she said, sometimes I like to be with people but
sometimes also I like to be alone, correct?
Arsenicum very good is a possibility also, especially by the end of the interview.
I was putting some questions concerning Arsenicum to which she answered negatively.
You could take her as Arsenicum case because she is careful with her appearance.
You can take her and the freezing is there and the warm drinks is there.
How is her anxiety about her health?
-I think I paid attention to my health but not in anxious way,
I just did something to remain healthy.
What I do, which is not good for my health, is that I'm smoking right now and I would
imagine if I had great anxiety about my health, I would not smoke.
-Love thunderstorm is not only Carcinosin. You have to be careful about these symptoms.
A thunderstorm is a phenomenon which is enjoyed by many people. Not everybody is
Carcinosin but if during the thunderstorm you feel good, that can be Sepia,
maybe Carcinosin but don't pay too much attention to this.
Some ordinary symptoms of every day life, they have been recorded as symptoms of
Carcinosin and that's why in your repertorization Carcinosin will come again and again
and again. This is not so frequent. I have a student of mine who gives only Carcinosin
to everyone. He claims he has 80% cures. I mean it, really. He is not a student of mine.
That's wrong. He is the only Greek who says I'm not a student of George Vithoulkas.
He is supposed to have learned somewhere in Germany, only Carcinosin and it's finished.
It's very successful practice. I have another one, another student, he is really my student
who gives 60% of his cases, he gives Nat. mur. and a lot of them will feel better because
there is really quite a lot of grief, so Nat. mur. will release a little bit of that grief.
The question is that remedy unfolds, makes the case open? This is the question.
To make it a little bit better, to feel a little bit better, this is not the objective.
So we are searching for her because if you give to her Ignatia, she will feel better
for a while, a little bit more free, you give Nat. mur, also she will feel better.
Psorinum for instance just before the storm they feel great but really that symptom has
to be strong.
Show me the Repertorisation. Put aversion eggs, it has been added several remedies.
Pulsatilla has been added and Nit. acid was there originally, why they put my name there?
Nitric acid, Phosphorus, Sulphur and Ferrum and Kali sulph.
these remedies were original remedies...
For me the problem, as I took the case, the problem was, she was Phosphorus.
Definitely the way she described herself she had a Phosphorus layer and for me the
problem was is she continuing with the same layer or it has changed.
That was the main issue.
What Phosphorus symptoms continue until today as she relates. It's first of all the
sympathetic element, very sympathetic because the way she described it, if we put back
the video, you will see how she describes the sympathy for others, she can not tolerate.
She will feel herself. She used words that usually describe Phosphorus, that if they suffer
I feel the suffering in myself, I suffer the same. That is one strong point apart from the
depression. We have the depression, we have the morning aggravation of the depression
that's correct but we have this sympathetic element very strong that carries on the idea of
Phosphorus and the other is the aversion to eggs.
The way she described it, very strongly.
So these two symptoms, sympathetic and aversion to eggs give Phosphorus.
She was Phosphorus, now what prevents us from giving Phosphorus it was that the
quantity of liquid she needs is quite strong, there is no problem there.
What is the problem? When she says, I would prefer warm drinks. The freezing is in
favor of Phosphorus as well. Difficult of deep breathing, that's very interesting but
the fear of being murdered which again from a very young age, she has this symptom until today,
this is carrying again the idea of Phosphorus and then this,
I just saw it now difficulty to breath deeply.
That is something which puts the seal in her case and gives the solution, that symptom
that we just found. We have the carrying through of the same remedy, from the child
who is afraid in the night, she wakes up and sees all these ghosts and fears, she has to
be taken to the ... and feel a little bit secure.
She develops by her own will into something else and eventually she comes to the point
where she says, I have a barrier now. But I have discussed about the idea of Phosphorus
being a very sensitive Phosphorus, they don't want communication with others because
they feel so much the pain, they are totally isolated. I had described a case where she
stayed inside the house all the time, she would not go and buy something in the super
market because she would meet people there and she would feel the pain.
So Phosphorus can go to the other extreme as well that becomes isolated in order to
protect himself. For these reasons we have to give Phosphorus apart from the last
symptom, which I consider it a very important symptom because this is exactly what she
said, she had difficulty in taking deep breaths. She says my breathing is superficial which
explains it as an Ignatia symptom.
My god, why don't you put this? If somebody had opened the Repertory and looked at
these symptoms would not have the problems that we had.
I had a problem to come and tell you this is typical because you would jump on me.
-I saved you.
-Yes because when we come to the class and we discussed this case, she asked me what's this?
I said, typical Phosphorus, before we entered the class but then when I saw the reaction of the class
I said George go slowly.
But these two symptoms make a case, Phosphorus 10M.