-I just agree that I will go on with Lycopodium.
-Because you took the remedy and you thought the remedy was correct.
-Because I had less cough because I had coughing nearly all my life.
So it's still very little cough. At home this summer has been very warm, so no cold.
I think cold is worse for me.
-When there is cold it aggravates.
-Yes, cold draft.
-But still from January until today you have very little cough, the cough has improved.
-Yes, I had very much cough 1 year ago here, I had a lot of cough in May here.
-But you took a remedy before coming here...
-Yes in January.
-And when you came here we decided that the remedy was acting, you had to let it act.
-Yes because I stopped crying with the remedy.
-You stopped crying with the remedy and some other things had improved
and we decided not to give you another remedy, to continue with the same.
Now after May how is your chest?
-It's very good, just a little bit here when it's cold in the evening
and especially yesterday afternoon was lots of people smoking outside and it was
a little draft and I noticed a little bit.
-With the draft you feel more coughing?
-Yes, it's always like that but I was very thirsty.
-You were but now you are not?
-No, I drink maybe 8 lit of water when it's hot.
-In your country you mean?
-No, this summer I drink a little less but I drink a lot when it's hot.
But it's more less now this time, here. I drink maybe 3 lt.
-And you drink small quantities or big quantities?
-Big yes.
-So you are very thirsty still but less thirsty than a year ago or something.
-Yes.
-Thirsty for cold water?
-It was but it changed, not so more because I noticed that very cold water aggravates the cough.
-Cold and draft and cold water aggravates the cold.
-And tobacco smoke.
-How many years you had the cough?
-Since my first pregnancy and that is 27 years.
-And this is the first time that you feel better?
-It's periods all the time, it's not always but for months it could be every day, several months.
Before, some years ago it could be for several months. My first pregnancy I thought
I will lose the baby because I coughed and coughed and coughed. I had to hold myself to ...
-How do you feel otherwise?
-The last time I was very sad, a lot of sadness, depression because I break up a relationship.
It's better but it's still there.
-Do you sigh a lot?
-Yes, I think so.
-A lot?
-Sometimes yes.
-Do you cry or you can not?
-Oh yes, I can cry.
-How much you can cry? A lot?
-2 years ago when I first broke up, I had break up twice, I cried every day for half year.
I asked for this separating, we were not married but when he walked out from the house
I started crying. I knew I will do that.
-So that means you sent him away but you still loved him?
-Yes.
-And when he left, then you started loving him even more.
-Yes. The first time and maybe this time too but little less because I tried to work
with it all the time but it's still very hard.
-Did you take Ignatia before?
-I don't think so.
-You never took Ignatia?
-No.
-Nat. mur?
-One time before Lycopodium.
It was a clever person saying to me take one dose Nat mur before you start Lycopodium.
-What potency was the Nat mur?
-200.
And that man said I should take it for 5 days one dose every day but I don't think I took it.
I took 2-3 doses.
-Did you feel any effect from Nat mur?
-I just wait so little after it, so I'm not sure but I did a mistake in August. I should take
something for my knee, I was walking in the mountain and something happened,
I don't know why.
-In your knee?
-Yes, in the left knee.
Before if it was something, it was always the right knee. Something starting and I should take Ruta
and by mistake I take Causticum and in 2 minutes I feel so sad. Everything was heavy,
I lost all my energy, everything was real bad.
-Did you know it was a mistake already?
-Yes.
-When did you realize it was a mistake?
-Right after because I had some small marks in the acute.
-So immediately after taking you say, I made a mistake that I took Caust and then you took Ruta?
-When I came home. I wait.
-And then you became sad?
-I was sad. The sadness stayed.
-So you are still in that sadness?
-I take Lycopodium again.
I had to take it because I couldn't stand the situation.
-And Lycopodium helped you this time?
-Yes, it helped me but I feel always I had to repeat it quite often.
-How many times you have to repeat it?
-Sometimes it works for 3-4 weeks but sometimes I have to take another one in 1 week.
I have done that. I have taken up to 10.
-10M?
-Yes the last one was 200.
-And then down again to 200.
-Yes.
-Except of this sadness is anything else at this moment that is bothering you
and a little bit of cough?
-Bad sleep. Sometimes it's quite good. It's periods.
-It varies.
-Yes.
-Your mood is always sad or it can change?
-It changes very fast.
If I have good time, company, everything is OK.
-And then back again?
-I don't like to be by myself.
I would wish I would like it more because it's a big problem for me to stay in a big house alone.
-With children?
-They have grown up.
-They left the house. They don't live in the same house with you?
-No.
-So why you sent this man away? Why you tell him to go?
Because he didn't want to marry you officially?
-No, no, no.
He is 11 years younger than me and his mental state was different.
I want everything and he wants nothing. He just watches television and work, so we can't talk.
-He was working this man?
-Oh yes he works very much.
-And then comes home and sees television, that's all.
-Yes or work in the house.
-As well. So? I don't understand still why you ... since you liked him.
Did he get another woman, did you find out that he was going with another woman,
did you tell you that he wanted to leave?
-No, but we were quite agreed that we weren't alike.
-Mentally you were different?
-Very different.
-He was very untidy?
-No, in a way too tidy.
-He seems to be the perfect man, why you ...? I don't understand.
Inside you, you were afraid you would get hurt one day because he was younger and then you said
it's better to send him away now because I don't suffer later on?
-Maybe. Because in the beginning, 10 years ago, he was just 24 and he had no children
he had not been married, I had been married twice with children, a small grand child.
So 10 years ago I didn't want this but it started and in between I go back with another man.
I lived with another man for 10 years and I go back to him and married him.
Nearly 2 years we were married.
-2 years ago you were married?
-No, it was 8-9 years ago and this last man, the young one...
-You met this man, you let him one time, you managed to leave him one time,
you got married to another man, then you went back to him?
-No. I lived with another man for 10 years.
-Before him or after him?
-Before.
And we break up and I met this young man in the mean time and I go back to the other again
and marry him.
-To the first one.
-Yes but I liked the young one better but the other was more safe and he was very sad.
-Then you left him again and you went back to the young man again, correct?
-Correct.
-And then you stayed with him 2 more years.
-No, we lived together 2 years, we started living together after that for 6 years.
-And then you decide if I stay with him, he is going to leave me one day
and then I'm going to feel very hurt?
-Maybe but we had been so very unlike people, we have the sensitive, we have the love that stuff.
-You mean the erotic was good but mentally you felt it's different.
He was irresponsible, he was young, he would have another affair one day and then...
-Yes, I feel maybe he needs to have children.
-I see now.
Do you eat fruits?
-No, I like it in a way but it aggravates me very much, bloated but after Lycopodium
the bloating is much better. Before I had bloating with other food, with milk products
I can't take them. Still I cant' take them I can take a little bit.
-How much do you need sweets?
-No, I like the spicy.
I like the smoked salmon, especially with mustard sauce and I like other smoked things too
but I don't eat pork.
-Why?
-I don't eat pork anymore.
-Why? For religious reasons?
-It was for health.
I had some pain in the joints and somebody told me don't eat pork, so I stopped eating
and my ex-husband was nearly a vegetarian, he didn't eat pork.
So it was 2 reasons but I like smokes and I like olives. I love the Greek salad,
there are lots of olives and onion. I like all kinds of onions.
-Onions do not bother you?
-Yes before but it's better.
-Not so much now.
If you wanted to describe yourself now, what would you say, how you would describe yourself?
-I feel I'm quite open person, I like to talk to people but in a way I'm a little timid too.
It's better if people start talking to me first but I think I'm quite open and social.
I can talk a lot, if we start, I can talk about everything.
I had great desire company when I was a child too, I haven't sister and brother
and my mother was quite sick and I used to go to the neighbor to eat because there was a lot of children.
-So you always liked being with others.
-Yes being in a big family.
-How much salt do you need now?
-Actually I don't think it's just the salt, it's more the spicy.
But I like salty things too.
-Are you afraid of anything? You have any fears?
-A little bit claustrophobia.
-Dark?
-No, not anymore but I'm quite restless in a way.
Before when I was sitting in the course
I was with the legs... but after Lycopodium it's better and I'm in a way more lazy.
-When you have this sleeplessness, it is the whole night that you can not sleep
or you sleep and you wake up, sleep and wake up?
-No, sometimes I could not fall asleep but more often is that I fall asleep and I wake up too early,
4-5 o'clock but it can be to 2-3.
-Your feet in bed can become very hot and you have to stick them out?
-No, maybe some years ago.
-If you go for high place on 10th floor and you look down, do you have a kind of vertigo?
-Yes but not very big.
-Are you tidy now in your home or you are too lazy, you just leave things around, you are sloppy.
-No, but I'm not too tidy, I'm normal.
My papers can be a little mess, I'm not so strict with the papers. OK the papers for the patients
but my own papers is not. But I have big desire to travel, if that means something.
-You like it very much?
-Yes, I would like to travel along for a little while. With few friends, maybe a boat,
here in Greece, Caribbean.
-But travelling is a big thing for you? You always wanted to travel?
-Not always but I want to do something. I'm quite active. I don't sit down.
-But why you say you became lazy?
-Because it's little less restlessness. It's less.
-Restlessness is not laziness. Laziness is you don't want to do. It has nothing to do.
You can be very restless and very lazy.
-OK.
-It's not the same thing.
-I don't think I'm lazy.
-When you cry now, you can cry in front of others or you need to be by yourself?
-I can cry in front of others but I try to stop it. But I'm much better now than half a year ago.
-What about the temperature of your body? You are more cold, more hot?
-More to the hot.
I'll be cold if somebody argues with me and then I argue with somebody, I get very cold.
-Your nails are strong?
-Yes, normal.
I somehow can feel the coolness, I could be very cold, the skin can be very cold in the evening,
I take no dress on because I feel warm. Others tell you are so cold, I didn't notice in a way.
-The body feels cold but you don't feel cold.
-Not much and I always before, I do it still but less, I had to take a cold shower
after the usual shower. In the end I had to let the water ice cold.
-And you enjoy this?
-Yes because if I don't do that, I feel clammy and warm, not feel refreshed
and I could go to sea water in very cold.
-You go to the sea water now?
-Yes.
-It's good?
-Yes, I can have it less hot, it's OK.
-How you feel in the sea?
-I love the sea, I love to be under the water.
-But you feel refreshed?
-Yes, very refreshed.
-Do you feel better in the morning, evening, night.
-If I'm by myself I'm quite tired in the evening, I'm awake in the morning if I have
a good night sleep. Usually all the years I've been an early one, early in the morning
it's good if I have a good sleep.
-So at this moment in general I feel you are quite good, why you should take another remedy?
-No? OK? Maybe I am.
-You are quite good and you don't have something bothering you at this moment.
The bloatedness is better, the coughing is better, you are not crying so much.
-The sleep is not so bad but I had to tell you I started a remedy in January and
sometimes I take a little coffee too because I was tired in the morning.
-Perhaps that's why you had to repeat the remedy so many time because you should not take coffee,
otherwise you will have to repeat the remedy too much and try not to repeat the remedy.
Try to stay away but stay away from coffee also.
-What was the problem that you came?
-The problem was the cough, the main problem is the cough but I already took Lycopodium by myself,
you didn't tell me.
-You had taken by the time you came here and so we said we see what Lycopodium is doing
and then we decide. Now I remember.
So you took Lycopodium up to 50M but you think it's no effect.
-No and with the 50M the mental state was very bad. I had to take a strong cup of coffee to antidote
and I feel ameliorated.
-Tell me again the main problem. Coughing and dyspnea?
-Coughing and always bad colds. I get it all the time and I have high fever
and I feel I have high fever all the year, sneezing, sometimes watery, sometimes mucus,
abstraction all the time, hoarseness, everybody asks you had a bad cold?
-Without fever or with fever?
-Not very seldom fever, without fever.
-Never you have fever?
-If I get a flu I can have some fever but very seldom.
-And you think it is hay fever or you think they are repeated colds one after another.
-Maybe it is hay fever.
-And the symptoms are, you wake up in the morning, just describe to me the symptoms.
-I go out of bed and then I start coughing.
-Not sneezing?
-After a while.
-But you go out of bed and you start coughing immediately? Or after 5 minutes?
-Sometimes. It's not that always, I'm a little bit better and the cough does not stay so long,
some weeks, maybe a little amelioration and then I get a bad cold, it starts
in the throat too sometimes and it goes always easily to the chest.
Before I came here it was so dry in a way, it changes a little bit, it was so dry that
I could hardly breathe during the night but when I get here I got something from a friend with herbs
for the chest and it helps.
So I got much mucus now and it speeded up that loosening but I got some mucus when I'm here.
-And you have taken Tuberculinum also in the past?
-Yes I have and it has done a lot for me.
-What potency?
-Up to 10M.
-Which was the remedy that helped you most?
-I think for the hay fever Tuberculinum helped me most but Lycopodium too and
sometimes Phosphorus helped me very much the spring time and I was taking this hay fever again.
And I'm very sensitive to all external, odors, painting the house, some bad smoke,
tobacco and tobacco and cold draft together is the worse. Warm drinks ameliorate
and some liqueur always.
-Like sweet alcohol.
-No, coniac.
I don't like sweet so much. Sometimes I decide for a chocolate and I can eat the whole plate
but it's not.
-Do you desire smoked food?
-Smoked fish it's better because I didn't eat pork and ham, bacon.
-Why you did not eat?
-Because 15 years ago I had some pain in my joints and I decided to not eat pork
and it's gone away.
-The desire is not there?
-If I smell the bacon I like it very much and I like the taste but I don't eat it.
But smoked fish and salmon yes.
-Onions?
-Yes very much. And before it aggravated me, now it's better.
-Now if you eat onions you feel better after eating onions?
-I like it, I like the Greek salad with the onion.
-In general you feel cold or hot?
-In general I feel more warm but I can get cold.
If I have an argue with somebody I get very chilly, I can't get warm again and sometimes
if I have bad cold and this winter I've been little more chilly because I didn't open the window
so much at night and I take an extra blanket and during the day time I use some wool shocks.
Cough better warm drinks yes. I can't drink any cold with the cough.
-And then you are coughing, coughing in the morning and then what happens?
-It changes very much. I can cough all time but I don't do it all the time. I was just before.
-When you will cough? If you run or if you lie down?
-Before it was worse to lie down in bed at night and still is but it's not so much. It can be.
Cold draft I think is the worse and some odors, perfume or tobacco smoke and the
sneezing too, there is sneezing of perfume and smells. If somebody has too much perfume
or smoke I sneeze.
-Do you have any fears you would say?
-No, very little fears.
-Are you bloated? A lot of bloatedness in your stomach?
-It's better, having a lot before because I was more constipated before
but after trying to not have milk products, I try to avoid that, it's better.
-Milk product made you bloated.
-Yes and fruits too and heavy food and sweet.
-And you avoid, so you are...
-I try to avoid.
Some days here in Alonissos I have bright red blood in my stool.
-You had blood in your stool?
-Yes.
-Red blood?
-You have hemorrhoids?
-No, never.
And a little strange because I have something in upper duodenal, some induration or some hernia
or something I noticed some weeks ago and I've taken an ultra[sound]...
not X-ray the other one where you are looking to... So they want me to take X-ray and
I do it 2 days before I come here, so I don't know the results.
But I have been very worried about my son because he has been sick for so long time.
So maybe it's something that has to do with that, I don't know. And he had the same.
-Cough?
-It was not main problem but he didn't tell me. He had the same red blood in stool
and he had it for half a year and after that I get more worried.
I'm quite depressed but I was more 1 year ago but it's still very much and I have sleeplessness,
if I wake 3-4 in the morning, the sadness is worse.
-What time is the sleeplessness?
-For half a year I sleep 3,5-4 hours during the night and it doesn't matter if I go to bed at 11
or 12 or 1 it's exactly the same hours. But for 2 months ago it's a little better.
I can sleep 5 hours and sometimes 6.
-So your sleeplessness is exactly you go to bed, you sleep 5 hours and then you wake up
or you sleep 2 hours, you wake up, then you sleep another 2 hours?
-No.
-What happens? Tell me exactly.
-Exactly it's always 3,5 - 4 hours.
-That's not what I want. What time do you go to bed?
-10 or 11.
-So you sleep 3 hours, that means 2 o'clock you wake up.
-3 o'clock.
-After 3 can you sleep again?
-No.
-So you have sleeplessness after 3. You can not sleep anymore.
-No. But it changed a little bit the last 2 months. So I can sleep little longer sometimes.
-When you go to bed you sleep straight away or you remain, you think and think
for half an hour and then?
-Yes I do that too.
-And what do you think when you are in bed?
-Worries?
-Only worries or you think something unpleasant.
-Yes sometimes, in the morning it's never pleasant.
-In the morning you have depression.
-I have to get up and do something.
I feel from beginning of December 1997, I feel the remedy Lycopodium didn't work anymore.
I had lots of anticipation before Christmas because I don't like to be alone and Christmas time
is the time that you are going to be with family. So I get very depressed I don't like
to be alone but if you give me the right remedy, maybe I'll be more independent.
-If you are angry you have chill?
-Yes very chilly.
-She feels cold.
-Chilly all over after I get angry with somebody, quarrels.
-Are you irritated easily?
-Before I was more irritated easily in a way yes but I have lots of suppressed anger I think
and not so good in...
-In attacking?
-To say what I want, I please too much all the others. So if I live with a man, I always want
to please and after some time I get very angry and one time I throw all the stuff in
one room on him. He think I was crazy.
-But did you hit him or you missed all?
-The soft things. And one time a cup of tea but it was not really hot.
After I feel very stupid or bad, I think.
-You were out of control.
-And I always feel very lonely in a way and that thing maybe is because I always had to be alone
when I was a child.
I had to take care by myself because my mother was always sick and I had to clean the house,
I was 6 years old and I had to do a lot of things and my father was busy, he had a shop
and he had no time for me. He was that kind of man that if I go and hug him in the evening
saying good night, he seemed embarrassed, so I stopped that and my mother tried to take off her life
since I was 14 but she didn't make it.
I was 15 and she died from cough because she always coughed and coughed and coughed,
sitting up in the night in a chair and after all these years I didn't think she could
make it anymore, so she died and after that my father nearly died when I was 16.
He was in the hospital for 2 months, I had to take care of the shop alone, I was 16 years old,
so I had always a lot of responsibility, too much.
So I always feel I have to take care of people and stuff like that.
-You have desire to travel you said.
-Yes.
-You like to travel very much?
-Yes very much.
But in a way I don't travel so much as I want because I don't want to travel alone.
I used to be very hurry but I'm a little less hurry now but I'm still quite restless
and it's very sad if I sit down, I have to be occupied in a way.
If I'm alone I have to be occupied and I'm quite fast, I walk fast, I write fast.
The only fear I have is be in public, I hate that and I'm quite timid person. I don't like
to start a conversation.
If I know somebody very well it's OK, if somebody sit down and starts talking to me it's OK.
-Do you get headaches at all?
-No.
I can from the sun if I don't wear a hat or if I had to drink quite a lot, if I don't do that
I get headache.
And I have to take bath all the time in the sea because it's too warm in the sun.
I hate driving in a very warm car. I love the heat for the feet but not for the head.
So I have to open the window or take off the heat and it's very strange because I can sitting out
in a cold evening without clothes but sometimes I'm very cold and I haven't notice,
other people notice it. I don't notice it in a way.
-You don't notice you are getting cold.
-You don't feel it. If you eat fruits you will have a lot of gas?
-Yes.
-Bloated?
-Definitely?
-Yes.
-How much do you underline this?
-3 times, especially grapes and sometimes an apple makes me sneezing and sometimes not.
I think it's the hay fever, sometimes it's another apple or something stuck on it.
I'm allergic to cats but I have a cat, I had it for 14 years and I'm better than before
but I think he is a problem but I hate to take him.
-You don't dislike cats?
-No. I love cats very much.
-And dogs also?
-Yes, I like them.
-You are not afraid of dogs?
-No.
It's OK?
-It's never OK, we will see the action of ...
-So I don't need to add something?
-Why do you say?
-If I should wait for you.
No, I think it's OK, that's the most of it.
With the hay fever many years ago I had pain in legs and this pain was back again.
It was a little bit strange but I think it's OK.
What's your decision in this case? Just tell me the remedy?
Tuberculinum, another one? Calcarea carbonica, another one?
Tell me some remedies.
Bryonia and China, another?
-Lachesis or Tuberculinum.
-Nux vomica.
-Pulsatilla.
-Staphysagria or Nat mur.
-Phosphorus.
-It's not clear. The case is not clear.
In such a case where the case is not clear, you will expect to have a series of remedies.
You can't do it with one remedy.
You are expecting now to have a series of remedies with careful prescribing,
the first prescription is careful. If it acts, then it will change whatever changes
and then you get the second remedy which is better.
Who wants to talk?
-If a series of remedies is needed I think the group of health,
vitality can not be very strong.
-In this case I tell you what has happened. The group is not very low.
It's the second group here but the problem is too many remedies have confused the case.
Therefore we have to deconfuse the case, you are expecting the same condition with Picric acid,
we start with Picric acid, then Ignatia, then etc. It is the 4th remedy.
Once you have taken a series of remedies which have not solved the problem, then there is confusion.
The side effects of homeopathic remedies is to modify the symptoms.
It's not the side effect can cause some kind of damage but they modify the symptoms
and nobody can find the right remedy.
This is the side effects of wrong prescription.
So in this case you see it is difficult and therefore we rely heavily on repertorization.
Here are 17 symptoms, how many symptoms you put?
17 OK.
Show me flat repertorization. Nux vomica, Arsenicum, China, Sepia, Bryonia, Aconitum
Pulsatilla, Alumina, Sulphur, Calcarea, Phosphorus.
All these remedies and then the Expert System says what?
Explain why. China has the dry cough, it has it on 3rd degree, you see? Strong.
The dry cough after rising it has it on 2d degree. Sensitive to odors, tobacco.
China is not sensitive to odors. Cough from draft of air, abdomen flatulence from fruit.
She is the only one, blood in stool, sleeplessness midnight after 3 a.m. and timidity.
These are the symptoms where Nux vomica covers more symptoms definitely.
No, Nux vomica does not cover more symptoms. How many symptoms were with China?
-9 also.
-Bryonia is... Where is amelioration with warm?
-Nux vomica has it. Amelioration warm fluids.
-In a hurry. She is in a hurry? Very much.
Bryonia dry cough, warm fluids ameliorate, sleeplessness night after 3, chill after anger.
This is important for Bryonia but what is against Bryonia in her case?
She needs company. Bryonia does not need company.
She will not stress that point usually, maybe.
Did you put all this? Put it desires company, underline it twice.
No change, Nux vomica, Aconitum, Ignatia, Bryonia, Arsenicum...
So my first prescription will be China to see if it will move the case and in case not
then the second remedy will be Tuberculinum, again Tuberculinum higher potency.
-What about Pulsatilla?
-Pulsatilla no.
-Carcinosin?
-No, I don't see.