-The proof now of whether we are right or wrong of course will be after we give the
remedy, in a few days. We'll see what happens.
But what is important for you to understand is, since you came to learn from me
is how am I thinking.
There are two ways of taking down a case where you are blank and you start
asking all the questions in the Repertory.
2531 questions and carefully you write down all the answers.
What I want you to note down is usually when we teach we say, don't guide your questions.
Let the patient fill you with information. And then you make a decision.
In practice, if you know enough, is different. Taking the case when you know enough
you don't waist your time into searching all kinds of questions under the earth.
If this case was brought to me as a paper case, I would not be able to make
head or tails, why? Because of so many questions and so many answers where the
essential things would not be there. They would not come out.
It is important for you, when you take a case, to have the essential things come out.
The real things, mentally- emotionally. Maybe sometimes it's only physical symptoms that
you have. Sometimes you have a combination.
Sometimes you have more mental and less physical.
You are interested in the truth. You don't make up the cases.
You saw how I changed my mind? Vacillated, this is not, let me investigate now Lycopodium etc.
She gave me symptoms of Lycopodium- Lachesis, Lycopodium- Lachesis constantly.
So what is the remedy? You study and in the evening you come and bring me your answer.
And say according to me, this is the remedy.
I give the remedy, I will not tell you anything, we'll see after a few days.
You just keep back your thoughts. Now here is the courageous one.
Don't give her ever Lycopodium.
-I want to give Lycopodium because the sciatica was right sided and lying on the
painful side it is getting worse and she said she has a despair recovery and my
observation when she came in was that she decided to take a deep breath.
So I used that rubric and you said lying on the knee-elbow position makes it better.
-Knee-elbow position how did you find that Lycopodium was better in knee-elbow
position? Show me the Repertorisation.
-It's general, lying knee-elbow position ameliorates.
-So for Lycopodium there are more symptoms in favor of Lycopodium.
Let's see from the beginning.
Sciatica right side, sciatica worse lying on the painful side, sensitive to clothing on the
abdomen, back pain lumbar region extending to feet, sacral region extending to feet,
which is combined of course, one symptom.
Then ailments from grief, jealousy, only one, thirst for small quantities.
Here the main points which are in favor of Lycopodium will be right side sciatica
lying on painful side worse plus the drinking of the sips of water and the desire for
sweets that has increased the last few months.
This will be in favor of Lycopodium and you can give Lycopodium and you will get good marks.
You pass.
One leg hot and the other cold also is in favor of Lycopodium.
Warm ameliorates also is in favor of Lycopodium.
You give Lycopodium first and see what happens.
-I just thought that Lachesis is not under the rubric sensitive to pain, so Lycopodium is there?
-Lachesis suffers more. In the suffering, when you see the suffering of Lachesis
suffering is more than Lycopodium.
-I would prescribe Lachesis because of a couple of observations.
First it is that she seemed to me highly possessive of situations, of partners, of things
like that. Second I acknowledge that she thought she was very nervous, she was
suffering a lot, she was walking in one leg and she started to talk and talk and she got calm.
So I took the modality of discharges ameliorate. And in my opinion, talking is a discharge.
The other thing is that she suffered disappointment, very high emotional disappointment.
I based my information on that.
-I have to make an observation concerning your remarks.
That she did not talk like Lachesis.
When you have a real Lachesis loquacity, she will not stop talking.
You just manage to put one question, how are you and the rest is for her.
There is no chance for you asking a second question. That is the typical loquacity of
Lachesis and when you see it how she jumps from one subject to the other, then she
goes there and then she goes to that and then to the husband and to the father, to the
son, then to the mother and then goes back again to previous lives etc.
And then you sit back and you say, I don't need anything more, this is Lachesis.
But the loquacity is of that order and then you say this is loquacity.
Was she loquacious? I will not put her as a symptom, loquacity.
Concerning your other remark possessive yes. Strong.
-First of all I would like to say the pain, I've seen in her such pain that you don't have to
go to the rubrics of very sensitive to pain to either confirm or eliminate it was severe pain.
And second when she was into amateur dramatic on the stage. She was very good at it
very natural and she has a passion, she is a passionate person I think.
-She is a passionate person. You see why we had a problem?
Because she is a passionate person, she says sex I enjoy, I still like this man who was
biting me and all that and I did not go with another man.
She wants sex, she talks with her friends, she says I miss sex.
Yet she will not say, forget it I need some outlet which is in favor of Lachesis and against Lycopodium.
Yet the one feet cold and the other hot is in favor of Lycopodium and against Lachesis.
She has no disturbance in the stomach abdomen where you expect that it will be the
weak point of Lycopodium.
Abdomen full of gas, stomach burping, you don't see this.
But is it possible the idea now Lycopodium and later on perhaps Lachesis?
We are scientists. We want really to find the exact situation.
That is what is important because if we make a mistake, OK you give Lycopodium and
then you give Lachesis, what is there?
You can do this also, it's not a big deal. Why should we discuss so much about it?
But this is how you are learning. This is what you came here to learn.
To learn to differentiate exactly on this problematic situations and how am I thinking
and what am I thinking? So you can get the ideas.
-I thought that she is Lachesis constitutional person but when you asked her about
her jealousy, she remembered when her husband gave a kiss in a bar, years ago.
That came up in her head at this moment and you can see a lot of things have changed.
She has developed acutely Lycopodium situation where some points are coming but
still the bloating is not there. I think eventually it will come too but when you take the
Lycopodium acute situation away, I think she needs Lachesis afterwards.
-My problem is that the sciatica is more of the Lachesis type.
I mean the acute situation as pathology it fits Lachesis and not Lycopodium so much.
It fits more to Lachesis the acute situation because Lachesis is characteristic that it is
right side and goes right down to the foot.
So she mentioned immediately some Lachesis symptoms as far as the acute concern.
Is Lachesis left sided? Yes but not in sciatica. Let's clear this.
When we say a remedy is left side or right side, we must be careful not always blindly think this way.
Because in sciatica actually Lachesis is a very painful sciatica situation.
Kali iodine, Lachesis and Colocynthis are the three remedies which are suffering a lot
with sciatica. I don't know why but the pain is really tremendous and when you see
you think this is Kali iodine or this is Colocynthis or is Lachesis. They suffer.
What was interesting in this case is the moment when, do you remember when she
calmed down? Who can tell me?
The pain calmed down when she spoke about a specific thing that came out.
-Her relationship with her husband?
-No. The relationship with her sister. She spoke about this relationship and after coming
out all that I noticed that she was not so much in pain anymore.
Therefore I suspected that this is again a jealousy situation between herself and her sister.
Now her father came later on and he said, that is true. I don't remember if you said it
to the class? Yes you said it to the class.
-I would like to hear your comment on another suggestion.
Yesterday Ernest asked to check her case acute, if we could something quickly.
We had no books, no computer but we got some other information than you got.
We asked about what happened before the sciatica and what her opinion was of what
should have caused it. Of course she mentioned the bad relationship and the fighting and
all that but also she mentioned she had a fall on her coccyx and she also felt that it might
have started there. That with all the modalities of the sciatica which was resembling
Rhus-tox but it was right sided and she also expressed a lot of guilt about how she raised
her child and a definite feeling of she had done wrong.
Taking that into consideration we thought about Ruta which she just got this morning in a 30.
My way of thinking is first she got an aggravation and then perhaps later on during
your interview an amelioration.
Also during the aggravation the pain killers which she used help her, didn't work.
What do you think about Ruta as acute?
-Ruta has been given.
-Only this morning, not before.
-Well I will tell you. When she felt the amelioration, she felt it while sitting, with no move.
So Rhus Tox is out.
In order to have an effect from Ruta, I did not see how this case could fit to Ruta.
I do not see it at all but as aggravation I don't see it either because she was constantly
in that situation. She said I'm in that situation for the last two months.
It's not a matter of today she was aggravated. It is for the last two months. I don't see it at all.
-What happened after Ruta? She said she had a terrible aggravation after Ruta.
So she tried to take pain killers and they didn't work as they used to.
-The pain killers she said, she had to wait for 6 hours. I mean she can not take a
pain killer after 3 hours again and this is what she knows she could not do.
This is the usual situation where the pain killer can make her rest for a while and then
the pain comes. So this is the usual situation. It's not different today than the other
days, as I understand.
If I don't have enough symptoms for one remedy or another remedy...
Here we have more than enough symptoms for both remedies.
In your question you say, if you don't have enough symptoms, yes I will look for a small remedy.
Here we have strong symptoms for Lachesis and quite strong symptoms for Lycopodium as well.
What is interesting is she says, the last few months I have developed a desire
for sweets which is very strong Lycopodium symptom.
Can you ignore it? This is the question and on what strength you may ignore it
because you may have to ignore it one or the other.
The remedy which is going to act is one or the other. It's not both at the same time.
You have to decide this is the remedy which is going to act.
-What about the clothing around the waist? Lycopodium is there as a capital.
I can't see why we can't give Lycopodium.
-I will tell you what is the problem. As a constitution this girl is Lycopodium?
You ask yourself and then you ask as an acute is Lycopodium?
So there are two different questions.
First answer the question, is this a constitutional Lycopodium case?
-No.
-The answer is no. You go now to the acute. As an acute it can be Lycopodium?
-Of course.
-And you say yes. You go to Lachesis now and you ask the question again.
As a constitution this can be Lachesis?
-Yes.
-And as an acute it can be Lachesis?
-So what prevents you from giving Lachesis is desire for sweets.
-And the coldness, heat ameliorates.
-Try to find worse cold.
What is impressive in this case is a point which you have not take it inside.
It is when she says all these things, all this came out, the father said for the first time
I heard all this, I did not know anything.
When it came out, then there is a relief of the pain, this is very important because the
aggression kept inside, I hate him. You didn't register, she said, I hate him.
I had a passionate relationship with him but he let me down, he bit me.
Still I like him. And then I can not touch here, don't touch me here, I can not  put anything here.
This is exactly what I said when I was taking the case. These are complementary.
This is what I'm thinking, first Lycopodium and then Lachesis.
What did I do? This, what you decide to do, is finally very important.
You balance the things.
A very strong sensitivity in the throat.
-So you give Lachesis.
-She has no fear of being alone. When she is in pain, she needs somebody of
being around, it's not a fear of being alone.
She said, when I feel well I don't need anybody. This is not fear of being alone.
-But she said she has fear of being alone now that she didn't have her husband and
she was alone with the child.
-It's because of the responsibility.
-She meant something else. Fear of being alone in life. This is different.
Lycopodium is different, it's pathology. What she says, it's a natural thing.
Now I don't have a husband, I have to work and I have a fear of what am I going
to do in life, who is going to support me?
-But he didn't support her.
-Let me explain to you. The pathology in Lycopodium is when without any reason
you feel of being alone. When I'm alone here suddenly .... in the room alone.
In the house alone. But if I have even a child it's OK, it's a comfort.
The other what she said, I have a fear of being alone in life, not in a room or in the house.
Because she stays alone now in the house.
So shall I tell you what I gave?
Lachesis.
I gave Lachesis high potency 10M because I felt from the story that she is telling
me that the emotions that she had once she expressed them, she was relieved.
Expressing, the observation that somebody did, with discharges Lachesis feel better.
She has to discharge, she has to bring out the turmoil which is inside and that turmoil
with Lachesis is really aggressive. It's like, as I said, Colocynthis, Kali iodinum
Nux vomica has that kind of state, which I perceived in her.
Aggressiveness, the feelings that they were inside were pushing this sciatica making that terrific pain.
The moment she started talking and discharging this because she was alive in the
interview. She was much more alive than the other one.
Do you all agree? That means she was bringing out real emotions.
When she spoke, she spoke really on her emotions. This is very important.
Lachesis can not hold back, they have strong emotions and bring it out.
And then there is a relief.
But most probably when she goes home and this relief will be temporary, it's not cured.
That is why many times they say to us, you take a nice case and you have a placebo
effect because you are so nice with the patient etc.
But I have never seen a cure like this, being nice with the person.
How they have found out? If they do an experiment of course some people will say
I feel better because I talk. Of course, they feel better but not cured.
It's a different thing to see that this girl is really coming back as a balanced person.
Not only the sciatica is better but as a whole person is better.
-I'd like to remind you what you said in the beginning today about Calc. carbonica.
Because when you saw her, her physical expression is very much a Calc. carbonica.
-Correct. We started thinking this most probably is a Calc. carbonica. Continue.
-In the continuance and follow up maybe the Calc. carbonica will appear sooner or later.
-Yes, there is a possibility.
Here looking at her you get the idea of Calc. carbonica, as I said in the beginning.
Flabbiness, white and a little bit plump, better heat, desire sweets, so the idea can be.
Why we do not go to Calc. carbonica?
-Because of the sciatica?
-No, the sciatica won't bother because Calc. carbonica has all kinds of sciatica.
It can have lumbagos and sciaticas of different types.
But Calc. carbonica will not load herself with this kind of emotional loading.
The whole thing in her started with the husband relationship, the conflict and keeping
a lot of anger and hatred and resentment.
So we have to go to remedies which can do that.
If she was coming back and say, well after this impact my digestive system is
unbalananced. My liver is affected, my stomach is affected, my abdomen is affected
then in spite of the fact that we will have this kind of sensitivity, will say more Lycopodium.
Here it's a tricky situation because usually Lachesis is worse warm.
What about worse cold?
That means in some cases you may get the worse cold in Lachesis as well.
She is better by warm, worse by cold but sciatica better warm. Wait you will see now.
Lycopodium, Magnesia phosphorica.
If we take this symptom and we take it as a primary symptom, is this a primary symptom?
-No.
-Did you get the idea that putting warm it just takes the pain away?
-In Magnesia phosphorica, in Arsenicum and Lycopodium putting warmth is like a big
relief; that is what it says in the Repertory.
In the Repertory it is this.
What she said was it this type of amelioration from warmth?
-No.
-Warmth of bed ameliorates, go a bit further, you can see it. Arsenicum, Causticum,
Kali bichromicum, Lycopodium. You see how strong is Lycopodium?
Did she say that in bed she is better? No, on the contrary.
Where is now this symptom? If you can not discriminate between these things, you have
to be very careful. What she says is very important. How she says it's very important.
Otherwise you go wrong.
She says, well I put some warm, she suffers in bed every night.
She says I have to wake up and have to suffer because she takes a pain killer and
during the sleep the pain comes.
If this is Lycopodium wouldn't have been better if you take that symptom.
If you take that symptom, forget it, you are not a homeopath.
You are a digitalizing person. This the computer can do it, not you.
You are here, you see, you understand what is written here and then you don't go to
make that mistake.
-It is best that generals, pain, night, in sleep aggravation if Lycopodium?
-In the generalities?
What has to do with the case? This is generality, this is talking about pain sleep.
What has this symptom to do with warmth ameliorates?
What has to do with sciatica? You can go and find and symptom to justify some idea.
This is not correct. You have to be very careful in what you are doing. I'm sorry, not you.
This is general, night, in sleep, aggravates. Mercury, Nit. acid. These are the syphilitic
pains which are aggravated and Lycopodium has a place there, somewhere.
It is a fact that in this case it is a very difficult decision between Lycopodium and Lachesis.
So we say Lachesis, I give you my reasons for that but we may have to go back to
Lycopodium or we may have to go back to Calc. carbonica.
It doesn't mean anything. The facts are facts.
And the fact is that before we see the effect, we can not be sure.
Especially in this case. We have to see whether she may have an aggravation before... We'll see.
-Just after the interview she had a menstrual flow started and it's about a week early and
she was frightened to go to sleep because she usually has an aggravation after sleep
and during sleep.
But she woke up with (?) and she was fine, the pain was a lot less, she was reading
and she was comfortable.
-You don't know actually now how she is?
-This is during the break, before I came in, she felt a lot better. She was a lot better.
And she took the remedy about 1 o'clock.
-The critical point will be tonight where we will see whether the pain really is...
There is a possibility that she maybe aggravates still tonight and by tomorrow evening
she will start feeling better, we will see. I'll see you tomorrow.