-The patient adds some information.
-When I tried once to smoke hashish, all the time I didn't want to, everybody did for 3
years and I didn't want, I resent it and then when I tried it once I had cramps and vomiting
and then I went into coma. And only lemon, after a few hours they put lemon, they give
me to drink lemon and lemon on my face and it antidoted it.
-After a few hours? How you take hashish, you chew it or smoke?
-No, one puff.
-Also alcohol aggravates her.
Now I want to ask you a question. Do you know why I did not say anything while taking
her case?
Second question. If she is good as a prover for homeopathic remedy?
-Yes.
-Yes absolutely. Will you being in charge of a proving, will you put her on the team for provings?
-No.
-Of course.
-Who says no? Who says yes? Equal but most of the people can not decide.
-Can you repeat the question?
-If you are the chief of a proving, knowing what you know about her because you took
her case, will you consider her a prover? Will you take her for proving?
-No.
-She is a good prover..
-She is a good prover, would you take her for a proving?
Who will take her for a proving? Who will not take her for a proving. Now you understood
more the question. You have to take precautions if you take her to the proving. If she says with 1 puff
of hashish she went into coma, you better be careful what you are going to give her.
They did a proving in Israel and she was regulator of the provings, she did not take the
remedy but she did developed the symptoms.
She developed some symptoms, it does not mean she developed the symptoms of a
remedy because her mind is so powerful that can play tricks with her. If somebody
decides that it is not good for me to be introvert and it is good to be an extrovert and she
became an extrovert actually as we see, this is amazing. It says a power of the mind over
the body, she says I'm not going to be sensitive anymore, I'm not going to take
everything, can you do it? Who can do the same thing? Let me see your hands? Nobody.
The other way around is easy, everybody can do it, without his will of course.
So you see how exceptional you are. You are the only one that your mind can influence
your body to such a degree. I have seen it a few times. I've seen it in a case of a little girl
let us say, 11 when she started developing her breast and men started looking at her,
she got such uneasiness that she stopped her development. She stopped the pituitary
gland from producing the normal hormones for growing, she stayed small, the breast
stayed as when she was 11 but she was much ahead of her class mates in her breast
developing. She stopped it right there.
And I have seen it again, this was a case of Baryta carbonica, where she was very
intelligent. It doesn't matter, still she had Baryta carbonica and she was helped
enormously and I saw it once again with a woman who stopped her desire for sex.
Stopped completely that, I don't remember the incident and she developed male
hormones to the extend that she lost all her hair. The male hormones were very high in
her blood, what was the remedy prescribed? Sepia. No. She had sexual desire which
she did not like, Sepia does not have that. Platina? Whenever I have treated a Platina
and took away the extra desire for sex that Platina usually has, they came back and they
complained, where is my desire? I have lost my desire? Has anything to do with your medicine? No.
Then of course they decide that, that is life, you can not enjoy all the time and then of
course the headaches are also gone and ... In her case will be the opposite.
She will soon have problems.
It is a normalization of the hormonal system and as we said in Platina cases you may go
to the opposite where you have the opposite and then you have the other symptom.
But she will have the normal desire which she is missing at the moment.
Pulsatilla, no. Lachesis, no. I took ailments from suppressed sexual desire. Conium.
And then she developed her hair again, her hair started growing.
The first thing we have to think about this case after we hear such a story is the potency
question. The potency question is very serious when you deal with such a case. So what
you do? Whatever is the remedy that you decide, you give rather a low potency that
means from 30 downwards, either 12 or 18 or at the most 30 if you are almost sure that
this is the remedy. Then see the reaction and then maybe you go higher but such a
sensitive individuals, see what we say sensitive individuals, proving every remedy, this is
actually a model. Therefore you have to pay attention to such sensitivities very much
otherwise you are going to have some problems.
So we settle this and then we go to the idea of the remedy, what is the uppermost remedy for her?
When you go to the idea of the miasms, in her case also it is clear that the uppermost
miasm which is expressing itself it is what?
-Sycosis.
-It is Sycosis. Now whether it's a Medorrhinum or whether it's another remedy, it has no
much meaning but the explosive, she is an explosive type, she is full of energy. I believe
she reacted much less than naturally, she is even more...
What is interested she has a defense mechanism that if it is touched a little bit, it reacts.
I can say something and immediately she can cry. Before I was something about you and
I couldn't believe, I passed my eyes and she was ready to cry again. What I was saying?
-About the mind.
-Yes and she got it. The moment I said she is the only one in the class that she can do
that, you see tears. It's OK don't cry. So you have to take into consideration and don't do
aggressive things with her, though she looks very strong, solid. It is interesting she looks
so solid and yet so sensitive, you think this is a typical Calcarea carbonica and then you
start doubting, are you feeling hot or cold? Hot, hot, so bye, bye.
And then you are thinking of Pulsatilla, crying and all that, I started with what you like
thinking of the idea of Pulsatilla fat but I didn't want to make it clear from the beginning.
She said, meat with fat, more fat than meat. And then she went on to the idea of ...
As the interview was progressing she went and talked about, she said certain things
which are very characteristic of Lachesis because immediately she came up with sea
food, she said desire for sea food so strong, that's why she was given Lachesis one time
and sleeping on the right side absolutely clear, sleeping on the right side, eating seafood,
choking. Is the choking of Lachesis?
She says, she hates the clothing.
-Only like this I go.
-Even in the winter she goes like this. She cannot have anything here. In your waist?
So strong symptoms for Lachesis and then of course she said, I'm very loquacious during
menses and you like that and you say, now this is a case of Lachesis, we go on higher potency.
She says correctly, the loquacity is not only the first day, it's during menses. That means
she is not relieved with the first flow which is Lachesis, which is correct.
He puts all these in the repertorization. You look actually if you want to do proper job, you
have actually to work with the symptoms and then as you go along you look in the
Repertory for the interesting symptoms or you put them in the computer and let the
computer an idea. It's no good to write 24 symptoms and then go and look in the
Repertory. This is not good. The good thing is to look in the Repertory as you go along
with the case. Here it says, Nux vomica, Nat mur, Lachesis, Pulsatilla, Lycopodium,
Causticum, Nat carbo and Calc carbo, where I cannot make a decision.
What other remedy, she was taking about another remedy. Medorrhinum.
As she was talking most probably she herself realized that she was talking about
Medorrhinum, correct?
-Yes.
-When did you perceive the idea that maybe you are Medorrhinum?
-When I told you about the Arg-n. and then you asked me about my stomach and I
already thought about Med. long time ago.
-You thought about Med. long time ago. This is very important because then you have
to suspect, is she giving me Med. because she knows what she is giving or she is
giving the right information?
-No.
-I'm just teaching, I don't say you gave on purpose Medorrhinum.
I remember a case in the Center where we had the books outside and people would
read, she comes inside one case and she gives a perfect case of Rhus tox.
The doctor very happy, Rhus tox go. She comes back after a month, no effect, nothing.
What happens? She says, I don't understand because when I read the remedy outside
while waiting, I had all the symptoms of Rhus tox. While waiting, read Rhus tox, went into
the doctor, gave very clear symptoms of Rhus tox, the doctor prescribed.
Why this is happens? This is something very, very interesting. They say I'm not going to be influenced,
tell me the remedy or something like that, they get it. The moment that something is written down
and the other person reads it, he says I have this, I have that.
I've done it as an experiment. I said OK read this, how many people have it? And you
see you read Nux vomica half of the class, you read Causticum half of the class, you
read Pulsatilla half of the class, but how is that possible?
Really I have it and they believe they have it. No, this is not the homeopathic case.
The homeopathic case is really to see whether she comes forward with the symptom, when
she gives out a symptom, then you grasp it. You say this is a good symptom, bring it here.
What is a good symptom for her? One symptom which no one can dispute?
-Loquacity.
-No.
-Green fruits, unripe fruits.
-Even that, no. That she is hot, nobody can dispute that. It's a warm person.
She gives examples in winter, I dress like this and you get a symptom which you can
not say, maybe this, maybe not, she is hot.
Another?
-Sensitive.
-Yes but sensitive is general.
-Weeping?
-Yes sure, she weeps easily, there is no question.
-Ice cold perspiration.
-Ice cold perspiration is a peculiar, too many remedies? Perspiration cold head? Did you find this?
-From the head is cold and then it goes all over the body.
-It goes all over the body. Calcarea, Hepar, Lobelia, Nux vomica, Phosphorus and
Veratrum. Can you tell me if there are any additions here? 16 remedies. Which are the
additions? Calcarea, Tuberculinum...
-Only Carbo Vegetabilis is from Materia Medica and Tuberculinum.
-Only these two, Carbo vegetab and Tuberculinum.
-My father had tuberculosis.
-Her father had tuberculosis, according to the pathology of her father what is the remedy?
-Medorrhinum. Because in young age he started having a lot of heart problems, heart emphracts etc.
that points to the idea of sycosis and most probably to the idea of Medorrhinum.
So Medorrhinum maybe is running through together with Turbeculosis and maybe she
has a peculiar mixture of sycosis with tuberculosis with psora and most probably
underneath there is some syphilis. Why do we say that? Because her brother has been
in this. Most probably we have a complex miasmatic condition with her and that is why
we have to go step by step and very carefully and we don't jump quickly to one remedy
after another remedy.
Another symptom?
-Desires fat.
-Yes there is no question about that, she made it very clear.
-Aggravation by the afternoon sleep.
-Aggravation by the afternoon sleep also is very strong. So actually when you repertorize
her case, you put these symptoms first. We talked about 5 symptoms. These 5 symptoms
you go and repertorize them and see what comes through these 5 good symptoms.
Can you open another case of repertorization and put these 5 symptoms?
Worse warm, desires fat, perspiration cold head, weeping easily,
worse afternoon sleep, sleep right side.
-Yes, I will put here 3 times, 4 times, 2 times, between 2 and 3 times, 1 time, between 2
and 3 times.
-I have a question about one of the rubrics for perspiration cold on the head.
Since it starts on the head and goes over the body, wouldn't be better to use perspiration
cold in the generalities than perspiration cold in the head?
-You can use that but we saw that they were 300 remedies and too many remedies and
we use the specific symptom which she has.
-I would be afraid there that I would miss a remedy because it was...
-Too few.
-Yes.
-We have been added some more.
-Open air also.
-Yes better open air, desire for open air. 2 times.
Do you yourself see any other symptom which you would like to see written here?
-Sensitive to medicine?
-Not really. No, in this stage of repertorization.
-Cold nasal discharge?
-Yes you can take this.
-Aversion water?
-Yes and there is another one which is aversion to water 3 times. Her symptoms she
present them in a strong way, right? That's why we intend to underline quite a lot in
her case the symptoms 3 times.
But now what you can decide is, for instance, you look when you take certain symptoms
you take 4-5 symptoms, you look what it comes, you add another one, see what comes
next, you add another one, see what comes. Can you do this for the class?
This is how you get ideas for the repertorization. When I used to take a case, I did not
have computers, there was a big pause, the patient was sitting there and I was looking
through and there was always some doctors next to me and sometimes they felt
perplexed. There was a big pause there, waiting, what are we doing and we are doctors
here doing nothing, looking at the books, studying now in front of the patient, the case?
They felt perplexed and some of them told me. I said it is much better if you do this and
the patient feels whatever he likes than give him the wrong remedy.
Because you don't want to look that you don't know, you say take the remedy.
Never do that, never mind what the patient will think about you. If it a patient who does
not understand it is better to send him away from Homeopathy. You don't need patients.
You need to do your work properly, so it does not matter what he thinks.
Many times they will discuss, a patient will say to a friend who sent them, they say he
was looking in my case he was looking to learn at the moment I was there. This is very
good because I want to do my job properly. Most of the people I will tell, I have to study
your case now, I have to study, wait. They felt very happy, why? Because I was
straight forward with them. I'm studying your case now, you wait. I open the books
take my time, study the case. If I give the right remedy, then they appreciate.
He is very good, you go to him. But if you want to present yourself as knowing
everything then eventually your clientele will go down, so you have every time a good
symptom looked in the Repertory to get ideas. This is what I'm saying here.
Staphysagria, Pulsatilla, you put all 8 symptoms? OK.
Staphysagria is interesting, why? Staphysagria has strong aversion to water and also
we put strongly the after sleep aggravates which Staphysagria also has very strongly.
So the system says, you have put and it gave me two keynotes of this particular remedy
strongly; therefore I would suggest Staphysagria and then Pulsatilla comes second.
Pulsatilla has 5 out of 8 and weeping easily, 3-3 and warm aggravates 4-3. Aversion to
water etc and then the third remedy, which is the third remedy? Causticum. What about sweets?
-She likes sweets, desire for open air and then Nat mur etc. Let me see Opium.
I give her Opium. Do you sleep good? Sound sleep, do you snore?
-Yes.
-Very loudly?
-Yes, she says yes.
-If we confirm Opium, we give Opium. Who says no for Opium. I also doubt it.
-A lot of sympathy for people, I cry.
-You cry if they suffer. Put sympathy, how you will underline this symptom yourself?
-3 or 4. With a cripple in the street I can cry. If somebody is mongol, even with a kid will
tell a story that it got offended I cry. With everybody.
-You sympathize with everybody who is suffering, so this element is very strong, put 3.
As she gives this, our mind goes immediately to Phosphorus. You enter one symptom
and you see, previously where was Phosphorus? Down but then suddenly comes with a
strong symptom, of course we think of Phos, of Caust, the same. Pulsatilla has gone a
little bit down.
Phosphorus is very thirsty yes. Put thirstless, give me this symptom, open your repertories
and see this symptom thirst less.
We see here what are the remedies, Antimonium, Apis, China... I just want to show you
the original thirstless, Phosphorus is there? It must be there. I just want to show you that
sometimes you may have a Phosphorus which is thirst less, this does not exclude
because other things being in favor, the thirstlessness may not exclude Phosphorus.
-What about the block in the ears?
-It's a local symptom which is not important.
-I have a question to the patient. Is it OK?
-Yes put the question.
-It's about this peculiar symptom you had, the freezing cold mucus, was it from the nose
or from the throat?
-No from the throat.
-If you look throat mucus cool, one remedy.
-Which one?
-Phosphorus.
-Can you tell me who has added this? Original Kent? Me?
-Vithoulkas!
-Desire company, I can't be alone, I need people.
-She is never tired from company, she enjoys company.
-Now the fact that she wants company to elucidate and to find out why really she needs company?
-Yes I know. I like company when I am with myself I'm thinking too deeply about the
problems of the world, I feel I can get depressed, so I don't want to go into it. I prefer to
be maybe to the surface of things but it keeps me from going deep into myself.
-The rubric offended easily, if you want to have that with, do you want it?
-Yes we can have this rubric. Mucus cool, add this.
She took us from the idea of Lachesis to Pulsatilla, to Medorrhinum and now she takes
us over to the idea of Phosphorus.
-I wonder why we don't talk about Carcinosin? Why don't we talk about that?
-Why? What symptoms of Carcinosin she has?
-She has a lot.
-She likes animals.
-Forget it, who likes animals? Look, all the class. Wait a moment, to take it as a symptom
it has to be pathology. The others must say, she collects all the animals, the house is full
of dogs, you enter the house and dogs and cats are sitting all over the place.
-Maybe she is like that.
-Still I doubt. I tell you why I doubt, she needs company and she needs to give her love
and affection and if she does not have some human being to do it, then she finds an
animal and then take some also.
Since we are in the question of Phosphorus, we have to ask more questions about the
Phosphorus. We ask about fear. We said, do you have any fears? She did not mention
any fear of Phosphorus. She did not say about thunderstorms especially, she is not afraid
of the dark.
-As a kid maybe, when I have to walk on a very dark alley here, I will be afraid.
Maybe not in Alonissos but in Athens yes and to walk alone in a dark place, I would think
that somebody is behind me and I will be afraid from robbers and from somebody will kill
me, I will be.
-Keep this.
-Yes I have problem with memory. I search sometimes for a word and it wouldn't come.
I have like if I'm studying about a remedy, I remember it very nicely and then the next day
it's mixed with the rest of the remedies and it bothers me a lot because I used to have a
very good memory. There is a time where I say to my husband can you bring me this?
And he says, say the word and I couldn't get the word.
-How many times?
-It was for about 2 years.
-Every day you had this problem?
-Yes, all the time.
-And then it went away?
-It still is but not often, the words go away, I'm looking for certain word, even a name.
-What would you like to ask concerning Phosphorus?
-Anxiety about health?
-Yes very, especially for my kids, mine also but then I take it out of my head not to think
about it, if I think about it yes.
-You had it. So either she is Pulsatilla with desire fat or she is a Phosphorus with
aversion to water. You chose.
-It's more aversion to water than desire fat.
-She likes to be Phosphorus.
-I can live without fat but I can't stand water, before I put water in my mouth I feel sick.
-Aversion to water, main remedies? Nux vomica, Staphysagria, Stramonium and the
Pulsatilla is on the second degree and then Staphysagria which also we are playing with
the idea. He is sure she is a Staphysagria.
-I have a question. She mentioned several times in different parts of the body a sharp
pain like a hard knife cutting, would you use that, you would be able to use it under a generality?
-You have too many symptoms already, so to go and use a local symptom...
Like for instance a stitching pain here, this will not because you have very strong general
symptoms on which you have to go by.
-But she mentioned several times with different parts of the body. It was the back...
-It doesn't matter, what you will say stitching pain or what? If you go to generalities and
you see stitching pain in generalities, there are a lot of remedies, you don't differentiate.
It is useless for differentiation.
-She mentioned early in the interview that she has an aggravation from coffee.
-Aggravation from coffee?
-I like coffee but I have aggravation from coffee. Afterwards I feel nausea.
-Again that is a symptom you have to take with care because she is sensitive to any
stimulants, she was stimulated a little bit with the hashish and she went off.
-We're talking about desires and aversions, she mentioned onions, I would like to ask
her how strong is the aversion to onions?
-Aversion to onions or worse from onions?
-When I eat onions, I like onions, I just feel afterwards it comes up.
-A little bit worse from onions, this is in favor of Pulsatilla. Then argue with what she says
now. Sometimes there is an expression "I hate it" but she means it makes my stomach so
upset but she may like it.
-I was thinking in the realms of Belladonna because she is thirstless and she is plethoric
and red and the sudden symptoms and the hemorrhage.
-Wait a moment, did you have hemorrhages? This is a good question.
-Can you put the underline?
-I like, I'm not craving.
Hemorrhage from the nose, a lot of bleeding in your menses?
-Yes in the menses and ulcerative colitis I bleed a lot. 16 times the day a bucket.
-But otherwise during the period when you were young you did not have.
-Not from the nose but when I get hurt I get easily bruises.
-Medorrhinum yes, she says in the sea she has a strong amelioration.
-Yes.
-You like the sea?
-I like the open air, the water but it's too cold.
-This is a controversial being so warm and yet saying that it is very cold for her. In winter
you feel cold?
-I feel cold.
-But you said in winter you go out.
-Yes I go out like this but if it's a real cold winter, my feet hurt and I have a headache here.
-Ice-cream, do you like ice-cream?
-Sometimes before my menses.
-It's not important for you.
-No, my husband loves it, he eats it all.
-She came here to confuse us.
-I wonder if you would add a rubric mind cares full about others. Do you want to take the rubric with the others?
-Very good yes. I don't believe the way that she describes the sea is not the amelioration
from the sea.
-No, it's not amelioration.
-Forget it.
Concerning her pathology what you would say?
It is interesting with her organism that suddenly she can go to extreme pathology and
then back again to normal. Then extreme pathology, back again to normal.
The incident which she relates with Argen nitr, going crazy, is very extreme. That means
her organism has easily going off and going back again like Staphysagria.
Do you think she is a suppressed person?
-No.
-At this moment she is not suppressed. If you want to describe her character, is the need
to give, maybe underneath you may say she wants to be loved also and that's why etc.
but this is apart, the need to give is very. The need to be with people together is another
issue that came up and underline her anxiety about her own problems and the problems
of the family, that's another issue that came up.
I will tell you, I came to the class with the idea that she was either Pulsatilla or
Medorrhinum. And I wanted to finally to discuss about this and most probably I will go
for the idea of Pulsatilla, in spite of the fact that there is a desire for fat because I have
seen it in a case and I have given this information to some seminars.
I have found some Pulsatillas which they have strong desire for fat. Nobody remembers
this from me? It is there recorded in some of these tapes.
So the desire for fat will not take me away, if Pulsatilla symptoms were strong otherwise
and she said desire for butter. Immediately, if you remember in the interview, she said
I love butter, which Pulsatilla has aversion to fat but desires butter.
As you investigated the case and you asked questions, the idea of Phosphorus came
quite strongly and now my problem is choosing between Phosphorus and Pulsatilla.
The idea of Medorrhinum went down but the idea of Phosphorus came quite strongly
with some possibility of Causticum but knowing, you see I have seen some Phosphorus
being so warm but not Causticum.
-It is in the rubric but I have not seen it, it isn't my experience.
-There is one keynote with Phosphorus, that's why I thought I'm Phosphorus. That was
the only thing I'm sympathetic and this keynote I thought I'm Phosphorus. A lot of times
I feel alone in the world, a feeling that I'm alone, I can't explain like I don't have nobody.
If you say about depression or something, that's the only closest thing that comes down
to being said.
-Pulsatilla is not as sympathetic as Phosphorus, not at all. Pulsatilla does not have that
sympathy, a little bit. Phosphorus has it very much and Causticum has it because it
feels... There are different reasons why Causticum and Phosphorus are sympathetic for
others. The Causticum can not see something which is painful to others and wants
immediately to correct it, the idea of Causticum is to correct it, to jump into the picture
and do something and especially the sympathetic element for Causticum came out
between this pain and also the injustice. When I see outside the injustice, I feel sympathy
for the person to whom is done some injustice, then I have to jump and do it.
The Phosphorus is more vulnerable in itself, as if there is no protection and I feel the pain
of others because I do not have protection. I go out to them and I feel the...
The one has protection and attacks, jumps into the picture. The other is like I'm not
protected, therefore I feel the pain of others. This can go to the extreme, as I have said,
where a Phosphorus can stay inside the house, does not go out in the society where we
have insanity with Phosphorus, they don't go outside because they feel the pain with
everything which happens around them, so much so, that they can not come in contact
with the society and then we have the closed Phosphorus, the sensitive Phosphorus who
will not associate. But the reason why he does not associate is because he feels the pain
of others. So it is a matter of non protection, it is different in sense.
Do you know why we are confused in this case?
What I think is because she is a homeopath, because she knows the symptoms, she has
given us several symptoms, which she says, oh I have this, oh yes I have that and she is
very alive type and perhaps if we go on asking we will discover, she is having a lot of
symptoms. And you see the problem? She has taken not too many remedies but she
knows about remedies and that makes it difficult and makes it confusing.
If we took it without her knowing anything, she would highlight the real things which
really bother her, now she can confuse us even without her knowing it.
I would say what is the intensity for the feelings of others, the sympathy. She said strong, very strong.
-It is, it's a problem, too much.
-Let's finish, let's sleep over it.
-No.
-You want the solution now?
-OK I will give you the solution, quiet.
I'll tell you the truth what I think, the absolute truth.
I do not know.
We almost forgot her. What shall we do? I thought the matter over this afternoon and I
found a very simple solution.
-Give both.
-No, give first the one and if it does not do anything, give the second.
Which one we give first? My idea eventually was to give first Phosphorus 30.
See what happens within a period of 2-3 months, then if she reacts to that, then we can
go higher of course. If you have no reaction at all, then you go to Pulsatilla 30.
After 2 months, no reaction at all Pulsatilla 30, then from there on you can see.