-So we brought this case because she had a big reaction and I would like to hear about
this reaction after taking the remedy.
-At the moment right now I'm terribly excited.
I know the state, my nerve system is tinkling and upheaval, I can not seal myself off
any influences, I'm in a very excited state and I just hope I can tell you in the right order
what has happened.
-She can try.
-I took the remedy the day before yesterday in the morning and the first reaction was that
I had a stinging pain in the heart.
Then all the acute symptoms disappeared within 1,5 hour.
I was in such a state of euphoria, even though it was raining outside I could have run out
and jump through the rain, yuppie I'm alive, so full of zest and joy of life.
The day was fine and I also slept well and then the next day, while I was coming up here
all the acute symptoms came back with such an intensity, such a violence that I was sitting here
in the class, thinking I will not stand through, I felt like I was going to slide down the chair,
I couldn't hold myself and it was all back very intense.
-Total exhaustion?
-Yes, while I was coming here it was fairly OK but then inside the classroom...
-She felt depleted?
-Yes and also all the pains came back.
-She means the psychological pains or the physical pains?
-The physical pains. I decided to leave in the first break and with every step I took going away
from the Academy, I felt better again and then I thought my god what's wrong with you,
are you such a hypochondriac?
But I had strong palpitations and this has remained.
Then at home I lied down and I stayed in bed all day but the palpitations remained.
The pulse rate itself was not much more high than normal, it was more the feeling,
what's going on.
-The heart was pumping strongly.
-Yes, I had the feeling that my heart was so loud that it would make sounds in the room.
-But today how are the physical symptoms?
-They are all gone, after this night many things are clear and it's all gone.
While I was lying there yesterday after some hours I went into my heart and constantly
I asked myself where is it happening, what is going on, where it is coming from?
While I was lying there, my thoughts went backwards and suddenly I found myself in a state
almost around the time when I was born and my mother had tried to abort me when
she was pregnant with me and I never really felt accepted, never felt loved,
never had the impression I was lovable.
Suddenly I started seeing images from the life of my mother, images of things that had nothing
to do with me at all, it was just certain pictures out of the life of my mother I could follow
and suddenly this feeling occurred to me that I felt it's not my fault.
I was wandering up and down in my room and kept repeating it's not my fault,
it's not my fault that she couldn't live her life the way she wanted to.
And I cried and it came from so deep inside.
In that moment I would have loved to rush up here and hug you, it was so incredible.
So many things straighten out in my mind. So often people said to me, why do you keep apologizing
that you are alive and now I have this feeling that I seem to be worth loving after all.
And these feelings of guilt, I was never aware of.
-She was never aware?
-Not in this degree.
Of course when I look back at my life I can see that I was behaving in such a way
but I was not aware of it and also when I saw these images of my mother yesterday I also realized
that it was not her who blamed me for the way she lived, it was me, myself
who took up this responsibility.
-Blaming herself. Very deep analytical work.
She had any traumatic experience with her previous husband that came up during that period?
-Not yesterday.
-It was concerning her mother and her relationship with that issue.
-Yes it went on for hours but I don't want to spread it all down here right now.
-How does she feel now?
-Liberated, free.
It's like I just can't believe it.
Just a few comments so you know where you are and what is happening.
Can anybody tell me why there was such an amelioration the first day and then
the second day such aggravation?
First I felt very happy, very much energy and then all the physical symptoms came back the pains,
everything that was as an acute state, they came back.
Why it was this sequence, first better and then worse, can anybody tell me?
She comes here, she is depleted of energy, she has a relapse on the depression when
she comes, the energy is low and she is developing an acute.
Then she takes the remedy and what happens?
It is that the energy gets up and the psychological state in general becomes very good,
she was so happy and then all the force of the disturbance goes to the physical body,
that's very simple.
Then the physical it continues and gets it out as well and then what happens is further,
she has a deep problem which she never realized actually.
Then that comes to her awareness because the organism is strong enough to face that rejection
or what she thought it was a rejection.
And she analyses and she understands that was a rejection that came from me, not from my mother
but now I'm in a position to face that fear, which I had all my life, which was the basis
of the depression and she faces so automatically, why?
Because she is back to health. It's very simple.
-Since two days I know that I'm going to have a follow up today and since then I've been really
occupying myself with me and my personal story.
Now I can tell you what happened after Phosphorus.
I got the second dose from you in May, then I had a reaction afterwards and a second follow up
and I was very happy afterwards, completely flowing, like a child, I could jump all the time.
And it was so clear to me now it's going on like this, I have all the strength to do the things
but then it went down again. I got in a short of a depressive state, it was not as bad as it has been
but it was still there.
-How long ago after the remedy?
-About 4 weeks.
-She started going down?
-It went down already after 10 days and when I got so depressive I got really scared
because I have already been at the point that I wondered shall I jump.
So I went back to see my homeopath in Berlin because I felt I needed a talk and
after we had talked together he said he was very sure that he had seen my remedy.
He wasn't convinced about Phosphorus and I asked him again, are you sure
and he said absolutely.
He gave me Silica, it didn't do anything, first he gave me C200 and then he repeated it in 1M.
Then he gave me Tuberculinum, it didn't do anything either, then I had Pulsatilla.
Pulsatilla was a little good but not very much, then I had Carcinosin.
With Carcinosin something changed, not so prominent but I felt a little better and I started
to eat different things again and to feel appetite, more spicy and I tried some meat again
which I haven't had since I was 17.
In the end of November he gave me Rhus tox in 1M and with this I made a proving.
I got a skin eruption, Rhus eruption and very strong pains in the left side of my back, which partially
are still there but then they were really bad, I hardly could move and I was just moaning
because of the pains.
I have had Chlamydia, I told you this in the first follow up and then you said this is a good reaction
after the remedy but because they didn't go away, I took antibiotics in February.
-This year?
-Yes, then I ventured by myself Staphysagria C200 but it didn't do very much either.
The whole winter time I have had tonsils and mucus going down from the nose and then
I had a treatment with my own blood.
-Isopathy?
-Isopathy to strengthen my immune system.
I had two flues in winter, one was in February and the temperature went up to 39,5 and
a friend of mine said, why don't you take Bryonia? And this really helped me.
Concerning my physical complains, I still have a low blood pressure, it's often 90 to 60
and taking a hot bath is helping.
I have cold hands and feet, every now and then I have a stitching pain in my thyroid gland,
my hands often feel numbed, it's like Raynaud's.
I still drink a lot but warm and cold in the same quantity.
-When she says warm, she means not warm water, she drinks tea or warm water?
-Normally I would drink tea but it's a short time that I started to drink warm water.
-Somebody told her is good?
-Yes.
Still I'm very frightful, I'm very sensitive to odors and to noises.
When I jump or run fast I have incontinence for urine, just some drops.
My energy is changing but never I'm really on the top of it and I'm still in between,
not in my full energy. And the best for me is if I have a nap at noon.
Sun I can't tolerate that well, it's uncomfortable to be in the sun.
I told you I have the pain in the back after Rhus tox and now I have both kidneys I have at least
the part of the back around the kidneys is somehow hurting, not so strongly,
it's not an acute pain.
-It's dull, deep or muscular?
-I don't think it's muscular, I really think it's the kidneys. It feels it's where are the kidneys.
-What antibiotics she took?
-I don't know.
-They were given by a gynecologist?
-Yes.
-For how long she took the antibiotic?
-One week.
When the lecture started here, I realized it was the second or third day, it was too much for me,
it's too noisy, it's too much going on. I had to leave and I felt like before
when the Phosphorus was repeated.
Immediately after I took the Phosphorus I was still in a Phosphorus state, then a colleague gave me
Phosphorus in LM 8 and immediately with this I felt better, I could take a deep breath but
then my lungs went down again and it was like Phosphorus before, I was happy again
and I was jumping about in the evening.
-Which day she took this Phosphorus 8?
-It must have been Tuesday or Wednesday last week.
-10 days now. She takes every day or just one dose?
-I just took one dose and then I took a second one when I felt so excited again, my palpitations
are so restless. But I wasn't in complete Phosphorus state, so it didn't do that much.
-The second time.
-It was more prophylactic.
-This is the LM potencies?
-Yes, Q potencies.
I had a dream the first night when I arrived here on the island.
I saw a children's handkerchief and handkerchief on this there were several teeth lying.
Some of them were mine but it was the back teeth, the big one and it was only the crowns
and then I said, these I take, I don't let anybody take them away from me, these are mine.
-During all this year, did she experience any fear during thunderstorm?
-Maybe once, I was afraid when I was a child but then my grandmother explained me
that you have to count and by the counting how far away it is...
And today I must say, I love thunderstorms.
-I think it's OK, it's enough information for me.
The conclusion with this case that we just saw is that she is still on Phosphorus layer.
So therefore the suggestion for this case will be since she started with LM8,
to continue with LM8, as she needs it, the moment she goes down, she will understand
and she will repeat LM, then she can go from there upwards again.
I just want to make a remark which does not concern so much spirituality
but how the Phosphorus is suffering through relationships because they feel very much
the pain of others.
When the quality of the person is a very good quality, then they suffer because of what they see
as suffering in other people.
You get Phosphorus who are more resistant but it is interesting that it is a kind of,
I would say, innocence because there is this lack of protection.
Somebody who is aware is protecting himself much more, the Phosphorus do not have
the means to protect themselves and this comes through again as a possibility for her.
I don't think the remedies that she took did anything but if she went into such condition
what would help her most probably would be Aurum.
And Aurum might had helped her to get out of it much faster.
But since now after all this going around she is back into the Phosphorus state,
we continue with the Phosphorus.
-I have 13 symptoms and Phosphorus is 28, how come?
-It depends what you put in the computer.
-What can I put in the computer when the Phosphorus is there?
-It depends, she said few things, symptoms that are not really important.
The important things here were what she implied, the very strong sympathetic element
which had to be very strong, the excessive thirst, they give you the idea of Phosphorus.
You don't need a third symptom.
Now why she drinks the warm water, most probably, as I said immediately, somebody told you
it's good for you? Yes, she said.
This is why she drinks hot water because there are some ideas, you know your type is not good
to have cold, cold is very bad for you, whatever.
Cold is bad, therefore you drink warm water and if you are in a sensitive state
and you need some help, then you try also hot water.
-Can it be that Phosphorus has to be repeated more often because that's the third time
that it doesn't keep ...It maybe that you have to repeat more often the Phosphorus?
-Yes. I would say that Phosphorus is a sensitive remedy ,a remedy which is spoiled easily
in your bottles, you have to have in mind this and the LM I like the idea, since it has acted.
Low potency she can repeat more often until she gets out of the layer of Phosphorus.