-So the problem is that I had some symptoms after the caesarean operation
I had 3 years ago and during the anesthesia I was conscious somehow.
This had a very frightening effect on me.
Since then I think I couldn't quite recover from that moment.
-What was the fright?
-I was aware of myself and all the surrounding.
It was like darkness and I couldn't perceive my body, just the darkness
and it was very frightening experience.
-During the anesthesia you were aware and you could see the operation?
-No, I couldn't see, just I was not totally unconscious, I could think,
I was not sleeping but I didn't see.
-Did you feel the pain?
-No.
It was like a point in the darkness, that can be the description.
I didn't feel the body, I didn't feel anything but I was aware of myself.
-Aware of yourself but not of pain, not of hearing the doctors, what they say.
No, only in the end when I started to recover, I started to hear.
Of course the doctors were shouting that I should breathe but I didn't feel my body.
They said breathe, I said I would like to breathe but I don't know how,
I'm not feeling anything and I think I have recovered very slowly.
It was a long time until they could bring me to my senses.
-So you went very far out.
-I think so and I could perceive how I was.
The moment when it was cut off so to see the image from reality,
I could perceive that something like spy... the noise has became metallic,
it was very frightening.
-Did you have a reaction after you came back, you were trembling?
-Yes.
-Can you describe exactly what happened?
-It is a trembling that usually patients experience after operation,
some of them so they have to give me some medicines for this and to cover me very well.
Some injections, I don't know exactly what it was.
But it was nothing so unusual for the people who saw me, only my own experience was not good.
-And after that what happened? What was left?
-Fear because I connect some of the syndromes that I have now with that moment.
I think it had a very bad impact on me. I started to have some dizziness
but not immediately after the operation, after some time.
Before that I had never had such things.
And two times I had acute episodes of vertigo.
One was approximately 1 year after the childbirth and it was preceded by impaired hearing,
so for 2-3 days I couldn't hear very well and then an episode of vertigo came with nausea.
I think also I was very tired because the first year I stayed at home.
This implicated a lot of work, I was alone very much because my husband was coming
very late from work, so I was very much time worried and alone with the child.
And then I started the work and probably it was too many duties to fulfill
and this thing happened. I also was drinking very much coffee at that time.
I connected somehow this with the fact that I was drinking coffee, I stopped drinking
and I was taking some phenylamine for a few days before for an allergic rhinitis.
Maybe it has a connection also, antihistamines.
-Do you still have the rhinitis?
-It was almost gone.
Sometimes very little but it was not very bothering at that time also.
-But definitely you had some reactions from the rhinitis and hay fever which are not there.
-Now almost not at all, very seldom.
Then another episode on this vertigo was a few weeks ago.
Some kind it is connected with the anticipation, before the travel. Ailments anticipation.
-It was things turning around?
-It was balancing, left to right, right to left.
-You had the tendency to fall?
-I was sleeping and suddenly I woke up in the night, 3-4 o'clock in the night
and I moved my head and then I perceived this unbalancing. It was induced by moving the head.
If I didn't move the head, it was OK.
-Did you check with your otolaryngologist to see the labyrinth in what condition it is?
-No I didn't.
Because I had it only once this and then I had it now some weeks before I came here.
-Your hearing is good now?
-Yes.
-No problem?
-No problem.
Usually I have a problem with the movement, if the movement is too quick, for instance in a car,
I don't like that and I may have car sickness.
-If you turn around suddenly your head, do you have problem like this?
-Usually I don't have problems but now I start to avoid doing this because I'm afraid
to cause something.
-This dizziness and vertigo started how long after your pregnancy?
-1 year after.
-In the mean time in that year, did you have anything else like rhinitis?
-No, it was not too strong.
-Did you experience a fear which stayed afterwards? It remained? What kind of fear?
-Yes, I developed strong fear of death. Maybe I had it before but not so strong.
Now it appeared this anxiety of death, that death might occur at any moment.
It was not so safe anymore.
-This was an out of body experience, a death like experience as they call it.
-But it was not very complete. I was stopped in a point which was very bad.
-You stopped to a black point which frightened you absolutely.
What else concerning menses and things like that?
-Menses are rather abundant and clotted.
-Black clots?
-The clots are dark but the blood is not dark.
It's not very bothering but I think it's too abundant.
-Before menses you feel good?
-Yes, I don't think I have any problems.
-In your medical history is something important?
-I had mononucleosis.
-At what age?
-14 or 15 years.
It was severe form with involvement of the liver and I had to take cortisone in order to recover.
Otherwise I think I had the children diseases, most of it, a lot of tonsillitis and
antibiotics during childhood.
-Since when is this operation?
-3 years ago.
-Since that time do you get acutes?
-Yes, I have.
This winter I had a very bad flu which lasted for 3 weeks.
I had to stay at home.
-Do you have any tonsillitis?
-Sometimes I have some colds with the involvement of the tonsils.
This year I took Silica for the flu. And it ended.
I stayed like this with the flu for 3 weeks and then I decided I have to take a remedy.
-What remedies so far you have taken?
-I took Staphysagria for many years.
-And you are still married?
-Yes.
-What was the effect of Staphysagria? Positive effect?
-I think it was positive.
-You felt better psychologically?
-Yes because I felt a lot of indignation, I had some parents with the parents in law
because they are very domineering people. It was a problem in that.
Indeed I was thinking to divorce many times but I didn't in the end.
-You had repeatedly Staphysagria?
-Yes, during the pregnancy for instance I also took.
I didn't dare to take it by myself so I consulted somebody.
-After the pregnancy did you get Staphysagria at all?
-Yes, after the operation. It was very good, I recovered very well from the operation.
I also took Arnica in the operation.
-What else you took?
-Then Lycopodium in 1996, it was followed by a very big aggravation I think.
-And then you had amelioration?
-No, only aggravation.
-Why you took Lycopodium? You had some digestive problems?
-On that time yes.
I had very much rumbling and abdominal distention, especially in public places,
where it's very embarrassing.
-You were a shy person?
-I couldn't speak in public at all and I can not now. It's very big problem for me to speak.
I can do it very seldom if I'm forced to do it, let's say to give a lecture about physiotherapy,
as I had to do it sometimes and I could do it but it's a very big effort.
So this was the Lycopodium.
Then I took Natrum muriaticum last year with some good results.
-On physical level?
-On this dizziness. I think I did not have it for many months afterwards.
-You took what potency?
-I took LM potencies for maybe two weeks.
-And then you felt good for months?
-I had a slight aggravation and then it stopped and then I felt good.
-Did you repeated it?
-I didn't because I felt very well.
When I prepared to travel, I had this again and I didn't know what to take,
I thought it's better not to take anything now.
-When did you take Natrum muriaticum last time?
-In August last year.
-And Silica?
-Silica in February.
And also I took for some colds oscillococcinum I think it was not a good idea.
- Oscillococcinum is good only for the pharmacy.
-It has an effect but it's not good. And for the flu I also tried to take Arsenicum in February.
-No effect?
-It had an effect but the flu didn't finish, so I took Silica.
-Now what brings you here is actually the fear or the vertigo?
-This problem with the vertigo.
-Not the fear of death?
-Also that is a problem.
-It's also a problem still the fact that you can not appear in public, that you have a timidity?
-Yes.
-This is a big problem, timidity is still there.
-Yes, especially in public.
-Now you sit there and you are so nice, you speak very softly,
but we don't understand anything about your real nature.
-Sometimes when I have such kind of excitement, emotion I have an inner trembling.
I don't have it now but usually in such a situation I could have that, a strong trembling.
-Can you describe aspects of your character?
-I think I'm very timid, closed person rather than low self confidence.
I like to read very much.
This is what I like best to do, to study, to find out about things to read philosophy.
-Philosophy which is towards religion? Towards finding truth?
-Yes towards religion. I was very interested in this since childhood.
-14-15?
-Something like that.
At that time my grand parents died, one after another and I think this put me to think
what was this all about.
-Because of your grand parents?
-They were very old and they died.
-Because you saw them dying and then you started questioning the idea of death and
why we are here and what we're doing and all of that?
-Yes.
-And then you went to study Medicine. Why you studied Medicine?
-I was willing more to help. I was thinking how can I help and how can I understand
things better. I think it was more from my wish for knowledge.
-Did you take a specialty?
-Yes, I'm doing physiotherapy and rehabilitation and also acupuncture
and I work on a Foundation for homeopathy in Bucharest.
-You are quite active.
-Yes, I think so.
This also might be a problem because they are too many things I'm trying to do.
-How many children you have?
-Only one.
-You don't want another one? You don't want the experience.
-No. And I don't have too much time, I have to concentrate in too many things.
-Yes, that's what I see. So this dizziness developed after the operation.
-Yes, maybe because of fatigue also. I was very tired, I felt very weak.
I'm not so weak now.
-Except of the medication which you took during the pregnancy and the operation
did you take any other medications? Drugs?
-No. Now because I have this dizziness I try to take, I took Torecan,
this is something special for this.
-Does it relieve at all?
-I took it afterwards, I didn't have it in the house when it happened.
For the moment it passed away in a few minutes.
-Do you have tendency to vomit?
-Yes, when I travel in a car for instance, if I'm staying on the back of the car.
-So sea sickness is quite strong for you?
-It was not until now on a boat, on a rough sea. I don't know if I have sea sickness.
But I think I have it. In the car, if I stay in the back seat.
-And it makes turns?
-Yes, then I have to vomit. Strong nausea.
Also the last times I don't fall asleep so easily but this is only in the recent time.
Usually when I'm at home it's not such a problem.
-You go at bed at 11 and you sleep at 1?
-Not so bad.
I need half an hour but usually I don't need so much time and it's not so pleasant
to go to sleep. I want to go as late as possible.
-Why is not so pleasant? You feel you enter death again?
-Maybe it's connected with this.
-But you are not conscious, you are not afraid that maybe you are not waking up.
-No, no. Only the moment when I get asleep, it's not a pleasant moment.
The process of getting asleep.
-The process of going into sleep is not nice?
-No.
-That means you are almost resisting going into that state.
-Yes, but this is not always. For instance here I experienced this feeling
because I'm away from home and maybe this has an impact.
-Insecurity develops. It's increased your insecurity and then you have this.
-I wanted to say more about some other fears I have.
Fear of airplanes.
-For crushing?
-Yes.
Fear of narrow places, but not so strong. Of dark.
Because I can not control very well these things I think I develop fear of insanity.
Because of the symptoms which are very strange.
-This fear of insanity bothers you?
-No, it doesn't bother me but I'm thinking, I don't know what is this all about
and I'm worried.
-Fear of dark how strong it is?
-It was strong before. Now it's not so strong.
-I may say I am a slow person. I have slow reactions, slow movements.
I don't like to be pressed to do things quickly and the last time I had to do everything
very quickly, because of too many things to do.
There is not so much time to relax, to stay quiet.
-Do you have fear of thunderstorms? Here with these thunderstorms yesterday?
-Yes, I have. I don't like it.
-How long you are married?
-10 years.
-And you had an affair with this man before?
-No.
We fell in love and we got married very quickly, in a few months.
-What did you tell him? Either you marry me or you lose me?
-Yes, something like that.
-You did not want nonsense.
-No but he is also a person who doesn't like nonsense.
-You had lots of affairs before?
-No, not at all.
-Do you feel good in sexual matters?
-Yes, only in the last time because of the fatigue I'm in desire a little bit diminished.
-Can you give me your desires and aversions for food?
-Desire mainly for cheese, vegetables, fruits, sweets very much.
-What kind?
-Chocolate and others.
-Ice cream?
-Not so much because of the tonsillitis problem. I can have very easily a cold.
-You get a cold, not tonsillitis. Tonsillitis is with high fever.
-No, I can get a high fever. Meat I can eat but it's not favorite.
-Fat of meat?
-I have an aversion for fat.
-Eggs?
-Eggs I like.
-What else you like?
-All this is what I like and I have a slight aversion to milk. And coffee aggravates.
-How many times you would underline aversion fat, yourself?
-3 times. And as I told you I can't drink coffee. This realization of dizziness.
-Now you can't drink. Before?
-Before I drunk very much.
-Now if you drink coffee, sensation of dizziness increases.
-Yes, so I didn't try to drink at all. But before I could drink 3-4 cups the day.
-No problem, no affecting your sleep?
-No, I could drink before I go to sleep and it was no problem.
-When you wake up in the morning is OK or there is a problem?
-It's OK my sleep is good, is refreshing.
-You sleep in a particular position? You like to sleep in a particular position?
-Yes, it's better on the left side.
-Do you perspire during sleep?
-During sleep no but usually I perspire.
-Where mostly?
-In the axillar region.
-What about this cervical region or back?
-Not especially, maybe the feet.
-Cold perspiration, clammy, sticky?
-A little bit and I have the extremities cold.
-Do you have to wear socks in bed?
-Yes.
-Do you take the shocks out during sleep?
-Yes after some time.
-Your nails are strong or brittle?
-Brittle.
-The eggs that you like must be boiled?
-Soft boiled usually.
-Why you laugh? You realize as you said your symptoms?
-The remedy. I was thinking also about this remedy but I'm not very sure.
I think I forgot to say that I took Calcarea carbonica.
-When?
-After Lycopodium, after that aggravation somebody recommended me to take Calcarea.
I also took LN potencies and it was good effect I might say but after some time
it ceased this effect. Then I tried to take a C30, I think I didn't feel much effect.
-You didn't feel anything with C30.
Do you have a problem looking downwards from high place?
-I don't like it.
-Do you have vertigo, dizziness, things like that?
-No, just a kind of fear. I also ate a lot since the childbirth, I put a lot of kilos.
Because eating seems to ameliorate in general. It made me feel very good.
I put 8-9 kilos.
-How much salt do you use? Normal, more than normal?
-I like salt but I don't know if I like more than the others, I don't think I put very much.
-It's not something excessive.
-No.
-You cry easily?
-Not so easily.
-You like consolation?
-Yes it doesn't bother me. I like now.
-You like consolation from your husband or from your friends, from anybody?
-Not from anybody. I think I need some kind of help now because I have too many things to do
and consolation if it is followed by some help is very good.
-You are practical.
-This kind of consolation.
-No nonsense. You have a big problem. I'm afraid something is going on with your labyrinth,
a little bit of inflammation, sub-acute, but let's see.
Do you have clear mind? Do you remember? You study and you learn?
-Yes I think it's not affected.
Only sometimes if I am too busy and I have too many things to do, I become more forgetful.
After a busy day it may happen I can't remember very well a telephone number.
There were some cancers in the family. My father died from cancer 6 years ago
and I think also the grand father, the father of my father had cancer but he died in very old age,
85 with cancer.
-Do you bite your nails?
-No.
-The foot nails do they enter in the flesh?
-The water you drink is how much, your thirst is normal?
-It's not so big, maybe less than normal.
-Do you prefer warm drinks, cold drinks or depends on the season?
-Not warm like tea but not very cold,
-Because again you are afraid of the cold.
-Yes.
-But you would prefer cold?
-Not very cold.
-In general you will say you are a person who is aggravated by cold?
-Yes.
-And you are also aggravated by wet cold weather?
-Not so much, by the cold especially but also I'm aggravated by sun.
I do not like to walk in the sun, I must have something on my head to cover the head.
Otherwise I feel weak and it's not good.
-You are very sensitive to sun?
-I should say yes.
-Milk you never drink?
-I drink but I don't like, especially the boiled milk.
-You drink it.
-Not so much, I prefer yogurt, cheese.
-If they tell you have to drink a glass of milk, you will be able to drink it?
-Yes I will be able but I don't like it.
-You can drink it pure or if you put cocoa?
-I can drink but for instance when I put in breakfast some milk, I forget to drink it
because I don't like it. I have to force myself to drink the milk because I know it's healthy.
-You think of the health that you need some milk but you can not drink it.
-Yes.
-The desire for cheese is really very strong? Pathological desire?
-No.
-For vegetables?
-I think it's normal.
-Fruits?
-Normal.
-Sweets.
-Oh sweets I like them exaggerated.
-And the aversion to fat also.
-Yes.
-The desire for eggs normal?
-Normal I think.
-Do you see any special dreams which are repeated?
-Yes, I may have sometimes clairvoyant dreams but not very often.
-These dreams are always something bad will happen or it can be this or that?
-Not necessarily something bad.
-Sometimes it's going to happen and you see it in your dreams?
-Yes, for instance before my father has died, 9 months before when I didn't know
he was ill, I was dreaming he told me he will die because he had cancer. It was true.
-Before he knew he had cancer.
-Yes and then I went to see him, he was quite OK. He had no problems.
I couldn't start to check him because he seemed to be very healthy.
And dreams of the dead, some dead relatives.
-Are you jealous?
-I don't think so.
-You can tight your clothes around your neck?
-Yes.
-You can sleep in the afternoon?
-I can but I don't like very much.
-Because you lose time or because you wake up unrefreshed.
-Because if I sleep too much I have a bad sensation.
-Over sleeping makes you feel bad in general.
-In the afternoon yes. I'm more tired.
-How is your energy at this moment? How would you classify your energy?
-I think it's good now, I used to be more tired before.
-When did you take Calcarea carb. 30? How long ago?
-More than 1 year.
-But you noticed no effect with Calcarea carbonica?
-After C30 no. But after the LN potencies yes, it was good.
-Did you take Conium also?
-No.
-Belladonna?
-Belladonna for some colds.
-If you lie on left is better for you dizziness?
-No, it's just a position that I fall asleep more easily.
-Not that if you have dizziness and you lie on the left, you are better?
-No.
-OK.
-This case is which group?
The first thing we have to think is the remedies which she took before.
For which she had a positive reaction, were they correct, yes or no?
Should they have been taken, yes or no?
The remedies she took, Staphysagria, Lycopodium, Arnica...
-I took Staphysagria, Arnica and I think also Aconite before the operation,
a small dose, Lycopodium, Calc. carb., Nat. mur. and for the flu Arsenicum and Silica.
For some colds I took sometimes Belladonna or Aconite.
-She says, she had a positive reaction from Staphysagria. What did you feel?
-I felt better psychologically because of the problems I had in the family.
So I could support them much better.
-Then you had a good reaction also from?
-Form Nat. mur. and after Lycopodium that rumbling disappeared.
-But you said you had an aggravation.
-Yes and in general was not good.
-So Staphysagria and Nat. mur.
You have here a case in which Staphysagria and Nat. mur. have acted.
She felt better but did not touch deeper levels.
The fears did not change the substratum but definitely there was some grief
and that was taken away.
The question is at this moment if these 2 remedies were not given could we give
the next remedy now or maybe do we have to go again to Nat. mur. for instance
and prescribe straight away Nat. mur. and then continue.
We don't have the absolute control of the case but the most probable is according to
my understanding that both Staphysagria and Nat. mur. were a level of grief
that was printed upon the level on which she has been living.
The incident with the operation brings out some fear which is deep inside
and makes a full blown case.
So according to my understanding this is a case that gets Staphysagria, Nat. mur.
and gets the next remedy, whatever it might be, so we discuss these 3 remedies.
Actually she was born here and this was added like a cold.
These layers are almost like acutes that come on top of you and they don't give you
the same remedy because an acute can give you the same remedy, as Cal. carbonica.
Here it might be an acute and give Calc. carbonica and both these levels can just go away.
This is not the case.
We don't know of course if this was Sulphur and it was given Sulphur from the very beginning,
what would take? It would take care of this as well? Doubtful.
I think these remedies were really indicated.
I can not say now because they are gone it's history.
I don't know the details, how much salt she needed here, for instance.
I doubt whether it was a typical case.
Anyhow now we are in a position to go deeper in the analysis and find what is the indicated remedy.
What is it? Anybody wants to give me the reasons why he thinks is this or that remedy?
-When we look at the case and we look at the rubrics and compare them with her story
especially looking at all the fears that are present in her case,
I'm quite sure that this is a case of Calc. carbonica.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
-Very sure?
-Then why when she took Calc. carbonica never acted?
-It could be, as you said, that a kind of shock was necessary to bring this remedy up
in the organism or it was so that the potency may have been too low.
-Good explanation. Anybody else is interested to speak?
-It's very interested for me that nobody spoke in favor of Phosphorus.
Show me the Repertorisation Margaret, you put so many symptoms.
Where is coming Phosphorus?
In spite of the fact that she mentions a lot of fears of Phosphorus,
even fear of thunderstorm, fear of dying.
-She sleeps on the left side.
-And how is her thirst? -Thirst less.
-Out.
-But nobody also spoke in favor of Conium. Why you left Conium out?
Vertigo turning in bed and if you concentrate in the vertigo area,
if you are a keynote prescriber of a superficial prescriber, you give Conium and hope for the best.
-It's possible that she may be fainted due to pain and that was the reason why her soul left
the body before the anesthesia was completely acting.
-No, she was not aware really. She thought she was aware.
She could not hear anything, she could not feel pain, so what kind of awareness?
She thought she was aware. What happened actually was they injected the anesthesia
and then the etheric body started going out and was stuck on a place where it was dark.
She said, I was a dark point. This is a terrifying experience because many people
have felt either due to injections or due to taking drugs, marihuana or LCD,
they are stuck in a place where it is very frightening. And she got a fright definitely.
She comes back and the fear remains.
That means with her in depth there was a fear of dying, a fear of death, that was the big issue,
that came up more strong after the experience with the anesthesia.
-The way she describes this, that she had been demanded or asked to breathe.
I estimate that they have been accident with anesthesia and she was actually on a point of dying.
Or it was a near death experience and that is why I suggest to give Aconite.
I wanted to support what my pre-speaker said. I have been in anesthesia for 8 years
and my experience is that when the anestheologist lets the patient wake quicker
then the remedy you have given to make the muscle dysfunction,
then the patient experience a terrible fright.
One colleague of mine, an anestheologist too had experienced this, as patient
and he told me he couldn't imagine a more horrible fear than this.
You are in a state but you can't move but at the same time you are already conscious
but you can't breathe. The doctor says breathe please, as a sign that they took out the tube
before it was already ready that the muscles would function again.
-That's correct, most probably they were trying for some time to get her out and
eventually as she was coming back into her body, she started hearing
but then it was not exact thing that you can move, like the "mora" state at night.
You may feel that, as the body goes out, you are awake but you can't move at all.
These experiences can be very frightening and these are experiences
which we go through death.
I had a case 3 months in coma, 2 months in coma in America and 1 month in the hospital
and he was describing the experience of living, he was living.
And he said it was really terrifying. He said, I felt alone in the cosmos.
I was just a point where no connection with anything, it was all empty and I was there.
Can you imagine? Alone. Sometimes you are alone, you have this feeling of isolation
which is very deep and disturbing and you are here in the world, you can go out and
meet your dog, your cat. That's why we have dogs and cats, because we can connect.
I have a very good cat, lots of animals.
-After my scientific colleagues is a different question.
I just heard from the colleague she said that she took Aconite before the operation.
So I would like to hear from you if there is in your observation a connection
with Aconite before the operation, with the operation?
-No, don't take a remedy if you don't have the symptoms of the remedy, that's the rule.
You go to the operation and you are terrified, I'm going to die, then you can take Aconite
and you will go more calm.
You go to the operation without real fear of dying and you take Aconite,
the only thing you may do is just create the fear, create a proving.
Think the same way always. The remedy can act only when the symptoms are present.
-You are describing this fear of being alone in cosmos in Camphora in your Materia Medica.
-That's different. I'm talking about an after-death experience, here.
I don't know whether I gave him Opium and he started coming back and then
I gave him Sulphur and then things like that.
I'm talking about an experience he had, while he was out of his body, in coma.
Out of his body the fear was terrifying he says because I felt alone.
There was no entity. I was there and there was nobody and there was an empty space.
These experiences are frightening, terrifying etc. but they can leave no mark.
This case of mine left on mark on him, no trauma.
-She said after the death of the grandparents began discussion with dead and
it is a strong [?] but the interpretation about fear of death and  out of body experiences
I can not share because there is a lot of different reservations.
I had a terrible accident and the doctors said to my wife it's finished
and my heart worked still I was 6 weeks later I was awakened.
I remember nothing of dark experiences.
-Sure, not everybody who has an experience comes back and has after effects.
This is what I say and this is confirming. There is no question about that.
What she is having is not absolutely and exclusively the result of this experience.
Not at all.
Who will prescribe Aconite? Who will prescribe Calcarea carb.?
Who will prescribe Cocculus? Nobody. Conium? Nobody. Cannabis Indica? 3.
That means there is another 18 people who did not vote.
They don't say anything.
Let me see the symptoms because I have to give you an explanation why I prescribed the remedy.
You put everything my god! Go further, let me see if you have the symptoms I'm looking for.
The symptom is not there, it doesn't matter.
-George one rubric that I put down is not there, ailments from anesthesia, Phosphorus.
-This was when anesthesia was with chloroform. They don't do it anymore.
Do they give chloroform?
-No.
-This was the idea of Kent by that time and then he connected the two.
Fear of thunderstorms is not there, only 1.
She said it in such a tone that I could not make it better, make it twice.
Calcarea will be stronger because Calcarea is in italics.
It is my opinion that this is Calcarea carbonica, I will tell you why.
Because we have the fears which they fit, fear of death, fear of insanity, of thunderstorms
they fit with Calc. carb.
This might not be enough because they fit also or they are close with Aconitum and Phosphorus.
So therefore we need some differential points.
Which are the differential points that you can say?
They are the cold feet, wearing shocks to get them warm and then during the night
she takes them out. We have said that repeatedly Calc. carbon. she said exactly this.
Then she said out of food, she stressed desire for sweets and then she said
my feet sweat. Is it cold? Yes. Is it clammy? Yes.
So these are the points which confirm the fears plus the fact she is putting weight lately
for the last years. Plus the vertigo from high places or fear, that was quite strong.
Plus the fact that she is a chilly person, I feel the cold.
Where is the contradiction for Calc. carb.?
There is no contradiction but she took Calc. carb. 30. Nothing.
I say ask the pharmacy what they have given instead of Calc. carbonica.
Most probably instead of Calc. carbonica she took nothing, she took placebo.
And that is what happens.
-I think another strong symptom for Calcarea carb. because she said I'm a slow person
and I don't like to be pushed.
-You see with Phosphorus or Aconite you have to see much more the intensity of the fear.
The eyes, the fear is there.
And then Phosphorus and Aconite are much more fast.
Therefore this is a typical case and she belongs actually to the uppermost group here.
Either uppermost second or first group. Low first group.
-George I don't want to argue against Calc. carb. I just want to say about the sun.
I've written down here worse sun, must cover head in walking.
Put that in the Repertorisation. Find worse sun.
Do you have the symptom?
-Yes.
-How strong you would like to put it?
-Put it 3 times.
-It was already there.
-No change at all.
You can not change because of this, it's OK sensitivity to the sun.
It's already recorded in the provings that has a sensitivity to the sun.
You don't change unless it is the whole case revolves around sun, then you change.
-George I have one question. The timidity appearing in public,
it's strong in Calcium silicata but it is in Calcium carbonicum, did you see it?
-In the Calcium carbonicum yes, it has a lot of timidity.
-Appearing in public?
-Appearing in public is not to make you sick. Lycopodium will become sick.
They will have burning in the stomach and Gelsemium they will be trembling.
They are sick. Calc. carb. is not so strong but it is there, timidity is there.
So, no question that we have to prescribe Calc. carbon. for this case.
This case also now appears to be clear as Calc. carb. case.
-If you look under the rubric vertigo when turning the head, Calcarea is there in 4th degree.
If it was not there, would you have hesitance to prescribe Calcarea?
-No, not at all.
-This is the main complain.
-It doesn't matter, once the case is clear as a total case, forget the details.
If you don't have a clear case and you have to treat only the details, then you pay attention.
But in this case even the vertigo fits, sleeps on the left side, look at it.
There are 4-5 remedies who say, I really like to sleep on the left side.
Magnesia, Calcarea, Bryonia...Calcarea is not there!
No, in my Repertory I have Calcarea.
-... has added it.
-Who has added it?
-I have it also, you put it in.
-Yes, there is no question. Here it's missing. Left side twice, italics.
In my mind I can't remember, it's 40 years of doing all this.
If you see my Repertory, I have 5 Repertories, you see the oldest one the things
are falling off and in this Repertory, the very first Repertory I had added Calcarea carbonica
since 35 years, sleeps on left side.
Now I'm thinking this was originally there. I was sure originally was there.
-I, too, have Calcium carbonicum at first place when I repertorize but I was disturbed
because it didn't have the clairvoyant dreams.
-Clairvoyant dreams to be pathology, you have to have disturbing you.
She saw perhaps 1 or 2 in her life. Everybody has clairvoyant dreams in this way.
When everybody has, you don't pay attention.
The only difference is you don't pay very much attention.
I am the most clairvoyant, I see dreams all the time, this is going to happen and that.
Forget it, because I pay attention. It's not a symptom to change the prescription.
Under no circumstances when you have a full case, you change it because you don't
see clairvoyant dreams or dreams in general.
This is not dreaming here, what we are doing. We try to be as much aware, as possible.
Dreams is something. How many times I've used dreams in my prescribing?
Maybe 2-3 times that I was led by a dream.
But when you prescribe thousands of case, I have prescribed at least 200.000 cases
personally, paper cases and live cases.
And only 3 cases that it was confirmed, not even lead by a dream.
What is this? This is nonsense and dangerous because you can be mislead.
You have a dream like this? You take that remedy. Forget it.
On the other hand it is good doing research, if it is serious research it is very good
but don't confuse the issues and make something which is not serious,
serious and the serious one you just destroy.
-But we strongly confirm symptoms like dreams of falling Belladonna.
-Yes, that's where I would use it.
I would use it in Thuja, I would ask do you dream falling and many times I would confirm
but not be lead by it.
That's what I say, it's few times that you will have that.
Also in the Repertories is a lot of information which is useless.
Do you know how difficult it is to take out an information or put it in an information
before you know what you are doing?
You can not imagine how difficult it is to come to the decision this symptom is useless.
We have to have Institutions, people researching and everybody's experience.
Did you have and experience with this symptom? Nobody had it.
When there is seriously working all over the world, then we can start refining the Repertories.
When you have reliable information.
Now everybody gets up, gives a case, when I read cases in Journals
"I was lead to prescribe by this dream and this dream of a tree growing and going up..."
I say, why you tell lies?
You prescribe this remedy because you found a keynote which was coldness of the abdomen
and you prescribe Menyanthes and now you made a whole story and you say Menyanthes has this,
trees falling up and down. No.
It is because you found a keynote and through the keynote you were lead to the remedy
and then the person also had 1-2 dreams.
First of all, in order to take a dream into consideration, it has to be constant repeatedly.
That means it's a chemistry in the body which brings you, when you go to sleep in a
certain position, in the night, there is a chemistry.
And the chemistry brings again and again a pattern and the pattern is depicted on a dream;
then you have the dream every second day.
That is a very important dream. But to have a dream once or twice...
I dreamt of snakes. Dreams of snakes you have to have it repeatedly.
Once everyone has seen dreams of snakes, at least one time in his life.
I have seen 5 times.
-Which potency?
-Very high. 50M! OK 10M.