-You got Calcarea carb. 10M one dose.
-Immediately after I had some pains in the sacroiliac region, I think bilateral
and that lasted for about 24 hours.
I think this is an old symptom which I had after child birth.
-This pain after child birth?
-Yes for some months I had this pain and it came back for 1 day, then it passed.
But it was immediately after I took the remedy, it was very quick reaction.
Then I noticed that the night after I took the remedy, I woke up early in the morning
with repeated sneezing. This is also a symptom that I had before.
-That was a cold that had started already?
-There was a cold 2 days after the remedy, after the party here it was very cold last time
and I felt chilly and then I developed a cold. I also felt very bad psychologically.
I had a kind of strong depression. I was thinking about the past, about some wrong things,
the death of my father, things like this.
-And you cried?
-Yes.
-For how long?
-I was here, I could not manifest myself for much but for 1 day or more I cried,
I didn't come to the lecture. So these were the immediate changes.
Then some changes that lasted, I can say the dizziness has gone, I feel quite OK
from this point of view and I feel that I am not so tired, I have enough strength.
-To carry on with your work.
-Yes but I repeated the remedy because before coming here I had a kind of anticipation syndrome,
I was very worried about how shall I feel here because I had some symptoms this summer
and I felt that they might come back.
So I took again the remedy before I travel in LN potencies because I thought not to have
an aggravation, so I took LM potencies.
I took for 3 days before the travel and then when I was here, I continued to take until last Saturday.
About 8 times.
-That means 8 days?
-No, I took 1 dose every 2 days.
-So 16 days all together.
-Yes and I felt very well.
After about 2 days that I started to take my worries were not so big,
I consider that I actually cope very well with the situation and I felt quite good.
I noticed that my appetite has reduced a little bit.
-That's good.
-And maybe the menses are a bit less abundant than before but still they are quite abundant.
-Still clotted?
-Yes and they come in 28 days instead of 30, 32 that they came before.
The sleep is normal, I tend not to sleep so much on the left side now but sometimes
I sleep on the left side and sometimes on my back with the hands up.
-Which you didn't do before?
-Yes they were times that I did it but in May I didn't notice this,
I think I slept very much on the left side.
-What about your fears, fear of death, of insanity, of dark, of flying?
-These fears are still rather strong. This is the main problem.
It is a kind of a state of anxiety that maybe I did not describe very well last time.
This fear of death is a kind of a permanent idea but it's not a fear of immediate death.
It is more the idea that one day we shall all die and this makes me regard the daily life
with a kind of sadness.
-Are you thinking about the after death situation?
-Yes, I think it is a kind of fear about the unknown. I don't know if this idea bothers me.
It is quite normal but maybe after the operation, after the experience I had which was
quite frightening. But not immediately after, after some time this started.
-You will consider that fear of the dark is still there?
-Yes it's more strong I think, to be alone in the dark, especially if I'm alone at home.
-Fear of insanity?
-Yes this is still present because I don't know if these ideas are so strong in my mind.
I think it's not normal and I can perceive that.
-Is this a fear or is some thoughts?
-It's a kind of fear, I think it's not normal to have these thoughts and I'm concerned about it.
-So you wanted to say something more about this anxiety?
-I noticed there is a fear that I maybe had also last time, it's a kind of new symptom and
I didn't mention it.
When I travel somewhere, it may happen that I may wake up from sleep with an idea
that I don't know exactly where I am and this produces for 1 sec or so a kind of fear.
Then I realize where I am and everything is OK but for a very short time it's a kind of panic.
And it happened also at home when I arrived, 2-3 times I had this sensation until
I could adapt to the place.
From this point of view I was worried when I took again the remedy, thinking that now
I'm travelling again and maybe this sensation will come again.
-And it did not come.
-It came only once.
Actually when I'm far away from home I have these fears more strong.
When I'm at home I feel quite fine. I don't feel these anxieties so much because
everything is familiar but when I go in another place, it's worse.
-I want to ask you some questions also. Your feet continue to be cold?
-Yes. I'm quite chilly, I need to dress very warm.
-And the desire eggs is still there, as it was.
-It is but I don't think I said it was a strong desire. I like eggs...
-But not very strong. The fear of high places have you checked?
-It is there. After eating you feel better?
-I think that I ate less. I don't feel so much this need to eat.
-Cold weather in general still affects you?
-Yes I'm chilly.
-I don't remember the nails.
-Brittle, soft.
-And they continue to be soft?
-Yes, maybe not so fragile as before but still they are soft.
When the weather gets cold, I have the tendency to get easily a cold.
There was a change for instance in the temperature from 45 degrees to 15,
in the beginning of September and I developed a cold, strong chills and a fever to 38,6.
-And lasted for how long?
-Very short because I took Aconite. Maybe I should not have taken anything.
-How high?
-C30.
-One time?
-One time and it was finished that day or next.
-Did you take any other remedy?
-No.
-The hey fever you don't know?
-I have a rhinorrhea, usually in the morning when it is colder, I sneeze maybe a few times
and then there is a rhinorrhea and then it is gone during the day.
-This is how it was before or has changed now?
-Maybe it is a little bit more than before but I had it before also.
-The hey fever was mostly in Autumn and Spring or it was all the time?
-All the time, it is connected with a sensation of coldness.
If it is cold outside, in the morning especially, I get stronger sneezing.
I also have another symptom, pain of the cervical region during night time when lying in bed.
-If you wake up in the night?
-Yes if I wake up I feel there is a pain and in the morning also when I wake up I feel
this kind of stiffness. I must have a good position of the head in order to feel comfortable.
-You have said you had vomiting from motion.
-I think it has improved this, I didn't notice it here but I sit mainly in the front of the car.
-You had difficulty falling asleep.
-Now I don't have that but I wake up rather early more than before.
I tend to wake up about 5-6 o'clock.
-Do you think we must have a remedy or do you feel we should wait.
-No, I feel rather well, especially after I repeated the remedy, I feel it did a good action
without having an aggravation but I felt good.
-OK thank you.
-So what shall we do with this case? Wait, repeat, go higher?
Who says wait? Exactly, this is the idea.