-The baby is due in 5 weeks. At the moment I have some problems.
I have very strong edemas in the legs.
This morning I still was wearing stockings for compression but now I have to remove them
because of the heat.
In the mornings I also have edemas of the hands and feeling numbness, especially in my thumbs.
It's not painful but it's very uncomfortable feeling.
My blood pressure was rising since June. The last value was 150 over 80.
And in the last urine examination, I had protein in my urine.
-How much?
-It's 2 axes but I don't know, I can't tell you how much exactly it was.
The medical assistance in this gynecologist office, where I go, told me that having up to 15
leucocytes per site field in the urine was normal and in the last urine check, I had 17 leucocytes.
The reason why I'm emphasing this is that I'm a bit worried since in May 1998 I had a severe
pyelonephritis with septicemia which was very bad.
One other thing which I personally don't think is that important is that my hemoglobin rate
is going down month by month and in the last check, it was 9.9.
-How she feels psychologically?
-I confronted a lot of difficulties.
I tried to find a way to deal with the situation and I also have tried to look for help.
The first place in the end where I have to go is to go and seek social security
and having to do this, for me was really terrible.
For me the feeling really was as if they had taken away my dignity because once I get money
from them, they have certain requirements, I have to obey.
I'm not allowed to have a car anymore, I must live in an apartment that has so and so square meters.
They told me that I have to close my practice, my office.
I'm not allowed to continue practicing Homeopathy and so on.
For me this is really terrible but there is actually no other way around it because my debts
have grown so high that the bank just refuses to give me any more money.
-Her boyfriend is not in contact with her?
-No, he hasn't contact me anymore since 2nd May  of this year.
And what made the whole thing so difficult for me is that I felt into depression which
was so severe that it paralyzed me.
-Is she crying easily?
-In the last weeks yes.
When I'm excited and somebody really turns to me and listens yes; otherwise not.
When somebody is really paying attention to me and really going into my situation.
This feeling I had during the depression, being paralyzed, the feeling of not being able
to do anything anymore, that's not new but it was never so strong as it is now.
What I realized over the last time is that being alone really tortures me.
It's really painful for me and it's breaking me. And I also had to realize that people
on whom I actually counted that something would becoming from them, for example the parents
of the child's father, who in the beginning encouraged me, come on, have the child,
we'll help you, we'll be there, now when I really need it, there is nothing.
Neither financially, nor emotionally, just nothing.
-The parents of the father?
-And right now there is just chaos in my life because I have no urge, no motivation
what soever to get my strength together and to get things done. I just let things pass by
I postpone things, there is no energy whatsoever and of course surely this leads to consequences
and to difficulties.
-Does she cook for herself?
-Every once in a while.
-She cleans the house?
-Sometimes but it could be done more often.
-And my problem with my kind of orderliness is such that I can part for many things.
I keep small memorabilia even small piece of paper because reminds me of some
wonderful situation that I would hate to forget and because of this I have lots of crap
at home that actually isn't necessary.
-How is her thirst?
-Almost unchanged.
I need 2 lit the day water.
-For cold?
-I prefer cold. It's more agreeable.
-How is her reaction to weather? She needs fresh air?
-I can not tolerate heat at all and I'm really happy if it gets cooler because I feel better then.
-She eats fruits now?
-I don't like fruits at all, every once in a while I eat some but I have to force myself to do it.
-Does she know if she still grinds her teeth?
-I have no idea because I sleep alone.
-Is she tolerating is somebody wants to say good words for her? She likes it?
-Yes, I like it very much but on the other hand it creates such an upheaval in me that
I can start to cry.
-She is still sighing?
-Yes.
I always have the feeling that I'm going to other people's nerves with my sighing
it must be really annoying if somebody is sighing all the time.
-She drinks milk?
-A little bit in my tea but otherwise not.
-She still smokes?
-Unfortunately.
The desire for cigarettes has been extremely strong in between.
Now it is the way it has been before.
-Out of this period, since we saw her, which is the worst?
From May until now which is the worst? Is September, August, July?
She said last few weeks was much worse.
-I would say the last 4 weeks things have been worse but it also has been bad before
these 4 weeks already. But the last 4 weeks, things got even worse.
-How much salt she wants?
-I take quite a lot of salt.
I like it a lot, I don't need it but I like it a lot.
I want to say something which I noticed frequently.
I very frequently swallow the wrong way, for example when I'm drinking I swallow and
it goes down the wrong tube and I have to cough a lot.
If you would like to know, I could report about the physical reactions I had after taking Belladonna.
-Yes.
-I developed tiny little warts in different areas of my body and underneath my arm and other places,
then I begun perspiring on my feet again which had not been the case for the last 3-4 years.
-She had complained if she remembers, the main complain was tension in here and in
the back of the neck and cramping, that was the main complain, how is that?
-That had remained unchanged.
-Why is she not mentioning it? She mentions some other symptoms but not the main symptom
which she complained the first time.
-I would report it, I also have written it down, it's just so many things.
I've noticed two things about this tension. It aggravates either when I feel insecure
or when I do mental exertion. That's the other time when it increases.
-What was the blood pressure when we first examined her.
-It was 120 over 70 for a long period of time, also 110 over 60.
-Before pregnancy?
-Yes and during pregnancy.
I sometimes have some burning in my stomach but I think that's normal in pregnancy.
-And physical exertion, I can not take much at all, in the slightest exertion I get
heartbeat very easily, palpitations.
I wake up every two hours now and have difficulties falling asleep again.
I have salivation from my mouth at night, I used to have it in former years and this
has come back now.
I had a feeling on numbness in the entire left arm accompanied them
and also coordination problem, I had problems forming words, speaking.
-She had two episodes like this?
-1 or 2 I can't remember exactly.
-Anything else?
-My lymph nodes are swollen in the throat and I often had that in former times also.
Physically that's all.
-In the first interview she had complained of headache in the morning, in waking.
-Not anymore. After sleeping I'm often more tired than before. Sleep is not refreshing.
-In the morning or afternoon?
-In the morning I need a long period after I'm really clear.
And this also happens in the afternoon, if I sleep in the afternoon.
Right now I have the feeling that I'm too open, everything can enter me directly and I feel
as if I have a lack of immune system on my mental, emotional area.
It's already a couple of months back that I saw a movie of a young environmentalist
in the Unites States who are fighting for these huge trees that are cut.
So the police started going against them and they smeared a kind of poison stuff into their eyes,
some chemical and it's something that shakes me up to today, just the imagination that things
like that are possible and anything cruel I see I can not shield myself of, it really goes right into me.
One last thing I would really like to mention because it's really important to me and
then I think I will stop, even though I have some more points in my list, is that I'm absolutely naive.
Whoever comes towards me I always suspect that he has best intention, best motivation
and here in this course I don't get disappointed often but I would say in the "real world" it happens
to me quite often. So I'm really deep down naive.
-She believes that somebody has something...
-Yes I easily believe and I always assume that these people are honest with me and
have good intentions and please don't give them a homework that they have to work on my case
now during the break because they gonna kill me when I come out.
-She was reading my mind actually.
-Maybe.
-OK we go inside to the class.
Let's see the rubrics that we can use in this case.
17 symptoms food and drinks, aversion milk, sighing underlines 3 times, aversion fruits twice,
cold drinks desire, collects many things, sentimental, desire salt, warts upper limbs
perspiration on foot, cervical region, pregnancy during, palpitation of heart,
salivation sympathetic.
Do you agree with this or you want to add something or take away?
-Take away.
-What you want to take away?
-George I miss swalling the wrong way and I think point 7, consolation ameliorates,
I think is a problem.
-Swallowing the wrong way, put this. We can not find it in the Repertory.
-And also the point consolation ameliorates, I think she said I like consolation but it's average,
I'm very deeply touched.
-Not aggravate, she is deeply touched.
In the previous interview she said, she did not like consolation.
In the previous interview it was underlined 3 times that she did not like consolation.
This time she did not say that I do nor perceive that but don't stuck in these little things
because we have big things here.
What are the big things?
You like this symptomatology?
Too many symptoms. So which symptoms you want out? Which symptoms you take out?
Swelling of feet.
-Complain during pregnancy.
-You want it out?
-Yes.
-But the complains are during pregnancy really.
All, what she has is because of pregnancy.
In this case because we don't have much time, we have to differentiate
between the following remedies.
Phosphorus, Ignatia, Pulsatilla, Nat. mur.
There are symptoms for these 4 remedies.
Out of the 4 remedies, which is the one that you will prescribe.
I would like to hear who will prescribe Phosphorus? 5 Ignatia? 28. Pulsatilla? 19. Nat. mur. 19.
So Ignatia is the preference of the class. You took Ignatia.
But after Belladonna did she take Ignatia?
-No.
-You took no other remedy.
-What is my problem with Ignatia? I'll tell you.
Because she has some sighing and aversion fruits, two strong keynotes both absolutely there.
My problem is first that Ignatia will not be presenting her case like she did.
She is too expressive, too open and too crying and in front of the camera.
I asked her whether she is crying, yes, in front of the camera also she can not hold back.
That is one thing that does not give me the impression of Homeopathy.
Another problem is that she is too warm for Ignatia.
Another problem is, last time if you remember, she was much more painful
and do you like consolation?
No, it was underlined 3 times. Now there was a change in that psychology,
she would like consolation
but she is in a vulnerable state and this consolation, this showing sympathy rises
too much emotions.
That does not go with Nat. mur. or Ignatia, it goes with Pulsatilla.
Now the first complain she says is I'm swelled up, I kept water.
Which is the remedy, out of these 4, that will do that in pregnancy?
Pulsatilla. The remedy will be Pulsatilla for her pathology.
Which is the remedy that she would say, I feel better in fresh air? Pulsatilla.
So therefore what is the Expert System saying?
The Expert System says by far Pulsatilla is the prescription because you see you took away
ailments from pregnancy? You put complains during pregnancy?
Phosphorus because there is thirst for cold water. Who likes cold water?
Pulsatilla likes cold things, cold water but is not thirsty. Phosphorus is thirsty.
Is Phosphorus sympathetic? Very sympathetic yes. She is sympathetic.
If you want to prescribe on pathology, you can prescribe Apis but we try now to prescribe more
on the totality of the symptoms.
Do we have a totality? Well, we have.
The numbness in the morning is not a rubric that you can base a prescription.
For the same reasons that we excluded Ignatia, we must exclude Nat. mur. because
she is not the type at this moment, she is not the type which is close. She would not have cried
so much and we have complains from heat, which creates a kind of varicose veins situation.
Which is the remedy which in the heat the legs are swollen and we have varicose veins?
The remedy is Pulsatilla.
Concerning Apis what you would expect more?
-Thirst less.
-Thirst less is one but also the swelling will be appearing primarily under the eyes.
Not only that but do you understand her psychological state at the moment?
What she does? She does nothing, she just smokes.
She sits around and says, I have no initiative, I don't do anything, I sit around, I can
imagine her sitting around, looking for hours, doing nothing.
Is this correct?
-No.
If it's not so that I'm doing nothing but if I do something it's not what I should be doing
but what I want to do right now.
-But if we come to the last remark which is important for her which says what?
I am naive, I believe everybody who comes along and tells me things.
This is something you will not hear from Ignatia, Nat. mur. or Apis.
You may here it with Phosphorus but in a different manner or with Pulsatilla.
Pulsatilla is the remedy that says, I believe everything. Easily persuaded,
you tell her something, she will believe, she will follow etc.
This is what she said but for me what is the most dramatic change is from aversion consolation,
now she says, I would like to have consolation.
The only thing is that it touches me so much that brings out a lot of emotion and I start crying.
-I hate that it might a translation problem. In German there is another word, which is a bit
different from consolation.
What I mean is compassion. I never, in general, had an aversion to consolation.
Perhaps it has been a misunderstanding in translation.
-OK, ask her if there is any time where she feels worse. What is this time?
-In the morning, when I wake up because of unrefreshed sleep.
-Psychologically when she feels worse?
-I don't know.
If I may add something, I've noticed that I have a craving or I like creamy things.
Yogurt with honey or sweets.
-Yogurt is creamy? What about fat? Fat in meat.
-I haven't' been eating meat in the past years because I don't like it much and also
because of ethical reasons, because I feel sorry for the animals.
I saw a movie in which animals that had been transported in trucks around Europe
to be slaughtered, how they are treated and since then I only eat meat every 2-3 weeks.
I can not eat food that is swimming in olive oil but on the other hand butter I like a lot.
-Butter you like a lot? Add butter.
Now we'll ask another question in which she will say yes. Taken Pulsatilla before, when?
-I took Pulsatilla once at the end of 1995, I was the speaker of the class, that was at the end of
our practitioner School and I had to cry so much of each mate that was leaving at the end
of the School.
-And she took Pulsatilla during that time?
-One dose C200.
-And what was the effect of Pulsatilla C200? Did she feel any effect?
-I didn't have to cry anymore.
-That's all.
-On that day I didn't cry anymore and I felt better. I felt lighter but I used to be addicted to  coffee.
-You still drink coffee now?
-No.
-Well, therefore Pulsatilla 200 is the prescription.