-I just want you to tell what you want me to do first. How I am now or what happened since?
-What happened since.
-So I have to do that very quick. The last remedy was Causticum LM 3 I think
which you told me to stop and wait, so that's what I did.
-The Causticum you have taken?
-Yes last time I was on Causticum.
-You were on Causticum which you had taken yourself or somebody gave it to you.
-You through the VES gave it to me.
-I gave it to you?
-No, I did a repertorization and it was about so many points only Causticum.
-So you took Causticum and then what happened?
-Then it was quite OK, the sugar level went down and after I came here you told me
to stop the LM, I stopped and I let it run freely and the sugar level was in the morning
between 100-140. And 2 hours after food went up to 200, which normally is supposed
to go up to 140 only.
The 10th of October I had lot of cramps in my calves and at 14th I had the herpes
in my left nostril up, which I know it from before and I had hot flushes and I didn't have
my period since July 1999. Around the middle of October I had a nightmares and restless
and hot and cold and gas and diarrhea in the morning. I have almost stool in the morning
about half an hour after I wake up and start moving.
It's always like gas and with urine together.
-With a lot of gas like an explosion?
-Yes, always like an explosion.
-Always explosion in the morning?
-Yes.
-Can you give me symptoms that are all along, instead of saying one day I had this and
one day I had that, give me symptoms you had all along, so I get an idea, a basic idea.
-OK, so I'm not going to tell... OK I have a list of them, I wrote them down,
so I can tell you.
There are a few things that happened during the time which are important I think.
Last year after I came back from here I had lot of energy and I opened the clinic attached
to my office, I was very happy about it but all the time I felt that I'm going to die,
I'm not going to the New Millennium, like I'm finishing to the end of 99, I had a knowledge.
I knew I'm going to die, I'm not going to move on the second Millennium. I didn't fear it at all,
I've just been sad to leave the family and my daughter got married, I had a grandson in July,
which made me very happy. Still now, it's like I feel like I fell in love the first time.
It's funny but when I hold him there is so much love. Then my other daughter got married
and I decided if anyway I'm going to die at the end of the year I better go and do something.
I wanted to see New Zealand, the things in the country were very bad for me the last year.
There were new rules, so at work I couldn't function as I like.
It's like they made me do things which are illegal through these rules, I felt while
I'm doing it I'm cheating. Like they sent volunteers before to (?) and they came to work
and all kind of tricks, people want them to do other things,
some companies wanted to bring them as foreign workers, so they start doing all kind of things,
paying money.
They changed the rules and I came to a point that I could send them, it didn't bother to
send them, I could send them and continue make a living but I told companies abroad that
it's illegal, they won't get a visa, they have to come in as a tourist and lie because
the farmers need them and they wanted these jobs, so all the sides wanted and people closed
their eyes but still I felt I can't.
So I just left the office, I left my daughters doing it, I felt very bad with it and
during last year, when I got diabetes, when I got the flu, I had an income tax inquiring.
I think it also came through these people and they wanted to check from 1994  till 1997,
then they add 1998 also and they treat me like a thief, they treated me so bad.
They said that the income went down and they want to know why, that probably I get money
from the companies who send the people and all kind of things which really annoyed me,
I was so angry, I shouted to them. They used to call me, making themselves like
they are calling the accountant by mistake and really hussle.
They were coming into my office which they are not allowed to, they have to deal with my
accountant not with me and then I got the diabetes and I was so angry.
One day I shouted to them, I said if you are a liar and you cheat, that's why you call me that.
So I didn't call you a liar, you behave like this.
You put me in a position that I can't do nothing, if these people come to you,
you can't do nothing, it doesn't matter what you say, you show them, you take everything out,
they go into every little detail of your life and you are helpless, the same with the government,
with these new rules that one clerk decided that because she is afraid of certain people.
So they put you...
-All this affected your health and the diabetes went up, what happened?
-I did get sugar, I didn't have before, I got a flu in March, last March 1999
and then I took the antibiotics and then within 5 days I had 700 sugar but I was so stressed.
After I look back I know that all the things together, these rules and the context and
everything was. On one side I wanted to get rid of this office actually.
I thought about cutting it, quitting and moving in full Homeopathy but I needed, you can't do it
because you owe people things, I had it for 20 years, you can't cut everything in one time.
Maybe because of my thinking about finishing what happened.
I always think that there is a connection, when you think about things, things come to help you
but not this way.
I wasn't ready.
-You decided to continue.
-My daughter got married in September and just a week before she got married
when the course started and I decided that I had enough from this crazy country and
if I'm not going out,
I'm going to have either heart attack or stroke because the pressure was so hard and the anger,
I used to go like this, I felt my head is blowing, so strong.
So I just went and booked a tour in New Zealand and then I said if it's New Zealand
then I go to Australia also, I took all my savings and ...
-You went for how long?
-A month and a half. I left beginning of November.
-This helped you health wise?
-Mentally great, fantastic. I took with me LM Causticum.
-Emotionally?
-Emotionally it was good. I had time to think about things and enjoy myself, really I had
full out of the problems.
When I came back I had income tax again and problems again but whatever.
-What I want to know is if you can give me some steady symptoms that were going on
all the time, for instance pressure was all the time, it's still there?
-This pressure is not there anymore, it's gone.
-The investigation has ended finally?
-Ended finally, I had to pay them cash some amount of money and get rid of it.
And that annoys me a lot because if I don't owe them, I don't owe them.
They couldn't find nothing but that's life, that's what is going on, so it's annoying.
-And you felt the injustice?
-Yes, there is a lot of injustice but now I came to know that I can't fight, I'm helpless,
I'm not strong enough to do it. All my life I used to fight, I used to stand, I used to do things.
Now the farmers call me why don't you do something to change the rules.
I said, that's it enough, 20 years I do the fights for you, now if you don't do it yourself
I don't care, I close the office and you get whatever you are supposed to get.
That's it, I just retreated, I went home, I'm at home now, I don't go to work,
I give good salaries.
The 5th of January we had flood, a lot of rains and the rain came at night into a terrace.
I live in the first floor and the water came this high into my clinic and ruined everything.
All the carpets, everything.
-But now you work with Homeopathy?
-A little bit, not much, I just had to take the carpets off and wait until they dry.
-But can you give me some of the symptoms?
-When the sugar goes up, when I'm eating I feel heavy, eyes are heavy, every time,
I feel dizzy.
-After eating you feel dizzy?
-While and after but the most important thing was that in Australia I had high blood sugar
and I walked around the icy rock, it's 9 km which we did in 2 hours and after the walk,
after we rested already suddenly I felt like somebody putting nails in my big toe.
-You could not move your feet.
-No, it was like somebody hit, terrible pain, I put Rescue fluid and then Arnica cream and
it went away.
But since then every time I ate, I had stitching pain in my big toe and both of them...
-Every time?
-Every time I ate, it's very unique. When I came home I did repertorization and Calcarea
and Carbo veg came up but I didn't have the cold for the Calcarea and I was not dead
enough for the Carbo veg.
So I took this symptom, this keynote and I came to Magnesia suplhurica which was the only one,
extremities pain toes first, dinner after. It's Magnesia sulphurica the one,
I went first to the Materia Medica, it's very small, very little.
I read it and many of those symptoms agreed with what I felt and I took Magnesia Sulphurica.
-What potency?
-LM 3. I did it for about 2 months.
-That means from March?
-From beginning of January to... I stopped it when I had abscess, the 17th of February
I had an abscess, you remember that I told you last time that I had one?
It grew again, I brought a photo this time. But only for the beginning, and that's when it started
and this is also the finger nail that became in brown.
-This is in the beginning or this is ...?
-This is in the beginning when it just started. My husband wanted to take a photo
when it was bigger, it's disgusting.
-But did you open it?
-No, I took the case and I prepared the cream with a few medicines and I put it
and then it went down again.
-Why it is brown?
-I cleaned it. I had nail polish when it happened and a month later I cleaned it,
I was in Hong Kong already and I found out that that's the color. It was brown.
Now since March after the Mag sulph it started growing again underneath
and it's coming off now.
-So after this tumor that came out, is this tumor opened and discharged?
-Yes it is open and discharged by itself.
-What color?
-Very green pus, green, yellowish, grey pus but it did open by itself after I prepared cream
and put it on because I have experience with this one. I already went to surgery
and they opened it twice, it happened before and it grows again.
-How many times it has happened?
-3-4 times during the last years.
-Continue, just give me the symptoms that are steady.
-I tell you what is the symptoms that are steady now.
-But can you just forget this, just give me from your memory.
-That's a main symptom.
-Don't look.
-OK.
-Whatever you remember.
-First is the memory, it's very bad.
-Forgetting what?
-Everything, I forget everything. If I want to go and take something, by the time I go and
take it, I forget what I want to take. If I want to say a word, it doesn't come.
I have to think like in the computer and then it comes and my husband starts laughing.
-Weak memory for what you have to do and weak memory for words.
-What I have done, what I have to do, letters are switching, words are switching,
everything to do with memory, so poor, really poor.
-What else?
-Sweating is always in the head.
-And cervical back?
-Cervical and forehead. And groins. That I have for long time. When I sweat,
I sweat in the groins and it smells like ammonia, like sperm, it smells funny.
-Male sperm?
-Yes like male sperm.
But only in the groins not anywhere else.
I have strong pains still in my finger joints, especially in the left and in the morning more.
I found out that in the morning I have the aggravation usually, like the high blood pressure
is in the morning, diarrhea in the morning, the pain in the fingers is in the morning.
-When you say morning the moment you wake up or after an hour?
-It could be after half an hour. The numbness on my feet, the soles of the feet numbed
in the morning.
-Numbness of feet or soles?
-Soles, not the feet, it's the soles and finger tips, also this part of the fingers in the feet
and the soles.
Even though they are very sensitive.
And my soles are very sensitive, always been.
When I was a child I couldn't let my mother to cut the nails and I can't go to pedicure
it's too much, I can't walk without shoes.
I need fresh air and it's not enough, I need it to be moving, fanning, I have right now eczema
between my fingers, which I had when I was young teenager and after pregnancies I had it also.
I have a funny thing the last 2 years about sex.
First of all my sex desire is gone, it's not there anymore.
-Completely?
-Completely.
-Aversion?
-I can't say aversion but it's not there, indifference but there is something
which is embarrassing. I see a movie and a movie doesn't have to be a blue movie.
Normal movies today have sex parts in it, people kissing, caressing, I can't see it.
-Why?
-Embarrasses me. I don't know why. It was not like this, the last 2 years I think.
Blue movies I never could see.
-Blue what do you mean?
-Blue movie I say sex movies, these ones I can't see, I never could.
-It's disgusting.
-I feel bad, I don't feel good with it.
I'm still sensitive to reprimands, if my husband tells me something I get very offended.
I still can't sleep in the afternoon, I avoided because I feel very bad when I wake up and
that's since I was a child, always. My mother says that she has it also.
-What time is this?
-If it will be 1 o'clock it's still kind of morning for me but if it goes towards 4 o'clock and
go to sleep then, then when I wake up I feel so bad, like vomiting, funny headache.
Something is wrong. I prefer to go through and sleep till the morning because
when I wake up I feel so bad that I can't stand it. So normally I never go to sleep.
-Do you know this symptom to which remedy belongs?
-It belongs to Staphysagria but it belongs to others too.
I don't go to sleep and I have a break between 3.30 and 4.30, especially here that
I want to go to sleep, I'm so tired but I never go to sleep, I always find something to do.
Everybody goes to sleep and I don't even lie down because I'm afraid that I go to sleep
and I then I wake up bad.
-What position do you sleep?
-I sleep first on the right, then I can turn to the back, now I found that I'm sleeping putting
my head underneath the pillow and my feet is one up and the other one like this or like that.
-One straight and one flexed.
-One is like this up, this one is up and this one is down on the bed.
That's how I sleep all my life and I have to be covered the feet outside,
everything here outside, I have to be outside.
-The feet must be outside?
-In the summer yes and I sleep with feathers in the summer. I put it like this,
only in the abdomen.
-So you feel cold in the abdomen?
-I don't know, it's like covering it, like taking precautions, I don't know why.
Also when I see a movie I found myself always putting my hands like this.
-Protecting your heart.
-Protecting here, I start looking at little things to give you some more special things.
Ascending I can't. I can walk for hours if it is straight, if it is ascending it is impossible.
I love animals.
Salt, it went up so high.
-Desire for salt?
-Yes people tell me that I just put thick salt, really a lot of salt and the desire
for sweet is up but only before menses. In the period that I didn't have the menses
for nearly a year I still had the symptoms but the menses never showed up.
-Premesntrual Without menses?
-Yes and in March the sugar was very high and I went to a homeopath that I know and
I wanted him to take my case and he decided on Laminitis you know the butterfly.
It's some kind of a new remedy made from butterfly. I didn't want to touch anything.
I take a butterfly and I fly like a butterfly, so I asked to be sent from England the proving.
It's by Nancy Herrick and I read it, the symptoms that he took were right
but when you read the proving it's different. They take the symptoms
but they don't correlate so much, it's very general, so it was different.
Then we had a seminar and we learned about Folliculinum and the symptoms that he decided to
give me the butterfly were in Folliculinum.
It was first timeI saw Folliculinum so clear, so I decided I take Folliculinum.
-What potency?
-LM 1 once, it was enough, it nearly killed me. I took the Folliculinum beginning of April one time.
Then 2 weeks later I had diarrhea and pain in my stomach, I felt really bad and
later I had my period, after I didn't have it for a year. And 28 passed and I had it again,
I still have it already for 10 days.
That's what the Folliculinum did I think. I don't know because in the middle I took Nux vomica
because I felt so bad, I had heart burn. That's another thing that happens to me a few times
but I take always Nux 30 in water and it helps.
Through sleep I'm vomiting acid, it's like the stomach contents go up in my sleep and
the acid really burns the esophagus from inside, it's terrible and I wake up like this and
running to vomit it.
So Nux vomica really helps in that. I took it 14th of April.
-How many times?
-I took twice and I took once, then I took it again in the middle of May that it happened again
and that's it. I found out that the main problem which makes me sick, like I can have flu
or something, it's conflicts.
If I'm in a conflict like I have to do this and if I do this I'll hurt this one and
if I do that one, I hurt that one.
I'm in the middle and I can't do nothing, I feel so bad and I just become sick,
all my life was like this.
I don't want to hurt this one and I don't want to hurt that one and I'm in the middle.
What happened the last few months, I think mentally I'm much better.
I went back home I'm happy suddenly after 20 years I'm happy to clean,
I'm happy to throw out things from the house, I'm happy to cook,
I'm happy to see my grand son but I get tired very easily.
It's like I went back home to save myself, to protect myself.
-You mean from Australia?
-No, from work, from outside. I wake up when I feel like it, I do what I feel, I feel safe.
-You feel safe and you feel good. But why you are so sensitive, you cry so much?
-Always.
-It's now or lately you became sensitive?
-All my life was like this.
-But you are more now.
-Yes.
-Do you know why you cry? Is it because you pity yourself?
-There is something in my life that I also question why I cry. Because I can cry when I see
somebody misfortune, some person who was with Down syndrome in the street I can cry.
If I see a mental case I can cry. I can cry with my patients and I can also cry when I see
beautiful scenery, a beautiful flower and a baby, it brings my emotions up.
-Yes but the emotions can be happy? They can be happy, this or that but in you it brings tears.
-It's like a switch, if I'm angry, I cry very easily when I'm angry, when I'm frustrated.
-Can you tell me why you cry now?
-I don't know. I try to investigate, that's what I'm doing the last few months and what
I'm thinking when I look back in my life is that my emotions are triggered by expressions.
By other people. I can feel emotional through something else.
When I take a case for instance or I hear a case and somebody is saying something,
it goes through my feelings, it goes immediately inside, only up to here, not more than that.
-But it is sympathetic, it's suffering together but now you suffer together with yourself.
Can you say that seeing yourself suffering, you cry, can you say that?
-Yes, it could be.
-You say why do I suffer, why I have to suffer?
-Yes, I don't think I feel pity, I feel angry, I feel helpless, that makes me...
Because I used to handle things all my life by myself and I can't handle them anymore.
-But now you don't have the responsibilities anymore.
-No but how can I treat patients when I'm sick?
-Yes but why do you have to treat patients?
Because you like it? Why you want to treat?
-I tell you. When I went to Homeopathy I was naive. I saw a way to clear this world from
all the sicknesses and now slowly I found out that it's not that easy.
It's difficult and it's not for sure and I can harm people also because the way I pass the remedy,
I go to hell and back and I'm not always sure that it wouldn't happen to the person I treat.
I'm scared. I don't want to make any harm to anybody.
-Yes but what I say is, you gave up your main job and why if treating people makes you
feel so uncomfortable?
-No, it feels great when I solve somebody's problem it feels good, it's the best thing that
could happen, I feel so happy.
-You feel happy?
-When he feels good, when I help them.
-When they come back and tell you they feel good, not when they have problems.
-When they have problems, I have problems, I can't go into the suffering.
It's so hard for me.
-It's so hard to go into their suffering. Why is so hard? To listen?
-I take it personally, it touches me, then it takes me away.
-But this is not good. To see patients if you feel so...
-I know, I stopped doing it. I don't do it.
-If you are so much affected.
-I told you I went home, I retreat. At home I feel safe, I do things that I know how to do
and I don't harm anybody.
-But do you feel the need for protection?
-Always. I never had it but...
-Maybe you had but not so much as you would like to have it.
-No, I always took care of myself.
-Your husband did not protect you?
-No.
-You protected him?
-Usually yes. He is strong but in some ways. He can't press the right buttons.
That's our karma together.
-Does he work or he stays at home?
-No he works, he told me give up your job, I'll take care of you. I'll take care of the family,
I don't need the money that you bring, everything will be fine but always I wanted to be independent.
I don't like him to tell me what to do. I was at home about 10 years when I got married,
I nearly went to asylum, I could not. I have to do something and it's the first time in my life
that I retreat. I never did it but what can I do?
I don't find any solution.
-Do you feel that at this moment you become like a pensioner?
-Yes.
-You feel that and you don't like it, is that correct? On one hand you don't like it,
on the other hand you like it.
-I like it a lot now because it's the first time I'm not stressed, I'm not obsessed about things,
I don't care. I don't care if I have this kind of sofa or this one and now my daughter bought a house,
an apartment and she is choosing the floor and I go crazy, what do you care if it's red or white?
It's not important. Really there are so many things that are important and this is not important.
I came to a phase in my life where money is not important, nothing is important actually
except health, except my little baby.
I go crazy if something happens to him or something happens to my daughters.
I worry about their health. There is another thing, if I know that they are supposed to come
and they are late I go crazy, I think in a minute I see pictures in front of my eyes,
like an accident.
I see visions like it was an accident and my husband always say,
why do you see the bad things?
Maybe she enjoys herself and she didn't come but she was abroad, she was supposed to call me,
she came in the middle of the night and she didn't call. I was scared.
-How is your thirst?
-I don't drink at all.
-What do you drink?
-Anything that have lemon in it, like refreshing. I can't drink water, I hate water.
Another story was in the dentist, I can't stand when he does it and there is water, I just choke.
He said that he never had a drowning patient before, I always drawn,
so he has a special thing for me.
He put some kind like a balloon and the water goes out.
Another funny incident with the dentist was that he made a filling, he gave me injection
without adrenaline and then when the injection finished my half tongue stayed without taste.
-For how long?
-A month and a half till I went again to him. Now the second time that I came to him,
I asked for the tube, I wanted to make homeopathic remedy from this anesthesia stuff
and then he didn't make any injection and then when he made the filling I felt very sour on
my tongue and I asked him what is that and he said when it is anaesthetized I couldn't feel it
and I asked him what is it and he said, it's Phosphoric acid.
He put it inside the tooth to make little holes because there is a new white filling
that have to old.
I took the tube, I went home, by the time I went home it's gone this thing.
I felt the taste again because half of the tongue had no taste. He said he never had anything
like this before. I don't know, I think it's the Phosphoric acid maybe.
Aversion touch, brittle nails, my nails are broken all the time, always.
-You feel better now you cried?
-Yes.
-Other times also you have cried but this time you really cried quite a lot.
Do you lately cry a lot would you say?
-Not a lot. I'm embarrassed, I'm not crying.
-But do you have tendency to cry?
-Yes I have tendency to cry. When I was a child, if somebody just looked at me that I thought that
he is thinking bad at me, I used to cry, very easy to cry, when I get angry,
when I get frustrated, when I see something beautiful, when I see something sad, movies.
My husband always laugh and he says even in the comedies I cry.
I can't go into myself. I have a feeling that I can't connect mental, physical and emotional.
It's like I stuck here, I hardly remember anything from my childhood.
-I don't understand that because you have so many feelings, how is that possible?
You are saying something opposite from what I see.
-Yes it's so funny. That's what I want to know. It's amazing because I can't do meditation
for instance, I cant' meditate, I get irritable. I think if I do it, I'll be better now,
I'll try to do it again.
-Tell me about darkness? You feel good in dark?
-No, it's unknown, I don't like it.
-But you are afraid?
-At home yes I can go in the dark and put a light but I wouldn't go in the street in the dark.
I didn't go to live in Melia Bay because I thought I will have to walk from here in the evening
and I' scared that somebody is there. I also don't dive in the sea which is very dark,
it's frightening.
It's the unknown. I have to be in control all the time.
I feel through other people feelings.
-What do you mean? If somebody is happy, you will be happy?
-Yes, I'll be very happy.
-If somebody is sad, you will become sad. Is that what you say?
-Yes. When you gave me Phosphorus it was OK, it was much better but now it's again.
I have a problem with robbers. I dream.
-Maybe they start stealing in Israel more and more.
-No, it's the last few years, I have dreams about robbers, they rob me. It has to do with work,
2 weeks ago I had a dream that somebody took my credit card and I woke up and
I looked in the bag if it is there. Real fear of robbers, it's very strong.
And last time when I was here I left my bag behind and it was...
It's like it goes in and out immediately. Everything in my body is like this.
If I eat something, it wants to go out immediately. Everything I throw out, the same with the feeling,
it goes in and I throw it out. I don't let it be in.
-You are affected very much.
We noted down, Marguerite noted down 29 symptoms and
I would like you to focus your attention, show the symptoms.
Every symptoms that she mentioned weeping from anger, weeping easily, sympathetic,
anxiety for others, complain brittle nails, fear of dark, fear of robbers, aversion water,
all the symptoms she mentioned is here and you will see something very interesting.
I could not believe that this computer could do this. I could not believe.
-What?
-I will show you just now. I will show you a phenomenon you've never seen before
in any case.
What, is that the case?
I told you not to change anything when I left you there?
-I didn't change.
-But it was Phosphorus first. What do you mean?
Anyhow, forget it, it doesn't matter. Show me the other.
Just the Expert System where it makes a decision.
It says I can not make a decision. The previous repertorization when I left it was even better,
almost all remedies were coming almost the same.
All the remedies they have almost the same symptoms, 5 symptoms for each remedy,
different symptoms.
This is very interesting, why? Even that repertorization where she changed,
I don't know what she changed.
Fear of robbers take it out, these 3 last symptoms.
-It's very strong, don't take it out.
-Don't worry, we don't take it out.
When I left I said don't change anything because what I wanted to show you,
what happened with her case.
We prescribed Phosphorus initially and she was doing better and she took remedies
after remedies after remedies and we arrived back at the Phos state.
This is what I have been teaching you all the time. She spoiled the case, it doesn't matter
but this was a fact.
When I left the room I looked at the repertorization, it was almost all the remedies coming,
Phos first.
All remedies were coming with the same.
This is what I say, don't interfere. You think you are helping yourself but actually after 5,
after 10, after 20 months then you will find the effect on the right prescriptions.
Don't expect that from one day to the other.
You changed something, I don't know what. It was very interesting because the moment I decided
she has come back to Phos, I said show me and there it was Phos and then Arsenicum and
then this, that, almost the same size of columns.
The computer says I can not make a decision of course. So therefore we don't have to talk
very much about it, we start all over again from the beginning.
I believe Phosphorus will act again. You see how she is open, she says I have no skin,
no protection, I have no protection.
Again the same thing. In the beginning she was not as bad as she is now.
If you evaluate the first prescription with the prescription today, today state is much worse,
it is much more unprotected, much more open to external influences.
She could not stop crying, she did not know why she is crying and therefore it is very important
to understand that the evaluation of a situation is even more important than the correct remedy.
Because you give the right remedy, you evaluate correctly, good.
You give the wrong remedy, you evaluate correctly, good. I gave the wrong remedy. I know.
Now what do I have to do? I have to give another remedy of course.
I gave the right remedy, what do I have to do? Wait until I see really that the remedy
has exhausted its action, that a new remedy is coming up, the same remedy, the same thing.
Therefore we can not say of course that we gave one remedy and then don't take another one.
No, we don't say that. But if you take another one, you make sure that the other one is correct also
and then you will have an evolution which is positive in the end.
That's all. You make one mistake, you have to know that this was a mistake.
Even that the patient may come and say, I feel better. Feel better it doesn't mean anything,
as you understand.
Therefore we have a state of Phosphorus which is not confirmed.
I asked her about thirst, she says, no thirst.
-The first time I didn't have either.
-Also because we were battling between Pulsatilla and Phosphorus because Pulsatilla was thirstless
and should we give Phos? But you see now much more clear the openness of Phos, unprotection,
the lack of protection from others towards feelings, thoughts etc.
Phos has no protection, they don't know what to do. They say I feel somebody and
I live through the other person, it is terrible. It's not a pleasant situation.
And then the anxiety comes of course about others and what is going to happen to my child, to my...
-The sensitivity to the menopause or being in that process coming to this?
-To this case?
-Yes.
-This case is not clear. If you look, if you analyze why, why, why, you will see 5 symptoms
from this remedy, 5 symptoms from another remedy, 5 from another...
There is no way. If you say where is that symptom, that means out of 29 you can say 24 where
are the symptoms;.
Yet the main, the essence is more towards Phosphorus.
-Going to menopause being more sensitive? Where is that? Weeping?
-Normal menopause would be nothing, nobody would understand.
it is not because of menopause that you have symptoms. No, you have symptoms
during menopause because you are sick.
She took a remedy for 1 week, for 2 weeks I felt very good, for 1 day I felt very good,
for 2 days I felt very good. This is always with her almost except of a few remedies
which aggravated.
-With Mercury I was suffering.
-But the fact is in the end you have no positive results because you don't allow the
remedy to reach a point where it will show the next possibility.
So this is very important because here we take the cases in order to learn.
It is not only to say bravo to George or she gave a good case, we all learn.
-George, so you never take the rubrics with menopause in consideration?
-Menopause as long as you have symptoms because of menopause but
menopause as a rubric is not correct.
Flushes of heat yes, depression during menopause yes and all the symptoms you will take
but menopause is not supposed to have symptoms in a  woman.
The menopause is supposed to go through without, either with very little changes or not at all.
We say, oh yes you have depression because of menopause.
Because of menopause but still it is a depression.
What I want to impress in your mind that if you give homeopathic remedies because many times
you have been angry.
You say, why George don't allow us to take a homeopathic remedy and you tell us take aspirin?
For this reason, because the homeopathic remedy acts much deeper.
Aspirin will act on a very superficial level and will go over an acute much more milder
than if you take the wrong homeopathic remedy because in an acute you may need
2-3 homeopathic remedies and then back again, back again, back again.
You may treat 20 years a person and you bring him back again and again and
finally is on the same state, as the initial state.
Still this person will say thank you very much, I was good with Causticum, I was good with Arnica,
I was good with Phos, I was good with this,I was good with that. It's no good.
And of course I will never impose somebody, I'm teaching theoretically now,
what each one wants to do, I will never say, don't do it.
If you like to do it, you do it but theoretically you have to understand that this is the truth.
-This action in the beginning of this year coming back from the menopause, this is actually
a very strong impulse to the organism and she mentioned that came through
the remedy Folliculinum.
Can you comment on this reaction?
-I don't believe. I took Folliculinum 30 and after a week I had this or that. It's just accidental.
I don't believe that Folliculinum actually brought that. It disturbed a little bit
the organism and it came.
It's not a matter of Folliculinum. It's a matter of the organism is disturbed
when it's given the wrong remedy. Disturbed. Don't try to justify the reaction.
When she got Calcarea silicata, she got disturbed, the organism got disturbed. That's it.
We have to understand and to admit this, that is a mistake. Then what shall we do next?
-My opinion in menopause it's hormonal change and everyone can't stand these changes.
It's a lot of remedies for this pathological change.
-Pathological, the change is not pathological. When the organism is not tuned absolutely
in balance, then this change has symptoms.
-Everyone has suffered with this.
-No.
-There is the hypertension and the osteoporosis after the change of homeopathic?
-I mentioned you have said when I see a follow up when we have given a wrong remedy
perhaps it can be that I have to wait for the action of the remedy but the first idea
everybody has I think is to antidote.
-To antidote yes and the idea of antidoting is only when you have found the next remedy.
It's not an antidote for Calcarea is Bryonia, no. For Phosphorus the antidote is
Causticum, no.
You disturb the organism, now the organism makes a picture, that picture it can be
anything, it can be any remedy, that remedy will antidote.
-George I think when I have the new remedy, the best antidote is the new remedy, when
I have a clear picture but in cases I see not a clear picture, the wrong remedy is acting.
While I wait for the clear picture, is not better to antidote for to see as best as possible
the new picture?
-The best is to relieve the case. What she did? She took more pain killers. The best is to
take pain killers.
-I hate my voice.
-She hates her voice? What is the remedy?
-I just said that she likes to stay at home, to do things in the house, care for her
grandchild and all that.
-That is not a symptom.
-OK, perhaps not but it's Pulsatilla.
-It is the natural quality of a woman.
I know the positive reaction to this.
Anyhow you believe something, I believe something else. We have difference of opinion.
The American mentality has changed the world into a matriarchic society which is the
American society is governed only by women.
-So what?
-Yes. I don't say it's governed only as Prime Minister or President, I also say that it's
governed through the bedroom of the governors.
-I would just like to say being one of the few representatives of America here that what
George says is quite true because we have a very clear and very definite scientific basis for
what George said and that simply is that behind every great man, is a greater woman.
-What I know as a fact, when I was in America, my student, the woman student, in parties
they tried to change my wife into becoming American. She said, don't cook for George ever.
Don't prepare anything for him, why you do this?
I said, wait a moment and she likes to do that, what about this?
No, no she must not like it. A woman must do nothing, nothing.
I said but she must do something. No, no she must not help you in any case.
I said to my wife, is it better we go away from America now? We don't stay any longer?
It was a time where we stayed long in America, becoming Americans almost. I'm just
joking. My wife enjoys total freedom, whatever she likes, she does, this is the truth.
I promised you to show you the gold medal which I received from the President
of the Hungarian Democracy. Thank you.
And this is the signature of the President who presented to us. I must say we were 3 that
were presented this very high distinction. One was a Hungarian Professor of Pediatrics
who did quite a lot for saving children with cancer.
Tamar was... Some they doubt is it possible that the President of the Democracy gave
gold medal to George? She was present in the ceremony. I said you have to confirm it.
So here is the picture in the Parliament actually.
I have to give you the whole story.
This also got the same distinction and also Professor Dostchy from Vienna,
he is also Hungarian, born in Hungary.
I feel this was the second distinction which I got, after the Alternative Nobel Prize,
which has really has opened a lot of official Schools for Homeopathy.
And these things though they don't add anything to my knowledge or to me,
they add a lot to the possibility for Homeopathy to go on to the level that belongs to,
which is the level of the Medical Schools.
We go to the next case.
-What potency?
-What potency you got the first time?
-30.
-OK, get 200.