-So this is a follow up of the follow up of the follow up of the third day and
you took Sulphur 200, I want to make a resume and come to the main points,
Sulphur 200 and the next afternoon how it was?
-I felt beautiful, in the evening I was full of energy, the next morning I woke up
full of energy, I slept good and then when I slept I was very cold, I felt very cold.
My feet were cold but I went to sleep about midnight and I slept very good.
I dreamed about Homeopathy and studying and journeys, normal. At 6.30 I woke up,
I had very clear mind. I felt really good, full of energy and good. And then at about 9
I started having pain in the nap here and slowly slowly it moved on and developed to
in the chest going up a little bit to the neck which was there before probably and  the neck
and starting to oppress.
-What was the time when you told me that?
-I told you when we came back from the noon break because it was very bad during the end.
-It was about 5 o'clock when you told me that I have this pain, you put your hand over here
you say I have that pain extending and all that and then I asked the cardiologists
to take a look at you again and at the same time I gave you a remedy after the ECG
We had a repetition of the ECG at 9.30 because someone all the time was phoning...
-The clinic was full.
-Then the next day you had another ECG and today you had another one.
-Today the pain is here already, it finished here, now it's on the right.
-But what did you feel when you got the remedy?
-One minute after I took it, I had a hot flash going up in the face for a minute and then it's gone.
-What happened to the pain?
-The pain went down a little bit and slowly slowly it went away, by the next morning
it was gone. Just when I was moving like a muscle pain.
-I see.
-Blood pressure also went down and down.
-That was interesting also, we will say in the class.
-Last night it was the diastolic was 80, from 160, this morning was again a little bit high.
-From quite high when we started.
-But today I feel bad, last night was very bad.
-What happened? Describe. You forgot to say, I said no food in the same night, only water.
-I didn't eat and I drunk only water.
-Then the next day you had the ECG again and because he told you everything is all right
he said to me and you went out and you smoked.
-Just one puff. I didn't eat for 24 hours, I didn't smoke.
-Not 24.
-Yes because I didn't eat before I came here, I ate last time it was 2 o'clock at noon.
Then you told me not to eat and I ate only the next day when I came back. I was very ...
-I told you from the very beginning you put too much weight, you are going on fruits
only fruits. Just find any fruit you like.
-I put on weight on fruits.
-If you eat fruits?
-Then eat broccoli only, spinach, zucchinis.
-I eat.
-Only vegetables, if you eat only vegetables and fruits I can not believe how you put on weight.
-I try. I ate yesterday in the evening, so I joined the celebration and I ate and
I didn't smoke, so maybe I ate more and at night I fell asleep but at 2.30 in the morning
I woke up with all sweat, hot. The whole night I was hot, I took the covers out and
I was sweating in the chest and the whole part here was burning like pain burning up here
with a pressure.
-What did you eat? You ate different things?
-I ate different things, they were many things like salad and...
-'Mezedes'.
-Yes a little piece of lamb which made it worse, I can't digest lamb and till now
it's burning only when I take soda water, normally I take Nux vomica for that and it works.
-Forget your treatments for the time being.
-So I took soda water but it's still burning in here, it's like rheumatic pain.
I feel down very low energy like a flu.
-What you have to do is to eat very lightly, drink a lot of water but also don't get exhausted at all.
-Normally as I look at you, you should be sleeping by now.
-I'm very tired.
-So I think... I'm suspecting the high blood pressure etc. something is going on with your
heart, so it's better to prevent than to treat. So I'm very careful and I don't want of  any kind of accidents here.
So we will analyze your case and then we finish. So actually I would
suggest that you just go to sleep, lie down and sleep and give us a follow up tomorrow.
And that's it.
-But can Paul explain me what is going on? That makes me worried. If everything is fine
but it doesn't behave like everything is fine.
-Let me worry. The clinical picture was worrying.
-I knew, that's why I told him to tell me.
-But you forgot to tell me that every time I take a remedy I have the same pain.
-Yes I have.
-Anyhow I will explain to you later on.
-Well I need that explanation, otherwise I get worried.
-Yes you need. The clinical picture which you presented indicates that you have to lose weight
and you have to be careful with diet, no smoking at all.
If we don't want to have a problem. Of course if you are careless...
-I'll say goodbye early.
-We don't want, let me say good bye first and then everybody else can do whatever they like.
As you hear by 5 o'clock in the afternoon she says, I have this pain here which I always
had every time I took Phos. I asked her whether it extends here. She says it was like this.
She showed up to there and what worried me is always when the patient,
this is taught in medicine, when the patient put their hand like this, I have pain, not like this,
it's dangerous. If they put like this, it's not so dangerous.
I don't know is this true, this is my observation.
-It is so, exactly.
-So she puts like this, she said like this, I called Paul immediately
I said please have a cardiogram, see what is going on.
Paul gave a cardiogram and then he will explain to you what he found.
-In the beginning just very brief introduction into ECG and I'm only focusing into the changes
which you will see in the picture. This is the classical picture of a healthy person.
It's one upper left. A very sensitive part which can react very quickly
to transitory circulation problems, is this part here, it's called the T wave.
Already a small attack of angina pectoris is efficient to get this whole part moving.
We often can see changes in the T wave which we call terminal negative changes.
Most of the T wave is on the positive sector plus here and the last bit goes down into
the negative side. So this picture I mentioned because we will see it in the ECG and
this is not pathognomonic, it's still kind of normal. This here is pathology.
Physiologically it can only appear in the third lead.
If you see any changes in the T curve like here in the lead 2,aVF, V5 or V6
which are from the side lead of the chest, it is pathological
and it means that in the posterior lateral area of the heart you have circulation problems,
not enough blood is being supplied there.
If you do an X-ray of the coronary artery of the heart, if you only see this picture
in the right coronary artery, it's still OK, you don't have to operate.
To make it more precise if only the right coronary artery is affected and everything on the left side is
OK and you have enough blood supply, you do not need an operation, it can be balanced.
The first ECG was taken on 16th of May at 7p.m. after she had reported that
she had pressing pains which were to her left arm.
Since then all ECG is very well, so you all will be able to see that over here
to the right side the T-curve, the T-wave is negative whereas at the beginning of the ECG
is still positive. Positive-negative. Over here on the third lead it also is negative but
we put in parenthesis because it can be normal in the third lead, under the...
If the other leads are normal and then in this ECG we see in the second lead and third lead
and the aVF we have a negative T-wave. This is connected with posterior wall of the heart
and V5 and V6 both also have a negative T and this reflects the lateral side of the heart.
We can also see that she is having pain, which is pushing her blood pressure up
whereas if we monitor the entire period of time, after she received Sulphur
the diastolic blood pressure value never exceeded the 100 and all together it never exceeded 180.
And I never in my life have seen such a dramatic amelioration within 24 hours,
going down from 220 or 240, down to 140, such a blood pressure usually is being treated with
at least a double combination, maybe of a triple combination of different allopathic remedies.
After we saw this ECG George made a prescription. 2 hours later we made a new ECG.
In the meantime the blood pressure had calmed down on the diastolic level.
Clinically the patient could report very noticeable amelioration of her symptoms,
the pre-cardio pressing pain had vanished and she could still feel a slight pain
in the area of her left shoulder.
In the ECG we can see that in the second and third lead in the aVF the alterations of the
T-wave remain almost unchanged. The first 3 leads belong to the posterior wall of the hearts
and in the lower bottom, as I just showed, you can see that we already have a big change there,
the T-wave is not clearly visibly in the negative anymore. It's more around zero.
This ECG was taken on Sunday at 11.30, the blood pressure is 100-160 and
I have to write here that she has a sinus rhythm in the ECG and it's normal.
I again mark the areas which we want to watch with little arrows.
Here we already have a positive T-wave, here in the third lead it may be negative and
also down here in the aVF we can see the slight positiveness of the wave.
Down here is very beautiful and visible and also here. Normal.
This is the control ECG from today 2pm, we see non specific changes to ECG.
According to these changes a cardiologist could never conclude ischemia.
So let's look at it together once more. Here we have the T-wave again, it's more or less
going around zero plus/minus zero, this is not specific. Of course a cardiologist focuses
his attention on these things but you have no evidence of an ischemia and
down here you see the ECG of the lateral wall of the heart and it's a beautiful non pathological ECG.
And at the very end when you see such a picture in the ECG like on the bottom left, this is the famous party wave.
If you see this, the patient has acute infraction of the myocardium.
-Here we see of course the necessity of a specialist and we see also something
that again and again I will stress, that we don't act irresponsible. We always cooperate with
the different specialties wherever it's necessary and at the same time we say that
Homeopathy is not only for common colds. Homeopathy is for serious conditions also
and here we have to analyze the case why we prescribed. What happened
when we gave Sulphur previous day, next day you have this. What has happened?
The patient felt good, as she said, full of energy again, no problems, the heart...
Are you going to treat yes or no?
In 2 minutes I said bring a dose of Latrodectus mactans. This is a case which is very close
to Latrodecturs mactans. You will have 30 here. And how do we know that this is the
effect of Latrod mactans and not of Sulphur since 2 days ago we gave Sulphur.
Now after 24 hours we give another remedy and then the 3rd day we have the normalization.
How do we know that it's not from Sulphur, it's from Latrod, can anybody tell me?
-I had one question before about the blood pressure. If you see the constitution of that woman,
you can think that she already has a coronary heart disease and this high blood pressure
she had maybe it's somehow necessary to get enough circulation in the coronary arteries
and when the blood pressure is going down very quickly, maybe this was a reason for ischemia.
So it's a question if it's right, the blood pressure it goes down so quickly.
-Well I don't if Paul has to comment something.
-Not in this area. The patient in the hospital with a blood pressure of 240 over 140 then
the optimal level to which you want to get the patient is 160 over 95, this is the best.
-It's not easy. Now in this particular case there are certain things which I would like to comment.
So not to give wrong impressions.
-I think the reaction came from Latrod because 1 minute after you gave the remedy
she showed a clear reaction.
-She had a clear reaction with the flashing, most probably giving the resolution of the situation.
Latrodectus mactans gave an immediate action, reaction and amelioration.
You understand that I was very very worried and I wanted to know how she feels.
And she gave the report 2 hours later that the clinical picture was improving but
Paul says the ECG is the same. Anyhow that was encouraging, it was not worse.
Therefore it showed, in the mean time I told her to go to bed and lie down, don't eat anything.
You don't fill up the stomach with food when you have a situation like that. I don't know.
Cardiologists most probably think the same. We would like your feedback, we are not cardiologists.
-This is of course an valuable advantage, if the patient doesn't eat because then
if the case is going down further, we have an empty stomach for reanimation.
-Give us your experience Paul when you made next day the ECG what did she ask you
immediately after you said it is normal, what did she say?
-That was the ECG from Sunday and while I was still cleaning the ECG machine,
she is lightening a cigarette.
-She said something immediately. She said, when can I have my breakfast?
-Yes.
-The first question was can I have my breakfast. It was in the morning because we were
on the telephone and she said please and when Paul gave me the good news, next day normal,
I could sleep. That's how I lose my sleep. You see how you lose your sleep.
When we have 3 cases with such aggressive high blood pressure and all the time to control,
to see what is going on and to see that everything is all right. You go and sleep
and when 160 nice eyes are watching.
-360.
-320. Mathematics.
-I think not only the reaction of Latrodectus immediately shows that Sulphur has not acted
because Sulphur has a superficial amelioration which could not stand.
It was this action that you told us in the third group when the remedy acts not,
it goes up and then it goes down. That's the wrong direction I think.
-No we don't agree in that. Unfortunately when you are treating cases where
you have depressions and low energy etc. and the energy rises and if there is...
The change in focus of disturbance will change. From that level in which is depression
now from the mental or emotional it will go to physical. So you feel very good but
where is a sensitive point in your organism. What the psychiatrists call somatisation.
Now she has been preparing herself for this. When I saw her with high blood pressure she took 6 kilos
immediately I know it, I say now what are you doing? Because you are afraid that
the arteries will not act properly. So the flow comes again, life comes back but
the artery or one point of the artery is not enough to take the flow and therefore it contracts.
Here fortunately I believe it's a contraction of the artery and not an infarct because
if we had an infarct, we may had different development. We don't know what was going
to happen of course. We suggest. We don't know what is going to happen if this person
after the pain is gone, she goes to the disco and she starts jumping around or if she goes
back to 'Niriides'. We don't know. So we have to be very careful with these things
because we know how these things start and by the time she reaches Niriides, then there
is a full blown heart infarct and then things are different.
So therefore the remedy is acting. It is correctly acting, it is bringing down the problem
into the physical and then it is life threatening, you have to treat. That is the case.
Something else also that I want to make you aware with the cases that we see.
Do not think that everybody, I don't say about her, in generally that everybody who comes there
and sits in front of the class can tell everything, what is going on in their lives.
And I don't make any connection, I don't know anything about this case,
so if I give you examples have nothing to do with the case.
A woman she goes for a few months in that state in which she finds blond hair and
I'm black in the pillow. Drops, she doesn't want to analyze what it means.
In her bed there is a hair of another woman and then she sees that the husband changes some
habits and then 2-3 months and she is watching and she is pressurizing herself.
She will not say anything just suspicions but actually the suspicions are more and more confirmed.
This in a case where they have the tendency of high blood pressure, you will see the pressure rise.
They come to you, they don't say anything, just suspicion.
That question is so powerful for the woman, the blood pressure is very high.
In this case when you have a reason to be there but the reason is not clear to the person himself
can not speak it out, can not discuss it, even with her best friend the woman will not say  anything
because it's something very hurting and all this is kept inside and she comes to you
and gives you symptoms. She hast the blood pressure, she loves, she talks, I have this,
I have that, desires sweets and you give the remedy and the blood pressure goes down and up again.
That you have to be aware to investigate a little bit further and if you can find a solution.
For people like this you have to find a solution because if they don't have,
they are going to lose their job. Their boss will say you are not good.
This, am I going to lose... Responsibility, especially pressures and fast to give results,
to give effect brings the blood pressure up. So there are reasons behind it and we have to
be aware of that issue as well that maybe there are reasons which are not told to us. Neither we care.
What we care is to find the remedy. If we find the remedy, hopefully the problems
will be solved but if you see it comes back, it comes back, it comes back,
then you have to investigate and to discuss a little bit more
to see whether such an issue is there for high blood pressure.
-I wonder if whether the change of potency of the remedy, she is wondering
if we would have taken a different potency if you could influence the reaction to a more milder.
If you would have given a higher or lower potency if you could have seen a milder reaction
and not such a very pronounced reaction.
-She is talking about Sulphur?
-Yes.
-We don't know because we can never test the same thing twice so we don't know, that's one.
The second is that we know that the higher the potency, the more potent is the reaction.
If we take this as a fact which is not always so but we take it as a fact,
then it's better we stay on the low side when we prescribe in such cases and low we mean from 200 downwards.
Now I don't know what we would have done, if we had given 30, maybe the same reaction.
If we have given 12 repeatedly, maybe she would have the reaction after 5 days.
We can not know exactly what is going to happen in the same person with a different situation.
This answer will never get, ever.
-George you are talking about choosing a remedy and worrying and not sleeping and
here is a patient who is doing almost everything to make her treatment impossible.
He is doing just the reverse of what you expect from her.
Could you comment on her personality and the relationship, what should be doing in such case.
-She is anxious, she wants easy solutions, she doesn't want to take responsibility.
The next day, she is there and she knows I have phoned 5 times actually before Paul is finished.
I said did you finish, did you finish with the second ECG. She is hearing, George has phoned
so many times, he is worried, she is not. And the first thing she asks next day is
can I have my breakfast now, I'm OK and then she goes out and lights a cigarette.
What can I say about this? The cigarette has to be stopped, has to be clear, finished.
Also the food has to be reduced, very light food. The lighter the food, the better so it
cleans a little bit the arteries. If you can keep, this has to be kept in this diet for a few months,
2-3 months on a very light diet it will do very good but it is very doubtful whether she will follow it.
It's very doubtful, it is true but what can you do?
You see my responsibility at this moment is not to say, you are bad.
-You are coming from the point that this angina pectoris which was quite heavy one was
a somatizing of a deeper psychological level. So you are sure that this attack
wouldn't have appeared without this dose of Sulphur.
-No, it would have appeared worse in about 20 days. 20days, 10 days, 3 days I don't know,
it would have appeared if she was left, it would appear and perhaps much stronger and much worse.
-A blood pressure of 240-140 is a very acute situation in your practices
and normally you send the patient to hospital because it's dangerous. You can suppose that
she is being going around with such blood pressure for quite some time and without Sulphur
I could imagine that every day something could have happened. Concerning the factors
which in large raise the risk, danger for heart attack in coronary heart disease,
we have overweight a hyper tony, high blood pressure, she is smoking, these are already
3, I don't know about the family disposition, she was mentioning something and
with the patient who has these factors you can expect something to happen any time.
-If Sulphur has really acted so well I don't know, I don't understand why you are coming
up with a new remedy in this situation?
-That is a good question but I said that if we have an acute appearing, this is an acute
episode and in this acute episode we have the possibility of life or death, life threatening
I have said, you have to treat first. Now what to treat? To give Sulphur or to give another
remedy which covers the acute symptoms. Now in this case the acute symptoms
according to my experience were covered by Latrodectus Mactans and that's why I think
Latrodectus Mactans has acted very fast. Because the clinical picture though the ECG
has remained the same, the clinical picture in 2 hours was relieved.
-Besides the precordial pain with the radiation what else lead you to...
-Nothing else, that's all you have to know. Latrodectus Mactans, this is a good one.
The experience is that you ... she puts like this, she brings it here, goes there and goes
there. Forget it, for me is 100% that this is a heart infarct. To make these movements
here and here.
If the pain is stitching, I have a stitching pain here, I will again check out but I will not
worry. With this I said better quickly we have to act and this is the good with Homeopathy
that you can act very fast in the very beginning, not when things are really disastrous.
And that is the time where you have your best results. How many times we have saved
cases like that? Many times. For those who do full time practice and they see cases you
will have several cases but of course to prescribe wrongly, then you end up to the
hospital. There is no question. I was waiting, I said OK take the remedy, then 2 hours
later, what happened? He says the ECG is the same, the clinical picture better. OK we
can wait until tomorrow morning, that's all. Tomorrow morning, I was not sleeping the
whole night, I was waiting and telephone at 10 he comes and says good news. Thank you.
-What do you expect in the future? The Latrodectus is working on the heart but...
-In the future I expect if she takes some care about food and smoking, she will not have problem.
-No more remedy?
-We'll see. If now by treating the acute, the whole episode will bring back the state of
Sulphur, we can repeat Sulphur, we may, we have to see.
The whole organism went into a crisis with this. So she has the aftereffect of the crisis.
Put her to bed, sleep. Don't let her eat, this is also important, don't let her fill her
stomach too much.
-From what she reported before we know that these pains have been coming before as well
and she used to lie down and these pains were quite strong and she was repeating Phosphorus over
and over again for such pains.
How much damage could that have done and if then the right remedy is given do you think such pathology...
-With the Phosphorus she repeated damage no. I think the damage came when she took
the several other remedies, Magnesia carbonica. What has to do with Magn carbo I didn't
understand. She took 3 other remedies and the organism was upset and then suddenly
the blood pressure started going up. You see how sensitive it is the organism? In high
blood pressure is down. It's not easy to bring the blood pressure down. With the wrong
remedy forget it, blood pressure will continue, there is no movement at all. Only if you
give right remedy the blood pressure can come down. You saw this, Lilium tigrinum
nothing.
-Another remedy to carry for example for people who have a history with angina, she
carried instead of taking digitalis?
-Only if the pain is exact like that, it goes here and there. In that case absolutely. They
can carry it and the angina and chronic angina you may see that it will relieve for several
months where the Nitroglycerin will relieve for 1 day, Latrodectus manctas will relieve
for several months. It's a better remedy than Nitroglycerin.
-You have to look under pain chest region of the heart and then you found out
extended to the left arm.
-It's the only remedy so you have to know...
There is a state of fainting, she was very pale and I touched the forehead and it's
perspiring and cold. What is the remedy?
Carbo Vegetabilis, first remedy, a state of collapse especially when there is a stomach
upset and the patient is needing fresh air. Put all these together quickly, computer wise.
It was a dramatic evening and we have to stop.