In this case, case Nr 23, we have two facts to think.
One is 16 years ago, he had some grief and the grief was really very severe
and left actually a situation which still is felt today.
And later on he had an accident where he remarked that ever since the concussion,
he felt his head was very sensitive, that even the pillow at times seemed too hard.
So actually 16 years ago he has a grief, 11 years ago he has an accident.
The question that you are going to ask yourself in this case is, has the accident
changed the picture and brought out some symptomatology which is characteristic
of another remedy than the one Natrum muriaticum, which seems to be indicated
due to the fact that he had a grief and also due to the fact that he still desires salty things
and farinaceous food?
Both are Natrum muriaticum, aversion to fish also Natrum muriaticum, aversion fat.
All his life is a characteristic of Nat. mur. You don't think of Nat. mur.
when you have desire for fat.
So what are the symptoms? Since five years he has developed several fears of heart disease,
so you have to look in the Repertory fear of heart disease, which is the remedy?
Look fear of heart disease?
Arnica, Arum, Lachesis, OK.
Fear of others approaching him and fear of being touched and fear of sudden death.
So he developed certain fears, which are characteristic of which remedy?
Arnica. So your decision here should be between Arnica and Natrum muriaticum.
You have symptoms for both these two remedies.
Which is the first remedy that you have to give?
-Arnica.
-Arnica, it is the last remedy which developed symptomatology.
Therefore the answer to this case is Arnica first and most probably Nat. mur. second.
-A question for the previous case?
-Yes.
-How about Ignatia?
-No.
Because we don't have aversion to fruits, we don't have the sighing,
it doesn't say sighing very much. Brood about her condition.
Nr 24 you have anxiety with panic attacks, with fear of death and palpitations.
Also certain recurrent ideas that she could not get out of her mind...
after her mother had gone into the hospital for a gall bladder operation.
She has fear of narrow or crowded places, of heights, of death, crowds, thunderstorms,
earthquake, rats, never goes into a lift, can go up 7 floors by...
Never goes into a lift it means she has fear of narrow places, of closed in a narrow places,
desires for company, does not want to be alone, amelioration by consolation,
despair of recovery, she wanted reassurance from me that she will get better,
worse from warm weather.
Here things are a bit confused between some remedies.
As we say, fear of death and anxiety about health and fear of heights and fear of rats,
comes to Calcarea carbonica but worse from warm weather does not go with Calcarea carbonica
and we have here anxiety about health and panic attacks with fear of death and palpitations.
The main things, the strongest things.
-Argentum nitricum or...?
-Also here you could prescribe Phosphorus in this case.
-You said Argentum nitricum or Aconitum, what should be the succession? Which first?
-Argentum nitricum should be the first and Aconite could be second or third and
Phosphorus could be second or third. Phosphorus is justified in case Nr 24.
Who prescribed Phosphorus in case 24?
Who prescribed Aconite?
And who prescribed Argentum nitricum?
You are getting the idea, this is the idea, because most of the class is getting the idea
how to sort out between several remedies, when several remedies are indicated.
This is most of the cases, you saw it in this case very clearly.
-Because you have this keynote of Aconite which is panic attacks with fear of death and palpitation...
-You see the panic attacks with fear of death and palpitations is an expression
which you may have an Aconite.
The difference is that here should be panic attacks underlined three times,
you have Aconite and anxiety about health should be underlined one time.
But there is the other way, anxiety about health with some panic attacks, with fear of death
and palpitation but then you have fear of heights three times where Aconite you don't find.
Fear of narrow places underlined three times goes to Aconite and to Argentum nitricum.
Desire for company Aconite, do not want to be alone, amelioration by consolation,
he wants somebody next to him, worse from warm weather underlined twice,
so the bulk of this symptomatology...
You have to choose between Aconite and Arg. nitricum or if you like, Phosphorus.
Because Phosphorus has anxiety about health, it can have panic attacks with fear of death
but narrow or crowded places we don't see Phosphorus so much.
Fear of heights Phosphorus is there but not so strong.
Fear of death Phosphorus is quite strong, fear in crowds, fear of thunderstorms twice,
it could be three times, fear of earthquakes you have Aconite, Argentum nitricum and
Phosphorus but the most strong are Argentum nitricum and Aconite, three times.
That's why the fight is between Aconite and Argentum nitricum.
But the Arg. nitr. should be first.
Desires sweets, you go there and you see, desires sweets three times,
ice cream three times, desires salty things twice, desires sweets and salty it comes
for Argentum nitricum and not for Phosphorus, neither for Aconite because it's strong,
it's very strong.
So there are arguments for Aconite but don't try to make it Aconite, forget it.
If you give Aconite, it will not act. Aconite will not act here.
-How can we search in the Repertory panic attacks?
-I don't think we have a rubric.
Fear and panic, which remedy?
-Excuse me, can you tell us which are the remedies which we should include
as a rubric of panic in the Repertory?
-Which are the remedies? Why should I tell you?
-In order to be able to solve better such cases. It should be a rubric.
-Why should I tell you? I don't think there is. I give you the Materia Medica of certain...
If I give you all the remedies with panic attacks, you will be confused in the end.
Fear of earthquakes, no.
It is Stramonium, it is Aconite, Argen. nitricum, Gelsemium, Opium.
Panic attacks you have in Arsenicum, Aconite, Argen. nitricum, Platina, Gelsemium,
Phosphorus, Hydrophobinum and other remedies.
Case 26 in your files. A male patient 35 complaining of pain in the stomach 2-3 hours
after eating which feels like if he has a stone in the stomach.
Failing memory three times which impairs greatly in his daily life, his dealings and business.
Because of this symptom he has felt great inadequacy in his work.
He explained that he remembers a stain in a head injury approximately
one year before his memory loss.
Headaches are on the whole head, feels a constriction around his head
as if there is a band around it.
He has marked aversion in meeting certain persons and he has been swearing quite a bit.
He likes music and he is very sensitive to music. At the end he told me that
because of this loss of memory, he was contemplating suicide.
Here we have symptoms of three different remedies, of Anacardium, Arnica
and Natrum carbonicum.
The remedy that you should be giving as first, should affect his memory
because failing memory three times underlined, which prevents him from doing his work.
That means he has a big problem. At the same time he feels inadequate,
that means he feels...
It 's a different way of saying I feel that I do not have self-confidence anymore,
I have lost my self-confidence. So this is another way of expressing a symptom
of Anacardium again.
He has marked aversion of meeting certain people. If you go to the Repertory,
this is strong, you find it in Natrum carbonicum but it might be
because of his failing in the memory, of his complex he has that
he does not like to meet everybody.
Therefore this symptom can be explained as a symptom of Anacardium,
as a symptom of lack of self-confidence as well.
And the swearing also is a symptom of Anacardium, as we said, desire to swear.
So the solution is Anacardium and if that does not work, we have the possibility of Arnica,
which we give it as a causative factor, because he had an injury, right?
One year before this memory loss, he had an injury in his head.
It might be that Arnica is indicated, so if you prescribe Arnica in this case you get some marks,
but definitely the first
remedy that you have to prescribe is Anacardium.
So who prescribed Anacardium? Very good.
Who prescribed Arnica?
Who prescribed Natrum carbonicum?
We have to sort out, to sort out what?
According to these symptoms which are uppermost and are most bothersome
at this moment, right?
- I want to put a question about the 26th case. Why it could be Natrum Sulphuricum,
because it has an injury to the head, suicidal thoughts, aversion to wet weather
and I think also photophobia?
-Yes.
It can not be because the main thing is failing of the memory plus the lack
of self confidence, which is expressed in different ways here in the case.
So these two elements you can not forget.
And also feels a constriction around his head as if there is a band around it.
This feeling we said: a band around here and around there and there, is a symptom of Anacardium.
So you have enough symptoms to decide on Anacardium
and that's why most of the class decided...
Now, who heard the remedy and just wrote it? She is honest. One? Only one?
The Anacardium, I say.
No when you read it no, heard by somebody else.
Stupid questions I ask, yes.
-In the case 26 I took Baryta carbonica, because it doesn't want other people around,
photophobia, worse sun.
-That's correct. She says I have written in case 26, I have written down Baryta carbonica,
because of the failing of the memory, of the inferiority complex and of the photophobia and
that is correct.
What she says is correct because these symptoms belong also to Baryta carb. with one difference.
Where is the difference?
It is in a peculiar symptom which belongs absolutely to Anacardium
and the peculiar symptom is a band around the head.
That they ignore it and that's why they went to Baryta carbonica.
I have to give marks for Baryta carbonica.
What I'm interested is that according to the information I'm giving, as I mix the remedies,
to be able to sort out the uppermost remedy. This is the most important exercise for me and
for you to go ahead and do it.
Do I see every time of half of the time or one third of the time or in no time
I found the right remedy? Then something is wrong. I have not got the way of thinking.
What we are interested here is to teach you the way of thinking under a circumstance
which is difficult.
-I wish to ask you why not Aurum because for example here on case 26.
I thought about Aurum because I thought somebody who has suicidal thinking
for such a small reason, only that he forgets, we must understand why.
This is the way I thought.
-Yes but I will tell you one thing.
From reading the case you have to come to conclusion that the failing of memory
is a big thing for him because he can not work, he forgets, he is a salesman
and he forgets a lot of things.
So this idea of not been able to work anymore leads him as a secondary effect to the idea
of I might as well kill myself.
If here was a suicidal tendency underlined 2-3 times without much reason,
you had the right to go and think of Aurum. But here under these circumstances,
the man has to stop working, he says I have a problem, I can't remember
and I have to give up my work and I don't feel confident anymore.
I go to people and I forget what I have to say, I lose my memory, what life is this?
I can not continue my life, this is the expression.
-It could be also over exertion and in this way you must think also about Aurum
who is working a lot and then he feels I forget, I'm worthless, now my life is away.
-You have to take into consideration everything.
He is 35 years old and we did not say he has over exerted himself and because
of being absolutely tired, he can not remember. We don't say that.
It does not give you the information that you project.
On the contrary he gives you failing of the memory without much reason plus the feeling
of inadequacy, feeling of losing self confidence, plus a symptom characteristic of Anacardium,
which is a feeling of a band around his head.
Therefore the first remedy has to be Anacardium.
The cursing, swearing underlined 2-3 times, he gives it as a symptom.
He says I was not used, otherwise it won't be written here as a symptom
because everybody more or little you swear.
But if you don't swear and suddenly you start swearing, that's a symptom.
You won't believe a child 7,8 years old when it's Anacardium or Nitric acid,
the parents will say he swears all the time and we don't know where he picks these words
because we don't use these words at home and the child swears just like that.
It comes to him as a must.
-I think the consideration between Baryta carbonica and Anacardium,
it says it's failing memory and because of these sudden losses of memory and in Anacardium
you have these sudden losses with a blocked of mind
but in Bar. carbonica you have a permanent...
-Yes and here also you have failing memory, which is strong, you have inadequacy and
you have two symptoms of Anacardium, band and swearing.
That takes you straight to Anacardium and this is how you thought most of you
and you wrote Anacardium.
Show me again how many? Almost 95%.
We have to encounter with the different remedies.
The pathology, which is giving in the beginning, with the swelling of the larynx
and around the face it gives what? It gives Apis. With insomnia, he wakes up to 2-3 am.
and can not sleep again it gives another remedy. It gives Kali Carbonicum which we don't.
She is sexually very alert but every time she has sex, she has sex she feels very tired.
Agaricus it might be with some other remedies like Calcarea carbonica, Staphysagria,
Medorrhinum. Very conscientious and duty bound, again the idea of Kali Carbonicum comes.
Worse from heat underlined three times, forget Kali Carbonicum and go back to Apis.
She also suffers from different fears like fear of the dark, heights, rats etc.
Fear of dark, heights and rats this combination gives Calcarea carbonica but she is clumsy,
dropping things easily back to Apis.
She felt tired, emotionally and physically and complained of lack of energy, any remedy.
Desires sweets Calc. carbonica, amelioration by cold applications back to Apis,
worse after sleep it can be Kali carbonicum, Medorrhinum etc.
So the first remedy that you have to prescribe in this case is Apis. Who prescribed Apis?
Very good.