So the grand rule on Homeopathy is
Similia Similibus Curentur.
This is the grand rule which means
that a remedy can cure if fits,
if it is similar with the pathology of the case.
So, that means we have remedies
that we know their pathology.
I want you to understand why such
a thing is happening.
When you have a disease,
you have a symptomatology.
This symptomatology is the result of a
defence mechanism who is trying
to re-establish itself into order.
To bring back order into the organism
through that symptomatology.
So the symptomatology is a useful thing
for the organism and the symptoms
are absolutely necessary for that particular
organism in order to stay in balance, not to die.
So we respect the symptoms of a patient whether in acute or in a chronic state.
We respect very much this symptomatology
and we try to write down
all the symptoms of the case
and then try to find which is the remedy,
which has in its pathogenesis when
it was proven in the healthy organism,
we try to find which is the similium, which
is exactly that remedy that fits the totality.
And then if you are given this, the patient
is cured. Why this happens?
Here we have a graph, right?
These are symptoms, strong
symptoms of the patient,
here we have a very high fever
with its modalities.
Fever which comes in the afternoon
4-5 pm, fever which comes
only in the morning, fever in the
evening, constant fever, whatever.
But fever is not the only symptom. He can
have also headache, strong headache,
headache with its modalities, we write them down exactly, the modalities of the fever.
And then we have exhaustion, tremendous exhaustion and then we have
together with these fever, exhaustion etc.
we have coughing.
And then here we have excessive thirst
and then here we have nightmares.
So you are searching to find a remedy
with fever with a specific modality,
do you understand modality?
Anybody does not understand
some words, I'm using words
which are used in Homeopathy and
I suppose that everyone understands them.
If somebody does not understand,
he has to ask so you can follow
step by step everything. Otherwise
it's not good, you just follow, follow,
follow and then a confusion is created, ok?
We try to find a remedy that has fever, that
has a particular headache we are looking for,
which has a particular exhaustion,
which has the coughing, nightmares etc.
So that means it will be a remedy similar.
The remedy will have more
or less a graph like this.
If the exhaustion is very great, then
it will have a graph like this.
So the most characteristic of this patient
is the exhaustion he is totally exhausted,
then the remedy has to have exhaustion
in very great degree also.
So for each symptom we have
intensity and modalities.
How intensive is and what
modifies this symptom.
If we give a similar remedy, the patient will
be cured. There is a logic behind this.
There is a very, very clear logic.
Can anybody know why? Can you tell me
why if you give a similar remedy
- that means the symptoms - I'm going
to be worse, not better.
The symptoms are going to be worse
because this organism produces this graph
that means this symptomatology
as a reaction to what?
To a bacteria, a virus or whatever.
So a bacteria has invaded my body
or has developed within my body
and then the organism in order to
counteract this invasion produces symptoms. And then I come and I give a remedy
which has similar symptoms. At this point
we have to be very clear because
when we explain Homeopathy we
have to explain it in this way
that makes sense to the patient, to ourselves
to understand what we are doing and this
understanding is useful for later on when you evaluate that case, what has happened.
Shall I give another remedy, shall
I wait, what is this, what is that.
Do I give a remedy for one symptom?
I mean these questions are going to be
solved if you understand very clearly
the mechanism of cure.
So my question to you is why this
remedy is going to cure this patient
and not make him worse?
There is a clear logic behind.
The explanation is this. If the organism
tries to bring about a cure through
developing this symptomatology
and he cannot succeed
because he comes to us to cure him,
that means he is suffering chronically
or acutely. That means that the organism is having the symptoms constantly
and through these symptoms the organism
is trying, 'let's make it a little bit more
this headache and then I will cure you'.
The defence mechanism behind.
You see for those who suffer with
chronic headaches, every week
there comes a headache, every
week 3 hours come the headache,
every 3 hours come the pains in the
abdomen, every day or every 2nd day
comes the pain in the gall bladder etc.
That means the organism
That means the organism is bringing
an epileptic fit every 5 days,
every 3 days, every day.
This epileptic fit we claim it is an effort
of the organism to cure itself.
This cough is an effort of the
organism to cure itself.
Therefore if we strengthen by
a mechanism, if we strengthen this effort,
the organism will be cured. If we find
a way to strengthen the defences
of the body, then the organism will be cured because the organism is saying that
'through these symptoms I try to cure myself
but I cannot, I need some extra strength
to make these symptoms a little bit
more so that I can overcome the disease'.
And there we come with a remedy
which is similar which
touches the organism on an energy
level, as the student said,
and for a period of time we have an
aggravation, smaller or bigger aggravation.
In every case, in the homeopathic cure
we have an aggravation of the symptoms,
what we call the aggravation of the
symptoms. That means that the symptoms
will become a little bit stronger for a small
period, for a fraction of a minute sometimes,
in an acute disease or for several days
in a case of chronic disease.
The patient may experience an
aggravation of the symptoms.
The symptoms become a little bit more
or sometimes quite a lot more.
If the symptoms become quite a
lot more then most probably
we have given the right remedy. We shall talk about the different modifications of that.
But giving an extra push, brings about what
the organism is not able to do by himself
and there is a release. Did you understand
this? Do you comprehend this point?
This is a point where we have to discuss so everybody will understand very clearly.
You have it in your mind
established very clearly.
- Dr. Vithoulkas, do you mean that if there is
no aggravation at all there is no cure?
-Good question. I mean yes, when there
is no aggravation it cannot be a cure
with a difference.
When this reaction has
reached its highest point,
the reaction is almost
imperceptible, is very little.
The organism needs a little bit more so the patient himself does not realise the reaction.
And usually this case is in severe,
acute diseases, where the patient
hardly realises the reaction,
a little bit more fever,
it doesn't' matter, a little bit more
headache, it doesn' t matter,
because he is in a very bad state already.
But when we have chronic cases
there we have to be careful because
the reaction can be quite severe.
If in chronic cases we have problems that
are functional, functional problems only
that means it is only a spasm of a
vessel which makes the problem
with the headache and that's all.
We have different kinds of headaches,
there are severe headaches etc.
and in Homeopathy we learn
that each organism has
its own severity of state.
That means, headache one person,
headache the other person.
In this headache which looks
similar to his headache,
is much more easy to cure
than his headache.
That means there is a depth on this headache and not a depth on that headache.
That means that this headache will be cured without almost any perceptible aggravation.
His headache which is of a deeper kind is
going to have a tremendous aggravation.
So it will depend on something which is
called the depth of the problem,
which depends on different characters
which we will be talking about, later on.
I don't want to bring a lot of issues
together at the same time.
I want to keep it clear, basic things
and then we'll elaborate as we go along,
we will elaborate more and more
on these issues.
But this I consider as a major
understanding of how the remedy acts.
That means that every symptom is an effort of the organism to be cured, to bring balance,
because this organism after this will
come to a kind of a balance, like this.
That means little symptoms anymore,
they don't bother etc. he's almost well.
Maybe at that state we can try
and give a second remedy
or may not try even,
to give a second remedy.
So my first question to you will be:
Find where, in the Organon, which
paragraph, states the law of similars
and in which paragraph Hahnemann
explains this law, how it works.
State whether this explanation is the same as Hahnemann's or Hahnemman is different
or my explanation is different.
State in which paragraph, the law of
similars is mentioned in the Organon
in which paragraph the explanation
of how the remedy works,
and 3rd question, whether this explanation
is the same as the one I gave you here.
The body is trying through this symptomatology,  to bring back the balance but you will say
if you have an epileptic fit is it possible that through the epileptic fit the body is trying to
cure itself? Have we ever seen a case of epilepsy where it has been cured
through the epileptic fit? Such questions
I would expect from you. Do you understand?
I want you to put forward your
questions or whatever you feel,
well I don't understand, and we discuss
until everything is clear in you.
Symptoms are developing in order to
prevent a more severe or fatal outcome
from the disease. So an epileptic fit
actually in the body which
points out to a heavy electric discharge,
it could have killed that organism if the
organism did not have the defence
mechanism ready to produce that kind
of unconsiousness and spasm etc.
So yes definitely, this is to balance the
body so it can exist, it can survive,
otherwise it can die.
But the fact remains, if we are
interested, that this points to us,
how we shall go about finding the
remedy, by taking into consideration
all these symptoms of the patient.
- I just wanted to say that several copying strategies for people who have chronic pain
and one of them is to increase the pain,
to go into the pain mentally and so
they can cope with the pain, they can
reduce the pain by increasing it.
So this is similar to what
we are talking about.
-Yes. There are strategies, as you say,
that the people who are really suffering
are trying to go into the pain and
increase the pain so it can relieve
but always in a kind of temporary
decrease, not real cure.
There are strategies in psychotherapy
which are the same,
for instance somebody is fearing
microbes, he is fearing the microbes.
In everything he touches,
he feels there are microbes.
So there is a strategy in psychotherapy
where they take him in a bathroom
where the bathroom is full of dirt
and say now wash your hands
into this basin and see how you feel.
I mean, you understand that the increase
of the fear will be so great and then
this symptom which is fear of microbes,
it goes very high.
And they have observed that through
such thing we can have a cure of what ?
Of the symptom. And this is the difference between Homeopathy and Psychotherapy.
Here they cure that symptom which was
over ruling the body, fear of microbes,
tremendous fear of
microbes and all his life is..
and then they put him
there and then it increases
and they find out that
this symptom goes away.
But many times they find that the organism replaces this symptom with another one.
So therefore, the patient remains as a mental case but with a different symptomatology.
- Mr Vithoulkas, I would like to ask, in par.2 Hahnemann uses the word gentle,
are you saying that the severe
aggravation can we call that gentle?
-Very gentle. We call it gentle in
comparison with suffering.
If the suffering is really severe and
for years, the aggravation of the few days
is nothing for the patient, who is suffering
for the last 10-15 years and after that
to be cured. A second question, and
be careful these are questions that
contain a catch inside, be careful.
Find in which paragraphs Hahnemann
talks about the aggravation.
And state whether this
explanation in the Organon
is the same as the explanation
we are giving here.
So you will write, Hahnemann talks for aggravation on paragraph 78,103 and 104.
The explanation is different or
it's the same. That's all I want.
- We know that with some patients we have symptoms that depend on the presence
or the absence of some elements in the
body, like for example we might have goitre
because we lack iodine in the water. How
are we going to differentiate such symptoms
from the symptoms that really have
a sense in Homeopathy?
Let's say for example, if someone
has lack of sugar in the blood
a very simple method to correct
this is if we give him sugar
and not if we give him a homeopathic remedy.
- Yes, that is correct. This is how most of us exist by doing certain supplement things in our life,
correcting the diet, doing a little more diet
of this type than this type etc, etc.
and these are measures on a level
which is quite superficial in order not
to suffer so much chronically.
The correct homeopathic remedy finally
corrects the organism so it can receive the elements, the micro elements that needs,
the vitamins, the minerals etc.,
it can receive them from the food easily.
Our organisms today, most of our organisms,
are not in a position to do that.
They are degenerated to a greater or
a lesser degree and they cannot do that.
So some supplements sometimes are
necessary to feel better, what we call better.
So if I take a particular mineral
I feel better, that is true.
The homeopathic remedy will correct
this, imbalance and this is the idea.
So the organism will feel best with
only natural food finally.
But many times we cannot attend
this and therefore we resort
to different other measures to
support the organism.
Let me complete this. What I want to say
now is, do you understand this?
Everybody understands this? Ok, now
we come to the question whether all reactions
from homeopathic remedies, that means all aggravations, are curative reactions?
So we know that we have a reaction
from just proving a remedy.
We have a reaction which is curative,
we have a reaction that can come from-
we said this we call the - similimum the best remedy, the correct remedy is called the similimum.
But things are so close to each other,
that many times we choose a remedy
which is similar, it's only similar.
What do we mean by similar? We go back to
this and we see that the remedy we choose,
did not have the modality of this fever,
it has another modality.
And it had the headache and it had the
microbe but this, the thirst was not there.
Actually, it wants negative here. So this
graph is similar because it contains
that similar, that similar, that similar but
we do not know anything better
and we give this remedy. Then we give
what we call a similar remedy,
we have a different reaction.
We shall be examining now the reactions
of the organism in each particular case
and make it very clear in our
understanding what exactly we mean.
So this 4th point it can be what?
You have an aggravation,
the patient comes and says
'oh, I was much worse'.
Because the patient is a hysterical
patient. He does autosuggestion;
he likes to have an aggravation because
he has heard that it is good to have
an aggravation. In this category there is
another case, hypochondriac.
The hypochondriac patients who
are both these categories,
they will produce symptoms of their own,
that have nothing to do with your remedy,
they will tell you here, 'oh I have such a big reaction' and it is good that I had this reaction
and this hypochondriac person will tell you,
'I had this reaction and I had that reaction,
what's happening to me, am I going
to die now? I have a little bit of
this buzzing inside my head and this
buzzing or a little bit of dizziness'.
It becomes almost a matter
of life and death for the patient.
And then you feel that your
remedy is not reacting at all.
You have to be able to perceive
these things.
And then of course, we have a reaction
from an organism when and if
we start the treatment while the
patient is on allopathic drugs
and we tell him stop these drugs and
take this remedy. Withdrawal of drugs.
Withdrawal of drugs can produce a lot
of symptoms that do not belong
to any curative reaction.
So these are the categories which
you have to be thinking about.
The patient
comes and gives a reaction.
You have to evaluate: is it proving, is it similar,
is it hysterical, is it hypochondriac?
Immediately you have to know.
If you are clear in this,
then you can continue.
If you are not clear forget it.
The patient will tell you this
time one group of symptoms,
another time that group of symptoms
and you will continue throwing remedies
without knowing exactly what
is going on with the patient.
So we go to the first category
and we say provings.
When do we have a proving
and not a cure?
What will be the difference?
In provings you will develop
symptoms that you did not have before.
But I will tell you something.
In a curative action, you may develop new symptoms that you did not have before also.
How do you differentiate between
one time which is not curative
and another time
which is curative?
In the provings there is no amelioration.
You have new symptoms
which have nothing to do with
the symptoms of the patient and
at the same time the patient says
'on my other symptoms I am the same'.
There is no general
amelioration of the case.
So in the provings what he will
tell you exactly?
You gave a dose of Nat-m 10 M.
You gave a dose of high potency,
what we call a high potency and the
patient comes and tells you,
'It's strange that I did not suffer any
headaches and now when I wake up
in the morning I have some headache'.
What do you have to ask immediately after that?
He says 'I did not
have the headaches before'.
Your first question immediately to
short out, there is a typical question
that you have immediately to ask:
how do you feel in general now?
He came for his phobias, for his fears, for
his colitis, for his duodenal ulcer, whatever.
How is your duodenal ulcer and pains?
'Oh, there are much better.'
But what about the headaches?
If the headaches are typical
headaches of Nat-m which has
headaches on waking in the morning
or at 10 o'clock especially, this is typical,
he says every day at 10 o'clock starts
a headache and he says my duodenal
ulcer is better. These two information
make absolutely sure that your remedy
is correct. But if he says that
'I have the headaches but my duodenal
ulcer is the same or my other symptoms
are the same, no change'
this is a case of a proving.
That means you gave a remedy
which had an effect and he is a prover.
So in a prover you don't have an
amelioration on the energy level,
you don't have an amelioration
on local symptomatology
and you have the appearance of new
symptoms that he did not have before.
These things you have to know very
clearly and immediately.
Otherwise my experience is that cases
have been spoiled mostly because of
lack of this knowledge. 'Oh, it is a proving
I must antidote' or different ideas
but if the person is better generally, better
in his ulcer, leave alone the headache
of the Nat-m because it's going
to go away very soon,
by itself without any further remedy.
If you enter with another remedy
you are going to spoil your good
action of your remedy.
And of course when you're dealing
with deep severe chronic cases,
things are not very clear.
But the general rules should be there,
the general rules should
be understood by you.
The first thing you'll see is a feeling of
being better, I feel better, general.
I have more headaches, I have more
pains etc. but I feel better generally
it is and indication that your remedy
is correct. Then, psychologically better,
that means in mental - emotional better
then most probably your remedy is correct.
Better in symptoms, better in the symptoms
and either no change psychologically
or no change in general that means
general the same, psychologically
the same.....you see you have
to be very precise.
Here, somebody tells you 'my stomach
pains, my headaches,
my physical symptoms are better but
I have no change psychologically
and I have no change in general', is it better,
is it curative action or is it not?
You see, immediately you have doubts.
Here we do not have doubts,
we have to be very clear, ok?
If these symptoms are better and
it is curative that means,
that the general state and the
psychological state are quite well,
quite balanced, did not need
a rearrangement. All the force
of the disease was in physical level.
That physical level gets better
and then that's all that the
remedy should do.
If you expect every time to say the
patient is better psychologically
and better generally, it is wrong,
as long as these states,
general states, psychological states
are in a good condition.
If the symptoms are better but worse
here or worse there, that is another story.
In curative action here, you
may have a proving symptom.
That means, better generally, better in the symptoms but one or two proving
symptoms are appearing that shows
that the remedy is absolutely correct.
It is a confirmation that your remedy
is correct if you have the proving
of one or two symptoms of the remedy.
While the person is getting better
psychologically or better generally
or better in the symptoms.
So therefore you say, you give a remedy
'ah I have a symptom, it's a proving'.
No, no, no wait a moment.
'How do you feel psychologically?', 'Better'.
Generally, better and
you have a proving?
That is a confirmation that the remedy
was correct, it's not a proving.
Now you come here in this group where
we have most of the problems, why?
Because the remedy we many times give, especially when we prescribe fast,
when we give a similar
remedy which what it does?
Here, in this group we have
1) change of symptoms,
2) no general amelioration,
3) no mental amelioration.
When I say change of symptoms what
do I mean? I mean that a headache
has been changing to vertigo. You gave
a remedy because of chronic headaches
and the headaches have been changed
to vertigo. The person says I feel dizzy.
Yes you feel dizzy but are you better
generally? He says no.
Are you better psychologically? No.
That means you gave a similar remedy
and you are going to change
symptom after symptom.
Now, how you handle that we'll talk.
In hysterical and hypochondriac patients
you have a reaction almost with every
remedy you give. You don't know if the
reaction is because of the remedy or
because of the make up of the person.
In these cases, hysterical, you see that not always the symptoms belong to the remedy.
These hysterical people can bring out a lot of other symptoms that do not belong to the remedy.
And many times in group 6
because you decided to give a remedy
under allopathic drugs you don't know
what are the symptoms underneath.
So you withdraw the drugs and all
other symptoms start appearing.
You don't know whether they belong to
the remedy or not to the remedy etc.
and that is why the best thing
to handle these cases is to stop
the allopathic drugs at least for one month,
see the picture and start from that picture.
If you start while the person is under
allopathic drugs, then you will have
a problem in evaluating what is
happening under your remedy.
So handling of provings. How you
handle a proving? What do you do?
A proving is when you have new
symptoms, belonging to the remedy.
Characteristic symptoms of the remedy
without any change of the condition
of the person. That's a proving.
What do you do?
Here you have to wait and the symptoms
of the remedy will subside within
a period of time which is between
a few days to a few weeks, 5, 6 weeks.
If you wait the symptoms will subside but
that means that the remedy you have given
is wrong and you have to search
for another remedy.
In such a case you can prescribe
the next remedy even when
the symptoms
of the provings are still there.
The organism does not care.
If you give the next remedy
which is the correct one, will react.
So here, for the provings the best is to wait
until the symptoms of the provings go away.
If the person is suffering a lot you cannot
wait. Then you can still go ahead
and give the next remedy.
Will you take in consideration the
symptoms of the proving together
with his other symptoms?
No, in this case, no.
You go back to the original case and
you study the original case only,
not the proving symptoms.
If you put together the proving
symptoms then you make a confusion.
- Can I make a contradiction and go to the
first remedy and then to the next,
right remedy, is it possible?
-To make a contradiction? Counteraction, antidote, you mean antidote?
No. It's not necessary
to give an antidote.
The best is going back to the case,
restudy and give the next, best remedy.
On the curative reaction, especially
when he says better generally
but the symptoms still are
there, what you do?
-Wait.
-Wait, better psychologically the physical symptoms are still there, wait.
Don't interfere with another remedy.
Please don't spoil a good prescription.
You will see eventually that these
symptoms also subside,
maybe they need time
3 weeks, 3 or 5 months.
If you leave alone the organism,
the symptoms will subside.
If you have a proving here, will you do
anything? No, leave it alone.
Once you make sure that the person is
better generally, better psychologically and
some provings are there, leave it alone, the proving symptoms will subside by themselves.
- How long can we wait?
- Three years. Bill Gray, you know
Bill Gray? Everyone knows him.
He came here to study with me for
2 years. He stayed in Greece.
One year he went back for one
month to see his cases
and then he came
back again for the second year.
In the meantime he was treating some
of the cases through correspondence
and all the cases that
he treated a year ago,
when he came back to me he said,
'I cannot believe it, all my cases
are doing well. Why? Because I did not
interfere, I was not there to interfere
with the remedy all the time. What I was
doing stupidly all the time before.
I left them alone, he says I want to see you, much better, diabetes, chronic diseases, everyone'.
He has given the right remedy many times
and he was doing this kind of things,
oh now I have this pain, take this remedy.
Now I have that, take this, take that
and you spoil the case. You leave it
alone and you see.
I mean there is placebo, you can
give placebo if you want,
if the patient needs to take
something, you give placebo.
But it is very important to know the rules
here. If you don't know the rules,
the proving,
the similar, the withdrawal,
if you are not clear in that how can
you proceed? You have to be clear.
The remedy is correct you leave it alone.
How long you leave it alone?
I would say if the person feels better
generally, better psychologically
, 6 or 9 months, wait.
As long as it is a real information,
not the idea of, 'are you better
psychologically'? The patient thinks,
'you are better, you are better,
oh you are better'.
Not like this, this is dangerous. You are
better,  I can see you are better.
Many times
I can see if somebody is better.
They enter the room and there is another
air, you feel immediately the remedy.
He says, how are you and you have
a problem there with the patient
who wants everything to go in one month.
Then you have to pass judgement quickly.
I see he's better, how much he accepts,
what type of the person he is etc.
This is what we have to learn through
taking the case and evaluating.
Because human beings are not simple
beings, they are complicated.
They have a lot of back thinking, think in
one level and there is another level
where he thinks something else.
And perhaps some of them are thinking
on 3 levels at the same time.
One level tells you one thing, the second level says let's see how he reacts if I tell this thing
and the third level is criticising you
and says this, this and that.
All these are happening together.
It's not so easy, we say better
psychologically and generally better, yes.
These reactions you get from people
living in the country, villagers, farmers,
people who work with their bodies
a lot, have simple reactions.
The more educated is a person, the more complicated he is in his reactions and
transactions and you have to be very
aware of how he gives you an information,
what he says, who he is. A simple
person, you say to him you are better,
you are better, he will say
yes I am better finally.
An intellectual he will not accept this
treatment, he will judge you,
he will leave you, he will say 'oh, you're
stupid you are this or you are that'
and he will go to somebody else.
But an intellectual can be better
and not tell you I am better because
he's judging you all the time.
He gives you one thing and he's
judging you on another level.
Does he understand, how much he
understands etc. and you have to be
aware of what you have in front of you.
The evaluation of the reaction to homeopathic remedy is an art really of high order.
Because you are judged by the gods how
much really you understand human nature,
do you understand human nature?
You say yes, I understand but who
understands human nature, nobody totally.
But as the experience comes, you see more
and more cases, you are able to perceive
more and more what is happening in the
soul of a person, in the mind of a person
who comes to you to be treated. Because
your desire is to cure him, you don't care
about judgement and things like that,
he judges me or he doesn't judge me.
What you are concentrated
upon is his health.
So you have to be an objective observer,
not conditioned, not prejudiced.
Because if you are prejudiced when
he comes there  and he judges you
and you understand, you judge him back
and you say he's pissed, he's this, that.
Forget about the cure, your ego comes
into the picture and then
some other person comes and you say
how nice, only good reactions
and you will have only your friends and
people who like you as patients.
All the others will leave you.
When you give a similar remedy you have
the most unfortunate thing happening,
changing the symptoms of the case
without curing the patient.
And this is the most unfortunate
that can happen.
Unfortunately
it happens frequently.
You give a remedy and then the patient
comes and tells you 'my stomachache is better'
but he comes after 3 months,
because he follows you.
These cases will follow you
for 3 years, 5, 10 years.
They are patients who will follow
you the rest of your life.
Because they have found out that
something you can do but not the best
and they follow you, they are good
patients, they support us financially
because if you cure everybody one time,
the whole planet in 1 year is finished.
No patients, I'm just joking. These patients
here you have to know yourself,
you don't tell them.  Or you can
tell them if you think they are
intelligent enough to understand, you say
I made a mistake and I just changed
your symptoms without curing you.
And I have to search for another remedy.
Now here the situation is very difficult.
We'll talk a lot about the second prescription
in such cases, in detail, how to handle
this because it's a very very serious
condition and it
goes into a lot of details.
In this case you'll find that certain of the symptoms of the initial symptoms
are going away or are going away on a big degree like 80% gone but some other
symptoms are developing of the
same order, of the same level.
Sometimes by giving these remedies a lot, you may change level and go in a deeper level.
Now, hysterical or hypochondriac patients
are those who will tell you with every
remedy you give, that they have different symptoms that you cannot find in the provings.
They are symptoms of their own.
Which do not present symptoms
of a remedy. You gave Sepia and
you have developing some phobias
fear of the dark, fear of this or that,
symptoms that do not belong to Sepia.
You search for Sepia and you don't see
clear symptoms of Sepia but the patient
is presenting a lot. Then you give
another remedy then they present
other symptoms etc, etc. All the time,
every time you give a remedy
there is a new set of symptoms. It's better
to wait with this patient to settle down
and give very low potencies before you
can make head or tail in this case,
before the case is clear.
- But the word hypochondriac means that
it comes from a very deep place,
so it means that it's coming
from a very genuine source.
So you may have to do something about
it even if it's called hypochondriac.
- Oh yes, absolutely. I don't say you leave
them alone, you don't treat them.
I say better be careful not to give,
with every symptom that they give you,
another remedy. You can wait for such
people for months to collect all
the symptomatology they present
and make an evaluation of the whole
of the symptomatology and
see the general picture.
Then you see the hypochondriasis
and what is hypochondriasis?
Usually it's about the health of the
person  and every symptom is exaggerated
and every time, I mean whatever,
some people look their (pulse) and say
'I cannot find this' or they pick
up the telephone and tell you
'I think I have 78 pulse'. You say, 'don't worry
it's ok, it's normal'. They say 'normal, 78?'.
'Yes it's normal', you have to be certain.
'78 pulses are normal', they say 'oh 68',
'68 it's also normal. The normal pulse
is from 68 to 78', you have to be sure.
Then you wait, what you're doing behind
your mind you are searching if this is
a case of Nit-ac. or Lyc. or Nat-m
or Kali-ars. The remedies with such kind
of an anxiety which all the time say
'oh, I have a little pain I think'.
'Do you feel pain?', 'I think, I think'.
You do not go and say pain in the right
hypochondrium and give Chelidonium, no.
You take the whole situation of the patient,
it's different all together. The one who
has pain in the right hypochondrium
he says, you read his mind at this
moment, he says: 'shall I tell him or not.
If I tell him that I feel a pain maybe he
will say it is cancer but if I don't tell him
that I feel a pain that means that he will
forget about me. So what shall I tell?'
That kind of thinking is going on
on a hypochondriasis state.
Then you don't take this pain and that pain
and that pain, you take the whole picture
which says wait a moment.
With the blood pressure,
hypochondriacs who have blood
pressure, forget it.
Because the blood pressure normally goes
up and down all the time, in the morning,
in the evening etc. and then when
they learn to put this 'I have 148'
Yes but then you are 58 and 148
is normal. They say 'it's normal?'.
So when you come to these cases you
have a lot of problems, stop giving remedies.
You gave 1 remedy, you gave 2 remedies,
every time it was a big reaction
you didn't know where you are.
Wait a moment, wait and observe now.
Eventually the picture will develop.
Is this Agar., is Nat-m., is Lyc., because
you think on another level in the case.
They guide you to look upon little symptoms
here and there when the main symptoms
are on mental level and then
you have a problem.
Because you are describing these
little symptoms all around and
you forget about the mental level.
What do I do when I give a remedy
and the patient has severe aggravation,
which he cannot tolerate?
We shall be talking about these cases and
if this case is very close to be incurable,
most probably you will have to interfere
with another remedy
in order to upgrade this patient.
Otherwise if you let him
go like that, he will die.
So in an aggravation, real aggravation
from the homeopathic remedy,
in the so called incurable case, it needs
an interference with the next remedy.
And usually the next remedy
appears, you can see.
- With the hysterical, hypochondriac
cases isn't a symptom on itself
when you look out  at the rubric?
- Absolutely, you take in consideration
the anxiety hypochondriac as a rubric
but this is not enough because
there you have 50 remedies.
Which of the remedies.... a lot of remedies
which you have to differentiate.
Is it good to give placebo to such cases?
Absolutely you give placebo 3 times the day,
you start with 1 time, you say double it,
3ple it, 10 times whatever satisfies their need
and because these patients are usually
led by their minds and hypochondriasis,
to keep them in a low level  it is very
good for them and will make them
survive enough time for you to observe
what other symptoms are there
so you make your correct decision. But have
in mind with these cases especially,
that it is an element which will always
be there to a certain degree.
It's like personality traits.
So it will stay, but the exaggeration,
the fears, the anxieties, the panic attack
which goes with such cases,
all this will go away. And in the back of their mind it will remain,  what about this pain?
But then just a thought and then it goes
away. Otherwise, the thought stays and
tantalize them and makes them really
fearful, I'm going to die.
Find in the Organon where Hahnemann talks about hysterical and hypochondriac patients.
Where Hahnemann talks about this group,
the similar, in the Organon?
And which are the paragraphs in
which he talks about provings?