Well, you are a graduate class and I'm going to ralate to you only the problems of Homeopathy.
The first years, we all say how wonderful Homeopathy is, how easy it is
and you can cure everything very fast, very easily with one remedy and it's finished.
By the last years you ralate only the problems, beacause people most propably come to hear only the problems.
So what I'm trying to make my students aware of, the last one or two years, are problems concerning prescribing, our prescribing.
I honestly say that if they were not these problems Homeopathy would have been at this moment already established in the world.
You will hear what are the problems which you have to be aware, otherwise you will be disappointed.
What do you think is the first problem in Homeopathy?
I say a problem after you have given a remedy which is correct.
Say you overcome all the other problems of studying and finding the remedy you overcame all that,  you are a graduate student,
you are able to prescribe correctly you gave the correct remedy, according to your understanding and then the problem starts.
What might be the first problem which you will encounter for many times and if you are not aware of that problem, you will lose a lot of your cases.
What do you think will be a problem after you have prescribed the correct remedy?
-That it will become worse and better.
-But this is in your knowledge and you expect an aggravation. So this is really not a problem.
-No reaction.
-Yes. How is this 'no reaction' going to be expressed?
One of the biggest problems that our society is facing, I mean the western society the sophisticated society, the society in which we mostly deal at this moment.
Our problem is because of the sophistication, because of the complexity of the individuals, because of the preconceptions; I took a remedy so I have to be well perhaps after a week or after 3 -5 days etc.
Because of these preconceptions, notions, you will get many times after the remedy has acted and it is the correct one, you will get an answer which it says, no effect.
The person who has received the remedy, which is the correct remedy, will say I have no change. I am the same.
-Now this answer, 'I am the same', for me it doesn't mean anymore anything.
There the problem starts. Because when you have a case and the person says, 'I had a big reaction and it feels wonderful', I say thank you very much, bye, bye, we finished.
The problem starts when you have given the right remedy and the person comes and says, 'well....'. Usually they almost like it.
I will show you a case where actually I will drive her to the point to say 'I don't want to be well'.
Now do you expect that such case in the beginning will tell you, I'm so much better?
No, it's too complex, too sophisticated, too confused emotionally the people.
They don't understand what is happening to them, their disease has become part of their lives and their disease is a complex within the society.
If you don't realize that this remedy is acting in spite of the person saying 'no effect' what you are going to do? You prescribe another remedy, it's very natural. Because you say OK there is no effect.
I have seen from the cases they brought me internationally in the seminars because as you know, I prescribe in different countries before the seminars.
The cases that they bring to me, most of them, when I take the follow up, you will hear this answer. Why?
Because they are the most complicated, the most difficult cases that they have received a lot of other remedies, they are mistrustful, they don't expect much
they don't say if they are little changes, they will not mention, the result is no effect! I am the same, I have no changes and this is a point where you have to be very aware.
If, on the other hand, you take too much notice of that, then you never change your remedy and if it is wrong, you continue with the wrong remedy.
And you say, wait, wait, wait and then what, nothing is happening.
If you wait with the right remedy, changes will start to happen almost in spite of the will of the person.
He doesn't want to get well but he will get, never mind what. So this we have to be very aware of, it's a big, big problem.
Then the second problem. Something, which I have found out that practitioners who use Homeopathy in the way that we do, in the classical way, prescribing one remedy etc. many times they misunderstand the reaction.
What may happen is that there is a reaction but the reaction appears to be either the wrong reaction, appears to be wrong.
What do we mean appears to be wrong reaction?
When is a wrong reaction in Homeopathy?
When the physical symptomatology is getting better and the mental-emotional levels of the case are getting worse, right? Do you all agree? Do you know this rule?
When the physical symptomatology, when a pain is getting better, when an eruption is getting better, when a physical pain is disappearing and mental-emotional the person is getting worse, then we say this is the wrong reaction.
This is a rule in Homeopathy. You cannot say I agree or I don't agree because it is a principle.
And according to the model I have given the 3 cones, mental, emotional and physical, I have said that anything that goes from outside which is the physical,
anything that goes towards the center when the disease is progressing in this way, then we say it's not a good sign.
In this we have to agree. It's not a matter of opinion, it is a fact.
But what do I mean when I say the reaction appears to be wrong, to take the wrong direction?
When the person will say, well now emotionally I'm upset, I'm this and then, I have this mental symptomatology now, you say what have I done?
It must have been in your experience, if you have enough experience in Homeopathy you must have seen cases where this took place.
In such case either you have given the wrong remedy or what? Can anybody tell me?
I would like before you answer because the class can benefit from your experience that you put your hand up so I can point out.
- Old symptoms come from the past.
-It is not possible that you have physical symptoms which are worse than symptoms in the emotional level and that may appear that the disease is getting worse.
For example I thought that psoriasis can be worse than emotional pathology on the emotional level.
-So far we had two answers. One is that this symptomatology may be coming from the past.
What is your observation here? Mental symptomatology coming from the past.
Here you have to be careful. Homeopathy is Mathematics. I guarantee about that.
You have to have a logical mind and think logically. And don't come and tell me in the end, you have intuition;  that's why you found the remedy or you said this or you asked this question.
No, I have no intuition and to prove that, my students are better than me. Do they have more intuition than me?
If you think logically, you will say in this occasion, this person he was mentally ill in the past and now he is physically ill, he has a colitis.
I cure his colitis and his disease is going back to the mental, this is most improbable.
The most probable is that he was mentally ill and because he was getting better, he got eventually the colitis.
It is very improbable that we have the second answer, where he was mentally ill, that means he had some anxiety in the past not very great anxiety
and now he had a severe ulcerative colitis. We treat the ulcerative colitis and now the anxiety is coming back.
This is a case where you may say, yes I feel now more easily excitable like I was feeling 15 years ago. That is a symptom returning.
But what I ask appears to be wrong I don't mean this case.
What is another possibility that you may have found from your experience?
-To be the right remedy but the patient is too sick, it is the only way it could go.
-Yes, it's quite close. It might be the correct remedy, the person is quite sick and the remedy activates another level of the disease
which includes mental or emotional symptomatology.
The person was too sick and the remedy you have given activates another level that means treats the person on one layer and brings out another layer, another remedy.
The remedy you had given was the correct one, it was the only one that could start the case and the next layer that activates will have the quality of being a clear remedy.
So when appears to be wrong, that means stimulating a level which has also mental emotional symptomatology, this layer which comes, has clear symptomatology.
Where initially your case was not clear. You say, is this remedy, is that remedy, is the other remedy, there are 5 remedies indicated, I don't know which to give.
You give 1 remedy and it produces a big reaction, the person gets emotionally upset physical symptoms are there but if you take the next picture, you will see that that is a clear picture of Nat-m. now.
That means that your first remedy acted correctly in spite of activating this layer which needs now Nat-m. You have given Sepia, activated the layer, brought
about certain symptomatology which is mental-emotional, as well as physical, but the remedy appears now to be more clear.
So when you will see this kind of reaction, don't be in a hurry to prescribe immediately. You say my remedy is wrong. No.
Your remedy most probably is right and what you need now is a second remedy, which will follow the first one.
And then you will see the real effect, the curative effect. Your patient will never say I'm better during this stage.
He may hint a few things here and there, maybe the energy a little bit here or maybe this is better, my tiredness is better
but he will relate to you a lot of other symptoms that are quite frightening sometimes.
I've brought cases to show you these points I'm relating.
I want you to have a practical experience of what I mean when I say these things.
So in the course I'm going to exemplify these points.
Because, as I said, unfortunately this class of cases is too big now and we have to be careful.
A third problem is, you have given the right remedy and the person comes and says 'nothing'. What it might mean?
And this is the most difficult to understand. And the most difficult to take action.
But unfortunately is happening more and more, in my practice at least.
Can anybody think?
Intoxication. The person is intoxicated so much that the remedy does not act, is that what you mean?
-He is intoxicated by environment or by social factors.
-Or by allopathic drugs?
- The amelioration seems not to last long.
- I say 'no effect at all'.
There is no doubt in your mind that the remedy produced no effect at all because you take all the symptoms, you see no reaction no adverse reaction no better reaction, no better somewhere, nothing.
You see no change at all really.
Let us that you are certain about the remedy. This is a case of Nat-m, this is a case of Sulphur. I give Sulphur, nothing.
-No energy in the medicine.
-The medicine is not prepared properly or the remedy has been spoiled in the pharmacy.
Unfortunately this is my experience again and again and again.
And it's only because I prescribe. Many times I'm very certain and I say this is this remedy, give it from another pharmacy and then it acts.
We have to be aware that our remedies are not checked, cannot be checked at this moment and also I do not know how well they are produced on the first place.
Finally you find out that Boericke and Tafel 100 years ago produced some high potencies that still selling. How much of this is spoiled?
And maybe we're giving high potencies without any remedy inside.
Don't forget that there is the factor which says placebo effect, there is that factor and
we maybe dealing with this factor and for a long period of time we'll be happy that we're doing something.
In the meantime when we see some severe case because you are medical doctors and you have the possibility to give also antibiotics, you say take some antibiotics.
Because you are afraid, you don't trust several things. Now these are the things I'm going to make you aware so you are more powered when you prescribe.
You say this is a Pulsatilla case, why it does not act? The Pulsatilla case is so clear. If you know your Materia Medica and you know this is a Pulsatilla case, why it does not act?
Let me try from another source. You have to.
In the course in London I will show you this Paris quadrifolia case.
One year ago in April a case of Paris came. I said, give Paris quadrifolia 30 or 200 I don't remember, one dose.
She took one dose and came after 2 months and says, no effect, nothing. No change in the case. The Paris did not touch the case at all.
Of course from my experience I said, this cannot be, this is a Paris quadrifolia case. Give from another 2 pharmacies, take the same potency.
They gave the remedy from another 2 pharmacies and I will show you the case now one year later.
First of all I will show you the reaction, what happened when the remedy was potentized. The woman says, 'now I'm worse'. I said, in what worse?
She said, 'my voice...', complained for different things. The remedy is acting but in the video you will say, it is not acting. This remedy made this woman worse.
And I say, no, no, it has acted and why. And you will see a year later what has happened with the transformation of that woman. The transformation of the case.
How the hell can we trust it's Paris Quadrifolia?
If it Sulph., you know Sulph., Puls. you know Puls., Lyc. and Nat-m. but Paris you cannot know, you might have made a mistake.
And you change your remedy and forget about it. You will never find the remedy again because this woman, she has been given different remedies and nothing has touched her.
In this woman we exemplify what we call a placebo effect.
How is that possible that this woman I prescribed the remedy and she said, no effect?
And I prescribed the same remedy, the woman does not even know, the second time she has a big reaction, where is the placebo effect?
You eliminate completely the possibility of placebo effect because the first time you see
the patient has no reaction at all.
You are the same person, you gave another remedy or the same remedy from another pharmacy and then there is a big reaction.
Then you know for sure that this is your remedy that is acting and eventually you wait long enough and you see the effect.
The fourth reason for which you may not see a reaction after your first remedy, what it is?
-Antidotes.
- You have to find out whether the person at the same time as he kept taking your medicine, he kept on drinking coffee, he kept on taking cortisone, antibiotics, the other remedies that he was taking.
There is a possibility that because there is antidotal effect, the effect of your remedy will not appear.
And many, many people will not tell you in the first interview that I have been taken for the last 10 years Largactil
because they come to you for a skin problem or for a colitis but they have been taking chronically a very strong remedy, a very strong drug.
And they keep on continue taking it, what your remedy is going to do under Largactil or Aloperidin or psychotropic drugs of that order? Nothing.
These are the four main groups that you have to be aware of in your prescribing.
The first group is the most frequent, the person has no effect and the remedy has actually acted. The second group appears to be wrong by bringing about the wrong reaction
The third is no effect at all because no remedy and the fourth one is the antidotes.