You have to study, there is no way that
you can learn without studying.
We tell whatever we tell here but you have
to be grounded in Homeopathy.
Homeopathy has to become a
kind of second nature.
Everything concerning health is evaluated according to that knowledge
which will be inside you. You have a
knowledge and then evaluate every time.
You cannot imagine the difference.
You'll see in your practice, the difference.
We'll talk a bit more lightly now.
This was a little bit heavy.
You know this graph from my book,
a human being functions in 3 levels
mental, emotional, physical.
These function as one, I'm G.V.
you are N.K. etc. as one individual,
through something which
connects the 3 levels.
That which connects these 3 levels
and makes them happen,
whatever I think, I have a fear,
I get scared, ex. there is an earthquake
- don't worry if it comes. It may come, the building is built in such a way that it will not fall.
So, if the fear comes, the fear is
a thought, I'm going to die,
immediately you see the perspiration
and the palpitation.
That which connects the mental,
the emotional and the physical is
what we call the bioenergy, the energy,
the vital force as Hahnemann called it.
It's the energy which connects the
3 functioning as one. This is something
extremely important and also important
is the fact that these 3 levels in us
are in hierarchical order, more important,
less important, less important etc.
Highest importance in us has the mental
level which you see it is included inside,
it is the most protected. We don't go crazy.
You see it took hundreds and hundreds
of years to make through wrong treatment
the population of western people, crazy.
We are, most of us, affected in mental
and emotional level. We have fears,
we have anxieties, we have all kinds of
psychological problems, perversions etc.
We have affected our mental
and emotional state quite a lot.
It took hundreds of years for this to
happen in such huge numbers
as we are today. The psychotropic
drugs which are sold by the companies
today are the highest from
other drugs. What happens?
The psychological disturbance on the
planet which we call western
civilized countries, the most
disturbance has gone to the mental
and emotional levels, where countries like
Africa, Asia and undeveloped countries of S.A.
do not have mental disorders
to that extent at all.
So you will see the connection
between what we did to ourselves,
what civilized medicine did to
our generation. Treating the wrong way
all along and pushing diseases more and
more to mental and emotional level.
You see, from the outside diseases went deeper and deeper to mental and emotional states.
This is our understanding today. So next question is to find in which paragraphs
Hahnemann mentions
the mental and emotional levels.
Now the different kinds of medicine that
we have applied ourselves, there were
different kinds of therapeutic measurements
that we applied all through the generations.
On mental level, there are treatments which
are directed towards mental level.
Which are these treatments
that we have today?
By affecting the mental level, they try to cure a patient. They do psycho-analysis, of course.
Almost everybody has gone to psycho-
analysis today. We have been through
psychoanalysis, that was the big
discovery on the 20th century.
Before the 20th century, no psychoanalysis.
At the end of the 20th century,
suddenly there was a need for psychoanalysis, and psychotherapists and psychologists
expanded to cover the demand. What
that means? Most of the population,
especially the American population, the Americans found out how good is to have
a psychoanalyst and what he does addresses you on the mental level and tells you,
don't worry there is a reason for your
anxiety, there is a reason for your fears.
Try to find the reason and then
redirect your mind instead of thinking
of the anxiety, to think why do I have
the anxiety and dig inside you
and you'll find out that your mother was
not proper mother, she had a boyfriend
you did not like him, he did not like you,
and then you reconnect with your father,
your father was this and that and you
search etc. and the anxiety is reduced.
Because the mind has been redirected
into something else but the main thing
for me is why such a need for
psychoanalysts in the West?
Do you have psychoanalysis in the Zulu tribe? Do you have psychoanalysts in India?
Thailand? China? Brazil?
Why? Because people there, are still
suffering mostly on physical level.
Why have we come about to this deep
level, ourselves? Do you know why?
Because of some measures that were
applied to us in a very general way.
What were such measures?
Except of antibiotics.
Vaccination was applied to all western population, thinking that we are
more smart than nature. And if we
analyze what vaccination is doing,
we'll see that it forces the organism
to produce antibodies.
At what cost is the big question mark.
Are you forcing so deep an organism
to do something without
punishment? Is it possible?
You change the structure of an organism
to behave in a different way.
Ah, wait a moment you are going to pay
for that. And what is the payment?
The payment is the increase in
neuro-muscular diseases,
multiple sclerosis, all kinds of myasthenia,
ALS, all these severe
neuro-muscular disorders,
which have exploded today.
So the nervous system, we see it primarily affected by these interferences and going
deeper into the nervous - from the
peripheral nervous system,
into the central nervous system - where
we have the change in the mentality
and the manifestations of fears,
phobias and all kind of
psychological disorders and diseases.
That is why the application of
psychotherapy on the mental level.
But you will see the difference between Homeopathy and these treatments.
The treatment is directed on one
part of the body, mental level.
And there is another level on which
some therapists are directed
and this is the emotional level.
Can you tell me any therapy directed
on the emotional level?
You need a positive shock on the
emotional level to bring about a cure
and sometimes it happens.
Musical therapy, yes. This is a therapy
but to cure really a chronic disease,
music is very, very, mild shock.
You need a big shock.
I will tell you. You have a person who
is living in a state of indifference.
He says 'I don't care, I'm not interested
to study, I'm not interested to go out,
I'm not interested in doing
anything creative etc.'.
And then happens one shock in
his life, on the emotional level
and this whole picture changes and
he becomes active, creative, enjoying
life and everything.
What can this shock be?
-Falling in love.
-Falling in love, of course. Falling in love
can act on the emotional level and bring
about a rearrangement of the whole
body and feels very very good.
Life has a meaning again!
The only problem is ...
- Getting married !
-Yes, getting married, very good.
What is the real problem?
Unless you produce such a shock to cure
you globally, to cure you group wise,
everybody is cured. The problem with falling
in love and becoming well is what?
-To disappoint?
-It's the problem of dependency. This state depends on an external situation.
It's like putting somebody who
is worse in wet weather.
He has pains and you take him and put him
in a very nice, dry environment. Ah, good !
As soon as you take him back
to the wet condition....
This state also is, I mean the modalities
which are using this level also are,
what we call faith cures or spiritual cures.
Whatever, energy cures.
You remember from Christ, he says,
do you believe? You will be cured.
This is an effect on emotional level.
You go to a spiritual healer.
Do you think you can change your
condition unless you believe
in that deep in yourself? The more
you believe, the more the effect will be.
And then the healer comes, he touches
you and you go ahh! the guru
has touched me. I felt so good. Again
we have the dependency on that state,
upon the relationship between the guru and
the disciple and how much he loves me
or he doesn't love me
or he touches me etc. etc.
So the spititual teacher acts
upon the emotional level
and how well the person feels
is analogous to the faith
and belief he has in his guru,
teacher or whatever.
People can live next to a guru
for years feeling very good.
The moment they get a disappointment
from this particular guru,
'I thought he was a saint and
I found out that he wasn't'
then the whole system collapses
and then the problems reappear.
So in the emotional level we have the
faith and love as positive emotions.
-But falling in love maybe sometimes is
the beginning of building a real love,
which is not just dependency but
interaction with support, which is good.
-That's what I said. In such a case,
the state of a better health will remain
for many many years and it will be
lost when the person is lost.
This is the case when people have
lived together for many years
and then one dies and the other goes totally
to pieces and within few weeks, he also dies.
It was a meaningful relation for those two persons, that means completing the needs.
It's like you lack a mineral and I have
the mineral, I lack a vitamin and
you have the vitamin, and I give you
the mineral, you give me the vitamin
all the time and then we are in
balance and we go ahead etc.
I'm just talking to you because you have
to understand the difference between
the different therapeutic disciplines
that exist all around you,
because you are going to be healers.
Somebody will come and tell you
'I was better with this or that',
so you know what's happening
with that person, how deep he was
affected, why he was affected, etc.
to be able to really help that
person more substantially.
The need to be loved is a situation where
does not bring a change in health.
It leaves you in a state of health which is
bad and it can become worse and worse.
When I say 'I am in love', I mean that
feeling of inspiration, exaltation, whatever
in which the other person also has
a reciprocal feeling for you.
Otherwise the change can not happen.
If you fall in love and the other person
doesn't reciprocate... you found somebody
you say fantastic... and after a week you say,
what about going out? He says,
I'm sorry I'm already engaged
... It was only for one week. It didn't last
very long because during this week,
you thought that the other
person is reciprocating.
The moment you found out she is not,
then back to the chronic state.
But what you have to know is when there
is a reciprocal love, health can improve
dramatically but not deep enough to
bring about a permanent cure.
It will depend on the other person.
I'm not against the gurus. What I say is, be aware of the workings of the human mind,
emotions and body.
Try to understand how it works.
How things are happening in this world concerning health and disease.
I have seen, for instance, somebody
who says, 'ah you will be well',
because he believed, his friend loved him,
whatever. You don't deny that, you don't say
'oh, it's only Homeopathy it can do', no.
If you feel better, it's good.
We don't argue with these things. We understand how deep they can go,
how long can last, this kind of cures.
And what is the difference between
these cures and the homeopathic cure.
What is really to be healthy?
We have to be absolutely sure when
we say that somebody is healthy.
Who is really healthy?
-Nobody.
-Nobody, ok. Nobody has total health.
Let's be clear on that, at least.
And we have therapists which affect
the physical level, which is the lowest,
and which are, first of all, primarily,
the allopathic drugs.
All chemical drugs affect the physical level
and from the physical level the action
is transferred to the
mental or the emotional.
In the same way that the affection of
the emotional can be transferred
to physical or mental, is it clear?
What else do we have in physical level?
All supplements. What else do we have?
All herbs. Herbal remedies are affecting
the physical level primarily
and of course we have  the vaccinations
affecting the physical body very deeply.
Why? Because vaccinations
affect directly the defense mechanism.
They go right to the core of the defence
of the human body and affect
the defence mechanism forcing
the mechanism to do
certain things which are
not in order with nature.
Saying all that, I do not mean you to
understand that I discard or throw away
all allopathic, herbal or vaccinations.
It is not as simplistic as that.
There are certain cases in which herbal
remedies will help considerably;
there are other cases where allopathic
medicine will help considerably
and there are other cases
where physical measures, like surgery,
can affect positively the human body.
I do not mean to just disregard everything;
to be clear about that ; not to give you
the impression that George said,
'ah only Homeopathy and throw
everything out', no. I don't throw away
the spiritual healing, I don't throw away
the psychotherapy, I don't throw away
all other measures. In certain cases even
with good homeopathic remedies,
you will need the support of some psychology
or psychoanalysis, in some cases.
In other cases, you will not be able to handle
an infection with homeopathic remedy,
for instance Syphilis, where you cannot
play around with homeopathic remedy
for a long period of time,
because Syphilis progresses quite fast,
from one stage to another and goes to the tertiary Syphilis state where you have
the affect of  the nervous system
and then you have problems.
So, therefore to say let us try to see
if we can find a homeopathic remedy
in a Syphilis case,
it's very very dangerous.
You better give immediately the penicillin
and after this treatment is gone,
which you don't do it yourself,
you send them to the specialist.
Then after that you try to bring about
the balance from the side effects
of the treatment or whatever.
But treating primary Syphilis with
Homeopathy, because we have some
records from old Homeopaths, who say
I treated Syphilis and I cured Syphilis.
In our literature we have these cases.
I never tried myself to treat primary Syphilis.
You have also cases where you have
severe peritonitis. The peritoneum is
in inflammed state and the danger of
life is imminent and you don't see
the right remedy clearly. You go and
give the antibiotics, though in
such cases of peritonitis, some cases
I have treated successfully.
But unless you find immediately the
first remedy correct, forget about the effect.
I once had a case of super infection on
an open eczema. The eczema was open,
it was running and she washed dishes and
there was a super infection upon the eczema,
which we had left untreated because it was
the result of a homeopathic treatment
due to severe asthma. Asthma treated
and then that state came about.
The eczema opened up and it was
really running out.
The woman tried to wash the dishes,
it was a super infection, and she came
with 39-40 degrees fever and she was red
from here all along and with high fever.
You know what is that?
-Sepsis.
-Yes, septicemia is called. In 48 hours
you may have the death of this patient.
It is septicemia which is starting, going
up and in 48 hours she is gone.
She came to Athens while I was going around treating patients from one room to another,
you know I was entering a room, writing a remedy, next room, writing the remedy
and in the middle of this, she came
and said, 'look at me!'
I said, 'come to the kitchen' because all the
other rooms were filled with patients.
I see her and I say ok,
the remedy is Sulphur,
I say to my secretary, give her Sulphur
50 M and I continue, go to the next room.
This was on Friday night. Then I go to
my home to sleep by 12:00 at night
when we finish, and I say to myself...
what have you done?
I mean, I did not even take her
telephone number to call.
It was Saturday, the center
was closed, Saturday and Sunday
and I had no contact with her.
I could not sleep of course the whole night,
Saturday I could not sleep,
on Sunday I could not sleep.
On Monday I was finished, I go to the
office thinking that most probably
she had died and I said
'why are you stupid?'
You could tell her go and get some penicillin
and now you would be sleeping nicely.
Ok, we cannot treat
everything and everyone.
This is to show us the possibilities of Homeopathy. Fortunately for me,
on Monday afternoon, she came
and said, 'look how well I am'.
I said, thank God that she had
this nice idea to come and tell me.
Because by this time I was totally
finished, in depression
I was telling myself how stupid
you are, we cannot save everybody.
And treating people, having
all the responsibility. It was fantastic.
50M fortunately, the remedy was correctly potentised, because it could have not been
correctly potentised and the
cure was fantastic.
She says, 'next day I was ok'. Yes, we
have this possibility but the remedy
has to be clear and we have to
know what we are doing.
Always keep in contact. You cannot do it in
this stage. Don't do it in this stage, please.
Penicillin it will save your sleep, you and
the patient. So I don't disregard all,
just to be clear about that.
But extreme cases in which I have put
myself in the process of these 35-36 years
of doing Homeopathy, have shown
me the the possibilities we have with
Homeopathy, which is great.
But on the other hand we can't be stupid
and narrow minded and think that
always we can treat with Homeopathy,
never mind if the patient is dead or alive.
-Excuse me, if I may go back to the case
of Syphilis. Isn't dangerous and
driving the troubles deeper with antibiotics
and maybe even confusing the case?
-Well, it is better to confuse the case
rather than lose the case all together.
Secondly, it has been found out that
penicillin will really manage to leave
the person with very little problems
considering the big problems
he would have,
if he was left untreated.
So, we have to chose between few
problems, little problems, huge problems
which will be unmanageable by anybody.
Don't even try, at least I have not
tried ever with Syphilis.
So, here you see all other treatments
are addressing themselves
either to the mental, emotional or physical.
And through the try to affect the other levels.
Try to affect mental level
through emotions etc.
The difference with Homeopathy is
that we go beyond that to the real
defence mechanism which is the
vital force and have an effect
upon the vital force which
connects these 3 levels.
By affecting the defence mechanism,
we have the rearrangement of
all these levels and we have the
best possible result.
In this same level, it works also, I believe,
I don't know very much Acupuncture.
Acupuncture works on this same level.