So today I think we shall be talking in the morning about the human being.
From the point of view that we are concerned,
of health and disease and what actually
happens, what actually takes place
within a human being.
In Homeopathy we're using new terms and
new understanding of the human being.
I don't say human body, I don't say
human mind; I say human being.
Human being is something which is
constructed from different parts and all these
they're maintained together with what
I would call cosmic energy,
that animates everything that
goes through everything.
And this is not a theory; it is something
which is tangible. There is something
which is beyond the human body,
the physical body and unless
we have this understanding we
cannot be real healers.
We must know where we aim at.
What do we want to accomplish
when we see a patient who comes to us.
He says I have this problem and
we give a remedy.
What do we want to accomplish?
These are crucial questions that
we have to be clear about.
The three parts of the human being as we
have been talking about in a kind of hierarchy.
Let's go to the physical. Low down in the hierarchy is the skin and then the muscles,
the bone structure, the kidneys,
the lungs. You see we have two lungs,
one can be taken away and we can
survive. The same with the kidneys.
The liver, if the liver goes away most
probably we'll not survive.
The endocrine glands which take into consideration the pineal gland and
all these deep glands and then the heart
and then the brain on top of the organism.
So we know from experience that if something happens to the heart, a scratch to the heart,
it might be fatal, a scratch on the
skin it means nothing.
The organs which are more high in the
hierarchy are more protected also.
The skin is the least protected but
the brain is within a scalp;
all around there is the scalp,
we cannot reach the brain.
The heart is also protected,
the liver perhaps a little bit less.
So in this idea of hierarchy, we just
show the idea that there is a kind of
hierarchy in importance. That is going
to be a major part in our understanding.
We're learning that the brain is the highest.
This is quite easy for you to understand,
is that correct? Is it easy for you to
understand that in the emotional part of our
being, there are also organs, organs
of the psyche, psychic organs.
Which are in a hierarchical order;
the organ which concerns with depression
is very very serious and is protected
mostly. The organ that concerns with
disatisfaction is outside and takes the impact,
like the skin takes the impact on this.
It takes the impact so we're
easily disatisfied.
Your wife got up and did not
prepare breakfast for you.
You're disatisfied but you don't
go to depression, right?
And then you see irritability.
How easily we're irritated but the organ
that concerns with irritability
is on a low hierarchy.
Then we go anxieties. Anxieties go
inside more and then we reach the
phobias which are even deeper. Then
finally we reach the suicidal depression
that means an organ that maintains life and keeps hold and does not want to be disturbed.
That organ is finally disturbed
and then life is destroyed.
The person jumps from the window
and is finished. When you are touched
on this level, you have a deep problem.
We do not yet know all the different
parts and functions of the psyche.
This is a gross enumeration of the parts
which are concerned with our psychic.
Why do we say that this is important?
It is important because when we treat
somebody and from apathy goes to some
melancholy and from melacholy goes down to anguish, then to phobias or to anxiety or to
irritability or disatisfatcion, then you
know he's going towards cure.
When the problems are going from
higher organs to lower organs,
we're going towards a cure. The person
is doing well and many times you will need
in your evaluation of a situation, where
you have given one remedy
you will need to think you will need to think
what has happened because the man
will tell you or the woman, men get
more depressed than women.
Men get depressed in a ratio of 2:1.
They need Aurum, the suicidal remedy
twice as much as women. So the man who
comes with suicidal depression and says,
'I'm thinking of suicide'.
'How many times?'
20, 200 times the day,
'I'm thinking of jumping from the window'.
If this man, you give Aurum, and changes
are coming and says, 'I now have fears,
I start fearing, I am a sinner, I have fears
that they are going to come and get me'.
Then you know he is doing better and he's
gone to another remedy which is Lachesis.
That is why the understanding of this hierarchy
is very important for a Homeopath.
We go to the mental. We start with
absent mindedness.
Lower in the hierarchy, forgetfullness, lack
of concentration, lethargy, delusions,
paranoid ideas, destructive delirium,
complete mental confusion.
So you see how the deterioration starts
and goes from one level to another,
from one organ to another. This organ
here has different functions etc.
-I just want to know for what reason you have
put the lungs under the liver in the hierarchy.
-Because with one lung you can live, you
take out one lung, it's not so important.
If you take the liver out, you go to
the next plane. These are only indicative
and we do not claim to have the
absolute truth. If a disease goes
from the lungs to the liver, for instance,
we have to know what we're doing.
If the disease goes from the lungs
to the brain or to the heart we have to know
that this is the wrong direction and
it is not good for our patient.
To know whether your treatment,
is doing well for this person.
Is he doing well? Yes. That means
he has to follow this direction,
from apathy to sadness, to anguish or from complete mental confusion to lethargy, to dullness etc.
In treating severe chronic cases, we don't
have the elimination suddenly of everything.
Most of the times you will have to encounter
or to treat the disease or the disturbance
that goes down to the hierarchy.
And then maybe you will need
the second remedy or the third remedy.
Here is a model with the 3 cones that the
3 levels are in a 3-dimensional picture.
It means that the body, the outside, envelopes, contains the other two. That's the first.
The second is that this model is divided
into levels. The third is, what is this?
The emotional or the mental, the highest emotional part of our being and the
highest mental part of our being I depict
them outside of the physical body, the blue.
They do not correspond to any physical stucture. It's something beyond the physical structure.
It is the highest part in us, the highest spiritual part which is its purity .... how you would call it?
Wisdom, pure wisdom.
That our highest spiritual part is
pure wisdom. That means we know
the truth if we can arrive at that state. And the highest emotional-psyche part is pure love.
Pure love and pure wisdom are
the highest parts which we can reach
as human beings which do not
correspond to our physical body.
They do not have correspondence
with our physical part.
We can reach perhaps beyond
our physical existence.
It means that most probably we can,
in this life reach, concentrate our attention,
awareness on that part and then become
as human beings the highest part in us.
Which maybe then it is indestructible.
Maybe after death there is a process where
this highest part of us, this understanding
and this love become a being which is carried
outside of us, through that cosmic energy
that is animating all of us at any time.
Well this is very practical. It's very practical
for us as human beings to know that the aim
is love and wisdom. To concentrate all our
efforts in that part of us which is the highest.
What is the proof that such a process
maybe true, maybe correct?
The proof is in several states in which we're going through, everyone of us in our life.
An experience which everybody has
between the physical body
and the detachment of that which
we call the vital body, a proof is what?
What everyday are doing in our sleep?
In our sleep we come out of our body
into a world which is totally different,
the dream world, we come out of our body
carrying in us, many times, our
understanding and our emotions,
fear, phobias etc.  whatever they might be.
Actually we're dying and resurrect every day.
In our dreams we have the condition in which
our psyche, our emotions and our mind is.
So if you have a nice dream, it means
that you had a nice psychogical condition.
A bad dream means that brought you to the place where your fears, phobias etc. are.
So for us there is very very clearly this part
which we call emotional and mental
it can be carried along with the vital body
which comes out and in the morning goes in.
Why do we go out? We go out and join
the cosmic energy from which
we get our batteries regenerated. We take
the energy we need to carry the next day.
We have several phases of dream.
First phase we say I had a light sleep.
That means the detachment was not great.
So we are almost aware between
this world and the dream world.
And then we have a second phase
where the detachment is bigger
and a third phase where the detachment
is really very very big.
In which way you may even travel
quite far from your body.
And if by chance your organism is such,
that allows you to carry with you
your awareness you may be seeing things
which are happening on a different place.
I remember once a girl studying in London.
She came in a panic to see me in Athens
because she has been to the psychiatrists and they said that she should immediately take
psychotropic drugs because of some
phenomena that were happening to her.
She was really terrified. I said, 'what
are the phenomena?',
She said, 'I don't know, the moment
I go to sleep in London, I fall asleep
and immediately I find myself back
in Athens, in my house.
And then I see my mother doing this,
my father, I hear what they say
but the most terrifying is that next day
I telephone and I say, mammy did you
talk to daddy yesterday? Did you do exactly
this? And they confirm what I have seen.'
Since this is happening every day she
was terrified, she could not stop it
and of course the psychiatrist told
her that she is crazy.
She had to take some
drugs to sedate her.
I said to her, 'I will tell you something.
I wish I had it. Your quality,
your body is built in such way that
the detachment from your vital body
is very easy for you, it can go very easily out.
Your desire to be with your parents
is very strong; so the desire to be
with your parents comes
and then you have the possibility
to travel back to Athens'.
She looked at me. I said, 'this is a quality which only saintly people have in a such a degree.
Why do we say saintly? Those who
have reached close to the love
and wisdom state can have that
clearness in their psyche.
Which they are not afraid to enter
this world and travel through.
So you are lucky person, you don't have to
be afraid of anything and I'm not going
to give you a remedy because you
are not sick, you are quite well'.
She wrote me 3 years later, she wrote
me a letter. I remember that letter,
she said thank you very much for your advice.
I finished my studies and I'm back to Greece.
Just because I had the correct information.
She was not afraid anymore, this would
not happen but only sporadically
because this was happening
out of her desire to be home.
The fear of what is going to happen,
the fear was exciting her psyche
and the psyche was going out
and she was travelling.
So you can imagine what happens if
I lecture in a medical university and tell
all these things to the students where some professors are sitting down there,
listening and say, this is the
most dangerous man.
Now there is some acceptance because of
the fear of death, the phenomenon of death
is coming, is overwhelming for
everyone, so they have to think twice
before they decide who is
dangerous and who is not.
Another state in which we have this
detachment is somnambulism. Sleep walking.
There we have the phenomenon
not of full detachment
but half detachment where the body can be moving but not completely, not totally free.
Next state is fainting. Fainting means that
vital body is suddenly ejected out.
Do you have a remedy in the Materia Medica where the body is going quite far
and then falling back suddenly?
We have mainly 2 remedies if this
phenomenon happens.
Te person comes back with a jump.
In the dream they feel they fall
from a high place, down and
they wake up like this.
We have 2 remedies; one is Belladonna
and the other is Thuja. Thuj. and Bell.
are the main remedies for people having
this phenomenon where
they feel they come down on a jump.
So fainting is also such a detachment
and then of course it is anaesthesia.
What happens with anaesthesia?
What they do, they eject out the vital body
and if you go to the medical schools
and talk about this disassociation,
they will tell you you're talking
occultism or nonsense.
But they are doing it every time and many
many times it is well known that people
who are under this state, they are able to observe and to hear and to see,
they have described it later on as
out of the body experiences.
Kubler-Ross, who knows Kubler-Ross?
Very good. I see you are informed.
She has described a lot of cases in which
people come back from this realm,
the beyond and they describe the experiences they had while they were near or half-dead.
Another state in which we have
this association, tell me.
Epileptic fit, short of.
Meditation.Yogi state.
Yogi state. It is described in many many
books where the yogis or these people
who are in deep meditation, they stay
motionless as if the body was totally dead,
while they are outside of their body travelling
and having experiences etc. etc.
This is very well described in many religions
by many people, by many authors.
See how many proofs we have of this phenomenon and still we are not able to
incorporate this information into the Medicine
and into the treatment of the human being.
And treating the human being only as physical body. Let's see some other states.
Another state in which the disassociation takes place is when somebody lives between
this world and the other. Schizophrenia.
In schizophrenia people live half outside
of their body, a little bit outside and having
the experiences of the next world, of the
world beyond and at the same time having
the body moved or doing whatever they are doing but not completely back into their body.
That's why in schizophrenia, they have
found out from old times they say,
let's inject some energy in there, some
shock, electroshock, they used to call it.
Still I think they use it from time to time.
They put energy through the body
and the shock brings back actually and fits together the vital body with the physical body.
And the person comes back in this world.
It's not anymore half of that other world.
Another proof of this phenomenon.
And of course the hallucinogenic drugs
that the young generation has used,
I would say, unwisely. The young generation wanted the experience of the next world
which they call it, the spiritual world.
I want to know what happens beyond.
I like to have the experience. They took hallucinogenic drugs which disassociate
the physical body with the vital body,
they bring them out and they have
experiences of different kinds.
Some of them, nice experiences,
some of them very bad and very
scaring experiences.
Can anybody tell me why some have nice experiences and some have bad experiences?
-I would say it's the mirror within them.
They project what they have inside.
-Somebody else what would say?
Is anybody else want to talk on this matter?
I know about 35% of you, you have
used these drugs.
Now that I look better it's more.
Maybe 50%. Once I was in America.
I was in a class like this, about that size.
I said, who has used drugs?
Everyone raised his hand.
Who has not? No hand.
For me I was, how can I say, I was
the forerunner of the hippies.
Because I left Greece to go to India back
in 58, still hippies were not existent.
And I went to India and searched for spirituality and all this kind but I never used any drugs.
It was not necessary.
It is not necessary to use drugs
because, can anybody tell me why?
If you understand the reason why some people have good experiences and others
have bad experiences, you will
understand why you should not use
hallucinogenic drugs
for such experiences.
The question is...I believe Stanislav Groff,
a man whom I met while I was in Essalen.
He was living next to Essalen. He was using these drugs for curing, mentally ill people.
Something which can cause, can cure of
course. It is the idea of similars in a crude way.
But my question to you, I know you have taken drugs and all that and you must not feel that
I'm accusing anybody, neither because
you experimented with anything.
For me there is no judgement at all. I'm giving you my understanding concerning drugs
because it is a problem that you are
going to face with your patients.
You have to know, to have clear ideas, what is happening to them, why this and why that.
We have to be as clear as possible.
Of course we cannot talk indefinitely.
But I want to give you my opinion concerning
the urge for spiritual understanding of this era,
of this time in the planet. Where the spiritual awareness has become a major target
for the young generation.
To tell you what I know about the drugs
and what cause and why. I have seen
a lot of cases that are going crazy
under the use of cannabis indica.
Where I hear a lot of people saying,
this is totally innocent. I'm not interfering
with this legal idea. What I know
is that I've seen cases under cannabis indica that have gone almost crazy, in panic states,
tremendous panic state which never
left them, 10 years, 15, 20 years.
And the suffering has been tremendous after that. The cocaine also, absolutely. Much worse.
Cannabis indica is hashish, you call
it grass, hashish whatever.
-I think it has something to do with
the susceptibility of the patient.
-I'll explain to you the mechanics.
We're talking on something
which is really beyond.
Here are the three worlds,
the physical, the psychic and the spiritual.
This is gross, but you will understand the idea. We are here on the physical world.
And we are in a hierarchy.
According to our spiritual evolution
we belong to different kinds of levels.
Now a person who is in this level, because
he is doing some correct things in his life,
he is really trying to clean himself,
to become a better human being
because of that, he may find himself going up
to the hierarchy, from one day to the other.
You take a decision. I will never do
again, whatever. You are raised.
So people who are taking drugs belong
to different levels according
to their psychical condition. What are
the fears inside, the guilt?
On the other hand are the aspirations.
You are going to eject yourself from this
physical world to this world, the
psychic world. This psychic world is also
hierarchically established. So you go out from the physical world and you enter this world.
According to the law of similarity, homogeneity, homogenous things will be together.
The psychic world is a dream wolrd
where we do not have our will active.
So what is active? Another law beyond our
will. This law says, if you eject yourself out of
your body, you'll go where you belong.
Not where you'd like to be.
How this is determined? It is determined according to the clearness of your soul.
How clear your soul is. So this lower part of
the psychic is a part full of gross nightmares.
This world where you enter, you fight. It is
the lowest part of the psychic world.
As this psychic world becomes clearer and clearer approaching the spiritual world,
it becomes very clear. So here is very clear.
The experiences on this level are fantastic.
If you enter there you feel sometimes,
you see a dream, you have an experience,
the skies are opening and it is a fantastic experience. You say, my God.
You deserve that because it happened to you. Now you take the drug and you eject.
You will find yourself in one of these levels feeling and having the experience of that level.
So if you go and take drugs by the time you
are depressed or you are full of hatetred,
if you go and take during this time, then your soul is disturbed, it's going to eject in the
lowest part and your experiences are
going to be really bad.
People have been relating to me their experiences and they were really frightening.
You see, this part of the world is the
protection for the spiritual world because
you cannot enter the spiritual world where there is pure love and wisdom; it has to be protected.
Otherwise everybody would take a drug,
shoot up to the spiritual part
and here I am with the angels or
whatever,  I came ejecting.
So there is a mechanism for protection.
The more you want to eject,
that means the more drugs you take,
the more you are punished and
you eject but you stay here.
Some young people who have a nice soul,
they are pure, they eject and they go quite high there; so their experiences are really beautiful.
But if they keep on doing that,
then what happens.
A young person does not know what it's happening. So he has this experience
and then what? He says, I'm now free.
Before I was afraid to have sex.
Now I took this drug, I felt more free,
I can have sex. They take drugs a few times;
then they go and start having sex.
That means violating again another law.
Then the opposite starts working and the purity becomes impure, more impure, more impure.
Then they end up, if they shoot up to come
back to the lower part. That's why some
of them have some initial experiences that
were very nice, very good, very uplifting
and later on they enter this world and
they had frightening experiences.
Of course it is not like this but just
to give you the idea.
These 3 worlds are interfering
with one another.
What I'm interested in is to give you the mechanics of how the human body
is working and whether you can help, so an individual takes the right way towards help.
Which is attaining the highest possible love
and the highest possible wisdom.
How? By the homeopathic remedy?
What the homeopathic remedy is doing?
She said, I had some autogenic
training and during
that training I left my body and I had
some experiences which were good
and sometimes were bad, so where
am I in this level, good or bad?
The good or bad experiences depend
on the time that you were doing this.
If at the time when you're doing this,
your soul is free of anguish, anxiety,
depression whatever, then you are
allowed to go on a higher place.
If on the other hand it is disturbed.
You left the house or you thought something
and then the sub-conscious is disturbed, what you are going to experience is your inner self.
This is not different. It is not that you are experiencing something outside yourself.
You are experiencing something
on which there is homogeneity.
You enter a field where things are;
your inner state of soul at the moment.
I don't know if you have ever confessed.
Let me give you the experience.
You go to the priest or whoever and you really confess. That means you are really shaken
by an experience and you go and confess.
And you say to the priest and I'm very sorry.
You went there out of instict to confess.
You enter with a tremendous loading,
in one minute, you go out and you fly.
You feel so well, so good, the air
is clean, the sky is open.
If that time you eject up, you will go quite
high. Then what happens with us is that
we again fall with our weaknesses and
we load our sub-conscious mind again
with guilt, fears, phobias etc. etc.
And then you go out again and again
there is a bad experience. But from one
moment to the other, your sub-conscious
can empty; the idea of confession is one
on which we shall be talking a lot
concerning the homeopathic remedy.