This disconnection we're talking about, is very great in one condition which we did not mention.
Can anybody think which condition
a person stays like dead?
-Coma?
-Coma yes. Coma is not like dead. Totally dead.
Sometimes they bury them. A state
of apparent death they call it.
A person may stay as if he is dead for three days. And the third day they come back.
There are a lot of cases, they bury them
and they turn around in the grave.
Which shows that the disconnection can be really very very great. The more the disconnection, the less life gives to the body.
I don't know the German medical term but the English term is "apparent death". In Greek the word is "necrophania".
It looks like clinically dead. It looks like but it is not. The doctor can check and feel the person has died.
There is no heartbeat. But actually after 2-3
days they can come back. You don't know?
What actually happens is that there is a withdrawal of the consciousness of the person;
that means the mental-emotional part withdraws together with the vital energy and goes to the next state.
So if these two bodies, that means the emotions and the mental, the spiritual part of the human being
have managed to create a whole, not being broken into pieces by the time of death, then it stays.
And in order not to be divided
during the time of death, you need what?
What is the power that brings things together?
What is the power that separates?
As an idea what is the power that mostly separates on a spiritual level I mean?
-Hatred.
-Hatred, yes correct. Hatred separates.
If you hate somebody, you don't want to see
him, the idea of separation is there.
So the opposite? It's love. If inside the human being there is love, there is connectedness, no pieces.
It will stay together. Not one piece of you loves this and another piece hates that.
You know how you are disturbed when you have feelings of that type? And when you have love,
you are not disturbed, you are
in peace, you are not in pieces.
So either in peace or in pieces,
you have to decide.
By the time of death, if you have peace, you will stay together. If you have pieces, the pieces will go back to their places,
pieces of love will go to pieces of love, pieces
of hate will go to pieces of hate. It's very logical.
I don't talk metaphysics. I talk facts.
But this, the beyond, we don't care. What we care is, can we help an individual to attain that state which is finally love and wisdom?
Can we help an individual to reduce negative feelings which are making suffering? Can we?
And the answer in Homeopathy is yes.
We know that we can change the negative
pathological emotions of a person
and reduce them to minimal.
Not that we take the part of the person
himself and his responsibilities.
He has responsibilities, he has to
do certain things himself.
But the extra pathological, negative emotions which a person has, extreme irritability, extreme hatred, extreme depression.
All these feelings we can reduce them through Homeopathy and allow the individual to use his quality for spiritual evolution.
Find in which paragraph of the Organon Hahnemann talks about this idea.
Hahnemann talked about this idea with one phrase. You have to find that phrase, where it is in the Organon?
You treat a patient and he comes
and tells you how depressed he is.
With this depression can you say
if he can be happy?
You treat somebody for extreme
anger, hatred, is he happy?
-No.
-So you see all these feelings, we call them negative feelings but be careful not to think
that anybody can eliminate totally
these negative emotions.
The substance out of which we are done is containing the idea of death. We cannot dispense with death.
We say that within us we have life and
death, going together hand in hand.
The cells are dying every day and new cells are produced in the body. This we know for a fact.
So the idea of life and death is hand to hand. Also is the idea of negative and positive emotions.
So negative and positive emotions are
necessary in order to create our structure.
If anybody lives in a state of pure love
and wisdom and clearness and purity,
can you imagine that, that means God
is manifesting through this person.
It's so much. The energy that no human
being can retain. It will burn out and
it will go to the spiritual world straight
away and stay there.
If we are here that means we have little devils inside us which keep us alive and in this condition.
Let's face the fact. Sometimes these little devils become excessive and overtake us and say,
I will kill him because
he has taken my girlfriend.
Once I was in London and I met a
scientology man. I met one and I said no, you are not good.
Bring me to another one, to another one.
So I reached the top man in London.
I said, ok I'd like to discuss with you. He said, are you clear? They claim to be clear, to have this state after going through psychoanalysis.
I said, are you clear? He said, yes of course.
I said, do you have a girlfriend?
He was about 35. Yes I have a girlfriend.
I say, 'can you imagine that I come and take your girlfriend? What will you do?', 'I will kill you'.
I said, ok thank you very much.
You answered my questions.
Another thing I did with this clearing.
They hold some cables and the engine shows,
if you have emotions, it goes like this.
You have emotions.
So the clear people, you can put any question, no emotions. They can handle any situation.
So it was a woman, that was in South Africa. You hold it and I put the question. I put the question, I said, you see?
-What was the question?
-It doesn't matter what was the question.
The fact remains they claim to be clear.
Who can be clear? For God's shake.
Even the most saintly people, if you ask them, that's why they are humble, they say we know.
It's only they don't say. We know
that we are tormented by little devils.
By saying all that I may give you the wrong impression that either before you treat somebody
you have to be Gods or that I'm something like that. That's why I clarify the issue.
So this is a good example that
we should not be prejudiced.
I was thinking of Apis and then she gives an information. We change. I have no problem.
Yes this is correct, I believe you. Take
Ledum. Not like 'I know, take Apis', never.
And this is a great danger for Homeopaths.
It's a great danger. Be humble always.
Do what is right,
not what suits you best.
I've seen many cases.
People insist this is a case of whatever.
Even if the patient is doing
well with another remedy.
I have a case on video. You will see the man brought his daughter, I gave Tuberculinum
if I remember.
So she was back in America. She went to a Homeopath. She was quite sick and she was much better.
So the Homeopath says, I don't agree with Tuberculinum. I will give her another remedy.
She said, no thank you very much
I don't want it. And she was saved.
But the idea is that you don't listen to the person. If she says, I'm better with this remedy don't
leave it.
I will continue to complete my thoughts. I would say that all this is animated by an energy which is neutral.
All these worlds are animated by an energy which is neutral in nature. They are neither bad nor good.
How do we know? That the nature of this energy is one and it is going right through everything?
We have a great proof for that. The proof is that when we potentise a remedy which can be
a plant, a mineral or from animal product.
There are three levels of existence.
All the plants. One level of consciousness.
The minerals is another level of consciousness which we consider it as the lowest level of consciousness.
The plant and then the animal. And then we are supposed to be in a higher level of consciousness, ourselves.
When we potentize a remedy from the mineral kingdom, we take a stone, Silica. And we crash it and we potentise it.
We crash it and then we dilute it and then we take one part of this dilution and again we dilute it and again we dilute it.
In the end of 30 consecutive
dilutions what has been left?
Nothing. Energy. Something like of the nature of energy. A subtle energy. A new kind of energy.
When we do the plant, we have the same result. We have energy. When we have animal we have energy.
Once we reduce these substances into their energy level, they can affect an energy level which can be homogeneous to theirs.
We have electric energy. Can electric
energy be affecting the human body?
No. It can kill it. But it cannot be affecting this energy on the level on which we are functioning.
We are functioning on some kind of energy.
Where from we take this energy? From the same place like everything else, like the animal, the plant, the mineral.
And the proof is that if we reduce these substances into their pure energy,
this energy can really affect a level in
us which is the energy level.
So therefore the two energies that run through animal, plant, mineral and the human energy
is of the same basic quality.
It's very logical that there is an energy which animates and passes everything and gives form to everything and if we find a way to bring
the substance to its energy level, then
that energy can affect our energy.
That means the idea of all
pervading God etc. etc.
Which we have a proof with Homeopathy that really there is a substratum of energy on which we all exist.
So that energy definitely
pervades all these levels.
If the two energies were totally different,
they could not have effected at all.
You cannot affect inhomogeneous things.
They cannot affect each other.
They have to be homogeneous.
They have to be of the same basic quality.
That's why we say that Homeopathy is a healing art which is really based upon universal laws.
So let us see what happens when this energy passes through each one of us and what we are doing with this energy.
The energy as I said, is neutral. It passes through a plant and takes the form of a rose or the form of a stone.
It passes to us and it takes the form of the human being. Then this human being is disturbed and eventually becomes sick.
What actually happens? How
responsible we are for our state of health?
Why we have so many sick people today and where lies the responsibility for each one of us?
Can we do something about it and what is the best thing to do? I mean these are questions that we have to answer.
The matter is not very simple but I will simplify it as much as I can and of course as we go along,
later on we can go deeper and
deeper and exemplify more and more.
The health of an individual depends on what?
Genetic predisposition. We have hereditary.
We take the good or bad predispositions from our parents.
We can do actually nothing about it.
The second that our health
depends on is on ourselves.
That means what we are doing
in every moment of our life,
we determine the state of health
in which we'll find ourselves tomorrow.
So what has shaped our state of health primarily is the hereditary which is behind us, not only our two parents
but a whole series of generations.
We are like the waves of the sea
and we are here at this moment. We bring all this along with us, as hereditary at this particular moment
and then we have our free will and
we decide what to do with our health.
What we eat, how we feel, how
we deal with matters of health in this life.
And then this shapes our health at this moment.
Now there is a third factor which plays, according to me,
a tremendous role in shaping the health of the human beings at this state. Which is the third factor?
-External influences.
-Yes but what influences?
-I think it's the collective thoughts
of all people living on the planet.
-Yes, they also play a part but I'm talking about a factor which really has shaped our state of health at this moment.
A tremendous factor,
very important, very strong, very obvious.
-Education? - No.
-Surroundings? -No.
-Nature? -No.
-Religion? -No.
-Nutrition? -No.
-The western Medicine.
-Unfortunately this is true. We are all victims of vaccinations, unecessary drugs that we took in our lives.
Not only ourselves but even our parents.
In this generation we have also the parents
that were bombarded with hormones,
cortizones, antibiotics etc.
which shaped the state of health in which we are today. And unfortunately these measures
have affected very deeply
our human organisms.
The people who were healthy enough and
were avoiding taking drugs are very lucky.
You will find them usually in the mountains, people who stayed without medical care.
Who existed with the traditional things which are going on in the villages. They are the most lucky as far as this is concerned.
Of course I do not disregard the fact, I have to say, that in certain cases we have to resort
to save the life of the person,
to antibiotics or to cortizone or to surgery.
But what I am accusing is the wide spread and wide use of unecessary very severe, chemical drugs.
Who is the woman who gave birth to a child without taking hormones, to give birth at a certain hour?
Because of social reasons the gynecologist is free only between 10 and 11 and you have to give birth between 10 -11.
So at 3 o'clock you start taking hormones
and by 10-11 you have the birth.
But this hormonal effect and what is
going to do at the child...
and then we have the children with cancer. Every year cancer in children becomes more and more prominent.
It's not only that. The child is born,
they say, it has to be vaccinated,
otherwise cannot go to school,
otherwise we have problems etc.
We are talking about unecessary vaccination.
- Would you like to tell us which
are the necessary vaccinations?
-I'm not going to give answers to all the questions of the human race which we're facing at this moment.
What I'm stating is only an information which
I know for sure, it is absolutely sure that
what I tell you is my experience
and what I know, not theory.
So I'm stating the information.
What has to be done is not up to me to decide.
Neither ever any government invited me and say 'come here, let us discuss what shall we do'.
Neither I have all the information which
I would need in order to take such a decision,
and say for instance this vaccination is necessary and the triple vaccination is not necessary.
The children used to go through
the children's diseases very nicely.
Why now they have to be vaccinated so
the child will not get the children disease?
I consider this unecessary. I consider also unecessary the vaccination of  rubella, chicken pox. All these I consider unecessary.
They have stopped now but before
they used to do quite a lot, the small pox.
I believe and I have done a research which almost proved it that the multiple sclerosis
which is so widely exploded today,
is a direct effect of the triple vaccination.
Because you can see multiple sclerosis only on western population. There is no one person
in Africa who suffers with multiple sclerosis.
There was not one person in Asia who suffered, why? Because they did not have vaccination all these years.
Now vaccination is starting entering these countries and you will see these countries also producing a lot of such problems.
I read a lot about M.S. and they had different ideas. One idea was that it was geographically distributed to certain areas.
But there was Israel for instance where
it had the highest rate in multiple sclerosis.
The highest rate in multiple sclerosis is in Israel.
Which is in the area where there supposed
to be no multiple sclerosis, why?
Because the Israelis went back to Israel from European countries where vaccination was introduced
many, many years ago. So they were vaccinated while in Israel were also vaccinated and therefore they had the problem.
While the Arabs next to them, they had no problem. The Arabs until recently, until 20 years ago
did not know what is multiple sclerosis.
They did not know the disease.
The Africans also. Who knew? Ourselves, here in the West with the vaccination and it is absolutely sure
multiple sclerosis is a direct effect of certain vaccinations. Most probably more than one.
-My son is 13 years old now and he is vaccinated for the DPT in the States 13 years ago
and 4 days after that, he had a seisure,
this was when he was 3 months old.
And it turned out that he had a
severe brain infection from the vaccine.
All the conventional doctors that saw him said that he is going to die, he had no chance to survive.
They were sure it was a genetic disease at the beginning, it 's a very long story but he had no hope whatsoever.
He came out of this with Homeopathy, with a lot of care and love and support that he had but a lot of other children
that were reacting to the vaccine had died or remained severely mentally and physically disabled.
We have seen a lot of cases like this in the States and a lot of years that I have worked
with many children afterwards that were damaged from the vaccine and victims
and very often after the first vaccine the children had high temperature, swelling, they go into seizures and
the doctors give them another vaccination
and then they get very severe reaction.
We were lucky because he became sick after the first one and we avoided any other vaccination.
If we had given him another one, he would be dead immediately. It turned out that this was a lab in England
that was producing this vaccine and after a batch, a lot of children in the States
became very sick, they stopped using this vaccine.
It turned out that it was cheaper than another kind. And it's all money and business behind it.
So many victims, generations of sick children
are becoming victims to this vaccination.
Even what we see in Israel, children that get the polio vaccine because the water is not clean
and you can get polio from
the water that you drink, react.
And it was 3 years ago a polio disease in
Israel and a lot of children were vaccinated
and some of them immediately got the polio disease through the vaccination, as a reaction.
So we see how Homeopathy is working with like cures like,  and the same can happen with vaccination.
-Well this kind of story I have heard,
in my 36 years of practice, so many times.
And nobody can tell me that 3-5 days after
the reaction, 2 days after the reaction....
Now when the goverments have to take some action? I don't know. What kind of action? I don't know.
I'm stating the problem and I say, this is a problem. Do you want to see it?
And not only this problem which is immediate; there is another problem which is much more subtle,
much more insidious and much more dangerous.
Because undermines the health of the planet. There is nobody who is exempt from side effects of vaccination.
Others to a great degree, others to a very minute degree but nobody is exempt.
And if we have time I will talk in detail about my attitude for vaccination and you decide which is good and which is bad
and whether vaccination is really protecting or not protecting etc. There are a lot of issues involved in this matter.
And for the Medical Doctors who are here and who are involved with the public health,
these issues should be raised in
every government, in every country.
And we have to say, here it is a problem, do you see it? First see the problem and then decide what to do about it.
But definitely there is a problem. But my point of view is that it's not only these few cases that are immediately so bad.
It's the long term side effects which the vaccination has, which are terrifying.
I went to India myself and I had to be
vaccinated by different vaccinations.
I went to a Doctor, I said, please
give me that you vaccinated me.
Because I knew that it would not affect me. There are some conditions which I will determine for you later on.
What I want to say here is that as the energy passes through us, which is a neutral energy,
our actions, drugs and hereditary predisposition determines the state of health in which we'll find ourselves everytime.
What actually happens is that, that state
of health is what? If we see it on energy level?
Through these factors we are creating blocks within our body, where the energy cannot flow through, undisturbed.
By affecting the physical organism
very much, we are establishing certain blocks
about which Hahnemann says,
we are affected by the miasms.
Hahnemann understood something almost intuitively. That they were certain cases
easy to treat and he gave a
remedy and they did well.
There were other cases that they were difficult to treat and he said, what is going on here?
So he brought out the theory of the miasms. That we were affected, as race, primarily by three miasms.
The psoric, the syphilitic and the
sycotic, which is the Gonorrhea miasm.
He said, sometimes 1, sometimes 2 and sometimes 3 of these miasms have been
intermingled into the organism and created a state of health which is much more difficult to treat and to cure.
This is his understanding. Now he says, if that state is further complicated by drugs, then the case is incurable.
Find the paragraph in which
Hahnemann states this idea.
Slowly as we go along, we're going to build a model which will become more and more clear for you
and will give you a quite precise
idea of what is going on in the human body.
Whether some patient that you have in front of you, will need 1 or 2 or 5 remedies before he is well,
whether you should use a high potency
or a low potency how you should go about;
we're going slowly to build that model
that finally will give us a clear idea
of what we're going to do, what we have to do when in front of us we have a serious case of chronic disease.
The psoric miasm Hahnemann says, it comes from the suppression of skin eruptions in general.
Actually in ancient times most
of the diseases were in the skin.
In the Bible when they talk about leprous, they talk about tumors and the organism was trying to keep
all disturbances on the external part of the body.
And that's why people were more balanced and definitely more healthy in general.
In ancient Rome, if somebody was sick he had to hide it because it was considered as a social stigma.
They did not have doctors; the doctors were the magicians, the charlatans, you know around the area
and go secretly, I have this problem.
So the whole population was quite healthy,
but what they did? Other actions.
You know the Romans how they behaved
and what they did with their lives?
How they lived?  Dolcevita, too much dolcevita and then what happened with the dolcevita?
Because it is very very satisfying to have sexual intercourse. It is a climax.  It is a high point of satisfaction.
If you can use this satisfaction, why not?
Use it every hour or half an hour, whatever.
So from psoric through sexual intercourse the syphilitic miasm and the sycotic miasm, the two miasms
which are concerned with venereal diseases were exploding through the generations.
Why? Because the human beings were using
a lot of sex in the wrong way, of course.
I'm not a preacher go and have sex and whatever you like, the land of freedom. I'm just stating facts.
I give you the information which is useful for you to know as doctors and healers, nothing more, nothing less.
I don't say 'oh sinners', for God's shake,
I don't need Veratrum album.
So what Hahnemann saw in 1890 or about that time when he discovered, what he saw is that syphilis and gonorrhea
were undermining the health of a lot of people. How this came about? It came about through sexual intercourse.
We know from history how the Romans lived while at the same time it was very shameful to have a disease,
at the same time they were doing all that.
And then venereal diseases were exploding.
And where came the venereal diseases from?
From where? God knows from where. Some say from the dogs or the cats or monkeys, whatever. I don't know, I don't care.
What we care is that now we know that
venereal diseases are sexually transmitted.
And instead of having only these two basic diseases today we have modifications of the diseases;
it's a host of sexually transmitted diseases
including the one which is AIDS.
AIDS is a sexually transmitted disease,
a venereal disease, nothing else.
According to my understanding it's only a modification of syphilis and gonorrhea together.
A new special bonus that
we get for what we're doing.
I would like to say a few things concerning sex and what I consider to be a healthy way of life.
I'm not against sex but I believe that you cannot have sex, just to have sex. This is not permissible.
That means not that I do not permit or you do not permit but the human body is constructed in such a way
as to function in 3 levels. You cannot separate and say, I'm going to function from here to there. Forget it.
It's connected with the psychic, it's connected with your mental and if you try to separate this, it's like schizophrenia.
Promoting a kind of schizophrenia. I will separate my emotions and I will just have some pleasure, forget it.
You're going towards schizophrenia.
You're going towards a schism.
The human being acts always as a whole.
The emotions participate, the mind participates
in an action, in the highest action which
is considered as very specific
moments of communication.
You communicate with the soul of the other person, not with the body of the other person.
If you say, I'm going to communicate only with the body, then you have made a schism and you're going to pay for that.
You are going to pay, absolutely. But not
the way you think you are going to pay, no.
By just creating on your emotions a hard place, a little hardness, a little nodule, a little tumor, a little cancer.
That is hard because you have your emotions and your body says, ok keep going have sex.
You have hormones or whatever which are pushing you and then you go and have some sex
and release them, whatever.
They are different ideas and theories about this.
But I tell you the moment that especially a woman, does not have sex under proper conditions.
That means first having contact on an emotional level, on a psychic level and then as a consequence of that contact
to feel loose and to feel happy and let herself into this climax, unless she does that, even a man will have a problem.
Whether she or he likes it, whether
he or he does not like it.
Of course you can separate, you can harden your emotions, you can close yourself.
And that is why we see, for instance in Natrum muriaticum where the person is closed and can not express the emotions
they go into a kind of sexual intercourse etc. closed. This makes harder the emotions, the same with Anacardium.
They feel terrified, they feel insecure. They close their emotions, they're feeling that the others
will crush them, they go into sexual intercourse without this connection on the psychic level and then they get hard emotions.
The emotions become harder and harder
and then they have to torture the animals
or human beings or whatever to feel the connection. Because the connection is lost,
cannot be felt. But you have to take into consideration something which is very important.
That as we are not isolated human beings, I'm not isolated, I'm connected, I feel your emotions, your thoughts, everything.
Everything you think I'm connected. The
more sensitive I am, the more I'm connected,
the more I feel how each one
has thoughts, doubts etc.
So I'm connected; I canot isolate myself.
If I do isolate myself, then I lose the opportunity
to evolve spiritually because the final state
of spirituality, they say is to connect with God.
But to connect with something which is supposed to be outside of you, it is to let
all the egotistical elements which
are in us and makes us feel isolated.
So the first action to let lose, is to love somebody else and to start from that point of view.
And to drop the egotism which
is you are there and I'm here.
In a love affair this is dropped and human beings are living the idea of connection with God.
In a real love affair, in the climax, the
experience is so great, if it is correctly built up,
that it is the same experience that we have that the saints have when they connect with God.
They let themselves, their feelings are open and they connect with cosmic or whatever they call it.
Each religion calls it in a different way,
it does not matter.
And then there is this great opening and great satisfaction and then we have the higher state of health.
We'll come to the definition of health later on, these are preparations for understanding
what I mean what I say as definition of health.
And what is health, where it takes us, how we promote health, in which way, where we take it etc.
There are a lot of questions that we have as healers, as people taking the responsibility to take her to a better state of health.
We claim that we know the way. But really
how many of us do we really know?
And what we're doing.
Most probably we're lost.
Grobing and darkness and searching, trying to find out. I gave a remedy and says, this reaction.
What is this? What have I done?
A lot of people. Medical Doctors also who
after all do not have such a responsibility.
They can kill anybody, anytime, you know.
Medical Doctor can take somebody in the hospital and say, he died in the hospital, no problem.
But if you are not a Medical Doctor and you make a mistake and somebody dies, then you have a bigger problem.
So we have to know what we're doing that the remedy we gave is promoting health.
Unless we know all this theory, unless we understand very well this theory,
forget understanding what we are doing.
Many times I' ve heard, 'I've given the right remedy?'
A beautiful reaction and I heard stupid comments on that case or some practitioner
entering and giving remedies to spoil the action of the remedy because he does not understand the issues.
So if we had healthy human beings, I will tell you, no woman would have sex unless she was 20.
At least 20 years old to understand what she is doing. Now girls which are 12, 13, 14 say why not I'll try.
See what happens. You see later on, when you are 23 you are dead emotionally and she doesn't feel anything.
Whether she marries this man
or that man, makes no difference.
She says why not, he is good,
he is rich, I'll marry him.
Good, rich, marry him you go for a husband syndrome. You know I have found a syndrome
which I call the husband syndrome.
Which gives us specific type of symptomatology in a woman who marries under such circumstances.
And then the woman come into connection with any man. And then of course she is in danger
of getting all kinds of sexually transmitted diseases. 'What's the problem. I like him'.
You meet one person one night, you go and have sex, then you feel nauseated almost because you did that.
When I talk like this sometimes
there are big reactions.
We say we need health. She comes
there to us and we say, ok what's your problem?
I have these phobias, the anxiety,
depressions and all that.
And I said, ok take Aurum.
Aurum will help him to what extend?
To the extend that he will catch up
with the idea that I'm now healthy
and act accordingly, according
to rules which promote health.
If he falls back into the habits he had
beforehis health will slowly go down again.
Then again Aurum. Then he picks up, second possibility. The third time he comes and the picture is changed.
You give Aurum, nothing happens. Then you give this, you give that, you give another remedy, another remedy
and then you lost him. He went and took Valium. Now Valium, then more Valium and then Tryptizol and then Largactil.
I give you too much, it's ok? You follow all this?
You are attentive but I'm not sure whether you really grasp the points.
So it becomes yours, your point,
your understanding.
Because unless you really understand
what I'm saying, you leave with doubts.
You'll say, is this or that?
Or maybe this or that or whatever.
Hahnemann's idea of the miasms is absolutely correct but experience shows that it is not complete.
And the idea is that in order to treat an
individual who is suffering chronically
with severe disease, you may need
to unravel to take away one by one
the different miasmatic layers
that have come upon him.
How you do that? We shall be learning the Materia Medica and then accordingly
we shall see how we handle an individual
who is miasmatically very much affected.
It's very strange that you may find for
instance, children who are very sick.
And you say, what they have done?
They have done nothing.
They are sick because of this heavy, this is very heavy, hereditary is very heavy for them.
And you get another individual who is born with a very good health and you find him at the age of 50,
his health is almost wreck because
of this. Our action.
And you find some unfortunate
people usually living in medical families,
who had very good medical care from the beginning years and they were drugged a lot;
they are very unfortunate. Maybe hereditary
it was good, their action is good
but they took so many drugs that
when they come to you, they are wrecks.
And this undermines the organism so deeply that it is very very difficult to untagle such an individual.
You will see when you take a case in front of you, we will take a case and you will be able to
perceive who is good, bad, very bad,
very good, quite good, etc.
You will be able to establish slowly the state of health in which that individual is and you will see
how much these factors will
determine what you have in front of you.