So the subject on which we are talking about is Objectives.
Through homeopathic treatment where do we take the patient, what are we doing?
We are clearing, as much as possible, mental-emotional and then physical, in this order.
First clearing mental, then emotional and then physical.
So we have the idea from up downwards.
We have the idea that the cure should go from Mental, then to Emotional, then to Physical.
This is a must in order to say that we are successful in treating a patient.
If a patient is here depressed and at
the same time he has headaches,
the right order will be depression to go
and the headaches will become worse.
Perhaps with the same remedy, if it's not very deep, we'll continue and the headaches will also be better.
What do we all want? You want to be a good Homeopath, that's one. Some of you have more ambitions, you want
to be good homeopath who will teach, some of you want to be a good homeopath who teaches internationally.
Some of you who have more ambitions,
you would like to be the Minister of Health
of your country and then
impose Homeopathy and say,
'Eh now you had it'.
And if you think in your mind, shall I be this? If I'll be this, shall I be really satisfied? And always there is something else that you want.
You'll find out that there is always something else, what is this something else ?
We want a state in which we are in peace with ourselves. That state we call, it's a generic name, we call "happiness".
Unconditional happiness, we don't want a happiness which is dependant upon anything.
Whether I'm successful or not successful in my profession, whether she loves me or she does not love me.
We don't want this dependence, we want unconditional happiness; this is what everybody actually wants.
If you search deep down in yourself you will find that this is really with what you will actually be satisfied.
And that is why also, people who could stay isolated in the desert, a little place in the desert, you see an individual
who is very happy, very content with himself, he has nothing, not even water.
What is that makes him happy? He is in peace with himself. That means, being in peace with ourself, it's a huge
objective that is very difficult for anyone to attain. We need to have an individual, a giant, a saint to attain that state.
So it is an objective. Since this is an objective for anyone to be satisfied, happy etc.
the Medicine which helps an individual to go closer to that objective, is the correct Medicine.
So if you are dissatisfied in your life...what is a problem with you? especially children do like this, you give a dose of
Calcarea Phosphorica and the child next day is happy. You give a dose of Chamomilla and the child is quite happy,
a dose of Cina, all these remedies with the very dissatisfied, inside them is like having worms.
So therefore Homeopathy is a system of Medicine which can promote the evolution of the human being.
Because it takes away the pathology which is in the mental-emotional and leaves the individual
to battle with what is natural tendencies
for him to battle, to fight.
All of us, as I said, we have negative points, weak points, we have to fight them ourselves, nobody can help.
But these points which belong to our personality, under pathological conditions, they are exaggerated.
So a person who is very quick and perceptive by nature, by character, becomes very irritable if somebody
does not understand what he is saying.
This shows already a pathology starting and then he fights with his relatives, he fights with his wife, with his children and
he fights himself and after fighting, fighting he finds himself isolated.
Once he finds himself isolated, the depression comes. Then from Nux-Vomica goes to Aurum states of depression etc.
So the pathology if it is left to work inside us, exaggerates more and more the negative qualities of our
personalities, it gives us the feeling that we are going away more and more from happiness.
That's why, when we are healthy and we were children, we say I was so happy, I had a happy childhood
and then problems came and then in order to fight the problems the pathology comes in
and then you have a huge pathology later on which leads the patient to come to you to ask for help.
This is the whole picture.
We have another objective to establish an understanding of what is health.
And if we have accepted so far the idea
that an individual is functioning on 3 levels
actually we have to have a
definition that fits all the 3 levels.
What is the word that can characterize the definition on these 3 levels? The word is "Freedom" !
Health therefore, is freedom on the physical level, freedom from pain, discomfort. I'm not the slave of pain.
Did you ever have a toothache? Did you ever have a severe pain to see how much slave you are in that pain?
Can you think of anything else?
Forget it, you are a slave.
Freedom from pain gives the definition of health in the physical.
But there are people who say I don't have pain but I have general malaise, a general feeling of tiredness in my body.
So therefore the freedom from pain has to be completed by a sense of well-being.
So the definition on the physical level has to be like this. Freedom from pain has having as a state a feeling of well being.
I feel well. It's a long time since we felt like this.
When I was thinking about these issues and I was trying to get an answer, I have seen quite a lot of patients in the meantime.
I have seen healthy individuals. I remember a case of a villager who had come, not here, I was in Athens.
He was relating to me a case where his neighbour came and put the boundaries of his land a little bit inside his.
He says 'I took my gun, I went there and I shoot him'. And of course when he came to be treated he was after prison.
Very strong, but was he healthy? I thought this man is not healthy in his emotional side.
And then I treated a lot, here in Greece in these times 1960's still the Communists were people of great fanaticism and passion.
Down, the government and whatever !
And I saw their psyche was always in a state of, you know if you mention the word "government"....
And I said, is this a healthy state?
Then I saw other cases of people who were attached to another individual, usually a man to a woman.
A man came and he was a slave to
that passion for that particular woman.
His actions were irrational, totally
irrational, like the fanatics.
And you say, these are healthy people but in these levels something is wrong. What is wrong?
And then I saw spiritual people who were trying at least to attain it, they had a serenity and all that.
And how they faced all these
issues, with much more serenity.
The definition of health was completed by the idea of freedom from passion on the emotional level.
If you are very passionate you are the slave of your passion, whatever it might be.
Then I saw individuals who had no passion at all.
They were people that had no passion
for anything. No interested, nothing.
You lose your wife, it doesn't matter, you lose your home, it doesn't matter. He is a Mahatma, but he was not a Mahatma,
he was sick. He has apathy. That may give
you the idea of freedom from passion
but on the other hand you are apathetic.
So the definition on this level should be that the person has to be free from passion but he has to have inside him
a dynamic serenity, dynamic calmness. The calmness which is alive, not a dead calmness, not I'm indifferent.
I'm calm but I'm alive, perceptive. I think about everything, I perceive, I respond.
Somebody is suffering I respond, somebody wants my help, I respond, somebody wants to talk, yes.
I am alive but not passionate !
Either you have Homeopathy,
everyone has Homeopathy or die!
I take a bomb and I throw a bomb in the world because the world does not accept Homeopathy. I could be like this, why not.
Many of you think I am like this, it doesn't matter.
I am much more tolerant unfortunately.
So, I felt that the people who are really more in peace with themselves, they were more perceptive,
more ready to come to the rescue, that means you have more love. Love flows naturally, you don't say to yourself
'oh, I have to help'. If you say this, forget
it, the emotions are gone.
You make a program, today I'll help this, this and then you try to accomplish these things, forget it, this is not healthy.
But if you attain that state where there is no irritability, no passionate attachement to anything idea or whatever
then you may have a dynamic serenity inside
you and face calmly the situations.
Who can do it? Nobody, but I say this is the target of a healthy state. It is where we should be looking at
not that anybody is like that. Perhaps
some of you have some grandfather
whom you remember in the end years being like this but it's not an easy state to attain. So we are looking towards that.
And then we come to the mental state. The health of the mental state that is even more difficult to attain.
Because there we have to have freedom from - nobody has that - a healhty mental state
is a state where you are free from selfishness. You are not selfish anymore.
This is something for sure impossible for anyone to attain. All, we are selfish, I want this, I want that.
It is not possible to eliminate selfishness.
Because if you eliminate selfishness
that means the sense that I'm separate, I am a separate human being - this is selfishness;
I am and I want this, that and the other is 3-5 meters away, and the world is all around me.
If we can eliminate that then the state in which we enter is a different state. We can make a jump in the consciousness
and then we are actually connected with the cosmic consciousness, with God. Who can do that?
You see it is pure mechanics. The moment I'm here and I'm separate, I cannot be flowing into the consciousness.
I have the sense that I am here so everything will be limited, everything will be measured
from me to that distance, to the other person, to the other things.
If I can eliminate this idea, I'm nothing,
then I'm one with the consciousness.
It is a very high spiritual state towards which we may be going, freedom from selfishness.
It's the effort that everyone of us is doing every day to be able to be less selfish to be more in connection with that which we call God.
We cannot eliminate that. I feel that nobody can really eliminate his selfishness, this egoistic element which is with us.
It's not possible but we all try towards that goal. And I'll tell you something, the new generation
is thinking a lot on these lines. That is why by taking the wrong path they went into drugs, they wanted to
experience the sense of not being, so they took the drug and some of them they experience something so nice.
And then they became slaves of that passion which is called spiritual passion or whatever.
Because we can be slaves of our desire to become this, to become saints, one with the cosmic consciousness.
So therefore a person comes to you and you talk with them and you understand more or less where they stand,
what they want, where are their shorcomings because we all have shortcomings, we all have weak points.
And what you do as a healer you try to ease out these points. It's like somebody who is suffering, because
people who come to us, suffer for years. Can you imagine somebody who needs a bit of attention, he never had
any attention and you just give a bit of attention and some care and he feels so good. You don't do that because
this is very little, temporary. Psychotherapists, psychologists they are doing quite a lot of that.
But we have a possibility to give relief on a deeper level and that is why we have to stay objective observers,
not to get involved. Oh I love you, you are so nice !
If you do this in a Homeopathic consultation you lose the truth of the other person, you don't understand what is happening.
You cannot see the picture, if you are involved. A person comes who likes you and you like her
you feel both very well doing the interview, she gives you some compliments, you give her some compliments.
She goes away today, tomorrow and then again in depression. Because you did not realize that this is a case of Aurum
or Natrum muriaticum, you did not realize because you got involved. So we don't do this temporary relief
where you give some sympathy. We are acused for giving attention and they say if you give so much attention
to an individual it's natural he will feel better and that's why you have some results with Homeopathy.
That for me is pure noncense. Because I have seen cases where I paid very little attention and I had the most fantastic cure.
I saw a sign, I saw a little thing, I asked one or two questions, take this and go. How is that?
I remember a case from Germany, he had come with his child, he brought his child in 1969. His child was suffering
with asthma, he was a greek architect living in Germany.
By that time we did not have pharmacy, we just dispensed the remedy. So I said to the child 'open your mouth'
and I put this and I said 'ok go'. They went. The child was cured. 10-15 years later I hear that this man
is back to Greece and he's talking and he says 'George he doesn't have to give you a remedy, he just does this'.
He had forgotten that I told the child open your mouth and I put it. All this has gone out and the only thing he remembered
was that I said ok, be well. He was an architect, he was an educated man. Later I met him and said, are you serious?
He said 'yes this is what I thought'.
That means autosuggestion or whatever you call it. This is pure nonsense, absolutely.
You have to be objective, to know what you're doing, you give it and then forget about it.
You don't have to give attention,
how nice you are etc.
Sometimes of course if the person is totally distressed and you feel that the next day is going to jump from the window
then you may say a few good words, pay more attention.
But we have the possibility to relieve this pain in a very deep level and give the possibility to the individual
to continue with his life and do whatever he likes with. it.
The problem is that they come to you so distressed and say 'I will change my life if I find my health back'.
You say but you have being doing all these things which are not correct, smoking, drinking a lot forget it, don't do it.
They say absolutely I'm not going to touch anything. You say 'ok take it'.
After a few years they have again the same thing.
The same thing and of course is a relapse because the way of your life brings about a relapse.
Then they come back to you and again they promise, no I'm not going to do it. They continue doing it. Third relapse.
So the definition for health is freedom, freedom, freedom.
Not anarchism.
This has nothing to do with governments, I'm not an anarchist.
It has to do with inner states.
How can we know how far we can take that individual to health?
You see an individual and you have more or less the idea how far you can take him to health through Homeopathy.