It is a very great pleasure for me to address you tonight and I also feel that it is a special moment.
A moment in the development of Homeopathic movement which is very important for the whole world.
I don't think that a few years ago if anybody was hearing to speak of Homeopathy and collect as many people as they
are here tonight;  that's a sign that the time is now for Homeopathy.
Tonight I have come to share with you some of my experiences concerning the human health in general, which I must say
are not very optimistic.
We are living in a time where there is a lot of excitement and the great technogical progress that promises to give us a lot
and promises to give us the possibility to live in abundance and happiness.
Well my concern is that it is doubtful whether or not we will, in the course of few decades possess an adequate state of health to fully enjoy
the fruits of our technological progress.
Why do I say that? Many of you may know that I have been directing a clinic in Athens where about 30 medical doctors are
practicing full time in which we see about 2.000 patients every month.
We don't see these patients casually.
We take the thorough history of their medical past and we watch them as we keep them on and on in the years.
As we attended all these thousands of cases and have seen how they react to different ways of treatment
I come to the conclusion that the human health in general is in great hazard, in great danger.
And my conclusion is that the health of the human race is rapidly degenerated.
Ten years ago during several of my lectures at the Athenian School of Homeopathic Medicine
I suggested, as a consequence of my convictions,
that soon the human organisms will develop a susceptibility to previously unrecognized violent infectious agents.
In less than 10 years, this prediction has regrettably began to be realized.
Legionaries diseases and a host of others new infectious diseases with the recent breaking up
of the disease which is called AIDS, and acquire deficiency of the immune system.
All these new diseases are breaking out, which means that the human body is opening up,
is exposing itself to new agents that were unknown before.
They were there but the human body had a protection and now this protection has been broken down.
This new susceptibility to infectious agents is however only the tip of the iceberg.
The deterioration of the collective health of mankind is far more perversive than this and it's reflected more dramatically
in the relentless progression of chronic diseases.
Serious chronic diseases affect tens of millions of people and the incidence steadily increases, even more in our juvenile population.
Diseases such as rheumatoid arthritis, osteoarthritis, cancer, epilepsy, heart diseases, allergic conditions, bronchial asthma, multiple
sclerosis and all the neuro-muscular diseases and serious chronic mental disorders are today alarmingly increasing.
I would anticipate that we are one to take a census.
It would be discovered that we, of the entire population over 20 years of age of our industrialized countries, are taking some kind
of medicine for some chronic disturbance.
I want just to give you an incident which was related a few months ago, where we have been treated a person with phobic state.
He was very reluctant to say, to confess his fears. Eventually we make him tell all his fears. And he said to us, a few years ago
it would be impossible to talk about all that, but lately it has happened an event which made me more possible to speak about my
fears and phobias. Why? Because I was on the American Express, he says, and some lady, there were a lot of people inside.
Some lady fainted and to my amazing, he says, I saw almost everybody in American Express, in Athens rushing out taking some
kind of pills from their pockets and give them to the lady that has fallen down.
I was amazed if so many people are taking pills, I thought I was the only one!
And having these panic fears where he was almost in the point of fainting and taking all these pills, he felt he did very secretly.
Well this is a grotesque example of what is happening today as far as health is concerned.
I just want to give you very quickly a few numbers in statistics which come from the National Health Service from this country.
The statistics say that malignant neoplasms from 1961-73, these 12 years, have increased almost 50 %.
50% in 10 years, in 100 years what happens?
The heart diseases have increased 54%.
The nervous system diseases, 36%.
Circulatory system, 24%.
Muscular-skeleton system, 36%.
You see all these diseases which I referred to, they are serious chronic conditions exploding.
Gastro-intestinal conditions, gastritis which is something which is not severe, has increased only 4%. That is normal figure.
If the general health of the human body was stable in a way, 4% or 5%, up to 10%,
up and down but some figures are extremely high.
Where are we going?
These examples are illustrations of the undeniable truth that our society's health is deteriorating.
And it is especially interesting to know that rising incidents of chronic diseases and the appearance of new diseases
are occurring primarily in the industrialized countries of the West which paradoxically provide the people with the greatest
access to orthodox medical treatment.
Thus one can arrive at one of both possible conclusions. That the order of health of the human population is deteriorating either because
of the employment of allopathic therapeutics or in spite of its use.
Certainly there must be many factors counting for the rising of chronic diseases and the increased stress in daily life in industrialized society,
nutritional inadequacies in our diet, environmental toxics in which we have plant ourselves.
But it remains my contention that our health is being compromised to great extend by the wide spread of allopathic drugging and effect.
Well, this is perhaps an assumption. This is perhaps something that you cannot take it for granted.
Tonight I would like together to go  through certain concepts that I hope eventually to be able to show to you logically
that what I have said so far, is true.
To understand what is happening we have to understand what is that we call a human organism.
What is the human being?
Is it the physical body? Is only the senses?
To my understanding the human being can be said to function in 3 different levels.
On a mental level, on an emotional level and on physical level.
Now immediately we have a different concept of the human being.
Maybe the concept that the human being is just pieces of cells or flesh is not very valid anymore, in our understanding.
What is the mental level? It's very simple.
I will give you first a generic definition.
The mental level is that part in us that registers alterations in our understanding or consciousness.
The emotional part is that which registers alterations in emotions.
I'll give you certain functions of the mental level, you see the thinking process. When we classify, when we criticize,
when we compare, when we calculate, when we create and conceive ideas or synthesize these ideas, we are working primarily on mental level.
So there is a mental-spiritual part in the human body which can said to function at a certain moment and the human being
as a whole focuses its function on that level.
And then there is the emotional level, what it contains?
All the degrees of emotions, from love to hate, from joy to sadness, from calmness to anxiety, from trust to mistrust, from courage to fear etc.
All these fine emotions are contained and they are interplaying in us; they are happening in the emotional level.
We cannot say,  we don't have emotions, we only have cells
We cannot say, we don't have thinking, we only have cells.