Who has a good idea about the
qualities of a healthy mind?
Who got the Agaricus?
Later on you will see the percentage.
Who got the Aconite?
More or less the same percentage
with the Italian group.
So, I would like to hear your opinion
concerning the qualities of a healthy mind.
-Clarity.
-Clarity of the expression of thoughts.
-Common sense.
-Awareness and flexibility.
-Concentration and good memory.
-Trust.
-The ability to make through
a plan and tolerance.
-Vitality and perception.
-Peacefulness, harmony and freedom
and being present in a moment.
-The ability to continually integrate
new information.
-Optimism.
-Optimism, that's all you need?
-Compassion and to be constructive and
to have wisdom and also yearn for wisdom.
-Creativity.
-Being able to control one's thoughts.
-Possibility to communicate.
-Dynamic, creative, positive way of thinking.
-Try not to hurt others.
-The ability to distinguish between right and wrong and to make positions accordingly.
-I'm very satisfied that the answers are from people who are thinking and are thinking deeply.
Because the answer, though some of
you did not answer the question,
you gave different answers than
the question requires.
It doesn't matter. Still you thought out things
of the mind which are of a high order.
For me a healthy mind has primarily 3 qualities, which some of you have mentioned.
These are coherence, clarity and creativity.
Coherence is somebody who talks in
such a way that everybody can understand.
There is no mixing of thoughts and ideas.
He talks clearly and coherently. That means one thought after the other in a correct, logical way.
And if the mind is clear in its expression
of ideas, and at the same time,
that same individual is able to think
creatively, not destructively,
you see for each one of these,
it has an opposite quality.
Here, in coherence is confusion, in clarity is unclear, and in creativity is destructiveness.
A man who is confused is unclear
and destructive.
And the idea of creativity again contains the idea of being creative for myself in order to evolve.
Let us say, I want to live comfortably.
The mind says, I want to live comfortably
and tries to find ways to have a good time.
So within these ways of finding ways to have
a good time, to have a good wine, good food, good woman, good enjoyment, good theater,
good cinema, good television, is this a creative mind? What has he created, what is he doing?
Then there is a point where the mind
will ask 'what are you doing?'
and then he will have a problem. Now this way
of thinking will lead eventually to disease state.
And he will come to you and he
will be so confused, he cannot even
describe to you how is he feeling.
Now this mind of course can be the mind belonging as a totality here, there, there.
There are different qualities of mind of course.
A carpenter can have a clear mind.
He can make a nice furniture,
he can be creative.
Whether a philosopher can also be clear, coherent and creative on a different level.
So you are measuring sometimes in
your answers, what is the best mind,
a mind near to God, near the truth,
I didn't ask that question.
What I ask is general rules where
you understand more or less
where the mind stands, the mind condition.
Because here in coherence - clarity - creativity belong the symptoms
that we see in the Repertory. You open the Repertory and you see "absent minded"
it belongs either to the clarity or the confusion.
"Abusive" it belongs here destructive.
You see "ambitious" "amorous" "answers slowly", "aversions to answer",
"difficult to answer" - destructive,
"answers confusedly",
"answers inappropriately",
"answers incoherently".
So each of these symptoms you can
see they belong to one of the 3 qualities.
When the mind is disturbed, is disturbed in
one, the second, the third or in all of them.
And when this is destroyed in the human
being and then it goes to opposite quality,
that is the worst minds that we have in the
planet, very, very sick minds, destructive.
There are some people who are sitting in
their offices thinking how to destruct,
how to burn out the planet.
It's literal what I say.
You create and then you destroy, attacking, violence, destroying, the urge to destroy,
to kill, desires to kill. It's a feeling of
destruction; there are sick minds
thinking in this way, they have coherence,
they have clarity and they are thinking
in a destructive way. Who are these individuals?
-Hitler.
Some politicians, never mind Hitler, not only Hitler, we have a lot of destructive people;
they have a very coherent mind, very clear mind and all the time they are thinking how to destroy.
I knew a person working for NASA,
a physicist in America.
He was one of the physicists who
calculated the intercontinental missiles
that will leave Nevada and hit Moscow.
He was one of those people who calculated exactly this and he knew where
this is going once the buttons are
pushed. This is going to destroy
this area and they were doing it coolly.
We are going to destroy this and
and this and we have to destroy
also this. After all this, one day
he got very sick and he felt that
he could not anymore work.
He did this job 12 hours the day; he was paid very highly but one day he got very sick,
he went to the doctors, they could not cure him.
His liver was destroyed very soon.
And then he felt he could not work anymore,
he quit NASA, he left, you know NASA?
And he tried to cure himself. It took him
a lot of treatment with Acupuncture
and then Homeopathy before
his health was recovered.
I mean they are doing these
things but at what cost?
They have to block their mind to
the idea of creativity and then
that quality goes to the opposite.
The man who killed the children he
may had coherence and clarity
but he felt destructive inside.
The next question I put it was, what
were the qualities of good emotions?
What are the qualities that will make a
healthy emotional side in a human being?
-To be free from passion like
jealousy or fears, anxiety.
-The possibility to express emotions
adequately to a situation.
-Satisfaction.
-Laughing, happiness.
-Serenity.
-Peace and tolerance.
-To let it go.
-Compassion and ability to open your heart.
-One to be aware of his deepest feelings, especially those he would not like to feel
and came into peace with them.
-The ability to find and feel the
beauty and love in nature.
-You are better than me. Well, my idea is that in the emotions, in the sphere of the emotions,
we have positive and negative emotions.
So who is healthy?
The one who has, who feels
positive emotions most of the time.
One emotion is love - hatred.
You have compassion, you have indifference.
So you want to see how healthy
you are on this level.
Measure actually your feelings during
the day. Are positive or negative feelings?
To that extend you are healthy.
Depression - Joy.
Question for homework.
I gave you the examples,
I want you to write as many positive
and negative feelings as you can think of.
For anxiety the opposite will be serenity,
for agitation, angry, irritability,
you have to write for me, it is like
a self-examination for yourself.
First you will write the emotions by mind
and then your feelings will come and then you
will remember your feelings and write
them down. And then you will know
and you will see that none of us has
positive feelings all the time, none of us.
So there are positive and negative
but where is the balance?
If the positive feelings are most of the time,
then the balance is towards health.
If negative feelings are overwhelming
then the balance is towards disease.
It is a very characteristic thing that people
will say after a Homeopathic remedy that
my anger is gone. But when the anger is gone, the opposite is replacing, automatically.