So even Hahnemann had some points in
which it was proven that he is not right.
One of these points is when he says that a disease is cured by the Homeopathic remedy because the remedy
is producing an artificial disease on the body which is stronger than the natural disease.
This is a wrong assumption of Hahnemann, definitely and it's not important not even for him because he says
in the Organon, you don't have to care howthis is accomplished, the cure but anyhow if you want me
to give you an explanation I can tell you.
An artificial disease is stronger than the disease and therefore
it takes out the disease and plants the artificial.
The artificial has some more symptoms perhaps, what we see after a time, after you give a remedy,
you may see some symptoms of the remedy, afterwards.
So Hahnemann thought that this is the artificial disease which is being planted, it pulled out the natural disease
and now it's the artificial disease running its course and it's going to go away in a little while.
I want you to follow what I'm saying and to make sure that we communicate; otherwise there is no need for me talking.
So this issue has to be clarified.
There was a misunderstanding concerning
the hours so the German people
might have a problem with this.
No problem, they are becoming a little bit Mediterranean. You see in Greece or in Italy or in Spain,
if this was taking place, we say we start at 9.30 and we start at 10.00 and everybody is happy.
So the moment you enter the class at 10.00 o'clock everybody is happy, talking and there is anxiety.
If you do this in Germany and you enter the class half an hour later, you had it. Nobody laughs, they sit there, straight.
Once in Germany I put the flash light to turn to the main street and I hear somebody bip, bip, bip.
I don't understand, what's happening? I did some mistake. There was a very small street
which I did not notice before I put the flash.
The street was there and I put the flash after that. I should have turned that some street and not the next one.
He thought if you put the flash before that street, you had to turn that street.
-That's right.
-So from tomorrow we'll have German time.
So I would like to start this class with the idea of the provings.
In Homeopathy we have the information of
what a remedy can do from the provings.
So since many people of today-and this is very good and very interesting-are really interested and involved in provings,
we have to know what we are doing when we are doing provings, otherwise we are going to be in trouble
and serious people will look at us and laugh. Unless we do seriously what we have to do.
How we do a proving? If in this class we want to make a proving, what should we do?
Hahnemann wrote in par.32, that all medicinal substances have an unlimited power over
the human organism while diseases have a limited power over the human organism.
You have to have a predisposition to get the epidemic, you have to have a predisposition
to get the disease, you have a genetic predisposition to get the psoriasis
or the systemic disease or the neuromuscular disease, you have to have a predisposition.
Hahnemann's general idea was that the medicinal substances, that means the medicines
have a power greater than the disease.
And that led him to the idea that the medicine
because it is stronger, overpowers the
disease and then runs its course.
Now it came from the idea that he said.
All medicinal substances have unlimited power
with one condition that they are given in large enough dose. So what that means?
In a class like this, if we start an experiment
with a remedy, with a plant, with Bryonia.
In order to produce symptoms in all the class,
we have to give a large enough dose,
not as a general rule, but as an individual
need for each organism.
That means we start with giving Bryonia mother tincture 30 drops to everyone. Next day 2 or 3 of you come and say,
'I have developed these symptoms'.
That means 2-3 organisms, out of the whole class, are the most sensitive ones.
And then you continue. Those people that they have developed symptoms already, have to stop taking the drug.
Then next day the rest of the class continues to take 30 drops every day. In 2-3 days another small group appears
to develop some symptoms, they stop. And you continue like this until you reach the most resistant organisms some
that they may develop symptoms in the 20th day and after a repetition of several times. That means 30 drops,
4 times the day. Then even the last one will develop some symptoms from this remedy.
Now the argument they bring, the allopathic physicians is that, how is it possible that you say you have symptoms
from salt, common salt, Natrum muriaticum, since we take everyone of us,
we take from 5 to 7 grams a day of common salt.
The solution is in Hahnemann's
remark, large enough dose.
There are some of you who take double salt than the others, yet there are no symptoms, right?
But try to triple the dose, that means
instead of 7 grams, take14 grams or 21
or half a kilo and see if you
develop symptoms, yes or no?
So each organism needs a particular dose.
Then immediately you will see the thirst that develops in Nat-m,
you will see the dryness, the headaches eventually and you will see all the effect on the whole system.
The same with Bryonia mother tincture.
Now the other argument which they say is that you claim that you give one dose of Nat-m 200
in a group and you produce
symptoms, is this correct ? Yes or no?
This is a subject that the class has to understand very well, otherwise if you involve with this kind of discussions
or application, to yourself or to others,
you know what you are doing.
So let us suppose that the whole class now instead of 100 gr of salt, takes a dose of
Nat-m 200.
Who will develop symptoms?
Who will not develop symptoms?
-The sensitive ones. The sensitivess
to Nat-m develop symptoms fast.
-Who are the sensitive ones? How do we
know who are the sensitive ones?
I'll tell you something else; I don't want to make
the real experiment like this, but I could do it
and then I could prove it to you
but it's easy to understand.
I'm giving you tomorrow a powder because you agreed to do an experiment on proving.
Everybody takes the powder and the day
after I tell some friends, like Fred there
who could do it very well, that the
substance I have given is radioactive.
And Fred whispers radioactive, radioactive! And then on Wednesday you come to give me your symptoms.
Then you will see all the kinds of symptoms
even fainting, epileptic fits, paralysis,
all kind of things will happen and
the class will go into spasm.
This is a proving you know, a great proving,
we write down all the symptoms and it's all imagination.
So when we give a high potency it's only the
very sensitive people to this remedy
that may develop some symptoms, nobody else.
So if you see a proving in which a remedy has been given
and all the provers have developed a host
of symptoms, hundreds of symptoms.
You say, wait a moment sir, this is, there is a
nice English word but not for ladies, nonsense.
It is the imagination of the people who are part on the experiment. I take a substance, so I'm going to develop
some symptoms. Now I close my eyes and sometimes I say, how do you do it? You see we take the potency
and then close our eyes and meditate.
And then you write down the symptoms
and all that, this is total nonsense.
We have a lot of provings today which are done in this way. And these provings have gone into the books,
have gone into the journals, have gone into the Radar system. Wait a moment, how did you get that?
So one project that you have, as you know, you are going to be doing test papers all the time.
One of the projects that you have to do is to write down the paragraphs which refer to provings in the Organon.
Paragraphs that refer to the proving.
These are individuals and everyone
of you has a different vibrational frequency.
So to which frequency you will be
sensitive when I give you Nat-m?
Here is a person whose frequency is very close. This person and this person who is close, we gave Nat-m 200.
This person's frequency is exact,
what is going to happen?
-Cure.
-He will be cured. Anyhow even with few symptoms. There was a scientist who came to take
an interview with me from a
scientific magazine from Germany.
She said to me, she is a biochemist and she said 'I don't believe all that, that 200 will create any symptoms
can you give me a proof?'
I looked at her, she stayed here for 3 days,
3 days interview. She is writing in a very serious magazine.
And I thought shall I excuse myself? Shall I give all the theories? Or shall I do the experiment?
I said ok, I'll do the experiment. In the meantime, I understood that her constitution is close to Nat-m.
I said oh god if she's exact, she will be cured.
If she is not exact, still she
will develop some symptoms.
So without explaining to her any of
these thoughts, of course, I said,
'ok you take Nat-m 200 and if you develop any symptoms you stop it; you take it every day'.
She came to Berlin and she said,
'nothing happened'.
I wrote in an envelope what symptoms she may have developed in case the remedy was not exact.
She would develop some headaches
and dryness in the mouth.
She says, 'none of these symptoms that
you wrote down I have developed'.
I said, 'yes but you are looking so radiant'.
She was looking really very happy.
The first time I saw her I said, 'are you sad?'
'No, no, no I'm very good'. 'Ok', I said.
Now, in Berlin, she was so radiant; I said, 'you are looking so much better than the time I saw you'.
She said, 'yes that's true'. I said, 'well this is the thinking' and then I explained to her.
She pondered on this idea. And this idea is exact, what I'm saying to you, here is going to be cured.
This, you gave a close remedy you are going to have some symptoms of the remedy developing but not a cure.
The vibrations which are changing, the further they go from the sensitivity of the remedy
the less are affected. And here they are not affected at all, these people will not be affected
at all.
How do we know that? We know because
when we give a wrong remedy to a person,
he comes back and we say: what happened? Nothing, absolutely the same.
But sometimes a person comes back
because you have given a close remedy,
to this person you gave Natrum muriaticum,
you will have some symptoms.
Let us say he comes for headaches and
you prescribe Natrum muriaticum,
and the headache goes away and now
she has developed vertigo.
This is what we call a close remedy which
does not cure but changes the symptoms.
So you can understand what is going to happen if you have given 5 remedies or 25 remedies.
How many of the symptoms of the person
will change and then there is a confusion.
Find for me in the Organon the aphorism in which Hahnemann talks exactly about this issue.
Which is the issue? You give a remedy, you hit one symptom, the main symptom perhaps,
you change it but the case is not cured.
Which is the paragraph in which
Hahnemann refers to this issue?
-247.
-No, you are wrong, unfortunately it is not.
Don't say it because all the class
writes 247 and all the class gets zero. I don't want cooperation in these test papers is not allowed.
If the whole class writes to me the correct answer that means that one person found it and then spread the word.
You have to study the Organon and then from par.100-200 you may get it. Just study 100 par. and then you come.
What is interesting here is that if we want to make an experiment, a proving how shall we go about?
We're talking now about the technical matters.
To prepare a sub-toxic dose of the remedy and then give it to the provers and see which
of the provers are the most sensitive. To which they will develop symptoms for this remedy.
And then in these provers, in the provers
who have developed symptoms the first or the second day,
only to those provers you can give a high potency and find out what happens with the high potency.
To the others is useless and they will give you information which is totally unreliable.
They were telling me of an experiment they did in America with 3 groups. One took the remedy, one took placebo
and one took nothing. The remedy
that was proved was Radium bromatum.
So we have some symptomatology
in the Materia Medica.
What happens is when the results came out, who was the group that has the most close symptoms to Radium bromatum?
-The placebo.
-No, those who took nothing. Those who took nothing imagined symptoms that were fitting
more to the proving of Radium bromatum.
Do you realize the importance in all the Theory? Everything that we do is based upon the provings.
If the provings are done wrongly, if the information comes and it is hap hazard,
it is mixed imagination and real information.
Because out of the 50 people, most probably
1 or 2 of them gave correct symptoms but who are the correct?
How can you find out who are the correct and who are the misinformed, it's not possible.
Because the leader says symptom, symptom, how do you find which is the correct one?
And then you apply this and sometimes they say, the people who do these kind of provings,
they will say, 'but some people gave this
remedy and then there was a cure'.
Of course there was a cure because we have what we call the placebo effect or they may have used
1 or 2 symptoms of  the real proving out of
the 500 symptoms that they were false.
If I give you a remedy, everyone will bring symptoms to me, of course.
But mostly probably 2 of you are sensitive to the remedy, that means your symptoms are the reliable ones.
How do we find? Only through this
process of going first
and prove all the sub-toxic level and then proceed to higher and higher potencies.
Otherwise, the information which will come
to be used by us, will be totally unreliable.
That's why I have decided in this course that
I will give you, out of all the remedies
which I'm teaching, the experience which
I have that this type of symptoms
are reliable in every remedy and you can
use them with great confidence.
-So they didn't know what remedy
they have been proving?
-No, nobody knew that it
was Radium bromatum.
-But nevertheless they produced
symptoms, how is that possible?
-You did not understand. There is another experiment, I had a problem with these provings.
They proved Hydrogen and they brought
out a book with symptoms with Hydrogen.
I said well, this is very strange because
first of all Hydrogen is a very volatile gas.
Hydrogen you cannot find it. The moment
it comes, it joins with Oxygen and
an explosion and then there is water.
Apart from that I said ok, the same thing that this group used and a group from Italian doctors came to do the proving.
What happened is that the placebo and the group who took the remedy developed almost the same number of symptoms.
There were 20 symptoms by the placebo group and 25, small difference, by the group who took the remedy.
None of these 25 were the characteristic symptoms of the Hydrogen that the other group was writing.
So where is the truth? The truth is that depends on the imagination of the provers.
They imagine symptoms and it depends on the interpretation of the symptoms by the leader.
Oh you saw a dream that there was standing
a ghost. So you have fear of ghosts.
You saw a dream that your mother was standing next to you but the shape of the mother was not exactly;
I mean she was my mother but not as
I remember her. Ok, that is a fear of ghosts.
It depends on the interpretation. In this way we have almost destroyed classical Homeopathy.
So I consider this subject very very important.
They told me, as I have said before, we potentise the Berlin wall. The wall that was built to separate Germany.
I said what did you do? Did you take a little piece of the cement, you potentise it? They said, no.
They said, 'we took a powder which we put it under the wall, we sat around and meditated'.
I said, 'to whom do you prescribe this remedy?' They said, 'to those who want a divorce'.
If a patient comes and say, 'I can't stand my husband', there is a desire to separate, Berlin wall !
I mean this kind of noncsense is going on and it has to stop otherwise Homeopathy will go down the gutter
and it will be disappearing and nobody will pay any attention anymore with all this crazyness
which is coming up in
the picture of Homeopathy.
What is scaring in me is that people
do not react to this nonsense.
They think that these are new ideas, why don't we incorporate the ideas, creative ideas.
-We have exact rules here in the
Organon about the way of proving.
-Of course. But this is not followed and
also you have to know that provings,
that means the information which is in the Materia Medica, comes from what?
The first source is provings. The second source is toxicology, that means accidental,
or intentional toxicity of subjects by the substance.
And the third one, which is one of the most important sources, clinical cases.
So the information in the Matera Medica comes from provings, we start with this, we add the toxicology
if we can find it and then we apply and we see
if in the clinical case, this remedy has affected the case.
And which other symptoms have cured apart from the ones which we prescribe.
And if there are some new symptoms which have been cured by that remedy, we note them down in a notebook.
And then in next case we see according to
these symptoms we can prescribe and then,
if this is active,
it happens that it cures then we may start thinking that these new symptoms belong to the remedy.
-Is it true that the most important point is the third? If is it proven several times that he remedy has helped in the clinic.
Is this the most important?
-You cannot say which this is the
most important, you cannot say.
Sometimes important symptoms come from
this source, sometimes from that source.
The problem is that such information has
gone into the Materia Medica already.
Unreliable information and for instance one has proving of the Luna, of the light of the moon.
This is nonsense, the light of the
moon cannot produce symptoms.
A substance in order to cure it has to have the capacity to produce symptoms in the human organism.
Otherwise it will not cure.
So the luna or the sun or the wind or the rain are physical phenomena that do not produce symptoms.
What they do, the physical phenomena, because our organisms, sometimes becomes deranged, even the sun,
even the luna, because you are sick,
the wetness, the rain, the thunderstorm etc.
all these physical phenomena
because you are deranged,
because the system is deranged then
it can react and produce some symptoms.
He says, 'I don't feel well during
thunderstorm', ok we potentise the thunder
and we give it to you and you
will be well, this is nonsense.
'I'm not feeling well during the full moon'; this is true but this is because you are crazy,
I mean you have a disturbance and therefore
I have an eruption because of the exposure to the sun.
Of course because your liver is not
working and therefore the sun etc.
When somebody says, 'I am worse in the sea', you don't potentize the sea. You give a different remedy
which is worse in the sea. Of course the sea, because it contains a lot of elements it can produce;
if you go and drink 3 kilos of sea water what happens? Of course you will be sick.
So I want to know if this is clear, if you have some questions. It depends how this proving was done.
If it was done with aqua marina, sea water,
first of all I don't know the proving.
Secondly, if the proving is done properly
then you can rely on such symptoms.
If it is not done properly and it is done like
one high potency and meditation, forget it.
As I said maybe some real symptoms are there but the majority of such symptoms are imagination of the provers.
Which are the qualities of the provers as determined by Hahnemann, in which aphorism?
It's a pity that people who are willing and they spend time and energy, they don't do it properly
so we can have reliable information.
It's a pity because you waste your time,
energy and you inject a lot of
misinformation into  the science.
Please give me all your thoughts
and all your doubts to clarify the issue.
-What about other impoderables like X-ray and Electricitas and the second point is, is sun
also produces symptoms like sunburn.
-What about other impoderables
like X-ray and electricity?
Ok, we take these two first to examine
and then we examine the sun.
Now, how long you can stay under X-ray?
Half an hour and see what happens.
Of course X-rays have the possibility of producing symptoms in the human organism;
therefore X-ray can be a remedy,
if it is proven properly.
Now how can we prove X-ray?
X-ray we do not need to prove on toxic level,
because there is no actual toxic level
but we have the side effects.
We have these cases recorded in the literature in Medicine which are the side effects of X-ray.
From this we can start and have a guiding mind and of course, in such a case, we go to these people
who were sensitive to the X-ray and we
invite them in an experiment with X-ray 200.
Then you may really find some
interesting symptoms to record.
But unless you do that, go and find those people who are sensitive on the X-rays and then they had all these
problems and then you organize it, you cannot say, I give X-ray and see what happens.
That's for X-ray, now for electricity.
If we have a big electrical transformer,
a worker on a power house of electricity
and we have such cases.
Since I'm working in this department inside the electromagnetic field of such power electrical generator,
I am not feeling well. What do you have? 1,2,3, 20 symptoms, ok. Find those people who are sensitive
to the electricity and then of course what you
can do is leave the powder under this powerful generator
for a period of time and then try to potentise
this and you give it and you see the result.
So powerful electromagnetic field of electrical generators can produce symptoms to sensitive people.
Find these people, do the experiment, give them the electricity and then find out and give us the results.
But these are serious experiments which are bringing forward serious information, right?
Now we go to the sun. The sun, if you sit in the sun from 9 o'clock in the morning without moving at all
to 9 o'clock in the night,
lying in the sun and see what happens.
That means first of all that you are crazy. By definition you are not well and the prover in order to do experiment,
one of the conditions, is that the prover has to be healthy, mentally, emotionally and physically.
The second is, if you put somebody on a furnace then you burn him. Are you going to potentise the fire to cure him?
So if heat is burning somebody you don't potentize the heat to cure him; neither you will have any effect of that.
So potentising the sun is a crazy situation, potentising the luna is also crazy.
And I will tell you something.
I had a case on magnetic poles,
the south magnetic pole exactly
as it was described in the books.
I said to the doctor, ok give South Magnetic Pole 200. It couldn't be a better case, as it was described.
No effect at all, nothing.
You will say there is a case which
was cured and the case was cured.
In a previous seminar an Israeli doctor said to me, well what do you say about a case in which a medical doctor
who had severe colities who went to several of his colleagues, nobody could cure him.
Eventually he went to a Homeopath who took the case and prescribed a remedy and this is a published case.
And the doctor was cured but, as he says, the patient claims, he never took the remedy.
So out of this experience the idea came that you may have to only think about the remedy, you don't have to give it.
You just think about the remedy and the patient
is cured.
That is another nonsense and another
thing which degrades the science.
In order that this man can justify why the person became well after the consultation, he said,
I thought of the correct remedy
and he became well.
And he brings a theory out and
everybody believes that this is true.
But what actually happens is that in many many cases, what we have as Homeopaths, we have the placebo effect.
The remedy does nothing and the placebo effect comes and the patient says, I'm better. We cannot ignore that.
And we have some rules to know whether the remedy has acted or not. We have rules in the Homeopathy.
-The question is that if we are talking about the X-ray remedy, which way we bring this influence of the X-ray
to the patient? By sugar balls which
undergo, by salt balls or whatever.
I mean it's impossible to take X-ray equipment, shake it 10 times, then take 10 times smaller
and then bring to the patient. The question is if there is any study about which substance is used for the remedies?
-These are legitimate questions for such cases, but the first thing that comes to mind is that you can expose
a powder to the influence of the X-ray and take this powder and potentize it several times.
Most probably you will have a potentised X-ray remedy but, as you say, there are several issues
that have to be examined
all along in such experience.
But what I say is let us become serious about it. You cannot say I will give you a remedy, all of you,
you go and sleep and bring me tomorrow the dreams that you saw. And because you saw several dreams,
I take this as produced by the remedy, that is nonsense. It might be 1 person or 2 or 3 but who are those 3, nobody knows.
All the other is nonsense. And many times they say, this group who took the remedy had the same dream
as the other group who did not take the remedy.
That is a proof that the symptoms were true for the remedy? Absolutely no. The opposite.
It is true that the dreams that you saw is because of the climate, a general factor that influences  the people.
-What do you think about the smelling of remedies? To just smell at the bottle?
-I've never done it so I don't know.
-How far can we extend the Materia Medica?
-That's a good question. I am supposed
to be a very successful prescriber.
At least when I came in Athens and I was prescribing, because I did not prescribe on
already spoiled cases from Homeopaths, as
I do now, now I prescribe on spoiled cases by different Homeopaths.
When I was prescribing originally,
the rate of success was very high.
I did not need more remedies than what we already had in the Materia Medica and I could say that even it was too much.
Now, because of the lack of basic information about the remedies, the practitioner found himself in a total mess.
What shall I do? I don't know.
Ok, let me try this and let me try that.
In a quiz which I wrote in the first European journal it was a case that needed Pulsatilla.
About 12 people wrote to me that most probably the remedy was Luna. Then I become aware of the problem.
12 people, out of I don't remember how
many total answers we received,
12 people wrote this is a case of Luna,
but this was a case of Pulsatilla.
-Regarding the provings of electricity you say that you have to find the person who is sensitive.
One of the important things is that you don't know what you are proving when you are proving.
So how does that go together?
How do we know in advance who is going to be sensitive to radioactive substances?
The provers will know what they are going to get.
-What I say is, concerning the impoderables.
For instance you want to do a study on Radium bromatum
or Radium or I don't know in Chernobyl
what was the radioactive substance.
In Chernobyl you'll find out that they were people already dying, the most sensitive. Not all the population died.
So the most sensitive developed
symptoms immediately.
What I'm saying is, go and find these people who are sensitive and give them a high potency,
to these people on  these cases of the imponderables, then you can find out.
The second thing I said is that, if you prove any remedy which has some toxicity then what you can do is you say,
take sub-toxic doses, you develop
symptoms, get out and first in the list.
Then second in the list, third
in the list, the rest forget it, out.
Those first in the list who are very sensitive,
they do not know what they are taking yet.
Then second step, take higher potency;
still they don't know what they are taking.
Third step, take another potency;
and then get all the information possible.
Is it clear? Ok.
-My question is to know if you really think that it is necessary to extend the Materia Medica and
I explain why.
I've been told that somebody like Lippe was an extraordinary prescriber who practically
never failed to cure any of his patients. If it's true or not, I don't know. The Materia Medica at the time was sufficient
to cure whatever has to be cured. So do you think there is a need today to extend the Materia Medica or not?
-For me a very useful experiment will be to go to what we have already as small remedies in the Materia Medica
and improve the information on these remedies. Find out mostly what they can produce in mental, emotional levels.
This is a very interesting for me experiment.
Now given the fact that most of the successful practitioners
do not really need all these extraterrestrial remedies, then we have to say, well the Materia Medica is already enough.
But it can be improved and we must not stop that. I don't want to stop the proving.
I want to rehabilitate those who are doing provings and do the provings properly.
And then I will be very happy.
Now I am very unhappy.
Because they invite me at the University, in Bonn University actually they invited me there and they said
'what is going on with your profession?'. We hear this, this and that, is it true? Do you believe these things?
I said, no for godshake, this is nonsence.
And this information you have to understand that it goes right through the planet and everyone knows what is going on.
And everyone is organizing, the other people on the other side, which is the pharmaceutical companies and the
Medical establishment are organizing themselves and they take this information and say, look at them.
Are they serious people that
you can trust to cure people?
And this is my problem because
I get the feedback, I get the impact.
They come to me and say, what are you doing?
-I have one more question about X-ray. There is no doubt that X-ray has toxical effect if you get
X-ray.
But I doubt if what I do is to produce a remedy that I put a powder under X-ray. And I think you could eat kilograms
of this powder without getting any symptoms,
so I doubt about the real value of the way you produce the remedy.
-But in this case, of X-ray, I say that the sub-toxic dose is the dose which you take when you let
yourself
under X-ray under certain time, because it can
become very toxic, as anything else.
But sub-toxic means that this organism can
stay for 3 seconds, this is a sub-toxic dose.
And you get people, if you search in the
hospital and the X-ray departments,
you will get some people who are starting
to be sick after being exposed to X-rays.
In these people we are interested, we find them and then we potentize the powder, not the powder as it is like this.
I don't think it will be active at all but if you potentise this powder I believe that it can cure
and also in certain sensitive
individuals can produce symptoms.
-Yes but this is a bit strange to me if you say, the powder is not active but if you potentise it, it will be active.
-Ok, it's strange but I will give you another example. You make a powder of gold or stone and you take it.
It will come out. Don't powder very fine, make little pieces of gold and take them. It will come out.
Make little pieces of powder of stone, of sand but potentise it and make silica, then it will have an effect.
You take a lot of plants that are not open,
what we call open in their medicinal powers
when they are in the first stage.
In the same way, a lot of other chemicals
maybe they are not affecting at all
but if you potentise them,
then they become very effective.
-I suppose that we come here
to a very interesting point;
we need the definition of homeopathic
remedy, what is this?
Because in that case like we are talking about this effect produced by X-rays, I'm sure it depends on
which substance undergoes by X-rays.
So if this is sugar, that will be one effect.
I really doubt that it would be the same
effect with undergo salt or whatever.
So here is what will be the definition of homeopathic remedy which you can give us?
I can't imagine the way how we can pass to the people the influence which is produced by some
electromagnetic vibration or fields or whatever.
If we do it through some substances then we
are talking
about the effect which produced by some substances which will undergo some influences
of these fields, electromagnetic,
gravitational or strong electromagnetic
like we can put it in physical accelerators.
This is the first question, what is the definition of homeopathic remedy?
And the second is, is it worth while for us to spend so much time for these substances,
for these homeopathic remedies, which
probably can be used for such extreme cases,
like Chernobyl or some others. 99 % which
we have in our daily practice is far from that.
-Well this is the same question as it was put before. Is it necessary to have all these new remedies produced?
I have stated already my opinion. But it is true also, electricity for instance it has cured, at least
I have heard
of 2 cases that have been cured, cases which work under strong electromagnetic fields and with the high potency
of electricity everything was fine. Now, was it a placebo effect or was it really electricity also, I do not know.
My interest will be to use X-ray potency in cases where they have been damaged by X-ray.
Interesting will be in Chernobyl to use high potency of Radium bromatum or the substance that was released there,
on high potency, to have an idea of how
many people they maybe benefited.
At this moment there is a big problem on universal level concerning the people who were in the Gulf war.
Some of the soldiers, the Americans and the English, they developed a host of symptomatology
and there is a big argument what is there, what has happened. Why these soldiers develop these symptoms?
My opinion is that the vaccination that was given to them to protect them from possible exposure to chemicals,
the vaccination produced such a turmoil in the immune system that brought out a syndrome,
that means it's a massive proving of this particular vaccination which I don't know how they produced it.
But it's very interesting that the French soldiers that were also in the Gulf war, they were not developing these symptoms.
Which is a proof that definitely those who took the vaccination were affected, not the exposure from gases,
as they want to make it or the imagination of the soldiers as others want to make it. It's a big issue,
there is a lot of money involved because they will demand for damages and they try to cover up the issue.
The issue is very clear for me. You gave vaccination, these people developed, and not all of them,
those who are sensitive, it is an 8% percentage that developed these symptoms.
Of course it will be interesting, in this case, to give a high dose of the same substance to see how many
of these, I believe a 10% out of this, will be
very much ameliorated by a higher potency;
the others will need a homeopathic treatment.
-I would like to say something to the Chernobyl. You said those who died or got sick were sensitive to the rays,
but I think they also got higher doses.
If you give high dose to someone, he will die anyway;
I don't think he has to be sensitive.
-That is correct for those who died immediately that is correct. But still after 10 years we still have the effect
of the Chernobyl and people are going to live for 20 more years with the effect of the Chernobyl.
-She asked if there is effect by smelling and you said, you don't know. But if we are talking about crystals
or the remedies of Bach flowers, they even
have an affect only by wearing them.
And this means the effect is by vibrations and when we are talking about homeopathic potency of 200,
they don't cure on physical level,
they cure even by vibrations.
-I don't deny that.
-I want to know if you have incorporate the globulis or if you just can wear them on your pocket,
if there is already the effect
by the vibrations that come from the globulis.
-Well, I believe Hahnemann was saying, you can rub the liquid remedy in arm pits or in sensitive areas of the skin.
That also I can understand, we also agree
that these remedies act on vibrational level
but the vibration has to come
very close to the person.
Otherwise we have to accept that those working in the  homeopathic pharmaceutical companies,
are exposed to thousands of remedies. If you imagine that this room is full of 3000 remedies
and I work all the day,
opening and closing bottles.
And that I would be affected;
this I don't believe, I'm sorry.
I believe that in order to be affected you have
to come in real contact; either with the mucus membranes
or the sensitive parts of the skin. Mucus membranes of course is the best.
-May I say something to this Chernobyl problem? I made an experience with a group of colleagues.
We treated Chernobyl children. They came for vacations to Bavaria and we had about 10 children
and we thought now we need those great radioactive remedies and we didn't need one of them at all.
Then we went to Russia, we treated them again.
-You treated them according to the symptoms which required other remedies.
-We had only normal remedies, and when we went to Russia it was the same. We didn't find one child,
even those in the hospital who need one radioactive remedy. This was for us a big lesson
that people react like everywhere.
They don't react in a radioactive way.
-That is correct and we agree and I say that even if there is some effect, your observation is limited.
You cannot generalize and say that nobody will need Radium bromatum you cannot say that.
So some people, most probably will need Radium bromatum and maybe it will be a substantial number,
maybe 3-5% up to 10%,
as I said with the vaccination.
But as a matter of interest I said this on the vaccination issue, give the high potency and most probably
you will see some of them getting out. But the majority of them, 90-95% they will have no effect
and they will need another remedy. The observation is correct but we cannot generalize
and say none needs because
you have not treated everyone.
-Excuse me I don't know great deal about the Materia Medica but gases can cause toxicity.
If someone is poisoned by gas. I don't know
what is taken to counteract that effect.
-Always you have to take the symptoms of the person at the moment. With the same gas, people
will develop different symptoms. Of course dyspnoea and some common burns etc.
but the modalities of each one of them will be different so you need to search to give the indicated remedy.
-You don't have to cool the gas
and make a material?
-Well you can do that as well but small percentage will be affected. It's like an epidemic exactly.
In epidemic you see Gelsemium in 10-15% of the cases, but the rest have to be treated by other remedies.
-George, there is a remedy, I want to have your opinion about it, which we use on a very big scale in France
called Oscillococcinum This is prescribed for anybody to prevent or to cure a cold in winter and it really works,
the prove is that the laboratory that makes it,
it's selling 32million boxes every winter;
so it has an effect and apparently the action is because there is a lot of amino-acid inside the remedy
and it boosts the immune system. What is your opinion about that? It's contrary to classical Homoeopathy.
-When I tried to use it, it had no effect but this is my personal experience. So I don't know.
I would need really the experience, if we want
to test, such a general medicine, then I would need
the experience of 10 serious and very important Homeopaths in 10 different countries.
And then I would say, ok you give
it and tell me the feedback.
Unless I do this kind of experimentation
I will not be able to make a statement.
-When you arrange a proving, sometimes you meet people that are too sensitive and they react almost to each remedy.
Are they good prover or not?
-They are good for you but not for them. If you find these people, but you find them seldom. In the experience
of a person like me I have thousands and thousands of cases, I could say
10 cases in my life that had this quality.
They are sensitive organisms,
quite hyponchondrial in their nature and they are very observant of the least change in their organism.
And then everytime you give a remedy they give you back the characteristic symptoms of the remedy
that you've given and you say, oh my god ! Then you try again and again, they are very difficult cases
to cure as Kent says but very good subjects for proving a remedy. Usually such cases will give you 1 or 2
main symptoms of the remedy, they will not
give you host of symptoms or new symptoms.
Very very seldom they'll give you new symptoms.