Many times we have to be careful. We have symptomatology on 3 levels, as we said,
not always. If the symptoms are on the physical level forget the picture on mental, emotional.
This is normal. What is normal?
When do we have symptoms
and when do we have normal?
This person is normal in these levels.
I said certain cases of Phosphorus may not
have symptoms on mental or emotional
and we say is normal. What is normal?
When do we have a symptom and
when we don't have a symptom?
This is a question I'm asking.
What the society considers as normal?
I want another definition.
-It depends on the suffering of the person.
-I think is when it doesn't bother
him to function normally.
-If he can fulfill his purpose in life.
-She says when you are free from pain,
you are free from passion and you are
free from egotism, then
you have no symptoms.
-The society considers somebody
normal when he functions,
when he is seemingly balanced;
then he is considered normal.
-When one is free from anything that could
hold him, he is free to choose what he likes,
free to do what he likes, free of any burden.
-Let me ask you another question.
When you are born, will you be considered
as healthy at this moment of birth
or you would be considered that
you have a predisposition for a
certain disease which may
or may not develop later on ?
How much of that constitution of the
newborn can be considered as healthy
or not healthy, depending on what ?
When you treat this person when you arrive
at the point you say, now you are healthy?
Do we have an easy answer
for these questions?
-I think healthy is when all needs are fulfilled.
-I need 20 women. I need 20 chocolates.
-I think that it is relative things.
This idea, to be healthy is to be free,
to be without negative feeling and so on.
-There are two different things which
are going on here. First we have an ideal
definition of health in which we all agree
at least. If you don't agree you cannot say
because I said it. But anyhow, we
suppose we agree in this idea.
That ideal health is freedom from
selfishness, egotism, freedom from being
enslaved in passions, freedom from
being enslaved in pain and discomfort.
Now we come to the reality of
treating an individual saying:
that individual is unhealthy in his liver or unhealthy in his feelings or unhealthy
in his mind or his lungs. We have to have
a guiding process to lead us to say:
this individual is healthy in these levels and unhealthy in these levels. How do we go about?
To attain the ideal health as we said
and we agreed, nobody can attain it.
Nobody can attain it. Nobody can be
free of egotism, free of selfishness.
If we stick it to our mind that I'm going
to free myself from all egotism
you are going to have a delusion
eventually. It is not possible,
even the greatest, even the people
who are considered as saintly people,
they have their own weak spots.
Now, were they unhealthy to what extend?
Is it possible that they would become
healthy with the homeopathic remedy?
Somebody is very selfish. Is it possible with
the homeopathic remedy to make him
less egotistical? These are questions.
She says, that if we treat a person
with egotism, we give a remedy,
the egotism becomes less and
the person is better in his egotism.
-I don't think so. Maybe it will round the edges but he will succeed better in his egotism.
-Egotistical person you give the correct
remedy, then his egotism will reduce
and other values will go up, so his
development will be more easy.
-If you give a remedy his egotism will not
be less but it will make him suffer less
himself as well as the people around him.
-The idea is that every individual
needs some kind of egotism
because egotism has good qualities
as well, like integrity, sincerity etc.
So you may need this quality and
by giving the remedy you don't take away
the good qualities of egotism which
is helpful in an individual in order
to progress and to develop spiritually.
-He will be more aware of his condition.
He will be uncomfortable with the fact that...
Somebody who is really egoistic
he doesn't bother at all.
But if he starts bothering,
maybe we will think twice.
-Yes but not always the symptoms bother
the person. They bother the others.
What I'm asking is from a totally
practical point of view.
You have an individual, you are treating him
and from a totally practical point of view
you want to see whether this individual is affected in his mental emotional level
and to what extend. Or you say, this person seems to be balanced from a totally
practical point of view, as a healer.
People will come to you to be healed.
And because of all these theories that we
have and this information about the remedies,
we start projecting and imagining things
and we may project upon the individual that
we have in front of us, certain things which
are not really there on the individual.
And we may make a case of Agaricus
where it is a case of Sulphur
and a case of Phosphorus where
it is a case of Natrum muriaticum.
This is what I try to clarify with this question.
And I found out that many Homeopaths
they go wrong because of not
comprehending well these practical problems.
He comes to you and he says, oh he looks
like Phos, or he looks like Nat-m or Agar.
But this person actually is normal
in his mental, emotional level
and he is suffering in his physical pathology.
His kidneys are affected, his liver, lungs
his joints are affected and that's it.
Otherwise the person is quite normal,
in the mental, emotional sphere.
How do we say he is normal?
What are the guiding lines for saying
so or making that statement?
-I think the symptoms; he's supposed
to come and complain about things.
First of all, take the first
symptom that complains about.
And see the whole picture, the real
picture whatever you see real,
not imagination, not all
kind of crap around.
-I think if the person has coherence, clarity
and creativity of mind and also a state of
calmness of emotions, then the person is healthy; we do not have to treat the person.
-Correct. Most of you have said more or less, correct things. But I still feel it's not very clear.
For instance, in questions like egotistical. You
go to the Repertory and you see 'egotistical':
Lach., Sulph., Calc., Plat. etc.
Some remedies say 'egotistical'.
What does that mean?
Who is not egotistical?
On the other hand we say, everyone
is selfish, everyone is egotistical.
Now why there are so few remedies on the
rubric 'egotistical' since everybody has an
egotistical element, that means looking
after himself, his own interests?
Why in certain remedies we say,
this is pathology?
-Egocentric and egotistical is more or less
the same as far as we are concerned,
we are talking about pathology. We are examining the pathology of the person.
-I think the most important question is if
the patient is suffering of this symptom.
Maybe egotism or anything else.
-But as we said, he may not be
suffering but others maybe suffering
because of that symptom, so then
again we have a problem.
You see the manic people, especially
manic depressive people,
during the mania stage they feel wonderful.
They feel on the top of the world,
they feel absolutely powerful and free but
they may be doing things that hurt others.
And then we put the labels
as manic depression.
-I come up again with the needs
of a baby. The need of a baby makes
an imprint when it is adult
for something it didn't get.
It is a blockage, disharmony and homeopathic remedy makes it harmonise again
and feel better, feel healthy.
-I thought you said that a person once he
has his desires fulfilled, he is healthy.
-But I say I have my desires fulfilled, I have
20 women, 20 chocolates. But am I healthy?
Or I am over sexed or I have
all kinds of perversions etc.
-You have been asking about egotism and
I think the pathological form of egotism
is the lack of ability for
empathy to other people.
-Ok, if we take this everyone has
indifference to other's suffering.
Then you go to Phosphorus who has
empathy and we say this is pathology now.
Phosphorus has empathy so much, sympathy, suffers a lot and we say this is pathology.
-We have to observe in that person
whom we call egotistical,
whether he is creative, whether
his creativity is affected.
Creativity towards others and if this
is affected then there is pathology.
-I think Hahnemann gave a very good description of the healthy state in his par. 9 of the Organon.
There he says, the body must serve the spirit
as a tool to fulfill the higher goals of existence.
So if someone is in a manic state he cannot see his higher goals. So this is one important thing,
he must be able to see his higher
goals and the other thing is,
the body must be a good tool
to follow these higher goals.
-This another question. Hahnemann
in par.9 speaks about the balance
which comes with the homeopathic
remedy and gives the opportunity
for the individual to develop spiritually.
This is not the question.
There is another paragraph and you
have to find it, in which Hahnemann gives
what we may say this is pathology. We say
now, this is pathology, this is not normal.
-I wanted to add something about this
egotism. I think the aim is to find the center,
the middle between the polarities of being too
much inside egotistical or too much outside.
There has to be a middle where we have
a balance between both polarities.
It's like in Phosphorus. Phosphorus is too
open to outside, then he also develops
a border line case. But you have
to find a place in the middle.
A baby also has the right to
egotism as when it gets older
and also concerning the time of life, you have different stages where you find the middle.
-You have to find the really middle
balance point between two polarities.
If you go to extremes, to one or the other side, then most probably there is pathology.
-I think many of the things that we
read in Repertory, we all experience
in different circumstances. What actually
makes it pathology is if it is appropriate
to the situation that you're actually in at that
time. For instance in children we do see
a lot of egotism because they have high
needs and they have to get these needs.
So it depends on the situation that
the person is in with egotism
or cheerfulness or whatever
is appropriate or not.
-I think it's very dangerous if you
want to have a middle of everything.
If somebody always is in balance,
no specialties, then never any special
or extraordinary thing would happen. We wouldn't have any extraordinary people,
for example artists always
were special, extraordinary.
In a certain way also pathological because otherwise they would not be able to create
what they have created. You always have to see in what time the person lives and who is judging.
-It is dangerous to say or to state or to
accept that everybody has to be balanced
and everybody has to be within a range.
Actually there are people who have gone
into extreme, like artists, like very
creative people who have done
extraordinary things, who have
gone away from normal,
maybe this is pathology
but still very creative.
-And my question is when do
we consider that this pathology?
Hahnemann gives 3 sources from which
we get information about diseases.
The patient himself.
People around the patient.
Physician's observation.
If you follow these rules of Hahnemann
you will always be able to state
whether there is pathology, there is no
pathology and when the pathology has started.
So actually each individual is different
and has qualities which are unique.
Therefore nobody can say this is normal.
How many times you eat a day?
The normal is one time the day. I can tell
you if you eat one time the day, you go to the
Caucasus people they eat one time
the day and live 100 years.
The normal is 3 times or 1 time?
To have sex is good, it's natural.
The normal is 1 time/day,
1/week or 1/month?
There are different ideas, different
people with different constitutions,
will do different things.
So what is normal? Essential things
like eating, having sex, every day
things that will come against immediately
some problems, if we put theoretical questions.
Here Hahnemann says, wait a moment
I will tell you when there is pathology:
If the patient tells you 'that bothers me'.
Then it's pathology.
I used to be very fast in my mind and now my mind is slow, this bothers me. This is pathology.
I used to have a lot of energy,
I cannot drag my feet, this is pathology.
I used to drink two glasses of water,
now I need 20 glasses. This is pathology.
So the patient will state the
changes that feels in himself.
But Hahnemann says, this is not enough
to determine that all the pathology
is what the patient says. Because the
patient might not be aware that he has
some other problems which the
other people around can perceive
but he, himself can not perceive. So the
others around this person perceive that
this person has changed. To what has
changed? This person was normal before
and now he has become so egotistical,
he thinks that he knows everything,
that everything he says is correct,
the only person on the earth that knows.
'I know, I know, I'm telling you, I'm sure,
I don't even discuss anything'.
But this person was not like this before. So
the people around him detect changes in him,
that's pathology, you have to
take it into consideration.
And of course the observation from the physician. The physician observes
mostly the signs, physical signs with clinical examination and the physician observes
also certain other things which can
be on the mental, emotional level,
there is no question about that.
So when we talk about pathology and
what is to be treated, it's these changes
which are observed by these
3 different factors.
Now, the rest belongs to the
personality of each one of us
who has a different personality.
So everyone can be jealous, egotistical,
but if you observe that this woman
has become crazy in her jealousy, you say,
here she is developing some pathology.
That pathology takes the form of jealousy.
Which are the remedies which have
strong jealousy elements?
-Hyoscyamus, Lachesis. This is the idea exactly. The whole class has to think immediately.
The main problem of this patient is jealousy.
More or less you shift your way of
thinking towards the remedy that has
quite this pathology that the person has.
Very sympathetic, a person is suffering a lot.
There are two remedies, Causticum, Phosphorus. Then you look at the Repertory
there are other symptoms also, but your
thinking should come immediately
once there is a big remedy.
Desire for cold water, how much?
A lot of cold water. Phosphorus.
What other remedies have strong... Bryonia, Nat-m, Sulphur. Out of these remedies,
which is the remedy that wants cold water,
has to be cold, otherwise the water is
like poison. Warm water for
Phosphorus is like poison.
That is why it says when it gets warm,
he vomits it. In pneumonia case,
when they give you this information,
immediately your mind should go to Phos.