Thank you very much for your warm welcome.
I would say that usually the Mediterranean people, Greeks and Italians, usually
we think about the Northern people as much more cool or phlegmatic, which I see it doesn't apply to Homeopaths.
I also see here in England a very encouraging phenomenon for the world.
We're with a member of the Parliament with
the status of Lord Ennals standing here
in front of some wired people perhaps,
and try to understand them, and also try to support from the political point of view.
And this is what I feel, everybody feels that democracy is for. I really feel that it would be
very nice also if such a phenomenon
would happen also in Greece where a politician would stand up and proclaim that I am a supporter of what you are claiming to be a good way of therapy, a good way of helping people.
In Greece perhaps we have very good Homeopathy but so far, there was not once
that a Minister of Health would come up
and support openly. Of course secretly everybody supports Homeopathy but to
stand up here like Lord Ennals is an
encouraging phenomenon.
And I really think that people of his courage
and understanding should be supported
by us as well.
Don't forget that we need the politicians
and the government and the authorities
as much as they need us.
And you must not forget also that a healthy government will always take healthy
decisions. Not always in favor of war but sometimes in favor of peace.
It's very nice to hear nice words and
I want to thank Lord Ennals for his
kindness to be present today.
I also would like to thank the Hale clinic
which did a lot to organize this event together with the society of Homeopaths and especially Steve Gordon who did quite a lot for
helping this event.
With this introduction, I'm usually not a good speaker, I cannot find easily my words. I would like to start with the seminar and with what we are going to talk in the next 3 - 4 days.
I don't like to speak in front of this podium.
Well I don't know whether the politicians are more threatened or myself because I feel that
I have created through my teaching a lot of
upheavals and a lot of conflicts and
I would say a lot of enemies.
But if one is the type of the person I am,
who'd like to say what I think is right always,
it is natural that I will create disturbance.
I don't like lights, I like contact, I like
to see you. We have to accept our fate.
I would say that one of our subjects in this seminar is the difficulty that a homeopath faces in picking from a patient the right information.
Collect the right information and then using it properly is the crux of the matter. It's really what brings about success. And there is
a lot of confusion concerning this subject.
When you have a patient in front of you and he starts telling his story, as you know, many times he is saying a lot of things which are irrelevant,
a lot of things which we cannot utilize,
we can not use in the analysis of his case.
But what we are interested in mostly is his symptomatology. We cannot say that we have
an idea of him being Phosphorus because
he is tall and lean, this is not good Homeopathy.
Many times there was a lot of confusion concerning what I was teaching. It was said, oh George brought into Homeopathy, essences.
So if you know the essence, you can prescribe and you can be successful. And the moment
I started talking about essences
and the essence of a case, it was confusion,
the idea was disseminated in the wrong understanding, in the wrong way.
And in no time, people would say,
oh George says you can prescribe only on essence. And what is essence?
And then I had to come up and clarify
and say that George is not prescribing
always on essence.
Essence means the mental-emotional symptomatology of a case, we call it more
or less - I mean it can also be physical symptomatology - the essence of the case.
But there are people who are healthy in
mental-emotional level, what shall we do then?
Therefore I said that we can prescribe on essence, we can prescribe on totality of the symptoms, we can prescribe on keynotes
or we can prescribe on a combination of the
information of all this.
And of course we have the causative factor that we take into consideration many times and the causative factor many times plays a very important part in our prescription.
What I would like to speak today...first is to
clarify what is a symptom. What is a symptom?
And how a symptom is evaluated.
I'm going to speak about the 4-dimensional
entity of the symptom.
Usually in homeopathic teaching we know that we speak about the intensity of a symptom,
how strong a symptom is and we speak about time, duration. How long that symptom stays
with the patient, how much occupies him?
Which are the other two dimensions of a symptom in Homeopathy? Can anybody
tell me? Which is the third dimension of a symptom that makes the importance of a symptom to become bigger?
-Relationship to the central delusion.
-Location.
-Peculiarity.
-So to put it in one word, the 3rd dimension
is the depth of the symptom, how deep it is
within the organism.
Its hierarchical state and according to the model
I have brought about, can you project the model?
Most of you know that I have brought about a model for health on which I have depicted the mind and the spiritual part of the human being
as the innermost cone and outside more peripheral to that is the emotional body and closing all that, is the physical body.
So the importance of a symptom becomes greater, the greater its depth in this particular understanding of the human being.
So for the importance of a symptom
we must take into consideration the
depth from which it arises.
The 4th dimension of a symptom is, you said
it also, its relationship to the information
we have on the Materia Medica.
Unfortunately there are symptoms which
may be very peculiar, very well established;
for instance in a patient with a heart
problem, you may have a stitching pain in
the heart while urinating. The urination is
interrupted during the pain and then starts again.
Very peculiar symptom, you would be very
happy to know which is the remedy, eh?
From all points of view, this symptom is very important for all the three but in relation to the information we have is totally useless.
So therefore the importance of a
symptom depends on all these factors.
All these factors have to be there strong
or less strong but all of these factors
have to be there to evaluate a symptom.
And if a symptom is the expression
of the defense mechanism that says
well this is the way I'm fighting disease.
A syndrome which is a totality of symptoms,
is equally the same and with the same qualifications.
I will give you an example. For instance,
if somebody with high fever tells you that
I have very hot head and very cold feet during high fever, what is the remedy? Belladonna.
Immediately you have connected the intensity, very hot head, very cold feet, very cold extremities with the information
you had from the Materia Medica, you
associate to, you say Belladonna, you give Belladonna and the patient does not recover.
Why he does not recover? Because sometimes of course is not Belladonna, because there
are other remedies which have similar symptomatology. What you missed?
But does the Belladonna want to be fanned?
No she feels hot but no air, no movements, why? Because if you make any movement his head feels pumping and it is very painful.
You see, the same situation very cold,
puts a lot of clothes on the body and you
see the face wants the fan but a lot
of blankets on the body.
You have not noticed that the whole body
was cold and he wanted to be fanned; that's another symptom all together and then,
what is the remedy?
Arsenicum is the remedy because we
know that Arsenicum is so cold, so chilly,
fever comes with chills.
But the head remains warm in acute conditions, not in chronic. So you pick up 2-3 symptoms
and you say, that's the remedy.
Where I'm driving at? A time when having enough information in your mind, in your knowledge you will be able to recognize syndroms and say, this is clear cut in case
of Arsenicum, a clear cut case of Belladonna.
And then you will be able to prescribe
more correctly.
How do you get intensity? Is the patient
going to tell you always about the intensity
of his symptoms? Not always.
I saw lately, well I didn't see but through the telephone, you know I'm working on
an island, I'm writing the Materia Medica
as you know, and I have a fax, I have a telephone and I'm in charge of the clinic in Athens with 30 medical doctors.
Sometimes they have a problem and they pick up the telephone and say, this is the situation.
So they pick up the telephone and one of the doctors says, well my child has a very high fever since yesterday I have prescribed this
this and that remedy, no effect. The fever
came with chills, there is cough, very
high fever 40,3 Celsius, I don't know the equivalent in Farenheit. And he is
coughing and there is pain in his chest.
He is quite heavy not exactly in a kind of
a coma but a little bit close and sometimes
he is talking nonsense. His mind is not there. What is the situation?
When I hear this description from the mother
who is a medical doctor I say, well it is an intense symptomatology not for the patient
the patient is a 14 years old child lying
there with short breath, pain in the chest,
very high fever. I say, ah he has pneumonia.
X-ray to find out, this is a pneumonia case.
His breathing is offensive and also his perspiration quite offensive.
Well for me is a clear remedy because
I was writing about that remedy, that day
I don't know. I said, give Baptisia 200.
A few doses.
What I am interested in now, in this case
is if I say, well this child constitutionally
what symptoms he had?
Shall I take into consideration the symptoms before? In which case shall I need to take
that as well?
These are questions you are going to face
every time. Which is a question when you
have a case in front of you, are you going always to mix symptoms of acute conditions
with the constitutional symptoms of the patient?
When do you need the help of the constitutional symptoms in order to prescribe acutely?
If you understand the 4-dimensional parameters of a symptom you will not hesitate very much.
So when you saw this picture of Arsenicum, the restlessness, the fanning, the high fever, the coldness immediately you say Arsenicum. Why?
Because the intensity is so strong. And the syndrome points to a remedy, like the symptom pointed to Baptisia, of course I knew Baptisia.
If you don't know Baptisia you would prescribe Belladonna but what about the feet? Were they cold? Not so cold but a little bit, you know how you try to make a case of Belladonna.
Let's see, let's see, I think yes it's more cold.
But that's not Belladonna. In Belladonna you have to have really cold feet and really hot face, flushed and the eyes go like that, flushing.
Then you have a typical case of Belladonna.
So you start understanding when to prescribe. Immediately, on the acute information.
When to hesitate and wait etc. and
get more and more information.
Many times you most probably have seen,
in a tooth abscess when the tooth is alive
and the pain is excruciating.
Pain, can you think of anything else?
So look at this symptom pain in the tooth,
overwhelming the whole of the person.
But you go to the lotto, the Greeks play a lot
of lotto, the lottery. You complete a paper
with 6 numbers, you got the numbers and
you got 5million. You got the lotto.
I don't care about the lotto whether I got
5, 20 million. At this moment the pain is so excruciating. At this moment the person
becomes one symptom.
Well that symptom has to be treated and
if you give the right remedy there is
immediately tremendous relief.
I shall give you an example of that. When you have pain in the teeth, since you don't have
the Repertory I have to use this computer.
Pain in the tooth worse with pressure,
can you show me the remedies which are
there? Let me read it for you: Carb-an
in ordinary degree. Cham. in 3rd degree,
Hyos., ordinary
Kali-bi, Mag-m, Nat-c, Nat-m, Phos, Sep, Spig, Sulph, Sul-ac and Zinc. What do we see from that information?
We see that Chamomilla has a tremendous sensitivity to pressure. When there is a pain in the teeth, Chamomilla has a tremendous sensitivity on pressure.
Even if you don't know that information,
neither myself I knew the information
before, so therefore I have to use the
books, I had to use the Repertory.
So I open the Repertory and I read this information. And immediately you connect what?
From that information you connect the intensity on which you see the person suffering.
I keep the mouth open so the tooth does
not press at all. When there is an abscess the tooth comes up a little bit. They cannot even close their mouth. Immediately what you do?
You connect the intensity of the symptom with the intensity you see there. And you say to yourself if I had to give only one remedy,
which remedy I would prefer? The first remedy
I would prefer is Chamomilla.
We see here with the red we have the
capital letters. What it shows that?
The capital letters show that intensity
and also timewise, duration is strong.
So this person is really having strong
symptoms, so we can look at Cham, Coff,
Lach, Sep and Puls which are with red colour.
And immediately what it says, that since
that person has already another symptom
with Chamomilla strong, most probably the remedy which would be indicated
for that person, is Chamomilla.
The next symptom is pain in the teeth
external, from the warmth of bed, terrible.
Again Chamomilla. You see there, Chamomilla appearing strong and you get another symptom
for his tooth pain which is:
once he gets vexed the pain becomes much stronger, again Cham. we see is appearing.
And also pain in the teeth lying on painless
side, Chamomilla again is there.
So you have an acute case with tooth abscess. Are you going to prescribe Chamomilla or are you going to prescribe .. because on further
inquiry if you want, to inquire further in this case....
Before we go any further, is anybody here who would not give Chamomilla in this case?
-George I got the impression that in the Repertory black type symptoms have to do
with the number of provers that came up
with that symptom and not the intensity
which they experience.
-Yes, the gradation we have
in the Repertory with the remedies.
We have 1 grade, 2d grade, 3rd grade very strong and sometimes we have 4th grade.
I have graded certain of the remedies to the
4th grade. What does it mean? As a general
rule we can say it means that this remedy
in the proving state has shown many times frequency, in many provers that symptom.
And also it has shown that this symptom in the prover was strong. So it shows in the proving intensity and frequency. Very frequently Cham produces this kind of pain, very stongly.
This is why it is depicted here in the 3rd degree. What we see here, we have a patient with equally strong duration and intensity.
And also fitting very well the relation between
the information in the Materia Medica and the case. What is missing here? What is weak? The third element of the symptom which says, depth.
Is pain in a tooth is a deep symptom? It's not a deep symptom. This pathology is next to skin and then we have mucus membranes and then perhaps one step further. It's not very deep.
But it is overwhelming. The person cannot live.
I mean if you leave a person until the nerve
dies, because the nerve will die if you just
allow him to go with with this pain,
the nerve is totally degenerated and
eventually dies and then it stops the pain also. But the person is going through hell.
Just because of a pain. So what is your
problem here? You are saying to yourself,
shall I prescribe for a symptom which has no depth? And the answer is.....
What I have to show you actually is that;
let yourself feel more what is right inside you.
You have a case in front of you, he came with this tremendous pain, overwhelming pain.
Are you going to think now what
about its constitutional remedy?
I will tell you something. If you do repertorise
the 5 symptoms, that we have been speaking about, it will come very clearly as a repertorisation process.
The system on which we shall be talking
also about, which I have done in cooperation
with the University of Namur.
It's an expert system; they said we'll
duplicate my mind and the computer will
analyze in the same way that you do
analyse the case.
So the computer can show you certainty on which you prescribe a remedy. Shall I prescribe
a remedy? Yes, prescribe it or no be careful, investigate this, this and that remedy.
Say you are given in the computer this information I just gave you; 5 symptoms,
what the computer says? It says the most probable remedy is Cham with confidence
213 and 2022 points for the remedy.
It's a very high score, the confidence is
over 213, and with great confidence you prescribe the remedy. Why it says that?
Because you have given him the acute symptoms on which you would like to
prescribe, the symptoms of the patient.
And the system says, there is no doubt, this is the remedy. But let us see what happens if you continue and this can happen to you not in a tooth case but in any other acute condition.
You enquire about general symptoms on this patient. You discover that this person has indigestion;  as soon as the food is brought
in front of him, he loses completely his
appetite. Indigestion especially after milk,
the pain in the stomach extends to the back,
there is burning on the stomach in the morning and also if he takes honey makes his stomach very upset and painful.
And then you discover that his feet are
very warm and he uncovers them during
sleep and then you immediately think,
of what remedy? Sulphur
And you say how are you standing? You know Sulphur they don't like to stand, they like to sit, they like to lie, they are lazy people but don't
put them on a standing position like that.
They feel uncomfortable and they have to move. So you discover that she cannot stand at all and of course she has great desire for sweets.
What are you going to do? Can you give me the constitutional symptoms? If you repertorise the constitutional symptoms, what remedy would come? I'll show you the dilemma.
If you repertorise the constitutional symptoms
of the patient, the remedy is Sulphur.
If you repertorise the local symptoms, the remedy is Cham. If you do a repertory analysis
of all the symptoms, what is the remedy?
How I would think? This is exactly the way I'm thinking. This program does not show anything else but how I would think in that case.
It says, I'm not confident, there are two
remedies you have to consider. I cannot
decide which is the remedy.
There are two remedies to be considered, Sulphur and Chamomilla. Which one you will prescribe? You have to be very clear,
you see this is all about Homeopathy.
If you prescribe Sulphur what is going to happen? If you prescribe Chamomilla
what is going to happen?
Who can tell me? I can tell you but who
can tell me? You say with confidence, this is
the process, this is how I'm going to go about.
Here you have to consider a few factors;
first of all you have a strong syndrome
which fits very well with the information
from the Materia Medica.
Intensity strong, duration strong, relationship
with the Materia medica strong, 3 factors very strong on an acute case.
You prescribe Chamomilla because in
the acute state you cannot always say,
that when a person has pneumonia
if I know his constitutional remedy
and I give it to him, he's going to be better.
You cannot say that, you have first to
prescribe the acute and after the acute is finished and you will see the reaction of the person, in that case immediately is coming down,
the pain immediately going away.
The person within a few hours will be much better with Chamomilla and will have
no effect with Sulphur.
You just waste your time and the remedy, why? Because after Chamomilla has acted then
it is the time for Sulphur to give,  to help him
with his stomach, with his constitutional,
with his chronic condition.
So we make some rules if we understand,
clear picture, strong symptoms for the
remedy, you must prescribe that remedy
for the acute condition.
I will give you another example. In a case of coryza. Just give me the first 6 symptoms that you can project. You have a coryza where
there is an obstruction of the left nostril
where the child is boring his finger and
picks his nose. He does this so much that
the nose bleeds.
The nostrils are raw, discharge is much more
in the afternoon and the lips are full of cracks.
You see a child boring his finger into his nose, the nose is red, raw, painful. The lips are cracked, bleeding.
What am I describing? Don't be afraid, I'm not playing tricks. I'm describing a typical case of
Arum Triphyllum.
If you had put this and you ask this fellow
here to tell you what is the remedy, it won't be difficult at all for him to decide.
He says, the remedy is Arum Triphylum with 4000 points, there is no question about that. Confidence 200 and something.
There is one symptom where it bores with
the finger, there is another one when boring makes it bleed.
These are made up cases. I'm showing you
the way you pick up symptoms, which
symptoms are you going to use and which
symptoms you must not use. In the end
you will have an idea, more or less, how
you should think about in such cases.
So if you look upon his coryza, the remedy
which you have to prescribe is Arum-t. If you go and read Arum-t you will see this person is exactly what is describing in Arum-t case.
Let us say that you don't know that this
case is Arum-t and you continue to
investigate on that case. And then you
find out that he has some peculiar symptoms.
Faintness from pain in the heart.
There is a feeling as if the heart is hanging
down by a thread, there is palpitation from anxiety and worse when lying down.
This person is depressed especially in the morning. He cannot lie at all on the left side,
it brings dysphoria and palpitation and
lying on the left side is much worse.
He talks a lot and changes from one subject to the other. He is there about half and hour and talks and talks about his mother and
how his mother went to the milk man and the milk man has a child, oh my god this child is a devil...and he had some friends and the other
day they were going to the cinema,
they put fire in the car....
And you realize that this is a case of
Lachesis, what are you going to give?
You see a case of Lachesis and you see
a typical picture on the acute of Arum-t,
what are you going to give?
When we put all these symptoms and we repertorise we may have again a problem.
It says, the most probable remedy is Arum triphylum and also question yourself whether
this is a case of Lachesis.
In this case, for the same reasons we have
been talking about in the toothache, because
the remedy is clear and also intense
in spite of the fact that the whole syndrome is
not deep, it's only a coryza; still you have to prescribe Arum-t first. Lachesis will come after
the coryza is gone and it will act beautifully but not during the coryza, don't make that mistake.
And we have said so far that if a case is clear on its acute symptomatology then prescribe that remedy and not the constitutional one, even
if the constitutional is clear to you during the
time of the consultation for the acute condition.
Also we said so far and we understood that
when a symptom overwhelms a case,
it becomes so important that you have to
take into consideration very seriously.
I will give you an example. I had a patient who was in France and I received a letter one day,
10 pages symptoms.
What happened to him, he had been in an osteopath, he twisted a bit his leg and after
that started a sciatica.
most probably there was a bigger
pressure and he had pains, he was
lying in bed for a few months
And I read 10 pages of symptoms, all the systems everything was written down very carefully, what shall I do? I want to commit suicide this is not a life, in the end.
I' m thinking of committing suicide but
I'm afraid to commit suicide.
Never mind how much Homeopathy you know, you take all the symptoms into consideration and to make a prescription is almost impossible.
What do you have to think in this case?
What is the overwhelming symptom beyond
the local symptoms?
The anxiety, tremendous anxiety, he wants to commit suicide, he saiys, this is not a life,
I cannot stand it.
There are some people here who do not have the Repertory and did not put up their hands. This is observation you have to develop.
But really as a homeopath you have to develop the observation, the ability to look at a person and know whether he is giving you the right information or not
and there are many ways of getting to that point. Like you read the paper, symptom, symptom and
he says I want to commit suicide but I'm afraid.
In the Repertory how you will find it?
Suicidal disposition but lacks the courage;
if you look in the Repertory you will see that
the remedies are Alum, Chin, Nit-ac, Nux-v,
Phos, Plat, Rhus-t, Sulph and Tabac.
There are two overwhelming symptoms for me when I read this letter. The one is a tremendous anxiety through all these pages.
He even had a pimple in his right ear.
Do you understand the anxiety?
Thinking, writing pages, pages,
all the symptoms say anxiety about health.
If we look, anxiety about healthy in the
Repertory, look one remedy stands out, Nit-ac. We all know Nitric acid has tremendous anxiety about health. With the other symptom 'I want to commit suicide but I lack courage'
these two symptoms are overwhelming the case and put aside all the details that were written in this letter by that person. So of course Nit-ac took him out of bed and he could walk again. This is a case where we say I prescribe on the essence of the case.
-China lacks courage and it's also
anxiety about health. What about that?
It also wants to commit suicide.
-Yes, the difference is this: that China has
some anxiety about health. Nit-ac has tremendous anxiety about health.
Therefore underline the anxiety 3-4 times.
Which is the remedy that has an equal anxiety, we have to match the intensity and the
frequency of the symptom with what
we have as information in the Repertory.
That' s why we chose Nit-ac instead of China.
If the anxiety was less, if he would say instead
of having his leg pulled up, he would say
I had a hemmorhage going on for quite a
period of time and now I feel suicidal.
Why China feel suicidal? Because there
is no energy left. The blood has gone out
he does not want to live, the nervous system
is in a terrible state and I say I better die
but of course I'm afraid.
It is a different picture that was coming through the letter I was reading. And this is so important to be able to really evaluate the symptoms and
to understand. I will give you some examples.
There are different remedies for the symptoms
I presented but again with Nux-v we do not have as a keynote symptom, anxiety about health.
Nux-v sometimes they exhibit some anxiety.
But when you're really searching for a remedy that has tremendous anxiety about health your mind should go to Nit-ac and a few other remedies which are Agar added in the repertory.
Actually I have given to this Repertory about 1500 corrections for the mind section and still
it needs a lot of corrections.
I have raised Agaricus; I have seen it again
and again and again in Agaricus, tremendous anxiety about health, tremendous fear of
cancer, especially. They come and say:
'I'm dying from cancer'. You see today everybody knows we are going to die from cancer. But we don't have the anxiety but you
get certain individuals that are overwhelmed
with the fear of dying from cancer.
Of course you will die from cancer but after
50 or 30 years. I mean living in this world
with pollution, with the ozon hole,
the greenhouse effect,
we know we are going to die from cancer but
you get some patients that are overwhelmed with that fear, then you think of Agaricus.
But you see Nux-v is there anxiety about health but sometimes very seldom and some anxieties which are not so overwhelming as the Nit-ac.
Another remedy which is not on your Repertory and most probably you have to correct your Repertory is Kali-arsenicum.
Kali-arsenicum has tremendous anxiety about health and especially about health relating
to his heart. The great fear of Kali-arsenicum
is a heart infarct, tremendous fear.