I must say that this was a great surprise for me to see so many people coming from so far,
like Brazil.  I got some information from your teacher. She told me you are using
low potencies mostly. Who is using high potencies, from Brazil?
Ok. I don't know what you have heard about my teaching.
Most probably you hear that I am using high potencies. This is not true.
I use from very low to very high potencies depending on the case.
What I wanted to say as an introduction; I respect whatever helps a sick person
to become better. Especially if the problem is chronic, deep and severe.
We have problems with such cases I don't know the general health state of Brazil
but I see the dancers and I consider them as very healthy population.
When I see these people I say my God this is the acme of health! I also see from your response,
you are not facing the problems that we face here is Europe and North America
where the general population is so degenerated in its health.
We have big problems treating these cases. You are lucky.
If Homeopathy is spread all over Brazil you can keep the population in a very good
state of health. Here in Europe we lost our chance and I will explain it to you.
There are people who are treating with vitamins, minerals,
herbs and all kinds of complementary therapies in health market. These products act
upon the physical body so if by chance somebody has a lack of a vitamin and you give
the right vitamin he feels better. If by chance somebody has a lack of a mineral
and you give this mineral he will feel better. So treating the physical body
is the easiest way of treating people. If somebody has a tumor,
removes the tumor and feels better. The problem is when the disease
is more complicated and it's not so simple, it's not a lack of mineral or a lack of vitamin
but is a much deeper problem where you have in autoimmune diseases,
neuromuscular diseases, diseases that have been the effect of several generations
that inherited them to the children and already had bad health.
Actually when I came to Homeopathy in 1960, 54 years ago, I perceived that
what was practiced was only with low potencies. When I investigated about the results
I found out that there was some amelioration. I took this mixtures
of 5 remedies and had an amelioration. I took this mineral and I had an amelioration.
So the amelioration was there but the real cure was not.
That means you were able to keep somebody on a certain level, tolerably well
but the actual problem was never eradicated. Do I speak slowly? It's ok.
The kind of Homeopathy that gives 5 remedies in low potencies is easy
because we have established that if somebody has headaches the best remedies for headaches
are these remedies and you give all of them . Sometimes first you give the first 10
then the next 10 and so on… At some point the headache is going to be modified.
This is the easy Homeopathy which I understand that it is necessary
because the other way that means finding the similimum is taking so much time,
so much investigation, so much effort and so much studying before you can give the remedy.
When you use these measures, low potencies, herbs and minerals you are treating
the physical body, you are affecting the physical body mostly. But we don’t have
only physical bodies, we have also a part which is not physical but is psychological,
emotional and mental. It is a psychosomatic medicine that we are dealing with
and what I found out quite early was that if by chance or by study you have given
the correct remedy there was a kind of rejuvenation, explosion of the organism,
it was touching the immune system in its very deepest core and the immune system
was mobilized, there was an immediate reaction and after an initial aggravation
you had a fantastic effect. You have seen such cases where you don’t believe the effect
of the correct homeopathic remedy. Here you have come to learn how you can find and apply
the correct homeopathic remedy. This is the idea. Those who have learned this science
they become so successful that then they can have anything they like but before you become
successful you must be dedicated in studying and make this knowledge your way of life.
Homeopathy is magical, very attractive because the moment that you have a patient
in front of you who is suffering for years and you have attained the art and the science
to bring back health to this person who has been suffering for 10-15 years, it's like a miracle!
It's not a miracle, it's a matter of knowledge, of understanding what you are doing.
With the other you can ameliorate. It's ok but if you learn how to do it it's a tremendous
difference between amelioration and cure. It's a battle. But a beautiful battle.
Something will give you back anything you can imagine. I've heard many times by many doctors
that I am a bad guy because I prescribe one remedy only. They should kill me!
There have been lots of fights and aggression but I always say this is correct.
If you like it you take it, if you don’t like it goodbye! Continue with what you want to do,
I will not accuse you. Why should you attack me all the time?
Later on I went to India in 1963 to different colleges where they were teaching Homeopathy.
All were teaching pluralist Homeopathy, low potencies with mixtures of remedies.
I went to different colleges to see if I could learn something. I went to America 1970,
and I asked how many homeopaths were in the U.S. and there 3 M.Ds and 10 other people.
Homeopathy was finished. Today there is a big movement and at this time 5 medical schools
are adapting Homeopathy for their medical doctors and the numbers are increasing fast.
How this came about… When I was teaching I told them that we should do something
to promote Homeopathy and especially to the medical schools. And they told me I am crazy,
medical schools would never accept your teaching. 25 years later…
Of course I live long enough to do this. If I have ever used allopathic drugs
I would be dead long time ago.
But I never took allopathic drugs for anything. Not one time. Only when I was 16 years old
I took one dose of anti-inflammatory drug because I had severe pains in my back
and my stomach was burning for 2 days. That was the last… one dose of anti-inflammatory drug
at the age of 16, nothing more. What you are going to learn here is a little bit difficult.
I will try to show you with real cases, either live, there are some people
who have asked me to take their cases so you will observe the taking of the case
but I have to tell you a few things of how I take the case. In medicine they teach you
how to recognize a case of bronchitis and differentiate it from a case of pneumonia,
pharyngitis etc. how you can recognize a gastritis from a duodenal ulcer,
how a spastic colitis is and what is the difference with ulcerative colitis.
Once you establish this you give the remedy. The way that a homeopath takes a case,
this information is a little part of what you need, the information concerning the pathology,
the diagnosis. What you are interested in is the whole of the human being, how he behaves,
how he behaves when he gets back home and he is tired and his wife starts telling him blah blah
and then he explodes and cannot control himself and throws things…
You realize that this man who has the gastritis is a case of Nux-v. It's not a case of Rob.
which also has severe gastritis symptoms. And then a woman comes and says that
before my menses I become a monster. Don’t let anybody talk to me 2 days before
my menses come, I will kill anybody that comes in front of me…
There is also chronic constipation. What type of constipation? With urging and no effect.
Just this little information is very important because you know the Materia Medica.
That is why you can differentiate between the one remedy and the other.
Therefore when you take the case as the information comes in and the back of your mind
there is information you have of the different pictures of Materia Medica
so you always compare the information with what you know from the Materia Medica and then
you differentiate and then the case goes towards Nux-v. because she is such a bitch.
Do you understand the word 'bitch'? She did not translate properly!
She makes modifications, I need the similimum! Exactly! Not modifications.
No low potencies! This woman says she is so irritated and irritable and speaks
so badly to her husband and she has a constipation but the constipation
is not like urging without effect because Nux-v. is a nervous remedy.
The nervous system is on the edge. The whole nervous system is becoming irritated.
Nux-v. has kept inside quite a lot of anger. Had a fight and she did not bring out all the anger
that was inside her. She was controlling so the nervous system kept the anger and the irritation.
This irritation appears on the peripheral nervous system as a spasm in the rectum.
Gives the idea that it wants to have stool, goes to the toilet but no stool.
Goes back and stool is not coming out, anger is not coming out.
This is the typical constipation of Nux-v. But you investigate the case and you see that
she has constipation but no urging at all. Is there is no urging then you have to think twice
before you go to Nux-v. So you investigate further some other remedies.
Which are the other remedies? In order to find out that this woman is a religious person
who is all the time under a state of irritation but also dissatisfaction on sexual level so she
becomes irritable, bitchy, says bad words, fly into temper, go from one room to the other,
shutting the doors, saying bad words to her husband and then you investigate about
the sexual sphere. How is your sexual life? Not so good. Sometimes women talk more easily
about their sexual life than men. When you ask a man about his sexual life usually says 'normal'.
All men 'normal'.
Unless there is total incapacity of erection and has for this all the others 'normal'.
But women talk because they are not so shy. I don’t know Brazilians.
Maybe they are shyer. With the sexual freedom that has prevailed in our countries especially
Europe, North America… Women have no problem talking about their sexual deviations.
I remember teaching in Berkeley in California, the class was here and I was teaching
about 20 meters away where I was taking the case and by TV students
were listening and I remember a case of an American young girl, she was telling
such extreme things concerning her sexual life that the class of 20 meters away,
I could hear them laughing. I went to the class and I asked why are you laughing so loud?
They said because we felt that you were going to have a cultural shock with what
you were listening. I said yes, I had a cultural shock with her telling all these things freely,
without any shame. I am talking about 30 years ago, 1975.
But still I could not believe the freedom. I don’t know if you have this kind of freedom in Brazil
but anyhow Brazilian race is a very loving one, with a lot of emotions.
If you have an emotional patient you have an easy case. If you have a person who
is closed and emotions are burned out, forget it. You will battle to get some information.
You will get 'yes', 'no'… But if you have an emotional person where his emotions are floating
there is no problem. You will have easy cases for what we are going to teach you.
What you will have to observe during the taking of the case, you will have to observe
the question because the questions I put indicaed what I have in my mind as a possibility
at the moment. Every question has a meaning and behind each question
there is a possibility of a remedy. Those who have the information,
who have attended the full course of Homeopathy, they can follow and know
George is now investigating the possibility of Plat. George is now investigating
the possibility of Med. George is now investigating the possibility of Calc.
Sometimes they don’t understand because the case goes to a very small remedy
Paris quadrifolia. Who know Paris quadrifolia. You have to attend the classes
to know Paris quadrifolia but the first time Paris quadrifolia appears in the class nobody knows,
it's ok, but most of the cases are understood, followed by the students
who have taken the full course. I'll tell you something to see how we are thinking
and how we are observing. In 1969 I was back in Greece and I had one student,
a M.D. neurologist Irene and we were thinking how to promote Homeopathy
in Greece together. She said she has a teacher in the University who I know quite well
so I will invite him in my home and you also come and by chance you will start talking.
He was a Professor of Cardiology in the medical school. He comes and by chance we start talking
about Homeopathy and he gets interested and in the end after 2 hours of discussion he says ok,
I am a practical man so I have a coryza and I know it is going down tomorrow
and then bronchitis comes. This is the usual course. Can you give me a remedy to stop my cold?
I said yes. Why? I had taken the full case while we were talking, 2 hours. First of all it was winter,
the house was a little bit cold but he stayed with his overcoat all the time.
I was wearing my sweater and he was wearing his coat. Then from time to time
he would get up from his chair and would sit in another chair etc. Then I noticed
his nose was red because of the acid discharge. So without asking any question
the remedy was Ars. Restlessness, cold feeling, acid discharge. You don’t need more than this.
I said to Irene to give him 1 dose of Ars. 200C. He did not hear the remedy,
because he would think that arsenic would kill him! He took it, greeted me and said goodbye.
He had my telephone number. I told him because the coughing had started
so he had some discharge and coughing, next day you have no cough but the discharge
will be much more. Next day he phones me and says it’s professor X the discharge is more,
no coughing and hangs up. Next day he phones, no discharge!
After that he called me and told about a case he had and he described me a case of severe acne
with thick discharges, can you do anything for this. Give one dose of Calc-s. 200C.
15-20 days later he calls me and says do you remember the girl with the severe acne?
Yes. I kissed her! What do you mean? Her skin is totally normal so I kissed her.
Of course he became my student later on. This is the type of effect you are going to have.
This is how Homeopathy was spread all over the world because of the effect
that this kind of Homeopathy has. There is easy Homeopathy, there is ghost Homeopathy,
there are all kinds of Homeopathy. Some people say I found the cure for AIDS.
What is it? I will send you a disc with a song and if you play the song for a month you are cured!
You call it ' Homeopathy'? Yes because the vibrations of this song is telling
with the vibrations of AIDS and then similia similibus curentur.
I said similia similibus you're crazy. Another says I will send you the remedy
through mobile phone. He sent some vibrations on the mobile phone,
now you received your remedy. Another one says you don’t have to give the remedy
you have a piece of paper, write Lyc. 10M. Take the water put it over it and then you drink it.
And then you took Lyc. 10M. All this is called Homeopathy!
Another one says you look like an animal. Which animal? Owl! Take owl!
If the person looks like an animal you give an animal remedy.
If he looks like a vegetable give him a vegetable.
If he looks like mineral give mineral remedy.
I had a class here and I presented a case of asthma.
A German man with big mustache, black hair. I asked the class if he looked like an animal,
a vegetable or a mineral. ANIMAL! Now I will show you the remedy that cured.
Put the video. This man was cured with Bell. What is this nonsense!
Before where you are a lot of people have given you all kinds of ideas and nonsense.
You don’t even have to make a proving! You just imagine what the proving could do!
If I tell you I have a remedy which is a plant and it is called Agave.
Please imagine what this remedy can do. Each one of you will imagine a different thing.
Is this Homeopathy? I said to them this is not Homeopathy, this is your craziness.
You are crazy but keep it for yourself. Don’t spread your craziness.
If everybody becomes crazy, then we have a problem. This doctor came here and said
I would like your blessing. I said you are crazy, you want me to bless you,
so you are spreading your craziness! Are you serious? I am sorry but you tell the people
that you are telling lies. You confess your sins. Tell everyone I was bluffing, I was telling stories.
I hear a voice from a man but I look there but all girls are there. How is it possible?
Is there a man? There is a man! Know I solved the problem. Blind. But does not talk, he is quite.
The other talks who is behind. I could not believe who is this woman who talks like this?
Go back to the way I take the case. Usually they teach you that you have to let the patient talk
and tell you everything. I don't let the patient talk and tell me everything.
I interrupt them and I ask questions and I told you why I ask questions.
I get 4 symptoms and I form an idea about the remedy and this is considered
as a bad way of taking the case. Because you may miss some information that the patient
would have given you in case you did not interrupt. That is true. But I have to take a case
within a certain period of time and I have to come here from the case taking room
and make the analysis and explain to you what I put these questions,
what is the remedy and support this idea for the remedy etc.
Therefore I do not have unlimited time. Sometimes you will be angry because
you don’t follow the process and sometimes you will shout.
I remember a case I was taking inside. It was a woman, a medical person, she had problems
with her mother, great conflict so she started talking about her mother.
I went to our  country house and there was my mother, and she did not greet me etc.
I let her talk for a while, I understood there was a big conflict. I put some questions,
she did not pay attention, she continued telling the story.
I said please I will ask questions and you will answer only the question.
I was very abrupt. She stopped and asked questions. Then I came inside.
That was a german group. I started analyzing the case and one German woman gets up
and she says to me George, I don’t understand you, you are so patient in other times
and now you spoke so badly to that poor woman… Then another one gets up and says
I also agree with her. I said you take Causticum and you take Causticum.
And the lady here also needs Causticum. So Causticum 50M. They were surprised.
The woman says I cannot take 50M! If you don’t like 50M take whatever you like.
6 months later the group comes back and she said she is better in everything.
Did you take Causticum? Causticum is a remedy that cannot tolerate injustice.
They felt I was treating her with unjustice. They felt they had to get up and they
respected me anyway. I feel my students must be free to tell whatever they like,
otherwise it would be like suppressing them. They cannot withstand to keep inside the anger
when some injustice is seen. The Causticum will get up and speak.
Once, there was a woman, she was quite short, and asked why would you do if you saw
injustice especially towards animals. Causticum has a sensitivity to people
treating animals badly. She said I once attacked a huge man because he was treating
his dog badly. Causticum is of that type. Therefore what we are interested in taking the case;
we're to know the psychology, the mental/ emotional picture together with the pathology.
Not only the pathology. But what about the whole person, how he behaves emotionally.
Do you know when you are going to be attentive to what I say? When you are emotionally open.
And when I put emotions in my sayings.
Then it becomes alive. Who can stay 1,5 hour alive and not go like this?
It's not possible unless there is emotionality in speaking. In order to communicate,
we don’t communicate with ideas, we communicate with emotion and then the idea comes.
If I give you ideas you may attend half an hour 35,36,37 minutes…
Terrible! The moment the teacher is tired, that means there is no emotional energy
the class is down. Usually the cases that I see are the most difficult.
Because they come from very far to the island to be treated. They are desperate.
These cases are not going to be cured with one remedy.
These cases have different layers of remedies that the homeopath has to recognize
which is the right one first, the right one second…then you may have the effect.
For you maybe it is not so difficult because you don’t have so many deep chronic conditions,
I don’t know. As I said I'm looking at the girls that dance… And I get an impression
girls are very healthy. Too healthy. Therefore you will have the experience of taking a case
I must also say that somebody wrote me about his case and I refused.
I said don't let this case come,
I cannot promise that this case will be cured but since he came I will take his case. Thank you!