I have said and this was a
question that you had to answer,
what was the difference between the
explanation I was giving for the
action of the remedy and what
was the difference with Hahnemann?
Hahnemann's explanation, is that the remedy is stronger and overpowers the disease and takes
it out and runs its course, the remedy runs its course. This is the explanation of Hahnemann.
And I had explained to you that this, according
to my understanding, is wrong perception.
Even Hahnemann himself says, you are not to
be interested how the remedy works but anyhow
if you are interested, I will give
you my opinion, this is my opinion.
This is what he says in this paragraph.
According to my explanation, the
reason why the remedy acts is this:
the organism under stimulation
develops certain symptoms.
It has big and small symptoms. That means
the symptoms are the means through which
the organism tries to find its
balance. Otherwise it will die.
Here stimulation is streptococcus,
bacteria, virus or whatever.
The organism raises the temperature, brings mucus brings cough, etc. to fight the disease.
Through the symptoms is fighting the
disease, the cause. Do you understand this?
The idea is that every symptom that the organism is giving out is in order to keep
a kind of a balance. What would
happen if there were no reaction
of the organism if the
bacteria were multiplying?
The bacteria may come to the organism or
the organism itself has the bacteria actually
and the bacteria under certain circumstances
they start growing 50.000, 100.000, 1million
1.5 million then the organism is
triggered. It says, danger.
What it does? It raises a fever. If it did
not do that you can imagine the bacteria
are overwhelming the organism and
one time without any reason you
would see the organism collapse and die.
This happens actually in certain diseases in
which bacteria explode very quickly and
you see the death within a few hours.
So therefore the symptoms are the means through which the organism itself says,
let me do this, let me do that, symptoms, symptoms to keep my balance,
give me water, electrolytes are high,
give me less water, give me sweets etc.
All these are symptoms to fight disease.
The organism has a way of
reacting towards the stimulus.
And this is the best way.
There is no other way.
The organism decides this is my best way.
We see what the organism is doing
and we say, ok let's take that
remedy which produces similar symptoms.
What we do? We help this reaction.
That means by giving in this organism,
the similar remedy, the similimum, we are
again exciting the organism towards
the same direction in which it
tries to fight the disease.
You give a remedy that has the same picture,
this picture but no so strong of course.
Something like that. The remedy
has a picture like this.
The remedy has more symptoms also.
But the general pattern it
fits in the main symptoms.
That means you stimulate the defence
of the organism in the same direction
as the organism has decided to
fight the disease. You don't go against.
If you fight one main symptom, ex. this is fever and you give a local treatment you suppress this.
Then by suppressing this, fever comes here
and then this symptom becomes like this.
Then the organism is trying
to find a new balance.
We try to find exactly the similar remedy which will stimulate in the same way the organism.
What we do? We strengthen the
defenses of the organism.
That is why initially we see an aggravation
of the symptoms because the organism
is trying this way, it says, raise a
little bit fever, just a little bit more.
It cannot and the fever comes up and down,
up and down, it continues, continues, why?
The organism cannot raise it
enough to burn the cause, the bacteria.
You will give the remedy and the fever shoots
up just enough to burn the bacteria;
maybe it is a fraction of a degree but
that is  enough for the organism
to overwhelm the cause. So what we
do here is to stimulate the defence
mechanism in the same way the
organism itself is fighting disease.
That is why we have initial aggravation
and that is why the effect is curative.
Otherwise, suppressing this symptom, no curative effect, suppressing that symptom,
no curative effect. Suppressing 1,2,3 and leaving out that symptom, no curative effect.
That is why we say the allopathic
way of thinking which says,
the most dangerous thing for the
child is the fever, bring down the fever,
but then you make the
child crazy. What is this?
Because you brought down the fever.
Because you acted only in one
part of the defence mechanism. So here
by trying to find the similar remedy,
we stimulate the organism, we give the extra energy that he needs and then we see
the balancing as a result; we have the
balancing of that situation, back to normal.
Is this clear? This is very important that
you understand this. A lot of questions.
-I have a question regarding suppression
with the remedy which is not very similar
and the other theory being that you can give
several remedies that are partially similar,
that's reaching a cure all together; if you
cannot find the correct or if it doesn't exist.
-It is possible instead of hiting
the exact remedy to hit a remedy
which is similar and then you see
a change in the pattern.
Then you take the change in the
pattern and then you prescribe
the second remedy
and then you proceed.
And then you give a 3rd, a 4th or
a 5th remedy in a case where
maybe 1 or 2 remedies would be
enough to bring about the cure.
It is true by changing the pattern
all the time, finally you accomplish a cure
but never a complete cure as it
comes with the right similimum.
Something always is left to be desired
but this is something which most
Homeopaths are doing due to the lack of
complete knowledge of the Materia Medica
and lack of knowledge of the Theory.
Many times we follow this path,
that remedy, that remedy.
These are the cases mostly which
are one-sided, what Hahnemann calls,
especially the mental diseases
Hahnemann calls, one-sided.
That means only the mental is affected.
He considers them very difficult to cure,
he says one-sided give a remedy and
then wait to see the next picture.
She says, I find it difficult to
understand when the organism
is giving out dangerous
symptoms like epileptic fit?
That's a good question.
These are the questions I'm expecting.
What happens, is an epileptic fit an
effort of the organism to cure itself?
And the answer is yes. Why? Because
if this epileptic fit does not take place,
then the organism is in danger of
having damage on a deeper level.
For instance, the focus of an epileptic
fit is somewhere in the brain.
That means there is a damage
there, whether is electrical
chemical, whatever. If you close this,
then the organism does not cure itself,
if you go and stop the fit. It takes the
disturbance deeper into the organism.
So you see with the epileptics that once you
stop, force it the rest of the organism on
the mental-emotional level becomes disturbed. So the people who take the anti-epileptic drugs
are people drugged, they have lost
the ability to think clearly, to feel clearly,
they develop different other perversions.
Which means that the epileptic fit has gone
deeper now into the organism and created other disturbances in the organism, deeper than the fit.
That's number one.
The second is that you could say, there is a difference between an accident and a disease.
Epileptic fit is a disease, it's not an accident.
But you could say, what about a heart infarct?
In the heart infarct, does this
organism need it in order to cure itself?
Of course not.
But in this case it is an accident, it is a piece
of clot which circulates in the organism
and goes and closes an artery suddenly
and then you have a heart infarct.
This is an accident which you cannot prevent. Once the accident has taken place,
then you can say Arnica, Rhus-t, Lyc, Bry because it gives out symptoms of course.
Every accident that happens to
the organism has a reaction.
But don't stick yourself to these
few things which may be
happening and we put them
on the idea of an accident.
The same way, as he said yesterday, he had swallowed something, is it possible that an
accident would have taken place and
would have created inflammation etc?
And in these cases we have the
remedies according to the symptoms
which will help the accident.
-Hahnemann says that the life force reacts without any sense to save the organism
but which may lead to death.
I want to know whether you think is a
misinterpretation because he
says it may lead to death or
he only says whether it may lead to
death, but I will explain it to you.
-Wait a moment. Find the aphorism which she is talking about so I can read it and I will tell you.
In the meantime you find this
and then she would like to respond.
She says for me there is no difference
between epilepsy and a heart infarct
because it is something which
happens inside the organism;
it is not an accident which
happens from the outside.
And therefore the organism is
diseased and not under accident.
Now let me explain this idea fully.
The organism before the
heart infarct is diseased.
That means is producing more cholesterol
and the arteries are becoming full
with cholesterol and eventually
one piece breaks out and circulates.
Now the organism which we have seen before the heart infarct, will give us some symptoms.
These symptoms will lead us to the remedy that the organism will stop producing high cholesterol.
Now take another. An organism is producing stones, on the gall bladder or on the kidneys.
They come to us, no symptoms but there are some general symptoms that we may use in
order to give the correct remedy so the
organism will stop producing stones.
You have given the correct remedy
and the organism is doing well.
Inspite of this fact one day because he eats
a lot of fat, there is a big contraction of the
gall bladder and the stone sticks in there.
That is an accident, it is not a disease.
That accident you have to treat at this
moment according to the symptoms
it has developed and if you give the
right remedy in most of the cases,
not all, will be almost immediately ameliorated.
So what we are interested in is the time that we have the spasm and the symptomatology.
The symptomatology tells you how to act.
It is the organism which tells you,
hey you homeopath act in this way,
these are the symptoms.
Find the remedy and give it to me.
You found it? Which paragraph?
-22.
- par. 22: " But there is nothing to be observed
in diseases that must be removed
in order to change them into health.
Besides the totality of such symptoms,
likewise Medicine can show nothing curative ..." am I reading the right paragraph?
-The sub-note.
-Sub-note, all right. "The other possible
mode of employing medicines for disease
besides these two is the allopathic
method in which  medicines are given,
whose symptoms have no direct
pathological relation to the morbid state,
neither similar nor opposite but quite heterogenous to the symptoms of the disease.
This procedure plays an irresponsible murderous game with the life of the patient by
means of dangerous, violent medicines etc."
....... (reading extracts from Organon)
He says, there is no other way and he repeats
it frequently that you can cure a disease,
only by taking into consideration the
symptoms of the person
and find the Homeopathic remedy,
there is no other way.
So the symptoms are the means by which the organism is trying to keep a kind of a balance
and at the same time it is pointing out the
means through which it's going to be helped.
If this is not given .....
......( reading Organon).....
Your question is: if you have a severe acute disease from which the patient is going to die,
is that considered to be a means of trying
to keep balance? Is that your question?
-No, you say that with the remedy we
make the disease a little bit worse.
-Ah the question is if you have a severe disease and you make it more severe, the patient dies?
-In disease of typhus I would say that.
And you say that this is the explanation
for all diseases so I cannot follow it.
-Ok. This is a good question. What
experience has shown in this respect is
that if you have a case in which
a symptom is dangerous
out of 20 symptoms of the patient, one is dangerous, let us take high blood pressure.
You have a patient with 250/160,
this is dangerous situation.
You give a remedy, you raise the blood
pressure and you say you have a brain stroke.
Is this your question?
-No.
-You want the fever? The fever will come. Now the organism under this, has several symptoms.
What the remedy will do is to
aggravate urination.
Urination was 5 times, it makes it 20.
It aggravates the perspiration
and then you see here coming down, 240.
So the organism knows what he has to do.
He cannot do it. You have to help him,
do it. In the same way with the fever.
In typhus actually the danger comes from
what? From perforation of the intestines.
The inflammation in the intestines is very
severe, you can have a perforation,
they just break, the inflammation is defused, becomes severe peritonitis and the patient dies.
So the organism will do the same process.
It will know exactly what it has to do.
How perforation is done?
To a certain point there is a big inflammation,
so the mucus membranes of the colon
are eaten up and then they break.
At that point the organism will
heal this inflammation first.
At the same time making more stool,
more perspiration whatever is the aggravation.
But the aggravation under the Homeopathic remedy will not be a dangerous
one that will raise the blood pressure. Clear?
-I have a question because for me your theory is
logical but what about the autoaggression illness
because it is against my body and I don't think
is a symptom to reach my balance back.
-In paragraph 67 Hahnemann says that in special cases you can use palliative when the life force
is so low that Homeopathic remedy
will be too much for the organism.
-Find me the paragraph-67. Wait a moment,
let's clarify one by one the issues.
What about a case of suicidal depression?
-Autoaggression.
-Autoaggression is a new word.
-She is talking about autoimmune diseases.
-Systemic, autoimmune diseases.
The organism the more sick it becomes,
the more it becomes out of balance.
And that is how death takes place.
We all die when the organism loses total
control. There is no way that we can stop
death with Homeopathy. So there is a
point in the organism where the organism
has reached its limits and therefore
the organism cannot do anymore anything.
Nevermind how much we try
homeopathically or allopathically,
people will be dying once they
have reached that point.
No way of saving all the people and
let them live indefinitely.
We have to accept the idea that at a certain
point death will ensue. Now you say that
a schizophrenic, total mad person, is
this a reaction to save this person?
And I say, yes this is the only way
that he will not commit suicide,
that he will not be killed, that he will
not have something which will end his life.
Still the organism is trying to find an outlet.
Schizophrenia is an outlet to get out of a certain problem which is so great for the organism;
maybe for you is very little but for
this organism is very strong
and it goes off and it becomes mad. So the madness is a reaction towards something
which endangers life. Also it has symptoms,
also you can be treating such cases.
Now there is another question that was put.
-I have a question concerning the suppression. Because after the suppression in this case,
you got the main symptom for prescribing
the remedy and I ask myself would
you have given this remedy before. So this suppression forced the body to produce
stronger, deeper symptom and
the suppression was gone.
And I am now confused because I thought
if there is a strong suppression you take
the symptoms before the suppression.
-Not always. What actually we are
doing here, is what Hahnemann
describes in one-sided diseases. He says,
many times a physical disease becomes mental.
These diseases I call one-sided diseases.
Then, he says, you give a remedy and the
mental symptoms go away and the
physical symptoms return.
In the case that we have seen,
we have seen mental symptoms
developing and I have seen cases
where these mental symptoms
have stayed for life,
after the antibiotics.
'My boy has become aggressive, dissatisfied'
and the mother describe that state
as a permanent state. Now he comes to you
and you see that the picture of the symptoms,
presented at the moment,
point out to one remedy.
You have to give that remedy. If the picture
was more clear of the previous state,
you could ignore these changes and
say  the picture was so clear before
that I will give that picture.
But the picture was so obvious,
having this dissatisfaction,
it was obvious for everyone to see,
therefore you have to prescribe on
this main symptom of the case. So we
prescribe on the main symptoms of the case.
I will be discussing further the strategies,
how to tackle each case and
what are the methods through
which we discuss the case.
-I have another question regarding par. 22, the footnote. How do you evaluate the life force?
Do you also think it is a senseless and what Hahnemann states here, life force ?
Or do you think it makes sense to actually put
a signal for the person to heal the disease?
Hahnemann writes word by word that he thinks that the life force is senseless, footnote par. 22.
-When we go to paragraph, we will discuss it.
What I want your attention is to par. 11 and
12 in which Hahnemann says that:
"when a person falls ill, it's only this
spiritual self acting automatic vital force,
everywhere present in his organism,
that is primarily deranged
by the dynamic influence upon
it of a morbific agent.
It is only the vital principle deranged
to such an abnormal state,
that can furnish the organism
with its disagreable sensation.
And incline it to the regular processess
which we call disease..........."
....(reading par.11).....
So the idea of Hahnemann is that the disease
is only the symptoms which are apparent
to the observing physician and to the
patient himself and to the relatives.
He says, this is the disease and these
symptoms you have to take into consideration
to cure the disease. Hahnemann
has a logic, you have to imagine,
behind all these there is a logic. He says,
the derangement comes from a dynamic
influence upon the vital force of a morbific
agent. Then the symptoms are appearing.
Take in consideration the symptoms
and treat according to the symptoms.
And then he says: all medicinal
substances have unlimited power
over the organism. That means
they can produce diseases
whether the organism wants it or not.
They can produce symptoms
whether the organism wants it or not,
take Arsenicum in big enough dose,
everyone will have symptoms.
Some they will die. This is what he knows.
So his logic is that since this medicine
is more powerful than disease,
if I give a more powerful agent,
the disease will be overpowered. He comes to this conclusion because he has observed
that in natural epidemic diseases,
an epidemic disease which is similar
in its expression with another one,
can annihilate, can cure.
One disease can cure another. So he develops
a logic according to this observation.
The logic is now that the medicine
is stronger, has a power.
Therefore if I give it like the
epidemics, which are similar,
the one annihilates the other
and runs its course.
In the same way, the medicine is more
powerful, I give it and then he had observed
there awere some symptoms left by the drug.
He says, now the disease runs its course.
The problem is that it has a loop hole that thinking and it doesn't satisfy a logical person.
How this is happening?
You throw a stronger and then they fight
each other and the other one is strong
and run its course? All this makes no sense.
When I was reading the Organon,
I had these problems.
I said, now this doesn't look logical.
Then I observed what was happening
in diseases and how the organism
when it is under stimulus reacts.
Let us, it's very hot in here. My organism
has to react in order to survive.
How to react, by perspiration.
Why to perspire?
Because I have to cool down my organism. Otherwise, heat, heat, I will just collapse.
So the organism under stimulus will react
to bring back balance. Otherwise you lost.
The organism says, trembling. These
are movements to heat up the body,
it says put on a jacket. If you don't
put a jacket you will die.
Heat, you perspire and you go and find a place
to sit not under the heat because you'll die.
These are natural reactions
of the organism.
If I will say to you something
very bad, you lost your child.
The heart immediately will go pap, pap, pap.
'I lost my child, what shall I do?
I must stay awake' because you may faint.
Many people have died under such a shock.
The reaction of the organism unless it
brings the palpitation then you will fall down.
So the organism says, what you can do? Palpitation, give more energy.
More oxygen, more perspiration, there
is a whole reaction of the organism.
This reaction is not mad, senseless or
whatever. It is very intelligent and the best
the organism it can do. If we agree
in that principle then we have to
admit that when we give a similar remedy,
we stimulate the organism in a similar
manner, very intelligent manner
and help him in his reaction.
This is the logic behind.
One thing I would like to say concerning
the senseless vital force.
I will explain to you
what he means.
He says that the vital force is a
neutral thing. It doesn't like this, that,
has no senses, no feelings, no thoughts. Whatever you do to her it responds.
You do good things, it responds good,
you do bad things, it responds bad.
So it is a neutral force
which animates everything.
Now you go and you do bad things
to that thing which it animates,
the vital force will respond. So senseless
means without preferences, without thinking.
A force which does not think does
not feel, does not have senses.
There is, as we have explained
in the first session, there is a force
which animates everything.
In everything there is a force which
takes the shape of the tree, the plant,
it's the same force that animates the plant,
it animates the body, it makes life to the body.
The same force animates the stone, the metal
and creates forms. So it's a neutral force
which takes the shape of the things that
animates. If this was not so, there would
be no correspondence between the force
of the plant and the force of the organism.
It is because this is common to all, that is why
the force of the plant can affect
the force of the organism.
Otherwise it would be something different. Different force that makes the stone
and the animals, the insects etc. The fact is
that everything is animated by a neutral force.
Neutral would be better than
senseless or thoughtless.
In religion they say that God is within us,
all religions say God is within you.
What they mean is God is that cosmic
force that goes through everything
and goes through you as well. The
difference is that human beings have
free choice and they
can do whatever they like.
They can be well, they can be sick,
they can be perverted, bad, malicious etc.
It doesn't mean that Hahnemann
is wrong, no. Hahnemann followed
a way of thinking and concluded this.
He was not wrong.
Actually everything he writes
is correct. Except of that point.
-Yesterday you talked about the vital force.
And you said it's automatic
and really you translated
Hahnemann, in your first book.
-From my book? I wrote it 30 years ago.
-Yes I know but it's about what we talked yesterday. When he says, self-acting
you quote it like automatic but then you quote Kent from his lectures and Kent said that
vital force is a formative intelligence.
And you agree with him. I just want to ask, how formative intelligence goes with automatic?
-That's a good question. We are talking
about a force, an energy and
what Hahnemann most probably
meant by "senseless" "automatic",
he writes about senseless, automatic or
without thought, is an energy which has no will,
has no power of its own. Because there are
other certain elements which interfere
with every creature. With the wood, the
stone we have certain conditions.
With the plants we have different
conditions. So we can say,
in another way, that there are several
levels of consciousness
that means minerals have a
consciousness of a-degree
and then plants have a
consciousness of b-degree.
It's a different cosciousness.
Animals have a
consciousness of c-degree.
And humans have a
consciousness of d-degree.
The higher consciousness entities are fed
by the lower consciousness entities.
Plants are fed by minerals,
animals are fed by the plants.
They are physical bodies,
physical entities.
But we have said that humans
are also having free will,
and  what is the difference between
animals and plants?
We have a part in us which we
call the spiritual part and
we have a part of us
which we call the love.
We have love and wisdom,
which is missing on these entities.
You are asking about what?
The question of Hahnemann is:
The energy which goes right through all
these entities has a kind of similarity?
You can say it's the same energy.
If this was not the same energy,
these minerals could
not affect the human.
When you bring out the energy of the
mineral, it affects the energy of the human.
A gas can affect a gas, water can affect
water. Liquids can affect liquids
and solids can affect solids. You
cannot affect a solid with a gas.
So there is a similarity in the
energy that goes through this.
What is the difference between this and that?
These minerals, they have their own rules and intelligence and they will form the crystals
or whatever is to be formed in
this level of consciousness.
So the energy is used by these different consciousness manifestations in the planet,
each one of them forming its own
needs, fulfilling its own mission.
These minerals, their mission
is to grow the plants.
If they don't grow plants they don't
have a mission, they are dead.
The idea of entropy, you understand
this law of thermodynamics?
When do we have the biggest entropy?
In the stone. The stone is considered as
the total entropy where nothing moves.
So the minerals do not fulfill their mission anymore. They do not sustain the plants.
The energy that goes through them
is used by each consciousness.
Hahnemann says, the energy
will not tell you: become sick.
You can use this energy, you can
be sick or you can be well.
And here as humans we have the freedom
to do that. Here, in this consciousness
what is missing is the free will. There is
no free will on these levels.
The need of the mineral in order
to sustain itself is minimal.
The humans have the possibility of changing their destiny. These, they don't have it.
These are only to support the humans.
And here we have the highest form of consciousness in the planet.
But underneath all this which takes
place is an energy which is neutral.
It is like somebody tells you, 'I will give
you life you do whatever you like.
You destroy, I will follow.'
We are talking about two different things.
When Kent says that energy
has informative intelligence, what he says,
the intelligence that Kent means is,
'if you stimulate me correctly, I will follow.
I will do good for you.
If you stimulate me wrongly, I will follow.
I will do bad for you.
Then it is in your free will, as humans.
to decide what you want to do with me',
with the energy which you have inside.
So the energy cannot resist the free will that we have. The energy will give you what you are.
These are difficult subjects to
understand but here we have
an evolution of consciousness actually.
That's why we say sometimes,
he behaves like an animal.
Here the idea is that he behaves without free
will, without choice, without discrimination.
He behaves like a pig, especially for men with sexual interference etc. What does it mean?
That the consciousness which you have,
you are using it against you.
Instead of going somewhere higher,
because there might be here another
level of consciousness which we
may call, the super consciousness.
This is a level of consciousness in which
you have evolved and you have reached
the highest possible state
for the human being.
Which is the state of love and wisdom,
feelings full of love, thoughts full of wisdom.
So the energy is going to make you
feel love or wisdom? Forget it.
The energy says, I'm here,
I will support you, I am behind you.
You do whatever you like with me.
I am senseless, I don't have thoughts.
I don't have feelings. You decide what
are you going to do with me.
I have given you this form because you
are born as a human being and then
you decide what you are going to do.
So when Hahnemann says, 'senseless',
he means something, he means this
neutral power which goes all these
different levels of consciousness
and when Kent describes some qualities,
he says this energy which gives you
the possibility to be a human being or an
animal or a plant or mineral.
I will tell you a secret.
On the physical level, the higher
is fed from the lower.
On spiritual level, the lower feeds from the
higher which is God super consciousness.
On the spiritual level, we feed on ideas but the real ideas come from truth, come from God.
So in order to evolve here and to grow up, we have to be fed, the lower is fed from the higher.
On the physical level, the higher
is fed from the lower.
Animals feeds from plants, plants from minerals.
On the spiritual level, the lower, we, fed on ideas,
fed from God in order to mature,
in order to become whole human beings.
We are half human beings, we vacillate between superconsiousness and subconsciousness.
- When you say about cosmic energy, is
that it must be a being without the body,
where you can put the vital force or the
cosmic energy in this degree, in this scale?
Where would you put it near?
-You see, here we have levels of consciousness, we say 4. Is it really 4 or 24 or 104
and what levels of consciousness do we have after our consciousness? How many levels?
We say super consciousness. Is it
possible that we reach one level?
What is the level of consciousness of a yogi?
Of a man who sits and meditates?
Of a man who prays,
of a man in a monastery?
What are the levels of consciousness
that they have reached?
All of them have reached the same level?
Similar levels or several levels
or struggling all the time
attaining a better level?
There are different levels of
consciousness, definitely after this human.
We realize more and more we go into Homeopathy, that we are not so much animals.
Or that there is some other possibility for the human being to become more evolved
and maybe we take the possibility.
But as Hahnemann says, the remedy will reestablish order but you are responsible
for the higher purposes of life.
You can use now your body, your good
energy for the higher purposes of your life,
par. 9 for your test paper.
Also there is an attitude by certain Homeopaths. They say forget about this theory,
just give me information about the Materia Medica. This attitude is very wrong.
Materia Medica can be learned.
Theory, is either learned wrongly or
not learned at all, is very dangerous.