Now I want to continue with strategies that we have to follow under different circumstances.
Sometimes we prescribe on one symptom, sometimes we prescribe on a psychological make-up,
sometimes we prescribe on different things.
There are different strategies and these have a logic behind.
Which is the first strategy that you
have to follow in every case?
The first strategy is the one that Hahnemann is mentioning. And he says, the totality of the symptoms.
Go to the totality, find the totality and
give the remedy that covers the totality.
That as a strategy is the first strategy
that we always follow. First strategy.
So you followed this strategy, you took all the symptoms of the patient and you repertorize
and you find out that does not give you an answer. What are you going to do?
Because you took the totality and you have 20 symptoms and if you take 16 of them you give Sepia
but if you take the rest 4 plus 11, that
means 15, you give Natrum muriaticum.
But if you take, out of the 20, you take 8, you give Phosphorus. And if you take 5, you give  Medorrhinum.
Now you may say, Sepia is the remedy
because it covers most of the symptoms.
But many times you say, no it is not Sepia.
Why you say that? Because you have some information
from the Materia Medica which shows you that actually this case does not look like Sepia.
What do we mean by 'it does not look like Sepia'? That means we bring into the picture another factor,
a new factor for analysing the case. We have the totality yes but the totality is only flat symptomatology
which many times misleads us into a remedy which is not the correct remedy.
So therefore you give up the strategy. I mean ok, Hahnemann said, take notice of the totality of the symptoms
but the totality has given me no solution
to the case, what am I going to do?
I'm going to bring another element, another information which I have into the picture and see whether
the combination of this strategy with another strategy which is called the essences, whether the combination
of the two will give me the answer to this problem. And many times I find out that the essence
fits actually with Phosphorus, not with Sepia, not with Natrum muriaticum. So inspite of the fact
I have flat
symptomatology more for Sepia or Natrum muriaticum, I go and prescribe Phosphorus
because the patient has the picture of Phosphorus. You've done this consciously or unconsciously,
this is what you're doing in analysing a case.
If we take for example, yesterday the child.
If we had taken down the symptoms of the child,
we come down to Camomilla, to Cina, to different remedies.
What we did, you have no symptoms actually of Calcarea phosphorica. We said, wait a moment
that picture as it presents to me, the essence of this picture, the mental-emotional picture of this boy seems to be Calc-p.
We ignore the majority of the totality and we prescribed on essence alone. In this case we prescribed on essence alone.
Go back again to yesterday's case which we took the case of this nice girl and we said, the picture is Phosphorus.
If you have taken the totality of the symptoms, you would see it comes down to Phosphorus.
The essence it comes down to Phosphorus and that's why you will say with great certainty, the remedy
which is going to cure this person, which covers both totality and essence, is Phosphorus.
Then you have great confidence in this remedy because it covers the essence of Phosphorus and it covers the totality
for Phosphorus. Drinks a lot of water, empty feeling of the stomach, sleeps on the right side etc.
All that are flat symptoms which if you repertorize, they will come down to Phosphorus but also
she describes the sympathetic element the suffering because of the suffering of others etc. so strongly,
I say Phosphorus. Also the sudden collapse counts for Phosphorus. To you this is a beautiful case of Phosphorus.
-But then what do we need the
totality of the symptoms for?
-Maybe I did not make myself clear. I said
the totality will give you the remedy.
You do the totality it gives you the
remedy, clearly, perfect you give it.
There are cases in which this strategy will not give you a remedy. You will take all the symptoms
but no remedy is clear. In such cases, you
bring another factor which is the essence.
And you look from that point of view now. But still there are cases which are not going to be solved by either totality or essence.
That means you have no clear essence and the totality fits in 10 different remedies. What are you going to do then?
This is the time that you will have to go by some keynotes, what we call keynotes.
What that means? It means that in the case of the boy that we saw, eventually the keynote which is very strong
for Medorrhinum, may lead us to prescribe Medorrhinum in the case.
Because the totality of the symptoms will not give us a clear picture, the essence is not there,
we have a strong keynote, we prescribe upon the strong keynote.
What I want to make clear to you is that you have to follow one strategy after the other. It is not a matter of,
I prescribe on keynote, George is prescribing only on essences, only on this or that, no.
It is a matter of systematic thinking about the analysis of a case. The systematic thinking, you do your homework,
you do your repertorising, you think about it,
is this remedy, that remedy?
It doesn't appear to me clear but that
case looks to me like Nux vomica.
But I have 5 symptoms of Nux vomica, ok take it. This is the idea. But sometimes the totality comes right through.
Or keynote symptoms of the remedy, ok give it. Forget the essence, forget everything else.
So you go down as a strategy and then you reach a point in some cases where no solution can be reached
by the totality, essence and keynote. These are the cases you have prescribed several remedies.
There is another paragraph in Hahnemann.
He says, (par. 153) in which he gives...
ok totality and essence. About keynotes he writes in par. 153. He says, those symptoms have to be taken
of much notice if they are strange, rare or peculiar. These are the keynotes.
These are what became meaning keynotes. Strange, rare and peculiar to this remedy. What are these?
These are the things we're trying to give you in the Materia Medica. In the Materia Medica we try to combine
the essence with keynotes, so we give you an information which is compact for each remedy and then
when you see it in the person, it will strike something in your mind. So here Hahnemann stresses the idea
of taking notice, especially notice of keynotes.
But you see here in the child of bronchitis.
The keynote is strange, rare and peculiar, is the Medorrhinum. But you have another impression
about the child which gives you this remedy.
So as far as the essence is concerned, the disatisfaction, in the morning expressing this disatisfaction.
You will see, if you progress more and more and you have more experience, you will see a difference
between the disatisfaction of Chamomilla,
the disatisfaction of Antimonium crudum,
the disatisfaction of Calcarea phosphorica the disatisfaction of Cina. You will see a difference which is
very difficult even for me to define it. With Chamomilla there is an element of maliciousness.
The child has some malice and it is more aggressive. You try to put the stethoscope
and the Camomilla child will react in this way.
You are very nice. This is what we call the essence.
You say, I did not see this. Disatisfaction and moaning.
Let's go out, Calcarea phosphorica. You walk
out, you want out? No. This is different.
I mean you say one remedy and the other is disatisfaction but actually there are some differences.
Cina does not have the moaning. It has the aggression and does not know what he wants.
Capriciousness. Give me this.
He takes this and throws it.
It is very interesting that we have live cases
that you get the feeling of each remedy.
You see the element of aggressiveness grows then you go to another remedy. You see the element
of moaning you go to another remedy, you see the element of capriciousness, you go to another remedy.
But all these remedies are close together and difficult in their evaluation.
So from a practical point of view what you will have to do? I say that there are some cases in which you have given,
you prescribed on totality the Sepia, you prescribed the Natrum muriaticum, you went to Phosphorus,
you went to Medorrhinum because of position, nothing. And then you find out that this case had an accident
15 years ago where it was a big concussion on the brain, he had one or two symptoms of Arnica, you never thought of Arnica.
Because only 2 symptoms out of 20 but the causative factor is clear and you go to causation which may
require only one information that does not cover totality, does not cover essence.
there are no keynotes but because you have the causation clear after this accident, then I started with my headaches.
The headaches do not have the picture of Arnica. The headaches may have the picture of Sepia
or a picture of Natrum muriaticum or a picture of Phosphorus. Yet Arnica is going to work.
You know the story with the peacock? The brain injury? The peacock who was raised back to life. Causation.
A woman which becomes hysterical and has hysteria and her tongue turns, she is unconscious.
You give her Ignatia, she comes back to life.
You know all that.
Here when we talk of essence, mostly we mean the mental-emotional picture, make-up.
Then sometimes you go all along and you cannot really find the remedy inspite of the fact that you have gone
through all these strategies. Still you
cannot find the remedy.
Then the fifth strategy is go to the essentials. Essentials is a very important strategy.
What are the essentials?
-I wanted to ask for this fourth point. You said, headaches for instance an accident but very often
the headaches have a relation to some problem with the teeth. Do you ever think of teeth?
-This is what I call causative factor.
Causation is teeth.
-No, I'm asking if you ever think that
there might be a problem with the teeth.
-No. I have heard that others have seen this, take out the teeth and there is an amelioration.
I also have heard that a lot of people have
been taken out the teeth, no amelioration.
-If you take out all the teeth...
-Not all, only the teeth which are not ok.
I have done this because I'm a dentist,
and I found out there is a change.
-I have seen cases of trigeminal neuralgia for instance which all the teeth were taken out.
No effect at all. And they come and tell the story of course. We hear actually the stories which are failures.
Because if there are success, we don't hear, they don't come to us.
They took my tooth out, they thought it was my tooth, they took 1,2,3 no effect. They took out all the teeth.
I remember at least 2 cases ,they took all the teeth out, no effect. So therefore they say, for instance,
if you fill the teeth with amalgam, Mercury, it might have an effect. So you change the teeth into gold which
I've seen some cases. But I have not seen this,
I changed the teeth, no effect. But, as I said, we see the failures.
I hear from journals, they have written it, that by doing this there was an effect and I believe it.
But my experience is to see the failures. Who has failed and after that, he comes to be treated.
'I did this, I did that, no effect. Can you do something?'. And these are the cases which
I have seen.
With this strategy here we have to go actually and see what are the essential features of the remedy.
When I write the Materia Medica, there is a chapter in which I wrote the essential features.
In the essential features I don't describe only the essence but I describe, especially in the small remedies,
the combination of pathology.
That means somebody who is suffering with a lot of otitis and at the same time you see problems with gums.
Gums bleeding, receeding etc. Then the fact that we have a remedy which actually concentrates its action
upon the ears and upon the gums, we can prescribe the remedy on these essential features of this remedy.
Which is the remedy? Mercury solubilis is the main remedy that you will think, inspite of the fact that
if you take the details of the symptoms, Mercury may not come down but given the fact that the combination
of pathology is for Mercury, then finally you prescribe Mercury and you see the effect.
I'll give another example. Hoarseness of voice together with an effect on the cartilaginous matter of the joint,
Argentum metallicum.
In this way you will solve many cases in which you try to find mental pathology. No mental pathology.
You try to find the totality? No totality. The totality gives you several possibilities.
No special keynotes. But the fact that the essential features, if you have eruptions and duodenal ulcer,
which are the remedies you will be thinking first?
Antimonium crudum, Graphites and
Kali bichromicum, Dulcamara...
Immediately the remedies come. You have cases that say, 'I have been bleeding from my stomach.
I've been in the hospital 5 times with bleeding of my ulcer'. And at the same time he gives you the information that is
fatty degeneration of the liver.
The remedy that affects the liver and causes at the same time very easy haemmorhages, is Phosphorus.
So the fact that you have a pathology you
just concentrate on the main pathology.
You have somebody who is having swollen glands, cervical glands, some maxiliary, inguinal glands swollen
and if they will tell you that such a person has also hypothyroidism, the thyroid is slow and the person is getting obese,
the remedy that you will be thinking is?
No. Calcarea carbonica. Getting fat, hypothyroidism with glands swollen.
If the glands are swollen, again hard swollen and the next pathology is diziness, vertigo, you see, Conium. This is the idea.
Then it becomes very important that your mind should think this way and ignore sometimes the totality
which will give you Sepia because the essentials are for Conium. And you need the information on the essentials
because we don't have the information for all the remedies about mental-emotional, what they can cause.
We don't have it. In all the remedies it would
be nice to have, it would be nice to know
the peculiarities on the mental-emotional
level of Cajuputum. We don't.
There is such a remedy? Cajuputum?
No. I made it up.
They have a very peculiar symptom where the tongue feels so big that fills the whole mouth.
I'm not joking. There is such a remedy, there is such symptom which has tremendous anxiety about health.
So you will see whether you want it or not, whether you do it consciously or not consciously
that in your evaluation in Classical Homeopathy, you follow this line of thinking.
The first thing you are looking for is the totality of the symptoms. Then you go to the Repertory, you go to the computer
and try to see which is the remedy and
then you see some things on the essence.
Then the keynotes come to correct. Therefore many times your decision will be based upon the combination of these strategies.
Some totality, rather the essence but it has one or two keynotes of this and the causation also it fits, perfect.
I will just give you a few things. In order to do this essence, you need observation. This is not going to be given
by the patient himself. You need some observation many times to come down to the essence.
The keynotes are given by the patient himself. The causative factor is easy if you go to the anamnesis.
The essentials is for you to clarify everything else, to trigger out and say, wait a moment.
The essentials here are these. What is happening with this organism is his stomach and his skin,
stomach and skin are affected.
I will give you an example going to Phosphorus again since we're studying the Phosphorus case.
I will give you an example of Phosphorus child.
It was a child of a couple of medical doctors who were studying
with me 20 years ago. They have a little daughter, she fell ill and she was prescribed several remedies, no effect.
And the pediatrician was called. He diagnosed encephalomyelitis and the child had high fever,
she had the stiffness in the neck and it was taken to hospital. By the time it was in the hospital,
they telephone me; they say well this is happening, the child is with encephalomyelitis
and would I come to see the child. I came to see the child and she had the typical symptoms of encephalomyelitis
and she was conscious but in semi-stupor.
Then the mother who described the case to me,
she gave me the symptoms, fever and pathological symptoms, I couldn't make nothing.
She described to me how this child was very courageous because she was punctured many times,
the doctors came to take blood, she wouldn't react at all, very courageous child.
I said, courageous? You see in my mind, it's a very strenuous time, you have to think fast because the child
is with fever there, what is going to do cortisone or no cortisone? You have to make very fast decisions.
And the mother, as I said, gave me no symptoms apart from the child being courageous. In my mind it didn't fit.
A child when it's punctured usually cries. And many times they took blood to examine,
puncture to get cerebral fluid and the
child didn't react at all. Very strange.
In the meantime the mother was sitting in the bed, holding the hand of the child. I said to the mother,
take out your hand from the child. The child
was in semi-stupor. She takes it away.
I said, hold again. She holds, she stops.
I said, take it out again. Hold again, stops.
Very good. I said, when do you want to be well, tonight or tomorrow? She was crying, are you joking?
No, I'm serious. Tonight or tomorrow? She said, it doesn't matter. I said, ok give her Phosphorus 10M.
Why? Because the child had such anxiety, such fear that the fear paralysed her and she could not react to the punctures.
The fear and the anxiety was so much that the puncture was not felt anymore and the desire for company
was so strong, that she wanted the
mother to hold her hand to feel secure.
These two symptoms, the anxiety and the desire to be held was so strong that it was pointing to Phosphorus.
This is observation for the essence of the case.
So they gave Phosphorus about 11 o'clock in the morning,
Phosphorus 10M. In the evening I said, call me in the evening to tell me how she is. In the evening the father calls.
He is also a Homeopath. He said, you know what? Do you know what she asked to eat?
The child had not eaten for 2 days. What did she ask to eat? Ice-cream. I said, go and buy her and give her ice-cream.
Next day by 11 o'clock again the fever was taking 39,5 high. They telephone, there is a relapse.
I said, 50M.
Give 50M. In the evening the child was well. The child has taken a lot of other remedies, don't forget, without effect, why?
Because the totality etc. What was missing? The mother was missing the whole picture of the child;
that the child was very anxious about her health.
She was hearing all kinds of activity, doctors. I'm dying.
They have such strong anxiety about their health, the Phosphorus cases, they are paralysed from fear.
And the child was under this condition.
So you are learning.
-I have not really understood the difference between essences and keynotes. The symptoms in the Phos case
were they essence symptoms or were they keynotes?
-Essence is referred mostly to mental-emotional picture in general. The mental-emotional make up
of the person in each pathology what it is? To be anxious with this kind of anxiety or that kind of anxiety,
to be irritable, to be aggressive, to be this or that. This is the essence.
Keynotes are symptoms, they can be mental, emotional also but physical as well.
Symptoms that this remedy has in particular. That means when you go to the Repertory and you look,
urination like yogurt, it comes out pieces of white matter, Phosphoric acid only.
This is the keynote for Phosphoric acid. So the person tells you he urinates this yogurt, you go to the Repertory
you see only Phosphoric acid, you better take it.
The keynote is when the child says, sleeps on knee-elbow position.
We used to have only one remedy Medorrhinum. Now we have some other remedies
also that we know they're sleeping in that position. And still I believe there are some more because
a lot of children are sleeping in that position. Not all of them are Medorrhinum but this is a keynote of Medorrhinum.
If the person cannot eat oyster, then is Phosphorus. It is a keynote for Phosphorus.
Let us define the keynotes more. A keynote is a strange, rare and peculiar or we need some more definition?
I will give you a strange, rare and peculiar. Anytime that somebody goes downstairs he has drops of urine coming out,
involuntary drops of urine. Try to find this.
This is a keynote mostly for Pulsatilla. Pulsatilla does not want to come out, she is very shy.
You see a few remedies are there. We have 2,3,4,6 remedies and one remedy is strong for that symptom,
peculiar symptom, then we say that Pulsatilla has a keynote which is involuntary urination while sitting.
It is not Causticum which you would expect because of paralyis of the bladder. It is Pulsatilla.
But involuntary urination while going downstairs, you search and search in all your Materia Medica and you cannot find.
Therefore in order to have a definition of the keynote you need to have the strange, rare and peculiar
plus that this symptom has been recorded in the provings. Otherwise you may have beautiful
strange, rare and peculiar symptoms and you cannot use them. Because they are not recorded in the Materia Medica,
not recorded in the Repertory and you
cannot find them and they are useless.
So the keynotes usually with which we work, have to have this element: strange, rare and peculiar and also
to be recorded in the Materia Medica and the Repertory as peculiar symptoms of very few or only one remedy.
So this is the definition of keynote. They have to be recorded by few remedies; few remedies will have that
because maybe what you think as strange, rare and peculiar, you go to the Repertory and this strange, rare and peculiar,
you see it has been recorded it has been produced by 100 remedies. It's not rare, so it is not a keynote
inspite of the fact it looks very strange to you.
In the Materia Medica is recorded by too many remedies; it's not a keynote.
Try to find malicious. You see, 150 remedies.
You think a person is malicious, very strange, rare and peculiar.
It is not. It is disappointing to see the picture of humanity in this rubric. God help us. Malicious.
Who is not malicious? So this is not strange, rare and peculiar. It's a common symptom.
Anac., Ars., Nat-m, Nux-v., Stram., where is Sepia, it's not there? Forget it.
Sepia in small.
Staph., Phos., Tub., Lach. should go higher to the third degree, Sep should go to the second degree.
But anyhow the maliciousness in each of these remedies has a color. It is different from one remedy to the other.
The maliciousness of Arsenicum is not the same as Stramonium. And the maliciousness of Tub is not the same as Sepia.
Each one has its own color.
It's very strange, rare and peculiar that a patient will tell you he is malicious. I've not heard it so far by any patient.
-So the keynote for the Pulsatilla here is for the case before and it's for five others.
-But Pulsatilla is only capital. Pulsatilla is sticking out and there are a few others. So, if the symptom is really strong,
then the first thing you are thinking is Pulsatilla.
So in your analysis there you have that symptom.
Let us say, you have here a case, where between other symptoms you have involuntary urination while sitting.
And Pulsatilla in the analysis here, comes with 6 symptoms. But with a strong keynote like this, you better prescribe Puls.
-If you have keynotes which are very specific for a certain remedy, are they then automatically in
the 3rd degree in the Repertory?
-No. There are keynotes which can be in the
first degree. What it means third degree?
Third degree in the Repertory has to do
with frequency and intensity in the provers.
And frequency and intensity in the patient as a clinical observation. That means a lot of provers have said,
clearly I have that symptom. That symptom goes and is registered as capital. If no other remedy has that symptom,
then it becomes a very important symptom.
If other remedies have been recorded but not so strongly,
then they will show other remedies there but
first or second degree, not capital.
But in the proving of a remedy where a lot of provers have said, yes while sitting I have loss urine,
then it becomes a strong symptom and it is recorded in the third degree in the Repertory.
Actually the recording on the Repertory is a matter of evaluating the information from the provers
and also evaluating finally that
information from the patients.
How many Pulsatilla patients are suffering with heat? A lot. It becomes strong, capital letter.
Pulsatilla, worse heat. How many Pulsatilla patients are ameliorated in the open air?
A lot. 80% of them. Capital. How many patients are losing urine while sitting from the Pulsatilla patients?
Not a lot but because this is a strange, rare and peculiar symptom and it is recorded out of 100 Pulsatillas,
it is recorded in 10,12 cases, then
it becomes a strong keynote.
-George I'm utterly confused because before you said, the essences are recorded by observation
and the keynotes by the patient. And after you said, the rare, strange and peculiar with the example
of malicious will not probably be said
by the patient, so there is a distinction.
-No. I said, strange, rare and peculiar it seems to be the malicious. Yet it is not strange, rare and peculiar.
It is common to many remedies. That's one.
And in this case we were not taking about a keynote.
Usually the keynotes are recorded by the patient but we said, we have three sources of information.
The patient, the relatives, the physician. So the essence usually it is an observation of the physician,
an observation of the relatives, of others. The person himself, for instance Nux vomica is very irritable.
I just give you an example. I was examining a professor of surgery with severe, chronic headaches.
And I had next to me George Papaphilippou who is a surgeon but he is a Homeopath now.
He studied with him, he was in the operation table with this professor. He brought me his professor to look at him.
I see a very nice professor who sits very calm. He is very obese, very calm and very nice.
He gives me symptoms of the headaches only and I cannot make out anything. I try this and that, no, normal...
But I get finally the idea, maybe this is a
Nux vomica case. But he looks so calm.
So I put the question to him, are you
irritable? He said, no.
And then George underneath kicks me. You got it. I said, what I mean is you don't shout, he never shouted
but inside him if somebody was giving
him the wrong tool, immediately ....
But the others would notice it. So George working with him had notice that actually was very angry and very irritable.
He, himself said no because he did not express his anger, he did not express his irritability.
So on that information I prescribed Nux vomica and the headaches were beautifully cured.
-This is a question about theory. Let's say you have a case where the totality of the symptoms leads you
to a clear remedy but the essence is in contradiction, is this a possible case and what do you do?
-You give the totality first. It fails, then you
go as a second idea to the essence.
Essence is something that comes from experience and it is very difficult to be transferred.
I transfer you an impression. I'm not sure that always I transfer the right impression, correct?
So when you see the real thing, I say this is Ambra grisea you say 'I thought this'. That's why
I say,
first totality, if you have clear totality
you give it. Then you go to essence.
Essentials is more easy. Facts. Essence I'm describing the soul, something intangible.
My experience, not your experience yet; until you see the real case, you prescribe the remedy.
I receive letters from students saying, it was great I gave a dose of Agaricus and it acted beautifully on essence.
That person means he got the essence. But I'm not sure everybody is getting the essence really from what I say.
- Would you take the essence?
-Leave my case out because I will take what experience has shown me I should take at the moment.
Not always also. I will read to you a case in London. I was in London and I was presented a case
without any essence, without any general symptoms, only some pathology.
I prescribed on pathology, I prescribed on the essentials, what I feel he had the essential features of that remedy.
In September we talked about when a patient receives a remedy which is not the correct one, that he then
develops proving symptoms. That means he has these proving symptoms plus his own symptoms.
And you said, if we then repertorise again we must not take the new symptoms he has developed into
consideration. But in the Organon, Hahnemann says, one should include the new symptoms
in the repertorisation when one
looks for a new remedy.
-First of all not every time that you give a wrong remedy you have provings of this remedy, that's one.
Because you gave the impression that I have said, every time you give a wrong remedy there is proving.
In some cases you will have proving symptoms of the remedy you gave plus the symptoms of the patient.
And I say, in such a case you go back to the original case restudy and give another remedy.
This is different than you give a remedy and the remedy is not the correct or we don't know yet if it is the correct or not
and changes some of the symptoms of the case without curing the case. That is a different case in which
you have now to take the new symptoms which have developed, into consideration. And only them.
You see the difference?
-No.
-You have a case and it has these symptoms. And you give a wrong remedy but it produces certain symptoms
of the remedy you gave. These are the new symptoms it produces without changing this.
What you have to do in such a case is that you go back to the original case and try to find another remedy that fits that picture.
We go now to another case, number 2. Where you have the same picture and you gave a remedy
that has not cured the case but has
changed the case, how? Like this.
It has changed the case to this. He even has a symptom which is more bothering now, more strong
but some of the other symptoms have disappeared, some have changed.
Now in such a case you have to study this picture, and give a second remedy.
Here is another remedy.
You give this remedy you ignore this part and you go back to the original case, you study and you give another remedy.
-I have another question concering this. Some people give like 7C every day and then
even if you give the right remedy after a while the patient starts taking out new symptoms of this remedy
you gave him. Then sometimes you get a bit mixed up because you don't know if it was ok,
if it was a proving, I want to be clear in that.
-I'm also mixed up with the question.
Forget the paragraph. The example.
-A person comes to the Homeopath. He decides that he has to give him every day 9C of a certain remedy.
-Wrong remedy?
-No, right remedy. That's the treatment he wants him to take. The first month everything is fine.
The second month everything is fine and then suddenly he starts taking out symptoms of this remedy like a proving.
-Yes it is correct. This is going to happen. If you continue inspite of the fact that the person is well,
you continue to give every day the same remedy, you are going to cause some proving.
So eventually this person is going to develop symptoms of the remedy you are repeating.
Not always.
There are many cases where you repeat with no effect. But some cases where there is some sensitivity there,
definitely you are going to see
symptoms of the remedy appearing.
-So that means if I understood you correctly, the second example that you drew on the board, is in cases where
I give similar remedy but not the most similar, similar but not similimum, correct?
-Not only that. But if she goes on with this logic, it's going to go wrong. Let me clarify this situation here, what happens.
A remedy has changed the picture. The original picture has changed by a remedy. That does not mean that the remedy is incorrect.
It means that this case needs a series of remedies. One, two, three, perhaps four remedies.
In such a case you have changes all
along as the person goes towards cure.
-One question about the first case. If there are proving symptoms, that means that the patient is sensitive?
-That means it is close. That is unfortunate. What happened here is not good. It is unfortunate.
What is happening here is correct.
There is no other way.
-Yes but I think if he is sensitive there would be a change. If there are other symptoms, if the symptoms
have changed, the disease has changed or the answer has perhaps changed too. It might be better
to wait until the proving symptoms disappear.
-This is even better. If you can't wait, it depends on the case, if it is urgent case, you have to give something.
If it is not urgent then the best is to wait
and the proving symptoms will subside.
And it is good also in such a case if either you allow coffee to drink or if it is something urgent you treat it allopathically.
The allopathic medication will bring you back to the original case. As long as it's not too heavy.
Allopathically of course you can cause damage quite a lot but in such case where we fail.
This is what happens actually naturally. The doctor will say, you are not responding to homeopathic remedies.
It's a nice way to say 'I failed to find the remedy. Your organism is not responding to homeopathic remedies'
it's a good excuse, if you want that excuse you can use it. But for yourself you have to know the fact.
Therefore take some pain killers or whatever. Try to avoid cortisone as much as possible.
Cortisone is such a deep drug that can change the whole picture and can leave you without symptoms.
Then we'll see afterwards what we can do. Then the original case returns and then you restudy the case
and you see the original and then you give it.
Hahnemann was not facing such problems as we did and we do. What they used to do is put leeches
to draw blood and to put cataplasms and superficial things that did not change the
organism in a deep manner as the
drugs that we have today.
So his observations are according to his experience of course. These observations are from our experience.
In Hahnemann's time they did not have so weakened constitutions that we have today
that need a series of remedies
before they can just survive.
-I wish to ask you something practical.
I had a patient who came to me because of hypothyroidism
and I gave her Medorrhinum and she felt much better. But nothing changed about hypothyroidism
and she needed more and more thyroxine till 150. I thought that maybe it can be Causticum.
I give her Causticum and this time she developed Causticum symptoms and the internist told her
that the doses of thyroxine is too high. Then he needed to put it down and I wish to ask you what happened here.
I thought Causticum was the right remedy, the thyroid gland began to work and the doses of thyroxine were too high.
-Let me understand. The thyroxine which was given by the internist was too high after Causticum
and then she had to reduce the dose. That is correct. That means Causticum was helping the patient produce
more thyroxine herself and she needed less from outside. That means Causticum was acting curatively in this case.
-They were really Causticum symptoms.
It was like proving of Causticum.
-We have said in the first session, that when we give a remedy and the remedy acts curatively that means
improves the general state of the patient and at the same time produces some of its own symptoms,
that is a proof that the remedy is correct.
If the remedy does not change anything  here and produces some of its own symptoms, then we have a proving.
When the remedy changes 1 or 2 symptoms without bringing any essential change in the state,
we have again a proving with a remedy
that was very close to the case.
In such cases, this and that, where we have given a close remedy, we have to wait
until this is the right answer, we have to wait
until the proving symptoms are gone.
-Another question to the proving symptoms,
your first example on the board.
When the patient suddenly develops diarrhea,
is also a proving symptom?
-You give a remedy and he gets diarrhea.
-Most probably diarrhea is because
he ate something wrong. -No.
-What about the discharge reactions after taking a remedy? Are they also part of proving or not?
-Discharge from the vagina, leukorrhea. You give a remedy and you have discharge from the vagina
or discharge from the nose. This is a good symptom, a curative symptom. It's not a proving.
-Does it mean all discharges are good symptoms and are a proof of a curative effect?
-The reaction of an organism is taken as a whole. What you evaluate is the total reaction of the patient.
If the total reaction says, this person is going towards cure because he is better, better
and he has some diarrhea, diarrhea is good.
Discharge from the nose is good. Discharge
from the skin is good.
But if you say, the person is getting worse,
he has diarrhea, he has blood in the stool,
you give a remedy and the blood is coming out
then that is an aggravation which most probably is the wrong remedy.
You cannot say in general discharges are good.
Depending on the whole attitude of the case.
The child we say, the remedy is correct
because it shows an improvement.
Has the child become well with this remedy? No. It shows an improvement, mental-emotional, in the fever,
in the appetite but still needs a second remedy.
What is the second remedy? We study the new symptoms and then we prescribe the new remedy.
-I had a similar problem. I had a manager who was in a very high position and was really worn out,
he was close to a heart attack. He was really washed out. He came and I took his case and then I gave him Pulsatilla.
Then after 4-5 months when he felt really relieved and beautifully to look at and really relaxed,
he came back. He had little problem with rhythm but this was small, it was solved with allopathic drug very easily.
When he came back he said he has serious problems with the people he worked for, because
he was not interested in this work anymore.
He was 57 and he had 3 years to go.
Then what could I say? Shoud I say drink
coffee or stop the job. I said, stop the job.
-No, neither. You encourage this person.
I mean 57 he works for 40 years most probably.
If he works for another 3 years is not such a big deal. I would say, I encourage him to work.
I have swear that I'm going to stop teaching, working a long time ago. I had enough, exausted,
I go back home, my wife says, 'why you kill yourself'. And then I say, ok let's see another 3 more years and I'm 65.
-It's because you love your job.
-I'm not sure.
-I still am not clear about this case from Marion because the Causticum improved the case
so the thyroid is working better. But what if the woman develops Causticum symptoms.
He said, she developed Causticum symptoms and now she has involuntary urination for example.
If the Causticum is working but produces
really very bad symptoms?
-Of course this question is because we have not completed the theory in Homeopathy and we shall be completing it.
I want to give you another idea. Talking in hypothetical cases is very difficult for me to answer
because I have to know all the parameters before I can answer specific question to specific cases.
But as a general rule, I want to tell you this. You start treatment with a child who is quite disturbed mentally
and the parents come. It is restless, it has that symptom etc. They complain of undefined symptoms,
you can't say the child is really mentally ill.
But it's not really balanced in mental-emotional level.
And you start a treatment with such a child.
This child you are going to have a lot of problems
as you improve his health. With what? With acute conditions mostly and chronic conditions on the physical level.
As you improve the mental-emotional level then the child starts getting colds easily, getting this, that,
pains in the stomach, in the guts, then you really have a problem. You cannot say these problems are
because of the proving of the remedy. It's because of the improvement of the organism which comes on another level.
It goes away the disturbance from the mental-emotional and comes to the physical.
The organism does not have the possibility to bring it straight to the skin and then it battles within the physical body.
And then you will get a lot of problems with such children. But once you bring them alone, when they grow up
and they become strong and you really feel that you have done something finally. But all along you have a lot of problems.
So if you give me a specific case, bring me the whole case, give me all the details and then
I will give you the answer,
whether this is this or that.