One of the greatest things which I broke, it was a rule in Greece very strict rule.
That nobody who is not a medical doctor is not allowed to practice Medicine.
I broke this rule for the past 32 years.
Another rule I've broken or it appears that I've broken is from this book
which is called the Organon of the Art of Healing,
from which I want to read to you with your tolerance.
I know most of you, you have read the Organon very carefully and some of you,
you may know it almost by heart.
I also had read the Organon with great interest in the very beginning,
with the greatest interest and the greatest sympathy for what was written there,
everything was appealing to me.
And I remember by that time I was reading par. 18 for instance,
which says from the undeniable truth that besides the totality of the symptoms
nothing else can by any means be discovered in diseases,
we are with they could express their need of aid of cure.
It is only the totality of the symptoms that expresses the need of the disease to be cured.
This is correct, it is clear. It follows undeniably without any doubt
that the totality of all the symptoms of the disease
and conditions in each individual case must be the only indication,
the soul guide to direct us in the choice of the remedy.
On this par. was based a whole homeopathic movement,
what we call today the Unicist movement.
Everyone by that time that I studied Homeopathy, everyone around,
in all the books, everywhere I would see search for the totality of the symptoms.
And then find the remedy that fits to that totality.
I will read you something now which will not agree with that statement and you will be surprised
and all my teaching has been based on what I found in practice.
In practice I found that this statement was not absolute, it was relative,
to what degree we shall see and I'm sure that almost nobody because myself also
when I read through the Organon, I did not pick up the discrepancies,
the points that were appearing to oppose each other and I was taken over by the general mood,
the totality of the symptoms and then it was a day where I decided I'll break this rule.
It is not the totality of the symptoms, it is something else and what was the other?
Then I brought my experience into Homeopathy and I'll tell you in brief what was my experience.
But before I go further, I want to read to you another paragraph from the Organon.
Listen to that. It says in another paragraph, I will not tell you which one, it's very interesting.
In this search for the homeopathic specific remedy, it says,
in your efforts to find the specific remedy which is indicated,
which means in the comparison you are making between the totality of the symptoms
of the disease with the least of symptoms in a proving, in this comparison you are making,
in order to find between these remedies, these provings an artificial agent
corresponding by similarity to the disease to be cured the more striking, singular,
uncommon and peculiar characteristics, signs and symptoms are exclusively to be kept in view.
Most solely, exclusively, do not pay any other attention but to what is striking, singular,
uncommon, peculiar. Where is the totality of the symptoms?
Because our subject on which I'm going to talk this time, it is how we select a symptom.
Why we take this symptom and not another? Why do we ignore certain symptoms?
In a case in practice you will have to ignore symptoms of the case.
So what it says for it is more particularly these very similar ones
in the list of symptoms of the selected medicine must correspond to,
in order to constitute the most suitable remedy for affecting the cure.
It is these peculiar remedies that must correspond to the peculiarity of the remedy.
And continues to say that the more general symptoms and undefined symptoms
and he gives examples like loss of appetite, headache, debility, weakness, restlessness,
discomfort and so forth demand but little attention from you.
So I had broken the rule of the totality of the symptoms and in my teaching, as you may know,
I have said that what has to be taken into consideration is first the essence,
the second is the totality, the third are the keynotes and the fourth is the causative factor.
I remember presenting my ideas of one remedy, that one remedy has to be found,
that there is a remedy which we have to find in order to complete a cure
and a doctor from France got up in Congress and says George's ideas are so nice
but this is a utopia.
Nobody ever can find one remedy that will cure a case. I'm talking about 10-15 years ago.
Why? Because in his experience this has never happened and I accept that
and in his experience he has seen that giving 3,4,5 remedies that was bringing some effect.
So this was his experience and I accept that but he got up and said this is a utopia,
what this man is talking in front of the class. And then I thought they think it's a utopia!
A utopia for me that was a total reality
because I had been treating with 20-30 medical doctors in Athens,
I had been treating thousands and thousands and thousands of cases
prescribing all the time one remedy, now this man gets up and says this is utopia.
I said to myself, well there is a big gap between our understanding
where they are missing some information these people.
And what kind of information they are missing in order to be able to do a better job?
And that was my anguish and my thinking during these years, what shall I do
in order to give enough information so they can do the same.
I would have seen that my students in Greece they could do it, they could repeat
what my thinking was and they could analyze a case and they could have results,
why not the others?
And then the idea of the videos came about. Because I said to myself
unless I show them really on a video I can present, then maybe they will continue saying
this is not so, this is not so, it's his imagination.
But what about breaking the rules of the totality?
Because I remember when I first came and taught in America, well they said where is the totality?
I said, where is the totality? I also don't see that a remedy can cover all the symptoms in a case.
But in the Organon also which paragraph was right? Paragraph 18 or paragraph 153?
Which of the 2 paragraphs was right? I want your feedback on that. What happened?
Well the most obvious answer is both are right but therefore we can not take any of them
in an absolute spirit.
The moment that your mind sticks on the totality of the symptoms and you try to find a remedy
that has 22 symptoms, the symptoms of the patient, then you may not be able ever
to fit a remedy to that patient.
But there are sometimes where you can fit 18 out of 22 symptoms to a remedy,
there you have the totality perhaps.
But in which cases you have the totality and in which cases you have the essence
and what do we mean by essence?
And what do we mean by the keynotes? What is a keynote?
Do you know what is a keynote in practical terms? Tell me what is a keynote.
A symptom that you will find very frequently with the prover. Do you agree with that?
I will give you an example.
For instance if you take Belladonna, you will have a face which is flushed. Is this a keynote?
Some they say no and some they say yes, now where is the truth?
We like to clarify these matters in order to be able to have a clear judgment,
what we are doing in analyzing a case? Where we'll put our focus of attention?
A keynote is something that does not fit the rules, the rules of pathology let us say,
all the rules, the common symptomatology of the diseases.
A keynote is a symptom that can be peculiar to only one remedy.
So we have to combine two factors here. The one factor is whether a symptom is produced
almost always in a person and the other factor in order for this symptom to become a keynote,
to be characterized as a keynote, the other factor should be that no other remedy
has that particular symptom. The more the rule is like this, the more we have a real keynote.
And we can prescribe on a keynote.
If you open your Repertory and you will see in a symptom 1 or 2 remedies covering that symptom,
there do you have a keynote?
-Not necessarily.
-Why?
The frequency of the appearance in the proving has also to be strong.
So if we have a peculiar symptom which is really strong in the proving
but no many remedies have that symptom, then that becomes a strong keynote.
So in paragraph 153 Hahnemann talks about keynotes and he talks about keynote
prescribing. But as you said we can not ignore par. 18 where he talks about totality.
So therefore we have to make a combination between par. 153 and 18
and when we prescribe pay attention, not only to the keynotes but to the totality as well
or to the combination of the two.
And what is essence? This idea which I brought into Homeopathy.
Because there was a misunderstanding on that as well.
When I spoke about essences everybody came out later and they said, well forget totality,
forget the keynotes, you can only prescribe successfully
if you know the essence of the remedy.
I never have said this.
What I have said it was a different thing.
What is the essence, has anybody understood by reading some of the stolen Materia Medica,
whatever you call it.
If you know this little book which was notes of one of my students and eventually was published,
what I was describing in essences.
Not intuition, I don't want intuition. This is a science, we try to reduce it actually to a science,
it is a science and we have to present it as a science and nothing else.
Otherwise we will be totally lost if we bring in the factor of intuition.
Anybody can say my intuition says give this remedy. My intuition says give the other remedy
and you will have 100 intuitions and a dead person.
So I never said intuition myself.
-It's a deep understanding of the personality of the remedy on the physical,
the mental and the emotional levels.
-The understanding of the personality of the remedy.
When you say personality, can you say his personality
and his personality are the same? Never.
Two people are ever the same? No. So when you are talking about essence,
you are talking again about the most striking, uncommon characteristics of a case
in another level, not the physical level but the psychological, the mental level.
So here we have keynotes on a psychological and mental level combined in such a way
as the total effect to be given as the personality of the remedy.
And what is your experience and my experience
and the experience of anybody practicing homeopathic medicine, what is it?
That sometimes you have prescribed, a remedy has acted based on one keynote or two keynotes
and sometimes you have prescribed a remedy based on essence and you have success
and sometimes you are based on totality and you have success and some other times
your prescription is actually a combination of all these four factors.
Because you see some kind of essence which fits with mostly on his totality
which contains a few keynotes and contains also the causative factor
and then you have a perfect case and then you say my god this is a Natrum muriaticum case,
you can not prescribe something else.
Is it possible to put this idea into practice? It is possible.
Can you show us in these three days that you will be staying with us,
can you show us how to do it? Is it possible?
No, it's not possible but the possibility is there, if you want really to learn that.
There is a possibility to learn but you have to stay with me or with my teaching much longer.
It's not possible in three days to point out to you all the phenomena,
all the parameters that go along to find the correct remedy in a case.
In the cases I'm going to present you I will focus always in these ideas and I will ask you
so together we can proceed in understanding my thinking, because I believe that's why you are here.
You have come to understand what is the structure of my thinking, why I give this remedy
and not another? What do I do different between my judgment and your judgment?
What is the difference and then inside you, you say I judge it differently?
And then see the effect. What is the effect? Oh he is right.
Because he usually brings cases which have been treated successfully.
So if I bring you a case that means I'm right.
When I give you an explanation I will prove it to you that it is right because of the effect.
Do you know the difference between somebody presenting a case and myself?
There is a difference.
For the last 15-20 years and actually all my life, due to the fact
that I always had the urge to teach and then I felt this is tremendous thing,
everybody has to know it, there were always around students. So I could never tell a lie.
I'm not alone in my room. How you are and things like that, no.
I'm not good, I'm the same, no problem out. Oh I'm so good.
Film it, we film it and then we take it, we present it to you and say, here it is, big case.
No, not with me.
Because in the last years actually all my cases were been able to be seen by the students,
so if I ever made a mistake it would be immediately seen
because they say they came year after year, in the seminars in Germany.
I would take cases, I would treat and everybody would see and all my cases
were shown the results of my prescribing.
They were not brought into a class selectively, there is a big difference
and I don't think there are many people have this courage, this takes a lot of courage.
That's why I got old very soon. I'm only 45 and I look 60, it is because of that reason.
Because you are very anxious, the situation in which you are put together says,
here is a case, we bring a pneumonia case, today she will die.
Now what you do, show us because you talk to us and you say you treat pneumonia.
Show us, here is a case of pneumonia, how you will treat that? That's different.
Then you start the excuses, not this kind of pneumonia. This is progressed pneumonia.
Actually they have prescribed another remedy, so they spoiled the case
so I can not find the remedy, lots of excuses.
There is one characteristic of my teaching. I never, ever in any case I excuse myself.
Here, he is dying, treat it. Here, another one, treat it. I never said
but you prescribed half of the Materia Medica in that case,
how do you expect me to treat that case?
I never said it. So was this a utopia?
What I was seen, what I was perceiving was a utopia? I don't think so.
Who was in NY seminar? Sixteen.
As I said to that seminar, I will repeat quickly.
For a symptom you need to know the intensity of the symptom, how strongly is felt by the patient
because that will be expressed immediately.
He says, oh my hip joint. I also have a pain in my hip joint and
I also sometimes on the wrist. He puts it first there and then there on the wrist,
it's different. When it is vague, forget it.
When George comes and says these things, they say Hahnemann said different things.
He didn't say different things. The experience was the same.
I'm absolutely sure and that's why I forgot about totality and he says forget it.
I mean there is a reality here. Let's see what is the reality.
This, this and that is the reality and then I went back and read the Organon and I said,
oh my god he has the same experience.
He has said the same things because he has said, totality only exclusively totality,
search for the totality and nothing else and on the other hand he says, forget the totality,
go to the keynotes, go to the peculiar characteristics. So intensity...
If a person says to you that in your search for the right remedy, a person tells you that last year,
because you asked about last year, the previous year, you want a full case
and he says the last year I have a very severe stitch on my hip.
Now this person has come for epilepsy, you are searching and he says last year
I had a very severe stitching pain in my right hip joint, would you take it into consideration,
yes or no? Practical matters.
Do you have this stitching pain, do you still have it? He says, no.
How frequently you have it? Oh just once. It was severe? It was very severe.
For how long it lasted? About half a minute. Because he wants to give you some information.
Last year for half a minute you had this and then you take it into consideration
and you are going to prescribe in a case of epilepsy, when there is pains in the hip joints
this is combined.
Which is the remedy that will come to your mind?
Because I have never said this before so nobody can bring the answer.
In a case of epilepsy where hip joints also are affected there are two areas of sensitivity
to that person where the most probable remedy is Natrum sulphuricum.
And if you ask him whether the epilepsy has started after an injury,
then it becomes really the remedy. Why? Because Nat sulphuricum has an affinity for the hip joints.
It affects very frequently the hip joints.
A few years ago, I think 85 or 84, I was teaching in Berkley, I was telling the other day
that it is the only place in the world where insane people are loose and running around.
So my wife and myself we went out in the streets and in every corner we'll see somebody shout
and making noise and sleep and undressing. In every corner it was somebody.
My wife says what's happening here?
And then I had to enquire and they said in Berkley there are no insane asylums
and that would be great if the whole world acted like this
because everybody would be able to see really what is going on with the diseases of today,
who is insane and how much take all away all the sedatives
and let loose all these 5.000.000 of people
and then let us here about the very high quality of medical services of the West.
Because it's in the West, the others are loose in any case.
They do not have asylums, they do not have the possibility to take all the sedatives.
So if there is somebody insane is out.
But you don't see this phenomenon. So what happened? All this is driven inside.
The diseases driven inside into the deepest recesses.
So I was there in that place, it was amazing, it was a culture shock,
they would call it George has a culture shock, ah he will get used and all these kind of things.
But I was in that place, I was teaching and they said, we have a case that is quite severe
and he is in a hospital, he is a child with cerebellitis,
inflammation of the cerebellum after varicella.
And would you like to see, you know how they put it? Would you like to see?
And my answer always is, I never like to see anybody.
If you bring it to me I will see it and I may even do something
but to like to see a paralyzed child who just comes from the hospital in front of the class,
I do not like to see. But anyhow, as I said, I never objected.
I said OK, bring the child and I will now show you certain things in this case.
You see there are a lot of theories in Homeopathy. It says drainage, it's one theory.
Another theory is treat first the pathology, the real pathology and then
go for the constitutional remedy.
Another theory is you give first all the nosodes, Tuberculinum, Syphilinum, Medorrhinum,
you give all, clear up the ground and the patient and then go to the constitutional remedy.
And there is success.
These people who claim all these things, they claim successes as well.
What we are talking here and what I feel for Homeopathy which is unjust
is that all these people they claim success but when you come and see all their patients
what is the totality of the result, that is very poor.
The one or the second case that was presented where I gave Tuberculinum,
Syphilinum, Medorrhinum, Bacillinum and did well, these cases are very few.
So we are talking about professional people who are healing others in every day basis.
Every day you have to see 10-12 cases and you have to have results.
In 10 of them out or 12 to be professional.
Ten of them must come back and Bill Gray who is here, he came and he tested.
He said I would like to sit with you next to you when you see the case
and I will enquire the patient how do you feel and I will get the answer.
So there are people who were treated a month ago, two months ago and Bill Gray
was sitting there and said, how do you feel and said, much better, much better.
He said, I'm too bored George I'm going. The answers are too boring, it's much better
and I know it and this is the idea of the professional.
Much better in a boring manner, to get bored.
Of course the cases I would see by that time they were first cases,
they were not the most difficult cases, they were not the kind of cases I have to see now.
Because now what is ending up to me is everything else,
where everybody else has not succeeded and so they bring to me and say, treat.
So I would like to see all these theories applied in these kind of cases
and then I would respect very much.
Not only but I have brought you cases to show you, where I have prescribed more than one remedy,
to show you in what kind of cases maybe you are justified to go to another remedy,
like Boericke perhaps or some others I don't think they would see cases like the ones
that we see today, these people of the old times.
Cases were much more easy during that time.