As we have 3 levels, we have the spiritual,
the psychic and we have the physical level.
We are concentrating on the death of the physical body and we say serious!
What about the death of the spiritual level
and the death of the psychic level?
A death here is more serious than this
death; it's very strange but it is true.
A death here is very very serious.
So what do I mean by death on the
spiritual level? You'll be surprised.
If the establishment hears me talking,
they will kill me.
Nobody of you belongs to the establishment.
The cases that are spiritually dead,
that means a person who has lost
all kind of principles, values in life,
spiritual values, he says
it doesn't matter, kill him it's nothing
or steel his money.
These people are preparing and eventually
go into a stage of mental derangement.
Then you see the death behind it.
There is nothing that moves such
an individual. It's finished.
Unfortunately, the death of the psychic level
may happen with the younger generations.
They break all the rules. The rule is that
you drink clean water, it's one rule,
you eat clean food, you breathe clean air.
If you break all these physical rules
then you have physical death, finished.
Here there are rules as well, if you break
them you're finished at this level.
What are the rules here? What are
the rules on the psychic level?
Who wants to answer this question?
-That you have clean thoughts
that you think in a positive way.
-No, I mean on psychic level, feelings.
-A hardening of the feelings.
-Yes but what are the rules that if you break them, then you have hardening of the feelings.
-You should not hurt yourself or others.
-A certain respect to nature
of human beings.
-Hatred.
-I would say it starts with love for myself,
if I can love myself I can also
love others and be compassionate.
-The emotions which foster community
should always be the overruling ones.
-Awareness and compassion
for the surrounding.
-You said correct things but as you may
realize also, this is a tricky subject,
it's a sensitive subject. And you have
in front of you a boy or a girl,
how would you advise them, what
advice would you give them as healers
so they can protect themselves
from becoming dead
on the psychic level,
on the level of feelings.
We are interested to find the rules how
a society should raise their children
in order to be healthy on that level.
This is actually the subject we are
talking about and you as healers
and me as a healer, we are concerned
with this issue.This is a very serious issue.
-Not TV I would say.
- I think you are very curious about our opinion but we are also curious about your opinion.
-It's very important for me when
I discuss such matters.
It's very important to receive the
opinion of the society
what is happening outside of me, right?
Because maybe I have some ideas
which are far away from the society and if
I give you these ideas nobody will notice.
So I have to adapt my ideas, if it is possible,
to your ideas, so they can be useful.
Otherwise if I tell you certain rules and
nobody can follow, there is no meaning.
What I have found out, you see always
when I talk, I talk from experience,
not from fantasy, theorising or
any kind of speculation.
I talk from experience and what
I have seen is this:
As you know I've lived in India and I've lived in a time when India was not so much modernized.
I don't know if today India starts
to get modern. By 1963-64-65,
what I found out in the difference of
feelings between Western population
and Indian population was something very prominent, very amazing and very obvious.
The feelings of the Indian people
were alive; they were alive people,
with a lot of physical diseases but their feelings, feelings of love that could come easily out,
were very alive. I could see them between
them, interacting, friends with friends.
And in India there are some rules
concerning the feelings of young people.
And the rules are that you have to
get married before you can have this
ultimate joy which is having a partner
and sharing with this partner that joy.
We call it sex in the West. And I thought that maybe these people here are more right.
The society has remained on
psychological level, on a psychic level
more healthy than our society which has
so much progress and so much freedom.
So there are some rules. They had
some rules that they respected.
We, in the West,
are breaking all the rules.
All these ancient rules that ancient societies
have established in order to keep a balance
in the psychological level, we are breaking
all these rules, one after the other.
So the young population of today they are
acting prematurely for a level that has not
come, they are acting the child of 14 or 15
starting having sex is acting like a man of 25.
So if you do something which is
premature you cannot enjoy
because you don't know
the value of that.
Another observation: I saw couples
that they were married and had sex
for the first time, they never separate.
All the other couples that have experiences especially if both parties have
sexual experiences, then the most
probable is that they will separate.
What keeps the one and what keeps the other?
If you try to find the reason why people
are separating you will find that
it's the sickness of the
emotional level actually.
She says, I don't enjoy, I like this man.
You know this idea has come into our minds,
we can enjoy, we can have anything
we like, and in this pursue of enjoyment,
we lost enjoyment. So the younger
people, a lot of younger people
will come and they're acting as
if they have lived through everything.
They are 22 and nothing matters anymore.
They have sex, they have drugs,
they have pleasure,
so what is left for them?
Especially children from rich families and
these are the victims of our society.
The victims of good life and the victims
of effluence in the society.
I had advised my students very
long time ago. I said to them,
with Homeopathy you make
easy money, you live easily because
I will teach you something which is
very valuable and you will have money.
But don't ever let your children
know that you have money
and you can buy for them this and that.
Because you are going to spoil your children
and they are finished. Give them the
impression that if they have to win something
they have to work for that and then they will become good children, useful and creative.
Now, some of them have problems, they did
not listen or they could not apply these rules.
You will say, would you
concentrate in the idea of sex?
These are the feelings. The feelings
are activated in relationships.
Somebody said, you have to
have a relationship? Of course.
If you withdraw from society, again you can
be killing yourself but not as much as
when you are breaking
the rules on the other hand,
just becoming loose and
do whatever you like.
It is a society which we break
rules and then what?
And of course many things of what you
said are correct. If you want your children
to be influenced you have to be an
example. There is no question about that.
You cannot theorize and tell your children
this and that and then the children see
that you are doing the opposite.
But you, as healers, have to understand
what makes somebody healthy.
They come to you, young boys and girls, and
you say, please wait you will enjoy later on.
Don't be in a hurry. You will see
later on - yes but I like him.
Ok, you like him, be just friends, keep
your emotions, keep the mystery.
Forget it, because the children are
already influencing one another,
they go their own ways, totally out of
control from the parents. It doesn't' matter.
You still say, this is correct,
you follow.
The whole society is doing like this.
My children will be different?
Yes your children can be different
and can be very nice.
You see the purity which has to
go together up to a certain stage;
the purity is homogeneous with God.
You see, the children who are pure,
their eyes look like angels.
And sometimes you see some grown ups.
You see the purity is there. And you say, she
has not broken the rules. She still has purity.
I will tell you something now which
looks religious but it is not.
You go back to the history of religion
where it says, Adam and Eve were nude
and lived in the paradise.
And suddenly the snake told them,
eat from the tree of the
knowledge of good and bad.
Once they ate from the tree of good
and bad, they've put clothes.
That means they became conscious
of separation between sexes.
I am different sex than this one;
therefore I have to have shame.
The purity was lost. I believe the society
in the future will establish itself some rules
that children will follow. That they cannot
have sexual intercourse until they are 21.
Children are to play, play soccer, football,
then they start to play with computer, etc.
Each age has its own pleasures.
You cannot have a child of 12 taking
drugs and having the pleasure of drugs. And
then these people come to us to be treated.
I look at the eyes of these young
people and they are dead on this level.
Forget it. You know how difficult
is to cure these people?
Do you know how complicated
are these cases?
If the conscience of the child is
suppressed and says, it doesn't matter.
Some people advise their children
and say, you have to survive,
it doesn't matter if you
step over the dead body of others.
The children say, do I have to do that?
And eventually they do it, of course.
And they come to us, cure me, cure me.
How can I cure you?
It's very difficult to revive this than revive this one, the physical level I can revive more easily.
But if they are dead in here, forget it. You need 20 remedies before you can revive this.
I have spoken about Sepia or I don't know maybe we'll speak about Sepia.
Sepia people sometimes if they go for spiritual truth or attainment, do you know what they do?
They kill themselves in the process of
seeking spiritual enlightenment.
That means they suppress their
emotions in order to find an outlet.
First you can't hear and you break the
rules and you're unhappy.
Once you're unhappy, then you seek
happiness. Where is happiness?
Only in God, let's see who is God.
God is guru. You go to the guru.
The guru says detach and the Sepia
is ready for detachment because
he has not sexual desire. Detaches
until the feelings are almost dead.
Then they go like this, they are alive
without meaning. Then they come to you
because they have problem and
you see a dead person spiritually
and in psychic and the body
just moving around.
Try to treat these cases,
because we have Sepia.
If they are lucky, they start reviving but
then you need a lot of treatment
before you can revive these levels.
-I find that this problem is not only
a problem of parents and society
but also a problem of babies and
small children. Once they get sick,
they treated allopathically, they are suppressed on the emotional level and their soul gets broken.
-Absolutely but here is the same
problem. We have a society that
does not care about mental, emotional,
spiritual. We have a society that sees
only the body. Take cortisone,
but what happens after? Correct.
Also correct is the fact that we have
genetic predispositions.
Now we have genetic predisposition for madness, for indifference, for depression.
So the baby comes and it's depressed or
the child is depressed at the age of 7,8,9.
They have anxieties, fears, fear of dying,
they have hypochondriasis, the children of 8.
They are finished, they cannot
enjoy anymore anything.
Here if you have pains and still
you can enjoy if the soul is alive.
Here is the enjoyment, not here.
-I think we should start a little earlier than
the sexual reasons only, because I think
we have to start even with the parents.
We are very thoroughly destroyed already.
I don't know if it's only by drugs.
I think it's because we have
the wrong values ourselves.
We are very split in what we want. We don't know. I don't know if I can give children
new values because I'm looking for
them myself and if this was not true,
we would not need desperately
the Homeopathic treatment.
Through all the societies I've seen so far is always the problem with the material things.
It starts with the US...we cannot give new
values of this kind to children.
I think we should start much earlier
to make all the 3 levels come together.
That means not like in Cuba that take
the children from the parents when
they are 7 and work  with them politically, for special reasons, that also destroys them.
But we have a problem in giving them emotional warmth. And you can see this in the society
in the ex-GDR, they always talk to the
children in the imperative, do this, do this.
I am from the GDR also until the age of 9,
the best thing I ever took was to work
with others in school. If somebody was not good in school, you had to teach him to be better.
You had to take care of your neighbor,
by that time.
We left when I was 8 or 9.
But this was not in the west later on
we had to have another mentality
and I think this is very destructive.
You have to fight for your own causes.
It's not my own causes,
I'm not living in this world alone.
This raises a lot of egotism
and this is what I think we should change.
And see that there is a different God,
not a material God. When we are dead
we're not taking these things with us.
-It's very interesting that when we ponder about these very serious issues concerning health,
we all agree. Then where is the problem?
Maybe the problem is that we are too weak and we follow what the general trend is telling us.
I say, no. But you are peculiar,
they will throw stones on you.
I believe this is correct, never mind,
you do whatever you like with me.
So if people are standing up for their own
beliefs which is coming because they are
different movements underneath, I don't
believe the society is going to be destroyed.
Something will bring back this kind
of balance. We have lost our balance.
-What I believe is that it doesn't make
much sense when we tell our children;
it goes in through one ear and out
on the other. Because we, ourselves,
are looking for the values. It's much
more important to live what we believe
and also this concerns the
Homeopathic treatment.
Lead them correctly, if they lead their
children correctly they will watch less TV,
they will get less involved in these
activities and they will look for themselves.
So I think through Homeopathic treatment
is very important to influence them,
to cure them at a very early
age on the right way.
-That is true but the children will follow the general trend of what is happening.
The American way is, unless the boy has no girlfriend at the age of 12-13 is not healthy.
Unless we understand that this is a
wrong idea, then we accept that.
The boy is unhealthy at the age of
14 if he doesn't have girlfriend.
But if the society is pushing the boy to
do this,  is killing the soul of the boy.
-I would like to say one thing to this issue.
I found very often that in the appearance
they cannot bear any skin eruptions on the children. So even if they are coming with
the babies and have some red points, they get exhausted and they always want that they
disappear very soonly. Of course, no
cortizone but they have to disappear
and they take Calendula and so on.
-That' s very important issue of course.
Because if all the disturbances that we have,
came out to the skin, everyone
would look terrible.
It is true, we see it many times.
There is a book that was written by a German actually who lived in Athens, in 1925.
And he had Tuberculosis and he stayed
in coma for a year in Berlin.
Then during this coma state,
he was living in a dream state.
Once he came back from the coma
after a year, the doctors advised him
to come to Athens because the
climate by that time was
much good for Tuberculosis people.
He says, go to Greece.
He got a place near Acropolis and one day he woke up in the morning and he remembered
what he was seeing in his dream for one
year and he started writing his experiences.
Once he finished, he was giving
German lessons to students.
When he was going to die, he said to
one of his students who is now
a Professor in the University, he says,
'take these and do whatever
you like with these notes'.
This professor translated the notes into
Greek and published a book.
Now in this book what is given is the
picture  of the future society.
How the future society is going to be
in Europe and the Western world.
It's a fantastic book which predicts actually in 1925, he says, in the middle of the century
1950,60 the people who will be adored, will
be the idols, will be hippies playing the guitar
and football players. He could
not have been more accurate.
What is his name?
Michael Jackson?
You see this whole thing, guitars and
shouting the people to the idols.
I don't know the names, Elton John?
I think also one of them became a Sir.
The English people made him.
All this adoration in the middle of the
century and many other predictions
and he said by the year 2500
this is going to be the society.
And he gives a picture of the society
in which he has lived there.
In this society children are working up to the
age of 21. Nobody works after that age.
All the problems are solved and after that
age, you can do whatever you like.
Up to the age of 21 you are like a soldier, you belong to the society, you work for the society
but no sex at all. What he says also
is that the people when they meet,
they recognize their partner.
Once they are at that age, over 21
and for the first time come together boys
and girls, they recognize really their partner.
So there is no this kind of confusion:
oh I got the wrong man or woman etc.
The society has totally different rules
but what we see today, as healers,
that people are coming to be healed,
the problem is here and it's very serious.
And the secret I wanted to tell you is this.
If you see cases that the remedy is clear,
then these levels are usually
still in good condition !