The idea of prevention in Homeopathy
is not a valid idea.
What is the reason? A remedy will act if you have the symptoms of the remedy.
Let us you have no symptoms and you want to prevent smallpox and then you take Thuja.
How it can act?
Then you want to make somebody sick through repetition of homeopathic remedies in order to prevent him
from getting the disease. It' s not possible.
You take Arnica before you go for surgery or before you go to the dentist.
You take Arnica so you don't bleed, that's nonsense, you may bleed more.
Or you take Phosphorus to prevent bleeding because you are going to have an operation? Forget it.
-I would like to ask what about the disease prevention of Malaria for instance or other diseases when
people do not want to take vaccinations or other remedies so they take homeopathic remedies preventively
as not to get this illness in foreign countries.
-I cannot advise this because it has no logic behind that. Where is the prevention? You want to prevent Malaria?
And you take what? Natrum muriaticum or China officinalis or China sulphurica?
-Hahnemann in the Organon writes that during pregnancy one should take Sulphur to soften the psora for instance.
What do you think about this?
-I don't agree with this idea. I don't remember where he writes it, if you can tell me I can look
maybe he means something else. But I don't agree with the idea of prevention because in order to prevent
that means you have to create within the human body, antibodies of the specific disease which you try to prevent.
How to produce antibodies unless you give really the same substance that you are going to prevent?
So you have to manipulate the immune system producing antibodies, so it can prevent. Once you do that
you disturb the organism with homeopathic or allopathic medicine. So I don't see the logic behind
and I have not any proof that homeopathic remedy will really prevent anything. I went to India and I said
I don't want to be vaccinated. So I went to a doctor and said please give me a certificate, how much it costs? So much.
He gave me a certificate, that was for yellow fever and smallpox and cholera, there were 3 at the time.
My organism was already very sensitive and I would be destroyed, I knew it and I said, I don't want it.
I take the responsibility, don't worry. Now if I had taken homeopathic drugs to prevent this, I would think that this was
prevented me from getting cholera or whatever because I was taking homeopathic prophylaxis.
This is how the confusion is formed.
I don't have any serious case in which I can have some proof that homeopathic remedy can prevent.
If anybody has this proof, he can give it to me.
-George what about Gelsemium which is supposed to be a preventive treatment to be taken before
an exam for example, when somebody is too nervous before an exam he is taking Gelsemium, is it a prevention?
-What about somebody taking Gelsemium before the examinations in order to calm down? This is something else.
You have the symptoms. The people say 'I'm terrible when I go, I tremble, I lose power, I cannot remember'.
That is the time you take Gelsemium.
That symptomatology starts a few hours or a few days before the examination. Then I say, you take it.
And many times the effect is fantastic but he has the symptoms. And the symptoms are going away.
This is not a prevention but to prevent Malaria. If I take China sulphurica and go to Africa thinking that I' m protected
that, I don't agree. I don't say, you are protected, I say, you are unprotected if you do this.
-I have a question for vaccination. In your book you write it is very dangerous to get vaccination.
So how can we do the prevention? Because getting Malaria is not very funny, for instance.
-If I knew how to do the prevention without the vaccination, I would have 5 Nobel prizes. I don't know.
-I have read in a book from R.R. that he suggests to give for instance nosodes of Hepatitis, Malaria, Typhus
and you give double dose of 200 and you get one dose, and after 5 minutes, the second.
And I have done this when I'm going to India.
-And you have been saved?
-Yes.
-I have done the same and I stayed to India for 3 years and I never was vaccinated with anything, still I was saved.
I was also saved without any prevention.
So it doesn't mean anything.
Giving remedies of high potencies you don't need. One possibility: no effect at all.
Second possibility: maybe some proving is there. Third possibility: you may need one of these nosodes and you are cured.
But not prevention.
-On the question of giving Sulphur, as the doctor pointed out, to pregnant women, in Delhi hospital
it was done for 6 months. And in the nursery about 35% infants were born with inexplicable rash on the cheeks
which was atopic dermatitis but it was happening over and over again until the Sulphur trial was stopped.
Also the practice of giving Caulophyllum in the last trimester or in the last 4 weeks of pregnancy and we had a lot of cases
going into uterine inertia and those people had to be induced for getting the pains and it had to be stopped.
-Correct. What you can do is make the uterus inactive and when it needs to contract to get out the baby, it does not contract.
Do you remember, was anybody in Aedipsos? Do you remember this dramatic with a Greek doctor bringing out, twins?
And somebody, an American, went to see her and gave a dose of Sepia 10M because she said, 'I noticed some
discoloration in her thigh'. I said 'why did you give her?', 'Because I noticed some discoloration in the thigh'.
What happened is that labor started and stopped. The uterus became inert and we expected
from 10 o'clock when it was dilatation of the uterus and should in 2-3 hours deliver, we waited and waited, it was 1 o'clock
2, 3, 6 o'clock in the night. The dilatation stayed there and the uterus was totally inactive.
By 9 o'clock I said to her, 'give me your symptoms, what do you feel?'
And she gave me symptoms of Pulsatilla, I gave Pulsatilla and I predicted in 1 hour you deliver. It was 3/4 of an hour.
21:45 that started the delivery. And what was the dramatic? The one child came out and the other one
came in the wrong position and the gynecologist who was there was trying to manipulate and bring the child.
But the child cannot live very long in the
uterus if they are from the same ovum.
The woman was fainting, he was telling me tell the woman to push, the woman could not push and then faint
and she was shouting and no contraction and I gave her Carb-veg to bring her back and then she had cramps
in the legs and I said, bring Cuprum, give Causticum. And finally at one time the second came out.
What an experience!
We were in a room like this and we had only one scissor of the woman of the house who used it for tailoring.
What shall we do? It was 10, 11 o'clock in the night, 12 o'clock, no helicopter was coming.
I said, what shall we do? He said, we have to cut the boy to save the mother.
And one time he says to me, it's finished, it's dead, the boy, he didn't feel it anymore.
All the class was there and everybody
wanted to know what was happening.
She is a strange woman, you know. She has now 12 children. And she was shouting, I want my daughters.
I said what about that daughter and save the life of the mother? We only had one scissor to cut, how to get it out?
It was not possible to get it out, the boy was coming with the back, it could not pass through the uterus.
It was a real dramatic experience which I think if we didn't have homeopathic remedies, forget it. It was no way that we could manage.
No contraction, no possibility to get it out, the boy would just die in a few minutes and that would be a very nice
advertising for Homeopathy.
Who is responsible? George.
After that experience I remember we came so close with Tony, the gynecologist. He was sweating and I was
exhausted because I was holding her and all the time I was trying to get the symptoms to give the remedies to be able to
push the boy to come out. He said 'I can't turn it, tell her to push I can't turn it'.
She was trying to push and shout 'ah, cramps I can't push' and then she was fainting. He said, 'don't let her faint!'.
Nice experience that natural childbirth.
-It's about the preventing. Hahnemann talked about epidemic situation and I want to know your opinion about it.
If you live in a situation where there is a very dangerous epidemic what is your opinion about?
-What is a dangerous epidemic, tell me first and then I will tell you?
-Cholera or Polio or something like that.
-Cholera, if there is an epidemic I would say, ok go ahead, for Polio also, go ahead, not for other  diseases.
All the other children's diseases I don't agree with vaccination. Even with Polio, we have a lot of side effects and
with Cholera also. Every time I have a case chronically ill, he was going to Africa, I must get Cholera.
I say, ok take the vaccination and see what happens. Almost invariably there was eventually a relapse of the chronic state.
But I cannot take the responsibility and say, don't vaccinate because one accident might happen and they will say
George is responsible because he advised it. For all the side effects nobody is responsible. Everybody accepts it.
I lost my child because of Polio vaccination, I have been brought autistic children after Polio vaccination
and the parents say the child started having epileptic fit after vaccination, 2,3 days later, I went back
to the pediatrician and he said forget it,
it's not because of the vaccination. They get away.
Also I don't agree with Hepatitis vaccination, I don't agree and I would advice not to take it.
I agree also that the children must go through the epidemics. If children do not get epidemics, I'm very suspicious
that these children are mentally ill. You do not realize how much a child can be mentally ill because he is functional,
especially if he is very clever. I'm very suspicious. My child is so clever, so intelligent and then it's a Veratrum album.
Then this child will not get an epidemic, it is protected.
-It was a man 23 years old, he had some vaccines about 4 years old, and then he developed asthma
and allergy and some intestinal problems , by the age of 23 he was really bad and then after 2 months of homeopathic
treatment, he was delivered to the hospital with severe allergy. He was totally covered with some skin eruptions and high fever.
One of the doctors realized that this is not allergy. This is variola and he got the vaccine of variola
when he had problem, when he was 4 years old. That means that homeopathic treatment brought out the reasons
for all these problems during these 20 years.
Is it this?
-Yes, you are talking about yourself?
-Exactly.
-I got it.
How do I know? By observation. What did I observe?
-Tetanus?
-Tetanus. How many times really tetanus?
I'm living here and one day a plank with a rusty nail fell on my leg and went inside so deep.
Everybody said, get vaccination and I'm a scientist you know? I want to find out. Let's see what happens.
Nothing happened of course. All the Greek doctors here were terrified.
I said, let me see I don't believe I will get anything.
A child falls in Athens. Where did they see a sheep or a goat in Athens? 50 years ago.
And then they go immediately and vaccinate and then the whole health level goes down. This is my experience.
But this is very interesting, what he related. Russians, the system is you have protection and everybody has to be vaccinated.
Everybody has to take antibiotics etc.
-I saw tetanus patient, when I was working in the intensive unit in a hospital, he was about 50 years of age.
He already had the tetanic rigors of his jaw and he came into the hospital because he should have been amputated
as his right index finger was the
entrance of the tetanic organism
and 5 days before he went into the hospital,  he suffered from a very small injury in his right finger.
He was repairing his caravan and there was in an area where it was only sand and beach, there was no horse,
goat, sheep and the disease came out within these 2 days. First he started with throat pain,
he thought about some flu and didn't do anything and he had troubles swallowing.
He went to a doctor and he was treated for flu.
2 days later he had to go to the hospital because his neck was rigid and he had the tetanic rigors in his jaw.
Then the diagnosis was established. He came into the hospital he had already fits, he could not speak anymore
he was completely rigid. I don't want to further talk about his development what happened to this man
this is another story but when I came home after doing my duty in the hospital, I went
home and said to all the people around, you have to get vaccinated.
-Which part of Germany?
-In north.
-In a small town.
-It's only a beach and a place for caravans.
- Most probably some animals were there but anyhow nobody denies that Tetanus is a deadly disease.
Seldom anybody survives and if he survives he will be injured for life.
But with Homeopathy I would be very curious. For instance in this case it would be interesting if this man
had taken Hypericum high doses constantly.
-The problem is nobody even thought of Tetanus when he had this little injury on the finger. It was obvious
only when he was shaking and had these convulsions, these fits.
-10 years ago when I worked as a surgeon in a little hospital in Germany, we had two cases of Tetanus within
one month after operation because nobody thought vaccinating them against Tetanus.
-Well now that all people are vaccinated, all children are vaccinated, still in Athens hospital there are cases of Tetanus.
-The great problem with vaccinations is that there is no scientific proof of how vaccinations are preventing people
from getting Tetanus. For instance in these 3 cases that are reported by our colleagues I would be highly interested
to know whether they had been vaccinated against Tetanus. In those 2 cases that I reported the vaccination
of Tetanus had been more than 20 years ago, and after they got a little injury their vaccination had not been refreshed.
-Theoretically in order to prevent an infection you have to make the whole organism, to bring down the health
of the organism so it cannot be infected by the specific bacteria, virus or whatever. This, at least theoretically
is correct and I will explain to you more in theory, what is my idea concerning vaccination.
But don't get the idea that I have the answer, how to prevent. Or what is the real truth about vaccination
and whether the vaccination has really done
good or bad. I'm not in a position to say it.
What I am in a position to say is some theoretical questions that I have concerning vaccination.