So we talked about the predispositions
there and I hope you understood this point.
This point is very important for you to understand, why?
Because of the reactions that you
may have after giving the remedy.
The reaction can be, it's called in psycho-
therapy, "somatisation" of symptoms.
That means from mental, emotional disturbances, the disturbance comes
to the lower part which is the physical body. Many times what we have seen is treating
a problem in the abdomen, let us say is
a spastic colitis or an ulcer or gastritis,
we have the appearance of
hemorrhoids which is very disturbing.
But since these hemorrhoids belong to the
place where the mucus membranes are joining
the skin, also you have the appearance of
cracks on the corners, you have the
appearance of herpes on the lips, so you
know that your treatment is doing very well.
Inspite of the fact, the patient may
complain a lot because the force
of the disturbance is the same.
The force is not reduced, the quantity
is not reduced, the place is changing.
And eventually of course, it will be reduced as well. That means, an eczema which comes
inside has the same force - itching- if it
is a severe eczema you itch the whole night.
Instead you have anxiety the whole night
and restlessness and feeling cold and stiff.
You give the remedy and then you have the whole night you scratch, but this is the only
way you can cure. You have to know that.
That it went the right direction.
Now so far, we have been talking about one individual. Its structure and how it behaves
in health and disease.
-When the level changes from mental to psychological, does the force come out
always at the same level?
Can it be at different level?
-Usually comes to the same level.
For instance, a severe heart problem
or a severe lung problem will have
as a result a severe skin eruption.
The person is going to suffer quite a lot. But
this happens if we have structural problems.
That means pathologoanatomical problems,
if we have really lesions in the organs.
If the problem is functional,
then it is light in any case.
The problem is here on the mental level,
but it is low on the mental level.
So when it comes, it comes out here.
These levels we call them, functional levels.
So either you will not have the appearance but very little manifestation on the skin or not at all.
In any case what is my experience is that,
for instance, you treat somebody who is sick
in this level and you give a remedy
and he becomes quite well and
no manifestations in the skin
or the mucus membranes.
After 2 or 3 years, that means it takes
very long time before it's organizing
something here in the skin.
You may be treating a case and
it appears to be well, totally well,
but after 2-3 years there is manifestation
of acne type in a grown up person
or some pimples, or some athlete's foot;
these are the least disturbing things
that you can experience.
We see here the direction of cure, it goes from inside to the outside and from up, downwards.
Here you see the stress going
from outside to the inside.
Of course we cannot show
all the possibilities.
A skin eruption which is on that side, will
manifest if it goes right to the mental,
with problems on that level. Much lower.
If it goes to the physical, it will manifest
more or less on the same level.
That means in practice,
you are treating somebody
whom you are thinking is not very ill.
He has some phobias, some anxieties, these phobias and anxieties are really quite deep.
You give the remedy and then you see
a manifestation on the physical level
which is too much. It breaks out into the
body with great force; which means
you have not understood the seriousness of
the mental-emotional condition of the person.
I remember back in 1969 or 70 a case
sent to us by the French embassy,
the boy of the French ambassador in Athens.
He came from France where he was treated
homeopathically with mixtures of remedies.
He had severe asthma.
He was taking cortisone and pills.
With a note, 'don't give Sulphur to that boy'.
The French Homeopaths giving different
remedies, they have found out that whenever
they gave Sulphur, there was a big
reaction and immediately they jumped
with 20 other remedies to stop the reactions.
The boy was still with cortisone and
bronchodilators. Of course, we gave Suphur.
We explained what is going to happen
and the boy was cured. But unless you have
this information, how can you do Homeopathy?
And this kind of Homeopathy was
going on for years and years.
People didn't know what they were doing.
Throwing remedies all the time,
patching up symptoms.
-You mentioned that they are coming
physical symptoms and my question is:
the physical symptoms can' t they be
very new or they have been existent
and they just come up another time?
-You remember in the model, we have weak spots, weak predispositions in different levels.
Which ones of these spots are going to be activated? Potentially we're going to
suffer with this or this or that disease.
Now we get a stress, we get antibiotics,
we lost our parents, our children, we are
in big grief, which of these spots are going
to be activated? It might be activated
a spot which is quite deep.
That means the organism jumps up very
fast, the levels of predisposition,
in the lower level and goes very deep.
That means the grief was so much
that almost killed the organism.
So it can go very fast to the heart.
It jumped several other predispositions
or it may go straight to the mental
or to the emotional and then confusion
comes or depression comes
and then the person stays depressed.
The person has predispositions, lower predispositions, which might have never
experienced, these lower predispositions
may never have been activated before.
In such a case when you give the remedy,
lower predispositions are activated
and we have the manifestation
of a new kind of pathology.
But if the person had experienced already the lower and then the more higher and finally
the highest, then the disease will
go back in a similar pattern.
I will give you an example.
You have an individual, he is quite
healthy, he gets gonorrhea.
After gonorrhea he gets condylomata.
Condylomata are treated and here he develops
insomnia. And then a shock comes and he becomes depressed, suicidal depression.
When you treat, you are going to pass
through the phase of insomnia 100 %,
he may be suffering with this insomnia 20
years and with depression he comes to you
for 6 -9 months or 1 year. You give the
right remedy and here is insomnia.
But insomnia is if you sleep 4
hours the day, this is insomnia.
Or 1 hour the day, all this we call
insomnia. So insomnia has a depth.
Before this goes down here, it goes
right through the whole range of insomnia,
that means under stress the person cannot
sleep at all for a certain period of time.
After that the organism gets tired and
jumps on another level which
is now depression, suicidal depression,
everything is lost.
Now when you treat him and you bring him
up, what part of insomnia will be activated?
That which was the deepest for him. There
were periods where he could not sleep at all
or he could sleep only 1 hour,
so the period after your treatment,
the person will sleep for 1 hour and
then for 2 hours and then for 3 hours.
When I say 'and then', it means a period
of time and another remedy perhaps.
So you have given 2 remedies for the
depression and you have given 3 remedies
before you can overcome the insomnia.
So within a period of, let us say, 9 months
you are treating him, you are going through
the phases of insomnia and then he comes
to the point where the condylomata  reappear.
-When I saw the model, 2 days ago,
I had to think of a patient who came to me.
His pathology was that he had an
eczema around the nose for 6 years
which was treated with cortisone, it developed into asthma which was treated also,
then he developed an ulcer of the stomach
which was operated on and then
he came with an angioneurotic edema.
He had to constantly take antihistamines
and with this fear, he came to me.
According to the symptoms I gave him Sulphur
and one month after receiving Sulphur,
he came back to me with great problem
because fears appeared and he remembered that he used to work in a bank and one day
there was a bank robbery and these
fears came back strongly.
So for me it was quite strong clue that it was
not Sulphur but Aconite and two days later
he had this angioneurotic edema but only
in a small spot in the hand and then
it disappeared completely. So what
was his basic theme, his main issue,
was it possible for the normal
traditional Medicine
to treat in a such a way that
his fears were somatised?
Were these physical symptoms something like
a layer which was put on top of his fears.
Could it be that the organism tried to
manifest this fear into the physical level?
Basically he had a strong fear of death
and then he had this angioneurotic edema
and it seemed that everytime something happens, I get my edema,
I have to take my remedies and then
he experienced the same fear
as when he was in the robbery.
-In this case what happens is that the Sulphur
is what Hahnemann says, one sided disease,
you don't have enough symptoms you
most probably gave Sulphur because
he had taken a lot of medicines,
for reasons of that type.
-No, he had Sulphur symptoms?
-Some, yes.
-The Sulphur is correct, what you gave as the first remedy. Then the picture was full, open.
Generally they say that Sulphur is given
when we don't have clear picture,
we discuss later on about all these things.
This is a question now which is for
advanced students but anyhow I'm taking
it up just to satisfy a little bit your curiosity.
Sulphur does not cure, it makes things
worse because it appears that
he gives to the person mental-emotional symptoms but at the same time
makes the picture clear. Then Aconite is given and the cure is following, it's more complete.
Many times we see this is happening,
when we don't have a clear picture
you give a remedy that does not cure,
it appears to make the person even worse;
but for the one who knows Homeopathy,
makes the picture clear.
Therefore the first remedy is needed,
it brings about a clearness of the case
and then the second remedy cures.
Now how is that before he did not
have or was not aware of some fears?
That means that person had the fears suppressed in his subconscious mind
and instead of the fears, he had
the angioneurotic edema.
When the organism becomes stronger then the force of the angioneurotic edema becomes less,
there is also fears which are manifesting,
then we have the completeness of the cure.
Later on, we shall see how the development
of mental-emotional symptoms in a case,
does not always indicate wrong direction.
You have angioneurotic edema here, on the physical level and then you have fears
and anxieties which are on this level.
So going from angioneurotic edema to this level,
it is already a promotion of health though you may have some mental emotional symptoms.
The disease on that level becomes less, this is activated also and then the remedy comes
and then goes out, angioneurotic
edema but on that level here.
Because he says the angioneurotic
edema now does not have a force,
it's not threatening the life of the person.
We will discuss later on, in detail, this.
We have to go step by step,
otherwise the information is so
much that it may confuse you.
For the time being I want you to
establish this knowledge.
Later on we have a lot of modifications
and questions and problems to solve.
-To this problem can I ask you something?
It cannot be that Sulphur was the right
remedy but on the wrong time?
Maybe Sulphur was constitutional.
Because Aconite is complementary of
Sulphur, now he is in Aconite level and
he gave Sulphur to the wrong time.
-No. When you have the development
of a clear picture after the remedy,
that means the remedy is correct.
You will see this in the videos later on,
when we present the videos,
you will see all these things and you will
be able to follow the videos, to understand.
-He developed Aconite symptoms after Sulphur?
-And Aconite acted. Where could you
find Aconite in the beginning?
If you give Aconite in the beginning
could you have the same result? No.
I don't say no because I like to say no, but because experience shows that this is the way.
Maybe some of you remember a case in
Celle with a little boy scratching after Tub.,
scratching, who was there?
Full of eczema with celiac disease, with severe problems, I remember I prescribed first
Tuberculinum and then after 6 months
I prescribed Pulsatilla and it acted
within a few days. The practitioner reported
3 days later, the itching has gone.
Pulsatilla was given to this boy 6 months
before I had given Tub and I came and I said,
now is the time for Puls. Tub seems it had aggravated tremendously the skin eruption,
it doesn't matter. Now it remained a clear
picture of Pulsatilla, now you give Pulsatilla
and then it acts immediately.
Before, Puls had done nothing.
It was given 6 months before and
the boy was suffering since birth.
-Did you see from the very beginning
that Puls would be indicated after Tub?
-No. I saw it afterwards.
After Tuberculinum.
-When you gave Tuberculinum you had the impression that it would do the cure?
-Yes, I had the impression that Tuberculinum may cure; instead of curing, it aggravated
the situation. For me it did not aggravate
that I know all these things
but I cannot explain in a class which
I don't know how much you know.
What I knew is that the child was suffering with celiac disease, with a disease that cannot
absorb starches, problems with
absortion and diarrhea etc.
That portion was ok. And then all the force of the disease came on very high level on the skin
where before the level of the skin appeared
to be here and the celiac disease was there.
So giving him Tub., all came up in this level but created a clear picture for the next remedy.
-So after Tuberculinum the celiac
disease was ameliorated?
-Yes. Because he could have a better
absorption. But this does not appear outside.
If you see the case, you will
suffer, in the whole class
people were screaming,
what is this? what has happened?
Because all the force is coming out, the boy
was totally covered with neurodermatitis.
I remember as long as the mother kept
it there for 1,5 hour, in the interview,
the boy was scratching constantly.
In 2 days she reported, that itching has gone.
In 20 days the skin was clean.
And we saw the case, 6 months later,
it was almost totally clean.
-Excuse me, I wish to ask you if you mean,
when you give a remedy like in these cases,
and this remedy brings clear picture.
And it brings order to the symptoms
of the patient, so that we can recognize
the next step, the next remedy
then this is always the right remedy?
-Yes, this is what I say, absolutely.
-I don't understand why Pulsatilla
did not work at the very beginning.
-You don't understand? Neither me.
The picture of Pulsatilla is not there.
It appears to have some symptoms.
Ok, I'll give you another information.
These are the big symptoms in
a case and this is the level which
we call Tuberculinum level; then we have
another level which is Pulsatilla.
You take the case and you see 1,2,3...7 symptoms and you choose Pulsatilla
because of this, this, this is
common to both and then
you decide the first remedy is
Pulsatilla, ok?  Nothing happens.
You choose Pulsatilla why? Because
some of the symptoms of Pulsatilla
are manifesting in the case
and you have to choose.
The cases I show you, all the cases you are going to study are cases of that type.
There are shooting up symptoms of the underlying remedy or supposed to be,
you do not know and all the time you
have to choose if I take this, this and that
is Tuberculinum, if I take this, this, this
and that is Pulsatilla. What shall I take?
And you say, I take Tuberculinum
because this is very important,
too important symptoms and then I choose Tuberculinum. That's all the difference.
When the Tuberculinum goes
away, then what it stays?
It stays the clear picture of
Pulsatilla underneath.
Then you give Pulsatilla and
there is beautiful cure.
In this category falls the
example that he's giving.
-I had a patient, she had breast cancer.
They had operated her and
and in two weeks after she made
hysterectomy.
It was too much for my knowledge so
I asked a colleague and he gave Tuberculinum.
And after 3 days the woman developed
very severe skin rash at the whole leg
that took 5 months, it looked terrible.
They also removed all the lymph glands
and so she had big swelling of legs.
-Before you continue I will tell you
something so the class will not think that
because you said it like this, I said it like that.
Now in this case what may happen?
The possibilities.
When you see severe skin eruption,
severe, developing after cancer and the
skin eruption goes away in 6 months,
it's no good. That means
you have to expect that if the
problem was really severe
this problem has to last for years
perhaps and be worse and worse.
If you see this coming out, then most probably the cancer will return or the inner state will return.
-The woman got fistula between rectum
and vagina and she got operated on this
and then in 8 days she was dead.
-I said that because I would give the explanation afterwards, you would think oh he makes it up.
I knew exactly what you are going to say. You realize how much the information is important.
It is so important, if you can
appreciate what I'm giving you.
When I see this, I see the organism
making an effort, it's not strong enough,
the whole thing is going to go back and most probably will have results which are fatal.
-George can I ask you something?
In this case when the person is so sick,
she had cancer, is it possible to
become even after the best remedy
after some days such a skin problem?
I thought it's the wrong remedy.
-No, no, no. The wrong remedy cannot do
this reaction. Tuberculinum is correct,
the problem is....
Here we have the possibility
to give... during the eruption state,
maybe another remedy is appearing.
If we don't give it to push forward the organism, then most probably we lost a chance.
The organism makes a tremendous effort but after a while it's coming back. That' s no good.
If by chance you see the next remedy,
after Tuberculinum, more eruption,
then the next remedy, more eruption,
then there is a chance.
But I also say this. If the type of the cancer
is not of a very malignant type;
for me cancers are not all the same. Now
they recognize, also officially, different types
and different prognosis. So in
"non malignant" cancer, you may get
reactions which even such
a reaction will be sufficient.
But in a really malignant cancer,
if you get such a reaction
has to be really, really strong.
-This would be different if different
potency would be given.
-I doubt it. This reaction is very good.
It's the optimal.
Now whether she needed another dose of Tuberculinum when it started going back,
or another remedy, I don't know but we are dealing here with very serious condition.
So you have to know exactly what you
are doing and what possibilities are
and what prognosis are etc.
What I did just now, is usual.
I do it all the time, to predict, why?
Because of this information. Because
I understood or I found out
by observation these things that
I'm trying to give you as knowledge.
I want to take you on another level.
The diagram says on the top, ideal state,
absolute health and the last one says, death
and in between, increasing
degree of entropy.
Entropy is the third law of physics which
says that everything tends to go
into a kind of chaos, chaotic situation.
Towards dissolution, towards disintegration.
This law also is applying on
the human bodies as well.
We have several levels of health
on which we find ourselves.
Each one of us belongs to one of
these 12 levels of heatlh.
The levels are 12 or there are 112
I don't know, of course I don't know.
I'm just giving a symbolic idea
of my observation concerning
the human organism and human health.
Human health you can categorize
in different levels.
So each one of us belongs to those
levels. What it shows is that we are,
let us say, all of us in level E. When we are in good condition we wake up in the morning
and we feel good. We are fluctuating
in the upper part of the level E.
Then we get very tired in the evening
and we fluctuate in level E
still but on a lower part of this level.
And because we fluctuate there
for several days because of giving too many lectures, walking too much, exhausting
oneself, then you are getting an influenza and then because you are getting the influenza
and you still continue to exhaust yourself,
then the influenza goes into pneumonia.
Now you reached the bottom part of
your level. This is dangerous.
At this moment you better be careful.
At this moment there is a possibility
of jumping a level and go to level F.
At this moment means that the predisposition
spots which I showed you which are
on a higher and more deep level
can be activated and from one day to the
other, you have the development
of a serious chronic condition for which you
have the predisposition that was kept there
dormant but under the influence of drugs
here, because in pneumonia you take
antibiotics. You take antibiotics and you
wake up the next day with asthma.
And the asthma now is going to remain
the rest of your life in level F.
So here while you are in level F, again
you display the same possibilities,
going higher in level F where you have
dyspnoia, where you can live without
some bronchodilators but then you
exert yourself, you go down, you need
bronchodilators, you need cortisone and eventually you need cortisone all the time.
And you are fluctuating there in
the bottom of level F, cortisone, cortisone,
and one day asthma is going away and
you find yourself in severe anxiety state.
Fears, anxieties, etc.
-How can you see that it's a different level and the constant decrease of the dynamics?
-What indicates the disease itself; the
symptoms that you are getting.
You see we have names for diseases.
I think you are in Medicine, right?
So when you go to the hospital they tell you,
dear sir you are having diabetes mellitus.
So from one moment to the other you
have gone into the state where your
pancreas has broken down and says,
I can't handle it anymore
and then the islands of Langerhans are destroyed and then you have
the raise of sugar in the body. From
that moment you are a diabetic.
That indicates that you have jumped level.
Before you had the potentiality
but no symptoms, no problems.
The moment the symptoms start and the disease is established then you have a new state,
a new level. Treating this person you have
to get away from diabetes and jump
again back to the state that it was
previously, of non diabetes state, clear?
These things you have to understand
very well. If you have questions,
please ask so everything is
clear in your mind.
-How does manifest diabetes who even needs insulin to go back from the diabetes state?
You said, we have to come
back from the diabetes state.
-I said, if by treating this case you bring
him back to the non-diabetic state
that means you have taken this person
a level upwards again, towards health.
Where the stress that was on that level, a stress that found you in this lower part of your level,
can push you down to a new level,
which is a stress of whatever type.
You are tired, you have been in a hospital,
you are afraid that if you lose your father
you lose everything; my father is supporting me, you run back and forwards from the hospital.
And then one day the father dies
and the grief instead of being
expressed with shouting, with crying,
is kept inside and then diabetes
from one day to the other.
Now what type of diabetes will
depend on your predisposition.
Let us say, your father also had diabetes.
You are going to be in a state of diabetes which is quite serious and may require insulin.
We have all kind of diabetes
and there is a diabetes which is quite
serious the infantile diabetes,
juvenile diabetes, very serious,
very difficult to treat and you
have the diabetes mellitus,
we have the two types, one who is gaining
weight to the fat ones and one who is
losing weight with combustions etc.
The better prognosis is with the
fat persons but this is not for the moment.
-Can the islets of Langerhans be
repaired through Homeopathy ?
-And I say yes it can be repaired.
We have seen cases which even
require insulin to exist, recent cases
where they can be cured.
As you may also understand, nobody asked.
Ok, I'm in level E, can I ever go to level D?
-Miasm is considerable? Can you explain
about miasm how it relates to this diagram?
-In this level E you already have
at least two miasmatic layers.
The deeper you go the more the complication, the more the severity of the disease
and the more the miasmatic complications,
we talk later on about it.
-As a baby we can be born
into any level, yes?
-Absolutely yes. You can be born,
a baby with epidermolysis bullosa,
I said the other day, is born right
to the bottom, the last level.
Babies born with severe cancer which makes them die within a few years, belong to this level.
The question is can we jump from E to D?
Let us say, the person comes here when
he is diabetic and you give a remedy
and you bring him back to this level where
he had again the previous conditions
where he was getting easily
influenzas and things like that.
The possibility in these levels is that with the correct remedy you can jump one more level.
Perhaps in our litterature the idea is given that with correct prescription you can reach level A.
This is not true.
This cannot be done.
Level A we cannot reach, it belongs to
the lucky people who are born with
very strong constitution and they are close
to level A and then with a little remedy,
they jump level, they go to the next. But this
is only for people who belong to level B.
Or people who were level A and went down
to B. Then with one remedy we push them up.
These are people who are
living over 90 years old
and are having a good
hereditary predisposition.