I said according to my experience
at the most you can jump one level.
And you can stay in the highest part of
that level with good homeopathic treatment.
What I wanted to say is that when you treat
here the pneumonia you go back there,
then another remedy and you go back there.
Then another remedy or 2 or 3 to treat the pneumonia then it jumps there, back,
then 2 remedies to jump there and
2 remedies to jump at higher level.
That whole process it may
need from 1 to 5 years.
-Is this also possible only with
one remedy, this treatment?
-Level E, no.
If you are on level E, no.
You have these levels, it's only indicative.
Here in this level, people are living 90 years
old and higher, born to live more 90 years old.
Here in this level born to live more than 80 years, here more than 75 years and
then it goes down 65, 60, 50.
I'm just giving you some indications,
here 40, 30, 20, 10, 5.
So each one is born with a possibility
to live certain years.
That means this one here is born
with a predisposition that his heart
will last up to 60 years of age.
When he reaches that age then
he has a heart attack and he dies.
What you can do is jump him up to
level 75, by treating him.
Here we have one miasm,
therefore one remedy.
In this level with one remedy
you have beautiful cures.
You find this man who is going to live to 90,
at the age of 65 he comes down with lumbago
and you give one remedy Calcarea
carbonica, everything is gone.
He is having a cold, a beautiful picture of Bryonia, you give it, everything is gone.
They go like this. Their organism is so strong
that produces a very clear picture
of a remedy each time.
And usually it is one remedy.
This person actually can happen, that with
one remedy you can cure everything,
the lumbago, the cystitis,
the pneumonia, whatever.
Now as you go more and more down, you start complicating, 2 miasms, perhaps 2 remedies.
You go here you have 3 miasms.
From 3-6 remedies.
You go here you have 4-5 miasms,
7-10 remedies.
You go down here you need a lot of remedies, you will be changing remedies very frequently.
Here you have very seriously ill people,
from the very young age
and you're going to need the drugs
intermingled and you will need 20 remedies.
20 remedies in order to bring
this child up in the scale of life.
As you go along this from here,
people who are in this level here,
they can jump a level higher much
more than people who are here.
You get a person who is going to live 75,
in this level, and the most you can do
is to reach him up to 80 or
he's 65, he goes up to 75.
But you get a person who is here
and if you treat him correctly,
you may make him jump
more than one level.
So this is a model that gives you
an idea of  what you are going to face
when you have a certain pathological
case which is quite serious.
So in this case, in a serious pathological case, you will have a mixture of all kinds of remedies.
These 20 remedies we're talking, we're
talking about different levels of remedies.
So which one you will choose? These are confused cases, you don't know where to start.
You take the case and either there is
very little symptomatology or
too much symptomatology,
which indicates a lot of remedies.
You take 2 symptoms, you need 1 remedy, another 2 symptoms, another remedy etc.
If you start correctly and then the second
and third remedy is correct,
then this case starts to be
clear more and more.
As you prescribe correctly they come
to these levels where you need
another 4-5 remedies before
you can bring him up
and then you can bring
him back to 30 years old.
There is another disease which is
called thalassemia, a severe anemia.
Do you know this disease?
How many types of this disease exist?
-Two types.
-Two types, minor and major. If we are
dealing with the major thalassemia
we'll see very early in life, the blood
is gone they need transfusion.
In the age of 2-3 years old, they start
having blood transfusions.
These cases have very bad prognosis.
Now you treat these cases, these people die between 10-12 seldom they live up to 18.
So you treat such a case and they
may live up to 40.
But you will never reach, a case like this,
the age of 70 or 75.
In this model it says also, that people
having a state of health in these levels,
can have a very high
potency without problem.
As you go down the ladder, the potency which you have to use is smaller and smaller.
So when you reach actually these bottom cases you can use only low potencies repeatedly.
Here you can use potencies like 6X up to
12 X and then you will have to repeat every day,
3-4 times the day, for a period of time
until you see some reactions and then you
have a new case or whether the
disease is not progressing anymore
you raise the potency from 6 to 7
and then to 8 and 9X.
The same idea is with LM potencies.
They are acting mildly.
So you can be using Q potencies,
some people use Q potencies
in everything here and
there is some effect also.
If you use 6X potency to these people here,
there is going to be an effect definitely
but in a much longer period.
That means here in these cases the
effect will be within 1-2 days.
If you use 6X, it will take 20 days. That's the difference but some action should be there.
I make it not very clear with the age
because we do not have enough
information at the moment to determine
exactly the levels and each level
how many years is going to last.
This is not possible at the moment.
If you are interested in going into such
research, I may tell you a model
out of which  you can do the research.
Apart from the general check up
of the boy,  which will show that this a case
of epidermolysis bullosa or it's a
case of thalassemia major
where you have a serious problem,
apart from this you have the diagnosis.
There are other parameters which can be measured to show that a boy with thalassemia
major, may live up to the age of 20, 22
and another one will die at the age of 10.
These parameters we don't
know at this moment.
But I believe we have parameters to
measure and be able to establish a reaction.
So for instance, a boy with thalassemia, measuring his mental-emotional
reaction, giving tests to this boy to
determine the mental-emotional state.
It will be determining whether
that boy will live longer.
If the boy seems to be healthy in these
levels, you will get the highest possible.
If these levels are affected they are
lowering down the possibilities of life.
The hereditary factors have to be measured, whether the parents had the same
or similar diseases. Then the voice
has to be determined,
what kind of voice when the child cries,
how he cries, how frequently he cries.
Then the level of communication with the
outside world. When he walks, at what age?
When the teeth are appearing, all these
have to go into a computer and eventually
to have enough parameters to
say that a person who is born,
within 3-4 years, we can determine what is his predisposition and how long, more or less,
this person is going to live.
Genetic information now, which is coming,
is proving all these theoretical conditions
that we have been talking about.
Genetic predisposition tells us that a person
is predisposed to multiple sclerosis or
to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis
or psoriasis, serious diseases.
So we have enough measures at this
moment, that if we put them together,
we can have an idea of how long that person
is going to live under normal conditions.
Then what happens is that we determine that
this person is going to live up to the age
of 75 and this person gets sick
and gets the wrong treatment.
He has some complications and he
has another wrong treatment etc.
Then what happens is that we find
at the age of 40, this person
who is going to live at 75,
almost dying.
We find him at this age but the possibility is 75. So what happens is that treating this person,
jumps one level after  another very fast,
because he was born with the possibility is 75.
This person will never go to the next of course.
Because you'll treat him and reach him up to 75.
But this is a great feat that we can
accomplish with Homeopathy.
So wrong treatment will bring him down
and wrong way of life will bring down
your possibilities and correct treatment
will bring them back.
This is not theoretical, it comes again
from experience, what we have seen.
We have seen people who have abused themselves through drugs,
through wrong living, drinking, god knows.
Yesterday I heard on the TV that N.Ceausescu, the son of the dictator in Romania,
died from liver cirrhosis at the age of
40 from internal hemorrhage.
But if I see his parents living to the age,
they intended to live up to 90 of course,
if they allow them, that means his
predisposition was at least for that age.
Wrong way of living, he was a playboy,
drinking a lot, taking the wrong medicines,
he brought his possibilities to 40.
Now let us say this man with this
predisposition, he comes to me, 2 years ago.
Within 5 or 6 years of treatment,
I will bring him up to the age of 75.
The way of life is very important. When I took
up the case of Krishnamurti, in 1965 in India,
he gave me his case and told me that
all his family died under the age of 50.
Mother, father, brother died under the age of 50. His brother died at 40 with Tuberculosis.
Parents died also because of infections.
Him, having a very good way of life,
very much protected like a king with his
court, very protected and when I met him
he was in a terrible state of health, why?
When I met him in 1963 he was
72 but in a terrible state, very weak.
That means he was going to
live another year or two.
He was taking allopathic drugs
for the last 10 years.
He had been to the best Homeopaths before;
he said, nobody could ever help me.
When I looked at him, he was looking so old
that I felt... I was going to his lectures before,
I was not even looking, I was looking
at the trees outside, he was so old.
I never asked an interview with him because
I always ask for interviews with people;
he was so old, he is going to die.
This is what I calculated.
In about 3-4 months I received a message
while I was in India, studying there,
whether I would go and see him to treat him.
I was a student in one of the
colleges there, very strange eh?
They came to take me to see him and he was
in a terrible condition. I started treating him.
I stopped the allopathic medicine,
I gave him the first remedy.
He reacted very strongly because he
was suffering chronic bronchitis.
He was exhausted. I said it's ok,
then the 2nd remedy, the 3rd, the 5th.
After one and a half year of treatment,
I was with him almost every day.
I became the physician of the court.
Every day I went to see him,
I prescribed for him very carefully.
In one and a half year he said to me,
sir I feel like 16 years old.
I said, very good.
Now this man who had, according to my understanding, only a few months to live,
he died in 1986 at the age of 95
without any further treatment.
After I left he had another homeopath
who gave him salts.
You know the 12 Schuessler's salts of course
he was doing yoga, exercises and all that.
He died at the age of 95, so these things work. This is a public information which I say.
Everybody knows at that time that I was treating Krishnamurti and the difference when I left.
He had forbidden anybody to
take a picture at 1963.
He did not want to leave his
pictures for posterity like this.
The gorillas would take your camera and say,
sit there, listen, then take your camera and go.
Years later, he has pictures which
look beautiful, in 1970, 1975.
So what I say is not theoretical
and comes out of imagination.
They are facts which I have
seen again and again.
You will get some teachers, they will say, especially one from Argentina, who says,
well you always have to find
one remedy, the core remedy.
That remedy is for the whole life of the person. Nat-m, you give for the rest of the life.
What they do not know is that we have
this kind of degrees of health and
they were talking about these
people here which it may be true
but only for those very uppermost
kind of people.
For those only who represent perhaps 5%
on the planet, not more than that.
At this day, even less. 30 years ago that
was 7%. Now it is going down and suddenly
also you will see this is going
down more and more.
-I think you are speaking about Mazi.
He says that he finds such cases
only 3% or something like this. 3% or 5%
I don't know but it's not so much.
-But to go and teach and say to the students,
well in every case you have to find
the one remedy, is a wrong teaching.
You give a wrong impression to the students
who think all the time, 'oh I did not find
the right remedy', he feels 'oh I did not
find the right remedy if I gave
Sulphur and then Aconitum'.
No. This is the wrong way of teaching
coming from wrong observation.
His observation is correct as far as this is concerned. Now we come to your question.
-People are getting older and older, the difference is that they have not all
good quality of life. It means they are
older and older and sicker and sicker.
-These are two different issues. What I'm
talking here is about a percentage of people,
who are destined to have only one
remedy which is going to help them.
This does not concern the general population.
I would say the general population is only 3%?
What I say is, out of the cases that we
see, these cases represent at the most 5%.
It's a different issue. The issue whether we
live today more or less is another issue,
we can discuss it but not at this moment.
I have my doubts, I have seen statistics
and I know things are not like that.
Mortality in children has dropped
dramatically from old times and it shows
on the general graphs that the
population is going up, living longer.
Actually the children are not dying as fast as
they used to die with epidemic diseases.
Therefore the general graph maybe
coming up, but still it's not coming up,
it's staying on the same level,
inspite of the fact...
That means that for instance in Greece
we had the highest life expectancy
from all Europe, up to 1970. Statistics
showed that Greek people
used to live longer than
any other European country.
Also Honduras in South America they
had a very high life expectancy.
Austria, very low, Romania forget it,
very low and all the countries that were
socialists countries, that means people
could get medicines without paying,
had the lowest life expectancy.
The average was coming to 60
where other countries were
coming up to 70, 72.
Greece on 1970 or 68,  forced medical
doctors to come the villages.
It says, first you go to the village,
you practice there for 2 years and then
you can come back to the city.
So all these young doctors went all over
Greece, treating allopathically the population
and today we are very low in the scale.
Unless you take into consideration these
things, you cannot really find the solution.
As we go down we also see more and
more difficulty in finding the remedy.
So another parameter that shows
that the case is low in that scale
is the fact the remedy
is not clear.
Further than that, if you see that in
a case, several remedies indicated,
then it goes lower that scale.
The more clear the remedy,
the more high will be in the scale.
Here, where there is total confusion,
you give one remedy and in 2-3 days
you may have to change the
remedy and give another one.
Here you must not change the remedy for years. You give one remedy and you may wait
for 1 or 2 years to see the effect and
the organism is improving,
improving with one remedy.
All potencies are useful, we don't say,
we are prescribing in our school
high potencies or low potencies.
We prescribe all potencies depending
on the condition of the patient.
A lot of wrong information has been
given concerning my teaching.
In the beginning they would say, oh George
gives only high potency and when they saw
actually what I was doing, they changed.
But you know misinformation is going on
in all levels; it is the disease of our
times and you have to be very careful
what you hear about the rumors.
So I would like to hear some questions to
see whether you understand the model.
This is very important to understand quite
well before start treating a patient.
-I would like to ask if there are certain
remedies that give a clue in case of
children that they are healthier
in their expectancy of life.
For example if a child needs Calcarea.
Does it indicate already
the direction of health of the child?
-In the past I have said that I have observed
that in the children, if the child is a clear
Calcarea carbonica, that means
that this child has quite a good health.
And I still maintain this idea. If the Calcium is disturbed, it is a very strange phenomenon
that in a child who needs a lot of Calcium
and the Calcium absorption is disturbed and
you give Calcarea Carbonica
and it is reestablished etc.
It is strange that this child will live
healthily for many years whether
another child that does not have at this
age, this disturbance but has another
disturbance which does not point to
Calc but points to another remedy
or between one or two remedies.
Why such a child should have
a worse health than the Calcium?
The organism when it's stimulated gives
out a disturbance which is of the
least danger. This is a good sign
but a child who needs Aethusa, why?
Because is vomiting everything it takes,
he needs Aethusa and not Calc,
that child if you see its development
you will see that its health is
not as good as the Calc.
The predisposition that has been triggered
it's on a deeper level on the model,
the predisposition that has been
triggered already at the age of 2
is deeper than the predisposition
of the Calc child.
-This is a question, maybe to think that
is also very important the remedy
which you need to begin to see the prognosis.
This case, you said Calc or Sulph etc. and
it's right but maybe there are other remedies?
-I will tell you. Maybe I gave the
wrong impression. I did not say
the name of the remedy is important.
I say, the kind of disturbance is important.
That means if I see a disturbance where
I expected to be, a child needs a lot of
Calcium and cannot take it,
his organism gives out a reaction.
Then this reaction is Calc.
I give it and I reestablish the absorption of Calcium. If the absorption of Calcium
is disturbed then it's a good sign in the child.
But if something else is disturbed,
that means the absorption on a more complicated level,
which gives out instead of Calc.
symptoms, it gives out symptoms
of Sulphur, that means an eczema
comes out in the child.
So it's not the Calcium, it's something
else which is disturbed
or a series of other minerals which
are disturbed, giving as a result
a generalized skin eruption.
If this skin eruption points to Sulphur,
it is a worse state than the Calcarea
Carbonica but still a good state.
If the skin eruption needs first Fagopyrum and then Tuberculinum and then Sulphur.
Then we have a problem with that child.
That child is more seriously sick.
Its life expectancy is more in danger.
But what is the most natural you expect?
The disturbance on Calcium
and you see it, that's a very good sign.
-Excuse me I insist more. I wish to ask you
if on one level where we have sickness
or a child who needs Calcium but when
we have another sickness, multiple sclerosis
or epilepsy, I wish to ask you if the name of
the remedy, if the remedy is showing also
the prognosis? Because only the remedy
can show how deep this problem is.
For example epilepsy, we have Ignatia
epilepsy and Cuprum epilepsy.
Only by the name, Ignatia is more functional, Cuprum is more organic. This is my question.
-I understand. You cannot say that.
There is some truth and it is like this.
If you need a remedy for epilepsy in a child
and that remedy takes him away from epilepsy
but develops now all kinds of acute diseases where you need to treat the child constantly.
Because he gets into bronchitis, then
he gets into cystitis, into pneumonia.
That is a different prognosis than a remedy you've given -whatever it might be the remedy-
and has reestablished the health of the
child and the child remains good, healthy.
So the epilepsy with one remedy that
was cured and the child remained healthy
is better prognosis than the epilepsy that was cured but brought about some other problems.
I had a child with severe epileptic fit and
I treated the child and the child developed
the children's epidemic disease after the cure.
And every time he had the chicken pox,
his EEG was going down. That means with
the force of the acute disease the organism
tended to go back to epilepsy. Not appearing
epileptic fit but when you check out the EEG
you see it's preparing for the next fit.
Then I treat it and he had mononucleosis.
And then again the EEG is coming
up again. Then he had this or that and
you continue to treat but always with
the idea that maybe he will get a relapse.
That's not a good prognosis for the child.
You have other children, you give one remedy
and you see the EEG becoming normal and stays normal and the child is quite healthy,
it's not in that condition. Now let me tell you something else according to this model.
These levels can be affected
by microbes and bacteria,
streptococcal infections, staphylococcal infections you can see in these cases.
Usually what you see in such cases,
that they have some chronic problems,
treated with antibiotics and these
bacteria change into Proteus,
treated further it changes into Bacillus Pyocyaneous or Pseudomonas.
It's a very strange thing that you realize
that if the person has been on this level,
his health has come down quite considerably.
In that state in which he is now, down here,
cannot be affected by microbes or bacteria.
And then you go all types of Fungi will
eventually develop in that body.
So as you go down the ladder, you
notice that the organisms are affected by
microorganisms, virus and here in
these levels comes the AIDS virus.
You have to bring your health to
that state, very much low,
before you can be affected
by the AIDS virus.
In this state here, you cannot be affected anymore by the gonococcus or the Syphilis.
Syphilis can affect people up to here. From
here downwards Syphilis cannot be contracted.
These people are protected from gonococcal infections because they have very bad health.
Here belong people who are
disturbed mentally, emotionally etc.
Take a person from a mental asylum,
anybody with schizophrenia and make him
have intercourse with one who has
Syphilis. He will never get it.
Eternal happiness. You get him to
have sex with somebody
who has Gonorrhea. He will not get it.
Make this person here with
severe mental disorders,
inject microbes if you want in his
organism. He will not be infected.
If he is affected then during the
time of the infection, that means
when he has a very high fever,
his mind will come back to normal.
These are observations which all
psychiatrists who have worked in hospitals,
they know for sure to be true.
There was a period of time,
in the history of psychotherapy
where they said, 'inject Tuberculus
bacillus into the schizophrenics
and then you create a reaction
and then you see some amelioration'.
The problem was that when the fever
was rising, it had to stay high
for a long period of time and then of course
they were getting afraid that the person will die
and would give him back the antibiotics
and back into the state of schizophrenia.
These, you think, they are theories.
They are not theory,
they are the rules that
rule health and disease.
- Hahnemann said about the intensity
of the external influence.
But in this case, when you inject
something, especially to Hepatitis B
or C which is from blood transfusion,
what do you mean about this?
Hahnemann said, when these influences
are very strong can become,
can be the origin of a chronic disease.
-He does not say that. I should put it to you
as an exercise to find out. Hahnemann,
what exactly says concerning the effect of the
human body if you inject foreign substances,
which are the paragraphs in which he talks about the effect on the human organism?
Another question since you are writing
is, where Hahnemann mentions
the idea of a second or third remedy?
Under what conditions?
-There are people who are mentally ill,
Alzheimer patients for example.
So they wouldn't get a flu or a
pneumonia and to die for that.
-This is correct, if they do get, during
the course of the pneumonia
their mental state will improve
but the pneumonia will kill them.
The pneumonia is not
treatable homeopathically.
It can be treated allopathically and throw them back to the state of Alzheimer condition.
Homeopathically you will not be able to
treat a pneumonia (very seldom phenomena)
that develops, in an Alzheimer person.
Unless there is a possibility for a cure
of that person, in which case you will see a
clear picture of the pneumonia remedy
and then you give and then you give the
2nd, the 3rd and maybe you bring back the
consciousness and awareness
of the people, very improbable.
The most probable is that during
the pneumonia now, they will die.
Even with allopathic treatment
is very possible that they will die.
-If a person has got AIDS and you treat
him and he develops gonorrhea,
would you say the case is on the right way?
-Yes, I will show you a case that I was
treating with AIDS, he was in that state.
It is very interesting also if you have some experience with AIDS people,
the young AIDS people who are suffering,
they started with  a very good
state of health. Very strong people,
what they did?
They took gonorrheas, they took
antibiotics, again gonorrhea
again antibiotics, then syphilis,
again antibiotics etc. then eventually
you have the development of AIDS virus.
That means they broke down from here,
usually people of that level, AIDS people
and you see they bring down, fungi,
they are full of fungi etc. and then
virus and then the AIDS.
During the state of AIDS, you ask them,
'did you stop having sexual intercourse?'
They say, no. 'Did you get again gonorrhea?',
'No'. 'Did you get syphilis?', 'No'.
I treated such a person and I predicted
in the class, not in front of him,
I said, this person with this
remedy is going to be better.
Now he will be so much better that if
he goes again and have unprotected sex,
he will then again get Gonorrhea and it
happened exactly as I predicted.
He got better, he got Gonorrhea,
he treated Gonorrhea with antibiotics
and then back to the state.
You are able, if you really know the model,
you are able to do these things.
I predicted another case, they brought me
in London again, a case of AIDS.
And I said if he keeps away and he does not reinfect, he will live 20 more years, no problem.
He was a man 53 years old, why?
Because his remedy was very clear.
I said, with this remedy this person can live 20 more years, though he had the secondary state.
You know in AIDS we have different
stages. We have 3 stages.
The first stage in which we have
very mild symptomatology,
the second stage in which we have the AIDS related symptoms, we have the glands swollen,
we have the diarrhea and the exhaustion and then we have the third stage in which we have
the Kaposi sarcoma and usually the
pneumonia Carinii develops very frequently
and this makes them
fast to go the next stage.
So if you get pneumonia Carinii
forget it, they have reached here,
how can you find the remedy?
Every time they try to find the remedy
there is no possibility to see it.
The case I'm talking about is AIDS
related, we have the diarrhoea,
the exhaustion and
the lymphadenopathy.
At that stage some organisms are still quite strong, they show the remedy, you give them,
you uplift them and then again back
to the possibility of getting reinfected
because all these groups here,
are affected by Gonorrhoea and Syphilis.
There is a state under which Gonorrhoea
and Syphilis do not affect.
The same as the people in mental asylum.
They can live in a terrible situation,
they can sleep in mud the whole night, they wake up in the morning, nothing happens.
No pneumonia, no bronchitis, nothing.
How is that?
Can you sleep one night inside the water?
See what happens next day.
Do you perceive what I say? These children
here they will not get epidemic diseases.
Because here we have epilepsy and
during this state of epilepsy the child
cannot get any epidemic disease.
You treat him with epilepsy, you bring
him up and then he starts being infected
by different agents which are for
this level in which he is.
You see, Fungi it can be all this. All this can be affected by Fungi, different types of Fungi.
All this can be affected by bacteria,
Gonorrhoea, Syphilis etc.
And virus can affect up to here. From
here, downwards virus cannot affect.
Is it possible for any schizophrenic
to be affected by AIDS? It's not possible.
If he is affected by AIDS,
he will improve mentally.
- I disagree with you. We have the AIDS
induced encephalopathy
and this can have forms
of schizophrenia too.
-You are talking about a different thing.
The symptomatology of AIDS can affect
also the central nervous system where
we have mental symptomatology.
The AIDS itself, that means the virus,
can affect different parts of the system.
It can affect the lungs, the liver, the brains,
the nervous system; in certain cases of AIDS,
we have the effect of the virus upon the
central nervous system. Why this is so?
Because of the predispositions I was
talking on the different people.
Once they have a predisposition on the
mental, once the disease is overwhelming
it will affect the mental level as well.
What I say is, that a schizophrenic who is from 16 years old to schizophrenia, now he is 40.
You may him have sexual intercourse
with a person who has AIDS.
He will not get the disease, he is protected
by the fact that he is more sick;
he is on a lower level than AIDS can affect.
This is what I'm saying.
-Is it true that there is a predisposition
to the vaccination for the babies?
Would you say that some of them
are born with predisposition?
And therefore they react, some of them react and some of them don't react to the vaccination?
-Yes exactly.
If you vaccinate these people
here, there is no effect.
-No, what I mean is, when they are 2-3 months old, when you give the first vaccination.
Is there predisposition that might cause the reaction to the vaccination?
-Yes. If they had a side effect, a complication
that means they had a predisposition towards
that disease. If they have a big reaction,
they have quite strong predisposition
and if that leaves them invalid, that means
the predisposition was really great.
The vaccination will affect this
population not at all.
From here on, you get a kind of a
reaction and there is a point in this,
where all these people are predisposed
for that particular disease.
Then you will have in these levels a
big reaction and then you have
the side effects of vaccination.
Let me take it from another point of view.
Every organism has or has not
predisposition for certain diseases.
Let us take Poliomyelitis. There are
certain people from us, who have
a predisposition for that disease.
If these people get the Polio vaccination,
they are going to have a big reaction.
Some of us whose their predisposition
is very great, they will actually get
symptoms of Poliomyelitis.
So the vaccination actually, what it does?
Those who are predisposed in an
epidemic will get the disease,
makes them get it in any case
through the vaccination.
The claim is, they say, that if the epidemic comes, the deaths will be more.
The argument is that if you give vaccination
to all population, then you will have
a massive side effect from mild to serious
which we have to measure whether
all this massive effect, that means bringing down the level of health in a massif population
is it worthy? Or is it better than having the epidemic itself and treat the epidemic?
If it comes.
I don't know, I cannot say for sure what
is better. I have an idea but my ideas
concerning health and disease are different
than the ideas of the governments.
-You say that a patient who has epilepsy
will not be affected by vaccination.
I had a patient, I managed to treat, not to
cure but to control the fit of epilepsy
for a certain time. He cut himself and his
mother rushed to the doctor
and he had the tetanus vaccination.
The fit started all over again.
Can you explain to me
how that happened?
-This is exactly what I say. You treated
this child and from this level
you brought it up to this
level, no epilepsy.
Now the vaccine comes while
the child is on that level
and brings the child
back to this level, of the epilepsy.
This is what I say, that if the vaccine has
any effect at all is to bring down the health
and protect the organism from the
microbes and the bacteria.
Smallpox is acting on these levels,
only on these levels.
What you have to do is to bring
all this population down here
through vaccination and then smallpox
will not affect you anymore.
That is why in older times when they used
to use the vaccination for smallpox,
people were having chronic conditions
after  the vaccination, headaches,
epilepsy, asthma. From which cause?
The vaccination.
Ok, give Thuja. That's how the idea
of Thuja came against vaccination.
Thuja treated a lot of such cases.
The idea is that unless you bring down
the organism, you don't protect it.
If the organism has a reaction,
these organisms most of them,
especially this type of people, will have
a big reaction to vaccination and
they counteract the vaccination.
That means that the vaccination
is as if it was never given to them.
That's why in a study they did in India
where we had smallpox epidemics
the epidemic came in a town
where it was vaccinated.
And another town was left unvaccinated.
The epidemic came and the results
were equally the same with the vaccinated
and the non vaccinated population.
Those who died were the same amount
with those who died non-vaccinated.
You will say, but smallpox
has been eliminated.
I would claim, that smallpox because it was affecting only this part of the population
you brought all the population down
here and then you protect it, of course.
If the theory is correct then we may have to rethink what are we doing to the population?
If what he says, which is my experience also, that after treating somebody who is quite well,
then you give a vaccination and you bring
him down again, that means that there is
something wrong with the idea of vaccination.
With AIDS now, they found a vaccination
that protects the people.
That means they will bring down
all the population down here.
Mentally sick people can not be
affected anymore by AIDS virus.
That means you have madness
all over but no AIDS.
-What offers this protection? Is it
that the force of the disease
is already spent on a focus?
Or the vital force or the reaction
of the organism is no longer
to get affected by these smaller ones?
What is the protection of the organism
when is too sick by one thing
to be affected by a smaller one.
-There is no protection. What I say is:
the more the population raises,
the more are affected by virus
and microbes of that area.
The more we bring down the health of the population, the more the population is affected
by new virus, by new bacteria, by new microorganisms that are going to be discovered.
I have predicted in 1970 the effect of
AIDS and actually I was talking on the Greek
and it is recorded on tape. I said to them,
the way you are prescribing antibiotics
is going to break down the immune system
and a new disease will appear
which will not be treatable by anything,
I could not name it, this is AIDS or whatever.
And actually what happened was exactly that. The immune system was broken down
by frequent use of antibiotics to the
highest risk group that were
the homosexuals who were taking
as protection every day, antibiotics.
They were finding someone to have sex
and before they use to take antibiotics
to protect them from contracting
Gonorrhea or Syphilis.
Many of them contracted the Gonorrhea
and Syphilis inspite the protection
and they had to take
big doses of antibiotics.
In 1983 when I knew the whole situation
I said, this disease is a venereal disease
and it's a combination of Gonorrhea,
Syphilis and antibiotics.
And Coulter was present, sitting in the
class and then he brought out the book
Syphilis and interconnections which is wrong.
Because he grasped part of my idea,
not the whole idea. It's not the Syphilis
that has a connection, no.
It's the Syphilis, Gonorrhea plus
antibiotics. The 3 combined breaks down
the immune system and then you have
the development of AIDS virus,
which virus was always there on the planet.
It's not something new that comes from Sirius.
The virus was always with us but it did
not affect us. The moment you bring down
the immune system, that particular virus
explodes and overwhelms the organism.
Then it becomes very virulent because
it takes strength by breeding.
If you breed a virus you make it stronger.
Then this virus can affect even somebody
who has never taken an antibiotic
but whose health is quite low.
You see if the health is low, our health
is low, we are in danger of AIDS.
If our health is here, not danger.
If it is here, no danger.
If we are close to die, no danger. If we
are close to absolute health, no danger.
Otherwise we are in danger.
-We know from children disease, that
whenever a child who is normal and healthy,
contracts a children disease and
then it comes over the disease,
he gets into a healthier state. Does it mean
that if you have normal children diseases,
they are the source of something good for them which is bringing their health to higher levels?
-That is correct to a certain extent because
with epidemic children diseases you may have
another level which is  the eternal level,
you may have the death of the child also.
So after a disease you may have the side effect of the disease that means much worse health,
you may have the same health and in
some cases it may be even improved.
The idea is if you have homeopathic treatment where the organism is stimulated well,
then most probably you have a
better health than before.
But not without homeopathic treatment.
Without it, you may have death, side effects,
same conditions or sometimes better.
- Next question is concerning
the remedy Carcinosin.
With this remedy we know that often
children do not get the children
diseases or they get it very late in life.
How do you comment this?
-I don't agree with that. With Carcinosin,
if it is indicated, in very few cases,
you may protect the child from acute
diseases like any other remedy.
Any other remedy which is indicated will protect the child from getting frequent acute diseases.
Carcinosin belongs to the same
category as every other remedy.
If you get this wrong idea that if I give Carcinosin, I protect, then it's wrong
and you are going to dispense a lot of
Carcinosin to the wrong persons.
Only if indicated, whether it is
Calc., Phos., Merc.,
whatever is the remedy
will protect the child.
- I said that with Carcinosin, as
a part of the picture, we may have
absence of children diseases at the
normal age because most of the children
get the children diseases
and it is written in the book.
-This is wrong, who wrote this?
-In the Materia Medica.
If you read my Carcinosin, you will not
see such a thing and it is beyond logic.
Unless there is indication of Carcinosin, and
it really improves the health of the person,
there is no protection.
The only protection is, if it is indicated
and it has an effect, if you just give
it routinely to protect it's wrong.
-Let's say a person who has in the
family history, he has had cancer.
So this should be that he was
born in the state which is here
so he can contract the children
diseases which are there.
That's why we are missing the
picture of the remedy.
-A person with cancer parents can
be born in any place.
He can be born here with cancer
which is curable. It doesn't mean that
he will be born here. But if you give
Carcinosin in this place and then you raise
and you bring him here, on the contrary,
he will contract the disease.
It is the opposite, not only you don't
protect from children disease
but you expose it to chronic disease.
I mean in our litterature if you go and read
all the opinions of different people,
you can go crazy. Everyone has an idea.
You have to use your logic.
-As I understood if the picture of the disease
is clear or not is a parameter to recognize
if the constitution is good or bad. Does that
mean that if we would know more
remedies more clear that we
could recognize much more?
This would mean that the constitution
would depend on our knowledge.
-In a way yes, that is true. What is
going to happen in the child,
depends on our knowledge,
absolutely yes.
But there are some rules
that we cannot overcome.
You can say that nevermind what
disease the child has, if I knew very well
Homeopathy I could save everybody
and lift them from this prognosis of dying
in 5 years I could make him
live until 90, this forget it.
But if you say that out of these children
who are dying at the age of 10,
you can save 5% and if I know better
I can save 20%. This you can say it.
You can also say that if I know
Homeopathy better, then I can lift a child
from this level to this level, not to
this only. This you can do.
But to think that by knowing Homeopathy
you can save all of them, forget it.
-I want to ask if there is any connection between this theory and the epidemic from Romania
of meningoencephalitis which affects
only the people between 30-40 years,
not the children and it's lethal.
It's an unknown virus.
-This falls again into what I say.
The swine fever, a new virus.
There are about 20-30 epidemics which
have been discovered the last years,
especially the swine fever which was affecting mostly soldiers who were fighting in Korea.
Most probably they took certain
drugs that predisposed them
to a particular virus
that brought out like this.
In Romania most probably, you see
the system was giving medicine
to the people without paying.
Is that correct?
-Yes.
-So anybody could go to the doctor and say,
give me medicine. He would give medicine.
But the medicine was really the good
medicine? Was it quality medicine?
They were over prescribed most probably.
So if you see statistics, you will see that
Romania is one of the lowest life expectancy, the same with Hungary, with Poland,
with Russia, and all these countries
were low though they had coverage
by allopathic medicine quite a lot
because it was social medicine.
Everybody could get medicine where in
Greece nobody could find medicine.
Here, in this island when I came, first
time in 1968, there was no doctor.
There was an old man living here who played
the doctor. He would take out your tooth,
he would set your bones and things like that.
Still before him there was nothing but,
what we call, herbal medicine. The old population used to live up to 90-95.
The younger population, you say,
are you taking drugs? Yes.
The pharmacy is selling tremendous
amounts of medicine to a population
that was healthy 20-30 years ago
and did not need any medicine
and they lived very long.
Now who sees that?
Is any government who sees that?
They all close their eyes to the facts.