The title of the article is ‘The Continuum of a Unified Theory of Diseases’.
When a person is born and starts having some medical problems
and the newborn child is treated most probably for acute conditions
there are 2 possibilities, after they have been treated,
usually antibiotics or cortisone or chemical drugs, anti-inflammatory depending on the problem
after they have been treated with such heavy chemical drugs the organism has two possibilities;
one is to get rid of the chemicals as well as getting rid of the disease.
That’s one possibility that means you give a lot of drugs, the pneumonia subsides
and later on the organism tries to get rid of the effect of the antibiotics or the chemicals.
The second possibility is in case the immune system is not strong enough
what is going to happen is subdue the acute condition but the organism does not have the power to get rid of the acute
and what is the best it can do is submit itself to the power of drugs in which case
the acute inflammatory process becomes a sub-acute chronic inflammatory process.
This sub-acute inflammatory process is what we call a chronic degenerative disease.
What kind of an inflammation of a chronic degenerative disease
an organism will develop will depend on genetic predisposition.
So, if the genetic predisposition is towards a sensitivity on the ears
it will develop ear problems of severe or less severe condition.
If the predisposition is for epilepsy they will develop epilepsy,
if the predisposition is for asthma, especially because
the primary inflammation in the children is in the respiratory system
that is why we have so many cases of asthmatic conditions that have been created by suppression
of acute respiratory diseases like bronchitis, pneumonia, pharyngitis, laryngitis,
it can push the disease to deeper sights, the lungs, and then we have the manifestation of chronic asthma.
The idea I was giving in this article was that; unless the organism had the possibility
to get rid of the disease and the effect of the drugs then we will definitely
have the manifestation of a predisposition of the organism.
That organism can manifest all types of diseases as we call today.
At least most of the times it’s not that the chemical itself will give a problem
but it will trigger the predisposition of the organism.
The suppression can create a chronic condition of asthma.
The suppression of severe laryngitis can create asthmatic condition.
As you go down to the respiratory system, the bronchi, suppression of the bronchi,
then the disease that will develop will be more and more difficult
if the suppression had started from an area in the respiratory system that is deep which is the lung, pneumonia.
Therefore, what I claim in the article is that there is a continuum of diseases
and these diseases acute, chronic or developed by chemical drugs they have a continuum, they are connected with each other.
We cannot say he had gonorrhea or syphilis, it’s nothing take some antibiotics and it’s gone.
Unless the organism is very strong in such a case then it’s gone.
But how many people have so strong organisms today?
In most of the people the treating of an acute condition, whatever it might be,
is going to leave most probably, its mark and from an acute inflammatory condition becomes a sub-inflammatory process.
That’s why many years ago I have said all diseases are sub-inflammatory processes.
I remember 2 years ago one of my students came and he said
“I found this in a medical journal that schizophrenia is an inflammatory process.”
Nobody could ever imagine that. There are some inflammations
which are going on either of some proteins or whatever and then they reducing
for some time and then the inflammation comes up again and then the crisis comes.
So Medicine in general in its effort to try to subdue acute, epidemic condition
they have found ways to suppress and in which case we have the side effects
and we have a person who is going in his life but is damaged irreparably in his life
unless the immune system is again stimulated by the right way to bring about the original inflammation.
Unless in a case you find again the original inflammation, that means the organism
as it was going towards a degeneration after the homeopathic treatment starts a regeneration
and must reach a point where the original acute must reappear.
20-21-22 this is the age they get gonorrhea.
The idea is that either the condition remains as non-specific urethritis that means in the morning there is a discharge.
It can go on for years. If the person takes a lot of antibiotics to stop this little discharge
this discharge will manifest in the respiratory and the upper respiratory system especially post-nasally.
If you study the blood picture of a person who had gonorrhea at the age of 20
and he comes now he’s 50-60 and you start looking at his blood you will not find any gonorrhea.
This is transferred to another type of microbe, bacteria, fungus etc.
They have modified the original bacteria.
When we say suppression we do not mean immediately that you will immediately find in a streptococcal pneumonia
that in the chronic condition you will find streptococcal infection in the organism.
No. There is no direct line in which you can say he was having a staphylococcal infection on the skin
and now he has a staphylococcal infection in the lungs.
You must not try to do this. The organism works differently.
I will give you an example. Let’s say you have a case of carbuncles
and you start treating with antibiotics.
After 1-2 years they appear again and now you find out that now it’s proteus.
You keep on giving remedies, antibiotics to fight proteus infection
and after a few years you find that it is bacillus pyocyaneus (pseudomonas),
much more severe infection that the original staphylococcal infection.
Yet there is one line but you must not try to say now it is bacillus pyocyaneus, it is a different infection.
No! The organism has changed, modified the original staphylococcal infection to proteus
and to pseudomonas and perhaps to new strange which we found now in the hospitals,
hospital infections which are resistant to all types of antibiotics we know.
How has this happened? How this new strange microbes have developed?
It doesn’t mean because you find something totally different in the examination now that that’s different.
No. It’s a continuum. And diseases can be considered, each one as a unified thing. It’s not isolated.Now I got this.
No. You got now this condition because of this, this and that you had before.