25 countries welcome and I hope you will enjoy the course, the sun, the heat and the heat
that is going be created inside here also due to some ideas.
What is the topic? That’s a good question.
As always I confess the truth.
I have to confess that until yesterday I had no idea what to say this morning
because the first day always there is a speech on theory and the main teaching here is done through live cases.
You have come here as professionals to see live cases, how I take a case, how I analyze the case and how I prescribe.
So most of the time you will be seeing live cases either for the first time or follow-ups.
Because here due to the fact we do not have available a hospital in any country where one could see live cases
we have to organize these courses in order that the professional homeopaths could see live cases
and not just see the case but also the follow-up which is the most important.
Because the most of the problems we have as homeopaths are when we have prescribed a case,
we have seen the reaction and then we have to decide what to do further in that case.
This is the most difficult part for Homeopathy, find the first remedy maybe is the easiest part.
To know how to follow a case is quite difficult.
The reason is that our organisms have been compromised in our lives due to several factors
that there is a confusion in the organisms that we see today as cases especially in Europe and the U.S.
I want to make clear some points which will give you a different understanding from the understanding you have from the medical schools.
When a child is born is a happy existence.
All happy children are very healthy what you see is they are laughing, they are very happy.
This is the primary goal in life. To be happy.
Now, we intervene in these organisms in different ways and by interfering we compromise the defense mechanism,
the immune system, finally we compromise the feeling of the well-being that we should be there all the time.
We become more and more anxious, depressed etc.
We become angrier, hypochondriac, phobic… All this is not natural for human beings.
The natural tendency is for us to be happy.
The more we lose joy and happiness on the process of becoming adults then the more we have compromised our health.
How this has happened? This has happened through interference from the very young age mostly with vaccination,
through antibiotics, through strong drugs that compromise the immune system.
Therefore my experience in treating patients and listening to the development of the pathology
which is in front of me I felt that this could not be just accidental. It must have had a kind of continuum.
That means we are born happy and through several interferences finally we become unhappy, depressed, anxious, phobic and finally mentally disturbed.
Most of the population especially of the population of the western worlds has become so unhealthy.
Therefore I asked what is happening and I wanted to understand and then I realized that what happens is that…
By the time I was looking at the cases, don’t forget it was in the 1960s, by that time I could see the history of the patient
that he was having acutes repeatedly as a child and at a certain moment the acutes were stopping and chronic condition was manifesting.
How this happens? It happens most probably because when the acutes were treated… tonsillitis with high fever in children,
it’s the first system that gets infected, the respiratory system and what guards the respiratory system are the tonsils,
tonsils are taking all the impact, high fevers, antibiotics and then next year 2 times antibiotics, next year 3 times antibiotics
and 4-5 years when the boy is 14-15 no more high fevers. And everybody was happy except of the organism.
The organism knew that something has happened in the whole mechanism of defense, the endothelial system, the neurovegetative system,
hormonal system, some changes have happened in 1 or2 of these systems that now the organism
would not react anymore to staphylococcus or streptococcus that was happening the previous years.
I thought what happens is that the organism through the suppression with antibiotics of the acute conditions they have been traumatized,
harassed and they could not anymore react to an invention of the bacteria that were causing the high fever.
In the meantime what we knew from the theory of Homeopathy was that if you prescribe correctly in a case then sometimes
an old condition manifests again, an old condition that was with high fever.
So you prescribe a remedy and suddenly though for 10-15 years the person did not have any high fever suddenly he develops high fever.
So, when we see this we say that’s perfect. This was not known before.
It was not known that if fever returns that means the immune system has been again complete, has recovered.
This is quite understandable, quite simple but if we proceed further to the analysis of this state we see that later on
we have the development of chronic headaches, migraines and he takes painkillers.
When I have a headache I take a painkiller and then there is a time after lots of painkillers suppressing the migraines,
a more serious chronic condition develops.
What can it be? We have the manifestation of autoimmune diseases, neuromuscular diseases, cancer, malignancies of all types
and then we wonder why in our societies there are so many people suffering of malignant blood pressure, with heart conditions.
Who is free from such conditions? Once you examine a person over 50 you can hardly find anyone
who is free from taking drugs to cover up the condition.
What has actually happened in the organism… If there is a treatment of an acute or a chronic condition
and that treatment is not according to the nature, what nature wants but it’s against it that means if nature wants to have a high fever
for 5 days before it can go over it and the second day you do not allow the fever to go on and you start giving antibiotics,
what happens is that the organism is in a turmoil and is forced not to show the fever.
That means you have killed all the bacteria and together with them who are causing the fever you have killed some useful bacteria
that now will start developing problems of a chronic condition.
If a disease has not been cured in a natural way and if that disease was a serious acute condition
then always you will have the imprint on the organism of that moment which will reappear after your good prescription
even after 20 years that this suppression has taken place.
That means with every treatment which is not natural, which you do not allow the organism to go through it, suffer as much as needed
in order to have an auto-cure then you invariably inflict upon the organism a problem that in its place manifests another condition
which is much worse than the acute.
All this idea gave me the idea of writing a few years ago the continuum of a unified theory of the diseases.
I don’t know if anybody has read this article.
I will send you the link of the medical journal that has published this, so you can download it and fully read it.
Through the life of a person, from birth to death, there is a continuum, a sequence of natural diseases, acute and chronic.
When acute diseases are not properly treated and the patient has a weakened immune system,
the over-all health of the individual is permanently compromised.
According to this understanding you see what we have done.
We said we don’t want to have chickenpox and therefore we have a vaccination that will not allow the organism to develop chickenpox
or scarlatina or whooping-cough or mumps, not any children’s epidemic diseases.
I was born as you know in 1932 and by that time there were no vaccination.
There were just natural epidemic acute diseases that all children had to go through.
I was fortunate to be born during that time.
The vaccinations do not allow the development of acute diseases which the organism had to go through itself
and of course either will survive or die. This is the natural selection.
We are living in that opportunity of living in a world that the population of earth is determined
how many will survive and die but what we call a natural selection.
So a child who could not go through an acute epidemic would die of course.
I see your eyes asking now what do you suggest? Let the children die?
Today, we have become so sick in our minds that instead of having natural selection we have war selection.
We select by bombs. We select by killing, smashing lives of people indifferently whether they are healthy or sick, it doesn’t matter.
War selection is not anymore natural selection.
But who thinks of the war? Ask yourselves, can I kill somebody? Bring yourself in such a state…
Maybe a Stram. would like to kill somebody.
But a person who is considerably healthy is impossible to think that I have in front of me somebody and I want to kill
or I don’t care if I kill or not.
It’s not possible. The minds of the people who conceive the wars are sick minds that we have produced through scientific medicine, unfortunately.
This is the fact. This is the truth. But my child is alive.
Yes, it is alive but what is the cost? You have a child that at the age of 12-15 because of his natural disease
which is in the mind he will go into narcotics, drugs, fights and killings.
The U.S., Bill Clinton had confessed that he was taking drugs.
I cannot imagine that a person who is happy will go and take drugs.
Why? To become unhappy? Who wants to become unhappy? Why people are going to drugs? The young population…
When I was teaching in the U.S. I said to the class, about this size, who has taken drugs? You know the Americans are very open.
Everybody raised his hand, the whole class, there was no exemption.
I could not find one that said I did not take drugs.
Why? Marijuana? Marijuana is good… they want to make marijuana legal to gain what? Because the people will not be exploited.
And then free cocaine, then eventually the whole world goes mad, we kill each other, we throw nuclear bombs and we’re finished.
I have been thinking all these and I wrote this article.
And I said why this is happening? We have to find the reason.
Why are we in such a state and we have to find a way out.
Otherwise the time is running very fast and we are going to kill each other very soon.
What is the alternative? Except of other alternatives for which I know
but I don’t know their impact Homeopathy has the possibility to cure a person.
What has happened with Homeopathy? Homeopathy can have impressive results. Not always.
But what has happened and Homeopathy is not accepted on a global level and not practiced on global level
since it is such a fantastic treatment? I’ll go to another subject.
When you give a remedy what is the parameter that will tell you that your remedy has a correct reaction?
What you want to see in the person to make certain for yourself that your remedy was acting towards the right direction?
You remember the direction we said in the beginning, when the child is born is happy so unless the direction is towards this,
making the person more happy, joyful, complete inside, unless you aim at this your remedy is either wrong
or the organism you are treating is yet not able to attain the state of joy and happiness. And you have to struggle more.
I’ll give an example. Sep. is a remedy that is over-sexual or under-sexual? Under-sexual, usually there is an aversion to sex.
So a case comes to you and one of the main problems is that she has aversion to sex.
She’s married , she still has sex, she never enjoyed it, never had an orgasm and such a person creates a social situation around her,
is a woman who is not caring about the husband, whether the husband is flirting, running away, because she doesn’t care.
So you prescribe the remedy and the remedy is correct and the hormonal system that had so low estrogens is reviving
and the woman for the first time feels the pleasure of sex. You know what is going to happen by that time?
Is she going to be happy? No. She starts being unhappy now.
Because she realizes that she is jealous with her husband and every time her husband looks… So she will come back to you to tell you
I’m unhappy and then you will say what is happening to you, suddenly I feel so much jealous about my husband
that I can’t sleep, cannot let it out of my mind that he may be running away. The husband may not be running away but Lach.
will imagine that her husband is running with somebody else.
And then you give Lach.
I speak about a case which is quite healthy because there are others more complicated patients, but after Lach.
the enjoyment for sex will continue without this tantalizing effect of jealousy so much but the disturbance now will start manifesting in the physical body.
In what form? It may take any form. It may take any form.
It might be the hormonal system, muscular system, joints, neuromuscular system, anything!
But the physical body will be taking most of the force because this organism has been undermined through their life,
their mother and father and hereditary condition, to such an extent that one remedy is not going to be enough,
second remedy is not going to be enough then it ends up in a rheumatoid arthritis that you need to treat most probably.
You have to treat that for a few years before the whole organism is completely free of disease.
Now, we have at our disposal such a system.
We have a system where when a child has high fever we go along with his reaction and we’ll give a remedy
which produces high fever Bell., Acon., Stram. or Calc.
Then the fever goes out and there is no trauma left.
You suppress it; you leave a trauma, you let it express through Homeopathy the similar remedy
because the similar remedy produces the same impulse within the body the impulse of the body
when attacked by a microbe is to create a totality of symptoms and that similar totality has been produced by the remedy.
You give it and you force the organism to express it, you help the organism to express and fight the disease.
Can you imagine a system of medicine which is accepted globally that takes this child from the very beginning
and treats it in a natural way and then you will have no traumas left into the body? This is not all.
Because the traumas, “τραύμα” is a Greek word, when I want to pronounce it with English pronunciation I cannot pronounce it.
I don’t know if it is traumas… The Greek word is “τραύμα”.
The English say not “τραύμα”, trauma… it’s very difficult.
But see what happens. You don’t have only the vaccinations, the antibiotics, the cortisone, the neuroleptics etc.
Because the organism has been undermined by all these drugs, chemical etc.
it has become unable to face mental or emotional stresses.
The moment that there is a mental/emotional stress there is a tremendous commotion in the organism.
We say we Nat-m., when a Nat-m. has been rejected in a relationship, even one time, what if it happens 2-3 times,
creates such a deep trauma in the organism that after that you may have a kind of reaction on the long run
that means after 2-10 years, when you have the manifestation of severe heart condition, severe neuromuscular disease, severe rheumatoid arthritis etc.
I had a case about one year ago. A medical doctor called me and says I have cancer.
I knew this man was quite healthy. You have cancer? Why? And then I take his case and I see Nat-m. is indicated.
I said did you have a stress lately? He said yes I had. What was this stress? I was accused falsely.
For what? For a subject I don’t want to discuss now.
But he had no children, he was 50 year-old.
Strong, a lot of energy, happiness and one shock like this where he felt his pride, his integrity,
everything he believed for himself, being a righteous person, was shaken in its foundations.
And this man he had in his mind to leave all his belongings, he was quite rich person, with houses etc.
to leave it to the child of the woman who accused him.
He loved the child and the couple so much that he thought everything that belongs to me when I die will go their child.
This woman comes and falsely accuses him for doing something wrong.
He was speechless. He could not defend himself. 1,5 year later he comes and says they found by chance cancer in my lungs.
I said ok… Take Nat-m. 50M. In the meantime there was collection in the pleura. I gave Nat-m. he started coughing.
I gave Nat-m. and he said I feel… there is a Greek expression but I cannot translate it which means in perfect health, within 3 days.
But the collection of the pleura was keeping on so I said they can draw the liquid from the lung mechanically to relieve you.
He is a medical doctor, he works in the hospital together with all other colleagues of all specialties and they want to save him.
He continues to feel well but there is a collection of liquid in the pleura.
So they suggest that they have a very simple operation in which they can close the opening in the pleura so it will stop discharging.
Do you understand perhaps? He asked me my opinion. I said you’re feeling well… yes, but the liquid is collection.
Yes but you’re feeling well. So it’s up to you, you decide. So they persuaded him to close this with a powder like cement.
Like wetness coming through the wall and then you plaster it not to see the wetness. It will keep on coming.
The moment they closed this, within a few days he started coughing. Coughing.
And once he started coughing he does not come anymore to see what we’ll do though it would be difficult for me now
to counteract what they have done so he goes and takes chemotherapy.
And they persuaded him to take 1 week of chemotherapy and it will over.
Then 2 weeks of chemotherapy and will be over.
Then 3,4 ,5 weeks and died… These are every day experience for us.
What shall we suggest? This article was written out of these experiences.
I suggest you should read the whole article and you will get some idea of what we are teaching here.
Because if you come to me with all the trauma from the antibiotics, the vaccination plus the trauma of your life.
One trauma after another in the life and then you say I feel tired all the time and I don’t feel very well,
I have some anxiety and depression sometimes and then I have some pains in the joints…
Underneath this organism who appears not to have yet a dramatic condition you realize as a homeopath that the defense mechanism as a total
is so much compromised that you may need 10 years of treating the case before the person can say I now feel well.
But listen now. The outside world, especially the scientific world and the skeptics and all these nonsense they ask where is the evidence?
Show us the evidence. How shall we show you the evidence? Double-blind trials.
What is double-blind trials? You have to give a remedy to the whole class for the same pathology and you have to show
that 70% of them are cured by this remedy. You have 100 cases of asthma and which is the remedy for asthma?
We don’t have but sometimes we think that a good remedy for asthma is Nat-s. or Kali-s. or Kali-c.
If you give all these only 5% perhaps will be cured.
How can you show that this is going to be a remedy for asthma? It’s not possible.
So you see the problem we have in establishing this kind of treatment that we believe in.
And what shall we do? We have to work. All of us. Not 1,2 or 10 persons.
If you are convinced about the correctness of the treatment you go along and you do everything possible; you write on Facebook, you tweet,
you send letters to your ministers of health.
Unless all of us are active what can we do? There is a English expression. “Let George do it”.
When I was living in England they told me “let George do it”.
I come back to the main idea of giving joy to the patient.
Then there is the responsibility of the individual after you give him the possibility to have joy again, have happiness again,
it is the responsibility of the individual to keep this condition.
Because if he exposes himself into stresses it is mathematically sure that he will have a relapse.
I’ll give an example. You know Staph. it’s a remedy that we give to individuals, especially women, who are suppressed.
That means they say yes to everything the husband says.
Yes, yes… But they don’t believe inside there is a reaction.
Then you give Staph. high potency to such an individual and suddenly there is a change in the mental/emotional structure of the individual
and after all she says why do you shout to me? So the husband says what did you say? I said why do you shout to me? He is surprised.
She never used to talk to me that way and they start fighting.
See now the sensitive point.
A woman who wants to keep her relationship with her husband she has to find a way of compromising a little
in order to keep the husband happy because the husband has been used to come and say where is my food.
This is not good… and the woman… oh yes, I will do. The Greek woman.
I don’t speak about the Danish or the Swiss woman. This doesn’t exist there. But Turkish, Indian woman maybe.
I am talking to you about real cases. You give this remedy and then there is a fight.
The woman demands respect. And the husband does not like it.
He says what is this? If the woman continues in an aggressive way then end result will be divorce.
The divorce has a price which is paid on the mental/emotional level.
So unless the woman understands how she should handle the matter now that she feels stronger and more demanding,
if she carries it to the extreme she will end up with a divorce.
The divorce will have a depression and the woman will come to you. I separated with my husband.
She doesn’t know that you gave the remedy and the remedy had the effect. Neither you tell her.
You don’t tell her take the remedy, you divorce your husband! You have to be very careful!
But this is a fact that we know that can happen.
And if the woman comes back to you because of her arthritis, skin eruption, for different reasons
and as you examine her you say you feel suppressed then you come down to the idea that Staph. is the remedy and you give it very high.
She doesn’t know why you gave. She thinks you gave it for skin eruption.
She doesn’t know that the remedy has given her the courage to demand her own and defend her integrity.
And if the woman comes after the divorce you may have a more difficult case. Staph. in not any longer indicated.
Then you have to find the new indicated remedy because of the stress she had through the divorce.
And because of that stress if she comes to you it’s ok, if she goes to the psychologist or psychiatrist
she will start getting antidepressants to overcome the period and then the drugs will take their toll on the condition
and then later on she will develop something much more serious and this is how the disease is created.
So we have  a system of medicine that compromises the immune system, then the immune system being compromised the person
becomes easily irritated, angered, anxious then you take drugs to cover all this and then comes the depression etc.
In the meantime life is so difficult that there is a possibility of a stress at any time.
In a person who is already stressed even one word from another person can destroy him. Leave me alone.
But what did he say? Leave him alone! Which is the secret that keep the husband or keep your balance?
Why a person who hears this ‘leave me alone’ that you means you’re junk, jerk, what is affecting?
You see the impact on the person will be directly analogous to your sense of pride.
The more the ego is inflated the more the impact is going to be.
If you don’t want problems in your life you better be more humble and don’t think you are the best homeopath in the world!
I am the best! Everyone knows our position and we understand…
Especially being homeopaths a lot of people will come to you to say you saved my life, you are so wonderful,
you are such a person, you are a divine person… If you take all these inside and you believe it, you had it.
The next month you have forgotten half of the information.
It’s very strange how it works. It works the opposite way.
The more you inflate believing what others are saying to you the more you are liable to become sick with the least stress.
These are truths we don’t like. I don’t like it myself.
If somebody comes and tells you are a lousy homeopath… I may be healthy! Because I believe I am good…
As I always speak out of experience I will tell you the truth.
I’ve been through all these and I have examined myself when some people where putting me down.
I will give you a personal example. I was in a congress of the LIGA for medical doctors.
I was in Germany in an international congress and I was in my first steps, just appearing internationally
to see what they were saying, hear others speak etc.
At the meantime they knew me because they asked me and I said take this remedy or the other, there were quite a few in the class 300 people.
The congress starts and there was a French Demark , he was the president of the congress, he said those medical doctors
who are members of the LIGA should come along and sit up to line 20, after 20 line associate members, so I was supposed to be an associate member.
I was sitting at about line 18 so he comes and he says “Vithoulkas you go back!” in front of everybody.
What could I do? I got up in front of everybody to go back to 21st line.
This is true. They said you sit at 18th line and I should have decided by myself to go.
I was speaking with someone sitting next to me all the time.
I was busy explaining to him homeopathic matters but still...
This particular was against me, this particular French doctor because he believed in specialties, mixing remedies and I was speaking about one remedy.
He was attacking me every time. Instead of Demark that was his name I called him Dr.Remark.
He always had to say something against me. It’s ok.
But you can understand how I felt.
If I had let myself been hurt, I was hurt, but not to the extent that I would develop cancer,
but if I thought I am such a great homeopath… Anyhow things came that next year or 2 years later
they decided in the LIGA to give me the status of a proper member.
So I was an exception in the LIGA, I was allowed to be present and represent my country. But that’s another story.
The moment he insulted me in front of so many other people I could have been very hurt.
And I could have caused a lot of problems for myself at this moment.
Is anybody who does not have ego? I don’t think there is any human being walking with 2 legs that has no ego,
otherwise we would evaporate but let’s be within our senses. Once you realize what your limits are then there is no danger.
Somebody may even insult you but you forgive. Forgiveness on the other hand is such a powerful tool for curing yourself.
I’ll give you another example. I have seen the trauma of mothers who lost their children in the west.
They may never overcome it. They come after 15 years the moment you mention this they break out crying,
you see the organism is totally reduced because of this fact and then I have seen people from the East.
They lose a child, they cry, shout 1 month, life continues.
What is the difference between the reaction of our western population and the reaction of the eastern population?
They’re basically healthier.
They have not been vaccinated, they have not been harassed with a lot of drugs, they are more primitive of course,
I accept it, we are more civilized we will kill with words, not bombs sometimes.
But what is going to happen if the whole world becomes as sick as we are in the west? I am afraid very much.
Sometimes I am afraid I may cause such stress in the people I am speaking.
They may have problem. That is why I say to you always do not take it too seriously what I say.
Thank you!