I want you to be clear as to how
diseases are manifesting.
We have been talking about predisposition
for a disease to manifest.
You need a predisposition, which is
lying dormant in a potential form.
Potentially you have the possibility
for going into depression.
for going into insomnia.
Potentially you have the possibility that your heart will get involved. Potentially...
So this is not enough. We need that some stressor will activate this predisposition.
So we said, disposition comes from
hereditary and predisposition is formed
also because of the way that we live.
We create predisposition.
We create predisposition also
with the drugs that we take.
The more chemicals we put into
the organism, the more we change
the predisposition.
And this I think is clear.
So how the predisposition is created?
Hereditary, way of life and drugs.
The predisposition now is activated.
By what stressor can it be activated?
Shock, stress, what else?
You have a predisposition for meningoencephalitis. You will not get it
unless you come in an area where there is
the virus where we have the epidemics.
So we have the nosological
agents. Bacteria, virus etc.
We know especially how acute
diseases are produced;
through coming in contact
with the virus, the bacteria.
What is not understood very well, isthe
stress. And the stress is of several types.
One type of stress comes from psychological, mental, physical, ok, but the source of stress?
As human beings we have to understand ourselves, living on the planet,
living in a society what
can stress us?
-Unnatural way of life, the way of life
which is not at a certain rhythm,
living in a city, living too fast.
-Yes, but the unnatural life why it comes?
You live an unnatural life for instance
because you work too much. You work
from day to night, very late at night
and you get sick. Of course you can have unnatural life by having pleasure
from morning till night, all the time
pleasure, you also get sick.
With the drugs ok, we know
that is going to cause some problems.
But what other stresses?
Where do they come from?
-I think is because we all are in
a state of fear; fear of losing,
fear of thinking what we are, why we live
this way, why we chose the other way......
-We fear we may lose the house, we may
lose what you believe is your support
in order to exist, in order to keep on living.
So stresses can come from
the instinct of survival.
The underlying thing is,
I want to survive, is the idea of life.
The idea of life is to bring us back to life.
We die, back to life, we die, back to life.
Cells are dying, new cells are created.
So these circles happen
in psychological state as well.
We lose a job, how can I live now without
a job? This is a big stress and this can be
exciting cause for the predisposition.
This predisposition, Hahnemann calls it,
the maintaining cause.
And this is called,
the exciting cause.
So it comes from survival instinct.
Most people when they
come to you to be treated,
you will find that either they have gone
through such a stress for survival
or they have gone to another stress.
-Frustration.
-On what level?
-Emotional level.
-Frustration on emotional and sexual level.
Here this instinct also has the idea
of survival on second level. Here you
have survival on first level.
I have to survive. Everything that threatens
my survival as a human being with body
and needs, everything that comes against
that can trigger disease, that's the first level.
Then there is another level which we
call emotional stress and conflict
on the emotional and sexual level.
And this I call it the survival of a second
level, the instinct to procreate,
the instinct to live through my children.
That is the basic, very fundamental instinct
which if challenged then we are very shaken.
So it's very interesting that this stress here is
not actually as powerful as this stress here.
This stress is much more powerful and much more frequent we see it as an exciting cause
for disease. And this contains the emotional
and the sexual stress which is
I lost my wife, I lost my child, I lost
whatever I loved and whatever
was made to make me live, to
continue living in the future.
It is a survival instinct which humans
beings are having very strongly
but you can see absolutely the difference between this and that levels;
here is mostly mental, here it is
mostly emotional.
Now the third source of disease for
our times, in our societies,
that means the western societies, another
source is the spiritual survival.
This level of stress becomes more
and more powerful and when
it comes to the point where it can affect
the body, it can really destroy you,
who am I ? What am I doing? It is so powerful this realization, 'I have wasted my life,
I have done nothing, I have just lived for pleasure, for nothing more than pleasure.
That can lead some people to commit suicide,
it destroys the life immediately,
this conflict on spiritual level.
Our societies have gone through the periods
of survival instinct on physical level,
that means we have enough means
to support ourselves physically,
especially the more north we go, the more
the survival instinct plays no part.
You feel secure, government will take
care of me. In Sweden I have heard
that it's better not to work because the gover-nment pays you more money not to work.
How many people will get sick from that
instinct? very few. But as you know,
Sweden recently, 10-15 years ago was
the number 1 country for suicide,
even for children. Children did not
find a meaning in life.
It is very interesting to look historically
upon these things and to look in a rather
comprehensive way to understand disease
how disease is affecting our planet.
So survival instinct for our society
is not powerful anymore.
That means that the predisposition is not anymore sensitive to information
that comes from that level.
What about this level here?
You see as the societies go more towards a sense of security, here, they also need security.
What was the security here?
You will see how diseases were
produced. Can we have security?
Because on the emotional level you will
always depend upon the other person,
whoever it might be.
The government cannot say here, I will
give you a wife forever, it's not possible.
So the insecurity of this level led
to a way of life to find security.
They realized that I cannot depend on one person. Therefore let me depend on 5.
So instead of 1 wife, let me have 2 or 5.
That is how the sexual liberation took place.
You know the sexual liberation
movement that took place in
the western world after the
second world war.
Seeking more security on that level brought about a culture which actually produces
disease even worse than before.
Because here the values were twisted.
Here you need a child, a family, now you
have your security, your support.
The society in America, let's say,
the child is 17 and says, bye,bye,
I can do whatever I like now,
no family I don't need you.
I was in America and a woman who had
5 children, 2 had left the house,
one was 16 and the other was 12.
She said, the 12 is ok to be here
but the 16 I'm worried. I said, why?
Because she has not left the house.
I said, in the age of 16 you expect that?
She said, of course to leave the house.
So the life, the support which existed
before, is broken down.
Now you try to find another security.
The child goes out by itself
and looks for security, to find a partner,
to find somebody who understands me.
It's a mad search for a partner
who is compatible and there
all the dramas are taking
place in this area.
The worst is what she related,
it's disgusting.
You see the perversion on this level
because with a child there is abuse.
He abuses a child to find what?
To find some pleasure? How much
insecurity this man must have.
He did not have any kind of affection
and then finds, this is extreme of course
but all the time dramas are taking place.
And stimulation on the predisposition
comes from that level.
So in analyzing in this way I will tell you,
maybe you don't see what it has to do with,
but analyzing and understanding
really the problem in depth,
we may be able to take eventually
some correct measures.
So you are prepared to be the healers.
A healer, what is the healer?
It's not that you have a pain and I give
you an aspirin, no. The healer is somebody
who cares about a situation which is
diseased and has to bring it back to health.
Now the despair comes because you look
upon what we have created in our societies
and we missed the way to health, it's not possible. Because here we completely lost,
with the conflicts inside that we have,
we lost completely the way.
We are totally lost, I can tell you.
No education on that level, at all.
In school, did you ever heard a teacher
teaching you not how not to make love,
because now in school they say, oh we must teach sex behaviour, the school is crazy.
It's not to teach a child how to make love,
a child of 12 to tell him, oh you lie down,
you lift your legs. I mean this is terrible,
they look and say I don't want that.
And the government says, oh we
put sexual behavior in our classes,
this is craziness which has
come because of that.
They don't teach the class that love is
very important, to give is very important,
music is very important, to feed this
emotional level. What kind of food?
Here, you take the mind and the
children and teach history, language,
I have to learn, I have to learn.
The child gets crowded with information.
We educate the mental level and then also
the body, athletics, ok mind and body.
And in between which are the emotions
it's a mess. We don't know what is right,
what is wrong, is it good to have sex,
is it not good?
Some say it's good for the girl to know
by the age of 12 what is sex.
That is pure nonsense,
it's criminal in my understanding.
Because somebody might have
a different opinion.
I understand we might have different
opinions but for me that is why
we are led to be  so
much diseased at this level.
Then when I see the case, what do I see? Conflicts in that level so deep and so dramatic,
that has teared off the health completely.
What actually is happening in our society?
This was solved by the governments,
by the civilization. This could not be solved
and brought about a lot of suffering and then
that suffering brought us to the next step
which was the spiritual inquiry. What
was there? Survival, the total survival.
People say, I cannot survive here
because my body is going to die.
I cannot survive here because I do not
have children, even if I have children,
they just left me. So how can I survive?
Only if I become one with God who is eternal.
We arrived at the spiritual level and
inquiry in our times prematurely,
through suffering on that
level wanting survival.
Because I cannot survive if
I don't pray I cannot survive.
That's why I said praying is Verat. or Aur.,
you give Aur. and they stop praying.
But they start praying and say, 'God help me'
whatever way you say, different ways.
It's the idea that I must survive and this
time the survival must be eternal.
And all these spiritual gurus are basing
their teaching in this fear of the individuals
that are going to be destroyed and
then there is eternal hell or eternal nothing.
There is a fear and then they play on this
fear and say, ok we give you the solution.
You sit down, you breathe properly and then
this gives you a sense of well being of course.
The problem is, are you ready, are you
healthy enough to reach that level naturally?
Or you reach that level in an unhealthy
state coming from conflict?
And then the hippy movement is exactly
that, the conflict on that level.
They said, make love not war
and they meant make sex.
And then pretending, take a flower
and give it to the soldier.
This is internal thing, it has nothing to do
with giving flower, it is an inner state
of peace and love which flows out.
If you don't have that, forget it.
How can you have that if you are on
the conflict all the time,
I want this man, I want this woman.
She doesn't want me
and then suffering,
what shall I do? I will kill her.
You know sometimes you reach that state
and then you've almost killed her and say
'God what have I done? Please help me'.
And then you enter in that level in which
the twist is so much that when you meet
even young people with that history,
is going to be very very difficult to treat
because of the confusion that has
been created and the outlet
which has been found which
now it has to be totally restructured.
How can you restructure somebody who
has been disappointed from love so much?
That everything has fallen into pieces?
And then you give something, she comes
out but the possibility of getting back
is very much, unless you make them
realize slowly by example,
by talking, by whatever way,
what is the right thing to do.
And the right thing to do here,
in order to survive what is it?
I talk very logically, I don't make
jumps in logic, neither I'm spiritual
neither I'm against spirituality;
don't get me wrong.
We have to reach that state
but not as a cause of a disease.
I would like to reach here, in the
spiritual level to which we have the
right to be, in a healthy way. Therefore the enquiry, who am I, what am I doing?
People are so aggressive, like
sharks, they want to eat me
and then outlet: I will find God.
This is the wrong way.
Maybe some people will survive
really but how many? Very, very few.
Who are these? Those who have a
good health will survive spiritually.
That means the spiritual people, the saints,
the yogis, those who have enlightenment.
If you examine them in the totality
their health is very good.
So of primary importance, for the
spiritual evolution of the human race
is a presupposition that we
have to have good health.
Otherwise we cannot enter these
realms of extreme ecstasy or
whatever is called that high state of spirituality.
The body will not tolerate so much energy.
It's like allowing yourself all the
energy to go through your body.
You have to have a very powerful body.
This is how I see spirituality.
Sometimes we have to
understand which comes first.
You cannot do all damage
here and then seek here.
You remember what I said,
Homeopathy is confession.
You give a remedy and
then the body confesses.
Brings out the eruption, all the problem
was coming out in her skin
and you say, great. She felt relieved
inside. Wait and it will go away.
-In the level of emotions, you have
several levels and some people can go
through the levels into the spiritual by getting through some levels and then pass.
But if you have something in the emotional
part, you can't  get clearly through.
-Yes. You have these 3 levels, here is
the emotional which is damaged.
Here is the mental. The highest
part of the mental here
is the spiritual part
where you are aiming at.
And then you make that jump unnaturally.
That means the organism is not ready for that
because still you're hurt, you hate people,
you are closed to yourself.
And then you say, I will seek God.
You can seek God but God is not there.
It's here, you brought down God here and you say, please God stay with my weaknesses.
Of course sometimes you may have an
uplifting, the total cure maybe,
I don't know, it's not my expertise.
But I say, it might be possible if
I see some healers or Christ let's
say. He was uplifting due to the power
of faith, was uplifting the body and
making the body function again
in a very harmonic way.
But I'm talking about whole, the
culture in the western world that
this emotional level is the most weak
because we left it totally uneducated.
And because it's very weak,
it's very vulnerable.
So we have created through the years a
great predisposition for emotional problems
and therefore even little cause
can overturn the health.
Sometimes you see a young woman,
she lost her first lover. What is the first lover?
Later on, she will look upon this
and say, that was nothing.
Yet at the time that she is
involved with this problem,
the health is going to
break into pieces.
-So it would be correct to understand that the emotional level is the center of problem?
This is where we have to come first?
Because in the emotional level
we carry the most difficult things to touch?
And would you say that we're carrying
them through childhood
about the age of 5 years, what happened
then? How it creates the pain?
-This is another subject but I will
tell you my ideas very fast.
I feel and I believe that we are the
end wave of the human race
that comes 5million years back.
We are living now in the world
and we are at the end.
We carry at a certain level,
we carry all this human tradition
behind us. That's one kind of predisposition.
The next kind of predisposition that
we create, is the physical
that comes from the parents and
grand parents, specific predisposition.
That's another, you add that. And then,
there are the predispositions which
are formed because of social behavior
around us. I was raised in such a way
that this happened. We all attribute a
lot of our problems in younger life
which is true in a way.
Though I feel that this issue has
been exaggerated too much
because of the psychotherapy, the
psychiatry etc. It has been exaggerated,
it's not that much. You find individuals
who have been hurt as children and
this is important but how much important
it is to justify for other things that happen? No.
Eventually we are, out of free will, deciding
to live one or another kind of life
and then we create this
predisposition more and more.
Drink alcohol you make a predisposition
to your liver totally vulnerable,
this is a predisposition here.
Even if you stop drinking alcohol
your liver is going to be affected easily
so you have a stress on this level.
Your liver will break down,
cancer of the liver.
-I'd like to add something in what you said
about the woman who is spiritually very high
but emotionally very weak. For me I also
think that the spiritual part is also lacking
in our bringing up, from the very beginning
and we don't have a connection with the
spiritual awareness and that's why is so
difficult to get the connection again.
We are struggling very much and we never
really got any connection in our up bringing.
And also religion really helps to recreate
this connection or to re-establish
I think the spiritual education is an
important factor from the very beginning
or we should not over emphasize the
emotional factor relating to this?
-I totally agree. When you have
eventually healthy individuals,
the need of a healthy person will be a
spiritual need. And the spiritual need
of a healthy person is totally different
from the spiritual need of a hippy.
Spiritual need of hippies I have a problem
and I feel it comes through a reaction
to the conflict on the emotional level. What I'm talking about here, is causes of disease.
When we come to the healthy attitude, what
is the healthy attitude of a human being
then we have a different discussion.
But talking about exciting causes of disease
and I say, this can be an exciting cause,
the search for spiritual enlightenment it can be so, I'll put it very down to earth, so selfish.
As much selfish as here, or here, or here.
You want something for which
you are not prepared,
it does not belong to you yet and
you say, 'I love my wife or my husband.
I want this husband, wife, friend forever'.
You have to deserve it.
How you deserve it? It's another story
how you deserve this survival here.
Here, there are people who are surviving
in the planet at this moment,
with this area in a good condition.
These are the simplest people on earth.
You will not find them in our societies.
You will find them in her society.
You will find them in South America, in remote villages, people who know what is right,
what is wrong, I cannot do that. But you
will earn so much money you can do this.
I cannot do it. He is stupid. He is not
stupid, he is healthy on that level.
They say, I cannot go against
my emotions, my conscience.
My conscience says, that I cannot do
that and I don't want to go against.
-Study the Buddhist tradition I was
quite interested. I bought literature,
started to practice, to meditate and this
continued for about half a year and then
I felt intuitively that at first I have to be full,
to then be able to become empty
and so I stopped with it.
It was not the right time.
I have to be filled first, emotionally filled,
then I can become empty.
-Exactly, this is what I'm saying, jumping
a level beforehand and going into...
it is so tempting to be free.
They say come and practice this and you will
be free. What do they really mean with this?
It's a matter of great debate. You will be enlightened and you will have such
a connection with God. I have seen
people who have gone through
such periods and they feel elated.
But this feeling elated and feel good,
puts aside the real problem,
does not deal with the real problem
and the real problem comes back.
And the real problem usually is here.
You see, these people why they give up?
Even the gurus, you know what is the problem? They go with disciples, a little girl.
The guru doesn't go with one. He goes
with 1,2,3.. in the 10th everybody knows
what's going on. That means that the guru is honest but he has not worked through this.
That means he has still the desire to go
with a young girl. Once you have that,
it will follow you all the time and
it's better don't become a guru.
You say, wait a moment I'm not a guru,
I'm not a saint, I'm not perfect.
But nobody does this because they
exploit and once they come to this level,
they become sick on that level,
the guru and their disciples.
Now we are entering that era where
everybody is dealing with these issues.
Why are you listening all of you? Because
you all have thought about these issues.
That's why you are listening;
otherwise you would be sleeping.
So we have entered that era of spiritual
search, of the need for evolution.
We had enough wars, we had enough
fighting, we had enough hate,
we don't want it anymore. So what
shall we do? This is the idea behind.
We had enough conflict. What shall we do ?
Ok, find God. Each one finds an outlet.
From healing point of view I say that Homeopathy is necessary to allow you
that passage to this level,
in a healthy way finally.
-I think it's different in the western
world than in the eastern world.
It's a matter of feeling. I think we forgot
to feel the right way and to connect it
into the intellect first, in order to get
healthy and then the spiritual can come up.
-That's what we are saying exactly.
I like this clearness.
At a certain level we are
clear to certain things.
I'm very clear in what I say and if this
clarity goes through, I'm very happy.
You have something to work, if you want to accept it or not to accept, this is up to you.
But as long as this is clear to you,
as it is to me, what I'm saying.
-I just wanted to say that my master who is
the nephew of Ramakrishna and his master
who is Mahashi and he is enlightened himself,
he says exactly what you are saying.
You need a healthy body and a healthy mind
to come to this point where you start
'enquiring who am I'?
-I believe all people who are honest and
who are quite healthy they will be thinking
more or less in same lines.
-I would like to come back for a short
question about emotional level.
You told us we should not exaggerate in the
early childhood and blame everything on this.
And you say, we have free will to
decide but here there is a point.
You see, we are not really free if we are
controlled by demons and things that
you haven't touched yet. So we are not really free and there is a cause for people to not
educate and touch it  at school and even after, this is the most difficult part to touch.
So as long as we are controlled by
demons and repressed emotions
we will not be able to go higher in other levels.
-I understand perfectly what you say and it is
true in a way but I have seen with Homeopathy
that you say, I have this, this or this. I have compulsory ideas or I have depression
because of a child abuse, that is the worst
case. And yet you give Nat-m and next day,
you forget about this. She described in the
video, I felt free, I felt so happy. Where is that?
It's a chemistry finally which is produced
through thinking, through feelings,
we change the chemistry. We come
with Homeopathy, we rearrange
the chemistry and the way of thinking
changes. You say, I don't have this.
I don't want to come to my personal
story because many times I heard
'oh poor child he was born in orphanage
and that's why now he is criminal and..',
I don't believe this. I lost both
my parents during the war.
I don't think I have so many problems
because I lost my parents.
It never came to my mind, I have a
problem and that problem maybe is because
I lost my parents. It never came to my mind.
So how can, whatever I have, blame the Germans? The Germans killed my mother.
If I want excuses for my inadequacies,
for this or that, I can tell whatever I like.
But the fact remains for me that Homeopathy
can eliminate a lot of what we call,
deep hurts of the emotional level.
For me it is a fact and that is
what I'm trying to drive in at, here.
Also I was seeking at 1950, I was 18,
at 52, I was 20 actually and I read a book
in spirituality and I wanted to go to
India. Because there I'll find truth.
I have been through all this.
I was a prerunner of the hippy movement.
I realized later on that the hippies were
doing exactly the same thing as I did
10 years before them. But I did not go to find excuses and taking drugs to find the paradise.
And I also found out that it was the
wrong search for spirituality. I mean,
you are asking spirituality because you
cannot solve your emotional problems.
That's true and when I had to think for
myself and look at others also,
I realized that this is true,
I'm trying to jump a level.
Actually I had a spiritual experience by that
time because I was practicing very hard,
I was celibate. You know to be
celibate at the age of 21,
not having sex at all, no masturbation,
nothing is something very...
And I had what we call spiritual
experience and  it was so powerful
that I heard almost a voice,
it said 'not now. You are not ready'.
What I tell you is experience either personal
or from sick people I've treated, it's no stories.
-What you are saying actually is that Homeopathy has this mysterious process
in which we can give up the demon
and go ahead  which I, for years,
try to find out how to do it better.
Now if Homeopathy has that process,
this is a real revolution for me.
-I will tell you something. The demons and
all these feelings and ideas and thoughts
which are tormenting us are
like the dark part in us,
the death in us. We have death
inside us like life. Death is like darkness.
Put light in the dark. What is remaining?
Nothing. This is what happens with
Homeopathy. That dark disappears
and you don't know where it is.
You say, I had these thoughts, where are they now? They've gone. It's as simple as that.
And from this point some of my students
come and say, everything is delusion.
So find why you have a pain
in the right shoulder.
Because you have a specific
delusion, find the delusion.
This is taking a real idea and make it
a play and then you start thinking
'if I have this what it symbolizes'?
And then you can get crazy.
But if you have here a pain that means
you are quite healthy in mental-emotional.
Because people with pains
on the joints are the most healthy.
With lumbagos, sciaticas, are the most
healthy. Why do I have the lumbago?
I cannot carry the life
of my delusion and bla bla bla....
and then you can become really
mentally ill, if you go through that process.
I never said such things.
Just to complete a little bit more, to give you
a more complete idea of the exciting cause
and the seriousness of the disease, the connection with the exciting cause.
Once we have problems arising from
survival instinct, on the physical level
then the diseases that we have are more manageable with Homeopathy.
If you have the emotional conflict or the
sexual conflict, it becomes more complicated
and most of it is the spiritual. The spiritual
conflict is cases where you feel
more and more the problem that you
cannot see through the case.
People who have been trying to reach a
spiritual goal, they have gone through
these emotional conflicts, they have
left them behind, it is like a bunch
where you cannot see through a pattern.
And there you get most of these cases
that we call today the intellectuals.
In this area are the intellectuals.
Those people who intellectually try to find
a solution for their inner problems.
These are cases where, if you see them,
you are going to have a difficult case to solve.
Why? Because they've gone through
a process which is not natural.
And the trail that was left
behind is not a clean trail.
Also here, in this level, you get people
whose cases are quite difficult.
Because on the emotional level
you don't have the phenomenon
of once it gets hurt, it's finished.
You get a phenomenon that once
there is a hurt and stays inside,  is every
day and it is aggravating every day.
You have the torment of these
thoughts, of these experiences.
A mother has a child who is retarded.
She comes there and you give Nat-m.
or Ign. and she does quite well. You will
have to expect due to the fact that
the emotional problem is there, it is not
solved, it is an objective emotional problem
that you may have a
relapse with this case.
The same if the problem is real,
objective and it's on the emotional level,
then you're going to have a
difficult case in hand.
But if such an individual whom you treat, becomes quite healthy and is able to evolve,
that means to see the world from
another point of view, then it's saved.
Then you may not have the relapses again.
That means acceptance on this level.
I accept I have a child and I'm happy
in spite of the fact that it is a retarded
child and I'll try to do my best.
This is a healthy attitude,
it is a spiritual attitude and the problem is
solved. Homeopathy will give the possibility
for this person to jump into that level.
If he grasps the possibility, he is saved.
If he doesn't grasp, he stays with 'why me,
why was I chosen by God to have this
catastrophy, this calamity all the day?'
If she sticks to that idea then the relapse
is necessary. You will tell me,
why do we need all these?
Unless you understand in this way, you
will not be able to deal with cases.
Because you will see relapses, you don't
know why they are, you will see phenomena
which you cannot explain. You do not
know what to say to the patient
and you are lost, try again with
another remedy and then full relapse,
then disappointment of the patient,
he leaves you, he goes either to
another homeopath or to accupuncture
or back to allopathic drugging.
There are a lot of questions which I would think you may have and I don't see these questions.
-I would like to know what would determine
in the individual to grasp the opportunity
or not to grasp? Is a predisposition?
If we suppose the remedy is the right one.
He will always take the opportunity
or he sometimes will take it or not,
is it the amount of pain or what?
-It's a good question. The answer is almost beyond logic and our possibility for analysis.
What will determine whether an individual
will evolve or not, as an individual spiritually,
is very difficult for us to pinpoint.  To say it
is hereditary or whatever reasons are there.
You know the Indian philosophy says,
it's your karma, your good karma
or your bad karma who did this or that.
These are some explanations,
it might be valid explanations but I'm
not in a position logically to argue
about such or another position.
At this moment I like to stay with what is
really logical and what everybody can understand without much doubt.
Of course the idea of karma makes
you feel quite good
and reincarnation makes
you feel even better.
I know that. I know that you say 'I'm
suffering this time because most probably
I was misbehaving in my past life but
then next life most probably
I will get the reward for this life that
I am so good' and things like that.
And also that I'm not lost. The idea of the unknown, the fear of death is minimized
with these theories or religious
beliefs coming from India.
Most probably there is some truth in it because
if you see Mozart writing a symphony
or playing the piano at the age
of 6 who taught him?
Nobody. Or some chess players at 6
they play like masters. What is this?
Something comes through the generations.
Some information comes through
from generation to generation which
according to our biophysical structure,
we perceive this or not.
Maybe these things will be
explained later on; we are
able to enter in these realms.
But it's a very difficult question for me
to answer. What will make an individual
after the homeopathic remedy to
grasp the opportunity and
proceed, spiritually
evolve in a correct way?
-Since suffering is a process of life,
when you treat on emotional level
what you do is not suppress the
emotions. You help the patient to deal
with the emotions and therefore you
continue living a normal life
but you have more strength
to carry on with your duty.
-Correct. Treating somebody you
give him the possibility to deal
with his emotions or fears etc.
But sometimes the fears are so much
the result of chemistry that
the fears overwhelm the individual
and it's not possible. He is trembling,
'I'm going to die, I have cancer'.
Then you give the remedy and then
suddenly, 'I'm not afraid of cancer anymore'.
Then they look upon their problems in a
much more concrete and complete way.
They are not lost in their fears. Later
on we shall be discussing about
different objects that we shall find in
treating an individual homeopathically.
We have cases where it will be very difficult
to make them really healthy and stay.
They relapse all the time for different
reasons. We have other individuals
where we cannot find the remedy. Then
you have to go all around, treating, treating.
-If a patient after getting the remedy, loses
life time fears and becomes very healthy,
the fears are gone. This you see imme-
diately after the remedy it has been given
to the patient, the freedom of asking
questions of how comes this happen?
And because it is an ambiguous question
even to us, I'm not asking for an explanation
as to how the remedy acts, but is it enough
to explain that you got it, you are better
and therefore it acts. Or is it that we
can explain the patient why he was freed
of a life time problem, suddenly
is over so simple.
-Well you can give an explanation
according to whom is in front of you.
Simple people you can say, that the
chemistry of the brain was such,
that it was creating these fears. Now we
fix that chemistry, you don't have the fears.
To somebody else you can talk in a different
way because after all the true is that
in order to have a real cure, something
happens of an order of, how can I say,
a situation comes in the right time, the
right people to bring about that miracle.
It's a kind of a miracle and it needs
something beyond the ordinary.
Extraordinary things happen and these extraordinary things may happen
in a very simple way. You meet somebody
and you will have the experience.
You meet somebody and you see
something very little, one of these things
that we have been discussing and
you say, why don't you take Pulsatilla?
He takes Pulsatilla and he says,
what was that? This was a little
divine moment where
synchronization took place
and you prescribed
the correct remedy.
Now in order to have this as a profession,
you need to create that synchronicity
inside you first and then it is created
outside. Then people are coming to you.
You give the remedy, again the miracle.
I'm supposed to know a little bit more
Homeopathy than you, but still I'm
trembling when I see a new case.
Is it possible that in this case I will see
the remedy? And in 1,2,3 minutes
you see the remedy thank God.
And you get another case, you struggle,
you struggle, this remedy or
that remedy, what is this?
But if you have done your duty, that
means you really studied and you really
got the information as much as you could,
then it's up to other forces whatever
they maybe to allow or not to
allow. But if you say,
'oh it's your karma not to be well'
because you do not recognize
a Calcarea carbonica case, it is the
karma of the person not to be well.
It is a simple Calcarea carbonica case,
so why don't you recognize it?
Because you do not have the
information, you did not study enough.
You cannot say it's your karma, you
have to suffer. It's my karma because
I don't say to myself 'I did not study enough
and that's why I cannot find a simple remedy'.
If it's a very difficult case really, ok.
But if it's a simple case and still you
cannot solve it, whose fault it is?
The person who comes?
-It is my own experience that on the
one hand there are these miracles
where you give the remedy and many things happen but in reality actually I experience,
you give a good remedy and still there
is a lot of work to do to go very,
very slowly through all this process. And
I think that this path where you have to work,
the patient has to work, you with
your patient is correct and a good way too.
I think we shouldn't think that everything
is easy if we get the right remedy.
I think the majority of cases is like that.
-I agree. As I said before, we
don't always have a clear cut case
and then we have to struggle and to
give a remedy which is one-sided as
Hahnemann called. That means we don't
have a full picture of the remedy and then
you proceed and then you go a
little bit further and further.
And in the end you find a point
where you give the right remedy
and then there is this freedom.
I gave a new definition of Health: Freedom.
You know how I came to that?
Because my patients who were coming
in the very beginning to a great extent
they would describe their new state, as
freedom. I was living in a jail and I feel free.
I got out and this feeling of freedom
gave me the idea of the definition of Health
which we have to have in 3 levels
and I gave you the definition.
It was by the patients
expressing that feeling.
A person comes and after the first
remedy you give, ah I feel so good.
Then he comes 2nd month,
follow up, still good.
3rd month good, 4th month,
I'm not so good anymore.
You have to judge at that moment,
it is exactly like somebody being in jail
for 5 years, 10 years and then
he got out. The first day is a fantastic
experience. As you stay free,
you get used to being free
and it's not anymore that shock of first
time I'm free and then they start saying,
'oh I don't feel so good'. Wait, if you
mislead to believe that now is the time
for the repetition of the remedy, most
probably you will be making a mistake.
You will say' yes, but you cannot
live in ecstasy all the time'.
You come and you are facing your
problems, you see what is happening etc.
You cannot say, all the time I want to
be in that state, neither is possible.
If you try to push your patient into going to
that state where he had first experienced,
you are going to make a
relapse, like her case.