-I just wanted to ask, could one
add something to the bruises?
Like Arnica or Calendula, would this
be possible without ruining a case?
-Yes. If it is applied not internally.
How it happened? By motorbike?
-Walking.
We have taken a remedy,
high potency. If you have hay fever,
could you have a small remedy?
- In case you have taken what
we call a constitutional remedy and
something acute happens, especially
injuries, you try to avoid as much
as possible taking internally a potency.
Of course if the injury is worse than the
disease itself, you have to treat it.
But if you can manage, I mean a little bit of Arnica outside, there is no problem.
-With hay fever I have been
told not to take anything.
-You suffer with hay fever chronically?
-Not all the time.
-Not all the time, in certain period,
like Autumn and Spring?
-Yes.
-This looks like Euphrasia.
-So I can take it?
-Yes, you can take it; I don't know.
Maybe it will cure everything but
what I see is Euphrasia
picture of the eyes.
-What is this?
-Redness in the conjunctiva,
redness on the lids together
with a lot of lacrimation
indicates Euphrasia.
-I would like to know if somebody is taking
his constitutional remedy and generally
is or was under Homeopathic treatment
and after that gets migraine attack
of very strong severity and then
calls me and says, what can I do?
Then I just can give another homeopathic remedy in between, what should I tell them?
Should I tell them to use some
allopathic medication to stop the pain
or what should the person do because
it's an intolerable situation?
But if I give a remedy then I disturb
again; so what do I do?
-You have to judge what is this headache
about. Is this a chronic headache
which has come after your medication?
The person suffers chronically
you give the remedy and immediately
next day, two days later
there is a huge headache much worse
than every other headache.
These are typical expressions of
good reaction of a Homeopathic remedy.
In this case you may wait for
2 days and then it's gone.
And then it's cured, no problem.
You say this is a good reaction.
Now if the headache appears, let us
say, one month after the treatment
and you were not treating the
person for headaches.
The headache is something new
for the person and unbearable
but in the meantime
this month is good for them.
That means they feel good
psychologically, more energy, etc
that means that the organism
needs this phase of headache.
Now what you will do?
Again it's better to leave it alone
and pass or at the most,
give some aspirin but not a remedy.
But if you have given a remedy and there is
no action and after 1-2 months appears
this headache, that means that most
probably your remedy is not acting
and therefore you can give whatever
you like, as a second choice.
But the moment that you feel that the
immediate reaction is because of the remedy
or there is a reaction later on but the person
is already reacting well to the medication,
the best thing is to leave it alone and try
to explain, let's see how you go through.
But sometimes the remedy has not acted
and we say, 'ok wait, the headache
has not gone away', headache, headache,
then of course you have either
to give another remedy
or to give some pain killers.
-George, you told us when there aren't
not so big injuries, you can use Arnica
externally, which potency? I ask
because I heard from a dentist he said,
under X6 the effect of Arnica is
controvert effect, it's leading to bleeding.
-These creams which they do,
not potencies, they have a cream
which they make and you can use.
Of course if this cream contains Arnica
10M is better not to use the cream
because by rubbing it also
you get the potency.
Usually these creams that they make are low potencies and this is not my experience.
If you take internally Arnica mother
tincture then most probably
you can cause some bruises,
because you make a proving.
-What was your question about aggra-
vation? Because we have been discussing
between us and it's obvious that in many
cases is very difficult to convince a patient
that he has to wait then it's going to get
worse, then it's going to take a long time;
when he comes to you he has a
specific problem and he wants
to get better as soon as possible.
What is the solution about the aggravation?
Especially in cases of psoriasis, a young girl
is desperate because her skin is very bad.
If I tell her it's going to be an aggravation
and the skin becomes worse,
she's going to run away.
-That is true, if you have a case
of psoriasis which is not so bad
because of the cortisone ointment.
She has put cortisone, she comes to you
and says 'treat me now'.
You say, 'before you get well,
you may just be full of psoriasis,
if you want you do it'.
Sometimes they say
'no, I want to get married first'.
Ok, get married first and then you come.
It is best to have a completely open
discussion and state your opinion
because if you don't tell them,
when the aggravation comes,
you will have a big problem.
Because how to explain it afterwards?
-From your experience did they always
have aggravation in psoriasis cases ?
-Not if the psoriasis is out, all its force is out. Then you don't have or you have little.
But if she says, at the age of 12 I was full.
And now you see only here and in the elbows;
that means that there is a possibility to go
back to full and you have to be careful.
But if she comes and says,
'this is the worst I ever was',
It's ok, give it, no problem.
There is not going to be an aggravation.
-If they come to you with an inner
problem like the liver, the kidneys
and then you don't always
know what was in the past
and then the aggravation of the skin
comes. Will you say it takes long?
-That's another thing you're asking.
If they come with an internal problem
and then you give a remedy and then
there is a skin eruption, this is different.
Then this can be quite strong, this skin
eruption and can last quite long.
Then you have a problem. Like her case,
the same. Her case is exactly like this.
She took the right remedy, it brought out the eruption and then immediately he tries to
manipulate the eruption. You have the
example, exactly what can happen.
You suppress the eruption, it comes back.
I told you about the child from France.
Sulphur, great eruption outside,
close it, then back.
-I know but what I'm asking is
what I can tell the patient?
-You say to the patient, it might
have a reaction like this
and it might last for 2 years,
you explain.
-The problem is that they will
go to the allopathic.
-You see if you know what you're
doing and you explain beforehand;
I never had a problem with this because
I more or less know what is going to happen
and I tell them. And when it happens, they tolerate; otherwise they cannot tolerate.
If they think you gave the wrong remedy
and now they have an eruption,
they can not tolerate it.
You have to explain properly.
But of course don't explain that
the reaction will be like this
when there is not going to be a
reaction. Because there is the possibility
that it's not going to be a reaction if you
did not have the eruption before.
Then when the eruption comes, it is going
to be little and then you can explain,
'it's a good reaction, don't worry,
you have some eruption here and there'.
-When a patient in his medical history
had mental symptoms, panic attacks
or fear then I can expect
that they come back.
Old symptoms reoccur. Can I do this, that
I tell the patient that your fear will come back,
your panic attacks will come back and
maybe it will take 2 years until they go away.
Can I say that to the patient?
And will they really last that long?
-Let us say the patient had panic
attacks, fears and the patient comes
can I say to him, your panic attacks
will come back and you are going
to stay with this for 2-3 years.
The answer in this case is that the
panic attacks will not come back
because if you treat a person for
something, that something is better
than the panic attacks.
You have to go here in the model.
Panic attacks are here.
But you are treating the person for
asthma, for liver etc. you see it's lower.
So this is a cure. That means the
person has been cured from panic
attacks and now he has psoriasis.
He is cured and now he has liver,
heart problems.
So this which was cured, will not
come back. Do you follow?
-No.
-Who does not understand this?
Only you. Ok, I explain to you.
The panic attacks is deeper problem, unless
you tell me that the person is schizophrenic.
I treat a case of schizophrenia, here is schizophrenia and now he has panic attacks.
In any case panic attacks is a deep
disorder and now he comes for asthma.
Asthma is a better condition,
not a worse condition.
That means his panic attacks, by one way or another, either he took some allopathic drugs
or some psychotherapy and his
panic attacks were somatised.
It will come back something which
was suppressed in the past.
Suppressed in the past, means
it was worse. The opposite can be true.
Here, you are treating for panic attacks
and if the person had asthma before,
then the asthma will come back.
But the opposite will not happen.
We said, it will come back something that
has been suppressed in the past, not cured.
So you're treating asthma now and the
person had in the past, panic attacks.
That means, the panic attacks
were transferred into asthma,
asthma is a curative process.
Panic attacks were not suppressed.
Here in the case where the person
originally had asthma and asthma
was treated badly and went back
to panic attacks, now that you treat
panic attacks, asthma will come back.
But it will not come back something
that was cured before.
-The patient had taken during the
panic attack, psychopharmaka.
-If he had taken psychopharmaka
and they produced asthma.
He comes to you now and he says, treat me.
If you treat him properly, his panic
attacks will never reappear, why?
Because panic attacks is
a deeper state than asthma.
Therefore it was cured by one way or
another, even with psychopharmaka
the panic attacks were cured.
You can have somatisation
of psychological problems
through different modalities.