-What about the people who are not
practising in a medical profession,
who are not working in a medical profession?
They do not have permission
to practice in Germany.
So that means I'm not allowed
to have patients.
-That's a problem. When you don't
have the permission to practice,
you are not going for the diploma, so
therefore you are not obliged to send papers.
But let us say eventually you go to
chiropractic, you get permission,
if you have done in the meantime,
you can have it.
Maybe you don't have it now but you are
going to have the permission in 3 years,
by the time you finish the course.
So if that is your objective then you will have to follow the rules of the class for the diploma.
-To this question I wish to ask something
else. Vassilis said that sometimes
he gives instead of placebo, he gives
salts in a small potency D6.
I couldn't understand why he doesn't give placebo and he gives Homeopathic
remedies which have nothing to do with
a similar remedy. Can you explain that?
- Do you know the 12 Schuessler's salts?
Who knows them? Ok.
There are 12 salts that are
called Schuessler's salts.
Now these salts are salts which
the body needs, they are
in this composition circulating within
the body. They are almost like food.
They are diluted in this dilution 1/10 to the 6th.
In this dilution is like giving extra vitamins
or a little bit of these salts. So whether you
give or not give it, it makes no difference.
In Greece, they prescribe always the high potency one remedy and then the placebo.
Instead of the placebo you give this,
for what? For reasons that in case
there is an investigation they see
that this is a little something.
But this little something cannot
do any harm especially
if it's given in a dilution
which the organism absorbs.
The organism absorbs this, brings
it to this dilution and then uses it.
So you give it prepared,
one little tablet, no problem.
-There was a difference between dilute Schuessler's salts and to potentise.
Because Schuessler's salts is just
diluted and not potentised.
-It's better not to be potentised.
We just dilute it.
-What you said about XM, 3 times, I think
for beginners it might be dangerous.
To say once more that nothing to be repeated
if there is any change in any direction.
-10M ok. I said in cases where you have a
lot of remedies given, 20-30 remedies,
you give one 10M, next day there
is no reaction. You can give a second
and you can give a third. Only in those
cases where the patient has taken
a lot of remedies you can do that.
And he does not react.
If he reacts the first day, stop.
If he reacts the second day, stop.
If he doesn't react at all,
find another remedy.
Having studied a case and having satisfied yourself that this is the remedy,
you don't go  and change it,
like the Romanian girl.
I satisfied my knowledge that
this is not a Nat-m case, it's a Sepia.
So with Sepia I will be patient and
I will wait. I will not wait, I said, take Nat-m.
No, I made the mistake. But if I see
it's a mistake, then you don't wait.
Why you should wait,
it will not be different.
If it is a mistake, at the most it's going
to change some here and there.
In any case Sepia will be indicated and
I will give her Sepia in any case.
- I would like to put a question about
some allopathic treatment.
It's said if people have coronary heart
disease to give aspirin daily once a day
very low, just to prevent any heart attack.
Is this a suppression or would you agree
to do it next to the Homeopathic
treatment?  Very low dose.
-I feel that you can do it. I have
found out that aspirin does not
very much interfere with the
Homeopathic remedy.
We have used it freely all these
years without much interference.
-I would like to ask about Homeopathic
remedies that we get from Austria
and Germany and they bring them here.
So, from what I heard these remedies
when they went through X-rays at the
airport, they might lose their efficiency.
What do you think?
In my experience, as far as I can
remember, it has not affected them.
-I didn't want to pass it and then the lady said,
'oh when you are going into the airplane
there is much more X-ray'.
So it doesn't change anything.
-George, she asked you about aspirin.
I think there is a difference between
high quantity of aspirin to treat, for
example chronic arthritis or headache
where the people
are taking maybe 10.
-Even so. For instance in rheumotoid
arthritis where the orthodox treatment,
is 12 aspirins the day. In severe cases
they prescribe 12 aspirins a day.
Even in such cases, I've seen the
Homeopathic remedy works.
That's why I said, I'm not afraid of aspirin.
-May I make a remark on the question
because of the X-ray check?
-I have a patient who did very well with
a Q potency and she took it with her-
she told me 6 years ago- and she
said from the moment she came
to the other country, no more
effect of the Q potency.
-That's something that we have to
check. This is the first time I hear that
and I want to check it. It's a very
serious issue if it is like this.
-I usually wrap the remedies with foil
and put them in the suitcase, no problem.
The X-rays don't go through
the aluminum foil.
-This is the first time I hear that
and it's better we be careful.
-About remedies. Is it a firm, some
producers that you prefer?
A producer of Homeopathic
remedies that you prefer?
-You see, I would prefer to make
the remedies myself.
I don't trust actually anybody.
If you say, you're going to make
50.000 times, emptying, filling, hit,
who is going to count.
Try to count 50.000, 1,2,3 just this.
So I had a problem myself,
what are we giving?
When we say 50M what
actually we are giving?
Then, years ago, I tried to find some
company that will make remedies
by a robot that imitated the hand
movement because that,
for me was also important
to have the original.
But at the same time because we went so
high, Hahnemann went up to 6X up to 30,
one time he gave 60, it was terrible,
too high. Now we are going 10.000, 50.000.
It's not any human being that can hit, empty
and fill 50.000 times, I don't believe it.
So I went to the different companies and
I said, I would like to give you my idea
and what you should do for
producing this remedy.
What do we need to do? You need to
make a robot to imitate etc. etc.
How much medicine we will sell?
I don't know how much.
You give one dose to your patients.
How many students do you have? They calculated, no it's too expensive, forget it.
I went to different ones and one company said, we are interested. We'll make these robots.
This company was making dialysis
machines. They had all the technology,
it was a huge company in Italy; they
said we go into Homeopathy also.
The factory is a huge
thing like half of Alonissos.
They said, ok little factory like that,
why not?  So what do you need?
I need an engineer, a chemist,
this, that. They produced the team,
I explained to them what
I wanted and they did it.
They did a machine who imitates
this movement, the hit.
This company is called SIFRA from Italy.
That computer now can be programmed.
You say, I want number 12, 30, 200,
1M, 10M, 50M and 100M.
So the machine starts and when it
reaches 12, it puts it aside.
It reaches 30 and then puts it aside etc. etc.
There is no interference with the human
mind, it's automatic and I said, ok.
But still I would like to do it here, to see it
with my eyes that this is done properly.
I can tell you, they helped, they did it
but still I would like to do it here.
I would like to be 100 % sure and this
is only if I do it next door, here.
If I had a laboratory, then I could
tell you this is 10M,
this is 50M, so when you give 50M
you know that it is really 50M.
Now how can I know? And of course
they produced this by the robots
that they were working day and
night, they don't stop.
You program the machine and it goes
for days until it makes a remedy.
It is 3 or 4 years that they
have started,
still they have not completed a full
series of medications.
Because it takes time, and they
produced 3 of such robots.
The human being is producing by hand.
I tried to make by hand myself. I potentised- some ideas which I had in the beginning-
and I saw how difficult it is. It's not easy.
You try to do it and you see how you feel
after 1 hour. You want massage.
This company it's a company which
I have done; I use this medicine of course.
Because I know, at least,
the system, how it works.
-With which potency do you start?
If you discover that the remedy is,
for instance, Calc for a child with
which potency do you start?
-In a child?
You remember when
I made this model for you?
I showed you in the lowest parts
here, the lower you go, the more the
the more the pathology here
the lower the remedy.
It doesn't matter whether here you have a
child or a grown up person who is ill.
Still the pathology is severe
therefore the potency is low.
What do I mean by low potency?
Low potency is from 6X up to 12X or 12C.
A medium is C200-C30 and a high
potency is from this up and the highest
potency is 50M to CM.
So it's C200-C30,
then 1M-10M, then 50M-CM.
But these are indications. Experience
eventually will show you and you'll say,
oh I can go higher or I cannot go higher.
They make the remedies in the
Hahnemann Clinic in N.Berkley
- Michael Quin- they
have this machine....
This machine does these movements up
and down. When Michael made this I said,
I want this. And then he produced the
machine. I said, no this is not correct.
This is not what I want. Well he says,
we made it now, we cannot change it.
What I'm talking about now is, this machine
is much more sophisticated, a whole robot.
It does like that.
Hahnemann did not do that.
He did like this, you see?
We found out through research
that we have clusters formed.
And as is the bottle here, they found
out from physics, not from us
that when you break down the molecules,
the molecules are forming little clusters like this.
These clusters, if they are given
some time, they tend to stick
to the sides of the bottle by gravity.
They gravitate towards the sides.
So you have to give them some time
to rearrange themselves.....
You are doing something but
not the original potentisation.
Some dentists, they have the amalgam machine. Very fast and very short.
Another one is doing like this.
So there was no standardization.
So I said, where are we going? We fight in finding the remedy and then we get a remedy
which is not a remedy, it's not
what we expect it to be.
So I tried to standardize that portion as well,
so if one company does it and the other
companies are threatened, then they will have
to imitate that company that was the idea.
Of course these Sifra people, they don't really care because this is a small business
and in their huge entertainment, that's
nothing.They did not threaten,
at least not yet, the other companies
who continue to make their own ways.
But if you really go and see how they
potentise, you will see the machines
going up and down,
like this, and very fast.
I did not want that fast;
that's how the remedies
were originally produced, by hand.
So what else can I do?
I try to fight all fronts.
You see if all Homeopaths suddenly
decide to buy from Sifra, the others of course,
next day they will make the investment
and they will make equal machines.
It is a matter of investing some money to
do it properly. They make such big profits.
Where are these profits are going? Why
don't you invest again to do it properly?