Anybody knows the theory concerning high potencies?
A group of us in Greece with small clusters, do you know that theory?
-No.
-Who knows? You have read our paper?
-...clusters of molecules diluted in water.
-This is a hypothesis we brought about.
-...200 K or C, it is the same, the difference is in preparation
but it is 200 times diluted and succused both.
There is a kind of misinformation which goes on that the C potencies,
the Hahnemannian potencies are stronger than the Korsakov.
This is not true.
If you prepare by taking one drop from the first solution
and you put this drop to a second bottle with 100 and you dilute and then you succuss,
this is the Hahnemannian method or the C.
If you empty the bottle and you refill it, the same bottle with 100 drops,
what is left on the walls of the bottle is one part and you so you have again 1 part in 99
and you succuss it.
In both cases you have 1 part in 99 and you succuss it and again 1 part in 99
and you succuss it, so the effect of both methods should be the same if they are well succussed.
There is no difference.
The difference is that preparing by this method you need 200 bottles
and you need a lot more solution, whatever you prepare.
It maybe a more expensive method. The problem is,
if they say this is 1000 times Hahnemannian way, have they done it really?
Because it means 1000 times somebody takes the bottle, takes one drop, goes to another bottle,
refills, put the drop and succuss it.
Take one drop again. So it's not automatic.
Where with the other method, emptying and refilling, is automatic.
So I have a problem, when they say this is 10.000. have they done it 10.000?
It really is 10.000 times the Hahnemannian way?
I have a problem there to believe.
In order to use the same bottle, you have to go through very high temperature to spoil
and continue etc. It's a big process which becomes much more expensive.
But some pharmaceutical companies in order to compensate for that,
they say the Hahnemannian potency, let us the 12 potency is equal to 200 Korsakov.
In Canada you don't say such words.
Where the small clusters are formed with this process,
there are clusters of molecules of the original substance in the water and around them
they are molecules of water which they go and envelop these clusters.
As you go higher and higher, what it remains are the clathrates,
it remains a kind of the shape of the cell of the original clusters.
These clusters, as they form in physics, they tend to go and stick to the walls of the bottle.
That's why the Korsakov method where it takes its original substance from the walls
- because if you empty the bottle and you turn it back what is left is,
what is stuck on the walls- so these are the solutions which contain most of the clusters.
So if you take from the middle, you may not be getting some clusters sometimes
where on the walls definitely there are clusters.
So the Korsakov method is more reliable than the Hahnemannian method.
And as you know I have great problems many times
because the remedy was not really potentized.
They would say it's 1M and it was nothing.
That's why I had proposed to different pharmaceutical companies
that they would prepare medicines, if I had given them instructions how to do it,
in a way that it would be with an automatic machine.
A machine that would duplicate an original way of preparing the medicine,
that was hitting, that is how it was prepared. And that is how Homeopathy started.
Different companies they had different ways, like put and vibrate, inject water
and different other ideas came in.
I said forget all that, I want the original way, I want an automatic electronic machine
which will not interfere at all, the human being will not interfere.
You can switch and say, I want these potencies to be selected
and the machine automatically will refill, will shake and keep at the same time,
keep aside No 12 potency, No 30 potency and work automatically day and night.
So therefore I'm sure when I give 1M potency that it is 1M potency,
it's not 12 or 20 instead of 200.
There were several pharmaceutical companies that were interested and when they heard that,
they found it very expensive, how many remedies would sell and finally they were not interested.
There was one firm in Italy that was doing dialysis machines for the kidneys
and they got interested. They said we want to go to Homeopathy, what do you want?
I want a team of such people, mechanical engineers etc. and I will tell them exactly
what is the machine that I want and I imagine.
I want the original and I gave them the strength with which you hit and the fastness.
The original is different, I can not imagine it's doing like that, like the machines they have.
It needs some time and it has to come horizontally and then hit and hit.
It's different because these clathrates, these clusters they form and they are allowed to settle.
Otherwise it becomes like a madness within the water.
But anyhow my idea of reproducing the original medicine was from the simple logic
that the original medicines were produced by a hand, brought about, manifested in Homeopathy.
So this is the way the medicines should continue to be done.
This company, the Italian company, is producing at this moment these kind of potencies.
Korsakov method.
-What is the name of the company?
-The name of the company is SIFFRA.
And now when I want to give a 10M or 50M potency, I know it is a 50M potency
and if it does not work, I know it is my fault and not the fact
that there is no medicine in that.
That is another thing I brought into Homeopathy in order to secure the idea,
because we depend entirely on the integrity of the pharmacy.
You hear the mandragora case, what she said.
Because she is sensitive she understands, she took medicine
and there was nothing in the medicine.
Bill Gray is here and maybe he will remember an incident in Berkley.
Baker one of the naturopathic doctors was sitting there and one time I saw him collapsing.
I said what is happening?
He was perspiring, he said, I have diarrhea, vomiting, I don't feel well.
We took him upstairs in one room in the hotel and what was the remedy that we prescribed?
I prescribed Carbo Vegetabilis for him. I left him upstairs,
I went down to continue the lecture and after 1 hour I went upstairs to see how he was.
After 1 hour, he was the same. He says, I think I'm not Carbo Vegetabilis.
I think I need Arsenicum. Why?
Because I have some fear, fear of dying, he was totally exhausted.
I had given him one dose of Carbo Vegetabilis 1M.
But for me when I give a remedy, I know why I give the remedy and when I see the symptoms,
the symptoms are Carbo Vegetabilis. I say, something is wrong with the medicine,
the medicine was not correct.
I go down, I say, has anybody Carbo Vegetabilis 200?
Yes, one student had, I go upstairs and I give 200. In less than one minute, the man says,
I feel better.
In 1 hour he was travelling back with his car to his place where he was travelling in
and out to come to this seminar.
The 1M what it contained? Nothing, it was pure water.
There was another case, Bill may still remember.
Phosphorus 50M. A month later comes the report by Nancy Herring.
It says the report it's a little bit better, nothing really...
I ask the class, what is wrong? Medicine is wrong.
I say this medicine, Phosphorus 50M has acted as if it was one dose of 12 to my understanding.
I said, the medicine is wrong give her a dose of 200 from another pharmacy, beautiful reaction.
A case of Paris Quadrifolia in London where I was teaching,
these are public cases I'm talking about.
I come 3 months later, I teach again and the case is presented, nothing.
The same. I go up to the class, I say the medicine is wrong.
We try to find another medicine? I said, no go to 3 other pharmacies,
find again Paris Quadrifolia 30 from 3 other pharmacies, to be sure and give it to her.
3 months later, she was cured.
All this and a lot of other experiences in Athens where a remedy was open and close.
A pharmacy gets a bottle and from this bottle gives to different patients.
There is a time where the bottle is spoiled, either because of some perfumes or whatever
and he gives a dose from that bottle and the remedy does not work.
Then the doctor, when the patient comes, the doctor thinks -
especially if he isn't very sure about the remedy - the remedy is wrong,
I give another remedy and another remedy and another remedy.
I remember another case in Berkley. I took a case, 150 remedies the person had taken.
150 remedies in 7 years!
I said, what shall I do? I read, I read, I read the remedies and I take the case
and I say the remedy I see is very clear, it's not here.
He gave 150 remedies and within 150 possibilities did not strike the right remedy,
that is unbelievable; the doctor was there and I did not know what to say,
it was a clear case of Gelsemium.
I say, this is a clear case of Gelsemium.
Ah, he says Gelsemium was the first remedy I gave. 7 years ago.
He had not written it because he wrote the last remedies.
He said that was the first remedy, from which pharmacy? From that pharmacy.
Give Gelsemium from 3 other pharmacies, action.
All these led me to believe that there is something wrong with the pharmacies,
we have to have reliable medicines.
When I say in this case that I'm not sure about the remedy, I say Psorinum and it does not work,
he will go immediately to Silica but if the remedy is not reliable, what happens?
Because I am not sure. In case of Lachesis I'm sure, in case of Sulphur I'm sure,
in this case I'm not sure.
So immediately I will jump to the next remedy and if the remedy is not right I lose the whole thing.
You understand how much important is for us to have reliability in the medicine?
And when we say 200 it is 200 and when we say 1M it is 1M.
That's why I asked them and they are preparing in this way, duplicating the hand made potencies,
in an electronic way without interfering at all by hand.
You know how much difficult it is for a person to sit down and measure 200 times.
There was that we ordered 200 and it was only 20 times, why?
Because between 20 and 180 that they were missing, the man was going to see his child
who was sick, that was in Italy.
The man who was in charge, after interrogation, after pushing we found out
that he had left and the time he was supposed to make the 200, he was in his house,
looking after his child who was sick. But this is what happens if you rely on the human factor.
That is why now I say 200, 1M and 10M. Maybe one of the three will be.
I have more chances to be correct because I saw you being aggravated a little bit.
But unfortunately this is my experience.
In one day morning, noon and night. In one day all 3 different, yes.
-Do you, in your experience, homeopathic remedies sensitive to  magnetic fields,
strong fields?
-No. There are not.
They are sensitive to heat and this is for sure.
If you expose them to the sun, to heat more than 40-50 degrees, then you may have a problem.
-I read a book from a doctor [name of the doctor] PhD and he reported experiences with dilutions.
And he said it seems to medication sinusoidal effect, different dilutions meaning
that some dilutions will product a positive effect and the next dilution
will product some opposite or no effect at all, control of dilution, kind of.
-This is the work of Benveniste.
-He was reporting many works on dilutions, control delusions and he was reporting
that whatever they tried, they are the sinusoidal effect with some dilution ...
-Maybe it was before Benveniste. Benveniste did the experiment. You know it?
This experiment had some problems and we back fire for Homeopathy a lot
and he brought out the idea of one dilution being active, the next dilution not active.
I don't accept that, no.
-Can you describe what you are looking for at this stage of the day that is coming?
Of the different potencies? Is it possible to describe the changes that you' re looking for?
-In that particular case? Why I gave three potencies?
-And what specifically you're looking for during the course of the day?
-I'm not looking specifically for anything. I'm trying to create a reaction from the remedy.
So if I was very sure that a remedy was really potentized 10.000 times
I would say take one dose of Psorinum 10.000.
But as I'm not sure about that, I give three possibilities, I give one 200,
there is a possibility that there is a potentized remedy 1M and 10M another possibility.
If all three of them are potentized,
then most probably we may have a bigger reaction than normal.
Some people claim like Marjory Blackie from England, she used to give that kind of schema,
she used to give three potencies and she claimed
that in this way minimized the reaction of the patient, the aggravation.
I'm not sure about that.
-I just wanted to ask if you had any experience with the LM potencies,
whether you recommend them at all?
-I do not have much experience with LM potencies.
I would recommend them sometimes when there are hyper sensitive people
and I want really to give a very low potency and bring about very little aggravation,
I resort to LM. I have done it very few times.
One time I've done it, my experience was in Italy with a child with epidermolysis bullosa.
For those who know a little bit of dermatology, they know this is a fatal disease in children,
where the skin is not formed, the absorption of different minerals are not done
and there is no skin actually, the moment they touch the skin it opens up,
it makes a wound and then the child is bandaged with wounds all over
and they live 3,4,5 years at the most 7 years and they die.
That child was 1 1/2 year old, he was so sensitive, he was Phosphorus, his remedy was Phosphorus
and I said give him 3 doses of Phosphorus LM.
With the first potency they gave, there was a tremendous reaction
and the whole chest became a wound, opened.
It was definitely very bad aggravation, with 1 dose of LM.
And after that there was an amelioration and then there was a repetition,
again aggravation and amelioration.
This is the experience I have with LM potencies and in some other cases
where it has been suggested in over sensitive, I have not seen that kind of reaction,
I'm relating to you.
-This kid you saw in Italy was cured?
-The boy is still alive, he is 5 years old, he is still alive, his skin is not perfect
but he is much, much better and I believe that if they continue treatment, he will be saved.
-And he is still Phosphorus.
-Eventually he went to Calcarea carbonica. After 2 years I think, I prescribe Cal. carb.
-The case that we saw, which you prescribed Psorinum,
is there any concern giving a 10M with the skin problems coming back very strongly?
-I didn't follow?
-Are you concerned about giving a 10M and having a very severe skin aggravation
skin symptoms coming back very strongly?
-No, no. I wish they come back and they come strong. I have no problem with her.
-If the higher potencies seem to be  less likely to be what they say on a vial
why they give 3 doses of 200 from 3 different pharmacies?
-Because if the bottle is spoiled and you give 3 doses, it doesn't matter, still is spoiled.
-But from 3 different bottles.
-From 3 different pharmacies?
That's another idea, which I've done several times
but it's more difficult for the person to go searching for 3 different pharmacies perhaps.
-Do you think we should give 3 doses of every medication that we give for everyone?
-If there is no problem with the patient, there is no problem with the aggravation,
yes you can do it, if you are not afraid of deep pathology and it's not an old person
and it's not the last stages of a disease, yes you can do that.
-What is your view of these pieces of equipment which prepare remedies?
-Like radioinics machines? I'm sorry but I do not agree with that. I don't agree why?
Because I have checked out, I have certain people who had the machine
and tried to persuade me this is perfect. I said, I don't believe it.
This person called me to take his case and he was quite seriously sick,
so I took his case and I said, OK now prepare the remedy with your machine
and take it and we will see after a week or 10 days we will see what happened. He says ahh...
I said, no if you believe it and you tried for 3/4 of an hour to persuade me
that this is a good machine, you better try it on yourself.
I'll tell you the remedy, you prepare it, you take it and see what happens.
You will do it this way and he had to do it and he came after a week, I'm the same.
Well you are the same but we still have to wait another week to be sure.
I said, you are a scientist, he was a physist and you want to know if it works,
you have  been trying to persuade me that there are magnetic fields and blah, blah and all this.
Now you better test it on yourself and I made him suffer, of course.
And there were other experiments which I did.
If somebody claims that this it, I said OK, it is honest that we do a real test.
If you believe in your machine, we'll make a real test and I'll tell you what kind of test
and if you pass the test, I'll be the first one to say yes the machine is good.
The pendulum.... but you are moving your hand.
No, no I'm not moving my hand it's moving by itself.
You see now it's moving the other direction.
Somebody else comes in the seminar, he had an antenna from his car.
So with his antenna, he would search the remedy and he would go to the people and say,
George said this remedy, it's wrong.
My antenna says this remedy and people come and say, what is this?
I said, come here find your remedy. What is the remedy? Veratrum.
He goes to another one, what remedy he told you? Veratrum.
He goes to a child, I have given a child Pulsatilla, he says Veratrum.
I had to call him, I said come, can you do it for me so I can see how you do it?
He went through the antenna, he checked all the meridians with the antenna
and then he goes over the thing, he says Veratrum.
The man went into an asylum eventually but it was very interesting.
Either he, himself had taken Veratrum or he needed Veratrum himself
and he would give everybody Veratrum and everybody would say, he is totally crazy.
Then I found out that really he went into a clinic, into mental clinic.
This is antenna Homeopathy.
-It is speculation.
-It was speculation yes. Why?
I might pick one remedy, give it to you and sometimes it may still work
but is this a science, what is this? I don't know what it is?
And that's why Homeopathy has such a bad name.
I had a case with this pendulum where it had been to a medical student in South Africa
at least 25-30 remedies over a period of years every day 50M, CM potencies,
every day for 3 months and again another remedy for 2 months and another remedy
for 1 month...with this pendulum.
When he came to me there was such confusion in his case,
it was impossible to find anything; I said, I can't help you, I can't see any remedy.
You have symptoms from all the remedies. The boy committed suicide.
He couldn't live because I heard after a year or two that he committed suicide.
These are real energies that we can not play with these energies.
You have a powerful tool that can heal.
We usually say it is harmless and there is no problem and you can take it,
yes but you better handle it very, very carefully with great fear.