-The first book I wrote, they stole it.
I said, it's going to be a success.
A woman says, my book was stolen.
I said, ok let them read.
-George, I would like to ask. There
was a little confusion about underlining.
Maybe you could state this once more.
-There was another confusion also. Karim
says that if we have a strong symptom
like a lot of warts on the face and you see
it in the Repertory with small letters, right?
The symptom is very intense, you see it
in the Repertory with ordinary letters.
This should not take you out of the possibility
of this being the remedy. With one difference:
This is there on ordinary letters because
it was said by one prover.
It was recorded and we have it.
Now we have a case in which Lyc.
was confirmed by a case, as he said.
Then this should become italics.
Once it is confirmed then it becomes italics.
It's very simple. If this is confirmed again
and again, then it becomes capital.
That's the idea. There is no difference
between what we said.
If a symptom is recorded one or two
times, then we are careful.
We see it frequently and
intensely, we raise it.
And that is why we have corrected
the Repertory. That's one thing.
The second problem is the underlining. This
is when in the patient the symptom is clear.
If it is especially peculiar
symptom which is clear,
you have to underline it 3 times.
If it is a common symptom which is clear
and intense, you have to
underline it 3 times.
And usually you will find it in the
remedy underlined also three times.
But through this process, the
Repertory is an alive information.
It's never going to be complete.
Nobody will write ever the total
Materia Medica, the final Repertory.
This is not going to happen.
It's an alive science.
Some of these symptoms which
are in the Repertory today,
they will just go into
the rubbish bin.
Some which are on small letters,
they will become italics,
and then strong, capitals.
So, is it clear now?
What I want to discuss today is a problem
which I feel the class is not clear about it.
And since you are good students, I will try
to give you the best possible information.
You remember this model which
we have been talking about?
This is the best way
to depict the 3 levels.
It is not the absolute way. The outside
which envelops the other two
is the physical body and this is the
emotional body and this is the mental body,
which is the deepest. There is a
cooperation and a synchronization,
everything works together. The
only difference is sometimes
the physical body is working primarily, then
the emotional body is primarily activated.
Especially when you get excited because
you saw somebody you like.
Oh, are you here?
There is no mind.
The other people are looking, don't
do it like this, what they will say?
No, no. Forget about it. Your emotions are overwhelming the whole human being.
The same thing when you sit
down there. You say to the emotions,
you better stay cool,
I want to understand.
I like George, I don't like George, he is
such an egoist, he says this and that.
Quiet, quiet, let's see what he says.
Especially if your interest is attracted,
then the mental level is activated more
and more. Then it's when you learn the most.
Now we come to people who are sick,
mentally, emotionally and physically.
Sometimes in all three levels,
in different degree in each level.
Then the first question
we ask the patient is:
where is the seat of the problem,
in the physical body?
Why? Because his kidneys are affected, they
are breaking down. It's a big problem there.
So, the mental-emotional will be maybe
affected but to a lesser degree.
You got somebody else,
he comes to be treated.
- Why have you come to be treated?
- For depression.
- What has happened to you?
- I just want to commit suicide,
I don't want to live.
And then you investigate and he says
'I have a pain here, I have another
pain here and then sometimes my
ear aches, my teeth etc.'. These are minor.
They go to the dustbin. You are not interested.
You're interested about depression.
If you give a remedy for the pains here
and there and you miss the remedy
which will cover the depression
element then you are missing the case.
Another one comes and says, I cannot concentrate at all. I'm finished,
I had a job and they dragged me out
because I could not do the job.
You are not going to say, do you feel
depressed? Of course he feels depressed.
But the main thing, the pathology is on the mental level, it's not on emotional.
The emotional is a consequence because
he lost his job. It's a natural thing.
When he comes to you he will say,
'yes I'm depressed
because I have two children and
I cannot support them now'.
You don't concentrate on the depression, you concentrate upon the mental deterioration.
You are supposed to know
all that very well.
When the confusion which
I want to clarify comes?
It comes from the fact that Kent - who is
one of our greatest Homeopaths ever lived.
Prescriber, teacher and irritable.
He was a great prescriber, great
teacher and great irritability man,
especially when you gave
the wrong answer to the theory.
He said, what? Out.
Nobody was passing the classes if he had answered incorrectly the theory.
- in his theory he said that whenever
you have a case, you give a remedy
and there is an aggravation of the
mental, emotional level, mind,
he called it mind. And there is an amelioration
on the physical level that is a suppression.
That means your remedy is incorrect.
Now we come to clarify these issues
as much as we can, at this moment.
Do you remember the other day
when we spoke about.....
and I said that every level is
structured in hierarchical way.
So you have organs, you have the brain,
it's an organ as a whole, the heart,
the endocrine glands, the liver, the lungs, the kidneys, the bones, the muscles and the skin.
These are organs or systems which
they are hierarchically structured
and we know that a heart ailment may,
in its way towards cure, develop -
the patient develops - arthritic pains.
We say that this is good or bad?
-Good.
-Good, if the heart problems go away
and then arthritis, severe inflammation
on the arthroses, start, we always say, this
is a good direction, this is a curative direction.
If the heart is affected and then you
develop spastic colitis, is it good or bad?
In the same way, as the physical body is structured on this hierarchy level,
is the emotional body is also structured,
with systems and organs
which deal with different emotions.
So if we go on the emotional level
we see that from suicidal depression,
people just commit suicide and finish,
we come down to apathy state, to
indifference and then sadness
where people many times confuse
depression with suicidal depression,
suicidal depression is when you jump,
finish, there is no way out of
this depression that's why you jump.
Then sadness, then anguish, then phobias,
then irritability, then disatisfaction.
Why I construct this out of my experience?
What I have seen in this experience?
When people came with depression
and I gave the remedy,
I saw that once the depression went out,
the people started living again,
the joy of life had come, the emotions
were activated and then
I noticed many times
the fears have come.
I'm going to die. First I want to die
when they are in depression.
Now they are afraid that they will die.
That means the joy of life has returned.
They developed different fears many times.
They go even better by developing,
you see irritability, anger comes
out, from depression.
The organism what it had done before,
it was suppressing the anger.
You wanted to say, 'you are a fool, you
are a bastard, you have done this to me,
you have done that to me' and you could
not because of different reasons.
The organism does not recognise
your reasons. The organism says,
'I'm dying, I'm dying,
tell him that he was unjust'.
'No, I can't'. The organism will push you,
do this. You say 'I cannot do this',
and then 'I'm dying'.
One portion of emotions dies.
The organ which is concerned with
anger, dies. I mean it goes into collapse.
In the same way the liver says, you
give it bad food, drinking,
the liver works and says, 'don't give
me more' and it collapses.
We call it liver cirrhosis. The other
organism is continuing, is going on.
In the same way we have portions of the emotions which die, they die and they die.
What is left? The final organ that fights
for life. It says, 'no, stay alive'.
But all the organs, all the defences
actually which are lower,
have broken down and
there is a life and death situation.
Life and death, life and death.
It says, death, jump, finish.
Jump from a high place and finish.
Or there is another possibility that the
organism will give to this person.
It says 'the pain is so much I cannot
stand, I cannot remember.
She told me to get out, you are a stupid
bambuin and all this, no, I have to die,
I'm nothing, I have to shoot myself'.
And they say 'don't shoot yourself you're not stupid and then it says, forget it, forget it'.
And the disease is transferred from
the level of the emotions
to mental level and there is a confusion.
It starts a dizziness, confusion,
I can't concentrate. And we have
transference from the emotional level
to the mental level which
is deeper.
Still the organism was given the
possibility to be alive but since
you did not manage to handle this
situation Mr liver, with so much wine,
since you did not manage, I give you
the possibility that the disease
or the disturbance will go on a deeper
level and your whole organism
will stay alive with a possibility.
Maybe there is a good homeopath
who can bring you back.
These are the facts, this is exactly
what is happening.
Unless we understand this very
well, we're going to make
the wrong judgment in
evaluating a case.
We give a remedy and the patient comes
back to us and says certain symptoms.
We have to evaluate the case and to
know exactly whether the remedy
has acted curatively,
suppressively or not at all.
Unless we have understood this
scheme, to be able to judge correctly
on the evaluation of your case.
So far, is any question that
you would like to put?
I want to clarify these issues,
I don't take much time.
-I have a question to get my inner peace.
How do you see when somebody
has a lot of grief, he is depressed,
cries a lot and you give a remedy
she gets quieter, she says that
she is ok, and she doesn't cry
anymore and she
has pain in her right shoulder.
She can't lift the arm anymore after the
remedy. She can't stand the pain and
she does take another remedy
and she is shouting
she is screaming, getting mad.
How do you see this thing?
-Very good. I'm going to explain
exactly what is her question.
This is exactly what I'm going to
explain to you where in a case
you go from the emotional to the physical
back to the emotional, right?
From the emotional problem to
a severe physical problem
back to the emotional problem.
What have you done then?
The issue is quite complicated and
you have to be very attentive
to be able to perceive
exactly what is happening.
-Does this mean that the symptoms that
come back, if you treat them someone,
let's say for depression, he gets fears,
did he have these fears before?
Or can other symptoms arise that
he did not have before?
This is a depression state, this is depression,
this is forgetfulness, pains in the arms etc.
and we had here grief when
the person went through grief.
Now, before the grief there was a
chronic condition picture.
There were some fears, not very much.
So this looks better than this one,
it is less disturbed.
After the grief the person was really
disturbed, here he has fear of death
fear of thunderstorm, fear of disease,
little other fears of the dark etc.
The person lives with these fears
without much problem,
he doesn't even go to the doctor to
treat these fears because they are
not very disturbing. There comes the
grief and changes the whole picture
where here we have apathy. This is the
biggest thing and then what you have to do
is to give a remedy for this level,
the fears etc that he had before
or the new picture that we have
established after grief?
The correct thing is to give a
remedy that covers the grief.
Here actually the individual who
needs several remedies
to proceed to a total cure,
will have several levels.
It is like this and here most probably
is Lyc, here is Sulph and here is Calc.
On top of this was a Nat-m. Because
the grief, the most dangerous symptom
was this apathy where the loss of interest in living took place, I'm not interested in living.
I just want to die, this is a very bad
symptom, it leads to self-destruction.
Then you give this and this second
layer will come up
and then the third layer will come up
and the fourth layer will come up.
Sometimes the one layer mixes
a little bit with the underlying layer.
So here in this bottom layer you
may have some sexual
disturbances but for the individual are not disturbances, they are normal things.
You cannot say not they are disturbances
because you do not have
the sensitivities of that person
and you may say that seems
to me very normal. So these
may lie here on the bottom.
Underneath Calc., we have Platina
and then you give Platina
and you get the normalization finally.
But if you take here, the person
will not deal with this problem.
Here he says, I'm not
even interested about sex.
Sex, under this condition?
Forget it.
Then the deep genetic predispositions
finally they will come out
and you will see this is a
Platina case now. Why?
Because the person will say, it
seems to me I have become
from indifferent to sex, oversexed.
-There is a question that bothers
me since our last case. I have a patient
and he needs Nat-s. for the deepest
suicide and depression.
I have to give Nat-s., I suppose, and
then how can I be sure that
the aggravation I must face,
could not kill this patient?
-As I explained, the organism knows
what is best for the organism.
What we do with Homeopathy,
we stimulate this defense mechanism.
The defense mechanism does
not make mistakes.
It is concerned about preserving the life.
That's why we say, defense mechanism.
Defending what? Life.
If you strengthen that, then it will
give you the best possible answer.
So if there is a severe suicidal
depression and you give Nat-s
and it is correct, there is no way that
this person will go to commit suicide.
If it's wrong, it's a different story.
He may by chance, commit suicide.
That is why in 1976 Ortega
presented a case and he said
it was a case with suicidal depression,
I gave Sulphur and the person
committed suicide. Now this kind of talking
is irresponsible in my opinion, why?
Because you cannot stimulate a defence mechanism which has such a wisdom
and knows exactly what to do and the orga-
nism by chance goes to the wrong direction.
That means Sulphur was wrong,
suicidal depression was there
and after giving Sulphur, the person
committed suicide.
That means Sulphur was not
the indicated remedy.
Now we come to the point of the original
lady who has asked about going backwards,
to the physical body and then go back
to the mental or to the emotional.
What is happening then?
So I can proceed now and I take as an
example a case which suffers a lot
on the emotional level.
This is the emotional level.
When the disturbance is minute
and there is simple dissatisfaction,
the emotional
problem is down there.
When the problem is suicidal depression,
then the emotional problem is right there.
It has destroyed the rest of the emotional
side of the person and has gone very deep.
Then we have the mental level.
The person thinks many many times
that 'I should end my life',
this is suicidal depression. And at the same
time this person has some minor pains
on the joints, physical body.
This outside line is the skin and minor
ailment in the skin would be right down here.
Minor ailment in the mucus
membranes will go a little bit higher.
So the person who has suicidal
depression and some minor
arthritic pains, I would say, he has
problem here on the physical level.
You have to imagine that these
are corresponding lines.
One ailment which is here corresponds
on this line, that means
if you push this ailment on this line,
it will go inside in this line.
So we take on the physical level
and on the mental level he says,
'I have some forgetfulness'.
This is very low, absent minded.
So we have here, emotional very deep,
physical not so deep, mental even less deep.
You give the remedy and this person
who was before depressed,
starts now having some fears. Where are
fears in the levels? Fears are here.
What happened with his physical pains? They became much stronger, they came up here.
What happened with the mental level?
A little bit more forgetfulness.
So we have another triangle now and
the whole triangle is on a lower level.
You give the second remedy because the
person complains a lot about the pains.
You give the remedy and
suddenly the pains go away
and a tremendous
irritability arises. Where is it?
Here, on the emotional level. So this will go
down here, irritability will come again
and the mental level, let us stay.
So we have this triangle now.
So the whole issue is much lighter.
Unfortunately this is not very clear.
I have to make a big one.
According to this scheme, when the
physical becomes dangerous for life,
with pericarditis,
the physical is not only pains.
It can be inflammation of the pericardium
or endocardium or an inflammation
of the liver, or the kidneys.
And you treat a person with
inflammation in the kidneys.
As the organism will be getting better
and better what you will see?
You will see coming up the genetic predispositions of the emotional level.
So genetically this person had some
fears but the kidneys are broken down
completely and the fears do not matter.
Who says now, I'm afraid to die, you're dying.
You have no kidneys you will die.
So the fear of death has no meaning.
You treat the kidneys,
the person gets strong,
enjoys life again, then the fear of
dying comes back.
Then you have fears but that
which was very dangerous,
the endocarditis it has
become much less,
the heart is functioning now and
now you have irritability.
So on this level, on these correspondences,
you will see that still the disease
will be going down on the
scale of hierarchy.
I want that you grasp this very well. Otherwise you cannot make an evaluation of a case.
Unless you understand that after
a severe, acute condition,
you're treating a systemic disease,
lupus erythymatosus,
rheumatoid arthritis; you're
treating something serious,
then as the person
gets better on the physical body
some disturbances may appear on
the emotional level which as
corresponding will be in minor,
in lesser, in lower level
than the original disturbance.
-Let's suppose that the patient took a remedy and on the emotional level came down
but on the physical level, on the skin
he developed a melanoma.
-What is this development? Is it good
or bad? This is the question.
If a person, after treated correctly homeopathically for emotional problems,
develops a very severe physical disturbance,
then that means that this physical
disturbance is of lesser damage or
importance than the emotional.
That means that this person was crazy.
If we have disturbances which are really
mental-emotional deep disturbances,
to see their corresponding
physical equal, it might be quite strong,
quite terrifying sometimes.
As the lady described it, so much pain,
she cries and she can't stand the lumbago,
these are still nothing.
But if you have something like melanoma,
even in such a case I have found out that
if this organism is shifted to this direction,
there is a possibility for a cure.
Most of the times, the next
remedy will be apparent
and then you will be able
to help further the individual.
Now, there is a possibility that all this development is accidental
which is of a different thing.
- There are 2 levels, very deeply
affected. Heart ailment- strong,
and on the other side suicidal
depression or destructive delirium.
Where do I have to put the
stress of the treatment?
-In such a case it will be very difficult to find the remedy. The remedy will not be apparent.
In so progressed cases in pathology
we cannot see the remedy.
So there is no a question where you put
the stress of the treatment.
You don't see the remedy. You just see all possibilities there without a specific remedy
which you're searching for. In such a
case you will not find the remedy.
-We always have to put the question,
how long may last such a process?
How long it may last until
we can come to cure?
-That's a good question. The deeper you
start here, the longer it will take.
If you start with the physical, even
severe, but the mental-emotional
disturbances are minute, then the
length of time that you need
to bring about a cure, will be much
less than if you are treating a mental case
of a deep disorder. It will take much
longer with the mental-emotional.
-In the case of depression that evolved into melanoma, once you have the melanoma,
do you think it is wise to treat it surgically or should we treat it with a second remedy?
-Especially with melanoma, it's not only
what you would like to do,
it is what society likes you to do. Society in general and I mean the medical society,
demands that you treat it surgically.
So what you have to do is to treat
it surgically so you don't have the attorney inquiring and then you continue to treat
according to the symptomatology
with the hope that it's not going to be
a metastasis
or a relapse of the melanoma.
-If I have a patient with a lot of
aggression and I gave him a remedy,
then he gets a big heart problem.
Is it possible that he can get a heart attack
or I don't know how to react in this?
-It's a heart problem, yes. Developing
from fears, strong anxiety neurosis
the heart
can maybe affected, yes.
-I wish to ask you about this
case with the melanoma.
I heard and I read about melanoma.
Before all of them medical doctors thought
that melanoma is very very aggressive,
one of the mosts aggressive cancers
but after a while saw that many patients
have melanoma since 20 or 30 years.
Now I think that this development
you can see after the operation,
this aggressivity.
And I think to let operate it will
be an explosion in the body
and it will be very difficult to manage.
-That is true, sometimes after an
operation with melanoma
we have the explosion and
we have the metastasis.
It is true in some cases. It is true also
that in some cases of melanoma
it might stay for a long period of
time without progress.
So there are different types of
melanoma and different individuals,
depending on their defences,
how they can handle
and they can bring about, balance.
That is true but what we say is that in case
you allow your patient to be operated,
by giving the homeopathic
remedy, you protect him
from going into metastasis state.
-If someone has a depression and then
gets a melanoma which I assume
in this case that it is  more severe,
on higher level than the depression itself ?
-No, no. It is on physical level but if you
take this, suicidal depression is almost
in the end of life of the physical body.
The melanoma is somewhere here,
depression is there. It's going down there.
You remember also that in this model
we have the uppermost parts
of the mental-emotional outside
of the physical body.
You remember that we have given the explanation. Why this is so?
There are some functions of the human
being which transcend his physical body.
These functions are absolutely essential
for the human being to exist
as a human being and therefore
are beyond the physical body.
-I have a question concerning age. When
you treat a baby or an elderly person
with heart problems or so.
Is something to consider in this case?
-I don't understand the question.
-Just with age if there is a difference with the treatment, if you have something to consider.
If there is something with an elderly
person, being more dangerous
and with a baby also or a small child?
-No, I think it's gonna happen both. I do not
have the experience treating babies
with AIDS but theoretically
we could say that...
-Not AIDS, age !
-Age?
-George, the question is about
the age of the patient.
-I will tell you something, whilst I'm
teaching you Homeopathy,
I'm teaching you English
also. It's a joke.
Actually it's not a joke, a lot of people
have learned, I see them year after year
understanding better English
because my English is so clear.
-Is it a difference between treating a
baby and treating a grown up?
No there is no difference.
Treating the baby only is more easy than
treating the grown up. Why?
Because their defence mechanisms are
not destroyed through stresses of life.
They have not time to fall in love
and then get disappointed,
they don't have time to become
alcoholics, you know all these.
These are stresses that are
weakening the human body.