-I have a patient that I'm treating constitutionally and one day a severe shock happened to her.
Her little baby was run over by a car and after that she developed severe fears.
She remembered that as a child she was attacked by a bird and this bird
actually picked on her face
and destroyed her face.
And according to this event of shock,
I gave her Aconite.
All her life long she was not able to move,
she always has a stiff neck
and after giving her Aconite, she
could move her head again.
My question is: is this person
strong person constitutionally?
Because her fears materialized to her
body by the stiffness of the neck?
-There are several things there. The first
is that this woman had a shock
when she was a young girl and has a
shock when she is a grown up woman.
Due to initial shock, the fears
somatised in the stiffness,
she became stiff from fear,
we say it. She could not move.
And the stiffness was somatised on the neck. Now she gets another shock and the baby
is run over and then the fears develop.
She comes with a stiff neck from initial fear,
with new fears which come from the baby.
He gives Aconite and actually what it does,
it takes off the first layer of this woman.
The first layer of that
woman now it's taken away.
After Aconite, most probably the next
remedy will be more apparent,
more clear and you will be able to go
deeper and help this patient deeper.
This is a good example of fears that
went straight to the physical body.
The body does not have anymore
the possibility to somatise the fears
and the fears are exploding. She comes
to the Homeopath, he gives most probably a
very high potency.
What potency you gave, you remember?
-1000.
-Not very high, eh? It's quite high and the stiffness as well as the fears are reduced.
Most probably, I don't know the case,
but most probably this case has been
left with some symptoms now,
is that correct?
-That's correct.
-These examples are important because you bring examples from your own practice
and it's important for others to listen.
-For me it was so interesting because these
fears before had never been in the foreground.
-This is exactly what we're saying here.
The fears maybe they were
not existing in the first place.
By the strength of the organism they were
gone to the physical body.
And then the second fears, the body cannot handle and then they are exploding.
-I don't really agree with what you said before that it's always less difficult to treat a child.
-Don't forget, he's a pediatrician so he has
an opinion which is quite serious.
-If they have severe hereditary problems,
I think the child will take a lot of time before
you find the remedy.
-This is true, he has faced the problem
because he sees the children. In children
you do not have the possibility to get
easily the symptoms, you rely upon observation of the parents and that makes it already quite difficult because you don't have the original
information from the baby. 'I'm afraid'.
Like in the case of encephalomyelitis which I described to you, tremendous
fear of the child and the mother thought it was courageous because it was taking all these injections without talking at all without crying.
Total misinterpretation of the woman concerning the emotional level of the child.
But what I said is this: that if we have a pneumonia in a child and a pneumonia
in an old person, equal things,
that pneumonia on the child will be easier
to respond once we find the remedy. He says, how do we find the remedy?
That is some difficulties we have there concerning how easy is for us to get the information for the child.
A child is very difficult to describe symptoms,
a baby especially but still many times we have
very obvious symptoms in the children,
which give us the peculiarity
we are seeking for in order to prescribe
the correct remedy.
-I have two questions. When you say,
take off the first layer you mean the bottom
one or the top one?
-The top one. Here in his case, Acon.
was the first. This is stiffness in his case
and these are different other remedies.
Now this person gets another shock
and this fear that was so little
becomes like this, fear of death.
And then the stifness becomes a minor thing concerning the present fears but still is there.
You give the Aconite, then this goes down and that goes down and all this goes away and then you had the next layer.
-How does the intensity of a symptom go into that painting? I don't quite understand.
You have different diseases, like heart disease, severe or minor heart disease, how does
it go into that?
-It goes according to your knowledge of Medicine. Your knowledge will tell you if this is
a severe endocarditis
or a minor endocarditis.
Your experience as a doctor will tell you that
and you know what might be a
dangerous or not a dangerous situation.
This is according to your medical knowledge.
-Does this mean in the case of Acon. that luckily Acon. was able to treat two levels at once?
-Not two levels, one level that was aggravated further. Acon. was needed as a first remedy,
at the age of 6,
it remained there as Acon. level; there comes another shock and makes the Acon. picture much stronger.
Then you say, oh my God this is Acon.
In spite of the fact you may have been given Sulph. or Lyc. before, without effect.
You may have been given the underlying
remedy even before the Aconite without
having the effect of releasing
that stiffness which means that
you gave either prematurely the underlying remedies or your remedy was wrong.
Let us say, you've given Ars., none of these remedies, not Acon. or you gave Phos. and then this and that, no effect.
It changes a little and then the shock comes
and the Acon. picture becomes so strong.
I have said many times that Acon. is not to be considered as an acute remedy for common cold.
It is remedy to be used for chronic conditions
and also for deep chronic conditions, this is one more proof.
-I have one more question to this Aconite case. Could it not be possible that he had treated the patient before
and isn't also possible that he gave different remedies which only uncovered the Acon. layer
which was maybe one of the underlying layers
and that at this time when the Acon. layer was revealed
she had a second shock which
made it more pronounced.
-It is possible of course. This person with Acon. she had a grief and then another grief and another grief
and then on top of the  Acon., there was
a Nat-m layer developed, and then he gave
the Nat-m and
took away some of the symptoms. Stiffness
and other symptoms which belong to the Acon. remained,
then the shock came, then the
fears appeared, that is also true.
But what I say is that one time the organism
itself does what the homeopathic remedy
will do.
It somatises, it takes the fears and put them
on the physical level. The organism by itself did this.
-George I want to ask you a question about melanoma. I had a patient, he's been with me
for 6 years.
He came to me 2-3 weeks after he
was operated for melanoma on his face.
I took his case carefully and
I came up with Arg-n.
There were clear symptoms of
anxiety and many symptoms on Arg-n.
I used it for 4 years, 200 and so on.
He became greatly improved, mentally,
emotionally and he even started to practice as
a psychologist. He got a degree and he became
very successful and somewhere around 4
years after treatment, it was discovered
a metastasis of the original melanoma in his brain. I was actually very upset because I thought
the remedy was so good, why
did he get this metastasis?
But he was very courageous and he got himself operated by a good neurosurgeon and much to my delight he recovered very well.
He continued to do very well, he still came to me occasionally and I repeated the Arg-n a few times.
Last year, he had no remedy for almost one year and appeared symptoms of Sulphur. There was no doubt about it.
I gave one dose Sulphur 10M
and he has been very well since.
Can you comment and show me some guidance? He has been extremely well,
he calls me from time to time, he refers
patients from time and he is very successful.
-Before I give you an explanation I will
say a similar case with a friend of mine.
We were playing when we were children,
more or less my age about 25 years ago,
he came with a melanoma and I prescribed
for him and 25 years there is no relapse.
Different type of melanoma, I think it was on
his chest or something, if I remember well.
What happened in your case, most probably,
is that: If we suppose that Arg-n was correct,
then maybe we can suppose that the
next remedy you did not see.
It was a Sulphur, and you did not see it.
So after Arg-n, you might have given
different other remedies but not Sulphur.
Then the organism progresses and goes towards disease and eventually the defence mechanism
throws out symptoms which for you at this time are clear and you give it and then he becomes very well.
That means Sulphur might have been indicated six months after the Arg-n and you missed this possibility.
As a result you gave wrong remedies, even
Arg-n after you repeated it might not have been indicated.
So we consider it as the wrong remedy after
the 2d, 3rd repetition. That means the disease progresses
and it reaches a point where the organism is really shaken and throws out a picture, you say a picture of Sulphur.
This is a case where we have a lot of hope,
when the remedy is clear and the reaction is very good,
then we can say, inspite of metastasis he
may be living another 10 years. How old is he?
-Every time he got Arg-n it was
repeated at long intervals, in high potencies.
He would report great improvement
of his mental and emotional condition.
-Why you stress mental and emotional?
-Because he had mental-emotional anxiety,
lack of confidence, he was angry with his
wife
and all of that seemed to improve.
His desire for sweets became less and less,
his eating habits became very nice and he
felt very much at ease in every day life.
-After he became at ease, then Arg-n
is not anymore indicated.
-Is it possible that without the Arg-n. the metastasis would have take place
much sooner rather than so many years later?
-Definitely, my answer is definitely because
if the melanoma is of such type that will
have metastasis, the metastasis will
come much sooner if the organism is weak.
-Also the metastasis was not large, it was very small metastasis. It was easy to detect and it was operated
and he came back home within less than one week. So what could I have done better?
Secondly, why did I not see Sulphur
is my second question.
This is speculation but I'm trying to
see what could I have done better?
Because now the  man is doing
very well, inspite the surgery.
-I have also made the same mistakes. There
is a kind of accusation, everyone of us makes similar mistakes.
Don't think that I don't make mistakes.
I could made as well the same mistake,
that means not recognizing the next remedy
though it might be apparent for somebody else, even for a novice.
He sticks his feet out or covers and a novice knows that Sulphur sticks his feet out of covers
and because of that he gives Sulphur and does better than you that you know all the Materia Medica
and all the Repertories and you have
eaten all the books of Materia Medica.
And he still comes and says,
how could I not have thought about it?
-He said I cannot wait to eat at around 11-11:30,
I have to bring a sandwich, and my feet are out at night and are burning
And I said, I don't give you Arg-n anymore,
I gave you Sulphur and I gave one dose only
and now for one year he does not come back.
-He will not come back. Was anybody in
London when I took a case about 1983-4.
I took a case of AIDS and I predicted
this man is going to live at least 20 more years.
Was anybody present? Do you remember,
a Sulphur case from Germany?
Remind me to tell you the name
of the doctor who presented the case,
I would like to see whether
this person is still alive.
-So, a disturbance on the upper level of
the emotional level is more threatening
than a disturbance on the
bottom of the mental level?
-No, no. There is a corresponding here
between emotional-physical-mental.
The corresponding mental or physical, for instance, if the disturbance on the emotional
is here
and it is doing better, it will go on the
mental level here. It will not go there.
If it goes there, it's a suppression. It has to go
on a level which is better in its correspondence than the original case.
A disease in the mental level which is equal in severity with an emotional, then it's more serious.
This problem here is more serious
than this problem on the emotional.
Because they are on the same level.
-Patients which after treatment say,
these fears I never had before,
is it possible that they are born with 3 or 4
layers as we have on the board there?
And then they come for treatment at the age
of maybe 20 years? And we, slowly but steadily, take away the layers?
And then if we reach a level of Calc then
the person develops Calc fears?
-Yes sure, it can develop. But these fears are not as serious as Acon. fear that was originally.
A fear has different shades or different intensity, each fear. You take fear of death and he says, sometimes I have fear of death.
Another person says, I fear death constantly
and another person says, I fear death so much
that I don't go out of my house.
That is a different intensity fear.
The first time, Acon. will take the very great intensity fear, then the fear remains in a lesser degree, Calc. will take it away.
The same with headaches. Severe headaches, you give Bell and then he says, 'I'm much better'.
Why are you much better?
'Because my headaches do not paralyze me,
now I can go at least at work. Before I had to stay in my home
because the headaches
were so strong, I could not work'.
This lesser headaches, still are there
and they are taken away by Calc.
A little bit of change in the nature of the headaches, the other symptoms change also
a little bit, then you give Calc.
and takes away the rest of the headaches.
-Is this the explanation for the patient saying,
'well I have never in my life had these fears before.
I experienced them for the first time'.
-When the patient says, 'I have a fear
I never experienced', it is very relative.
He may have experienced the fears but in a
such less degree that he did not pay attention.
Even in a proving of a remedy, has a kind of similarity with the genetic predispositions
of the person in order to bring out
such symptoms. There is a similarity.
But within these 3 different levels I must tell you that I'm absolutely insecure in swimming and
I have real problems following you. In this jumping physical-mental-emotional level.
-How it happens? The mechanism?
-Yes, I have not understood the mechanism.
In the case of him, since he has an amelioration
on the emotional level, can you exclude an aggravation on the mental level in this case?
-No, you can not exclude but the aggravation
on the mental level it will be minute. Of no great importance.
-One more question. I'm treating someone
who has compulsive neurosis.
Suppose this person ameliorates and he then develops either diabetes or high blood pressure.
So if I understand correctly and I'm not
sure, this would be an amelioration?
-Yes.
-Now, I'm treating this endocrine problem and during this treatment he develops a depression
with suicidal thoughts. Is this an aggravation?
-She said, suicidal depression. Suicidal depression means at any moment the patient
will jump.
This is different than depression. If you ask
this class, do you have depression?
Everyone will say I have some
depression, little, bigger etc.
If you say suicidal depression means a person who is sitting there - Aurum state - and meditate all the time how to kill himself.
Then, this is an aggravation.
The depression is an amelioration.
It is a matter of intensity.
Sometimes it is difficult to get to
know what is more serious. A suicidal depression or a heart condition?
Usually the heart condition,
if it developed after a treatment
for suicidal depression, a heart condition is better though it endangers the physical
health of the person.
Either we like it or not, these are the facts.
These are described in paragraph,
you go and find the paragraph in which Hahnemann describes exactly that.
That when a physical condition goes away,
you may have a suppression where the
problem goes into mental-emotional.
And when you treat this person on the mental-emotional, the physical problem reappears.
Where in the Organon, Hahnemann says that physical conditions can be suppressed
and mental-emotional conditions
may appear? And vice-versa.
During treatment, you treat a mental-emotional and the physical condition becomes deteriorated.
Yeats, I think an English poet....
-Irish.
-Irish? Who wrote a very interesting poem,
I remember a phrase which says:
'they doubt and sigh and do not love
at all, of these am I, of these am I'.
That means he was in a depression state
and he was expressing the torture of an intellectual.
They doubt about everything and they sigh and then the feelings go away. And then he says, of this type I am.
It's beautiful, it is expressing a
state of a human development.
As we go and go, we have more
of this type of people today.
-My question is, as you told us, if I understand
it correctly that the more layers we have in
our patient,
the less obvious picture will be at the first layer.
And the more obvious picture, this will give us idea
that the closer to the bottom, constitutional
layer we are in. That surprises me.
- Are you a mathematician?
- Yes, I'm a mathematician.
- Really?
- Yes really. I am theoretical physics.
- Not mathematics.
- No, it's the same.
-Many times that you prescribe for people for Russian group, for some cases we took here,
for some of them you did just give one dose of let's say 10M and that's all.
For some persons like you did to my case, you prescribe 200, next day 1M, next day 10M.
Does that mean that you expect if you do it so aggressively, attack the vital force?
And you suspect that those persons are closer to the bottom and it's time to push a bit?
-Mostly, I repeat, thinking two things.
One that maybe the organism is more
lazy,
and it needs a little bit more pushing
before starting go towards a cure.
The other time, I may think...we are in America, from where will you get the medicine?
I'm not convinced that all pharmacies are good. So I may do it like this with the hope that if 1M
is not potentized,
then 10M will be potentized or 50M, one of
the three will be potentized. So there are two ways for doing that.