We have a problem and the problem is this.
I will show you a case, for instance, and I will make some questions to the patient.
The questions I put have a purpose to discover what is the indicated remedy for that organism.
But the questions are guided by the fact that I know the Materia Medica.
What is the Materia Medica?
The Materia Medica is the information which has come from proving of remedies
and has been recorded in an encyclopedia which is called Materia Medica.
That means my questioning will not be like a questioning of a conventional medical doctor
who asks and wants to know about a specific pathology from which the patient is suffering.
I would like to know, except of this pathology, the local pathology,
I would like to know how his global organism responds and is trying to balance.
The idea of examining a case is to find out how the organism has trying to bring balance
for a certain pathology which is suffering from.
For instance, a man with a duodenal ulcer, he may have heart burn
and pain 3-4 hours after eating. That is typical of duodenal ulcer pathology.
But then this is not enough for us to give the remedy. Why? I will tell you why.
Because one organism wants in order to balance a lot of water.
So the person says I'm very thirsty and not only thirsty but I need water
which is really cold, very cold.
The other says, I'm not thirsty at all. I don't need water.
Actually if I drink water and especially if the water is cold, then I have a reaction
and I have a nausea.
So we cannot give the same remedy to the one and to the other.
We have to find which is the remedy which is indicated in this organism.
In this way the modalities or the different symptoms which an organism develops
in order to counterbalance the problem are innumerable.
And out of these details of how the organism is reacting,
we try to find out the individual remedy which is indicated.
And this is the big secret for Homeopathy.
If you don't find the exact remedy which is needed for an organism, there is no effect.
I'll give you an example.
Many people thought how is that possible, you search for this remedy and you have to study,
you have to take properly a case, it takes a long time
and I suspect that in a duodenal ulcer there are about 20 remedies
affecting primarily the duodenal ulcer.
Why not give all 20, which we call polypharmacy, and one of them
will be the correct between them and most probably will help the patient.
This was an understanding many, many years ago and there were in France
and in Germany pharmacies they sold specialties for Homeopathy.
Specialties for headaches, specialties for bronchitis, specialties for gastritis, for colitis,
for duodenal ulcer etc. That kind of Homeopathy is charlatanistic Homeopathy.
If you are a charlatan, you can prescribe in this way.
Otherwise if you want to help your patient, you have to sit down
and very methodically get all the information from his organism and then study properly
in order to find what?
To find the remedy that has the same kind of vibrational frequency actually.
Do you see the idea?
Because the remedy does not contain one infinitesimally small amount of the remedy.
So what are you giving?
You transform the remedy to an energy remedy and then you give energy.
But energy affecting energy, it can affect it through what?
You cannot affect air by taking a stone and throw it to the air.
You affect an air substance by another air substance and then you can mix them
and then there is effect.
Liquid with liquid. Then you can mix them. Liquid with air you cannot.
Here we have energy and when we mix it with the energy of the organism...
What is the idea of affecting the energy, affecting that energy?
I'll give you another example.
How many of you play the guitar?
If you strike a 'La' note and you have next to it a chord which is in this frequency,
the other chord without touching it starts vibrating. If it is 'La', it's the same frequency.
So this is the idea, the same frequency.
You find the frequency of the organism by doing all this research and actually excavate,
bringing to the front symptomatology of the patient.
But what is the difference? It's not only that we have to know
the physical symptomatology of the patient. Therefore a human being is not only material body.
We talk and when we talk we get ideas from another plane and we get also emotions.
So we are emotions, we are ideas, we are thinking and also we have physical bodies.
Each case, every pathology case can affect, may affect, not necessarily will affect
but can affect the mental and emotional state of the human being.
So if a pathology has affected the feelings or the way of thinking of a human being,
then we have to know the changes, how it has affected.
You know how duodenal ulcer is produced?
Duodenal ulcer is produced when anger is not expressed in time and is held inside
and all the anger which is held inside produces acids which burn the mucus membranes
usually of the duodenal or the stomach, in which case you will have gastritis,
or the duodenal, in which case you will have duodenal ulcer or affects the colon,
in which case you will have colitis.
Therefore holding the anger creates a situation in the physical body
and the two are affecting each other and that is why they have found out
and it is very well known what they call the psychosomatic medicine.
The only psychosomatic medicine which exists is Homeopathy because this is the medicine
that takes into consideration the psychology and the physical.
And there are laws according to which you are proceeding.
You are not treating...for your depression I will give you an anti-depressant
and what happens after that?
Because you are anxious, I will give you an anxiolytic remedy.
It is like trying to target in one point in the organism,
where a depressed person is a person that does not produce enzymes, opiates
which give a feeling of well-being.
There is a series of facts.
Somebody lost his job, he has a fight with the director, they shout
and then he says I go from the company, I don't want to be in your company anymore,
you are this and that and he leaves.
Such a person who has spoken out all his anger, he has no danger in affecting his body.
He spoke out, he said whatever he had to say and he is relieved.
Another person goes to the person who has accused him unjustly, he tries to tell
that I'm not responsible for this mistake, no you are responsible, he cannot speak,
the anger is increasing more and more and he is discharged from that company.
That person within 3-4 days he will start having pains in the stomach because of the anger.
Because of the anger the pathologist to whom he goes,
he does not take into consideration what happened, the suppressed anger.
What he knows is that the acids in the stomach are increasing.
Therefore I will give you an anti-acid remedy.
Take an anti-acid remedy, you take it every day and then what happens?
You do not allow the physical reaction of the organism, you suppress it,
you do not allow it to bring out the acid, to bring out the poison of the organism.
So by not allowing there to come out the anger of the stomach, then the anger
which was inside and it was expressing the anger through the acid in the stomach
cannot express it anymore and the person becomes depressed.
So depression now is much more a serious condition
than the suppressed anger that was before.
Then depression and depression and then one day the person commits suicide.
You see how things are happening.
I describe to you very grossly what happens.
Actually targeting your medicine in one part of your body does not solve the problem.
If I give you a remedy which can stop the acid coming out is not a good idea
because it may be suppressing and then all the different reactions will take place
within the organism and a more deep problem will manifest.
If I have a case and she tells me I have a problem, my main problem is with menses.
I have a lot of pain before menses, during menses, a lot of bleeding...
Why she has this problem?
Maybe we don't know, maybe we cannot find the real reason but we have to investigate why.
Even if we can't find, then we can go the ancestry. The mother had the same syndrome?
Then we can explain by genetic predisposition.
Then we cannot find because these are unknown but we don't give a remedy or we don't
have a remedy for stopping the excessed blood or stopping the pains in the abdomen.
Usually the women take spasmolytics in order to counteract the pains.
So while the problem is local, we start investigating what kind of fears you may have,
what about anxieties, what about fears, depressions,
mental-emotional structure of this organism?
Together with some other areas in which apart from the premenstrual syndrome,
she also has a chronic constipation.
So all this, the mental-emotional symptomatology, the menstrual symptomatology
and the constipation symptomatology are studied together in order to find the remedy
that synchronizes with such a global symptomatology.
I made this introduction for those who do not know that
when you will see a case taking you will say why George is asking irrelevant questions.
She came for headaches and he is asking whether you have diarrhea or constipation
and whether your menses are normal or not normal. But here I came for my headaches.
The problem that has been so far with Homeopathy is that people
who practice Homeopathy did not understand the basic truths of Homeopathy,
that we have laws according to which we prescribe and then they thought
we prescribe symptomatically, according to the symptoms.
Somebody will relate a few symptoms and the homeopath will write a prescription.
I have pains in my abdomen before menses, OK I'll give you 5 remedies, take 10 remedies
that they have pains before menses.
But that is wrong and not only do not cure but it can suppress to a certain extend this pain
which is going to be transformed now into a deeper problem of pathology
and usually on the mental-emotional level.
That is how we have pushed diseases from physical body to the mental-emotional sphere
and we have made a society today which is a crazy society.
Do you think that we are sane?
We are insane but because everyone is insane we admit that everybody is OK.
But what are these reactions that we are having each one?
What happens in America? One child gets the gun of his father, he goes to school
and kills 1,2,3,4,5 of his class mates.
Another one takes a gun and kills his colleagues, these are extremes
but are these reactions of a society which is sane?
Maybe you say you take some extreme examples. It's not a few extreme examples.
You have every day all fights which happen within a family
and you will see in the family they tear to pieces each other
and you will see hysterical reactions, you will see crazy reactions in the family.
The children don't know anymore what is normal and what is not normal.
Parents don't know anymore what is normal.
A child of 12 years old to have sex and the mother and father think that it's normal.
It's not normal.
The moment that a child 12,13,14,15,16,17 starts having sex from that moment
onwards starts the craziness, the child will behave in a crazy way.
Because she will get hurt, she will get misused, she will develop hatred,
she will become a feminist, she will have a lot of mental-emotional problems after that.
And then she goes to the society and she accuses the society
since everyone in the society is more or less in the same boat.
It is understood and the society says it is acceptable.
Anything is acceptable and you see all the deviations and the craziness which is going on.
We live in that society.
How this society has come about?
You know the responsibility of wrong medicine, applying wrong medicines.
That part is quite big, I would say 60% is responsible for such a society.
The vaccinations, the conventional medicine, the antibiotics and all that.
That is why the Western societies, Europe, America, Canada are in that state.
Not developing countries like South America which is much more down to earth people.
And also the Asians. They also have some samples but it's very limited.
In our society because we are all vaccinated, we have all taken antibiotics,
we all have this miasm, we will be talking about the miasm, this miasm of cultural deviation.