So for those who do not know the kind of Homeopathy which is practiced here, I have to say a few things.
That you will see me taking a case and you will not be able, sometimes, to understand the questions, why?
Because you have not been educated. You have not taken the whole course to know all the remedies, all the questions etc.
So, be patient those who do not understand.
I have to explain to you the strategy
I'm following in order to understand
more or less what's going on.
As I am a person who knows Homeopathy
and I have some experience,
when I hear a few symptoms, immediately
I'm thinking of some remedies.
The usual thing that you are learning in certain schools that you have been before, according
to this, they say first let the patient tell you the whole story and then put some questions and then you decide.
Here, it's not so.
Unfortunately we do not have
the time and the luxury to do this.
Because if I do this for the whole
week we will see one case.
You don't want that. You want to see how Homeopathy is practiced in a practical manner,
in real situation
where you have a practice and people are coming to be treated. You have scheduled
5-10 people in a day.
You're not going to hear stories and stories. You want to find the remedy and this is the most important thing.
Because it doesn't matter how much
the person will say about himself.
Still he will not be healed. It may be good
for the person to talk about himself.
So in this way, we may have what we call a placebo effect. Somebody comes and sees that we are very sympathetic,
we are listening to him, we are very perceptive of his problem.
He feels at ease to talk and that is
a kind of psychotherapy, some kind.
And that is why, as Homeopaths,
we have a lot of cases of placebo effect.
It's not the remedy, it is because you
listen to the person very carefully.
So we come back to the strategy we follow. When a person gives me a few symptoms
I know more or less what might be his remedy.
I ask certain questions concerning this remedy,
I try to confirm.
In this way he adds one more information which is negating what I thought, ok, I go to another idea.
I ask questions concerning a new idea.
This is the kind of taking of the case that you
will follow.
But I have to tell you a few things which are
very important. For instance, as you know,
a person is bothered by heat and when he comes to the fresh air, he says, he feels better.
This is a subtle point which
is so important for Homeopathy;
you cannot imagine the
importance of such a symptom.
Why, what happens to the organism who is coming out to the air and the whole organism is rejuvenated?
How comes? In the fresh air the energy
is coming up, better feelings.
Then you get another one, he sits there
and feels, oh my god there is a draft
somewhere I feel it.
And more and more is constricted; his cervical region becomes more and more constricted.
His back, oh my god where is
coming this bloody draft?
Nobody realizes actually where this draft
comes that the organism perceives.
This little bit of draft contracts the muscles and creates in the whole organism such a difference
between a normality and total discomfort.
These things are so important with Homeopathy which you cannot dispense with.
For instance if I ask you, which is the
remedy which is better in open air?
-Who says Pulsatilla?
Who doesn't say Pulsatilla? You know what
that means? That those who put their hands
up know Puls for sure.
Pulsatilla is better in open air.
The others, they are not sure.
This lacking of knowledge is very important because you may not be able to recognize
a Puls case.
When you examine a person and you find this
is a Puls case and the person has come with hay fever etc.
If you ask him when you are in the open air,
you feel better? What is the answer?
-Who says yes?
No, Pulsatilla in this local symptom
is worse in the open air.
You see already you got two
little things for a hay fever.
Puls eats the fat?
Meat with a piece of fat very good for Puls.
This Puls hates. It will take out all the
pieces of fat but you say, what about butter?
You will hear, I relish butter. I put a lot
of butter. Little things like that.
If you have a case in which the main symptom
is depression and the desire to die really.
I'm not interested.
And the person says, you ask the person, 'is any condition which makes you feel better?'
And she says, usually a woman, 'when I am outside and the wind is blowing my depression
is lifted'.
If that is what the person has told you, then the remedy is not Pulsatilla. It's Aurum muriaticum.
How comes that the headache is better in the open air? We don't know the chemistry.
We don't know really what happens but it is a fact that when the headache is better, is Pulsatilla.
When the depression is better
is Aurum muriaticum.
How can you define this through
physiology and anatomy?
It's not possible to know the chemistry
what takes place within the organism.
Because the organism is so complex,
you cannot imagine the complexity.
I mean nobody could ever imagine the complexity of the human brain. And I don't believe
that anybody ever will find out what's
going on with the human brain.
They try to locate where is, in the brain,
where is located conscience.
Not consciousness. It's different.
I have a bad conscience. I have a clean conscience, it's different than I'm conscious of, I'm aware of.
Where is located? They are trying to locate it,
the neurophysiologists, different experiments.
According to me, they will never find.
Because that quality of the human being
belongs to
the whole human being, not to
a particular place within the brain.
Never mind how long they may be trying.
So, we Homeopaths, are hundreds of years ahead
in understanding health and disease than what materialistic Medicine is knowing so far.
That is why if you are a good homeopath you
can do a better and more quick diagnosis of a case
than all the laboratory tests they can bring you.
I will show you a case. I had seen in Berlin.
I was there, giving a seminar and a case was presented to me, a little girl. Her mother is a medical doctor.
She said to me, my girl has been diagnosed as Still's disease, it's juvenile rheumatoid arthritis.
It makes the joints swell and distorted.
I took the case and I said, who said this diagnosis? She said, 3 hospitals in Germany.
I go inside the class to analyze
the case, the mother was sitting there.
I said, I'm sorry but this case is not Still's disease. She said, what it is?
I said, I don't know the syndrome but this is a hereditary syndrome which is very severe
and according to my understanding the child will not go over 7 years. The child was 1,5.
The mother comes afterwards and says, what are you talking? I said, I don't know what is the syndrome
but definitely this is not a rheumatoid arthritis, it is something much more severe and it is hereditary.
She takes the child and goes back to 3 different hospitals. One of the hospitals they made the correct diagnosis.
Morbus Farber's disease for those
who know some good medicine.
It is a deficiency in a particular enzyme,
it's called ceramidase.
In the books, it was written when I went
back I read, children live up to 7 years old.
It was unbelievable what I was saying.
Because I didn't know the syndrome and
yet I was able to understand that a person with this problem is not going to go over 7 years.
With Homeopathy all these years, about 12
years of Homeopathy, the child is now 13.
I don't know how long it's going to live and she
is on a wheel chair. Still the deformities are apparent
but not to the extend she was,
she was not able to talk.
But I will show you some pictures of the child to understand. Why a homeopath can make
a diagnosis and all the laboratories
and all the knowledge of
speciality of the people could not understand
the difference between Still's disease and something else.
This is not Still's disease. You see the nose was deformed because this disease affects the cartilages
which are expanding and the cartilages expanding make fantastic deformities.
The person cannot really
use the hands or the voice.
So I come back to the idea of
what you are going to watch.
When you are learning in the school how to take a case, actually you are not learning anything.
One time I had a class like that; I said to them, you don't know anything about Homeopathy.
They were medical doctors. Ok, take the case of one another and show me what information you had.
Two lines, each.
He had headaches and he had this.
He had vomiting at the age of 10
and then tonsillitis.
You see what you have done, you went back to your memory to what you know about medicine
and you applied this knowledge
to the taking of the case.
Is anybody eggastrimithos? (ventriloquist).
You know people who talk with their abdomen,
it seems to me there is somebody here
who is doing this. No.
So I told them, ok now I'm going to teach you in this course something else. What is this something else?
It is what we call the Materia Medica.
But the question is: is it possible that any
human brain can hold all the information
of 12 volumes of Materia Medica?
Is it possible?
By the way, my 12th volume of
Materia Medica Viva is coming out soon.
So if you are interested maybe put some orders because in about 20 days, it will be out.
I will tell you which remedies are there. Iris, Hepar, Hyoscyamus, Ignatia, Iodum, Hypericum.
These are the remedies which are contained in this Materia Medica in a very expanded form
with the original, essential features
which is about 2 pages each.
So the information that you must have in your mind is tremendous. How can you hold it?
It's not possible.
What you need is to hold in your brain
a few main points, we call them keynotes
of the remedies.
If you manage to hold the keynotes in your
brain, then you have a fantastic information.
Now the problem is who is the one who will
tell you which are the important points in
each remedy?
-You.
-You see, the person who has a lot of experience can really transfer to you the information who says,
in many cases of Iodium I have seen
this, this and that keynotes.
Therefore you have to get the correct information about the remedy. From whom?
The problem is that today we don't have legalized schools. Anybody can open a school, no problem.
What is teaching, I don't know. But there are
no standard things which are taught in these,
so called, homeopathic schools.
Unless in a school you learn the correct Materia Medica, you are gathering in your brain information
which is rubbish and you need to get it out in order to put the correct information, later on.
You see this is a big problem which happens
in our science. I tell you some facts.
When I was practicing in Athens, and I had
a lot of medical doctors practising with me.
What we were using?
Kent's Repertory and Materia Medica and Materia Medica Boericke, basically.
You won't believe the success
rate we had with this information.
Why? Because I have given to my students the information which I have gathered 15 years back.
I have given them the main points
so they would be able to recognize
whether a case is a Mercury or it is a
Calcarea carbonica or a Pulsatilla.
Which are the differential points to understand the difference between the one and the other?
So, when Bill Gray, who knows Bill Gray?
Who knows Roger Morisson?
Both of these American doctors came to study with me in Athens. Bill Gray came in 1976,
he sat next to me like some other doctors were sitting and I have asked Bill, when a person was coming in as a follow up,
I said to Bill, ask him in English: 'how are you?'.
And the 99% of the answers was 'much better'.
After a few months he told me, 'I will not sit next to you because it is routine. I know if he comes he will say, much better'. Why?
Because the information on the Materia Medica that we had, it was the correct kind of information.
That is why you will have these results.
I come back now to the idea of the
specialist who has some knowledge.
If you are a medical doctor you
have the knowledge of medicine.
You have added now the knowledge
of Materia Medica.
So you are able now to see a case with
a different perspective all together.
You are asking a question, 'how are you affected by drafts?'. 'No problem'. Finish the question.
The other one says: 'drafts oh my god I can't stand them'. Another one: 'I don't like them'.
So in experience what you will find out is that each symptom has a degree of intensity.
It is this degree of intensity which becomes important eventually because if the person
will tell you: 'I can't stand drafts at all',
your mind goes to which remedies?
-Kali-carbonicum, Lobelia, Hepar, Silica.
There are 3 remedies which are quite strong, Rhus-t., Calc-p. and Cimic. for what?
If there is a draft affects their cervical region.
You see you have to be very careful because here you are going to do the most detailed examination, right?
The one who is affected by draft mostly in
the lumbar region, is not so much Cimic.
It is Kali-c, is Calc.
The Calc-p., is affected very much
in which kind of weather?
Just after the snow, this weather which
is wet and cold. It's killing for Calc-p.
There are a lot of remedies which are affected by wet and cold. One main remedy is ...?
-Dulcamara! Correct. But Dulc., how
mostly will be affected?
-From warm to cold?
-No, where in the body?
-Knee joints.
-In the joints, yes. The pains in the joints
will increase. What else?
You will see that also he can affect the
colon the guts and you may have diarrheas.
So exposing especially the feet in cold and
wet and getting diarrheas, the remedy
is not anymore Rhus-t
and it's not Calc, it's not Kali-c.
But if the person says, worse from drafts, very much worse but I'm better from wet weather?
-Hep. and Kali-c and Nux-v, except Caust.
Causticum is better in wet weather. He feels more energy and that his  pains in the joints
are better.
How is it possible, if you have a case in front
of you and you give one hour for the case to investigate that case.
How is it possible to speed up the time,
to arrive to the correct remedy?
You need some technique.
You need first of all to know the keynotes of
the Materia Medica, the first you have to know.
That's why I said, did you go through  the complete course? Because there I gave all
the keynotes.
It's not possible to give all the keynotes in
a seminar like that because it's not the first
year studies.
It is a post-graduated study.
Some of you were waiting to hear this
new case that we are going to hear
and to see whether you can spot the remedy.
And sometimes the remedy is so difficult
to spot that even the whole class,
maybe there is not one person in the
class who can see the remedy, why?
Because there are some degrees of
knowledge of the Materia Medica,
either we want it or not this is a fact.
The Indian books they smell. If you
smell an Indian book there is a smell.
If you enter India there is a particular smell all over. And if you don't like that smell, don't go.
I had a colleague, a gynecologist, he is a Professor now. He says, I went once and we landed in Bombay
in the airport and he said, 'I got out for a while,
I got in again and I don't want to fly over India because it smells so much'.
Yet when I was in India I was so happy, I never was so happy in my life. Indian people are real people.