You see we have to be very careful on one more point that we don't always say everything that we see over there.
We say what is necessary to be told in order to understand a subject matter which we are talking.
We don't have to go into observation which may be correct or it may not be correct.
We may be doing observations on patients
that may not be correct.
So what is necessary for me is to have enough symptoms to make a prescription.
If I take privately a case people get mad at me. Three minutes you are giving the remedy?
I said, this is what I need. I don't need to excavate you and to analyze all your soul.
We do these cases on the video. When I saw her, she came and she cried, I said Ignatia finished, next.
I will not go, what happened with your husband, did he sit next to you, right or left?
These are projections that we do not need. You see the remedy, there is no question, ok you proceed.
I say that especially when you make comments on a case publically. It's not possible that we like each other all of us.
It's not possible. We have priorities and similarities and connections. I mean, you don't say, I like or you don't like a patient.
It's not important but if you make comments
and comments may come from like or dislike.
This person does not fit you, why?
Because you don't understand his position.
You project yourself into his position, how I would act but you think on a different way; therefore he acts wrongly.
This is not a good logic.
Honestly I have never judged anybody that come and tell me terrible stories. I don't remember anything of them.
There is somebody there who seeks my help.
If I can, I would give it. Whether he's good or bad,
he has killed somebody or he was a killer, a mass murderer, all kinds of projections you may have.
He says, symptoms of Sulphur, take Sulphur. He gives me symptoms of Sepia, take Sepia.
So, you have to be careful because I have observed in other classes, not at all in this class,
but in public seminars which I have given
people are criticizing very much somebody who
is giving publically his case. It is very very important to be gentle and say whatever
is necessary to say to bring out your
point but not further than that.
You may be a very astute observer and you may find the weak points of everyone especially if you are Sepia.
With Sepia because the emotional involvement is not strong, you will make correct judgments about others
if you are in a Sepia state. No emotions, you look objectively, then you see the truth. And that's why in Sepia they say,
Sepia is spiteful. That means he finds
easily your weak point and he says it.
Now in Michael's case, is this the case? No. Because Sepia is not his constitutional remedy.
It's the first remedy that has to be given because of the influence in his life. He was a different person.
There is an influence which creates a negative impact upon him. Then he becomes Sepia.
We give Sepia, takes the negative, then underneath will come the next remedy.
So therefore he will not have all the characteristics of Sepia, he will not have.
Because a Phosphorus underlying
that becomes Sepia, he cannot have.
Phosphorus on the other hand is gullible, whatever he sees, he believes. Why? Because he has a lot of emotions.
You talk to him in an emotional way,
he will believe you.
Real Sepia stays cool, observes and knows exactly the weak point. The moment you come into fight,
she will hurt you very deeply. Because she knows what are your weak points. Did we speak about Sepia?
No, but we have been understanding Sepia more and more and you will see it when we speak in the Materia Medica.
-You just said, you don't judge. I have observed that two times during a divorce, twice you asked question for the fault,
whose fault it was? Whose guilt it was?
If somebody is guilty, he has been judged.
If this is not so, why do you ask?
What is the purpose of your question?
-Well, when I will try to show you the mental-emotional make up of a case, this is the objective.
I have to bring out with the least possible disturbance, this mental-emotional structure
of the patient that we are treating;
so you can learn from this experience.
What is the fault of you or you? What is the meaning of such a question?
There is a lot of meanings in a lot of different levels. First of all you want to see whether
the person you have in front of you, you see
it for the first time and you don't know.
Is he telling you objectively things? Is he
telling you stories? With a question like this,
more or less you judge the rest
of the information.
If the person says, my wife is wrong, then your mind should go to remedies that are in this or that way
and then you understand the nature of the remedies. I don't say, this is your fault, no.
I just want to see, can he be objective? Is it possible to be objective? Then I will believe the information he is giving me.
The information is subtle. I am in a conference and I perspire, I don't feel comfortable, I gave up my job because
in the conference I felt I was judged. What is this? What does it mean? How objective this can be?
Do you have to translate this into lack of self-confidence? All this depends on the purity of the information.
You cannot believe how many times the same person will say different things. You ask him this way, he will say one thing,
you ask another way, he will give another information. You don't have to judge and say, you tell me lies,
you just note down that this information
he is giving that he is not objective.
Ah, wait a moment, I have
to be careful with the information.
When my reputation depends on whether he will be well or not and it's not my reputation, it's your inspiration.
Finally you say, if you see the result, you will say, Homeopathy is good. If I make a mistake, if I am superficial,
ok take this remedy and fail, what is your impression not about me, about Homeopathy?
-No, I didn't want to say that. I would have asked, who was the first one who went to find out who actually went away.
Who had the courage to stay in the situation and actually confront themselves with the problems?
-It doesn't matter. I mean, I cannot duplicate your way of taking a case like you cannot duplicate my way of taking a case.
The fact still remains, you are interested about reliable symptoms, on which you can rely.
We said this, I thought is this jealousy, yes or no? He said, I'm jealous but still in my thinking,
he didn't say the way I wanted to hear it.
His wife also said, when I asked is he jealous she said, yes. In this way ehh....
Then I wanted to think, it's not judgment,
it is analyzing so you get the objective truth.
And I came to the possibility that most probably he didn't want social affairs because of jealousy.
Because I have seen it before happening. You know the jealousy is so much, they protect.
No, don't go there I have a headache. The moment they feel you will go to a particular place
where there might be somebody whom you like, the Lachesis will have a headache,
they will even develop fever, will do different things not to go. Not to be there, not to be near.
Then you become unsocial. Is this a case?
It is a matter of analyzing correctly.
- During the case taking I have a problem. When you take a case, it's not only the information
that the patient gives to you but you, yourself
are observing. You are part of the thing.
For instance, let's take the Aurum case. When we took the case most of us lived that and I lived that as well,
that we have actually to battle struggle
with our own emotions that came up.
Is it advisable not to take a
case like that or what can one do?
-When you have a case, the case it is whatever you see in front of you. You cannot manipulate the case
to change the way she is giving the case. This is the way this person decides to give her case.
So you take this information and you evaluate the information. You cannot say, it's good to take the case
in this way that means not to allow the person to cry or to promote crying, no.  I don't do anything of that type.
I let anybody to develop the symptomatology and the expression that he prefers to give.
I don't say, don't cry or don't do
that, let your emotions out.
-The question was I have my own personality and I take it in the case and the reaction of the patient
is always the reaction of my inner feeling. To observe myself to be quite objective is nearly impossible.
-Well, maybe it's difficult but not impossible. I have said that we must be very objective and sit back
and detach from the patients emotions, as much as possible. Then we make a correct judgment.
If we are involved ourselves in the emotions, then most probably the judgments will go wrong.
Because this time you will feel pity, the other time you will sadness, next time you feel joy,
I like her, then you have sexual feelings
and things like that. She likes me, forget it.
Forget judgment, you have to be objective. Your patient is your patient.
I had a case in Athens where I have medical doctors working there. Some of them are the type of the doctor
who always receive very well the patient
and also console them.
Sit down, what's your problem? People like it. The patient likes it.
Most of his cases were going wrong but still his patients were coming back to him in spite of not getting better.
A few cases like this, they behave with such love and the patient feels the doctor likes me.
The doctor has learned to show his
feelings. Forget the judgment.
Finally the case would come to me because it's not doing well, 1,2,6 months, sometimes 1 year.
Nothing has happened, the case comes to me. Whose cases come to me after a year of not feeling better?
It was his cases. Who is full of patients? It's him. Why? Because he involves his symptoms.
If you involve your sympathy to the patient, you will have clients but you will not be successful prescriber.
-I want to say to this jealousy. Now I understood why we didn't see it so clearly. Because Lachesis has big suppressions
and he even suppressed the biggest Lachesis symptom. So we got a double Lachesis but he wasn't conscious about it.
He told us what he could and then we have to discover that he was so Lachesis that he suppressed
the biggest Lachesis. Now I understand why often I don't see symptoms because I used to say,
Lachesis you must see jealousy.
-But when I asked him, he said yes. He answered straight. But there is yes and yeeess!
It's different. Yeeess, I realize I am
jealous. Or oh my god I'm very jealous.
But when I asked, are you jealous? He said, yes. He let some doubt in my mind and then his wife
came who let more doubt. I said, what's going on. Then let me think. Something is not right.
In my mind I want to be in peace with my mind when I prescribe. I prescribe for this and that reason and these are quite strong.
I said, let' s forget it. Then I thought about it and
I said, tell me more about this element. He said, yes it is true
I don't want to socialize because I was jealous. To admit that it is an absolute seal for Lachesis.
You are too involved with the case. I like, don't like should not come to the picture.
-May I come back about the story of taking a case? You explain that you have to be very observant
but at the same time you have to be detached.
A person who comes as a patient and gives you sometimes
such a personal information who sometimes never give to anybody else, including his own family,
has a certain communication with the practitioner, otherwise it's not going to open up.
-Ok, I'll tell you the secret. There is a secret in that. I say, detached. I don't say disinterested,
be very interested, what you
are going to hear is very important.
But don't get involved emotionally.
So I'm interested very much to hear,
I'm very attentive for you. When you look
at me you will say, he's interested in me but
I don't get involved with your emotions
unless it is very, very strong case.
Like her case, it was difficult not to get
involved. I got involved in her emotions
and I have admitted it.
Very seldom this happens to me and very little, not much. You cry and I cry, we embrace each other and we cry together.
It's a healing crisis, I don't know maybe some crazy psychologists may do that.
I had a case actually, I prescribed Medorrhinum. He was 15 years with psychologists. So 15 years
all these crazy things she has been told.
Do this, do that. Now he said, the last month
I feel better
and you know what? I telephoned my psychologist who said to me that I must change the exercise
I was doing before. I said, what was the exercise? The exercise was that I had to wake up
and don't jump out of bed, wake up slowly, turn to the right, then get out of bed, go to the sun and touch
the ground and then I'm grounded, the patient is grounded and then he can go to work.
That' s ok, 15 years now this person is with anxiety and starting symptoms of M.S., paralytic symptoms.
He telephoned and said, Dr.Vithoulkas gave
me a remedy and the psychologist said, very good, take the remedy.
But what exercise you do? No, no, no.
You wake up slowly, you turn to the left,
then to the right
and then you get up. He says, is so important? Absolutely important. The patient says, the psychologist said
that finally he got the right exercise for me.
And that's why I'm feeling better. I said to him, very nice.
Next time you have a relapse turn to your left, turn to your right and come to tell me what is happening.
He said, 'I was so angry with him because I told him 15 years you have not showed me the correct exercise'.
Most probably he did this to exploit me.
I don't think so, I said.
He goes back and he said, 'why now you
gave me the correct exercise?'. He said,
'now I perceived it'.
I said, out of 15 years of psychotherapy it is suddenly and accidentally this month that I prescribed
Medorrhinum 10M, that you are feeling so well, that the right exercise of the psychologist was given.
We have to deal with these issues as well.
I took the case, it took me 1,5h take the remedy and left.
Now he wanted contact, the psychologist says this. Now the psychologist produced the cure.
Why? Because the psychologist is interested.
I'm not interested. I've done my job.
I've done what I think it's right for him and
I leave him, be free. Do whatever you like,
it's not my job after that.
Do you want patients? Turn to the right, turn to the left. When I heard that I said, 'oh my God'.
We have to deal with all these nonsense.
Now he's trying to get in contact with me,
it's not possible.
Wait, let us see what happens
with the left and right.
I had another case,
he never came to one lecture.
You know the Greek doctors have learned Homeopathy, just by listening. Many of
them they did not know English.
They became quite good. He, never came
to a lecture. The lecture starts at  20:00 and ends at 23:00.
About 22:50, he appears. He sits there 10 minutes, then we leave. This doctor had a lot of clients but still
after 25 years he had somebody else prescribing for his cases. But still he had a lot of patients because
he is very nice to the patient though very mediocre success.