-That moment he comes and he has certain problems. Are you really interested to hear all
the details about the life of the person?
He's going to relate to you. Events of his life from childhood. I lived in a place where we do not have trains and we had a lot of chicken around.
I exaggerate a little bit but this is the situation, are you going to write down?
How do you come to the point where he or she wants to say something important but he does not say it? Why he does not say it?
Because he has no contact with you. He feels here I am, here he is and no contact. Shall
I expose myself? Can you undress in front of somebody who is a total stranger?
Very few people will do it and if you do
it you get Hyoscyamus. It's exhibition.
But the interview is a very intimate affair,
you are going to undress the person,
you're going to make him undress;
so he has to feel familiar with you.
Otherwise you will not get anything. Many of you, not all have you ever tried having an affair for one night? You just meet somebody for one night, you go to bed and you have sex.
You are undressed, you have a very close, intimate relationship. What is coming out when you finish this act, you feel much more alient, strange than before even. What have I done?
Have you given anything from yourself? Nothing. It was all a superficial kind of contact and affair. The same with Homeopathy.
What do you have pain in the stomach, then what else? nothing else. It can be a superficial affair and it can be a deeper affair.
You're interested to know is this person who
is in front of you, has really other problems
that maybe pointing to the right remedy?
Which are even more important than the
pain in the stomach? He may not have
but you have to find out by hook.
The greatest trick is, you want information?
You want communication? You better be
open yourself and be ready to hear and be
ready not to judge what you are going to hear.
Because the other person always perceives whether you are judging him or her. He
perceives it immediately and closes up and he will give you only superficial symptomatology.
Where what you need is a real contact to find out, without losing your mind in the stories he is telling you. Always have your mind composed and fixed on the idea what is he suffering from, what is he suffering from?
What really makes him so sick?
and then pick up the information. There
is a time when the information comes.
That is important and that is peculiar.
That's clear and that's the remedy
we have been talking. So you keep open.
You will see the cases I'm going to show you. These cases were recorded with all this equipment you see there, with all these people plus the interpretors plus the assistants.
Sometimes they were recorded in front of the class. Is it easy to undress a person in front of
all these? It's very easy to undress a person when you talk, one to one.
That's why you will see they are not the perfect cases but definitely I will show you that the remedy is appearing. So actually what you need is a kind of information which is enough.
You say, I have enough information I don't need to intrude into the life of the person actually. Once I have the information which
I need, I stop. Then I talk friendly, what
is your business, what are you doing?
You can talk anything you like once you have the real information. You don't have to go in and dig and dig and dig. We are not psychologists. And to tell you the truth I don't believe that
psychoanalysis, I mean making a person talk, talk, talk, will have a real effect. I have seen many many cases which they have been
talking for years to somebody.
The last case I saw I didn't not realize when
I first prescribed the remedy, she said for 15 years. For 15 years you have been going to
a psychologist? She said, yes. How frequently? Twice the week. And why you stop now?
Oh, I had enough. But she had enough after
the remedy, after I prescribed the remedy she stopped going to the psychologist, of course.
Maybe she does not realize why she is not
going anymore to the psychologist but I know that the organism is now more composed,
more whole, she is grounded more. She does
not need that support anymore.
Baryta carbonica for instance. Bar-c goes into the mental level and we have the picture of Bar-c the person who needs somebody to hold on.
She will not let the psychologist go, the psychoanalyst go, they will stick they
will be very dependent upon the psychologist. And you will see long years of psychotherapy
in Bar-c.
It's the same thing when you see the child holds into the mother for many years. Not when he is 1,2,3..5,6...15 holding, now go to school. It's a big thing for Baryta Carbonica, can not let go. The same with the psychologist.
I know what I'm talking is a bit difficult and perhaps I'm tiring you but we'll start with cases and you will see.
But I feel what I tell you is so important. I feel where the whole movement has gone wrong at this moment. Too much intellectualizing.
Much intellect and very little heart. You need more the combination, you need really to see things with your heart.
When the woman sits there, you ask the husband, do you like chocolate? And the woman says, I like chocolate.
If your heart hears it, then it becomes very
strong symptom. Do you have fear of death?
Ah, I have fear of death.
An intellectual person will say, when your turn comes and when I ask you, then you will tell me.
This is not evaluation. Evaluation is when you stick in your mind that she has that symptom. When she comes to me after a year or two
I will remember what she told me because it's very important what she told me. There are cases that I have seen once
and after 10 years I see the case and I don't remember the face. But if I remember the face,
I will say yes, you were Ignatia case
and I will remember the symptoms that he had. You see, the impression that his symptoms have made, I have seen thousands and thousands of cases, how is it possible that I will remember?
Because I did not close my heart though I looked very composed, very aloof when I took the case.
You will see me when I take a case, I'm thinking because I have responsibility.
The person is here not to communicate
with me and have a nice time, he needs the correct remedy. I never forget that but I'm open and search with my intellect and open with my heart as well.
You can't say, yes you go to the church 5 times the week. When I hear that I say, what did he say? 5 times the week to the church? Why?
Why so frequently?
Well, I feel consoled. The religious element and how much of that element is pathology?
Otherwise I hear 5 times the week she goes to the church, there is no symptom. 7 times to the church, 5 times, maybe that is the remedy.
We don't have such a thing.
We have religious affections yes. We have the mentality sometimes turns towards a religious kind of disturbance.
5 times to the church, maybe...
Maybe not always because if he is a monk
or if he is a person who meditates and
things like that you don't see disturbance.
But you see disturbance when he goes 5 times to the church spending 3 hours. Then what are you doing? Then I go around and I have a sandwich. Then I go to my garden
and then what are you doing?
Then you go through the list of what he or she
is doing and is doing nothing. How old are you? I'm 36. It is not healthy. Somebody who does
not do anything, who can not keep a job
who goes to the church and spends all
these hours, there is a problem.
Let's concentrate on that; never mind that he said 'my scalp is greasy'. I had a case, maybe
you heard it from Vassilis where he had a case. He said his scalp is greasy. By that time I was prescribing for the cases.
They would give me the case and few other symptoms and I was prescribing. Thuja.
Next time he says, I feel that somebody is
behind me and the police department is after
me and I'm hiding here and there.
I said, what is this?
It's a mental case. You don't realize at all that you believe that his scalp is greasy and he has come to give him a remedy for that.
What case is this? Another case he says, very nice just 3 minutes more. I tell the story because it makes it more alive just to show you the problems in case taking and evaluating the symptoms.
Another case from a woman doctor from the center. I read the case and he has headache on the right side and then everything else which is written, no symptoms he looks so nice, he's so kind, praising the patient.
I looked at the age, 25. I looked at the height, very high, good looking and the doctor is a woman. And there is a headache on the right side and he is not working, 25 years old.
I sent back the case and I said, you better take the case properly. You were flirting with the patient, not taking the case.
The patient was saying, how nice you are.
She is very good looking. And the doctor
was saying, how nice you are.
I said 'be careful this is a mental case underlined. Call the patient back'. When she took him back she said, 'yes it's a mental case!'.
Of course it's a mental case. But you
got too much involved, too much heart
and very little brains now.