I want to say a few things which I have not said before to such groups they are coming here, in the Academy.
Because the main object of coming here is to observe the application of Homeopathy.
So many people, many times they have come before, they expressed a wonder of what kind of Homeopathy
or case taking is going on here?
I have a special way of taking a case
and I never explained really why I do this.
So today I want to explain to you what you are going to observe in the taking of the case.
But before I say this, I want to say that if a medical doctor is going to see a case
when he receives a telephone call, somebody is with very high fever and chills.
He is not a homeopath.
He goes to see the case.
What is he going to examine?
What is he going to ask?
Immediately he wants to know what's going on.
Is this a pneumonia case? Is this a urinary infection? Is this a more severe condition?
So he will start examining, from this point of view, the patient in order to differentiate what kind of a fever is this.
How he does this? By using a knowledge which he has received in his medical studies.
And during his internship and then later on in his speciality.
So he will examine the patient with this knowledge in the background.
Take another example. A patient comes with some psychological problems to a psychiatrist
who is following the Adler approach, inferiority complex, the social contact behavior of the patient etc.
to see whether the problem comes because of the inferiority complex etc. or because of social deficiencies.
What is he doing? He's examining the patient according to what knowledge he has received in his speciality.
Is he interested whether the patient is thirsty or not? Is he interested whether the patient feels more cold or more heat?
His questioning will be to understand whether he can put the patient into a context which he knows before
and so he can prescribe the necessary medication.
If he is a Freudian psychiatrist who follows the Freud idea, sexual behavior behind all that etc.
he will put questions according to what he knows to understand whether the boy, the girl have traumatic
experiences in their childhood with their sexual behavior, with complexes related to sexual
sphere.
If he is Jungian, he will try to find out about the subconscious, how much importance there is in this psychotic patient
the collective subconscious etc., the dreams.
You go to another speciality. You see somebody broke his elbow, he goes to orthopaedist.
He is not interested whether you have psychological problems or other problems.
He takes an X-ray, he sees it's broken there, he makes a sketch how I put a plastic new hand etc.
So everyone of these people have become good or not or very good according to the knowledge
they have attained and how they
apply it in each particular case.
And they do their job quite good,
very good, excellent etc.
Now what about the homeopaths?
You, most probably learn like I use to
teach also, you must take a full case.
You let the patient talk and let the
patient give you all the story.
Don't interfere, don't ask questions
or ask the minimum questions.
And eventually the case will manifest
in front of your eyes.
One time I did an experiment when I had new comers, starting Homeopathy; they did not know.
I said, how many of you are medical doctors? Quite a lot, 40% medical doctors, the others chiropracts etc.
I said, ok we do an experiment. You take the case of each other and then you give it to me
and from the case you give me
I will decide the remedy for each one.
You know what happened?
When I had the feedback each one was writing according to his knowledge and not according to homeopathic case.
As a result it was impossible to
find any of these remedies.
The medical doctors have written the medical history. At the age of 6 he had a pneumonia, at the age of 17
he had an infection, he got antibiotics.At the age of this, he got this etc. And this was a homeopathic case.
Totally useless.
So what was missing from these cases?
Many of them were medical doctors, they have been trained to take a case, a proper case,
they wrote in detail what has happened. The medical history of this case. What was missing?
It was missing what we call a homeopathic case.
Now I had another example. You know in Athens I used to have a center with medical doctors,
about 30 medical doctors working there.
They used to take the case and I used to prescribe, he gave me the case, prescribe.
There was one case, a woman doctor who
was programming her cases for 3 hours.
10 o'clock first case, 1 o'clock second case
and she always gave me about 30 pages of information.
I was never able to see the remedy.
Whose problem was? The problem of the teacher who had not explained properly how a proper case is taken.
So while you are here you have to learn how
to take a proper case, as fast as possible.
Because in practice a medical doctor needs certain time. He cannot be paid for 3 hours of taking a case.
Nobody will pay him for doing that. But if you don't know the way how to take properly a case
you will be lost in a lot of useless details.
So how we manage to get away from such a practice? This is what I want to explain to you now.
And what you are going to see me doing,
so you may understand what is going on when
I take a case.
Because here, as I said, you are going to
see many cases. We shall be talking about
differential diagnosis, we shall be talking about other things as well, some theoretical matters
but mostly see cases and how the case is
taken and how the analysis is for this case.
This is what you are going to see.
But you will wonder, especially those who come for the first time, why George interferes so much with the taking of the case.
Why do I interfere and what is happening in a proper case, you want to be a professional
and you want to take a case and have a result?
As I said, all the other specialities examine the case according to the knowledge they have received in the University.
The question now is, what is the necessary knowledge in order to differentiate a case?
Whether it is Pulsatilla or Phosphorus or Argentum nitricum?
What is the necessary knowledge that you must have before you can take a case properly?
You see the moment that you have a case in front of you and the person starts talking,
already by the first information that you are getting your mind goes to certain remedies.
Now, who is in the best position to find the remedy? The answer is very easy.
The person who has the highest
knowledge of Materia Medica.
With this knowledge of Materia Medica
in our heads, we approach the case.
The more we are experts in knowledge of the Materia Medica, the more we are able to think
of several possibilities, immediately
with the first questions.
The approach that you will be observing here is an approach which comes from the knowledge of Materia Medica.
As you know I have the Expert System, sitting next to me, putting symptoms in the Expert System, the VES.
I don't look always in the Expert System, many times I write the remedy in the beginning of the case.
But the investigation continues, I continue the investigation for 1 hour which I'm allowed to take the case.
Sometimes I change the prescription but
many times I don't change the prescription.
That means from very early in the case, you
may be able to have an idea about the remedy,
if you have a good knowledge of Materia Medica.
Of course, the VES will help you, will give you some ideas, of course the Repertorisation is necessary.
Of course we have tools to help us decide for the remedy; but if you have not studied Materia Medica in depth
it will be very difficult for you to come to a conclusion.
You will always feel lost.
Especially if you have difficult cases.
If you have studied well 10 cases, most of
your prescriptions will be within 10 remedies.
I can guarantee. As I said, I had students
there who were taking cases.
One of them gave 60% of the cases,
Natrum Muriaticum.
And he claimed he had some results.
Of course you will have some results. Why?
Because Homeopathy can treat the whole person or can treat some symptoms of the person.
We have the possibility to change the symptom, one symptom, two symptoms. We have the possibility to do it.
No problem but the real central remedy which will change the level of health of the individual, will not be seen.
And what happens? We start confusing the case and from one remedy to another remedy to another remedy
some people they even give 3 remedies,
the same day, 4, 5 remedies the same day.
Take 10 remedies every day and in the
end you say, my headaches are better.
Yes, your headaches are better but the general state of health has remained the same.
There is no real improvement.
And the real improvement, as you know, starts when you have the laws of cure applied in this person.
We have some laws, most of
you know these laws.
You have to have the movement of symptomatology towards the physical body,
if it is
a mental-emotional problem they have to be moving into the physical body the symptoms or when the symptoms
are in the physical body they have to move outside on the periphery, in the skin and in the mucus membranes.
In order for us to say, we have succeeded in a case, we have to see this movement of symptomatology.
The symptomatology has to move from
deeper levels to more peripheral levels.
From mental-emotional levels, to physical levels.
So what you are going to see is an examination with the background of knowledge, which is my background of knowledge.
Many times you will not understand why I ask
a question. Many times my students know why George
is asking now these questions.
He is thinking of Medorrhinum,
he is thinking of Argentum nitricum most probably.
And then the people who are knowledgeable they can follow very well almost all my questions.
Sometimes if the case is really a small remedy, maybe it's difficult, you may not follow it.
But I will explain when I come into the class, I will explain why I have decided on this remedy and not on other remedies.
So it is very important if you want to become professional homeopaths, to learn the Materia Medica properly.
Now this is the big question. What is to
know the Materia Medica properly?
We have 12 volumes of Allen's M.M., 12 volumes of Hering's M.M.. You can say what the hell you're talking?
Are we going to learn 12 volumes
by heart? It's not possible.
I remember when I had started bringing
out these ideas of essential features etc.
I remember criticism and groups
that they were formed against this idea.
One of the group was the Dulcamara group
or something like that, the Sepia group.
There was a leader and about 10 people,
the Sepia group. I said, what did you do?
One of my students has been there
to report to me what they were doing.
He said, we went to a kind of pension to stay together, all of us and from the morning till the night, for 3 days
we studied Sepia. How you studied Sepia? Each one took a different Materia Medica and he was bringing
into the group the information from
the different Materia Medicas.
For 3 days, they were studying Sepia and
I said to him, ok what was the conclusion?
What are these symptoms that they
brought out as main symptoms?
You see the answer was that there was no conclusion. They were just symptoms, symptoms,
symptoms each one had noted
down thousands of symptoms.
And what is the Sepia case? If you go to really understand, to really find out whether the case is Sepia or not, you are lost.
What are the main points which you have
to have in mind and to remember for Sepia?
If you don't have this, how the hell are you studying Sepia with 3.500 symptoms?
Only Sepia. Sulphur has 5.000. It'a total loss.
And now the problem is who is going to
tell you what are the main symptoms?
If somebody who is not knowledgeable, he tries to teach Materia Medica, as many times it has happened,
what he is going to tell you?
He is going to read the Materia Medica just before the lecture and bring out all the symptoms of Sepia
and you are confused as much as he is.
The only person who can really teach
you, is a person who has experience.
Not only who has experience but whose experience has been proven to be effective.
That means you have effect; so you have to get this knowledge from a teacher who knows what he is talking about.
Otherwise you will be confused. One teacher says this, the other says that and then it starts the whole fantasy.
I will give you a lecture about fantasy
because it is a very interesting subject.
You can fantasize anything. You feel this field of Homeopathy, because it concerns human beings who are not static
and are alive entities, you can apply any
possible theory or idea upon them.
The problem is all these fantasies, whether you teach in a class, when you go to your practice
can you put them into practice
and can they have an effect?
This is the problem. So it depends who
you listen to as a teacher in order to say,
yes I understand now Homeopathy.
The problem of Homeopathy is that we don't have a University. We don't have standardized information.
Anybody can become a teacher, anybody can say whatever he likes and anybody can listen to everybody and say,
oh well George why don't we let things just
fly like this?Something will happen one day.
No, nothing will happen one day. It will be more confusion and more confusion and more confusion
and finally people will be disappointed
and give up Homeopathy.
This is what is going to happen, nothing else.
I think that you must be tolerant when you listen to taking of a case and to be observant only.
Try to understand what I'm
doing when I'm taking a case.
Otherwise if you have your own ideas applied during the taking of the case, you will miss completely the point.
In such groups I had an American guy who after the analysis of the case would go around and say, George is wrong,
the remedy is this. When the patient comes back and gives the results, then he shuts up of course.
He doesn't say anything but by the time you take the case, he says George is wrong. I know the remedy.
Who was in my lectures in Celle in Germany? Do you remember a French guy, medical doctor?
There were 3 people from France.
One of them was a medical doctor who said that he could find the remedy through an antenna.
From a car. He had taken the antenna, the radio antenna from his car, pulls the antenna and
I prescribe a remedy and then
some people come and say,
you know the French guy is telling everybody that George is wrong, the remedy is wrong.
You see, I can find the
remedy with the antenna.
I said, it's very interesting and what was
the remedy he gave for this case?
He says, Veratrum Album and what he gave to the other guy? The remedy is Veratrum Album.
About 80% of the cases were Veratrum Album.
I said, very interesting. I want
to see how you find the remedy.
So we prepare all the scenery, we put all the remedies on a table, he pulls the antenna
to find the remedy, he goes like this.
And then he goes over the remedies,
this is your remedy. I look, Veratrum Album.
I said, now I have a very difficult case.
Can you help me with this case?
Veratrum album. I said, thank you very much.
I thought the guy is not balanced. Next year I think I was going every 6 months in Celle, if I remember well,
every 6 months I was returning. The next 6 months I see the two women doctors and not the other medical doctor.
I said, what happened? Why he did not come, the Veratrum? She says, he is in a mental asylum.
They closed him down. I said, poor guy, we were trying to help him with Homeopathy. It was not possible and they locked him.
All these are really sad events which are happening in homeopathic community.
And you have to be very aware and very pragmatic, you see you are interested to practice Homeopathy,
you are interested to have results.
You'd better don't fly in the skies.
We have a science which is proving a remedy, get information from the provings, apply it to the person,
see the results what you have done after
the application, make your observations etc.
All the other theories, you see when I hear
some other teacher from Holland saying,
actually we don't have to prove
the remedies. What you have to do?
It's just to meditate and through imagination, understand what possible symptomatology can be created by this remedy.
I said, are you in your mind when you say that?
No George you are narrow minded, you are old, you are this, you are that.
But don't you understand that if you say that
to a class, I give you a remedy and I say,
imagine the possible symptomatology of this remedy.
There are 130 people in the class, it will be 130 provings. Each one will have his own imagination.
And he will give his own version of the
remedy, don't you understand that?
No, you are narrow minded,
you don't understand.
And all kinds of nonsense which have caused the English press to attack very viciously and I had to write an article.
Some of you, do you know
this article on Homeopathy?
Who has read the article? Only few. I think it is good you read this article because you may discover
you don't know things which are going on in Homeopathy which are real nonsense.
Is anybody wants to ask some question?
Concerning the taking of the case?
Who has listened to this idea that you must allow the patient
to speak and to say the whole story?
Who has listened to this idea originally?
-It's in the Organon.
-It's in the Organon, very good.
The Organon was written in a time when we did not have so many psychotic patients as we have today.
Not only that, I will tell you. I remember a case.
I was taking a case and at a certain moment,
she had a problem with her mother.
And she started crying and saying
all these conditions etc. For half an hour
I let her talk, bring out all the grief etc.
So I said, that's enough. You answer my questions now. 1,2,3,4 questions.
I finish the case, I enter the class. There are two women, one she gets up, she says, George I'm really angry
because I know you are patient, you are treating the patients very nicely and in this woman you have been
very hard and harsh. Why you did that?
And then somebody else comes and says, I accuse you for that. I say, ok hands up.
But if I let this patient talk for 3 hours, I will never in the end be able to find the remedy for this patient.
And the patient will not be cured. It was very interesting that she, herself, that was very much offended
by the way I took the case. After 6 months that she was back, she said I am much better.
Because I have found the remedy, of course.
It doesn't matter because usually they tell us,
you treat your patient so nicely and you pat them in the back and they have the placebo effect.
Well, many times I have treated patients very abruptly because I'm anxious to get the real information,
what is behind of what they tell me. I understand you have a problem with your mother, I understand.
She has offended you, she has put you down etc. I understand all that, I don't need any more details.
You had problems with your mother and I understand that, I don't need more information.
And I went into the house of my mother and my mother was lying in a sofa and her feet were out of the blankets
and I tried to cover the feet with
the blankets and bla, bla, bla.
And I said, no. The whole class will go out because you can't stand it, I mean I can stand quite a lot.
The students can stand so far. You cannot ask them to wait to listen to all this kind of details
which are irrelevant of the real case.
Do you have any questions? You don't have questions. You are afraid of asking questions.
In the beginning everybody is afraid, is calculating if he is going to give me a bad time.
No. You can ask any question. You can say, dear sir in the Organon Hahnemann says let the patient talk etc. etc.
Yes, the patient by that time of Hahnemann would say, I have a pain in my elbow and my left knee is also painful
and Hahnemann would write Agaricus.
Because of what? The diagonal picture.
But if somebody comes today and relates to
you a case of Agaricus will be totally different.
I tell you, if you don't know the mental picture
of Agaricus and the total anxiety and fear he creates about death
and dying, especially with cancer.
Cancer is the word they cannot pronounce.
Usually Agaricus case will say for
cancer, 'you know they died from that.
He died from this'. 'What is this?'
'You know'. 'No, I don't know'.
You cannot make them
pronounce the word cancer.
The pronouncing of the word cancer is impossible for such a case, Agaricus.
So little details like that. When you push somebody to tell you the word of cancer,
it points out to the core, to the inside
information from the patient.
You may ask a direct question,
whether he is afraid of cancer.
You will get an answer like mm....
you will not get a straight forward answer.
But you have to have the picture in your mind of how Agaricus is reacting to the idea of cancer.
To understand the tremendous fear which is going on in the person and the anxiety.
Unless you know that kind of picture, let the patient of Agaricus talk to you now.
He will talk and talk, talk, talk . Another thing I've observed with Agaricus is that they think that
all people around them are dying from cancer.
Why? Because you hear somebody has died from cancer and the other day you forgot.
It seems that the idea that this person has died from cancer, you say it's your relative? No.
It's your friend? No. Who is? But I have a friend whose friend was 42 and died from cancer.
And it has stayed in the mind so powerful
that overwhelms the individual.
So that is the anxiety of Agaricus, that kind.
When you see that kind, you see the details how it is expressed this anxiety, then you have to know,
somebody must have told you. He must have described to you the anxiety of Agaricus to be able
immediately to say, I don't want anymore, now
I can ask you some practical questions.
- The cases we see you take here are very
often people who know about Homeopathy
and they've seen homeopaths before.
They know what to expect.
We see or I see many people in England who have wrong ideas about Homeopathy,
they are not sure. What would you say to these people at the first appointment, about Homeopathy
and the process of treatment to ensure
that they stay with Homeopathy.
-That is a good question.
The answer is, I don't know.
Why I say that? Because first of all
these are English people, not Greeks.
With Greeks you don't have to explain. He
comes to be treated by you, he sits down there.
He has come because he has listened to 10 other people who go to George, I have been cured, I have been cured.
They sit there, they are trembling.
Whatever I want to ask, I will ask.
English people are much more investigative, much more complicated in their mind they have
a mind which is
much more complicated and they can think
3 different aspects at the same time.
Such people you have to deal according to your race. You see I cannot give you advice for a person
who comes with a lot of doubts in Homeopathy.
If you say, I will cure you, it is absolutely wrong.
If you say, well I don't know, it is absolutely wrong. This is what I know.
If you will say, that 'first of all I would like to hear what you have and in the end I can tell you
whether I can help you or not' the person
will settle down and will give the story.
Further you can say, 'I'm going to ask some strange questions but we need these questions
in order to find out what is your remedy.  For instance I will ask you whether you like eggs.
It may appear for you that it's irrelevant but for us it's very important because a desire for eggs means that
your organism does not absorb calcium and egg having a lot of calcium, the organism needs this egg.
So the absorption of calcium is very important for your organism and that's why you have osteoporosis'.
If the age allows you to make the prediction also. So he says, 'oh, this doctor knows everything'.
But this kind of approach I think for the English people. For Greeks you don't need to do anything.
But for English people you explain to them that if I ask you if you take your feet our of covers, for instance?
Oh yes my feet I take out of cover.
Number 1 symptom you put it down.
But you explain to them that it has been researched and found out that the temperature
regulator of the body is the big toe. The big
toe regulates the temperature of the body.
If the temperature of the body rises beyond
a certain limit, then people have to
stick out their feet to cool down the
temperature of the body.
So you bring some examples of this type but never promise to anybody that 'I will cure you'.
That is rule number 1.
Never promise 'I will cure you'.
Of course sometimes you find a case in which the anxiety is totally overwhelming and at a certain time
the patient calls you on the telephone, in a panic. 'I'm dying, I'm having this, that and I'm dying'.
At this moment you have to be quite strong and say, don't worry I'll give you a remedy and you will be fine etc.
But they're trembling during the panic attack, nothing can peace down such a patient.
If you say with steady voice, don't worry
I'll give you a remedy and it will help you.
At this moment you are allowed to do it.
But only at this moment.
Because these persons are usually lead to the emergency room and they will put some injections
with valium or things like that and sedate the patient. You see, you don't want that, you want
to continue.
Some times during a treatment you had given wrong remedies, 1, 2 remedies wrong and then suddenly
you see the full picture of an anxiety remedy. Like Arsenicum, like Phosphorus, like Agaricus, like Nitric Acid etc.
Then you prescribe the remedy and the person really after that time starts to be better.
And he comes after 3 years, because people with such deep disturbances where mentally
have been affected so deeply, it takes years before you manage to bring them around,
to make them feel ok now I can stand on my feet. I was flying in the air, I was in a different world.
But finally when they say, I'm centred again,
they use such words, I'm on my foot.
When you hear these expressions and you ask them, do you remember how you were? Yes.
How are you now? Yes I remember. This means that your treatment was really successful.
I don't know, I answered your point? Not really.
-Yes but I have to tell them a little bit more about the process of treatment and I wonder how much
you would tell them at the start?
-At the start I would not talk about high potency, energy remedies, nothing about these matters
which are not clear and known. You have to bring examples of known facts. It is known that soft boiled eggs
contain a lot of calcium that absorbs easily.
I know that the feet are the regulator of the temperature of the body.
These are written facts and I'm using these in order to understand how your organism is working.
And if I can find your remedy, maybe
you will feel better. It's very good.
You don't take the authority, I'm the doctor and you are the patient and I know everything.
-What do you say to them about
possible aggravation?
That is another very good question.
You're asking very good questions.
You see, in my experience when I had an aggravation from a remedy and the person
calls me on the telephone and gives me immediately I understand this is not something else,
it is an aggravation from the remedy, my first word is excellent.
Very good. Very good? Yes it's very good, excellent.
We're expecting this aggravation,
in a few days you will feel fine.
Immediately the anxiety, the fear goes down and they wait for a few days. And when comes the period
of amelioration they come back and say 'you saved my life'. You have all that experience.
But if you have given 2,3 wrong remedies in 3 months and the 4th month he telephones in a panic attack
and you think that the panic attack is an aggravation from the remedy and you tell him very good
for the panic attack keep your panic attack, you will search the patient and you will find him in the emergency room.
That's for sure, they cannot tolerate. At this moment they need, in order the organism to tolerate the impact,
the tremendous impact of the fear
they need reassurance.
You say, don't worry I'll give
you a remedy, your panic will go.
-I'm from South Africa, if you don't understand
my accent I'll speak slowly.
-Yes if you speak slowly and clearly
everybody will understand.
-Some homeopaths that I have spoken to, say that if you give a person the wrong remedy it will do nothing.
And they give them wrong remedy after wrong remedy and they say, it's fine, when you get
the right one you fix them up.
Can you comment on that?
-Well I'll tell you something. From this
point of view which is in a way correct,
many times you give remedies they have no effect. On the other hand, come the people
who suppose to do the provings and with one dose of 30 they have created 1000 symptoms.
So there are two extremes which are not correct. The truth is in the middle.
Sometimes the wrong remedy will have a partial effect. Sometimes the wrong remedy will give you
a proving or 1-2 proving symptoms.
Most of the times the wrong remedy will
have no effect. But sometimes is this or that.
But neither is going to create a host of symptoms like Jeremy ...or a host of imaginary.
Don't forget always you have to take into consideration the human factor of self suggestion.
You have to be very critical about that point. Because the moment you have given a remedy
and the patient comes and says: 'I have a
lot of symptoms because of your remedy'.
Usually a mental case will attribute all her symptoms into the remedy you gave.
And you have to know that this is a self suggestion; it is not because of the remedy.
Because if you write down all the remedies that the patient is relating to you because of the remedy, then you are lost.
But neither you can say, ok take another
remedy, another remedy, 100 remedies.
I had a few cases here that they have taken more than 100 remedies from the Materia Medica.
When they come here; still I manage in
a way to find a way out. Very difficult.
Because the case is really confused.
It is not so simple. You know, it's not
going to do anything.
No, it can change the symptomatology
and confuse the case.
-I need to get a clarification. When I listen to mental symptoms normally the patients
are not comfortable during the first visit.
-Especially if they are Indians.
-Indians. I come from South India
and they are very unsure, why we are asking a mental question. So maybe it's during the 2nd or the 3rd visit
that they open up on the mental features. So what is the approach that we have to take in such a case?
We might have prescribed after the first visit not knowing that there is more to come? What is the best thing to do at this point?
-It is true when I was in India I had faced this problem. Because you are examining a woman and you are asking,
are you good in sex? She will leave
immediately. What are you talking about?
Unbelievable for an Indian woman
to answer such questions.
The good thing is that Indians on the whole are much more healthy than the Europeans or the Americans.
And therefore very few really
have mental symptomatology.
So mostly the symptomatology is physical and therefore you can base your prescription
on physical symptomatology.
But if by chance, there is anybody who might have panic attacks, he will tell you.
But don't ask them about sex. About menses?To that point you can go, are you regular? Regular, regular.
What do you mean by regular? Normal, normal.
But if you want to confirm whether a patient is Platina or Sepia, forget it. It's normal, normal.
I always defend India, as you know. India is
an amazing race which has kept ethics
in their emotional contacts so strongly that it is to their advantage today that their marriages are staying.
Very few divorces, I don't know the last years. By the time of 60's when I was in India, divorce was unthinkable. Why?
Because the man and the girl come for the
first time in sexual contact after marriage.
That is the ideal for keeping a marriage. If one of the two has a lot of experiences, usually the men have a lot of experiences,
the woman may suffer that the man will look around.
But if they come together, even the parents arrange marriage, the marriage will stay and they will enjoy sex.
You think, ah they are enjoying?
They are enjoying really.
Where you ask the European or the American people that have started having sex at 12, 13, 14,
what the hell can they feel at this age?
They can feel nothing.
They don't wait to become a woman and then you marry and you enjoy it the rest of your life.
You enjoy 1,2,3, 5, times, 20 times, 100 times.
And after that you are dead, you are not interested.
You cannot feel anything. Oh it's the same thing. Whether there is this one or that one, it doesn't matter.
Then let's try some other deviations.
You see Indian people like South American races are much more keeping to the culture and to the ethics.
We have destroyed everything, all the values, nothing.
You know my ideas. I'm not religious person, right?
I appreciate all religions but what I told you, what I teach is experience and how people can become happy.
Unfortunately we have overused this area.
- Could you please tell us something from your experience about fast acting remedies or slow acting remedies.
-According to my experience there are no fast acting remedies or slow acting remedies.
There is no such a thing. There is no such a thing as acute remedies and chronic remedies.
The only thing that exist is, if the remedy is indicated will act fast; if the remedy is not indicated
you think, it will take time etc. etc.
It's not because of the remedy that you may see a delayed reaction but because of the organism.
If the organism is weakened his
reaction will be a little bit delayed.
But not because of the remedy. I told you
I have seen cases with Aconitum where it was
considered as a remedy good for
common colds and I have given it
to very deep psychological trauma, fear that manifested at a certain point and lasted for 10 years.
And you give Aconite and the person feels free.
And then you see the next remedy of course, because in such a case of what we call small remedies
the idea is that you free the organism from a level of health, a level of remedy
you free it and the underlying pathology is manifesting more clearly.
You take out the effect of tremendous fear.
We had an earthqueake here in Greece and most of the houses are down.
These people, some of them, they will get a trauma because of the earthquake that will last all their life.
Now if you try to cure such a person and you take Calcarea Carbonica, you give it no effect or little effect.
Or Lycopodium, little effect. And then you go down to the trauma where she describes and she says
when I hear the word "earthquake" it makes me tremble. It's either Aconite or Gelsenium or Stramonium or Opium.
You give one of these remedies and then Calcarea Carbonica is coming again, beautiful now.
Now I can give you the Calcarea Carbonica. Because it has been printed upon the organism.
Like an imprint of the traumatic experience, whatever it might have been and the remedy
has to be targeted towards this uppermost layer which is waiting for you to recognise it and to give the remedy.
-You said that when you're taking a case after about the first or the second question, you come to an idea about the remedy.
Is that the information about the patient?
-Have in mind that I never see the cases beforehand. I don't want to know anything that you don't know.
So therefore I don't know what is written there and when I start taking the case, I am at the same position as you are.
I have not studied before the case so I don't know what you're talking about in this case.
-I just wondered if you set out the questionnaire before the person came.
-No, no. You are asking whether it is good to have a questionnaire filled by the patient before you see him?
-Yes.
-No, I don't think this is a good practice.
Because it can give you false impressions.
That means main points can be lost.
Because the patient does not realise that his main point is his fear of cancer.
He thinks that the pain he has in the right hypochondrium is the problem. If the pain goes away, then I have no cancer.
But he does not tell you 'I'm terrified with the idea that I have cancer because I have a pain in the right hypochondrium'.
So you miss the case if you do this.
-I would like to say something about
patients coming for the first time.
I know that most of them are doubteful whether Homeopathy is the right therapy for them.
I want them to read the book "medicine of a new man" before they come, so all of them know what is important
for a homeopath to know and even in
the first interview, most of them tell me
what I'm telling you now
I never told anybody before.
-Because they have been informed.
-Yes, I think that's a good way.
-I also think it's a good idea.
-I practice in London and this is what I actually do. To all my patients I give one of your books and I insist they read it.
And not to come if they don't have read it. I used to give one each because they used to be 20 pence those days
but now I just lend them and
I ask them to bring it back.
-Thank you. I have one of my books printed by an important publisher in Greece, a new book I wrote about
the information 'Basic ideas of Homeopathy' which is translated into English now and it will come out soon.
It will be shorter than the New Millenium and quite informative. In this book I write also an idea
which I did not want to speak publically, before.
Now I think it's time that we say everything.
What I say in this book is, and I give some examples, that our social behavior
our sexual behavior, our behavior in general is directly related to our pathology.
That means you are a character, they call you this, this or that and it's because of your hormones.
It's because of your pathology, because of your stomach not working properly that you behave in this or that way.
The society today has to understand that unless we are able to find a system that brings back
balance to the whole organism,
the society will go from bad to worse.
And we have a violent society,
we don't know why.
People become violent and if you ask them really why, they will admit they don't know exactly.
It's something inside me, you know like the Causticum, Argentum Nitricum, impulsive people.
They want to throw a bomb to the government and go to the government building and blow it all up because
of unequality, because of injustice, because of this or because of that.
In the same way when the child takes a gun and kills all his class mates. A child of 10 years old takes a gun and kills.
What is this? Nobody says the child is sick.
And we, as a society, should be able to detect his problem before he reaches that point of killing.
And not only to detect it but to have a way of eliminating this problem with the child.
You can understand how important Homeopathy becomes more and more, especially for Europeans and Americans.
It becomes more and more important. The danger is not so much with South Americans and with Indians,
people more balanced who
still keep the morals of a society.
Once the morals are breaking down, we have broken a barrier within us, a barrier which is brought about
by what we call as our conscience.
Once we make concessions about our conscience, 'it doesn't matter', then we broke the barrier.
And once the barrier is broken, then all hell
gets loose. We don't have a point to stop us.
See how important it is. I wrote an article about conscience and consciousness and the difference and what it means.
Maybe I will translate it into English.
I wrote it for a journal.
But I can tell you this: that once you make a concession with your conscience, there is no
way back.
All hell will get loose. Anything goes.
We had a case recently of a homosexual.
Very famous man. Actor.
Because Greece has famous people
only actors. Nobody else is famous.
He was going out every night, getting a young boy, having whatever having, making a deal, you do this,
you do that, I give you so much. In the end
he says, you don't get anything from me,
he goes to the kitchen takes a knife and kills him.
This man he must have been living in a hell because the barriers have been broken down.
Finished, nothing could stop him. He would go openly because everybody knew what he was doing.
He was not doing it even in secret, I'm famous I can do whatever I like. Go to the market, get somebody.
Ok I pay you so much, you do this.
I remember I had seen him and I said,
this man is Tarentula.
If he had got Tarentula, he was so much
in a hurry whatever he was doing.
A state of anxiety you could see it, restlessness.
I said Tarentula. If he had taken Tarentula maybe his hormonal system
that was driving him to have so frequently these kind of experiences, could have come down, reduced.
You see the importance of Homeopathy?
It's tremendous, it's unbelievable.
But at the same time because it is so
needed, there are so many noises.
You know in a system which is clean,
how the noises can destroy the system?
A lot of noises from the outside and the world
cannot realise the importance of that system.