What is my function here is show you real cases.
You will be seeing cases for the first time, like me, as if you were the doctor who takes the case.
I have to explain to you a little bit, especially for the younger ones, what it means to take a homeopathic case.
For those who are MDs they have learned the conventional way of taking the case.
The investigation which is performed by a MD is to find out what the diagnosis is,
what is the pathology, what the patient suffers from and this is enough.
You have rheumatoid arthritis.
We know the treatment, cortisone, aspirin etc.
Or you have a spastic colitis etc.
This is something which Homeopathy needs up to a certain extent, what the diagnosis is.
The patients who are coming to Homeopathy, they usually already have this diagnosis
because they have been to different doctors and they have tried very hard to cure themselves,
it was not possible and then they end up in a homeopath.
This has been already investigated and comes ready to you.
If there is a patient who has never had before any treatment you are going to make the diagnosis.
That means you are going to use your knowledge in Medicine, lab tests and all the technical things which exist today which help in making the diagnosis and then you will start the homeopathic investigation.
What we want to understand from a human organism is his reactions to external and internal stresses.
We have to find in which way the organism reacts.
We will hear a homeopath asking peculiar questions which are not usually asked in a medical consultation.
For instance, if a patient takes his feet out of covers during sleep.
You say for god’s sake I have colitis or rheumatoid arthritis, what does it mean if I take my feet out or not? For Homeopathy this becomes very important information.
We know from all physiology information that the thermostat of the body is the big toe.
This is the thermostat which regulates the internal temperature of the organism.
So, if an organism during sleep is heated due to external conditions, has to regulate itself immediately,
otherwise this rising of the internal temperature will cause a damage to it so automatically the organism needs to cool down and the patient takes out his feet.
Otherwise there is a problem.
We cannot say which problem, but definitely there is going to be a problem.
I'll give you another example.
For instance we take into consideration whether a patient has an organism which is easily heated up by external condition.
If it is warm he cannot tolerate it and takes off his clothes etc.
Because if he does not do that he is going to have repercussion, his blood pressure will rise, he may even have a brain stroke, or if he is outside under the sun he will have sunstroke.
In the seaside there are 30 people lying under the sun and one has sunstroke.
We want to know what is the difference in this organism that external heat rises the internal temperature to such a degree that becomes unconscious.
I'll give you another example.
We all know people complaining when the weather is wet.
Once there is wet weather I am stiff, I have lumbago or I have problems.
Why is that? It is because the tissues of the body are always containing the right consistency of water, minerals etc.
So an organism that is sensitive to wet weather absorbs water from the environment.
As a result we have excessive water within the tissues and the cells and then the tissues become watery, weak and then he says I have a lumbago.
A lumbago is the tendency of the organism to go out of alignment of the spine.
The moment that the tissues which hold the body straight become weak because of excess water within the cells, then it is easy to go out of alignment and there is a lumbago and sciatica.
Whether a person is sensitive to the external as it is today, today is a very wet day, it is very important for us to understand the organism how it functions.
On the contrary another organism who does not receive extra
water that means is lacking the absolute good quantity
of water within the cell when there is a lot of water
outside, the atmosphere is wet, he feels very good.
He says if I am in a wet weather I am in my best.
Because his absorption process cannot absorb the amount of water the organism needs in order to have the exact amount that the organism needs.
The organism regulates itself every moment in all elements, vitamins, water etc.
that needs to have its best performance.
The problem is that the organism cannot do it because of malfunction of the alimentary canal, guts, liver, gallbladder etc.
Cannot absorb certain elements.
He has been damaged and cannot absorb certain elements.
You will hear a question from a homeopath saying "do you eat onion?".
You say what is he talking about? The problem is that the general medicine has not realized the importance of the microelements which the organism needs in order to balance itself.
So onion contains a lot of sulfur.
If an organism has difficulty in absorbing sulfur or its composites calcarea sulfurica, kali sulfuricum etc then when you ask the patient do you like onions
he will say "Oh my God yes! I want onion from the morning till the night!" There is a need for onions…
In the children who are growing and they need a lot of calcium to build up their skeleton structure because their skeleton is growing fast and they need a lot of calcium.
So what the children mostly need is food which is rich in calcium.
Which food is rich in calcium primarily? Milk which he takes from the mother, milky products and what else when the child becomes one year old?
There is some food which the child badly needs and you may find out that the food the child eats very easily is eggs.
Because eggs contain a lot of calcium.
So if we see a child with a special desire for eggs and milk we realize his calcium intake is not good enough.
Therefore he needs regulation on this level.
But the child has come for dyspnea or asthmatic condition or constant diarrheas.
It doesn't matter.
The lack of calcium brings about a disturbance in the organism that will express itself in the most weak part of the organism.
Which is the weak part of the organism? The respiratory system and will express itself in a respiratory disorder.
By getting colds very easily, the child gets cold very easily and the cough stays to the bronchi and sometimes he ends up even in pneumonia.
Due to the fact that his absorption of calcium is inefficient.
The homeopath is trying to find this deeper reason for the pathology of the child in order to correct it and then the colitis of the child, the respiratory problems of the child resolve...
You mean if you take the examinations of the child.
Whether calcium low intake will be seen in the blood of the child...
Most laboratory examination will say from so much to so much, the highest, is normal.
A little bit out of this area is abnormal but actually for this organism there is only one normal.
It is not from here to here normal.
Let us say we have from 1 to 10.
For this organism the normal is 7, for the other organism the normal is 9 and for this organism the normal is 5.
The fact that the calcium level goes up to 3 for this organism it means damage.
Eventually you will find out that the organism will produce damage.
That means the child gets colds easily.
This cannot be seen in these examinations from lowest to highest.
Because the child's calcium level is from 8-10.5.
You see the child the child which is in 8.2 and is normal but it is not normal, the child craves for calcium, drinks milk, eggs, especially soft boiled eggs.
It has been proven that if you boil the egg and you make it hard some portion of the calcium in the eggs is lost.
That why the child wants soft-boiled eggs.
When you give them he takes them.
It's such an important issue among others and it has been ignored in conventional medicine.
Totally.
The pediatrician doesn't even ask and or know.
They say give him this but if I force the child to eat this he says no and spits it out.
No, you have to give it.
That means you provide elements to this organism which the organism fully receives and has aversion.
If the intake of calcium in a child is enough from all foods, if you give him eggs he will spit it.
So it goes both ways.
Desire and also aversion for eggs.
Eggs can become like poison in an organism that is anemic because we don't realize that the organism has its own intelligence and regulated everything, all the intakes and non-takes.
I don't like this, don't give me this food because it becomes like poison to me.
Like the example of onions and sulfur.
If an organism takes a lot of sulfur and doesn't need this, if you give him onions he says that his stomach takes 2 days to digest it.
I feel aversion but if you force him just to see what happens I have distention, dysphoria, my breath became bad; I feel very bad if I take onions.
The human intelligence is different and very restricted.
You say this is good for the child, you do this and that.
But who really knows? Is there any human brain that can enter an organism and by super-wisdom understand what is good or bad? It's not possible.
But yet Hahnemann said we have been given a way to understand what is happening in an organism by the symptoms.
Take the totality of the symptoms, take all the symptoms down and you will understand what is going on with this organism and only then you can correct it.
This is a tragedy that the whole of medicine has not understood this idea.
You know originally whose idea is this? This  idea first time was given very clearly by Hippocrates.
He says "δια τα όμοια νόσος γίνεται";with the similars we produce disease.
"Δια τα όμοια προφερόμενα εκ νοσευόντων υγειαίνονται".
By giving the similar you bring the patient from disease to health.
He said there are 2 ways to treat; one by opposites that means you are having fever I give you a anti-fever remedy, so I suppress the fever and the fever goes.
That means you burn you hand and if you put it into cold water the pain will stop.
The pain will stop but what happens afterwards?
There is a tremendous blister and he has noticed that if you burn your hand and you want to cure it don't put it in cold because you will have side effects.
Put it back in the fire, not to burn yourself totally
but to have enough heat, to give heat back, so the
organism will get out of that situation slowly and you
may be spared of the blisters and the aftereffects.
In WWII here in Greece where soldiers were fighting in snowy areas in the mountains, a lot of them because of bad shoes, they had frostbites.
They became blue.
Those who did not know they went and put the frostbites to the heat.
Those who did this they developed gangrene and their legs got amputated.
But then soon the soldiers learned that once you have a frostbite treated with snow, you go and take some snow and then slowly put on some snow little by little, your leg doesn't go to gangrene.
And they were saved, a lot of them by treating with similars.
So these are few examples, there are hundreds of that type.
But what it means for us...
The little symptom, any symptom that a person has it has its explanation and physiology.
When somebody comes and tells you I have a dysuria, difficulty in urination, there is a pathology which explains why this man cannot urinate properly.
How do you differentiate between a stricture in the urethra or a swelling of the prostate gland which is the most usual?
How do you differentiate that this kind of dysuria that this man has is of a different type than the other one which can be cancerous?
All this information will be given by the totality of the symptoms that the organism is presenting in front of you.
The totality of the symptoms means, in other words, it the language of the defense
mechanism which is beyond the reticuloendothelial system or the hormonal system
or the different other immune systems that we have known in the Medicine.
It is an intelligence which is beyond that which sees in the totality the whole reaction of the organism.
Why is there dysuria and at the same time there is lachrymation of the right eye?
Who can put this together and at the same time why is there in this organism a lack of thirst?
And why at the same in this organism there is constipation? And why at the same time this organism when he goes upstairs, 10-20 steps becomes like this?
All this becomes a totality together with some others which you cannot understand even if you are the most intelligent brain in the world, a computer or whatever.
You will never understand why there is this reaction and not the other.
Why this organism needs a lot of water.
He says give me water but I need water with ice.
Why does he need this very cold water? We know the remedy...
Phosphorus which needs cold water and because we know what is the most probable pathology of Phosphorus which is the easy
bleeding, the peripheral arterioles of the organism of a Phosphorus case are breaking up easily and they open up and they bleed.
So the patient will tell you I have been bleeding, I have nose bleedings since childhood and I need very cold water.
Because the cold water makes the arteries, especially in the stomach, constrict, they do not allow relaxation.
If it breaks the bleeding of the nose will be transferred to the stomach.
That is why the organism says don't give me hot water, because by hot water the arterioles will relax and break up and I will have a big problem, bleeding of the stomach.
Now in the hospitals they know a little bit of these things we know and they say give me him cold applications, cold water...
don't give hot things in a patient who is bleeding from his stomach.
They know it from experience.
We have a better knowledge and a deeper knowledge of pathology.
Because we have studied all possible reactions of the organism.
There is no reaction of an individual who is not registered in our Materia Medica.
It has registered the different pathologies which are produced by different remedies when they have been given in healthy individuals.
You are going to hear much more about that, much more explanation.
But what I want you to understand at this moment is, because I will be taking real cases, patients who are suffering,
and you will hear me asking questions which some of you especially those who come for the first time will not understand.
Why he wants to know all this? Why I want to know all this is not so much because I want to understand the pathology, for this also,
but what I'm trying to do is to collect information for the organism and at the same in the back of my
mind or in the computer today, we have all the information of the pathology that is produced by medicine.
All medicines produce pathology.
If you take antibiotics everyday for a month you will have a pathology in the end, having a certain set of symptoms.
If we wanted to use antibiotics as a remedy what would we do? We would collect all the possible side effects of antibiotics in all cases, in this case it produced stomach problems,
in this case it produced kidney problems of that type, this produced liver problems etc.
We would collect all this information of the side effects and then we would have a remedy we call a antibiotic of a specific type
and if we have a case with similar pathology then we would use the antibiotics but in a very minute dose.
Absolutely small dose.
What you will see happening, you will the see reacting to this very minute dose.
It reacts in such a way as to bring about balance again.
I will give you a short explanation how this happens.
In pathology all the symptoms of a patient are its effort to bring about balance, a cure.
An organism wants to be cured and that's why it produces a set of symptoms.
His intelligence is such that he says if I make an effort and I will detonate the electrical imbalance in the organism by an epileptic fit.
The type epileptic fit which detonates the electrical imbalance of the organism, this type is the best this organism can do to rebalance his electrical discharges.
It can do no better.
He's an epileptic and once in a week he has an epileptic fit or once in month or once in a year.
This is an effort at this moment to rebalance the organism.
If an organism is invaded by bacteria, all bacteria are existing in the organism, and then we say that the organism is invaded.
What does it mean? It means the organism at a certain point becomes a good ground for the developing of those specific bacteria.
The bacteria cannot come outside all the time.
If the constitution of the organisms lowers itself in immunity, it prepares the ground for allowing the streptococcus or the staphylococcus to develop in a great degree.
Once this staphylococcus is spreading within the blood then there is a time when the organism says wait, it is dangerous.
So what I have to do is raise the temperature to burn these invaders, like fire.
Actually it raises the fever in order to kill the bacteria.
And that is why certain bacteria are killed when the organism reaches 40,2 degrees while some, other 39,5 degrees etc.
Now that bacteria are modified due to antibiotics some others cannot be actually burned out,
that means the organism raises the temperature but if you allow him to be like that he will die.
In pneumonia this is what happens.
There is always a percentage in pneumonia, in the old times it was 20%, 20% of pneumonia cases would die, today depending on the age is maybe 5%.
This is not actually a total victory of antibiotics.
Antibiotics are useful, don't misunderstand me, in certain cases, in septicemia, pneumonia etc.
The antibiotics will save the life of the person.
But the life of the person who is not in a condition to face the problem itself, if the organism cannot face the invasion of bacteria himself by allowing him to raise the fever up to the point he wants
and then he will survive the organism and then bacteria will die but there are organisms who cannot survive a very high temperature,
in such cases the antibiotics who are targeting in not allowing the bacteria to spread may be life-saving but with side effects.
This is when the organism compromises and says I will not go to the end, I will not die but I will become chronically ill.
That is why from sinusitis of an aggressive type, when antibiotics are fully given in order to cure it eventually we may see asthmatic conditions developing.
I come back to the idea.
The organism produces symptoms, raises the fever, the cough, the cough must bring out the mucus which has been collected for a reason.
The mucus has been collected in order to reduce the development of local bacteria so there is mucus in order to kill the local bacteria and if there is a lot of mucus that stays the lungs will collapse,
the bronchi will collapse and the person will die of suffocation.
That's why the organism brings on the idea of cough.
Coughs and brings out the mucus in order to release.
The mucus starts again collecting because there is a local problem and it has to reduce it etc.
What I want to show you is that the symptoms of the organism are useful in order to cure itself.
Since they are useful what should we do? Suppress them or promote them, give them an extra push? The whole idea of Homeopathy lies in this.
But how can you find a substance that can act like the organism? We have tried and tested remedies and we have recorded their action and then the
action of arsenicum of producing diarrheas is the same or similar with the diarrheas produced by a poisonous food which the person has taken.
He takes a poisonous with bacteria, he goes home and tremendous diarrhea starts.
This kind of diarrhea in toxicology we know it is produced by arsenicum.
By giving arsenicum, of course if you give pure arsenicum you will kill the patient, he already has his symptoms, arsenicum has his symptoms you do not give a high quantity, you have a minute dose.
Once that minute dose touches the sensitivity of the organism it will cure the diarrhea within a few hours.
If you try to give suppressive drugs to stop the diarrhea it may take several days and still with a lot of side effects.
This is the big difference.
I see you are very tired today and I have spoken too much.
If you like you can ask a question.
- Hello.
Nice meeting you.
You told that story about calcium, eggs and milk, dairy product.
You said a certain person Calcarea Carbonnica will manifest lung disease because of his predisposition but his predisposition is also lack of calcium.
That bad mechanism who doesn't allow absorb the calcium.
These are two paths?
- No this is the total picture.
This organism because of lack of intake of calcium has a picture of lung disease or whatever that becomes one picture but how do you find the remedy that you have to give?
Not by investigating only the lung by x rays, auscultate etc, you may have all this information as a pediatrician and then if
there is dyspnea you give theophylline or whatever for releasing the bronchodilators in general, sometimes you give cortisone...
This is a part of the picture.
For the full picture you go deeper and you find out the child needs a lot of calcium, you realize calcium intake is in default and then you prescribe calcarea carbonica.
The picture is full, both taken into consideration.
- What I meant...this part of lack of calcium, this bronchomechanism is a miasmatic predisposition and the other one with the lung disease only a genetic predisposition.
It's a different thing?
- The miasmatic and the genetic...
You are progressing too much.
We have not spoken about miasms and the idea of miasms so it is a question which can be answered later on when the whole class will have heard about the idea of miasm and the predisposition.
What I can say here only is that genetic predisposition always comes from the two parents.
For us all diseases are genetically inherited by the parents.
Because in conventional medicine they say epilepsy is perhaps only inherited or psoriasis is inherited and other diseases are not.No.
Every disease each one of us has come from the mixture of the two parents.
It is a predisposition but not directly from the one or the other but from the mixture of the two parents.
That means the child who comes with psoriasis which the father has, she may have it much more
that the father or much less than the father, the much less from the father means that his mother
was in a better condition than the father when the father got married, the mother was in a
very good condition so the child took the predisposition from the father but to a mild degree.
On the contrary, the mother was neurotic mother and the father had psoriasis, the child might appear much worse psoriasis.
He may not be neurotic like the mother but all the impact is taken in the psoriasis in the level of the skin.- Hello.
You talked about producing mucus in pneumonia, bronchitis.
So this is normal...
Every one of us produces mucus in a order to overcome the bacterial disease but some people may produce which is not easily expectorated.
This shows us maybe a remedy but this is not healthy, I cannot understand how this symptom is useful.
- There is a tickling in the trachea and the person has to cough.
The tickling means that some area in the trachea or in the larynx is inflamed.
There is a little inflammation.
Tickling is like a skin eruption, an eczema when it is very itchy, what is the natural thing you do, scratch it.
By scratching it relieves the pain, the itching.
It's the same thing with the coughing without mucus.
This organism either will produce mucus and the cough and then in the end mucus will come and then most probably you will see the end of the problem...
And it is well known that in a dry cough when it becomes loose it's a good sign.
That means until the organism is able to bring out, complete its defense, then he has to do whatever is possible to relieve itself.
Cannot cure it but has to do something to relieve himself.
So the dry coughing is like scratching in a place where it is itching until the
inflammation becomes too much and then mucus comes and the mucus comes out or the
overall problem is over and the organism has rearranged the elements that has to take
in order to fight that particular inflammation and then the problem will be over.
There will be cough for some days and then it stops without ever bringing mucus.
That means the inflammation was not of that severe type.
Another theory I have spoken about and I have brought out for the Medicine in general is my theory that all diseases are of inflammatory type.
Some are with high temperatures but once this is suppressed then we have a sub-acute inflammation process that is going on all the time for all chronic diseases.
Later on you will learn an idea which I brought out of observation when the organism reaches the point where he will be able to raise fever it's in a good condition.
I will show you a case in the afternoon and I will try to explain during the taking of the case what I am trying to do.
Thank you!