-How high you would go as far as potencies with the people that are over 70 years old?
-The highest 200 but if it is a strong case of a farmer, then you can go 10M even.
Because 70 years old a bower no problem, lumbago no problem.
-George in one book you mentioned something about inimical remedies
and it is dangerous or difficult to use them instead of simili.
Can you explain something on this?
-Yes, when we say inimical remedies, we only mean remedies
which have similar symptomatology.
If the symptomatology of two remedies is quite similar these two are inimical.
That means if you are given one of these and it has acted, don't give another
which is very similar because most probably you will be disturbing the case.
But this is not for this level. I did not talk because later on when you have more remedies
then you see what is similar and what is dissimilar in remedies.
-I have two questions please. The one is if there is an eruption in each full state,
would you give another potency than in an eruption where there is a big suppression?
-There is a full blown eruption after a remedy?
-No.
-He comes for the first time and we give one potency.
-200.
-Yes. If it would be the same case but with suppression of the eruption,
would you give another potency?
-No, the same potency.
-If we expect an aggravation of the skin and the remedy we have chosen
it is known in its provings that we have a great skin eruption,
does this influence the choice of the potency?
-No, what you have to be careful only in skin eruptions is Sulphur.
In skin eruptions if you give Sulphur and Sulphur is not the correct remedy,
it's going to aggravate the skin eruption without amelioration.
It will aggravate, aggravate... You wait for amelioration, nothing.
Because Sulphur produces a lot of eruptions.
So in this case also you have to be careful with Graphites
because it produces a lot of eruptions and you have to be careful
especially of Sulphur in skin eruptions.
-May I ask a question? That came up in the morning session with me.
In Germany right now it's quite common, I know some patients
who use a cream containing uric acid to treat their skin.
It doesn't have any cortisone or any other contents but it contains uric acid.
And I would like to know if you consider this also as a suppression or not
because I'm treating people who have all skin conditions.
I'm expecting them to come up but they say if it doesn't work,
they put this on and it gets better. How to deal with this?
-I don't know. I did not know it exists such a thing and I don't know how effective it is.
If it is effective, that means if it suppresses, then you have to avoid it.
-But they have cracked skin and that heals, if they put it on.
-I have seen a depression developing after treatment of the gums.
The dentist treated the gums and the inflammation in the gums went away
and a depression followed.
I gave the remedy and the inflammation of the gums came back.
You remember a case, I don't know if somebody was in Celle?
A case of severe multiple sclerosis who developed after the suppression
of a little eruption on the knees.
He suppressed that eruption and then he developed multiple sclerosis symptoms.