-Important questions.
-If you see what your computer repertorization always symptoms that you put
just by your estimation.
I would like to know how you do the hierarchy of those symptoms?
-This repertorization, what you see, I hardly say a symptom.
I discuss with the case and Margaret is there or Christian is there
and they put their own symptoms.
Then I look from time to time what this repertorization is coming out.
I don't say put this symptom, put that symptom, no. Neither underline the symptoms.
But I get some ideas whatever they hear, they put the symptoms
and that's why there are so many symptoms in the Repertory.
There are not my symptoms, it's their symptoms.
Sometimes I agree or I disagree with the symptom.
You don't give always the remedy that comes first, like the Aurum sulphuratum.
Aurum sulphuratum was not there at all in the repertorization.
Like the way I said about Palladium. Palladium was not except of the first symptoms.
-Nevertheless I would be interested when you take a case what are important symptoms for you?
-Symptoms can become important if they are peculiar.
Like the one we saw this deep breath, this is a peculiar symptom
you better take into consideration.
But as you take a case, you miss a peculiar symptom.
This was a peculiar symptom, I did not open the Repertory to see it.
So what is important to have a peculiar symptom.
What is very important is to have a symptom present, not only in the past.
What is important is to see whether some symptoms are coming, showing a Lachesis
but then the present symptom shows Belladonna.
So the present symptoms are important, the peculiar symptoms are important,
symptoms which are clearly expressed by the patient are important.
But always see what are the present symptoms.
At a certain moment I could show you in the repertorization
where at first I thought of Phosphorus.
Then I was investigating Phosphorus.
If you investigate a remedy, you don't take in consideration a symptom which is like this type.
It has to be very strong. You investigate keynotes of the remedy.
You have to get this keynote strongly.
I was investigating the sympathetic element with her. I had to see that this was very strong.
I was investigating the clairvoyance, how strong. I was not happy with how strong.
Startling easily she said, that's another Phosphorus symptom.
When she came to the sympathetic element of Phosphorus, then it was strong.
Then the aversion to eggs, you show it, everyone put it three times.
So these symptoms which are clear, you need to work with them.
What are the symptoms which belong to her personality.
She is a strong woman. She has become strong out of circumstances.
It is her character, her personality.
Also what you think is strong or weak is different than the person himself.
You have to take into consideration that.
In the same way you see the Phosphorus, this little angel,
and you see the other Phosphorus and you see the difference in personalities.
And you see a third personality. It is different personalities but the underline symptomatology,
the pathology is Phosphorus.
What it may be confusing for you is the difference in personality.
She is more closed, she is closed and open, she is affected etc.
But you are taking into consideration the personality.
You say for her she is too strong for Phosphorus. For her also you said the same thing.
She is too strong for Phosphorus. No, it's the same thing. It's her personality.
I've told you many times with the Pulsatilla.
You get the idea from the books that Pulsatilla is weak, easily led etc.
This is the pathology. If a very strong woman can become a little bit weak,
then she goes to Pulsatilla but still she is very strong.
I told you the Ministry of Exports in India, she was a powerful woman,
she would do transaction and I saw a little bit of weakness.
That was enough for her personality, for me to be persuaded that she is going towards Pulsatilla.
So don't mix the personality with the pathology.
Pathology is she cannot take a deep breath. That's pathology. I can't take a deep breath.
Then that is a symptom of sighing, she did not say sighing.
She says my breathing is superficial.
I do not look because there is not such a symptom, superficial breathing
and then I go of course to the essential.
It is better to go to the essentials and see the picture and say that is now a Phosphorus case.
This case which is Phosphorus to be confirmed by symptoms like this. It is better.
You have done a better job than just have given on superficial breathing Phosphorus.
She may not being Phosphorus.
The fact that she has been Phosphorus and she confirmed by the symptom,
then it's beautiful, then you feel comfortable.
But the recent symptom, Phosphorus. The most recent symptom, Phosphorus.
What continues? Sympathetic element. What has gone away? The fear.
The fear of thunderstorm, this anxiety, this openness she had as a child will come back.
As a child she was open. She will go through a period where she will feel this openness again.
She will lose this barrier. She will be more connected, she will make more easy friends.
She will have a boyfriend or a husband in six months.
-I only wanted to make a few remarks concerning the repertorization.
Because this repertorization in my eyes is a kind of documentation
because when we do the follow-up we have which symptoms did she have.
I would never make a repertorization where I put every symptom into the computer at home
and I hope that [name] didn't get the impression that we put symptom, symptom, symptom
and make together a remedy.
Because at home normally you don't have someone beside you work on the computer.
You take the case, evaluate and then you go to the computer.
-It is true but if I was teaching you repertorization,
I would say do repertorization in different ways.
You put a few symptoms, you look. You put more symptoms, you look again.
You put one more symptom, you look again. One more symptom, what happened?
You look again. This is how you do repertorization.
You don't put all the symptoms and see what comes in the end.
You see what comes step by step and then you have an idea of different remedies,
from which you are going to choose the right one.
Then after you have all the information, you put it down, you analyze it,
then you come back to the case and you think now what shall I do.
If she was a Phosphorus case, now still Phosphorus symptoms appear,
then that is a beautiful case of Phosphorus.
That means she is going to be benefited deeply by Phosphorus.
-I would also like to say that when I'm sitting beside you putting symptoms,
you keep asking questions to confirm remedies like ideas of a remedy that could be possible.
You ask certain questions and if it's no, I just leave it out and if it's yes, I put it in.
So what comes up like in that case in the first few minutes
there was Palladium coming up of course.
Also Aurum sulphuricum was coming up but as we proceeded it was coming back.
So this is very important to do the repertorization step by step.
You put a symptom or two just to make an analysis and see how it develops.
In my practices it's very possible that the remedy I prescribe in the end, it's not on top.
That's normal.
Also Lilium tigrinum was coming up very high at the beginning.
-Also it is interesting that sometimes I arrive at a stage where I write the remedy, Sepia.
Then I ask tell me, he has put Sepia. Sepia is on top.
Because I do a repertorization of course with what I know from the Repertory
but coincides many times with what is coming out.
Without repertorization I feel that you will not be secure.
You think many times the remedy is correct.
Just do the repertorization and confirm, don't leave it to chance.
-We had some cases where you prescribed remedies in low potency like C6, 7
or even D to be raised one week a time and take it continuously
over a certain amount of weeks of even months.
I'm very familiar with this kind of administering of remedies.
My fear would be that I lead the patient into an over stimulation
because I keep repeating, repeating and I haven't heard any advice from you to the patient,
what to do if he gets an aggravation after a certain time?
-I suppose that everybody knows that if there is an aggravation they will stop the remedy.
If there is aggravation, stop the remedy.
-And wait how long?
-In such cases until the aggravation goes and then better, wait and then relapse,
then you stop again.
This case Acetanilidum, the nephrotic syndrome we did not discuss
because I think we discussed it already.
These symptoms he continues with the same remedy and as you know we gave 200.
It was not real effect, then we went down very much to 12.
Then he started having an effect and we have repeatedly given low potency.
Now last time we went even lower to 6C.
I want to see what is happening but as I see by the repetition
the case is progressing more and more. And this case is quite a serious case. He is here.
He was treated in Norway by two nephrologists and they have been given Methotrexate
and cortisone very strong to control the albumin of the urine. This is a serious condition.
They know it very well and that's why they said that nobody can help you.
When he said I'm going down to Greece, they said forget it, this is nonsense.
Who can help you? So it's serious pathology.
The remedy was very clear fortunately for me.
Who has seen the case originally?
You have not seen it originally? The original case on the video?
-Yes.
-OK.
It doesn't matter whether you saw it on video or live it does not matter.
Also another case of cancer of the pancreas with metastasis in the liver,
you have not seen this case?
It's the Italian group?
-Yes.
-That is a similar situation where we repeat for second year now, we repeat in low potency
and we just slowly go up.
Serious pathology the remedy becomes clear eventually.
In his case the remedy was clear originally, in the other case he needed three remedies
before the remedy was clear in the case of cancer.
Now I think we complete two years in a case they have given him only three months.
In three months you die.
We repeat for 1 1/2 year almost. For half a year he took three remedies
and then the rest is taking the same remedy in low potency. The same way we try for this case.
So when we have strong pathology the organism cannot push.
The high potency is like an electrical push, an energy push.
It needs the whole organism to be in a position to follow.
If it is not in a position to follow because of an organ breaking down,
then you have to stimulate slowly.
You will learn, you will see these cases.
Maybe I will show you these cases which is in Greek and translated in Italian.
-If the vital force is so weak, as in her case, would it may be a possibility
to continue the treatment by giving a C30 once the day.
Because of all the potencies she has had this acted best or it would not be so good?
-This is really a problem with this little one because I have seen several times
and everybody who was near could see being totally out, paralyzed
and just by touching the Phosphorus she is back.
We don't have it on video yet but I think it would be very impressive to have it on video.
That means she is very sensitive to Phosphorus, there is no question.
Why she does not stay? Maybe she needs more time, maybe she needs another potency.
So my idea would be actually not to give her 30 but to give her more material dose.
And let her have an aggravation, if there is an aggravation like 6C,
don't go to the Q potency.
But 6C and give one every day and when there is an aggravation you stop.
Then you continue.
In case there is a collapse, you have 6,7,8,9,10 and if there is a collapse you got one more.
Let us say you take 6,6,6,6 one month, then there is a collapse.
You give 7 and then you start 7 every day. Then there is a collapse, 8,9
and you go higher like this and we'll see how she will be doing.
-I want to ask there is a paragraph in the Organon that Hahnemann says that you
shouldn't repeat any potency. I think it's 246 or 247 that you shouldn't
because the vital force is not in the same, as it used to be, when you gave him the remedy.
Here I see that sometimes people do repeat low potencies, high potencies.
For instance in the Phosphorus to repeat very low potency, I found out
that it gives hemorrhages for instance.
-If the remedy is not correct, it may give some hemorrhage.
-If it's correct?
-No.
But you see in his case Acetanilidum, you go 200, you have no effect.
You go to low potency, you have an effect.
The same way with the cancer case. We went to 200, no effect.
We went down to 12 I think, immediately it showed an effect.
So we don't know everything and we just are careful into going into these matters.
With Tom's case with the kidneys, if we take the initial action, I answer to you
because being Phosphorus you are anxious.
If we take his initial reaction, no reaction, nothing, Acetanilidum no reaction,
you will see nothing happened.
But his case is more than 60% better now by going lower and by repeating.
You cannot deny these facts.
-Are there any special rules for giving potencies?
Which potencies to give for pregnant women and for small children or babies?
-Small children and babies you can go very high, this is the rule
unless it is a life threatening situation.
You don't go and give very high, the moment that the baby cannot breathe
and it's blue you give a CM. No.
Was anybody in the Cicuta case in Alonissos where by mistake I said 30
and they gave CM in an epileptic child, paralyzed, retarded?
And I said 30, they didn't have 30, they did not ask me, we could not find 30, we give CM.
And it was a very severe aggravation to the extent that the child could not breathe.
We try to find some oxygen, by this time, I'm talking back to 80 or 81.
There was no oxygen, there was nothing actually and the child got over.
But you don't go and give in such severe pathology very high potency.
The children you can go very high, as long as it's not a life threatening situation.
-I asked also about the pregnant women, if there is any problem?
-Pregnant women you don't have problems as long as the remedy is correct.
But you may have problems if the remedy is incorrect.
Incorrect remedy you may have some problem because the woman during pregnancy
she is in a sensitive situation and with incorrect remedy you may have some complications.
Do you remember the case in Aedipsos? Who was in Aedipsos? Only Richard.
Where she gave birth to twins.
Then what happened is that she started to have dilatation of the uterus
by 10 o'clock in the morning.
By 10.30 she was given by absolute stupid for me reason, she was given Sepia 10M.
As a result the dilatation stopped, the uterus collapsed and she could not give birth.
Until it was 9 o'clock in the night and we had a tremendous battle.
Because one of the students went, discussed with her.
I said why did you give Sepia? She said because I saw some mark in her thigh.
I said did you realize what you have done? The helicopter could not come, it was night.
There were twins, there was no contraction of the uterus. The uterus had collapsed.
The gynecologist was there, a German gynecologist and we battled.
At a certain moment the one child was coming and the other came with the wrong position
and the uterus was not contracting.
He was trying to turn the child, the child would not turn and we were sweating
and he said to me the one child is dead, he made some signs. I said god.
He said what shall we do? We have to cut. We just had a scissor from the woman
who had the house. She brought a scissor they have when they cut the clothes.
We have to cut the child to bring it out piece by piece.
I said forget it. We battled. You have to be careful.
By 9 o'clock in the night, it was almost 11 hours. 11 hours there was no movement at all.
And then as I was desperate, I asked her tell me the symptoms. What you felt?
She gave me the symptoms and they were symptoms of Pulsatilla.
Then I give the Pulsatilla and I said to the others in one hour she will start giving birth.
9.50 she started giving birth, one child came out and then the second child came in this position.
And he was trying to turn and he said push, push and she got cramps and she fainted.
He told me don't let her faint, then Carbo vegetabilis, Cuprum.
I just throw remedies to keep her alive and to make her able to push with the uterus.
It was terrible.
Because the child could not come. The one child came out, the other child would die.
We have to be careful with the pregnancy, that we make sure that the remedy is correct.
-I have a question concerning the administering of homeopathic remedies during pregnancy.
Is there any risk that those remedies are given to the mother could do the child any harm
because of course it is the victim within the whole process that is going on?
-With the homeopathic remedy in pregnancy there is no problem with side effects.
Something happening to the child, something happening to the mother.
What I say is we have to be careful with the remedies that affect the uterus especially.
Causticum, Ustilago, Caulophyllum, Sepia.
Such remedies, if you give, you make sure that they are indicated.
Otherwise the wrong remedy will have some aggravation that it is not for...
But if you go and repeat Phosphorus, 200 every day, she is pregnant
and she does not need Phosphorus, you may have some hemorrhage.
This is what I say, you have to be a little bit careful.
There is no side effects that some damage will be done to the child or anything of that type
which we have with chemical drugs.
We don't have toxicity at all.
-A homeopath in Austria he gives remedies to pregnant women by way of so called "ugenic cure".
You give nosodes high potency at certain stage of the pregnancy.
It's not classic Homeopathy but some homeopaths do it and recommend it still.
What he found out was that the child had a defect when it was born
and the defect of the organ system, the time when the organ system was developed,
was matching the time when he gave this remedy, one of these remedies.
-What was the defect?
-I think it was cardio-vascular but I'm not sure.
And since then he stopped practicing this type of cure.
-It's good that this happened but I don't believe that such a defect could be initiated
by homeopathic remedy, I don't believe it.
The homeopathic remedy can go deep and have an aggravation, which is quite strong
but in such a case the child is going to be benefited definitely.
If it is a superficial aggravation, there is no effect on the child. It is like a proving.
You give a remedy and you do a proving in a child or whoever. There is no danger.
If you give a high potency and you repeat it for months, 50M for months, of course...
It may be making a deep proving.
-I can add a public case for problem from wrong remedies during pregnancy
that it was published last year in Germany where a homeopath gave Carcinosin.
Carcinosin not indicated, only with family problems on cancer,
to a pregnant woman with asthma problems.
So asthma aggravated and comes an abortion and it was very ugly aggravation
due to wrong remedy by pregnancy.
-One is what you think about the practice which is done sometimes
if you have a nursing mother and a baby.
The baby is ill and the mother received the remedy because she can give it to the child by nursing.
That's one question.
-This can happen yes.
It can affect the child. The mother gets the remedy, she is nursing, the child also gets the remedy.
-The other question is, the mother is ill and the child is ill and the child
needs a different remedy than the mother. What do we do in this case?
-Give different remedy.
-I think maybe you misunderstood something here because I cannot agree at all with what you said.
You can't basically always say that if the child is ill, while the mother is still nursing
that you always administer the remedy to the mother
because also can have an effect from this remedy.
I think if the remedy does not fit to the mother, you can't give it to the mother.
-First of all I answered to the question whether by giving a remedy to the mother,
the child also may be affected and I said yes. It can happen, we have seen certain cases
where the child is affected.
The diarrhea of the child stops when the mother takes the remedy. That's one thing.
The other thing we have seen, the mother is sick, the child is sick.
They need two different remedies.
The other question that you are asking, the mother is sick and needs Argentum nitricum.
The boy also needs Argentum nitricum, you give it also to the boy
but we have seen cases actually where the mother takes the remedy and the child is affected.
Also we have seen that. But don't make a rule that when the child is sick,
you give a remedy to the mother.
Such a rule is wrong because you have to take into consideration the child who is sick.
You have to take the symptomatology and maybe it's another remedy, it's not the same remedy.
-Maybe you understood Mayra wrong because she asked because of the paragraph
that says that every time you repeat a remedy, you have to little change the potency by shaking.
Not give the same remedy, not changed.
-Is that what you said?
What Hahnemann was saying in the last edition is that he went back to the LM potencies
and he says you repeat this, it's good to shake them. That idea I also agree, it's OK.
You take it for one week and then you go higher.
What you are saying is a little detail for me that during this week is good
that you also shake it twice, it's good yes.
But if you don't shake it for me it's going to be the same. It's not an important issue.
If the remedy is acting in a low potency, it's going to act whether you shake it or not.
In this case, the cancer case, you will see that the person says the remedy stopped acting
because of the control with the phosphatase and the gamma GT and the transaminases.
You will see the remedy stops, then all these start going up.
Then you will go higher the remedy and all these start to go down.
Then you repeat the remedy and then eventually going up again.
Then you go higher and this is the experience.
Now we don't know everything at this moment, neither me, not anybody.
How many times we should check. We are just developing the knowledge.
I'm giving my experience, I'm giving you real cases.
Here I don't hide anything. All the cases you have seen, I bring the follow ups.
Here it is, here what happens, here what we did.
As far as truth is concerned, you know exactly what I'm doing and how I'm proceeding
with a case and this is important for you at this moment.
You get this information, you get this knowledge at this moment.
Maybe after three years I will have crystallized different other ideas,
which I' m going to give them to you. At this moment these are the ideas.