-Another question? No question.
-We have that allopathic remedies can interfere with homeopathic remedies
and that is why I wanted to ask what about the pill or other allopathic remedies or pain killers?
-Yes, pain killers they will influence the case definitely.
Also the anti-contraceptive pill is influencing not so much, not so drastically
but in some cases we stopped this after we came to the conclusion
that the relapse was because of the pill. But not in all cases.
It is much better if you can use mechanical contraceptives, not hormonal.
-I saw in many cases after the suppression of the uterus, after the operation of hysterectomy
that the women are getting thyroid problems. Did you see the same?
I have now a case where she has thyroid problems and after the hysterectomy
she gets now problems of the genital hormones, the female hormones.
She is feeling much better but the problem is going back.
-After you gave a remedy for thyroid, she is better in the thyroid...
-Yes and generally she is better but the problem of hormonally disturbance,
sexual hormonal disturbance are coming back now.
-That is normal, what you say is normal though I have not seen it in all cases of hysterectomy
that the thyroid is affected but maybe this can happen.
And by correct treatment the thyroid is getting better and the hormonal disturbances
are coming, which means that she needs a second remedy now to regulate this level as well.
-But after this suppression of the uterus, after the hysterectomy, can we help really?
Because the uterus is gone.
-Yes we can help definitely, without the uterus.
It would be more easy perhaps, if the uterus was there but you can help.
-Did you ever seen an application of the homeopathic remedy in ICD
and the contraceptive device come out?
-No.
-A question about pain killers. Supposing you are on a remedy and you have a severe headache.
The best thing is not to take anything but if it is unbearable,
is it better to take another specific remedy in low potency or pain killer?
-No. It is better to take aspirin, not any pain killer.
If you take Lonarid or Cafergot or this kind of pain killers it is dangerous
but aspirin is not so dangerous. You can take two aspirins.
-What about paracetamol?
-Paracetamol also I don't trust very much.
Pure aspirin diluted in water.
Don't take it directly because it may just make a hole in your stomach
because it goes into the stomach and starts diluting, creating acidity
and it just can make a hole in the stomach.
Especially if there is some predisposition.
-I wish to tell you about paracetamol. In Germany there are some cases of child death
after taking paracetamol.
-Enormous amount.
-It really is a problem because in former times we gave aspirin to the children
and then the so called Reye's syndrome appeared, which brought death in children.
So it was a shift towards paracetamol and it was just a question of time
when you would find out the sides effects of paracetamol. They give it to every child.
It is forbidden to give aspirin to the children in fever diseases because of this Reye's syndrome.
So they will find out that Homeopathy is better.
-From a point of view of development of the case I have found out
that aspirin does not interfere so much but the low potency of a homeopathic remedy,
if it is not the correct one, it can interfere. From that point of view it is better to give aspirin.
Of course if you are aware of the possible side effects,
then you ask if the child has taken before etc., you give it slowly,
you don't give 10 aspirins together.
-I've seen in family dynamics where a couple brings a wild child in for treatment.
Once the child is treated then it comes out that they sort of triangulating their problems
into the child and it's manifesting whatever problems they have.
As the child starts to cure, then you see the problems with the parents.
My question is have you ever seen that in a physical level,
for example when a woman whose child had psoriasis? Her psoriasis disappeared
when she gave birth and then the child got it.
So when she is cured, would you see go back to the mother on an energetic level?
Is that happened?
-Not in this way.
I also don't consider this fact when she gave birth, then her psoriasis disappeared.
I don't consider this as a family dynamics.
I consider it more on purely physical, chemical levels.
Family dynamics are mostly on an emotional level and an effort to readjust your emotionality
towards the new situation.
I have seen it for instance in women who have their daughters being married
and go away from the house. So we have this in Greece.
Of course in America you don't have it because children, once they reach age 14-15,
you have to go out, the mother says out.
Here in Greece they keep them in the house and there is a family dynamic.
The daughter is married and she is gone.
The mother does not have somebody anymore to look after.
She was looking after the daughter and she was active. And then she goes into depression.
That is what I consider as family dynamics.
That the mother may develop whatever, skin eruptions.
Usually they develop depression and also fear, anxiety, hypochondriasis,
fear of dying and their place on the planet is shaken.
What is my role now? I don't have anything to do
because they have invested so much in a child who was sick and needed more attention
and they had a role, they had a mission to help the child, the child is better, it goes out.
-How do you handle the subject with antidoting through Acetic acid and Sulphur?
For example Sepia?
-Sepia it is said that she should avoid sour, vinegar or lemon.
Usually we advice to avoid, that is true but now in my experience
whether vinegar had antidoted, I cannot say.
Maybe, I remember one case that maybe she was using vinegar and we found out
that she had to be careful with vinegar, yes.
But it is not something which I specifically believe.
The problem is that you have a relapse and then you search why there is a relapse
because the relapse is too soon.
And you find that she is using vinegar and somebody else has found it and then record it.
I'm not sure that in all cases of Sepia the use of vinegar will do the same thing.
I'm not sure. But as a precaution.
The same way with mint. I saw mint antidoting definitely a case of Nat mur.
Just that case. From that time onwards when I give Nat mur, I say don't use mint.
Some of my students they generalize it and said mint out.
It is not my instructions or experience.
-I have a question concerning Mercury corrosivus.
I had a case of Mercury corrosivus in my dental clinic years ago.
He was a case of juvenile periodontitis.
This is a disease which is not curable or treatable by orthodox medicine.
And the picture is that young people at the age around 18-25 lose their complete teeth
within 3-5 years. Unfortunately he received Mercury solubilis from a homeopath.
Could you imagine if he had received Mercury corrosivus that this losing of the teeth
could have been stopped?
-I don't think so.
There are certain diseases like juvenile diabetes that we cannot have real effect.
Like amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, you don't expect.
The Jakob Creutzfeldt disease, the spongoid encephalopathy,
you don't expect to have an effect with the homeopathic remedy.
These are end stages diseases.
Schizophrenia of 10-15 years, forget it.
And spastic children when after birth it brings the raise of bilirubin,
where they have to change the blood, they have to change the whole blood of the child
and then the child comes into a spasticity state, forget it.
You battle for years and you just improve a little bit.
These are diseases which you cannot have an effect.
And you may be battling and some effect will be there.
Like autistic children, you may be battling with some effect
but you will be disappointed in the end. You cannot bring around health.
-What is your feeling on homeopathic medicine and Chiropractic or Acupuncture?
Do they contradict one another?
-No they don't contradict, they can complement each other,
especially when the homeopathic treatment does not give further effects on a local problem,
which can be due to dislocation of a vertebrae or to a wrong position.
This can be complemented by chiropractic practice.
-Do you know what happened to the Indian baby girl who was treated with Agaricus 30?
And we had the follow up in Athens?
-I have long time since I did not have news and I have to write to them
to give me the latest news.
-I'm thinking of her because the case was extreme and you, yourself were surprised
by the treatment.
-I had predicted that such a case will improve. To what extend we don't know.
Because It was an amazing case for me also.
But the remedy was clear at that moment and I said OK let's see what happens.
And what happened it was very impressive because the epileptic fits stopped immediately.
And then she started developing slowly. I published exactly the letter as it was coming from India.
I do not have the latest report but as you reminded me I will have to write
to get the latest report.
But such cases you don't expect to bring them back to normality.
-If we took a remedy and after a while we have to make a stomatologic treatment?
-That's a problem.
-We repeat the remedy?
-Because they use strong medication, especially for anesthesia which affects the system.
-What can we do?
-Nothing.
-We repeat the remedy?
-Oh yes afterwards either you repeat or many times there is no complete relapse,
so you don't know what to do actually.
-Also I want to ask if hemophilia is...
-Forget it.
-I want to ask you about Silica. I had a case two months ago of a young man
who was diagnosed 12 years ago with a big tumor in the colon.
They took the whole colon out and they connected the large intestine to the rectum
or the tube and Silica came to my mind.
What is your experience with Silica, as far as rejecting the foreign body,
like the tube of the colon or the tube..?
-You may do it.
-Let's say he needs a Silica, what you will do or what you will give?
-I will think it twice before I give it or you give it in very low potency like 6X
in the beginning to see how it will develop.
-Generally Silica can reject all foreign bodies like the silicon breast?
-Yes.
-Then what do you do? How you approach that?
-I said you give it very low 6X and see how the organism is doing.
You don't give a big shock like 200 or 1M.
-I have a question about a patient who had a bypass surgery and he's had a mess screen
implanted in the aorta in one of the larger veins.
-What is a mess screen?
-The doctors feel that it may be from aneurysm and so they have implanted a mess screen
like mosquitoes.
-A kind of a net to support the artery.
-That's correct. This patient has had a stroke and he is severely involved after the surgery.
It is a complicated case but the question I have is this mess screen
that they have implanted I think 5-6 years ago, the stroke happened 1 1/2 year ago,
it is made of titanium and it is shown to the wall of the artery.
The remedy that I have come up with initially is Silica and I'm wondering if I can give Silica
without possibly disturbing the screen and if the Silica will cause the screen
to be rejected by the body?
-I don't think that there is any problem with the screen because the screen
just keeps the artery open. It doesn't interfere with the function really of the heart.
So I don't think it will be any problem with that. You can go ahead and give it.
The problem which I see is whether you will have any effect or not. That's another story.
-I don't know about Europe but in America everybody is taking Prozac.
Women, children, everybody is taking Prozac.
-It's an antidepressive remedy, which there was a big article on Times magazine
or Newsweek three weeks ago, which shows that there are a lot of side effects,
especially affecting the sexuality.
It goes into pieces, you don't have it anymore, you get rid of it and so it's better.
Some people say it's OK, some they say no, out with Prozac.
My idea is that if you give a powerful chemical drug which affects the brain
definitely it's not only the hormonal disturbances that they create.
They create a generalized disturbance which they will find out most probably
that it'll catch the expectancy of life or whatever other problems,
cancer or heart problems that they may develop together with the hormonal disturbances.
Hormonal disturbances are quite immediate and quite obvious and that's why they record them.
What about other subtle effects on the long run? We don't know.
But you see the problem is, as I see it, that we make a population
which is on a massive depression.
Because otherwise you don't need to take Prozac, unless you are on a depression state.
And also craziness because these people have anxieties and fears.
They resort to this kind of medication.
The extends to which is prescribed it shows the problem that we have created
in the western world.
Because these remedies are not needed by Asians, are not needed by South Americans,
are not needed by the Africans.
They are needed only for the white population, that is going crazy more and more.
The same idea was in America with the psychoanalysis.
Everyone had to have a psychoanalyst or a psychotherapist or a psychologist
to support him or her. Almost everyone. They could not live unless this is my psychotherapy.
For us, Greeks when we hear about this, in the beginning I remember back in 1960
when I heard about this I thought Americans they are all crazy.
What do they do with the psychotherapist? What do they say?
Of course now a lot of Athenians need psychotherapy as well.
-I think often needs are waken by advertisement for example or by giving certain offers.
They have to eradicate every slight discomfort or every tiny little fear they have
and I believe actually it's normal to have fears once in a while or something else.
-That is also true that advertising has inflated the problem but the problem exists.
Go to India and do the advertising or to South Americans, they will not pay attention.
Here also in Greece there is this advertising but they don't pay attention.
In America of course there is the need, that's why they say it makes me feel good.
-I have two questions. First of all I want to come back to what you said this morning
concerning the Repertory that there are too many rubrics and too many remedies in every rubric.
Wouldn't be very interesting to collect your experience and to publish a new Repertory?
-What I will try to do, I will try to do this.
Because there is somebody who has offered to subsidize such a project.
There are some people, especially in Germany, who are very hard working
and very meticulous and I have some ideas concerning the Repertory.
I collect also Karim who spoke about the Repertory. Karim is one of the team I'm thinking.
I'm thinking of another two persons from Germany, myself and Schroyens,
the one who collected the information about the Repertory.
We make a team and I have invited them already to decide on certain guidelines
that we have to follow to make a new Repertory.
This idea actually I have put into action by writing letters, communicating with these people,
and trying to bring them together and together with the finance here,
who will finance such a project?
And we see if we can do a better Repertory.
It's absolutely necessary to clear the Repertory and this Synthesis is now quite good
but not good enough.
And if they keep on taking information as it's just produced, it's no good.
We have to screen the information and we have to evaluate the information.
We have to have a team that can do that.
They have the knowledge and the energy to do this screening.
So I try from all points of view and of course I work but I can try
that maybe in a few years time we may have a better Repertory.
But it is necessary absolutely, the same way like the Materia Medica.
I'm writing the Materia Medica. You think the Materia Medica,
ah George has it all in his mind, he sits down and writes the Materia Medica.
Neither it's possible for any brain to see whether this symptom can belong to that remedy,
yes or no?
You remember when I was writing some other symptoms of another remedy,
I said to myself what the hell, it doesn't fit with that remedy.
Then I said to you forget about what I'm saying and then you will find it in the Repertory,
if you remember that comment.
Because this symptom doesn't fit with the nature of this remedy.
But who can do all that for every symptom? There is no brain
who can know all this information by heart.
So we need a system that you get a cured case that confirms that symptom which is there.
OK you take this or you need two cases because it has been confirmed by a clinical experience.
To do that do you know how much research and hours you need? Fantastic.
And then they say why don't you write the Materia Medica?
The Materia Medica in English has sold 400 copies. Let's say I get 10%.
How much do you think I have spent in research and doing these 150 remedies I did so far
and the Royalties that you get from such a project? It's nothing.
So you need to subsidize.
Of course by the School we subsidize the different other activities but you cannot do it indefinitely.
-I would like to come back to these horrible publications we find in Germany
and in different countries.
Wouldn't it be advisable to have some Public Relations Offices in these countries
to somewhat control these publications?
-Unfortunately you can't do that because we are a free planet, free countries.
Anybody can publish anything he likes.
-I know but we should respond immediately. And you can't do it by yourself, it's too much.
There are so many publications and we should respond immediately
and put our own articles into these newspapers. To try.
-Yes but always you need some people who will devote their time and energy
into doing that and these people will have the repercussions of all those who believe...
They say why don't we prove a song? We play a music here and then we have our impression
of what is the proving the song.
Somebody says it's a good idea, why not?
And I say for god shake this is going to destroy and to kill Homeopathy.
The people who believe in proving a song, they say you are so closed and start attacking.
And then I have to sit down and write again by arguments why I said this.
-I don't mean this, also the media in general.
-Yes these are important. That's why I have written all the answers.
-Yes but you can't do it by yourself, it's too much.
-That is true but you have to take action. Once you see that immediately you write a letter.
In the German newspapers this chronic headache article killed Homeopathy in Germany.