-Is it true that you can't repeat Tuberculinum?
-You can repeat Tuberculinum.
The only remedy which I would not give every day perhaps is Lachesis.
Even Lachesis for 2-3 months it might be creating some problems.
-You just said before that Lachesis is the only remedy that shouldn't be given repeatedly
and I'd like to know why.
-Because of some comment by Kent, I have not tried myself really.
Of some comment by Kent who says don't repeat Lachesis.
Though I have asked when I was In India. There they repeat. They repeat high potencies.
Then I asked do you also repeat Lachesis? They said yes.
I don't know. I have not done it for Lachesis.
-I would like to ask you to repeat about Lachesis, how often can one repeat it?
-Especially with Lachesis we have to be a little bit more careful than other remedies
and we don't repeat unless we are sure that there is a relapse.
It is better to wait a little bit more longer, be sure and then you give it, no problem.
Otherwise to repeat Lachesis every day, especially when it's not indicated...
If you have somebody who does not believe Homeopathy, do it.
Give him Lachesis and you write in an envelop what is going to happen to him.
-Mr Vithoulkas about Tuberculinum as well.
I'd like to ask, this is a two year old girl who was given Tuberculinum 30 for eczema
and she did very well.
After one month she gets vomiting diarrhea for about 4 days and then it was decided to treat.
She was given Arsenicum which helped immediately and after Arsenicum
the Tuberculinum came back immediately.
She was then given another 30, a repetition and she got a prolonged
and severe aggravation from that Tuberculinum.
She was then given the LM potency Tuberculinum, which brings the eczema down
but it seems that whenever the LM potencies are stopped, she gets the eczema back.
Could you please explain what is happening?
-After you gave Tuberculinum 30 the second time, she had a big reaction?
-Yes.
-Then you gave what potency?
-LM 1, Q1.
-And with LM1 what was the effect?
-The eczema gets better but whenever the LM is stopped, the eczema becomes worse again.
I would like to know after the acute why was such a severe reaction to the same potency as before?
-It would mean that the acute brought a little bit more down the organism than before.
The acute was quite severe, brought the organism down and that's why she got this strong reaction.
I would suggest at this case to give Tuberculinum 200.
-OK, thank you.
-I have a 35 years old patient. She had an aneurism which broke and she had a hemorrhage.
She completely recovered but what remains is strong pains in her left arm and left leg.
I gave her Arnica C200.
She reacted on this with a terrible headache, which she had then
at the very beginning of this event.
For one week she was so well that we thought it's all over but then she got a relapse.
But I'm afraid to give a higher potency because I'm scared that something could happen.
-In that case because of the previous episode, the cerebral episode,
I would be careful to examine why she has the pain. What is the pathology underlined that pain.
If the pathology underlined the pain is gross pathology, I would not give higher potency.
If nothing can be found and it is a rheumatic pain...
What is this? It is a pain in the arm? In upper arm.
-As she describes, it is inside and she describes this pain like burning metal pain
and cold pain. If in winter we touch a metal, it's burning for us.
-The way that you describe it, it's deep inside.
-Yes.
-It's not connected with the heart?
-No.
-Try Rhus tox. Try 30 first, give a few doses and if it improves, stop.
I would be careful in her case repeating Arnica.
-I have a very severe case of asthma. She is taking a cortisone spray
and she is very bad or she is very weak.
I would like to know what to do because the only symptom is that the asthma is getting worse,
as soon as she stops the cortisone.
I'd like to know how to deal with such a case because I think it's difficult to stop the cortisone.
-What is the pathology of the asthma? She has an emphysema?
The lungs have stopped functioning?
-I don't think it's that far. She is too very depressive but the asthma is getting very bad
when she stops taking this spray.
But in the situation with the cortisone, I don't get any clear symptoms.
-That's true. The main symptom for her is exhaustion?
-Yes.
-You can try Stannum but you have to repeat it twice or 3 times the day.
Stannum 30, three times the day, together with the cortisone and then try
after a week to reduce the cortisone to see if there is any effect.
I would think Stannum and Bryonia, try first the one, then the other, see what happens.
-You said that in children if repeated vomiting the first remedy to think is Ipecacuanha.
-Yes.
-In the case of my son, he is 12 years.
He had a very strong hypothyroidism  after grief and after some month he got Natrum muriaticum
and hypothyroidism  went away.
And now after this he is always vomiting very short and very frequent
and he is very chilly and also fastidious.
In this case would you also think as the first remedy, Ipecanuanha?
-Yes.
-Concerning our diabetic child, is it possible that even if we find the correct remedy
and give it and the pathology aggravates in spite of that, that this is an incurable case?
-If the pathology is really serious and you give a remedy and you see an aggravation,
you always suspect that this aggravation may go on and on and not that it is the end.
That means the patient will die but you have to do something, to stop this by the next remedy.
When the pathology is strong, like the boy that has juvenile diabetes...
This I want to know if his mother has given us today how is the boy?
Can you call her? Call her. Just to give you a report after the Carcinosin.
-I would like to ask about a case. She has headaches since 10 years,
severe migraines that begin from the occiput and neck going towards the left forehead.
She has no modalities only that she needs to lie down quiet and she has to vomit.
There is no aura before the headaches. I have tried Iris but it didn't help.
What are the main remedies?
-The main remedies can be different remedies.
But if she has to vomit and vomiting ameliorates, try Sanguinaria.
In spite of the fact Sanguinaria is more on the right side, try Sanguinaria.
-My question is concerning the layers you have been talking about.
For example I have 4 layers on top of each other and I take one by one away
with the correct remedy.
You said that it is not possible that the organism falls back in one of the layers before.
In Elisa's case we saw that we start with Nat mur, then after Nat mur
we gave 2-3 correct prescribed remedies...
-We gave Arsenicum and then Nitric acid.
-Afterwards she again received Nat mur. Can you please tell me how to understand this?
While she was in Germany she faxed you and you told her to take Nat mur in February.
My question is even though I'm taking away layer by layer correctly,
how is it possible that I come back to a certain point where I started with.
-First I want to ask why she asked me for a remedy by fax?
Because I can't remember all these things.
If you think that I have on my mind everything, the names etc.
One name and then I have the symtpoms, I say to my secretary prescribe.
I read very fast, what do you think?
Now you ask me why 2 years ago I prescribed Nat mur? I don't know.
-I understand that you can't memorize everything by heart completely.
I just want to fill you in.
I sent you a fax in February, 6 months I had had persisting  headaches,
20 days per month and panic attacks for which you have given me Arsenicum
and which they had ameliorated in the beginning.
They were aggravated again and happened twice the week.
The fax I sent you was very long and very precise and Nat mur
which you prescribed for me in C200 took away the panic attacks.
I assume you gave it to me for these panic attacks. That's why you prescribed that.
I had written that my fear was that these panic attacks
could ressemble something like an aura before an epileptic fit.
It helped me very well for the panic attacks, it didn't help me for the headaches,
so I hope we can do something here.
-This is a case of partial action. I could not remember which was the case.
I saw this fax, it was very dramatic and most probably I said to my secretary,
I saw the picture there.
It is not possible for me if I don't know what is exactly the case.
I have to go and look for 5 hours the case to decide, is it possible?
Therefore it was a mistake.
-No.
-Of course, it's a partial action. Actually what was needed was Lac caninum.
This is the right remedy, that's it.
It's a partial action of a remedy, it is not the correct remedy.
You give remedies and you see he is getting better on this or that.
This is partial action of the remedy, not the correct remedy.
The correct remedy has to open up the case in such a way as to make a clearer picture next time.
That was a mistake and by chance it acted partially.
What it did for the headaches? Nothing.
The headaches remained all the same.
-I have a patient, she is 50 years old.
She has a spastic paralysis since she was 2 years old , which was probably caused by vaccination.
She is now coming because of climacterium [menopausal] complaints.
To which amount can I influence this spastic paralysis
and how it can affect the problems she has in the menopause?
-This spastic paralysis you can influence from very little to little.
The menopausal premenstrual syndrome you can influence quite a lot.
But the spastic paralysis is like having a damage, like you miss one leg.
-My question is that if we have 2 remedies in a case like a patient  is already on the remedy
and then you prescribe another one for an acute condition
and the patient is better. For example, let's say Stannum helps my mother.
How soon I go back to Lilium tigrinum? Do I go immediately?
-As soon as the exhaustion leaves and this peculiar cough ameliorated is going out, start again.
But if she stays better, wait, don't do anything.
Your mother's case is also incurable. So we have to keep her stimulated
and keep her the best possible way.
-I have 2 questions.
The first one, if in the repertorization comes up Opium and the patient has diarrhea
immediately after eating, can I give him Opium?
-You can give him Opium yes.
-The second question. I have a patient 9 years old who had tumor to the brain.
He was operated 1 1/2 years ago and I gave him Carcinosin 200, one dose.
After 9 months the tumor disappeared.
-But you said he was operated.
-Yes but they left the tumor there because it was a bulb and when they wanted to take it out,
he may stop respiratory and the heart. And they left the tumor there.
After 9 months the tumor disappeared.
That means the tumor can appear in other place?
-It may yes.
-Or it is cured?
-Maybe it is cured.
-They said it is cancer.
-What kind of cancer?
-I don't know, they didn't want to tell. They give him one month to live and he lives 1 1/2 year.
-These are sometimes happening and I say that boy may belong to this group.
Once they belong to this group and they are operated
and they take chemotherapy and radiotherapy, the level goes down here.
Sometimes it happens. I hope it won't relapse.
There is a possibility for a relapse of course, there is a possibility
of developing somewhere else the cancer, there is a possibility that one day
you may find it's diffused the cancer.
But still it's better than having followed the orthodox treatment.
-I have a 70 years old patient with many symtpoms of Argentum nitricum.
For the last 4 months he has said a very peculiar symptom.
His right side of his body is very sensitive to cold or heat, he feels pain like needles
and only in the right side of his body with heat or cold.
Could this belong still to Argentum nitricum or to some other remedy?
-This is a symptom, when the one side of the body is behaving different than the other,
it's a symptom of Causticum. So you investigate Causticum in this case.
If this person is desiring sweets and is hot, forget Causticum.
If he is cold and not desire sweets, most probably he is a Causticum case
but it needs more investigation. It is not enough that symptom to prescribe.
-I have a question to the levels. You said that 4th level they don't get acutes...
-Mild acutes.
-And in 1st level, people who stay in 1st level all their life they don't get many acutes.
-From time to time they will get an acute and this acute can be with high fever,
strong reaction, they get over it. No danger.
-You can only differentiate because one person has a disease
and the other person doesn't have a disease. Or how can you differentiate?
You say you don't get acutes, that's no good.
But for example my mother never had an acute all her life, she is 89.
-She belongs to the first group where you don't get acutes or very little acutes.
If you get acutes twice the year, a flu and suddenly one year you don't have a flu,
that is a bad sign.
Unless you have become really very healthy, that means you have taken the correct remedy.
Unless this is happening, this is not a good sign to have.
Where in a situation where you say I stayed under the rain, I got wet, still nothing happened.
Where in another case I would have been in bed, that is not a good sign,
unless previously you have taken your remedy which supposed to be the correct remedy.
But if for some time you did not have this acute and suddenly you take your remedy
and then you develop this acute again, this is a very good sign.
-I would like to ask again about the acute. I didn't understand exactly what it means acute.
There are some times that you can get something like a flu which takes one day to finish.
The next day is gone.
-That's an acute. It's an acute but what we call a mild acute.
-I found out that many people after taking remedies have this kind of acute.
It doesn't develop to a strong one.
-Don't take it generally.
Each individual has to be evaluated according to his past, what she was getting
and what she is getting now.
The comparison is that makes the evaluation correct.
-No, I'm talking about people who used to be strong ones and after the remedy
they start to have this kind of episodes.
-If they have stronger acutes, they had acutes but mild, now they have strong acutes,
it's a good sign but at the same time showing that the level of pathology was quite deep.
Because for years they were getting mild acutes. I get a cold but it is mild.
I don't know what exactly happened.
We can have some research to find out why this is happening but definitely
when you go into stage where the pathology is quite serious, the acute subside in general.
As a general idea.
Now if the acutes after the treatment start reappearing it's a very good sign.
Then I said what you have to do, treat or not treat.
-But if it's the other way around, a person used to have an acute strong ones
and more frequent ones and then the remedy is taken and then the acute comes and stops.
-That's a good sign, showing that the person is not down here, it's on the second group
and the remedy is correct and it's minimizing the acutes.
-When you explained this morning about being in the first two and having an acute
it's not a good sign, if you have it immediately. On the other hand...
-I said immediately, if you have immediately an acute it's not a good sign
unless the acute was prepared before even the remedy.
If the acute was prepared, the organism has a prodromal period for the acute.
Always an acute has a prodromal period.
Some acutes have one day or two days, then you take the remedy
and the next day you develop an acute.
-So how you would know? If the person said he felt good before?
-You don't know immediately what that means. You will know in the future.
Because if you go over the acute easily most probably the remedy is correct.
The problem is that the remedy has exhausted more its action counteracting the acute
and maybe a relapse will take place within the next few months.
But it shows that the remedy was correct.
But if the acute is very strong and you are in these groups,
that shows the remedy was doing nothing.
-Years ago I treated very badly behaving youngster.
-Personality disorder.
-Yes, very deep personality disorder. More than 4 years ago.
I treated him with Syphilinum and I repeated the dose too early
and then he turned very aggressive towards a person, he raped an old lady.
Does that have to do with the remedy I gave him? I could never make up my mind.
That was the reason he was raping the lady?
-No I don't think.
-It was wrong remedy, I know it now.
-Personality disorders are deep disorders.
Don't think they are simple things because we call them personality.
Because there are people who live in the society and they have these disorders
and nobody takes much notice of them.
But like the man in England who took the gun and killed several children
and his behavior so far supposed to be proper.
And one day he just took a gun and killed the whole class of his own students.
Nobody paid attention to him, he was a bit strange. That's all.
These kind of disorders are very difficult to treat and when you treat you will see
that you need a lot of different remedies and slowly you will get what I call acutes.
And then even you treat the acutes, still difficult to bring around this person
and make him a healthy individual.
-You consider the vitamin and minerals as a suppression in Homeopathy point of view?
-No, you can take vitamins, you can take minerals. It's like better food,
it can't cause a suppression unless, like this woman who was here from Australia,
you take this kind of not milligrams but grams,
30 grams of vitamin, this I'm very skeptical.
-Is there a remedy that has amelioration during pregnancy? I have a patient,
she has two children, during both pregnancies she didn't change anything else in her life.
She continued working and so on and all her symptoms, she had a severe migraine etc.
everything was ameliorated during pregnancy.
-She is a phenomenon because many times the organism
due to the change of the hormones becomes balanced.
It's like a homeopathic remedy. Then she is healthy. No remedy during that pregnancy.
You don't need to give a remedy.
You give a remedy afterwards if she falls back and you see the changes.
I was not like this and now I'm irritable. You take all the symptoms and you prescribe.
Maybe you reorganize her hormonal system.
-I have two questions. The first one concerns the acute prescription in children.
You have said if a child vomits immediately after eating, then it's Ferrum metallicum.
Does this also count for new borns and infants when they vomit after being breast fed?
-No I don't think. When the infant vomits, especially if it comes out as a piece,
the milk does not come as liquid but in little pieces, then it's Aethusa.
Maybe Lac defloratum, Natrum carbonicum also but the first remedy Aethusa.
-Then I have another question concerning anemia during pregnancy.
Could you say something about that issue?
-Forget it, there is no specific remedy.
Local anesthesia also is possible to antidote, in the dentist.
-I have a question about alcoholism.
A couple friends of ours the man came and told us that his wife was drinking secretly
and we knew this, it wasn't that secret.
So he asked if I could do something ,if she wants to get help.
My question is what potency do I use? Do I go very high or do I go lower often?
-For the one who is drinking?
-When I find the remedy.
-And she is drinking a lot and you want to give the remedy without him knowing?
-No, no, no. If she wants treatment, because her husband asked me if I could do something
and when I find the remedy, will I go high or will I go low?
-You go high and you repeat but the first thing that she has to agree is
that she likes to stop drinking.
If she says you give me the remedy, so I will stop drinking, forget it.
Maybe she will stop drinking for a while and then she will go back.
The will of the person...The same thing with drugs.
When you have a person under drugs, you have to have supporting team to make him decide
that I don't want to take drugs anymore.