-I have been wondering for a long time what is Hahnemann mean with the low potencies
and the high potencies?
-Hahnemann used potencies like 3X, 4X, 6X and at the end of his life reached up to 60.
This was the highest.
Hahnemann was dealing primarily with low potencies and what he wrote mostly referred
to low potencies.
That is why we have said that when Hahnemann talks about aggravations,
he means aggravations because of too much substance given, poisoning the person.
Belladonna 3X, three times the day, for so many grams, then he would observe aggravations.
This is different than what we have today where we took the potencies much further
and we are dealing with entirely different rates of potencies.
-He was working with mother tinctures and then finally he diluted the mother tinctures
and potentised them and this set from the mother tinctures to the potentization,
where do I find this?
-The idea is new.
When Hahnemann thought of succussing or triturating, this was a new idea,
as far as I understand, coming from Hahnemann directly.
There are some people who say that Paracelsus was influencing quite a lot
and Hahnemann was knowing the teaching of Paracelsus.
In Paracelsus there are very specific references to the Similia Similibus Curentur.
That is true. Also there is reference to another way of preparing medicine
it was up to that time.
Paracelsus went further with some ideas which I have not studied Paracelsus
and I can not tell you exactly.
What I know is that he was preparing medicines with very strange procedures.
Now Hahnemann having read Paracelsus, having read Hippocrates
because Hippocrates also was there and having read this army doctor Staul or what is his name,
who specifically to this law of similars, he got the idea finally and then
as he was prescribing mother tinctures he saw of course aggravations,
what he calls aggravations in his Materia Medica.
And then what he got the idea to dilute and then not only to dilute
but to succuss or to triturate.
This does not minimize the importance of Hahnemann discovery.
Because neither Hippocrates, nor Staul nor Paracelsus made a system out of these ideas
and we would have been lost totally today, if it was not for Hahnemann today.
Therefore the contribution of Hahnemann to humanity which has not been yet acknowledged...
It's going to be acknowledged in the future and most probably he will be the man
who really benefited humanity.
You get Nobel prizes, you get Einstein, you get all these things.
All these people who did discoveries, they contributed in destroying the planet.
All the medicines which have been discovered, penicillin has been discovered
and Fleming became a very great man but what we see today is that penicillin in fungus
is circulating the human race. You will see the same thing.
Einstein said, if you explode this, then they exploded and then you see what happened.
And now we adore these people who actually we consider they have contributed
to the evolution of human race but how much they have contributed to the destruction
of the human race.
Where Hahnemann is the only one who has contributed only to the evolution
and to the regeneration of the human race.
Now we are only a few thousands or a few millions who know that
but I believe in 20 years most of the planet will know about the contribution of Hahnemann
and then they will realize.
And that's why in Washington, in a big square there is his statue
and this year it's very interesting that the American Institute of Homeopathy,
which is the oldest Medical Association of America, they are paying tribute to this statue
and to the memory of Hahnemann. So it starts already.
-This time I speak in German. I'd like to suggest that when he speaks about the smallest amount,
when he speaks about the Q potencies because in the end of the Organon,
he introduces the Q potencies...
-In the last edition. If this was written before, that doesn't mean about Q potency
because Q potencies were introduced in the last 6th edition and this what you are reading
it was there on the 5th edition.
-So you mean that he only added the paragraph 270 to the Organon.
I never read the Organon edition number 5, I never read it so far. I just had the 6th edition.
So you mean he just added that. In the rest of Organon, he still means the potency
that you were talking of?
-I was talking about 270.
-If we give too strong a dose of a medicine which may have been even
quite homeopathically chosen for the morbid state before us, it must not withstand the inherent
and beneficial character of its nature, prove injurious but its mere magnitude.
This means low potency.
Also in the proving, a paragraph in which he says all herbs, all substances,
they will have an influence upon the human organism, all, as long as they are given
in large enough doses.
Large enough it doesn't mean high potency. It means low potency.
Large enough means you don't kill the person but you go to the sub-toxic state of the case.
And that is how you do real provings.
-I would like to convecture the case of Hyoscyamus.
These cases that we need in our office, in our practices.
You said that the real changes, like the change of temperature, would only appear about
after five months of taking the remedy.
-No. You are not right.
The patient will say, I felt the change five months later but the real change has started
immediately after taking the remedy.
The real change is immediately after taking the remedy.
Now the organism does not feel it, yes but the real change has started.
So where are the changes as far as the patient is concerned?
When he will realize of the different changes but is he attentive enough to know
or to realize that now I can walk on the snow where before I could not walk?
He says something happened, I don't know what it is.
What he is interested is the panic attacks.
When the panic attacks are gone, then he says my god.
This is six months later but this does not mean anything.
The change has started the next moment that you put the medicine.
-Nevertheless I would like to point a question. We have such difficult cases
where the problem is going about 20 years in which case we should inform the patient
to come back only after 8 weeks or 12 weeks? What is the best to do with such cases?
-It depends. There are cases which you may have to see quite soon.
And there are cases where you may have to see after two months.
So there is no standard, one standard.
More or less what we have done in Athens, in the Center, I established a time,
which is one month, the minimum time to evaluate a treatment.
And I found out that in most of the cases I was able to evaluate.
Now some of the cases I was not able to evaluate and it took two months or three months
before we evaluate and in some of the cases we made a mistake and changing the remedy
because we believed the patient.
Many times I have told you tricks where you can trick the patient to tell you the truth.
Because the patient when he comes with a panic attack, he means that my panic attack
will go away. He doesn't need anything else.
Whether his feet are cold or hot, he doesn't care.
So therefore when he comes and tells you I'm the same, he will come after a month
and say, I'm the same.
Then you have written down all the other symptoms and you go one by one and you ask him.
And you see spicy food and you see hesitation.
You used to like spicy food. Yes, I still like.
There immediately this should make you suspicious. How this has changed?
And then you can find little fine symptoms that will point out to you there is most probably
and action and you have to wait.
Especially little things.
It comes someone who has a tremendous eczema and the eczema is oozing
and you are asking, no I'm the same and he looks the same and maybe he is a little bit worse
but he doesn't say it.
But in the meantime you ask you were quite irritable. Yes, I'm still irritable.
And then you perceive in the eyes that he is searching, am I still irritable?
Then you must jump and say, I see your eyes you doubt? Well, maybe I'm a little bit less.
Then immediately you start thinking my remedy has started working already.
Unfortunately Homeopathy is also an art of observation but real acute observation,
not imagination observation.
Because you can stretch something out, you can project into the patient things.
You have to be sure that this is happening. Not, I think he is hesitating.
You have to confirm that he is hesitating because he will say,
oh yes now you are telling me I had a case where I should have been exploded
and I did not explode.
That is enough for you to wait for this eczema, 3-4 months before it goes away.
The remedy acts immediately.
And also depending on the person.
I told you many times I had somebody came from the CIA and he said, I'm the same.
I have the same panic attacks.
And it was something very light and I said, wait second month. I'm the same.
Panic attacks? Yes.
A CIA man you know what it is? Somebody who says, this is a chair, it can not be anything else.
He has to touch, to see, to be sure, they have been trained like this to suspect anything,
everybody. He is a magician, who is this? He is telling me, I'm better?
I'm not better, I'm the same.
It depends whom you have in front of you and on the other hand you may have somebody
who wants to please you and he will say, I'm better and he is nothing.
The remedy is wrong. You have to judge all these things.
A mother who is very anxious, what she will tell you?
She will tell you ever that the child is better? No.
She wants the child to be better and better and better. She will never admit it is better,
especially when we are dealing with psychological problems.
The mother always is very anxious, my child is it going crazy? Yes or no?
So she will not give you objective but you cannot say, you are a bad mother
or you do not know what you are doing. You have to judge yourself, the anxiety of the mother
and how much she gives you information. And base the description on details.
Is he going to school? Oh yes, he went to school.
But you told me he was not going to school in the morning, now he goes in the morning.
That is enough for you to wait.
-A patient had a lot of hematomas and swelling on the face
and I was very insecure to give Arnica or Hypericum, the more important remedy
and I tried to find out from the patient which is more painful and he said, I don't know.
I looked up in the first aid book for homeopathic remedies
and they said give the remedies alternatively and I wanted to know was that OK,
is that correct or not?
-In emergency cases you can do whatever you like.
Especially when you have somebody there and he is lying down with a brain stroke
or a heart stroke, you have to act very fast.
So nobody will accuse, if you bring back this case, that you gave three remedies.
I gave three remedies because I had no symptoms and I thought 3 remedies
and I gave 3 of them alternating.
Now in your case I don't know how severe it was the case because I have been
in the same case exactly. Rather worse.
Because my wisdom tooth had stuck on the lower jaw and when it was extracted
by a severe operation, the dentist who was holding the tube to suck the blood,
she fainted twice.
The dentist who was not a young dentist because he was quite aggressive, an army doctor,
cutting bones, cutting this and that.
Then just to give you an example he said, be careful this is the nerve, don't suck it.
The nerve had been uncovered, it was passing from the trigeminal gland,
it was uncovered and was full of blood and she was sucking and said,
be careful this is the nerve, don't suck the nerve.
And she fainted and I was sitting, totally exhausted for 1 1/2 hour.
When I came out, I was bruised up to here and on Monday I had to give a seminar.
And it was Friday and I said, I'm so stupid, why I did that on Friday?
I could never imagine that this was a major operation and I was in that same situation,
I took one remedy after another, it doesn't matter.
On Monday I had to be back, so I could speak or I could survive.
So I took Arnica definitely because it was black all this.
It was black and my neck was swollen and it was Bryonia, Arnica, Hypericum, Calcarea phosphorica
and Magnesia phosphorica and Hevla lava and what else? Whatever.
On Monday nobody believed this that I had all that. Still is on video.
I said OK, it's an emergency case. Shall I wait for the action?
No, you don't wait, especially this type of operation.
But I will tell you something.
If the bone is cut and infected, which will give you pains like lightening
because of the bone of the jaw, then one of the best remedies is Hecla lava.
But if you give Hecla lava in the beginning, it will not do anything.
You have to have the Arnica, repeated Arnica.
Next.
-Two short questions. One is about Berberis. We weren't quite sure.
We wanted to confirm one symptom of Berberis.
Is it true, you said they can' support feeling lonesome. Is that true?
-It is true but it's not a keynote. In the examinations I will not give you this.
-The other question is when Hahnemann writes about narcotics
which make a stronger second reaction, than other remedies,
didn't just mean Opium of Nux moschata or what kind?
-By this time I believe he means all the derivatives of opium, hashish, cannabis, morphine.
-Thank you.
-Next.
If you have a very old patient and you treat him and give a high potency,
most probably if your remedy is correct and he does not have the possibility to cure,
he does not have the possibility to make an aggravation, then most probably
what will happen is that the remedy will suppress the situation.
I believe that if we had the possibility to do a double-blind studies
where people who need a transplant, half of them would go to Homeopathy
and half of them would go for heart transplant.
And find out the time and the quality of life after the two treatments I think,
I cannot prove it now, but I think with good Homeopathy, homeopathic treatment
in severe heart cases will be much better than heart transplant.
The life expectancy will increase and the quality of life will be better.
-The size of the dose is depending on the action of the size of the dose is connected
with the Avogadro number.
Meaning everything about 23X it does not matter how large or small the dose is you give,
whereas everything below D23 does have an effect on how large or how small the dose is?
-I would even go lower. More or less this is correct but D23,
which is if I'm not mistaken D18 is the Avogadro number. D23? OK.
In this case we suppose to have one molecule. It doesn't matter.
So therefore when you come even lower, you will have very few molecules left,
in which case they cannot really poison the patient.
So even the 12D, I would say, it would be the time where it doesn't matter the amount.
If now you give of course this kind of potency, the amount here is very important.
Here you have to be careful not to give too much.
-In 221 or 223 of the Organon, Hahnemann talks about treatment of acute mental cases
or acute mental disorders.
The question is, is it also your observation that if you treat an acute case
of a psychological disorder, that it is always necessary to follow this with a second treatment?
Hahnemann calls it antipsoric treatment but of course we know this not only as psoric
but is it also your observation that in all cases a second following treatment is needed
to prevent a relapse and then it acts better?
Hahnemann clearly states if you do not let the second treatment follow
the first acute treatment, then already a very minor cause can lead to relapse,
which then it might be much worse than the first acute that you treated?
-My experience and what really happens is that during an acute psychotic episode,
you may need 1, 2 or 3 remedies before you can get over it.
After this when the patient comes back to his senses, you need to take the case
and to see if you can find the remedy underline or whatever happens after the acute episode.
Then it is much better, if you find the remedy, then either the episode will take place
much later after 3-5 years or it will not repeat itself.
But if you just treat the acute insanity, during which maybe you are prescribing
also the underlined constitutional remedy there might be.
So the case I related to you from the previous seminar, it was a case of Mercury.
You said syphilis is there because of the Mercury.
Then she goes into that state in which she brings out a picture of Platina.
Acute insanity, Platina. You will see the sexual element is very exaggerated,
it's not under control and I have to describe to you a little bit but it is rather embarrassing.
You can imagine the Platina being not controlled. The sexual element is loose
and therefore cannot control and I could see for instance in this woman...
she would do movements, which are sexual movements, that's one.
As if she was having a sexual intercourse and then everything was happening
around the area of the genitalia. That was not all.
There were men who were holding her and at a certain moment she would grab the man
or she would do... I don't want to go into detail because the main idea is ...
When I arrived I had Platina and two people were holding her and I said, let her.
She immediately brought down my zip and tried to grab me and the men hold her again
and I put this Platina and the people who were holding felt immediately the loosing up.
One of these people because they were holding in shifts.
One woman was holding and a man on the other side and she said to me,
you are not the only one.
But it was amazing, she said, I'm amazed I've never seen such immediate reaction to the case.
She went back to England and she was normal.
This Platina was really her underline state? Maybe, which I did not see.
When I took the case here I saw the Mercury and then the Platina.
Both are syphilitic remedies, if you can say that.
But maybe later on a Calcarea carbonica, a Sulphur, whatever remedy is indicated.
But during the acute state you may need 2, 3 remedies before you can control the acute insanity.
And it's not an easy thing I can tell you.
You have to be observant, you have to evaluate correctly the symptoms, the signs,
depending on the education of the person.
What kind of education she received from home, how much she was controlled etc.
And you have to evaluate the sense because we don't have a sedative.
Just to give a sedative and forget about the details.
Platina 10M.
-One of the main problems in our clinics are problems of the metabolism of the fat.
50 to 60% of all the population of the western world have problems with their cholesterol
and if you look where this originates, the problem of the metabolism of the cholesterol,
then you either have missing or defected enzymes or missing or defected receptors.
Which means that actually homeopathically you can do nothing because missing organs
you cannot replace with Homeopathy.
In our practice even though patients are treated very well, I see only marginal
or no change at all concerning the cholesterol levels.
Of course your attention is there and you have to pay attention to this
and if you read that if you give medication to lower the cholesterol level,
this prolongs the life expectancy and here I come to a conflict.
If I treat them chemically, I can't treat them homeopathically.
If I treat them homeopathically, that means that I ignore the risk of them
developing arteriosclerosis.
Now I think that with Homeopathy, I come to the conclusion that maybe
the positive effect of the homeopathic treatment would be that the patient
do not develop the arteriosclerosis, meaning they will not have any deposit
or residue in the arteries.
But it's no problem with the patient who comes to me and say what I do
with the high cholesterol and tell them there is no problem but when they get a brain stroke
or heart attack. So what would be the possible action of Homeopathy even though
the blood produces cholesterol to prevent the patient from having arteriosclerosis?
-The question of cholesterol is not a simple one.
It is for many reasons why cholesterol will raise.
It has been found out through research that, for instance, if you get angry the cholesterol
will rise, if you get anxious the cholesterol will arise, if you eat badly the cholesterol
will rise, if you are missing some enzyme the cholesterol will rise.
What you are doing or how you are treating with such cases where you have high cholesterol?
First of all you try to find out the correct remedy,
if you want to treat them homeopathically.
You give the correct remedy and the correct remedy does everything else
except of lowering the cholesterol.
In such a case most probably the person is doing something or is under
such a certain stress which you cannot handle.
In such a case you will take other measures as well.
That means your remedy has not been able to lower the cholesterol, why?
Because the person continues to eat very badly or because the person is under such a stress
that cholesterol is produced all the time, in spite of the fact that you gave the remedy
and in general your patient is doing better.
So in case he is eating badly, you have to investigate and change the diet.
In case there is a tremendous stress in the life of that person, you will say take it easy.
After all you discuss this matter.
But cholesterol is only one point in the million points,
which are affected through different factors.
So homeopathic remedy will do what it can do and then you have to take measures,
which are auxiliary, which are assistant, assisting your remedy.
My experience is that cholesterol may rise even when you put a patient on a strict diet.
You put him on a strict diet and instead of seeing cholesterol going down, it goes up.
Ask this patient to take 2-3 eggs every day and the cholesterol you will see it goes down.
We do not understand all the mechanisms.
The general question whether you should bring down the cholesterol,
there is no question about that. If you have means to do it, you can do it.
There are chemical drugs, which suppose to lower the cholesterol.
I'm not sure if in all cases will have an effect but if you find a case in which such a drug
has really good effect, you can even prescribe this drug.
But if you try this drug and you see very little is happening, then you have to find out
and correct other things which are happening with the case.
We continue later on.
-George I want to make a remark concerning this fat metabolism.
I also saw that cholesterol you cannot change it very much
but it doesn't concern the metabolism of triglycerides.
Triglycerides you can influence very good with Homeopathy.
I have a patient who had 3800 triglycerides, where the normal is 170
and when you put his blood on the table it was white like on a soup and he is a politician
and he has always to drink.
He is drinking vodka and I told him to stop drinking vodka
and triglycerides went down right away.
Then he said he cannot stop drinking, he has to drink when there are official things.
Now he is drinking and with Sulphur, which is his remedy, the triglycerides are 300.
So I think you can influence the triglycerides.
-Yes you can influence but not in all cases.
You remember a case you brought in Celle, a liver cirrhosis?
-Yes, I never heard anything from him. I thought of him and I wanted to check
if he is still living but I lost track of him.
I have another question George. I have a patient with Parkinson and he is doing very well
on Causticum but there is one symptom, it's a symptom which goes with Parkinson.
It's typical for Parkinson.
They want to start walking and the impulse from the brain does not go to the leg.
He has to wait until 1-2 sec until he can start. That's the only symptom that has left.
-Cocculus.
-And do you remember the child which I asked you?
With convulsions, you take blood of him and he only cries 30 sec later.
He doesn't feel the pain right away and you said Cocculus and it's almost healthy now,
no more convulsions with Cocculus. Thank you.
-In which patients do you prescribe small remedies?
Are they any rules indicated [...] especially looking at this week where we have been dealing
with cases where [...] an exotic remedy.
-I've never given an exotic remedy in my life.
Small remedies sometimes you will need it once in your life time
but then what you have to have is enough information about these small remedies.
We don't have enough information.
A good thing if people would wanted to do serious work, would be to reprove small remedies
instead of giving us all this lunatic symptomatology.
When I was practicing Homeopathy, what I mean you have to understand.
I started 8 o'clock in the morning, I was not alone, I had 1,2,3 doctors, then 5,6,7,8
and I would go around and prescribe.
The rate of success was really fantastic.
That means when Bill Gray came on 76, he said I want to stay one month to observe
what's happening. He sat next to me all the time.
I asked every patient who comes back to speak in English first.
How do you feel? Can you speak in English?
The patient would say very well, very well, very well and Bill would hear very well.
He says your practice is boring George and then of course he decided 2 years later
to close his office and come and stay 2 years and learn Homeopathy.
Because he said I have never had this experience.
Of course by this time treating Greek people who had not been yet degenerated
to the point that American people were degenerated already by excessive drugs,
the cases were much more easy and much less complicated.
You cannot imagine what a difference it is between somebody
who has not taken chemical drugs and a lot of injections and vaccinations
with somebody who has taken a lot of drugs, a lot of vaccinations.
You cannot imagine the difference, the cases become clear.
During this time when I was prescribing for thousands and thousands of cases,
I calculated I prescribed for 150.000 cases, I never needed an exotic remedy.
So learn first this, treat 99% of your patients and then the 1% once you have learned all that,
you go and learn the exotic remedies.
But don't be fools and believe that by wasting your time,
studying the imagination of somebody who wanted just to write symptoms,
you are learning something in Homeopathy.
You are not learning, you are just wasting your time.
This discussion should go to the internet.
-In Kiev there was an alarm due to radioactive pollution of the air
which resulted in the nuclear catastrophe that happened in Chernobyl.
There were huge forests fires North of Chernobyl which to Chernobyl
which led all the radioactive material and dumped it over
Kiev. Is there any possibility to protect oneself?
-No, there is no way. Not homeopathically.
You take a nylon, you put it, you close it and stay there for a 3 days
and instead of dying from radioactivity, you die from loss of oxygen.
-I remember something you have mentioned concerning healthy food.
In some magazines I have read that soya beans are now being planted in huge fields,
very large areas and that for harvest helicopters are flying over these fields
and let down some agents which are similar to the agent [name]
which were used in the Vietnam war, which takes off all the leaves of the trees.
But the huge machines which they need for harvesting the soya fields can more easily
go through the fields but for people who try to change their diet
because they think it's healthier, they are influenced by this poison.
-It is true that this is a result of globalization.
Globalization as an idea is not a bad idea.
If the rich and those who have, they care about those who do not have
and they are poor but globalization has degenerated into rich becoming more rich
and the poor becoming more poor.
In order to become the rich more rich, he has fantastic fields of soya beans
and he finds it easy to spray with the helicopter to make the corn easy.
Unless we understand as human beings what we are doing to the planet,
to other human being, forget it.
The drive for profit is so great that it will be inconsiderable of anything terrible
that happens in the planet and we have to understand this first.
That primarily what is important is to have a quality of life
and the quality of life is not only to have a lot to eat but to have less and more quality.
-One of my problems is I don't know when I should take Hahnemann literally
'word by word' and where not. I have been confused.
-What paragraph are you talking about?
-For example chapter 157, paragraph 157.
-What is your problem?
The other symptoms of the homeopathic remedy, which are often very numerous
being in no way applicable to the case of disease in question
are not called into play at all.
Is this what she is asking?
-She says Hahnemann says do not take these symptoms into account...
-No, I will explain what it says. I understand the question. The question is wrong.
She has not understood what Hahnemann says. When I explain, she will get an answer.
Hahnemann says here that you give a remedy which has Sulphur, 2586 symptoms in
the proving.
You give it to a case and he explains that if you give it to this case,
out of 2586 symptoms of Sulphur, only 10 which are in the patient will be active.
All the others will not be imprinted upon the case. This is what he says.
-Would you allow reflexology in her case or only Homeopathy?
-Yes, no problem.
-I have a question to the Organon again.
-Which paragraph?
-Paragraph 161. I wonder is the initial aggravation depending on potency or not?
As far as I understood the paragraph, Hahnemann says it is depended on the potency.
-To explain what he says or you have a specific?
-As far as I understand Hahnemann says that aggravation is depending on the potency.
If you give high potency enough, there is no aggravation. If you give it too low,
there is aggravation.
-In order to understand this paragraph, you have to understand the idea of Hahnemann
concerning the proving.
He says if you give this kind of potencies in a proving,
because this is what he was giving more or less, then we have two actions.
One primary action and one secondary action.
The primary action is what this poison for the organism is doing.
The secondary action is when the organism tries to get rid of the poison.
So there are two phases, one primary action where the effect of the poison
and the secondary action which is when the organism tries to correct itself.
In this case, in the paragraph 161 he says that if you give low potency,
especially in acute diseases, you will have the primary action.
That means you will have the primary aggravation of these remedies.
But now he says with chronic cases I found out that if you give a 'proper' potency,
he calls it 'proper' and this proper potency is given every day and it is given every day
in a higher potency, then you will not see the aggravation.
So he talks about the quintecimal  potencies here and the and the dilution.
And he says I found the way not to have the aggravations.
That is by the time of Hahnemann and by his observation it was somewhat correct.
I believe he has found some cases in which still he would get aggravations from this
but he was experimenting.
Hahnemann was experimenting all the time, till the end of his life.
Therefore today that we have a different type of diseases to treat,
which they have gone very much deeper,
to deal with such diseases with the quintecimal potencies without an aggravation
will be almost impossible.
That is why, let us say 50 years later, when Kent came into the picture,
50 years after Hahnemann, he spoke about the aggravation from high potencies already.
That means Hahnemann was treating different type of diseases with low potencies still
and mild potencies.
Today in order to handle cases of this type, that we have today,
we have to go high potencies and we cannot avoid the aggravation.
It is very interesting that when we did a research in our practice with two of my students
we found out from our cases that about 82% of the cases were prescribed,
there was an initial aggravation.
We presented this research to the Congress in 1970's and there came Prof.Ortega
from Mexico, who either because he wanted just to be opposing, controversial,
he got up and said I have never seen an aggravation.
He was supposed to be a follower of Kent, he was a Unicist and suddenly he said
I have never seen an aggravation.
Then there was some articles written in the Journal of the American Institute of
Homeopathy by that time and of course I didn't want to be nasty but what I said
if you ever seen an aggravation, have you ever seen a cure?
And you can practice Homeopathy without an aggravation but have you ever seen
a cure? That is another question.
So there was this idea that from time to time somebody gets up
and makes an over statement 'I've never seen an aggravation'. So what can you say?
Are you practicing Homeopathy or something else?
-It's a family, he is living in Germany and he is 44 years old
and every day he has great difficulty of having stool.
He needs 3-4 hours the day to pass stool.
-Because of pain?
-Because of an bothering urge here in the abdomen.
The urgency of stool is not felt in the rectum, it is felt here in the abdomen.
He has to sit, the stool is not dry, it is soft.
-He has to sit 3 hours to bring down the spasm?
-Yes.
Because he has a constriction feeling in the rectum and this urgency is too much bothering.
So he has to sit there and to hit himself to get out the stool.
-I understand.
-Another very interesting thing is if he drinks, he makes like this.
I have to demonstrate because it is unbelievable.
It comes up the gas or I don't know what.
But it is really torturing him every day and he cannot...
-Tell him what he can do for Homeopathy if we cure him?
-He does not have big connections.
-He is a poor man? OK we cure him for nothing.
-I tried Nux vomica and initially...
-Forget. What else?
-I tried Alumina.
-Next?
-Nat mur.
-Next.
-Causticum.
-Next?
-Magnesia muriatica.
-Next.
-Sepia.
-Next?
-Collinsonia.
-Next? No next.
What happens in this case is like this.
-Also Argentum nitricum.
-That's the correct.
What happens in this case, if you understand the pathology, you understand the remedy.
What happens in this case is wrong peristalsis. Instead of going... it goes back.
And the remedy is Asafoetida.
Everybody is happy with Asafoetida?
-Yes.
-You don't like it? You gave Asafoetida?
-No, I thought about it and I read in the books that it has the wrong peristalsis
only in the esophagus. So it was partial...
-What is this? Esophagus? It is one digestive system from here to the rectum is one system.
But your question was to show you how a homeopath should think.
In this case you think about the pathology, what really happens and then the remedy comes.
The issue of symptomatology or use, it appears during aggravation as appears
and then disappears.
How much weight do you give this during evaluation of the case and the repertorization?
If a symptom appears after the remedy as an aggravation,
the symptom goes away after few days,
then it has the following value.
If the symptom belongs to the pathogenesis of the remedy, it confirms your prescription.
That means the remedy was correct.
If it does not belong to the pathogenesis, if the case is cured, that means
that the new symptom that appeared belongs to the pathogenesis of the case.
If the new symptom appears, without the patient being cured, it's a useless symptom
which you don't pay attention because you don't know why it appeared.