-If someone is taking a medicine for high blood pressure,
is it necessary to repeat every day the homeopathic remedy?
-Sometimes yes, you have to repeat every day.
-Besides the allopathic medication?
-Besides the allopathic definitely you have to repeat.
-In the beginning of this teaching, I get a little shock in hearing your emotional blockage.
It really shows that a good indicated chosen remedy cannot heal blockages in emotional level.
-Blockages yes but the type of blockages I'm talking about it's difficult.
I'm sure you can cure most of the blockages.
You try to heal somebody who is in depression
and that somebody has a problem in the family which is not solved.
All the time, all the day they see the problem, they live with the problem
and the problem affects them.
Because you may live with a problem but don't see the problem.
You accept the problem, you say no problem but if the problem affects you
and it is there in your family all the time, then this can become a blockage
which does not allow the organism to go forward.
-What can we do to help such patients with such blockages or what would you do in such a case?
-I would recommend other means like Acupuncture or Psychotherapy or whatever.
I'll tell them yes you do it.
Sometimes these people they have to resort into chemical drugs or into prescription drugs.
Especially the husband syndrome.
The husband syndrome is a very dangerous syndrome
and you may end up taking Valium or Tavor.
-I would like to know if you ever give patient consolation,
how he should behave to better his condition.
For instance in the case of Sabine how we had seen that she didn't behave well
according to her fever, you didn't say nothing.
I would like the concept behind if we ever give consolation to the patient.
-Consolation is different. Consultation, advice it depends.
If I feel that advice is needed, for instance I will tell them don't go out tonight and tomorrow.
This in Sabine's case I would say don't go out to eat. She will feel quite good by tonight.
You may see her in the restaurants. This is not good because the organism may relapse.
I will tell them not to and I know that the correct remedy creates an idea that I'm well now.
I feel well, why should I stay inside?
This is misleading because the organism is very weak and it can be overturned
and relapsing very quickly.
-One very important question concerning aetheric substances, like thyme,
like sage aromatic. We discussed it several times.
-Aromatic I cannot say but there are some people who are sensitive to certain aromas
and these they should avoid. But in general the aromatherapy they put in the body an oil.
I have no experience, I cannot really tell.
-We discussed whether ouzo is an antidote?
-It depends how much, if you drink a bottle like this, most probably.
-I would like to clear something about Palladium.
Did you see cases of Palladium that they did fish for compliments and also praising themselves?
Saying what they think about themselves, that they are OK.
-They have to be very progressed, very much going to the mental.
He thinks he is the best basketball player. But this is almost mental.
They can think it and maybe they can say it in a way but not overtly.
If they do it like this it's Platina. They can imply it.
-According to you Americans can now drink decaffeinated coffee?
-Yes according to the GV. I would produce a GV coffee.
-You would make a fortune more than remedies.
-Who is speaking? The American spirit.
-That ice cream that has coffee in it, even small amounts or yogurt or candies?
-Small amounts in cold drink or in ice cream it's OK.
-You have made millions of Americans happy.
-I hope millions of Americans will take Homeopathy.
-Just out of personal interest could you please explain to me what you mean
with being eligible to take exams? If you are not allowed to practice in your own country?
-Yes. Those who have the legal right, this is a condition which was said from the beginning.
Those who have the legal right to practice in their respective countries
are allowed to take the examination. Otherwise they will just take a Certificate of attendance.
That means if you are allowed legally to practice in your country,
you are eligible to take part in the examinations.
I'm not eligible to take part in the examination because in Greece only medical doctors
are allowed to practice legally Homeopathy.
-I don't want to do any splitting but I'm Dutch and in Holland I'm legally allowed to practice
but at the moment I'm living in France, where legally I'm not allowed to practice.
-So you are not eligible. You are eligible to practice only in Holland.
So if you want to practice in France...
If you bluff me and you say I'm practicing in Holland and I'm allowed
and you take this Diploma and you go to France.
In the Diploma we will write underneath that this Diploma does not give you the right
to practice, it gives you only the confirmation that you know Classical Homeopathy.
The right is given by the respective country in which you practice.
We will write this in the Diploma.
So if you want to take examinations, you will take examinations because you say I'm Dutch
and in Holland I'm allowed to practice and I want to take examination.
The Diploma will be valid for Holland.
-You said it again and again that you believe in the institution of marriage.
Two people living together and of course you also said that if they cheat each other,
this is not very good but if they build a true love, this is better.
Could you a little bit elaborate more on how a man and a woman
who live together may help each other to remain in health?
Do you feel that by living together they can be more healthy and it what way?
-This is really a big issue and it cannot be answered immediately.
It depends on the culture of different nations first.
The second is when we say marriage, what do we mean?
Do we mean a decision and whether this decision for one or for both means bondage,
not marriage. This is not good and unhealthy.
There are people who live very well together without being married.
I knew a couple like this, for 10 years they lived beautifully
and suddenly they decided to marry and in 2-3 months they divorced.
They didn't want to see each other.
They were living for 10 years, each one living in his own house, they met together,
they did everything together, they were very much in love, sexually very good.
They got the idea of marriage and they married and the whole thing is finished.
From my experience in looking upon the different nations and understanding
what is happening with human nature, I have come to the conclusion
that a marriage can hold only if the two parties, not only the woman,
come together for the first time and they have sex for the first time together in the marriage.
In such case the marriage will stay.
You feel very secure in the situation of the marriage and the pleasure is quite good even
if there is no very much chemistry.
If we had societies that could restrict the young people from going into sexual activities,
when they were 13 or 14, we could have marriage that would stick.
When I was in America in 80's and it was a class like this, I said how many of you
have been divorced once?
The whole class raised their hands.
As you go towards more to the South and you reach India for instance,
out of this class perhaps two would raise their hands even today. What is the difference?
The difference is that these people don't have sex before marriage. This is the big secret.
Whether you believe it or not, whether you want to accept it or not,
whether you feel this is regression or going back to the Dark Ages,
I don't say that we have to go back to the Dark Ages and forbid sex. You cannot do it.
But the people who managed to retain themselves and not going into sexual activity
before marriage are the most lucky people.
They are the people who are going to live a harmonious marriage life.
But if you have learned from young age to go with one girl, to go with one man, check this,
check the other, in the end it's nothing for you to say bye, bye, I don't like you.
Because you are used to this idea before.
Also this society may develop eventually into such a society because either the society
has to degrade and die or it has to regenerate and understand consciously
that these values have to be respected by the human beings.
You cannot destroy all values that we consider as values in life.
You cannot because you are going to pay.
You can not destroy the laws totally and say I don't care, I have the power.
Which power? You are going to die.
When you come to me trembling from fear, the death is near. Where are your bombs now?
Everyone is under these laws, so society will understand eventually
what laws has to respect and then you will see another society all together.
A totally different from the society we have today.
And then I can tell you something, I will be dead long time before this happens
but I can predict, in such a society the young people will fall in love with the right person.
If you wait long enough, holding back, the emotions become stronger and stronger
and you will recognize, you will have the innocence to recognize the real partner.
And the society will be another society all together.
Now what happens?
You make the first mistake too early, then you are bound to make the second mistake very soon
because it's very painful, you have to get out of pain.
And how you get out of pain? You get another boyfriend, get another girlfriend.
Then how you get out of this pain? Another and another and you reach marriage
with this experience and both the individuals, they have become individualistic.
But marriage says I give you myself and you give me yourself.
You give up the idea of I'm the strong part. You give up!
How can you do it unless you are innocent?