-Kent described in (?) if the patient has (?)
-So in a case of tuberculosis, tuberculosis in young age, you gave Sulphur.
The question is... Did you understand the question?
What Kent meant is actually when we have tuberculosis,
gonorrhea is dangerous to give Silica or Phosphorus or Sulphur?
Because these remedies, say Phosphorus, has the tendency to break up the arteries
and bring up a hemorrhage.
The tubercular also has a tendency to break up arteries and bring up hemorrhage.
So it may speed up the process but not when you have in the past.
20 years ago, you had tuberculosis and now it is indicated Phosphorus
but you cannot give it. You can give it.
Or Silica or Sulphur, there is no danger.
In our experience we found that there is no danger at all,
neither to bring up the tuberculosis of the past.
What may happen is that if a person was Sulphur in his young age
and he went into another remedy and he was Arsenicum and then during that time
he had tuberculosis and he needed Sulphur...
and tuberculosis and the Sulphur picture went away and Arsenicum came
and you give Arsenicum and this layer goes away and the layer of Sulphur appears,
that does not mean that tuberculosis will appear.
What it means is that during that stage he had the possibility to get again tuberculosis,
that means if he stresses himself, if he does not sleep for certain days,
if he does not eat well, if he goes to over exertion...
The predisposition is there for tuberculosis at that state but if you give Sulphur
you take away the predisposition as well.
It does not mean that you turn up the tuberculosis per se but that state which admits tuberculosis.
He cannot admit tuberculosis at that level.
One of these remedies (?) then he can admit tuberculosis again.
I've seen it in one doctor, where he came for his stomach.
He had vomiting and asthma and ulcer and he was given Phosphorus 10M.
Then 2-3 years he was doing very well and something happened to the eyes of his child
and he took it to the ophalmologist to examine it.
So they examined it and either by mistake or by wrong diagnosis, I don't remember now,
he was told that his child was going to be blind.
He stopped from work on a hospital for tuberculosis.
For 2-3 nights he could not sleep, he was in turmoil that his child was going to be blind.
He did not eat, he did not sleep, he had excess work in the hospital.
Within 20 days he came down with tuberculosis.
What happened? He took (?) and (?) which is the allopathic drugs for tuberculosis.
Eventually he developed some fears, fear of killing his child actually and other fears.
The X-ray shows on the upper point that through allopathic medicine hadn't reduce it
in spite of a few months of treatment with allopathic drugs.
I prescribed Sulphur on that state and I think it was Sulphur 30 every week for 5 weeks perhaps.
And fears disappeared and the fear went away.
In the meantime he was fainting, he was afraid to give out the pus
that he had retained for 3 months.
(?) under Sulphur, he was continuing with anti-tubercular drug also.
This thing disappeared and what is most important is that the fears went away as well.
The other remedies were suppressing that (?) where with Sulphur,
both this and the fears went away and he stopped taking any drug
where they usually keep this treatment for one year.
-I don't believe this observation of Kent.
I don't believe that if you give the right remedy, because in this case I gave him Sulphur.
I believe that if it is not so much indicated, it's not exactly and if you give Phosphorus,
you may create hemoptysis.
That's the problem. Phosphorus is not indicated, the person is ready to have hemoptysis,
you give Phosphorus, then you speed this up.
Because Phosphorus acts only on the (?) and breaks them down.
So you break it more easily and then you have the hemoptysis.
Silica also, it breaks up this, the organism tries to insist, to reduce this.
Silica has the tendency to break up the tumors.
So if it is not indicated, it will tend just to break up, instead of helping (?)
but if it is indicated even in acute actual tuberculosis.
As long as we are sure, we can give it.
-Who can be sure?
-Because the time I was in your position, I was very young in my practice,
so I took a case of tuberculosis and I took a dose of 30.
Then I go home and I said, what have I done? I could not sleep quite in my house.
So I went back because to the home of this man and I said I think I gave the wrong medicine.
Give it back to me. And I was afraid to give it.
Sulphur is the same.
But I was afraid Sulphur for tuberculosis?
It's better to ask the questions here because the more interesting questions are asked outside.
So I have to answer and here is one person but here the whole class will have the profit.
They have this person and let's suppose that you have to give in the center here the similimum,
then you give other remedies, what do they do?
Say, they are sitting here. This is quite far from the similimum, nothing...
There nothing, there nothing...
But he has a pain on his left arm and you shoot here and this pain is taken away.
But because you did not shoot here in the center, that it is replaced by another pain here
or another pain there.
Then you shoot again, try to find the similimum, you shoot there, this pain goes away.
That pain on the knee and you shoot there and you shoot there...
But if you shoot here, here, here, then you may take a lot of remedies.
You may take some remedies, which may have some effect, which is local.
But you will not be able go to the center and cure the person from the inside.
Especially when we have the psychological amelioration.
This is a great, great instrument of measuring health, joy of life.
If you see people having joy of life with any pains, better don't give anything.
If you have somebody who has a pain here, a pain here...
but you examine the person and psychologically is well and his energy is good
and he is enjoying life, he has joy of life... don't give anything, give placebo.
-If you give a remedy which aggravates for a while...
-You give a remedy that aggravates for a while or for long term?
-For a few months.
-For a few months it aggravates the psychological state without amelioration?
That you shouldn't have because it goes towards the center of the human being...
without bringing about a curable reaction.
The provers... this person is a Pulsatilla person.
Pulsatilla will cure but Calcarea carbonica for this person is here.
So you give Calcarea carbonica.
This person also will prove (?) It is here.
He cannot prove Sulphur, it is here. He cannot prove Mercury, it is there.
The closest the remedy is, the more the effect upon his organism.
It needs Pulsatilla, Calcarea carbonica is here.
He has fear of insanity, you give Calcarea carbonica and the fear of insanity becomes worse.
Plus now the person is putting on weight more easily.
Plus that person that goes on warm side, because being Pulstila, now starts from (?). But is not cured.
-To close this case you should wait or should get the totality of the symptoms (?)?
-The thing is that you can't wait because the patient says I'm this, I'm that...
They complain, so you take your second chance.
-If you have a different remedy and you have very,
very strong aggravation of almost all the symptoms, is it possible
that you have picked the right remedy that has aggravated that person so much that it is difficult
that you see the amelioration on the psychological side?
-Yes. The aggravation can take place also on emotional or mental level
and it can last for some time and then you are more able to assess
whether this is being to have amelioration.
It is best to wait for one and a half month, two months.
If you see that the aggravation continues for 2-3 months, then forget it.
It's a close remedy.
-I have such a case that for (?) has to do something for him.
So I (?) and (?)
What happened is that she did (?) to her former state but (?)
and disturbed aggravation from (?). I could see some amelioration.
-That means that if you waited more, the person would have such signs
and would have been better without (?) You will find an amelioration.
-You said a single dose of the remedy cannot (?)
-(?) and you give it once the month, once the week, once a day and once every hour.
Every hour you give one single dose.
The way you say it is not very clear, the way I said it is one dose every month.
If you say one dose every three hours, that means another dose every three hours in one week,
21 remedies. That is going to do harm.
But you give one dose and wait the whole month, what happened?
You evaluate and because the person is nearly well and needed another remedy (?)
But give every day another remedy, it's a bad practice.
You give the remedy at the time but you have to give it and see what it does,
whether it affected any change and this change you take into consideration.
These changes do they indicate another remedy?
Sometimes when we feel it's the wrong remedy, it produces a state of the next remedy quite clear.
For instance you give Arsenicum and it doesn't actually help the person.
He says I'm the same but what we see is changes indicating Sulphur.
So you gave Arsenicum and then you have Sulphur, Sulphur, Sulphur.
That's very interesting because without Arsenicum you could not see Sulphur.
You give Arsenicum, it does not help but produces a new state which indicates Sulphur.
You gave Sulphur and then the cure comes.
-Also if you keep (?)
-No this is not heat (?) It is a paragraph on the Organon...
-Arsenicum is a very cool remedy.
-The cold person becomes warm. This is the change of Arsenicum.
When a person is cold, he cannot take Sulphur, you give Arsenicum, then the person changes,
he becomes warm and then he can take Sulphur.
Which is the part of the Organon which talks about this case?
-One sided cases.
-One sided cases, one of these paragraphs...
-67.
-172.
-He gives ideas when you don't have the real picture to give a remedy,
then it is best to give (?) and then the real picture will show.
-If you make one person cold...
-No.
Actually the person to start with (?) which is rather a cold remedy,
eventually goes to Calcarea carbonica state...
It takes Calc. carbonica and becomes cold and then there is a big change.