-Looking at the amount of the questions that you are put, first thing that comes to my mind
is that I need another seminar to answer the questions.
The second is that I left you with too many questions.
-First question is which remedies are the most suitable to soothen the pain,
which arises after an operation, with which for example a lung
is taken out in relation to cancer?
-Well if I knew that I would be the most popular man in medicine.
It will depend after an operation.
You don't give a remedy just because there is a cut.
The pains of an operation usually will not last long.
If you have pains that will stay after the normal period of the operation
that they should stay, then what I would do I would take the general state of the patient
and prescribe according to the general state, not according to the pain.
We have remedies like Staphysagria for instance, even Ledum
but I would not base a prescription upon these legends.
Mostly, if we have to be effective in such cases,
we have to take the whole symptomatology at the time of the suffering.
We have to take everything that is possible to make a good recovery for the patient.
At least I have not used Homeopathy in that way.
I have knowledge about different remedies but I never used them in this way.
For these kind of pains, these kind of remedies.
I don't want to give you that impression ever.
-When the teeth have a lot of amalgam with a high potential difference,
which you can see in electro - Acupuncture how far is this blockage for homeopathic remedies?
-I have had certain people practitioners, especially in America,
talking about this problem with amalgam in the teeth and there is a differential
on the potential and there is some pain, which is appearing.
But I do not have the experience myself.
Those people that they have given me the information said it was blocking really
the treatment and they had to take all the fillings out and refill them with gold.
But this is not my personal experience. It might be so.
-Could you give us a list of remedies you think of in a person characterized
by the word 'workaholic'?
-I'll give you.
Aurum will be one, Nux vomica will be another one, Tarentula will be another one,
Kalis, the Kali carbonicum especially, the Kali bichromicum.
For different reasons it depends what you mean workaholic.
Sometimes the desire for work has to be excessive, too much, to take it as a symptom.
Because in the society in which we live and under the conditions in which we live,
we tend to work on a very fast pace.
So I would not consider that as a symptom, unless it is very excessive
and more or less these remedies can be considered.
It doesn't mean that one of them will be indicated.
-There are several questions about the companies who make homeopathic remedies.
So there is the question, where do your remedies come from?
What factory or which firms do you recommend?
-You are asking me to stick my throat out so that somebody can cut it.
This is a big question for me also.
In Athens initially we used the Nelson's medicines, when Mr Every was in Nelson's pharmacy.
Mr Every was a person that was killed in an accident where several English homeopaths,
the most prominent died actually, died in a crash airplane accident,
going over to the Congress around 1970-1. He died during that accident.
He was responsible for preparation of homeopathic remedies in Nelson's.
Nelson's were quite reliable at the moment I was using it and by this time we bought
and we used in Athens from Nelson's pharmacy.
The story I hear is that they had remedies, the high potencies,
from Boericke and Tafel in America, in Philadelphia.
Most probably they were old remedies of Boericke and Tafel that they have kept
and they have repotentised. I'm not sure now what is the situation.
What I would like to see is repotentising of high potencies to very high degree, like 10M,
50 M etc. I would like to see somebody who would do it all over again.
And he will take the responsibility and he will say I have done it, you can try
and test these remedies. I would like that to happen.
I hear there is a new firm who is arising in Brussels and they say they have done it.
I don't know, I have been just given a few remedies to try them.
Another good source I would say is Borneman of America up to 200.
I have tested the remedies as well and they are good.
Ainsworth is the same as the old potencies of Nelson's, I don't know how he repotentised.
All these are kind of secrets that if you go and investigate, they are not very happy
and neither you can know what is really going on, unless you take the remedy,
you applied it, it works and then what you can do if the remedy works and works really,
you put a red mark on the bottle.
So you know, otherwise you forget.
This remedy that you prescribed 1M from Carbo vegetabilis it works.
Put a red mark in that bottle. So you know next time that this bottle has acted.
In this way you can have some reliable remedies.
It is a very big problem with the high potencies because they cannot be detected
whether they are potent or not. Only if you give it to them.
Last year in America I had this experience.
I prescribed in a class, somebody felt very ill in a class
with symptoms of Carbo vegetabilis. We were having in the hotel of the Conference.
So I prescribed, I said you are having Carbo vegetabilis 1M, he was given
and he was put in a room upstairs.
After I finished the class, I went to see him because he was really very sick,
he was almost collapsed as he was sitting there, with vomiting, diarrheas etc.
One hour after when I went to see him he was not better. I said how you are?
He said I'm the same.
And he said because he knew Homeopathy of course, I think I'm Arsenicum
because I have fear of death. He tried to persuade me that he was Arsenicum.
I could have believed him also because he is telling symptoms but for me
this case was Carbo vegetabilis. So I say how it does not work?
So by chance that day I have been given 200's from Borneman and I had them with me.
So I take 200 Carbo vegetabilis, I give it to him and say take this
if in 10 minutes you are not better...
Because these remedies if they are acting in such severe cases,
the man was completely exhausted, almost dying there from exhaustion, from vomiting,
he was in a terrible state.
The remedy must activate quickly in such cases.
The more severe they are, the remedy is correct, then it will act.
You don't have to wait for hours.
I said in 10 minutes if you see no difference, take Arsenicum because he was feeling cold.
He took Carbo vegetabilis 200 and within 3 minutes he came back to life.
One hour later he was driving back home, it was 50 km away.
And I had given 1M and it didn't work.
And the people who gave the 1M, they said it has worked before
but it has been spoiled in between the process.
The first 1M I gave it was nothing, the remedy was finished.
Because the remedy definitely was Carbo vegetabilis, I could see Carbo vegetabilis,
I could see it so much as to insist.
Usually I know what I'm doing. So this is Carbo vegetabilis, why it doesn't work?
But most people they don't have that kind of experience, so they are not able to check
and I understand that.
With me it's a little bit different. When I give a remedy and I say this is a typical case
of Nux vomica, it has to act. If it does not act, I take another potency, lower, higher
and see what happens.
In this way we may find eventually some remedies which are good but not in another way.
At this moment the pharmaceutical companies have to compete very much and they have
to produce reliable remedies in order that we feel secure that the remedy that we give
is a remedy and therefore if it has not acted, then we go to another remedy.
But at this moment I'm not sure.
I give another case. In America I prescribed a very difficult case, a mental case
I prescribed Phosphorus 50M because for me it was Phosphorus, clear.
I prescribed 50M Phosphorus and the practitioner comes and says it has acted a little bit,
it has changed a little bit. I don't think it's the right remedy.
The way it was described was as if I had given a 12C, not a 50M.
Like acting for a few days and then back again.
I said OK give again 200.
200, a big reaction and the patient got a very curative response.
He was very sick, which for me it indicated that this 50M was not potentised properly
but it was put in -what they call- a fluxion continuous that they have here the remedy 12X
and they inject water with force.
The water goes through and potentises this and after two hours they say
this has been shaken 50.000 times, so this is 50M, take it. You drink it. It's water.
-You explained that the mental base of a human being cannot be changed by Homeopathy.
It can only take away the disturbances that have come during the life.
In your book you have written something about the relation between homeopathic treatment
and the karma of human being.
It was one of the pages I did not understand quite well.
Sometimes I see children who start their life full of troubles, I see they are not happy
and they suffer more than they should be.
This has something to do with the karma they are suffering from
and can we treat that form of basic unhappiness in children?
-I don't remember where I wrote about the karma.
There are different questions here. I don't understand very well the question
but I put another question to you and as it has been put to me several times.
I will tell you also what I meant. If I wrote something, it must be to that import.
The question is, many times I have been asked this question.
If suffering is a means through which a person has to learn certain things,
if suffering is a way of involvement, a spiritual kind of involvement
for the human being he has to suffer to understand certain things and then he can proceed,
the question is you come as a homeopath and you give a remedy and stop the suffering.
What is your right to do that? That's one question.
Do you have the right to do that or you stop the spiritual progress of that person?
That seems a legitimate question. The answer is that
we are healers and our mission is to take away suffering from the people.
Therefore we have to do the best to our possibilities and abilities to take away
that suffering from that person.
Whether this suffering will be really taken away or not is not a matter of concern to us.
What we have to do is to apply to the best of our abilities,
the best knowledge we have and we have the duty to learn, as much as possible,
this science in order to be able to be effective.
Will everybody be cured? That's another question.
In my practice I have seen several things.
Just as an observer, the persons came, asked me for a remedy.
He confessed to me that he has done a murder, sometimes they confess,
they want somebody to talk, they have stolen things, they have done all kinds of broken laws
and then you are thinking shall I give him a remedy? Let him suffer. He has killed people.
He suffers, it's good. No.
We cannot judge if he suffers still.
What we must do is to find the remedy and I'll try as much as I will try with an angel
to cure him. If an angel was in front of me, it's the same effort. My duty is to relieve him.
Whether he will be cured it's another thing because I have seen certain cases
where I have given the right remedy and I told them also don't drink coffee
or don't take other remedies etc. Severe cases.
I remember a case of pheochromocytoma.
For those who don't know the word, it is a malignant tumor in the suprarenal glands,
which as a main symptom has the rising of blood pressure, very suddenly,
very high and the people are constantly under the threat of having a brain stroke.
The man came. He was a teacher and the treatment for that disease is surgery.
The man came and the doctor who took the case, he comes to me
and says he has pheochromocytoma.
So I go inside and say sir we cannot take your case, I'm sorry.
He says why? Because you have to be operated, this is the normal procedure.
We cannot act because of the consequences and you know the consequences.
He says yes but I have not decided to make the operation.
I said this is your decision and I tried to go away.
He calls me back, he says please I'm going to die if you don't treat me.
Because I'm not going to take the operation, I'm afraid so much,
I'm afraid I'm going to die during the operation, so I'm not going to take the operation,
so please. He pleaded and pleaded to take his case.
So I said OK I will take your case. I sit with the doctor and it was a case of Staphysagria.
I prescribed Staphysagria 10M. He was taking antihypertensive drugs.
I stopped this and I gave the Staphysagria 10M. It was a beautiful reaction.
The blood pressure went down, the man was living outside of Athens
and what happened is that one day he got a cold and instead of trying to communicate with us,
he went to the doctor. The doctor said you bronchitis, you have to take antibiotics.
He took the antibiotics and soon enough the whole syndrome started again.
After the blood pressure was up, he comes to Athens for a second interview,
he tells all this, how well he was and how he took the antibiotics
and after the antibiotics it was a relapse.
We prescribed again Staphysagria and again it works.
It brings down the blood pressure until he develops an abscess on his tooth.
He goes to the dentist, he treats the abscess, the dentist tries to kill the nerve,
he uses a lot of injections for anesthesia and one day coming out of the doctor's office
that he has been a few times, he fell down with high blood pressure.
The blood pressure shoot up again.
They take him with the ambulance to the hospital in Athens.
They knew the diagnosis and the hospital was roaring against me.
Vithoulkas, pheochromocytoma, he tried to cure you. The whole hospital ...
So he got so scared, in the hospital he didn't say a word about what has happened.
Anyhow they said we must operate you. They took him, whether he wanted or not,
he was operated. During the operation it was found not exactly pheochromocytoma,
it was found a kind of malignancy but it was not exactly that malignancy
which they expect usually in pheochromocytoma, which to me it shows that
it had started already a process of recovery.
And unless this man had not stopped the treatment, he would have been well.
Now this is what I call karma. This is not my responsibility.
His karma was to suffer and to go through all these experiences.
This looking backwards, I would say this is his karma.
Like another man many times you give a remedy, he does something and he antidotes
and he does not come back to you.
He says nothing happened because I was well only for 3 months and then
the whole situation came back and he does not come back.
And after 3 years, after going through many other doctors, they come to me again.
They say do you remember I had come 3 years ago and for 3 months I was better
but then I took this, this and that and then I had a relapse
and for 3 years he was suffering.
I give again the remedy, it works, we explain to him that he should not antidote.
He did well. Now for 3 years that he was suffering, was my fault?
Was I deciding whether he should suffer? Somebody else was deciding. This I call karma.
His fate was to suffer another 3 years.
This is most probably what I write and what I feel concerning this question of karma.
The children they will come suffering. I will try everything to stop suffering of the children.
Of course. There is no question about that.
Whether the child will be corrected or not it's another story all together.
I have seen autistic children, very severe mentally ill children.
Some they have stayed for treatment for years.
We have a child from 67, 18 years, he is 25 now.
He is not completely well but he can live in the society.
He does things with his hands, he can buy things, he can talk.
He stayed 18 years in treatment. Other autistic children one time, no effect, they go away.
This is their karma, this is what we call their karma.
I'm not deciding whether I shall give the right remedy or the wrong remedy or because
you have been a murderer I'm not going to give you a remedy. This I've never thought.
It has never crossed my mind. People come and say how do you do that?
This man has to suffer but I'm not a judge,
I'm not god to say whether he should suffer or not.
-How can the illness AIDS be cured with Homeopathy since there is a state of weakness
and hardly any felt symptoms?
-This is also what I have said that treating AIDS is going to be very difficult
because of these reasons. Because we have very few symptoms and only weakness.
Before we can make a verdict, before we can say that we can do something,
we have to have an experience, we have to have an experiment with such 100 people.
I have proposed many times and I have spoken, the BBC had come
and made a film last month on my life, my works and there I had spoken
and said publically that we in Homeopathy are willing to make and experiment concerning AIDS
to see what can be the effect of Homeopathy on AIDS.
And it's my belief that it will be the best possible treatment.
If there is a possibility for 10% of these people to be saved or 20% or 30%,
I don't know at this time but I believe because we stimulate the immune system,
we help the immune system through Homeopathy, this is the main thing we do.
I believe this is going to be the best way of treatment but at this moment
I cannot say definitely we can cure.
-Can you say what a rubric in the Repertory means 'pulling of hair' and what kind of
pulling belongs to Lilium tigrinum?
-Pulling of hair is an impulse to pull the hair of somebody who is near you.
Pulling the hair is an impulse, like we have so many crazy things that
in the human race. That's one of these crazy things, especially long hair and...
It's an impulse, let's pull this. The other one has the impulse to spit, they cannot hold it.
This is what it means. Pulling the hair it means an insane impulse.
You cannot say that the person who has this impulse is insane
but to pull the hair of somebody is a 'natural way' of letting your emotions to be expressed.
-Can we speak of blockade also when an organ is extirpated like the uterus?
-No, I don't think that this can become a problem because the uterus is out
as long as it's not an important organ. The organism can work quite well with one kidney.
You have one kidney out and it can be a very healthy person.
Of course if you take both kidneys out, it's another story.
But always it will be left with some sensitivities perhaps.
The person will be more sensitive to say urinary infections,
more sensitive to throat infections, if you take away the tonsils.
They are performing some function but what about the appendicitis? No problem.
-What are your experiences in treating hypertension?
-Hypertension has a different etiology if different people.
The etiology is not always the same.
We have a hypertension which we call it idiopathic hypertension, that means
there is no pathology behind it and it is without reason the hypertension is high.
We have very good results in such cases. Hypertension is a big story.
I think it has been misunderstood because who really has hypertension?
It is a big question that sometimes is not answered properly by the doctors
because you take a blood pressure and it's high...
You go to the doctor, you take the blood pressure and it's 170, 180, 190.
Is this hypertension? No. It might be because you are stressed at this moment
that you're having hypertension.
Real hypertensions stays quite high all the time. That can be the result of a stressful life.
Such cases what I have seen is that they are shooting up to 190, 200 back to 170.
Then you give them treatment and the whole range comes down from 15 to 18.
That is a good result, without any medicine then the organism can tolerate very well
that range because there is a different tolerance for each individual in hypertension.
I remember a case of an old lady, she came to the office
and we measured the blood pressure, it was 250.
And usually the blood pressure was 240-270 and she was 78.
This woman lived to be 86 with hypertension. We managed to bring it between 23-24.
That was the normal range.
She was having some symptoms when it was shooting up to 25,27.
She would have numbness, headaches etc. She lived to very old age.
I had an aunt that she called me once and I went to see the blood pressure
and the manometer went 25,26,27,28,29. It was pumping. I said lie down, no problem.
Just lie down. She was terrified and for the last 10 years
she had not taken the blood pressure because when she was in a hospital,
they took the blood pressure, they say 25,26 and it was a young doctor.
He said my god the other lady last night she had the same blood pressure, she died.
From that point she didn't allow anybody to take her blood pressure again.
I don't want to know how high blood pressure I have.
She was living most probably with 23,24,25 and by the time she was pressed 29.
I didn't dare to go further. The pressure was...
At 29 she was pumping. So I said lie down and I took some symptoms,
I gave some remedy and I normalized the pressure to 22,21,20.
Until a year and a half later a doctor comes next door to her neighborhood.
I believe that nobody will take her blood pressure.
But she got confident that her blood pressure was not very high,
so she asked the cardiologist who comes next door. Why don't you take my blood pressure?
He says but it's 21. You have immediately to take the remedies, diuretics etc.
And then she calls me after 10-15 days, after taking these drugs and says
I'm not feeling well.
Why? What happened? You have to come and see me.
I said OK I come and see her and she tells me the story.
She is an old woman within 15 days, she is very typical arteriosclerotic woman.
She was living happily with 21,22 blood pressure.
He thought that it was too high and brought it down to 16 but with 16
she was completely paralyzed, like an old woman.
Now what can I do? I was afraid to take away the drugs.
If I take away the drugs and next day it's up to 29 and she has a brain episode, she dies.
She died a year later in that state under allopathic treatment
because from 22 it went down to 16.
It was not for her to live in 16.
So all these things they have to be taken into consideration.
There are other reasons, big arteriosclerosis like this one, what do you expect?
The causative factor is different, the result is different.
-Do you stop allopathic medicine like beta-blockers, psychopharmaka,
psycholeptica when homeopathic  treatment starts?
-We do not stop allopathic medicine that can have a fatal effect by stopping them.
We are very careful with stopping the drugs and depending on the pathology,
which is behind, we may stop or we may not stop.
We have different procedures if we don't stop, what we do or if we stop, what we do.
What we give together with the remedy if we stop and then we wait for a month
before we give another remedy depending on the pathology of the case.
Usually unless you are medical doctor, where you know what you are doing,
you are not advised to stop drugs which are pertaining to the heart and also cortisone.
Because you may have a very problematic case.
Severe cases of asthma that they take cortisone, I won't advise you to take up such cases.
You are going to have a lot of problems, very long treatment without much effect and
finally if you manage to cure one of these cases, it has taken away the possibility for you
to treat another 100-200 individuals.
Unless you want to do that, you have the energy to really deal every day,
to be with that person and to prescribe and to go back to cortisone in case of wrong treatment
and then back again to homeopathy, reduce cortisone, bring up treatment.
It needs a great muster to do that in Homeopathy.
A person who is one year, 1-2 years with cortisone, living with asthma, forget it.
-About Dolichos picture. What is the effect of destruction or occupation?
Is there a modality? Does it make it better when the patient is occupied or destructed?
-If you are talking about itching, during the day itching can be less
because you can be diverting your attention. During night it's not possible to do that.
During night all the person is there with itching and he cannot escape from that.
Never mind what you try to do the itching is so severe in the night that it will overtake you.
-What is your opinion about the Volt electro homeopathy,
measuring homeopathic remedies through meridian tests?
-Well, it depends. Different people who are using that machine do claim different things.
I have told to these people if you claim this would you show this to me.
And nobody ever has come and said OK, we have a case, we'll take the case,
the Volt machine will show what is the remedy and I will take the case
and I will see what is the remedy, whether they are together, then I will see something is there.
Usually what these people do, especially in America, it's they have this machine,
they tell the patient to hold the vial and the machine says this is good for you, take it.
Another one, this is also good for you, take this and that is also good for you, take this.
And the person lives with 20 or 30 vials which are good for him through the Volt machine.
I don't understand that, it's something beyond my logic, my comprehension.
How 20 remedies can be good for this man? Maybe one out of these 20 is right
but I do believe that if it is right it is by chance and not by the Volt machine.
Some people they say we can actually detect whether this is a Pulsatilla 10M with that machine.
I say can you do that? OK. Then I will make 10 packages of Pulsatilla.
I will make 1 Pulsatilla 10M and 9 packages of nothing, sugar.
Find me which is the Pulsatilla and if you find it I will be bound to say great
and that machine I will learn it myself.
But nobody has ever come and really challenged in this respect.
So I hear stories where they are using perhaps homeopathic remedies
but according to my understanding this is not Homeopathy. It is something else.
Voltopathy you can call it.
-How to choose a potency of medicine?
-How many more questions?
-About 120.
-How to choose a potency is a seminar by itself because you have rules,
regulations how to choose the potency.
I'm not able to say anything of substance at this moment because the subject is too big.
-Can homeopathic treatment be combined with Acupuncture treatment?
What is your experience on that?
-Not together, they should not be combined together. That means not at the same time.
But if you fail with Homeopathy, you can apply Acupuncture.
If you fail with Acupuncture, you can apply Homeopathy.
If you benefit your patient a little bit with Homeopathy, you may complete this benefit
by Acupuncture, that I understand. But to apply them together I don't understand
because we have to know what we are doing when we give the remedy.
And how do we know if it is from the remedy or the Acupuncture effect
and how to proceed further.
I'm interested to see if somebody I have taken as a patient, after 10 years
he is better than he was before. That is something that Homeopathy can do.
It can make the person better and better and better and this is a scientific process.
This has done with this remedy and then you proceed this is the following remedy
that he needs now.
Shall we go into another group where he is falling, what is the miasmatic condition
which is appearing now? Is it something else?
There are so many questions to be solved in the process.
How can you do this if you are mixing all the time 2 or 3 different therapies?
-How is it possible that I potentise remedies which work on an energetic level,
can be antidoted by material things as peppermint, coffee even after several months?
-Legitimate question but don't forget that if you drink strong coffee
it will give you a lot of energy.
If you drink strong coffee for 15, 20 minutes you may have a lot of energy.
How does coffee changes the energy level? Of course it changes the energy level and
affects definitely the energy and every chemical we put into the body
affects the energy level on which is lying the defense mechanism really.
Behind the immune system, the reticulo-endothelial system,
behind the neurovegetative system, which is called the sympathetic and parasympathetic system,
which we all know this is the defense system of the body, lies an intelligence
which gives order to each one of them what to do and when to do it.
In that energy level we are dealing in Homeopathy high potencies.
But anything that comes to the physical body will affect that energy level as well.
Even the most physical blow, that you can receive a physical blow, the energy can drop
down like that because the organism says drop down quickly. Faint, no energy at all.
Here we have the 3 levels, which are all connected
with what we call the defense mechanism or the vital force.
Any stimulation on the mental level or the emotional level or the physical level
will pass through the vital force that rearranges how the defense should be.
And the defense says you stimulate here with coffee, the defense says
increase the pulse rate on the physical.
Increase the pulse rate on the physical but the increase of energy as well must take place.
Not only that but emotionally you feel an elation and mentally you have a more clear mind.
So actually the coffee affects mental, emotional and physical level for a time,
let's say 20 minutes or half an hour.
After this half an hour, after this initial primary reaction, we have the secondary reaction
of the coffee where we have exactly the depression.
It is like a pendulum. Here the organism is in balance.
Then coffee comes and stimulates. How much it stimulates, it is 30 degrees.
Then in order to find balance the depression will be equal, 30 degrees exactly the opposite.
And then eventually it will find this position of balance after the effect of the coffee is over.
In this process everything takes place including primarily the vital force
or the energy level of the body.
Here is the defense mechanism really, here is the central intelligence that gives order of
what and exactly how it must happen.
-Would you treat a woman taking birth control pills or having a spiral in the uterus
for birth control?
-The birth control pills can affect the homeopathic treatment and can be stopping
the homeopathic treatment.
The IUV does not matter so much unless the woman is sensitive to this device,
in which case she will have constant irritation in the uterus and constant inflammations
with the resulting symptomatology.
In such a case when she is so sensitive, then she has to take it away.
But if she is not sensitive, there is no problem, you can treat.
-In Germany they often say dead teeth are blockage and they have to be pulled out
so that the remedy can work. Do you have any experience on that?
-No I have not seen that, that a dead teeth can be a blockage.
-There are some questions on birth pregnancy and early childhood.
Do you think that it is wise to prescribe rubella for pregnant women
who don't have enough antibodies?
-No I don't know this practice.
-Is it possible to cure a miasma in utero . If so, can you say exactly
what miasma the baby has?
Can you give a nosode when the symptoms do not agree with those of the mother?
Is it perhaps advisable to cure the mother symptoms only?
-The moment that the woman is pregnant and the fetus is in the uterus,
you do not separate between the fetus and the mother.
You only treat the mother and through the mother...
It's one thing up to the time of birth.
You treat the mother and by treating the mother correctly, you treat the fetus.
There is no question about that.
I would say that all pregnant women should have good constitutional homeopathic treatment.
It is a must for pregnant women because definitely it's going to be
an improvement in the children.
We are exactly in the opposite position with allopathic medicine,
where the pregnant woman should not touch allopathic medicine, as much as possible.
On the contrary she must have homeopathic treatment, even when she has little symptoms.
A good homeopathic treatment from a good homeopath, constitutional, just one remedy,
wait and see what happens,  improving the health, is improving of the child definitely.
-There are many questions about vaccinations.
Do you have a lot of experience with the prophylaxis of polio and has this always worked,
even after a few generations that are vaccinated in the allopathic way?
In a case where a grandmother has had polio, will the grand child be more susceptible?
Would you treat that child differently with homeo-prophylaxis?
And other questions with treatment of Thuja, Pyrogenium and other vaccinations.
-Lathyrus for polio vaccinaton...No, I do not have experience
in giving homeopathic remedies for prophylaxis.
We don't do it.
-You showed us a child who was ill in all the plans.
Now, sometimes we give a remedy for a human being who is still on his second plan,
in the emotional sphere and the remedy is very chosen and finally a cancer comes up.
A cancer disease, let's say in the rectum, and I would like to have a few explanation
how this happens and how we should make evaluation of something like that.
Because it's not only once.
-You mean in a child?
-Not in a child, in a person that you cure on the emotional plane
and suddenly it goes ill on the physical plane but in very serious illness.
-Yes, when the disturbance is on mental-emotional level and the general health
of the case is quite low, it might be possible by the disease coming
and focus in the physical body, it produces and analogous state of affair.
That means the disease that was on a mental-emotional level like schizophrenia,
like manic impressive cases, like paranoic cases, these cases as they are treated
and they are becoming clear in mental-emotional level,
they may develop serious physical problems.
Usually in such a case if you continue with the right way the treatment,
usually you can save the patient. You can cure this kind of cancer.
-LM potencies or higher as you repeat for the physical disease?
-You can go quite high.
I don't know if you heard a case of mine that I had with a metastasis of the brain?
Somebody who came with a cancer of the lungs metastasized in the brain
he came from America and I prescribed Tuberculinum 10M.
That case had a beautiful reaction. It was the last stage where we saw the metastasis
in the brain and the metastasis on the bones, where definitely reduced,
the pains were gone completely and the lesion grew bigger.
The force of the disease again came out from the brain,
which was very fast progressing and went back into the lungs.
If you remember this case, I do not know what you would have happened...
He flew to Athens from America and then due to connections he had with the hospital
in Tokyo, he was the owner of a big Tokyo hospital and the general director came over.
Eventually while he was doing very well, he took him over to Japan, put him in the hospital
and we were on the line with his physician who was there.
Finally the American physician who was following him to Tokyo said to me
that the Japanese doctors they wanted to give chemotherapy
because the lesion here was growing, the cancer on the lungs was growing
but at the same time the person was feeling quite good.
I said I don't agree but he said they insist and they believe that if they do give,
the person will get cured.
If you hear that story you cannot say anymore...
So I said OK they can proceed.
They gave slight chemotherapy together with some antigens,
in order to produce some reaction, fever reaction.
Immediately the case relapsed and in one month he died.
And I have seen this again and again and again.
I have never been able to see any kind, when Homeopathy was in contrast
with some other therapy, I said OK this man is not doing enough progress,
why not try this allopathic formula.
I have never seen improvement but I have seen most of the times a regression.
You may say you are an expert of Homeopathy, you are not going to say otherwise. No.
I have seen cases where Homeopathy could not help but in what case?
In a case of pneumonia where it is not Homeopathy that cannot help, it is the remedy
that you are giving or I'm giving is not the correct one and the person is not getting better.
That's not the fault of Homeopathy.
This is the fault of me that I don't apply correct Homeopathy.
In that case I am obliged to give antibiotics. I'm not going to say no, no.
I will show you a case of double pneumonia we had in America and I believe this case
might be here. Double pneumonia, an X-ray.
She has been given different remedies. She has been given Phosphorus,
she has been given Kali carbonicum, Kali sulphuricum etc.
The person was going from bad to worse.
When she came to me she was in the last stage. I was not going to wait.
I said this case is Pulsatilla.
So you give Pulsatilla 50M but by tomorrow if the fever is not down, hospital.
Next day the fever was down, next evening the fever went up again.
Again CM was given 10M, 50M, CM and since that time fever dropped.
When we had the follow up 20 days ago she was much better and there was no question
of pneumonia anymore.
In this case if the reaction was not immediate, that means I could not find the remedy,
I would resort to antibiotics.
But if we knew good Homeopathy, how many antibiotics could be spared,
the whole of humanity that is now ingesting tones of antibiotics.
If we could produce good homeopaths in thousands, you can understand the implication
of such a treatment.
This is last question.
-I was wondering Hahnemann in his early days developed Q potencies and he used them.
The LM potencies, do you use them? When do you use them and what do you see to use
rather than high potencies?
-The LM potencies I don't have an experience, I don't use them and so I cannot comment.
I got used in using these potencies and I know the results of these potencies.
When I treat a case I want to see results.
Because with Homeopathy we say, wait, wait, wait. You are doing well, we'll see.
All these potencies will act as long as the remedy is correct.
They will act much more slowly. I believe they will act.
Also don't forget that the cases we see today are mostly mental-emotional cases.
There is such tremendous suffering in mental-emotional level that cannot be touched
to my understanding by very low potencies. There are some cases in which I go low.
But not LM. I will go 12X or 6X but not LM. I do not have the experience.
I'm not against LM. Don't get it wrong.
I say that the experience I have is with these potencies.
-I have a question concerning cancer.
Over the total population I see a tremendous increase in the rate of cancers.
In future, a homeopath will be confronted with breast cancers even in young children.
Would you recommend still trying to treat these children with the risk of breast cancer
coming out again? What's your feeling about it?
-The only way that they may suppress a cancer is by making the person
completely mentally deranged.
-In the sense of radiation, chemotherapy?
-Once a radiation has been given and chemotherapy I don't feel
that we have any chance with Homeopathy.
It' very little chance to cure with Homeopathy and most probably in all these cases
there is a natural relapse of the case.
The persons may die after a certain period of time, whether you give Homeopathy or not.
-I refer especially to children. There are children who are on the face of death
and they get radiation and later in their life they recover.
-The only case that we can be talking about is cancer of the blood.
In such cases you have definitely possibilities but depending on the type of cancer
we are talking...
The squamous cell cancer is a cancer that develops very fast in metastasis, very quickly.
In such cases I don't feel we have any chance with Homeopathy or any other system.
But there are some types of cancer which are either slow growing or you can stop them
at a certain stage of development. Homeopathy can be useful.
I don't want to discuss the question of cancer because I don't want to appear
saying that we are treating cancer, that we are curing cancer.
In spite of the fact that the experiences show that with Homeopathy
we can have amelioration results.
Cancer cases are ameliorated and perhaps they are more ameliorated than if
they have taken allopathic drugs. But we cannot talk about a cure.
-In general if a case of cancer has been radiated, you would say don't touch it with Homeopathy.
-I will not take such cases.