But the goal is that you look at the page in the Repertory and now listen because this is not the exercise.
The exercise it is a bit more complicated. Please listen two more minutes.
You read on this page every rubric and I expect from you to have any questions on this page.
... you make sure that you understand what it means and second you make sure that
you can imagine how a patient would express this Repertory symptom in natural language to you.
Third, if you look at this rubric maybe you say it is so similar to another rubric, what is the difference?
Or why is it positioned here? Why is it written here in the Repertory?
Any questions you have about Repertory parts of the symptom, you ask them as well.
And for some people maybe the real incentive will be try to find a mistake on that page.
I give everybody 15 minutes to find the page, to read it, to have a question and then I will ask some people to give one concrete remark.
So I will hear what remarks, questions you have and we will go forward from there.
-On 176, chapter generals, sensitiveness externally.
-So you have a rubric sensitiveness, body, bones, cartilages externally, glands internally, medicines, pain, periosteum and remedies.
So you have a question about sensitiveness externally. Can you repeat the question now please?
-I'm not quite sure what is external sensitiveness; it means the person is sensitive to external pressures
or does it mean the outer sphere of the body, the skin, is sensitive? What does it mean outward?
-Anyone has a reply to the meaning, I will complete the question, if I may.
You have a rubric sensitiveness internally and sensitiveness externally. Anyone has a comment to make on these two rubrics?
-I understand this recording to the skin because when you look at the remedies, you see Lachesis for instance.
And Arnica, Belladonna, Apis so that's what I understood.
-Up to now I understood it like the outward sensitiveness refers to things which come from the outside
and influence you just in an external way, like it's too warm, it's too cold, it makes my skin shrink.
Whereas the inward sensitivity refers either to inner organs or to my mind and my feelings.
-Yes you make it more general and I would like to continue the reply, after your reply.
There are several rubrics in generals, which have on the third level - you understand
general is the first level, sensitiveness is the second level - which have on the third level internal and external.
Even swelling and other rubrics. In other cases it is the same, we perceive the environment by the senses
most of us.
What we perceive from the external world through the senses is the external sensitiveness.
Then what we perceive of happening, what is happening within the body is the internal sensitiveness.
I will see if I can find another example.
Trembling, you have the same. Trembling internally and trembling externally.
So people may tell you I'm trembling inside. In this case you perceive objectively what is happening outside
or feeling of trembling but objectively you don't see it.
That is the difference between internally and externally.
Twichings is the same.
Heaviness internally and externally.
So there are many rubrics where these are opposed the internal and the external sensation in general.
It is in this case again a perception...
-I'm sorry. That is one of the rubrics I never understood.
How can you feel heavy outside? It's always for me an inside feeling, Pulsatilla like...
-Sepia like, Lilium Tigrinum like...
This is always the point. You have a certain perception of the symptom and something is related and you say, but I don't understand at all.
Until the day a patient comes in and  says, yes I understand you feel inside. No, no, no it's not what you mean, it is different.
And this is very interesting. So if you have this type of symptom heaviness externally, it is different.
So the internally it is related to the internal organs.
I can have feeling of heaviness in the head but I can have a pressure of heaviness onto the head.
So the heaviness is not in my head. I have this impression of heaviness which is coming to my head.
Just the same in my bowel. I may have this heaviness internally or I might have this impression of a pressure, heaviness here.
I know and you should be aware that probably 20,30,40 % of the people say, what the hell is he telling now?
What is it making a kind of a difference? Because for you it is very logic to have heaviness of the internal organs.
You understand heaviness in the stomach, heavy head.
And you understand it so well that it is difficult to imagine this little difference of meaning.
But this is normal. We understand the Repertory in steps, in jumps.
And suddenly a patient will come and will explain you no, no, it's not vertigo, it is different. I have no vertigo, it is more a sensation that I'm no stable.
You are looking in the chapter vertigo already and it will explain you the difference.
Be aware that again and again you will be confronted with symptoms in the Repertory
always expressions of the patients, more or less the same, which will tell you something you don't understand.
Because we all have certain limited experience of our own body awareness and senses, perception.
But this is the explanation. So internally the senses inwardly.
Externally the senses outwardly.
-(?) because I thought if you are unconscious, you don't have any mental sensibility anyway.
-Yes if you are unconscious, you don't have any mental sensibility anyway, that is correct.
But there is a difference between consciousness and comatose situation.
If you are in a state of coma, you are unconscious.
But if you are in a state of unconsciousness, you are not always in coma.
I will give you an example to make it clear.
You came here, you flew down to Skiathos and you were sitting in a restaurant, drinking some kind of Greek beer
then turning to French wine, because that's what you prefer, then you go in the boat
and they say, Alonissos!
Mamamia where was I?
And this one hour between Skiathos and Alonissos has just come by. You were not conscious of the travelling.
You were not in a coma but you were just not conscious and that' s why in this rubric
we also have a relation to what is called automatic conduct.
You do things, ironing, ironing and ah... it's finished. Two hours. You do things automatically without consciousness.
This rubric, as well, mental insensibility goes in this direction. It is not the loss of consciousness
in the meaning of coma, where you are not only out of your mind but in a way, out of your body
it is more the meaning of not being conscious in a sense of not being aware of what you are doing.
-Like day dreaming?
-Like day dreaming almost but still a step further because you can be aware that you are day dreaming
and you can even be aware of what I'm telling you while you are day dreaming.
You're thinking all the time of Washington and NY and what you saw in television or you missed but you're still aware.
And I think you pay attention, I'm very happy about but this unconsciousness would mean everybody is out of the hall
and suddenly you say, ah it's finished. So there is a gap in the consciousness.
-For example I see the remedy Hyoscyamus and they just sit there and do the same (?)
-Yes it's a lower state of consciousness. It goes inside with that.
You want me to show it? What is the question?
You have self-sufficient impression of importance.
She asked me a question very interesting one. I don't know the page but anyway.
Minds, fear of business. Two remedies.
And she says, this rubric is a little bit unclear for me. What is the fear about? To lost business, to do business, whatever?
I must admit I didn't know immediately to reply to this, so I went to the Materia Medica and I typed the word "business".
You remember the remedy was Lilium Tigrinum and I have 5 symptoms which I will show you.
Here is the full text. You must look at this, loss of appetite with headache, distress of the head
(?) to labor, dread of business in this position to any exertion of mind or body.
So it is the mental effort which is implied in doing business, which this person is afraid of.
I agree that in the Repertory the rubric should be completed a little bit to make it clear, that is it the mental effort of business that Lilium Tigrinum is afraid.
In general, if there is something unclear in the Repertory and I admit that there are still many instances
you go to the Materia Medica and you try to find the information over there.
-I had mind, fear, calamity and then it was explained misfortune.
-Are you sure calamity is there? Fear of evil.
There is an explanation, did you see what I do?
Here there is a little grey square, so there is an explanation of this rubric by our friend (?) from Argentina
and if you click on it, you get the text which explains something from this symptom.
(?) did the work of commenting mental rubrics.
You can read it more easily because I have made the letters very big.
Basically he says that it is very close to the fear that something will happen.
If we must make a difference between fear something will happen and fear of evil
it will be on the color of the story of the person. It's listening that comes in.
He will tell you that he is afraid that this will happen and that will happen etc.
but the color which is different, evil is like black forces, like devil, like some kind of black magic
like super power which is organizing it.
So it's another fear something may happen but evil is more "doum"
In this case you may prefer use the rubric fear of evil instead of the rubric fear something may happen.
-(?) I find remedies there which actually can no do much.
-You can always prescribe them. What do you mean?
-(?) use the larger rubric fear of whatever it is and not so much the small sub-rubrics because they are so small (?)
-Yes, this is a very interesting point and I would like to make little parenthesis on this.
The use of rubric, of sub-rubric or let's say in other way, the super rubric.
If you look at certain places in the Repertory that you find a remedy in blah, blah, blah morning which is not in blah, blah.
Many examples can be quoted.
We will begin historically.
The history is first of all that Kent did not make a mistake, if he said it that way.
Because the idea was that a remedy is added to the rubric mind-fear, if in the proving
or the clinical cases, the remedy has fear, just fear.
And then you ask what are you afraid of? Fear, fear, fear, no modality comes.
It comes in fear.
The other reason which Kent mentioned somewhere in his writings, why a remedy is put under fear
is because it appears in at least 3 different fears.
So if someone has a fear of being alone and of the dark and of ghosts, he has fear.
Three sub-rubrics legitimate the presence of the remedy in the super rubric.
Kent wrote this as such and if you enquire the Repertory on the basis of these two rules
you will say, yes but he didn't do it here and he didn't do it there, I agree.
There are a lot of exceptions. But these were the rules.
Now the second point is that some people advocate the systematic copying of remedies from sub-rubrics to super rubrics.
If a remedy appears in fear morning, it should be in fear, in fear morning waking it should be in fear.
In fear afternoon drinking tea it should be in fear etc.
I must give you a warning by two easy jobs. You take (?) You take all remedies from the sub-rubrics and you make a bigger rubric (?)
That's possible because (?) has quite a few remedies which are not in the main rubric.
But take care because if you look under (?), one of the sub-rubrics is aversion to (?)
which is the opposite.
And if you look in the Materia Medica for (?) for each of these remedies, you will see that some of these remedies
they have aversion to (?) and not (?).
So if systematically you put all the remedies of the sub-rubrics in the super rubrics again you introduce a lot of mistakes
in the Repertory or in the repertorization.
For sure in a systematic  way, it's not a correct way.
Then another way comes and people say, you know a typical remedy which has a desire for salt it is Natrum Muriaticum
and I find that in Natrum Muriaticum they often have aversion for salt.
And I believe that probably this can be generalized, if you have aversion for salt, you have something to do with salt.
So you have an aversion and maybe another Natrum Muriaticum has a desire.
You have Phosphorus with a desire for fish and you have Phosphorus with an aversion for fish.
And then they say (?) they have a problem with (?) so maybe they have a desire to (?)
But the same remedy has an aversion for (?)
And you can go on. I agree that up to some level maybe it's correct to say
Natrum Muriaticum has an aversion and a desire, has something to do with salt, for this symptom for this remedy.
But to generalize this and to say, desire (?) desire rest, aversion to rest, desire to go home, desire to stay home...
restlessness, indifference, it is just extremes of one of the same line, then maybe you need only
500 rubrics in the whole Repertory, you can put it all together and I wonder which remedy you will find.
So I don't believe that you can be following this line of thinking and put remedies in super rubrics because of this.
If you have a proving and several provers they say, I have desire for radishes, desire for radishes etc.
they did not say, they have an aversion.
Maybe the desire is the very interesting point.
If they say, I have an aversion to (?) I think it's game of the mind to conclude that this remedy we can use it
if the patient has (?)
So to copy remedies from the sub-rubric to a super rubric, you should be careful.
On the other hand I must admit, as I told you, that if we look at Kent's Repertory with Kent own rules
that is to say, we put a remedy where it belongs and if it's 3 sub-rubrics
we put it in the sub-rubric, a lot is lacking and we will address the issue with some next version of Synthesis.
But be careful because if you have a symptom like fear of death when alone or fear of being alone when thinking of death etc.
it is a very specific symptom, in this combination, in this sub-modalities. Can you find the remedy?
And it is a typical symptom for the remedy which is there and if you just put it in fear of being alone
and fear of death, I believe the remedy is in both rubrics, yes it's OK.
But the typical point is fear of death when being alone and we should not globalize, generalize everything.
I will speak a little bit about information in the Repertory, Repertory itself.
Everybody is aware there is a lot of interesting information in Materia Medica, we should use Materia Medica etc.
to know the remedies, to confirm the remedies, to differentiate the remedies and so on.
But I want to make you aware that the Repertory carries a lot of very interesting information as well.
Just for the single fact that it has been the result of many people's many years work.
To such an extend that it is even complementary, even today to the Materia Medica.
Also for the simple reason that it is so easily structured, much more structured than the Materia Medica.
Some of you, including myself, maybe they have  done, what we call, extracting a remedy from the Repertory.
You take a typing machine, you go to page 1 of the Repertory and you see a remedy Phosphoric Acidum
and you type the symptom anxiety eating apple. Then you go down the page for the next symptom
with Phosphoric Acidum and you find anxiety fever during, you type anxiety fever during.
Like this you type all the Repertory symptoms of one remedy and in the end you have the extraction of Phosphoric Acid from the Repertory.
What I tell you is that this type of extraction is a very interesting piece of information.
I will show you now in 2-3 min. something which you will repeat.
Write down the instructions stepwise and then you can repeat it to see if you can do it.
The first step is that you decide about a small remedy in which you are interested.
For example I'm looking here at rubric abrupt which contains remedy Rauwolfia.
I will first tell you what I do, then why I do it.
The first step is that I make, what is called, the extraction of Rauwolfia, so I drag for the Radar program
in the Macintosh is a little bit different but I drag the remedy to this icon, which is the extraction icon
so I drag Rauwolfia to this icon.
Second I click here which opens this window and the remedy Rauwolfia is there.
Then don't worry to read all this, just look for extract and you extract the whole remedy Rauwolfia
from the Repertory. In one sec you have the 121 symptoms out of the whole Repertory
it starts with mind and it finishes with generals.
The first step, the first procedure is make an extraction of a small remedy. A remedy you don't know.
If you make an extraction of the remedy...
... and it has 1000 symptoms is too much. You chose another one, one you know even less.
Try to find a remedy which has 500 or less symptoms.
Any questions about the first step? Extracting very small remedy?
The second step is that you will repertorize this small remedy. How do you do it?
You go to edit, select all, all your symptoms become black or blue and then you say
take with intensity one.
If you do this, it will start adding all the symptoms to the clipboard.
121 symptoms are in the clipboard.
Then you repertorize, you know how to do that, and you find the analysis, you take sum of symptoms, of the symptoms of Rauwolfia
which of course brings out Rauwolfia on the first place.
It covers 121 symptoms.
You repertorize Rauwolfia. I repeat from step 0 before going to the next step?
Step 1 - you extract a small remedy. Step 1a - you decide which is the small remedy you want to extract.
Just by looking on the screen and saying this is a remedy I don't know. I take the example of Rauwolfia.
Step 1b - you drag the remedy abbreviation to this icon.
Everybody knows? Someone needs an explanation?
If you have a mouse, you push on the left side, you move to the other icon and only when you are there, you release.
I will show it. I push on my left button and I drag the point of the arrow to the extraction icon and I release it.
Step 1c - I click on the extraction icon, click with the left mouse button and I see this screen.
Step 1d - don't worry, don't read the screen, just look for the extract button.
You click on this button and it's finished, you have your extraction. 1a, b, c, d. This is making the extraction of the small remedy.
Can I go on to step 2 please?
Step 2 means repertorize the small remedy with totality of symptoms.
Step 2a - you select all the symptoms by going to edit it, select all in the menu.
When you select all, your symptoms turn black, which means they are selected.
Step 2b - you take them into the symptom clipboard by going to take with intensity 1.
Step 2b - you take the 121 symptoms.
You know you have succeeded because here the figure 121 appears.
Now step 2c - we repertorize the results and the easiest way is that you quit this window with escape for example
and you hit F8, as you usually do, and you have the repertorization.
I would like to continue now to the third step because I'm not making my point.
The third point is suppose you have Rauwolfia and you never prescribed Rauwolfia or not often
and you would like to prescribe it more often. Here is a way which will help you in a very precise manner.
You see that also the other remedies are repertorized and you see that
next to Rauwolfia is written Lycopodium, Phosphorus etc.
You will now, as a third chapter of this task, you will compare Rauwolfia to another remedy.
So 3a you decide with which remedy you want to compare your small remedy.
I will give the example of Rauwolfia and Lycopodium.
I want to compare my small remedy Rauwolfia I don't know, with the big remedy Lycopodium I know pretty well.
Now 3b we will make the comparison.
What you do is you drag Lycopodium to the extraction icon again.
That's what I'm doing. I open the extraction window one more time.
And now appears not only Rauwolfia but also Lycopodium.
You must read the screen a little bit. I don't exactly the text in German because you must indicate the third option.
It is for all languages the third option.
Don't worry about the meaning, when we do it you will understand.
After you see Rauwolfia and Lycopodium click on the third option which will create a list of common and exclusive remedy symptoms.
Then step 3c - you make the extraction.
Now listen carefully. Now comes the 4th and the main point.
You will need to study a little bit the result of your work. And it is extremely interesting.
Because first you get 80 symptoms in fact which are common to Lycopodium and Rauwolfia
and which mean that for a remedy which has only 121 symptoms, there are 80 reasons to confuse Lycopodium and Rauwolfia.
And that there are 80 chances that you miss Rauwolfia because you prescribe again Lycopodium.
To go of this little speech, it is to help you find the way to not miss Rauwolfia.
If you click on these two arrows, you see the next list of the extraction because at the same go at 2-3 sec.
the program made common symptoms, which are here, but extracted also the symptoms of Rauwolfia without Lycopodium.
These are the 41 symptoms which contain Rauwolfia but not Lycopodium.
And how you will find now a good reason to prescribe Rauwolfia and not confuse it with Lycopodium?
First of all because you know Lycopodium very well and second you read through this list and at a certain moment
in most of the cases, you will find 1,2,3,4,5 symptoms which are opposed to what you know about Lycopodium.
You see for example here... or which are lacking in Lycopodium.
I see here a lot of dreams, drowning, parts of body, teeth breaking off or fracture of jaw.
So there are dreams is dying, accidents. You have a theme you could say, a concept of the remedy which has to do with the fragility of the body.
Which is expressed in these dreams. Lycopodium is not present in this.
Lycopodium does not have this type of idea as the main feature of the remedy.
So one feature of Rauwolfia is these dreams about the body falling apart, deteriorating.
Remember this one.
We read on, we think of Lycopodium while we read these symptoms, we don't know if Lycopodium is relevant or not.
We read pulse, nothing special and we see another symptom, for those who know Lycopodium
a symptom which is absolutely not Lycopodium, sugar aversion. Rauwolfia has aversion to sugar.
How often do you believe you will find this in Lycopodium?
What does it mean? You have your little card on your shelf, in your pockets, in your computer
and you write Lycopodium but aversion to sugar, Lycopodium and dreams teeth breaking off, disease, (?) falling apart ....
In this case you don't prescribe Lycopodium, you prescribe Rauwolfia.
And the 80 reasons, the 80 moments you missed the Lycopodium, you will have a tool to guide you to the prescription of Rauwolfia.
Now everything falls together. You got the logic?