We will begin now with a little chapter on the Expert System.
Not only for interest for those who have the Expert System
but also for everybody attending this course
because you know George is using the Expert System
and maybe I can tell you a few more things, which make it more interesting
when you look at the screen to understand more of what is happening.
First, you have found and you have selected the correct symptoms.
And we have spoken about that.
Obviously there is some kind of variation.
Maybe you put the symptom which is not completed correct
but we have discussed finding the correct symptoms and taking them.
That's one thing which is needed.
Then second, the VES basically works like different people or different visions
looking at the same symptoms, adds it all together and brings forward a balanced suggestion.
However there is one third element and that is the underlining.
I will explain you very precisely and schematic the way of the underlining.
Underlining of a symptom means that we indicate the intensity
which the symptom has from the interrogation of the patients.
A patient gives any symptom, desires "mousaka" and what do we ask was it just now
this morning or you like "mousaka" every day or every time you come to Greece?
No, no mousaka in Greece, mousaka in Munich, mousaka everywhere!
So you get the intensity of desire mousaka. That is the intensity from the interrogation.
Now the first thing is the frequency of the symptom, how frequent is the desire for mousaka
or the pain in the wrist. How frequent it is?
The second element is the intensity.
How intense, especially for everything which is subjective
how intense is the pain in the wrist?
Then when we combine these, you will get a suggestion
on how to underline correctly the symptoms.
The symptoms is underlined once when it is frequently present or intense,
which means when it rises above this level.
You remember the drawing here that the symptom has to rise above a certain level
before it is a symptom?
So the desire for mousaka has to be sufficiently frequently present to be a symptom
or the pain in the wrist has to be sufficiently intense to be a symptom.
Everybody has some pain in the wrist some day. It is clearly present. It is a symptom.
The underlining 2 when there is a relevant frequency or relevant intensity.
It is not just yes I eat mousaka many times.
Now it is I eat mousaka every day, when I'm in Greece, whenever I have an occasion.
It is very frequent, more outstanding.
This is enough to give it intensity 2 in underlining or when the intensity is outstanding.
It's not just correct that it is present the symptom; it is outstandingly present
because of intensity. We give it an underlining 2.
So this is just the symptom is present.
This is really frequently present or really intensively present.
Then we underline 3 times when the symptom is very frequently present and very intense.
It is really overwhelming.
Then you know you have 4 degrees in the Repertory and for some reason
you have 4 degrees in the intensity of interrogation, as well.
The fourth degree in intensity of interrogation,
it is like something you wouldn't believe it could exist.
It is really so strong, every day, 3 lt of milk, every day for years, it is really very strong,
at least for some people.
The fourth degree, as you know, in the Repertory it is seldom. Maybe 200, 250 remedies
which have 4th degree in the Repertory.
In the totality of your patients, the totality of all the symptoms of your patients,
4th degree should be indicated about once in two weeks.
You see patients every day, once every two weeks you give a symptom a degree 4th for a patient.
Then you are not exaggerating.
Because the whole issue is to underline, as correctly as possible.
So 4th degree is seldom.
There are also figures about the presence of 1st, 2nd and 3rd degree
and the idea is the higher you go, the less the symptoms can have a 2nd
or 3rd degree of underlining.
It is something like if 80% of the symptoms have a 1st underlining or less it's OK.
If more, you will get a message when you use the system and you will see...
change the underline etc.
I think for 2nd degree is about 50% and 3rd degree about 20-25 %.
Of course one patient is not the same as another one.
You don't need to think about it. I have already 4 symptoms in the 1st degree,
I must have one symptom in the 2nd degree... You don't have to think about it.
The program will tell you if you go too far, out of the range which is normally accepted.
And it will tell you, change your underlining a little bit or try to understand
underlining in a different way.
I give you some hints further to this to try and underline correctly.
Of course there will be occasions that you doubt between do I underline twice or three times?
Do I underline once or twice?
And you know frequency and intensity are two ways to reflect on this.
There is a third, less important feature, which may help you to decide
between 1st and 2nd or 2nd and 3rd underlining.
That is the peculiarity of the symptom.
If you doubt and this is more common you will underline it 2, if you doubt between 2 and 3
and it is more peculiar you will underline it with 3, to give it more emphasis
because it's more peculiar.
So apart from the schedule, frequency and intensity, the second way is to consider peculiarity.
The third thing you must consider is that different people
express their suffering in different way.
If someone is talking all the time like this, giving a symptom, I had this and I had that...
and you say, do you like bananas? Oh yes, I like bananas you put it very high.
If someone says, I had all the problems of the world, I fell down the stairs
and I went on a boat and I slipped on the boat ....and you say, do you like bananas?
Oh yes, very much.
And what about the mousaka? Yes the mousaka is very nice...
So if put all these in 3rd degree, no good.
And he is talking and in your job? In my job everything is all right.
You've seen that in his flow of intense, so called 3rd degree intensity symptoms,
there was a little hesitation and you know what he is going to tell you about the job?
All the others, maybe you don't even take the symptoms.
Anyway is not in the Repertory falling next to the "flying dolphin" is not in the Repertory
but then what he will tell you about his job, that he has a lifetime,
many years of frustration, ailments from (?)
that is the symptom you're going to write down.
The intensity is relative to the way the patient expresses himself
and that is important as well.
-This system deals with the difference between mind symptom and body symptom.
Is that not special influence of the (?) of the symptoms?
-Yes. I would like to ask if there are questions about the underlining.
-(?) to become a symptom, how would you evaluate if there is a very rare symptom
that only appears once every two months?
-In one person?
-Yes.
It depends but I would say if it is a very seldom symptom, very clear present,
with clear I mean they suffer from it, then even if it appears once every 4 nights,
it is important I would say so.
You can have a headache which is better from drinking coffee,
he has the headache every two weeks only but he drinks even half a cup of coffee
and the headache in minutes disappears, so head-pain-coffee-amel,
even if it happens every 2-3 weeks it is a strong modality.
-Concerning the underlining. Does it happen that remedies are selected by underline?
For example, Mandragora is found in the rubric restlessness.
If I have a patient who is (?) very intense restlessness,
I would use the rubric as a 3rd degree but Mandragora is only in the 1st degree in this rubric.
Does this underlining give any preference to certain remedies and not to others?
-Yes. This is a very good example and I will explain you in the next step,
the reason of the underlining. And it comes down to reply to your question.
If we have a patient and we suspect, say Stramonium.
You know at a certain stage we will ask some confirmation questions to know
if it is really Stramonium. One question could be fear of dark.
So you ask what do you feel in dark? And what is the reply you expect from Stramonium?
Oh yes, in the dark I have to put the light on all the time. Very strong fear of the dark.
Now if you go in the Repertory and you see fear of dark,
you will see Stramonium is in the 4th degree. It is the strongest remedy.
So for Stramonium, it means that in the provings and the clinical cases,
it was very often present, fear of dark in Stramonium.
Now we take this one step further, if we go to the patients and we suspect Stramonium
we expect that each patient has a strong fear of dark.
This is the confirmation of Stramonium.
If the patient has some... fear of dark, this is an argument against Stramonium.
Or it is not pushing Stramonium forward to the maximum.
This is called correspondence of intensity.
So Stramonium has fear of dark in 4th degree, Stramonium patients, for the best,
has fear of dark 4th degree, corresponding of intensity.
And the rule is the better the intensity corresponds, the better case you have for the remedy.
-Just before you mentioned that the degree in the Repertory has nothing to do
with the intensity but only how often it appears in the rubric.
And now for the analysis it is very important to underline according to intensity
and it makes a difference for Stramonium, for example.
Now you refer to the intensity, as if the 4th degree for Stramonium in fear of darkness
has something to do with the intensity, where before you said
it has to do with how often it appears.
-Yes that's correct.
That's why I was trying to escape all morning from continuing in that level.
Because I know it will bring some confusion.
I will now try to clarify the confusion. First step, the Repertory was made.
Why was remedy put in 1st,2nd or 3rd degree?
Because of frequency in proving and clinical case. Everybody agrees?
Then Repertory has been used, more information has been added and in fact a woman,
Margaret Tyler came with this idea and said, it's interesting I see
that for some of the remedies I prescribe, the symptoms which contain a remedy in bold
the patients express these symptoms in bold.
The Arsenicum fear alone or fear in dark, the Arsenicum patient has a lot fear alone
or fear in dark.
And so she brought up the idea that the correspondence in the degrees
was an interesting way to process the information.
That's why I leave this on because another way to look at the symptoms of your patients
is this correspondence of degrees.
You are right, it is in a way opposed because you are using like a tool for paint
you use it to make a sculpture. It is a different application.
But it is a fact and then George has really brought it into Homeopathy
the famous underlining, he really uses it all the time, to that extend
that the VES refuses to work if the case is not underlined.
It is his way of thinking that you must know first of all from the patient,
how intense is the fear of the dark, how intense is the jealousy etc.
Then you correspond the intensity from the patient with the degree of the Repertory
and I will say "whatever has that meant in the past".
I must admit that these degrees in the Repertory is now been used for another goal.
And it is correct. But first is the history and today, since Margaret Tyler,
I think she was active in the 30's, in 40's there is this idea,
especially with George now of correspondence of degrees.
So it's just another idea with which George agrees, that correspondence of degrees,
patient and Repertory, is an interesting way of analyzing the case
and decide for the remedy.
But it is true that it is a little bit gone of the original intention of degrees
and it means also that we will need to reconsider the whole story of degrees in the Repertory.
And we're doing that. In the next version, you may expect some new things about it.
But for the time being it is important to understand that it is true
that if look at 10 Stramonium patients, most of them will have strong fear of dark
and it will be only 1 maybe, who has fear of dark, which is not so pronounced.
And you can repeat this for many examples.
So I explained to you the first 6 methods of repertorization, more or less classical
I told you there is correspondence of degrees, someone else gave me another idea
that there are still other ways to look at information.
So if 2-3 symptoms come from mind and they indicate to Pulsatilla,
it is maybe a different thing than 2-3 symptoms from extremities which point to Lycopodium.
Because it corresponds to 3 symptoms in mind, it's more argument for Pulsatilla
than 3 arguments for Lycopodium because they come from extremities.
Because we say mental symptoms are more important, if they are present
they are real, they are more important.
So the chapter has an influence as well.
In fact I write down 6, 7 maybe 8 rules but they are more.
There are many ways to reflect about the homeopathic information and the symptoms.
What we did with George is made an exhaustive, complete list of all these rules
and for each rule defined the applications and the exceptions
and the possible relation to other rules.
So we have an enormous form with a lot of calculations and you get
what is called a probability rate as the results.
If a remedy is suggested as 1 or 2 or 3 in the Expert System, it is probability calculation.
What is the interest of this?
I have used this case in the morning to explain you a few things. You still remember it?
And I used it in every method of repertorization.
There is another way to look at this. If I click here, then I see the 6 different methods
of repertorization all together in one screen. The first remedies for each of them.
If you didn't remember, you see remedies which are the 1,2,3 and 4th possibility
for each method of repertorization.
Now if we combine all this, some al-chemistry starts to work
and all the elements are added and those who have taken a symptom they know,
if they use the VES which is just hitting another key,
that it is confirmed that Lachesis is the major possibility of this real live asthmatic case.
That Lachesis was given with some results but not with continuation of improvement.
And that the remedy which brought the cure to completion, it was Aralia.
So this is an example of how the VES ...
You had this case, you know it.
So you can tell me the difference between Lachesis and Aralia?
Let's make it in a different way. A person has asthma, Lachesis is the remedy.
When do you expect the asthma to aggravate? Give some ideas.
Aggravation in asthma for Lachesis?
-After sleep, the heat.
-Before menses.
-And another one, general aggravation of Lachesis?
-Waking, after sleep.
-Going into sleep.
-When falling asleep. Lachesis is the remedy when it falls asleep, it wakes up again.
When is falling asleep, asthma comes up again.
So the falling asleep process is difficult in Lachesis, as with the real snakes by chance.
And what is the point here with Aralia? Now you remember?
It is not when falling asleep but...one hour after sleep, after the first sleep.
The point I want to make now is that we have the same symptoms,
as for all the other methods, they speak about Calcarea, Lachesis, Pulsatilla, Silica,
you've seen it all.
You use the same symptoms with a little bit of this more complicated calculation
and you have a nice suggestion for Aralia.
That is what the Expert System does.
I will explain you, as a next point, the figures.
Because when you use the Expert System you need to know what it means
and if it is projected you can know, if George wants to continue, yes or no.
So the messages I believe they are clear.
You can read the messages understand the messages but I want to explain he figures.
Every remedy here, which is projected as a first possibility, has a figure
which we call the absolute confidence rate you may have in that remedy.
And there is just the result of calculations and it may be a figure of 12625 or 6720
it doesn't matter.
It is recalculated in such a way that you can consider that the figure 100 is the ideal to go for.
So when you get closed and above100, it means that there are very good arguments for Lachesis.
That's what it means.
So you will see in the beginning it will be 45, 60 etc. When the case goes on
and it is coherent, these figures will increase to 80 and 90000, it may become very big
if some confirmatory symptoms are added.
But then there is still another figure which is important, the one between brackets.
The relative confidence we have in the prescription.
Now what does it mean? It's a technical explanation for real life.
If you have very good arguments for Lachesis, will you prescribe Lachesis?
It depends. If these very good arguments for Lachesis are only for Lachesis.
Or maybe because of the same symptoms, you have very good arguments for Pulsatilla
which is often close and for other remedies.
So you have very good arguments for Lachesis but still you're not confident
because the confidence in Lachesis is relative, there is good arguments for Pulsatilla,
for Natrum Muriaticum or whatever.
So the relative confidence in a remedy becomes close to 100 again,
if it is outstanding if the arguments differentiate it from confidence
or the arguments for other remedies.
And this is what you see on the screen, which George calls the columns show me the columns,
he says and where the confidence in each remedy is put in a graphical way.
This is the probability for each remedy at this step. The longer the bar,
the more confidence, the more arguments for each of these remedies.
And you see there are two big bars, Lachesis and Aralia
and then Calcarea (?) is a bit less and all the rest still less.
So mainly still 4 remedies are possibility and that is why in this case the prescription says,
100 very good argument for Lachesis but 57 in the second figure,
not absolutely sure it is Lachesis because there are still possibilities for other remedies.
And you look at Calcarea (?) and Aralia.
We look which are the symptoms here, look what I will do.
I will take another Lachesis symptom, clothing aggravates and I will add it to the
previous ones.
If I run the Expert System again you see arguments for Lachesis even better 126.
And it is a bit more outstanding, if we go to the columns, you see the Lachesis
and Aralia are stronger.
So the relative confidence for the prescription in Lachesis will increase.
Nevertheless still take care of these other few remedies.
Another one.
I go here desire for farinaceous food, I add it
and now I have an outstanding case of Lachesis.
253 outstanding arguments for Lachesis and confidence of 111.
Because now Aralia is still somewhere but we have no over powering arguments for Lachesis.
Of course this was not a real case.
I just showed you how typical symptoms can move confidence rate up for a remedy.
This is the way you play with these figures to understand if the consultation
has come to an end or not.
-One more question concerning these figures.
In the beginning you said the first number could only go up to 100
when should be close to 100 or around 100. But now it goes beyond 100.
-Yes I said should go close to 100, when it goes to 80, 90, 100
and above it means good arguments for. So for sure it can go above.
If I add all the keynotes of Lachesis, it will go to 500 and 600.
-I have the same question for the second figure.
-Same reply.
-But how much more less is very sure?
-For the absolute confidence next to the remedy 80 and above.
For the second figure I would say it starts from 60-70. But don't rely on the figures.
If you doubt between Aralia and Lachesis, just say the patient,
I'll call you back tomorrow, you read your little book and you find out from Materia Medica
which is the better remedy.
Don't rely on the figures, don't rely on repertorization. It is just tools that show a road.
-Can you say something about the numbers of rubrics which are,
(?) says that at least 4 rubrics have to be chosen
but maybe there is also a maximum where (?) becomes useless.
-I believe there is a figure, a number of symptoms at which virtually
every repertorization becomes useless.
First of all I agree with you 4 symptoms is a minimum.
We must have some ground on which to stand and then it may be 6,7,12,15
sometimes up to 20 but most of the cases will follow in this range.
I mean single symptoms. Of course one symptom, which is 5 symptoms combined it's not 1 symptom.
This will be the range, you may expect.
If it' much above you feel you get too much symptoms, maybe it's better
to clear away a few symptoms and keep the essential ones.
Then I would like to speak a little bit about the future.
-One little thing. The use of the VES is very important,
as you said already in 91 to start right away, first to use it with the patient,
not when he is gone.
It is much better to use it when he is here and second to make evaluation
every time you have added one symptom.
So you get continuous development of the possibilities
and probabilities for the prescription.
It's very helpful, we should use it this way.
-Yes absolutely. Perfect.