The topic of today is repertorisation, analysis of symptoms and everything you want to know about it and never dare to ask.
When I was preparing this day with you, my wish was that I would be able to say at least one thing to each of you
which you would find worthwhile.
But I had two problems. The first is that I did not know everyone of you
and the second that I didn't know what has been taught to you before about Repertory and repertorisation.
I prepared a few topics and I will speak about these topics before noon and in the afternoon
I have prepared some exercises and we will spread them throughout the day.
But what I would look to request is that each of you reflects to find a question, at least one question
about Repertory and repertorisation. One question, one topic you would like to discuss today
and I will collect the papers at the last by 1 o'clock. Then I will read them during the break
while you swim and take siesta and I will try to move the topics and the exercises and the things I bring to you
even more at the direction of your requests.
So this means that it is also your responsibility if you will be happy at the end of this day.
Start reflecting about the one question you would like to discuss. Some of you may know it already, other ones they will need deep reflection
I will remind you from time to time but it is the one thing I expect from you.
A question in writing. You can write in English, you can write in German or for you in (?)
and I hope this will allow us to cover the topic in a very thorough way.
-There is one question. I don't speak for the class, it's only my question and you have to decide whether to accept or not.
We have in the Repertory some kinds of repertorisation and then you can see what it is, symptom, evaluation, great remedies, little remedies ...
but the specific feature of VES from George Vithoulkas, I'm very interested in.
What's the (?) idea of his VES given in the repertorisation? You can use it and you see the results but I don't know in every step
what's the specific behind this.
-I will offer the rules for the VES from Manfred.
I'll speak a little bit first about repertorising, in a very general way.
I would like to start to ask from you a clear and concise definition of the repertorisation.
Can anyone give me a precise definition?
So you say find the symptoms, evaluate them and there is something lacking...
... combining. Because the point is that every rubric contains a number of remedies.
Repertorisation is combining the symptoms so the common remedies stand out.
I say the remedies stand out, is that clear in German what I mean?
I don't say to add because that' too limited. There are many ways to look at symptoms.
It's not just add.
We have a symptom which contains remedies, another symptom which contains remedies
and we combine them. This is the idea of repertorisation.
The next step is, I don't know if you heard, there are different types of repertorisation
or that at least the word is being used in different contexts.
You have repertorisation, using the Repertory and you have repertorisation of Materia Medica.
You heard about these terms? Repertorising Materia Medica?
Only one person, 2, 3?
I will explain you shortly because my idea was that this concept of repertorising Materia Medica was much more reknown.
As I have introduced it, I will now go ahead and explain what it is.
Some people used the Materia Medica books to computer soft wares, any of the computer soft wares
to create a rubric, symptom with remedies.
So they say, for example, fear of dark. They search fear, dark in Materia Medica, they get a number of remedies
and from this they create a rubric which they use in repertorisation and which is possible because, as we just learned
the precise definition of repertorisation is combining symptoms which contain remedies.
So in a way if they come from the Repertory of from the Materia Medica, you can use the Materia Medica rubric with remedies.
I want to explain and show you a little bit about this because I believe there are some misunderstandings
about repertorising Materia Medica, especially for those who begin to remember and read about it and now realize what it is.
I will first show you how it happens.
In the Materia Medica we have fear of dark.
And when we search, we find for all the different books, the remedies which contain a symptom
with the word fear and the word dark.  A symptom, any sentence which contains as well the word fear and the word dark.
The next step will be to say create a rubric. So we will have a Materia Medica rubric, fear of dark, Lac Caninum, Lyssinum, Medorrhinum,
Variolinum, Camphora, Aconitum etc.
You could then go to your Repertory program, combine this rubric with any other rubric and you have repertorised Materia Medica.
-In our version, when we put the word and search for the rubric, we got the books and we have to look for the word in the books that we got.
-I will show you that you can do it during the break. Don't worry.
But this is not the point I'm making, I'm not talking about how to set up and options of the program.
I'm talking about repertorising Materia Medica. You understand?
I must tell you about repertorising not about option this and ...
I will repeat what I do, I click on this icon. The second icon from the top, I click on it.
Then I get this screen, I type the word fear space and the word dark.
I type two words, then I go apply to all and I have these results.
You may have different results but that's an option in the program and I will show you if you like during the break.
I put two words and it finds all the symptom which contain the two words.
We have a set of remedies, a symptom fear of dark with a set of remedies, we put it in the Repertory to repertorize.
There is a problem.
When you read the texts, so I click on documents
when you read the text of these symptoms, you see fear of the dark, there is much anxiety
fear of ghosts when in the dark, fear of dark, fear of walking in the dark, fear of darkness etc.
for every symptom you read, you get  a sentence which expresses fear of dark.
However when you continue reading each sentence
for this symptom which is Lac Caninum, there is a phrase which speaks about dreams and that (?) troubles by dreams after dark
but that he has a fear of snakes. So in this symptom fear and dark is not present.
It is in fact fear of snakes and something else about dark.
But in the same sentence, the word dark is there.
The next symptom here it says fear of suffocation and the uvula is dark red. So the word dark is related to the color red.
And the fear is related to suffocation.
If I take this symptom into my Materia Medica repertorisation, as a symptom of a remedy for fear of dark
I make a mistake.
It means that if I do a search for fear of dark, before I use these results in the repertorisation
I must read every symptom to make sure it corresponds to what I'm asking.
If I say fear of dark, I must read every symptom, if it contains fear of dark and not fear of suffocation with a dark red uvula.
The people who repertorize Materia Medica, they are not sufficiently aware of that. That is my feeling.
And in this way a lot of mistakes are introduced while repertorising Materia Medica.
In fact the correct way would be to go to the Repertory and check if Lac Caninum, for example, is in the rubric
the Repertory rubric fear of dark and if not to add it.
Once and for once.
And the next time I use my Repertory rubric fear of dark, it contains the correct information from Materia Medica.
And it doesn't contain this remedy which has fear of suffocation and dark red uvula.
So to repertorize from Materia Medica it is first of all dangerous because you introduce errors without knowing.
Second, if you are aware that you must read the symptoms before you decide, the remedy belongs to fear of dark
you have a lot of work. So it is very laborious and you should do it only once for one rubric.
And then possible update your Repertory in a correct way.
Of course you could say, but in my program I can say the word fear and dark must be near to each other
and not too far away. Correct.
That is correct but even when they are close to each other, there is still a chance of mistake.
For example he has a red dark uvula with a fear of suffocation and dark and fear are very close to each other.
So still you need to read.
Someone else may say, if it's a program for two words maybe we can use it for one word.
It's more easy to repertorize Materia Medica.
So I will give you the example of jealous.
I find all the remedies which contain the word jealous.
But if I go to the texts, of course I see all the symptoms contain the word jealous
and most of them I agree, they will fit to the rubric jealousy, correct.
But read the first symptom. Ailments from jealousy, it is different.
Can anyone tell me the difference between jealousy and ailments from jealousy?
Or fright and ailments from fright?
-The difference seems to be the causation. Jealousy has gone up to some specific aggravations.
Jealousy is simply a state and ailment from this is aggravation by it. Jealousy you can see in certain kind of the body or at emotional level.
-The person who is jealous, is jealous. The person who has ailments from jealous is jealous as well.
But the difference is that the person who has ailments from jealousy, at certain moment got into a big problem
because of feeling jealous, because of a certain precise situation and from that situation onwards, an aggravation, as you say
develops on ailments, complains, which have remained and which are deep ailments from jealousy.
Which may well be something very different, maybe headache, jealous episode when a man discovered his wife was going to Alonissos
and there are some affairs there...
The man had a big surge of jealousy and from that moment on, headaches all the time.
I see many people nodding so I must probably made a case.
Even for one word if you repertorize Materia Medica, you must read the symptoms before you repertorize Materia Medica.
Before I give the conclusion, I would like to know if there are any questions about this repertorising Materia Medica
and the things you must watch for?
-Why can't we use the same search function in Materia Medica, as one can in the Radar program
where you have the possibility of the search function using two words putting them together...?
-I must say I'm not quite clear about the question because I believed I used two words to search the symptom.
So what is the difference ?
-When I use the search word fear and (?)  I only get rubrics which have exactly (?).
-No, you have a misunderstanding. If I am in the Repertory and I use the word fear and dark
I may as well find other symptoms because the result will also be any symptom which contains the word fear and dark.
You are right, the problem is less. Because the Repertory is much more structured.
You don't have these big symptoms with all kinds of variations but as a principle
as a rule, the problem is the same.
It is only much less because Materia Medica is (?) where anybody says anything and in the Repertory it is structured.
-If you put in, fear and dark and shows you all sentences where it appears fear and dark
it shows if it's divided by a comma, by a semi-coma, by a dot as well?
So what is the range the two words have to appear in Materia Medica?
-For this version of the program which some of you have, the range is one sentence.
-So if it appears in two sentences, then it will not show?
-No, then it will be even worse, in a way.
-Thank you.
-To improve this why don't you just take fear of dark and give it a certain range?
-You will improve it, if you use fear of dark, you will have less mistakes but still you will need to read through each symptom to make sure.
-It could be dark red of something else.
-Fear of suffocation with a dark red uvula will still come up.
So whatever you do, even one word, as I saw you, you need to read the results before you can use it.
Anyone has an idea to which conclusion I want to come?
-That is very interesting to use the Repertory to repertorize.
-Because when I go here and I look at the rubric mind, fear, dark I know that every remedy in it
has a big chance of being correctly related to fear of dark.
When I have a patient and he has a fear of dark, I can either repertorize Materia Medica
and I will have the problem of reading all the symptoms and make sure that the remedies correspond to the fear of dark etc.
and this is one thing or I can just go to the Repertory and look at mind, fear of dark.
But the information in the Repertory for the precise rubric is more readily available.
That's the difference.
-Do you actually need  the Materia Medica repertorisation and we have some kind of a special thing
which usually can't find in the repertorisation.
Then what I think, it should have been, if that's the way it comes out when I put fear of dark, then all the fears and all the ofs
and the darks coming up, it's complicated.
Isn't something that combines certain words? You can do this or that or only this and that.
It must be something like that in the program.
-Yes. You could search for the fear of dark and not uvula.
-No, to search for fear of dark and not all the ofs in the Materia Medica or all the darks or all the fears.
-Yes but the problem remains. You may diminish the problem but the problem remains.
-Of course I have to read it, that's the main thing, you read Materia Medica and it's beautiful.
You learn while doing it, that's the main important thing.
-What you have not seen maybe, if I want to use the rubric Materia Medica jealousy
and you say, it's a beautiful thing to read the Materia Medica, there are in this search 149 symptoms I have to read.
For the first symptom. For fear of dark, there are maybe 180 symptoms.
And I think if you like to read the Materia Medica, it's nice but your patient who is sitting and wait for the prescription
he would prefer you just take fear of dark and Repertory jealousy ... give Stramonium and he goes.
-That's it, you never use this for the simple things. Jealousy you can look in the Repertory.
And fear of dark also. It's only for the special things that you don't find in the Repertory.
-Exactly, that's the place. So I may have given the impression (?) against using Materia Medica.
It's not true. It's not what I want to communicate to you.
I want to say first that to repertorize the Materia Medica you must be very careful
I even don't say, don't do it. I say, be very careful.
The second thing I say is to repertorize, use a Repertory.
And then the third thing you say, we can easily add, I totally agree with you
is that, if you have special information or even if you have jealousy and you don't find the remedy
you may use the Materia Medica for all these occasions, absolutely.
Don't disregard the Materia Medica.
Just the topic of today is repertorisation. The first thing I wanted to explain to you is the difference
between repertorising Materia Medica and repertorising Repertory.
I will now speak about repertorisation methods.
Repertorisation methods.
If we have a set of symptoms and I will show you a set of symptoms
we have 11 symptoms, so to repertorize means to find the remedy which stands out related to these rubrics.
The obvious and most often applied way to repertorize it is the sum of symptoms.
Sum of symptoms which means if I find a remedy which is present in 9 or 10 of these symptoms
I'm very happy and if I find a remedy which is present on 11 symptoms, I'm exceedingly happy.
That is the repertorisation by sum of symptoms.
Now if you read the cases of Kent, in his (?) lectures, anyone knows how he repertories there?
-Usually he uses the remedy according to the totality, meaning he was searching for a symptom which covers most of the symptoms in the case.
But he made a distinction between all the symptoms checking which symptoms were (?) for the case.
-Yes, so you say Kent used the totality of the symptoms to find the remedy which covered the totality for the best.
Do you know how he did it?
-(?) to create a Repertory and should be used as Repertory.
-What he did is he took the first rubric and he writes all the remedies, maybe 30 remedies.
When he explains the case he says, this is an interesting symptom and he writes down all the remedies.
Then he says, the second symptom I find interesting is a symptom so and so and
if I look at the remedies of symptom 2, the remedies which are coming with these are 1,2,3,4,5,9,11... and
he comes down to 20 remedies.
Then another very interesting symptom is a symptom Nr 3 and he looks symptoms Nr 3 by itself
contains 20 remedies, he checks which remedies are common with the results so far
and he finds there are remedies 1,4,5 and 11.
So at the end, after he has taken for example 6 symptoms, he says the remedy is Nr 4.
It is in fact totality. In the cases of Kent you will see a lot of cases when he uses this method
he writes down all the remedies for each symptom and then trims down the list.
So it's really totality and there is a second aspect which has a technical name
especially nowadays because we can do it so easily yes or no with the computers.
He uses totality, sum of symptoms but he uses also every symptom as an eliminating symptom.
An eliminating symptom, I will explain to you what it is.
An eliminating symptom is a symptom and the remedies of this symptom eliminates all the other remedies
from any other rubric you will add to repertorisation.
In a case you may have 6 symptoms and you decide that symptom Nr 3 should be an eliminating symptom.
Why would you possibly decide this?
Because you believe that this is a very important  symptom, so to say the remedy must have this symptom.
So you make it an eliminating symptom.
And if this symptom contains 6 remedies, these 6 remedies are the ones who are considered.
Any other remedy which contains many more and different remedies, these remedies will be disregarded, eliminated.
The computer programs today, if you introduce an eliminating symptom, will only look for 1,4,5,11.
So for the remedies of the eliminating rubric. And this is called an eliminating symptom.
You can have in a set of symptoms, one eliminating symptom or as Kent did
in fact every symptom is an eliminating symptom.
Are there any questions about eliminating symptom and this little parenthesis about Kent?
-This method is very good but it's very dangerous.
Because you have a remedy which goes through all symptoms but it's not the right for the case.
You have another remedy which doesn't go through all symptoms but in a higher degree
it has something to (?) to the remedy. Therefore it's very dangerous to do only this method.
-Yes.
This is another chapter I will explain you. Using repertorisation by hand induces us to reason in a certain way.
And using repertorisation with computer soft wares, helps us to reason in another way.
We will come back to it but I agree it is dangerous. I will give you another explanation why it is dangerous to do this.
Suppose in the last but one step, we have a remedy for 9 and 11.
And then we add one more symptom and we see it's only the remedy 4 which common.
So we eliminate 9 and 11. Remedy 4 is found in each of the 6 symptoms.
Maybe this last interesting rubric of 15 remedies contains another remedy
for example Nr 3. Nr 3 is present everywhere except in symptom Nr 5.
Can you follow mathematics?
If remedy 3 is not present in step 5, it's not there.
And remedy 4 may cover totality but remedy 3 may cover the 6 symptoms except 5.
Then if you aren't not a slave to the Repertory and you go to the Materia Medica
you may as well read remedy 3 is a much better fit than remedy 4.
Don't drown into mathematics.
Therefore I agree if we use everything to eliminating symptom, very dangerous.
Because it may well been that out of the 15 remedies of the last interesting symptom
about every remedy covers 5 symptoms instead of 6, but we have eliminated them all at one step
because of the one symptom which was not present.
Just to explain about totality, about eliminating symptom and about the limitations of this method.
A second way to repertorize is because of the degrees.
The degrees of the Repertory.
First of all can you tell me the degree in the Repertory where does it stand for?
Can anyone tell me what is indicated by a degree in the Repertory?
-It stands for that the symptom has to be very clear like it's capital. Then it has to be very clear and very intense.
-The symptom is very clear and intense on what level?
The intensity means that for the patient who (?) that state, he would describe the symptom as being very, very intense.
-Yes OK.
-(?) an information how often the symptom appeared in the provings.
-So the frequency of appearance in the provings. The (?) indicate frequency of appearance in the provings.
-You have to consider both, frequency in the provings one, the intensity of the provings two and both frequency and intensity three.
-OK but we are missing one half I would say.
-A mixture between how often you find it in the provings, how intense is in the provings and clinically how often it has been proved.
-Yes. It is frequency of appearance in the provings and frequency of appearance in the clinical cured cases.
And it is this mixture, this combination which defines the degree.
-An interesting, important question always is, the old ones say, as far as I'm informed, that
a remedy goes to the Repertory after it has caused symptom in a healthy person.
-So it means proving.
-Yes, proving symptom goes into the Materia Medica.
This occurs frequently so we make it more important in the Repertory.
Now we have a Repertory where the intensity is extremely important.
I do repertorizations frequently and sometimes they change only the degree of one symptom by one step
and it changes completely the results.
The old authors also say, the intensity is very important or did they say it's just the frequency of occurrence?
The intensity of the proving, does that go to the Repertory straight away from the old authors or is what we do nowadays?
-If you want, I can search for it in the afternoon but the original texts from Kent they only speak about frequency of occurrence.
And they do not speak if the fear of dark was very intense in one subject or so.
They speak about it happened once in a proving, it happened sometimes or many times?
Also on the clinical cases it was sometimes cured or clinically often very (?) it's frequency.
But it is true that the remedies are introducing the Repertory because of the appearance in the proving.
But also some remedies are introduces because they appear on the basis of clinical information.
I replied about intensity for Kent but this notion of degree has changed.
-We used the intensity of a symptom of the Repertory like fear of dark Stramonium 4th degree
and it says this remedy is the most important remedy for fear of the dark, it has it with the highest intensity you can imagine.
So we take it as intensity but the old ones actually gave it to the Repertory from frequency of occurrence.
There are two things we must separate. The first is when a remedy is introduced
why it gets a certain degree.
And then this normally so far, especially for the old guys, it is the frequency of appearance in the proving or in the clinical cases.
That's one thing. The other thing is the intensity of the symptom in interrogation of the patient.
Someone says, I drink some milk, I really like milk, I couldn't afford not drink milk, I must have milk.
Someone else says, I drink a lot of milk. I drink a liter of milk, I drink every day 3 lt of milk.
So there is intensity. And then there is this correspondence which is in fact part of the VES.
That's a different thing.
Right now I'm explaining only about the degree in the Repertory and how it has got a certain degree, a certain number 1,2,3,4.
And there is some people saying because the symptom was often appearing in the clinical cases and in the provings
we believe that you must consider the degree.
Some people make a big case out of this and one of them is an Israeli homeopath, Joseph (?)
who believes that we should repertorize mostly emphasizing the sum of the degrees.
I must change it a little bit to explain what I want to explain.
You remember they were 11 symptoms. The figure beneath the remedy is the sum of symptoms.
It says 9 for Calcarea. You see next to symptom 4, you see a little dot. It means that Calcarea is not present in that symptom.
The sum of these 11 symptoms for Calcarea is 9, for Lachesis is 8, for Bryonia is 7 etc.
This is the first thing I explained to you. So we just add the symptoms.
The second possibility it is to have the sum of degrees.
You get a bigger figure because the addition which was made is for Lachesis for example 3 points, it is in 3rd degree.
Plus 3 points, plus 1, plus 2 etc. When you add the degrees of the remedy to each of the symptoms where it is present
you have 17 for Lachesis etc.
So in this sum you consider the frequency the remedy appeared in the provings and in the clinical cases.
Is it clear for you, you understand sum of degrees?
It is a different way to look at the same information. That's why I say, find the remedy which stands out.
You repertorize, you find the remedy which stands out, if you make sum of symptoms.
It's a way to look at it, it's the way which Kent used.
If you take sum of degrees, you look at different remedies in a way.
And by chance Pulsatilla, Lachesis and Calcarea are first in this case but for some cases the remedy has just moved (?)
because you look sum of symptoms and other time you look sum of degrees.
So different approach.
-The first one you showed us was the sum of degrees.
-Sum of symptoms was the first one.
-Sum of symptoms 9, 8,7 on 11 symptoms.
-And the second one is sum of degrees. You add the degrees of the remedy in each symptom.
-And which one is the middle between them ?
-What do you mean between?
-I press here, I press on this icon to have sum of degrees.
-So which one is the second?
-That's a little detail. It's a sorting on alphabetical order or not.
-These both first items are sum of symptoms, alphabetical or not, these two sum of degrees, alphabetical or not.
-You had a question?
-Obviously one person says, we emphasize sum of symptoms, other person says, we emphasize sum of degrees.
And so obviously another person says, I would like to combine and to have sum of symptoms and degrees.
And you add these figures and you come up with another number which considers as well the totality of the symptoms
as the importance of the degrees for that remedy.
It's a different approach.
Sum of symptoms and degrees. Then I will explain you different repertorization matters
and another one it is to emphasize small rubrics.
Small rubric means the number of remedies which is present in a symptom.
Fear of dark has so many symptoms, fear of dark when alone has fewer symptoms. It's a smaller rubric.
Emphasizing smaller rubric it means in repertorization matters, that if a remedy is present in a small rubric
it gets more weight, more emphasis.
And this is a relative matter. If the remedy is present in a rubric which is smaller and smaller and smaller, it gets more and more weight.
If the same remedy is present in a big rubric, it doesn't get a lot of weight because of this big rubric.
But if Silica is present in a very small rubric, it gets a lot of weight.
The result of this method is that the remedy which is put first is a remedy which is most present in smaller and smaller and smaller rubrics.
So repertorisation method, small rubrics has as a result the remedy which is most present in the smaller rubrics.
-What does the computer consider to be small rubric? Where does it start?
-It doesn't start anywhere. It is gradual.
Say, if the rubric contains 50 remedies, it gets a certain weight.
If the rubric contains 30 remedies it gets more weight.
If the rubric contains only 10 remedies, it gets still more weight. So it is gradual.
There is no border. The smaller the rubric, the more weight it gets.
You want to have the keynotes in a way? The small rubrics, you believe this is important for this case
or you want to look at the same information from this angle, you use the method small rubrics.
The 5th repertorization method is small remedies.
As the name says, this method of repertorization emphasizes small remedies.
This is a small rubric, this is a small remedy.
A small remedy is a remedy which occurs only few times in the Repertory.
Calcarea Silicata is a small remedy than Calcarea Carbonica.
When we first developed this method, which is available in all computer soft wares
emphasizing small remedies, first we did again gradual.
The smaller the remedy, the more it is upgraded.
When we first did it, we found that it's a bit of a problem to make this method useful
because you always get remedies which are extremely small.
Like Zincum, Valerianincum.
So we changed the rules a little bit and we took into account with this method the totality.
So little bit of combination of method one.
You must have been wondering sometimes, those of you who have computer soft wares
if you look at the method small remedies, you see Dulcamara, Causticum, Magnesium Muriaticum which are
maybe relatively small but then you see maybe Anacardium, which is rather a big remedy
and it appears already on the 10th place.
It is because totality is considered a little bit as well, also in a gradual way.
So small remedies, the smaller it is, the more weight it gets, the more totality it has, the more it appears
whether it's big or small.
So it's a combination but obviously (?) is to find small remedies.
You have 11 symptoms, you search for a remedy and you gave all the (?) the Lachesis, Pulsatilla, Calcarea Carbonica
all the remedies which were in the previous methods and today you want to give a small remedy
you use the method small remedies and you find that you can think of Dulcamara, Causticum,  (?)
The last repertorisation method is called prominence.
I will need to give you a little explanation to show what is prominence.
In this rubric mind-fear to be alone you have a number of remedies in the third degree
a number of remedies in red, it's third degree, a number of remedies in second degree
and a number of remedies in first degree which is black.
Let's take the example of Lycopodium.
You can say Lycopodium is prominent in this rubric because it is a third degree remedy.
It appears well.
You can also say it is prominent in relation to the other third degree remedies
because the fear of being alone is also shared by Argentum Nitricum, Arsenicum...
So it is relatively prominent.
However if we go to another rubric, to desire sweets, you see Lycopodium is there as well
and you can say it is prominent because it is also in the third degree.
But this time instead of blah, blah, blah it is only 4 other remedies in the third degree.
So it means that in Lycopodium is more prominent in this rubric than in the rubric
where it was accompanied by 10 other remedies in the third degree.
So prominence means if you would make a curve of all the remedies at first degree
second degree, third degree that this curve is sharper for the remedy which we're looking at.
And in a big rubric where they are 12 remedies in third degree, the Lycopodium stands out relatively.
In a smaller rubric where there are only 5 remedies in third degree, the Lycopodium stands out more, it is more prominent.
So prominence it means to say it in a prominent way and homeopathically
prominence means that the remedy which is prominent is more typical.
If the symptom has only one or two other remedies in third degree, it is clear that this remedy is typical
is important for the symptom and vice versa.
If you look for Rhus Tox in restlessness, you see a lot of third degree remedies. It is not so prominent.
But if you have, you look at the rubric continuing to move ameliorates, there is less third degree remedies.
So the Rhus Tox is more prominent on that symptom than on the restlessness.
You got the idea about prominence?
This method makes again not black and white but a gradual calculation of the prominence of each rubric
and each remedy.
And it gives a certain factor, it says this is only the first third degree remedy in the symptom, so it is very prominent.
And as a result you get this kind of prominence.
Argentum Nitricum, desire sweets but aggravated from eating it.
It's very prominent for Argentum Nitricum.
It is the only third degree remedy. That's what we call prominence.
And if we look at ailments from anticipation, which has Argentum Nitricum as well, it is less prominent
because we have the Lycopodium and the Silica and the Calcarea and all the other remedies which have strong anticipation as well but less prominent.
So do you have the difference between prominence and the degree?
-Could I please ask again about intensity?
Like you had that rubric desire sweet, food and it had a few remedies in the third degree like Lycopodium.
So we could say, it's quite typical for Lycopodium to have desire for sweets
and my question is, if I look just to understand because I always thought that if you look at the rubric
and you see it in the third degree, it also would mean that Lycopodium has very strong desire for sweets.
That's my question. What you had in the third degree is also intensity or not at all?
-It is related but I would like, if I may, ask a bit more patience because when I will explain the VES
the VES is using this feature very strongly and I will explain it at that time.
Before I go a little bit further, I would like to ask is there any questions you have about these 6 different methods of repertorization?
You ask me to repeat small rubrics?
I have 4 symptoms in my repertorization.
The symptoms contain this amount of remedies.
My repertorization contains 4 symptoms and this is the rubric size.
If I want to apply small rubrics, I see that the lower I go, the smaller the rubric is.
To go to the extreme, these 6 remedies they are not by definition small remedies.
It may very well be that we find Calcarea, Silica and maybe a small remedy
but Calcarea and Silica big remedies may be in a small rubric.
So this is why there is a difference between small rubrics method and small remedies method.
Small rubric and small remedy doesn't go inside all the time.
If I calculate from these 4 symptoms my method of small rubrics, what will happen?
Every remedy which is present in the repertorisation and which is maybe 450 different remedies
each of the 450 remedies, gets a certain figure.
Because of its appearance in every symptom where it appears.
Let's take the Calcarea.
The Calcarea appears here but it is in a big rubric.
So it gets figure 1. It appears in 200, in the symptom with 200 remedies
so it gets a bigger number.
If it appears in the still smaller rubric of 55, it gets a figure of 6.
And because Calcarea appears as well in the very small rubric of 6 remedies, it gets maybe a figure of 10.
So if Calcarea appears in a smaller, smaller, smaller rubric, it gets more and more weight.
More and more importance.
And this calculation I just need to do it fro every remedy and every rubric.
The result of this method is that I get a remedy which is present in the smaller and smallest rubrics.
Whether it's a big remedy or a small remedy. That is not relevant.
The more it is present in smaller rubrics, the more chance it has to appear on top of the list.
-I think this word small rubrics and small remedies are in correlation to (?) often used remedies only.
And so the degree it's very hard to see, it's fluent, you can not say this is a small remedy, this is a big remedy.
I give you an example, on daily experience you prescribe (?) or Phosphorus and as a remedy (?) is not at all represented in the Materia Medica.
It has no proving, no clinical experience and it's a remedy you need in daily practice every week.
And when you have these terms, small rubric and (?) it's not appearing in (?) but it's a great remedy.
Therefore I would say these words have no sharp definition. I think they are complementary to (?)
and it's often the representation in the Synthesis ...
-In fact I would say that now you're talking about a different topic which is combination remedies.
We can talk about it at a later stage.
I would like to do two things. First I will summarize and conclude what I have explained to you now.
I have given you the logic and the technique of the different repertorization methods.
We have discussed a little bit the advantages or the goal of using one method rather than another
and most of all I understand that you can use one time this method, another time another method.
The point is that if look at any given case, that you use these different approaches all together...
I will give you an example. You take symptoms and symptoms, again a symptom for Lachesis, again a symptom for Lachesis
so you're thinking about totality but then it gives you a keynote.
Look, he has that symptom, itching in the ears when sneezing in the morning after walking, what a symptom!
And you find a small rubric, only 3 remedies, that will be interesting.
And you reflect in your mind for the small rubric.
You say, maybe it's one of the remedies in the small rubric.
Consultation goes on and you see aggravated from sweets and still desires.
Prominent for Argentum Nitricum and Argentum Nitricum appeared in a high degree in other rubrics as well.
So you jump from repertorization method 6 to repertorization method 2.
It moves on, it moves on. Then you see the appearance of another small remedy
Calcarea Silicata and you say, ah I saw a few Calcareas, a few Silicas, so maybe it's a small remedy.
And you focus on the case from small remedies.
The first I've given you is stones and within the stone you build the house as a whole.
And the name of the house for me it is the VES.
It considers the different repertorization methods and combines them all the time.
To understand the VES this, in a way, is the first step.
To understand we can look at information, the symptoms of a patient, from different angles.
And then not so much to use repertorization method 1 for one patient, repertorization method 2 for another patient etc.
No. It is to use all the different repertorization methods and even other reasonings
in a balanced way, for each patient.
And that is what the VES is doing.
-When I take the repertorization, the analysis, they are always lots of numbers
shown in the second row and I do understand that the first and second apply grades, degrees
but then you get up to 1100 or 3900. What does it tell me?
What can I do with it? What can I use it for?
-Anya is asking about numbers which appear if you look, for example, here.
These figures indicate the importance of the rule which is applied, prominence in this case
for the remedy under which it is written. So it is just the results of a calculation
and the higher the number in this case, the more the remedy is prominent.
It means the most prominent remedy for these 11 symptoms, is Lachesis.
If it would be a different method, the number would just indicate the relevance of the remedy.