Today before we go into follow ups, I would like to suggest a few things
that you could be doing, which are very important with your cases.
In the Materia Medica and in the Repertory, there is a lot of information
that has gone inside without being valid, without being confirmed really.
So we have a bulk of information which stays inside the Repertories
and in the Materia Medica without ever using it or if we try to use it, it doesn't work.
For instance, Herring's Materia Medica, I found out that gives a lot of symptoms
especially when you have peculiar symptoms, which you find actually in the cases
which you are treating.
You find the exact symptom, you go to Herring's, to Knerr's Repertory
and you find the exact symptom and you give the remedy and almost invariably never works.
Which means that for the symptom for which is given one remedy,
maybe there are 2,3 or 5 or 20 remedies or the symptom,
as it is presented for this remedy is not correct, it's not valid, it's not confirmed.
Therefore I had the idea that this material which we use, the Repertory
and Materia Medica, should be revised from the very beginning.
How it should be revised? And what you can do about it?
This is the work of course of a team of doctors or researches.
Let us you go to the cases that we have treated here.
In these cases there are a lot, as you have noticed most probably, a lot of symptoms
that have gone away, that do not belong to the remedy.
For instance, an idea which comes from yesterday's case,
he mentioned that aversion tomato went away with Tuberculinum. He mentioned also...
-Grinding?
-No, grinding of teeth is in Tuberculinum.
If we had the opportunity that you stay here and you start some research.
You could, each one of you, go to several of the cases, let's say you take 10 cases each
and you look at the case and you check every symptom that the patient says is gone
you check it out whether it is in the Repertory or it is not.
The basic idea is this: Repertory, then New Symptom, then Confirmed.
You go in your case and you check the symptoms that went away
whether they belong to the Repertory.
If they do belong, it's OK you don't take them into consideration.
But you see also another symptom which does not belong in the Repertory.
So you write it in this column. You write the symptom and you write the remedy.
Then, such a symptom, it will become valid
when somebody else in another case confirms this symptom.
First of all we have symptoms which are in the Repertory and which are confirmed.
I confirm with this case that Ignatia has aversion fruits.
This is confirmed that Calcarea Carbonica has aversion eggs... It goes like that.
But if aversion eggs is not recorded, you record it here, as a new symptom.
Aversion eggs for Calcarea Carbonica and then somebody else comes and says
yes I also had a case who did well with Calcarea Carbonica.
There was actually in a case where the desire for eggs went away with Pituitary.
The desire for eggs (?) which is not recorded.
And there was another case, after Silica the desire for eggs came. Whose is this case?
After Pulsatilla went away and after Silica came back.
As you may understand, the symptoms which are extremely important,
are symptoms of desires and aversions.
They are important and at the same time they are dangerous to use.
Why? Because we like to ear something out of habit. You eat too much sweet
according to the habit eating sweets and then this is not valid but the moment that
desire for sweets goes away, you say desire for sweets is cured with this remedy.
Not symptoms as are given in the beginning. I'm not talking about these symptoms.
I'm talking about the symptoms are going away after the remedy.
So if we have these columns, first of all in the Repertory we say yes finally and then
in the new symptoms we say yes, if it is confirmed once or twice.
And eventually if we all organize ourselves into keeping records of that type
eventually we will have a reliable information in Materia Medica and Repertory.
That's the only way we can do it. From the very beginning.
Even symptoms which are in the Repertory and which are in black letters, they have
to be confirmed before we can use them.
The material at this moment is quite in a primitive state.
In this way it can be refined. I proposed that on some discussion groups that we have here.
Some committee is elected, an international committee or it can be a few Germans
because Germans are more thorough and more hardworking,
that this information will go now to the committer and the committee will decide
whether it will publish the information in one of the Journals.
In this way, the information can be going into different Repertories of the people
who will receive the information and you can put a red mark in each symptom
that the committee is sending now. New and confirmed.
New symptom, confirmed, Repertory symptom, confirmed.
Can you imagine how in 10-15 years the material we have it will be cleared up?
The question is of course who are the people who can send information
and can be taken seriously.
-You!
-I'm not going to do not even one thing.
You know how many cases I have seen, you know the files
and all that millions of symptoms, which have been recorded.
But the problem is that I did not have this idea from the very beginning.
Neither we had video cases from the very beginning.
When you are busy, as I used to be, and somebody was coming and saying I'm much better,
I didn't care how much better, in what extend and what exactly.
Maybe sometimes I would write down but this information is lost.
I'm much better, placebo go or don't come again.
In this way, the committee will know this comes from John D. he is good, he is reliable.
We can take it seriously.
Because unfortunately we have to exercise very strict critique in what we are doing
because it is so difficult for anybody to check out where this is yes or no.
That we have actually to rely on the integrity of the individual.
If he says this is a new symptom, is this really a new symptom or there are other parameters
which are happening in the case and the person does not anymore feel this or that symptom.
Is it because of the remedy that the symptom went away or is it because some other factors?
He fell in love. Dreams of waves...
You remember yesterday? Dreams of waves... Ah, Magnesia Sulphurica.
Forget it. It's not because of the remedy or because the remedy will take it away.
The dreams of waves will go away once she will settle down a little bit more in her enthusiasm.
I consider this work very important for the future of Homeopathy.
Because if we have symptoms of the Repertory confirmed
and if everybody was working with this idea in mind, in 5 years ,
10 years we could have a confirmed Repertory a confirmed Materia Medica.
So who would like to work on this project? There are some people who would like.
What I mean is that we may have to establish a committee,
which will receive the information and we have to find a way to make it easy
for the practitioner to note this information.
Maybe those who write fast in the computer, they can write the whole symptom.
One of the problems that will appear it will be the different way
of the expression of the same symptom.
The patient may say the same symptom but in a slightly more defined way
than it is in the Repertory.
So do we have to have the exact expression or do we have to enter it in
the expression of the Repertory?
These kind of practical problems and what can be proposed, it has to be a committee
it has to sit down and discuss the possible modifications of this program.
And once this program is settled with details
then we publish it in all the homeopathic Journals.
It is not possible that we will expect from 1-2 individuals to come out and give everything.
It's not possible. Sometimes you know I feel that you are waiting for me to tell everything.
It is not possible. I had 10 cases of Myristica, maybe there were some new symptoms
of Myristica. I lost them.
But I am prepared if an individual or two, three individuals say,
we're prepared to work on this project, I am prepared to let them see all the video cases
and see how they went and what symptoms were cured and go on
and confirm or write down the new symptoms. But this requires a lot of time.
That is why the medical Universities put the students for a doctor,
they say you are doing a doctorate now and they put them to work on the ideas
that the Professors have or the students maybe have some ideas.
But the student works with the idea that he will get a PhD.
Here, you may work for a Master Degree.
Once you have passed the Diploma Degree, you can not jump to the Master
without having the Diploma.
Do you realize the importance first of all?
Do you realize that in the old Repertories, not these ones, I have four in Athens
in each Repertory were written some information.
This information was coming from different sources plus my experience.
As a result, they took this information, coming from (?) from Boericke,
from wherever I found and I said this is interesting information
and I wrote it in the Repertory.
Then people came and you know the editions which were circulating for years.
Editions of Vithoulkas which were not my editions.
They were editions from different sources.
All the Repertories have these editions which are not mine.
With which I would disagree. Knowing the structure of a remedy
I would be able to say this is not so much fitting with the personality of the remedy.
We have to do something collectively to improve the material.
And we need volunteers.
Exactly this is what I say that we have at a certain moment cut down
from the daily practice and going into research, for the general good.
It's not possible to continue in this way.
-George you said with several editions by Vithoulkas you disagree.
I also asked Frederick (?) this problem.
I also asked him about this problem and he told me he may extract from Synthesis
all your additions, put is in a letter, send it to you
and ask you to confirm these additions or to deny these additions.
But he never got an answer by you. To me he said he got no answer.
-The real story is a little bit different.
I said, I will make my additions in the mind section.
In the mind section I manipulated the degrees, I added, I subtracted etc.
But I told him in order to do this, what he was asking, I had to work for months before
I could say this is so and so. And still I will not be able to be sure of what I'm saying
because it's all by memory or by understanding the remedies.
But this is not good enough, it's not this kind of scientific thing which can go on.
Can you imagine you have confirmed Belladonnas syndrome of right sided?
Confirmed, confirmed, confirmed...
What you will get finally in this column here is such symptom of Belladonna confirmed 150 times.
You know how useful is that symptom when you hear it and you will have some surprises
in this way because symptoms that are there and perhaps in black letters,
you will never confirm.
On the other hand, you may have a new symptom for Belladonna which can be confirmed 10 times.
It's beautiful, you can rely upon that symptom.
Then we can make an Expert System with reliable symptoms.
And you can give a tool which will be very accurate.
The accuracy of prescribing depends actually on this information.
Did I ever give you a prescription without justifying the prescription?
I say for this and that. When I say for this and that, usually I pick symptoms which
I know are confirmed. That's why I prefer to pick these symptoms, confirmed symptoms.
That's where our differences come.
And especially in older times when I was speaking in a seminar somebody would say,
but this remedy does not have the stitching pain on the second toe which this case has.
Where it was a picture of Calcarea Carbonica and you could not find Calcarea Carbonica
in this symptom. And he says, forget it.
The one attitude is forget it, why? Because this stitching pain has not been recorded yet
with Calcarea Carbonica. With this case starts to be recorded.
Until now I have to say, forget it. Why? Because it has not been recorded yet.
But now when you give Calcarea Carbonica and the pain goes away, you record it.
Once it is recorded, then it can be confirmed.
Then once it is confirmed, especially not by the same individual but by another individual
this already becomes a valuable symptom that can go into the Repertory
and then confirm it 3rd time, 4th time.
Now we have the computers, we have access to more accurate tools.
We can do a lot in refining. There is a wealth of information in the cases that you've seen.
Let's say you've seen 50 cases. In these 50 cases.
Never mind the hundreds of cases which I have on video.
The same is with Alf (?) who is doing the video work.
I spoke with Alf and I hope they understood the importance of that scheme.
-I'm not quite clear about how do you differentiate between suppression
and healing of a symptom? What does "go away"mean? You understand what I mean?
-That's a good idea which has to be discussed with the committee.
We discussed this, there were several people here, we took decisions,
who is going to do etc.
He works with this Repertory and he has some ideas and we try to bring him into that scheme
but now it comes the problem.
He says, I have done some work, I can do the Repertory, I need 5.000.000 marks to do.
When you start with these conditions, we're not going to finish anywhere.
Where can we find 5.000.000? 500 yes, 5000 yes but 5.000.000 to clean the Repertory?
And I don't believe that an individual even if he has a little team, can do it.
Because you don't get a case of Myristica every day.
You may get one in America and one in India and one in Finland.
(?) a practionner to find out what the new symptoms of Myristica is.
-George on Saturday we talked about the Synthesis with Frederick (?)
If I understood correctly, there is more and more information.
We were discussing about the quantity and the quality.
And he came with the idea he said, I've been criticized that the quantity
or the quality is not what it should be.
My idea is now it's up to you and you go to confirm each time you go to the symptom.
From what I understood also since you started teaching us, you always refer,
you said show me on the original Kent, if the symptom is present.
And you don't seem to trust anything else than this original Kent.
So what is the value of something like the Synthesis, where there is a very big information but ...
-There is a value. There is a value but we don't know where is the value?
For instance when I criticize the kind of "provings" that are done today,
dreams and little groups, they give one dose of 12 etc. and they bring out 2000 symptoms
in these 2000 symptoms there is a value in 12,10,15 symptoms that might be correct.
But which out of 2000. This is my criticism on this kind of provings,
where the whole class takes one remedy...
If I give you a remedy to prove and each one comes with symptoms,
can I take all these symptoms and publish them? This is ridiculous.
Now this information has gone in here. Scorpion, chocolate etc. That's one thing.
Then dreams. (?) was doing dreams, dreams, all the dreams went there.
Some things must be correct.
Because you take a substance and every substance since it can produce symptoms,
it can cure them. But which are the symptoms?
The Repertories and even worse the complete Repertory has everything
that has been published anywhere damned into the Repertory.
I said this is a wrong strategy for Homeopathy because you make this Repertory so big
with a lot of junk inside. And you will be lost.
I will die and this Repertory will be so big and you will be lost.
You don't know which remedy to give finally. Because all kinds of remedies will appear.
20 remedies will appear all of them, because all of them will have all these symptoms.
Tell us, tell us, what to tell you? What I could tell, I said.
Further from that point some individuals they have to understand the problem
and they have to apply themselves and say, I am available to do this.
I am available when we agree together, 5 of us, 10 of us we come here
and we discuss in detail what kind of rules this committee
should apply for such a refinement.
-George we (?) information. Can you make your own Repertory that's wrong?
-Yes. Somebody has suggested, forget all Repertories, you just write your own Repertory.
I will write what you know to be correct. This is not a solution.
Because it is not possible for me to know...
-George, I'm afraid this idea takes us away from the basic idea for classical provings.
Because when you are on (?) and you see in daily practice some symptoms,
you have the patients, you don't know if they are over sensitive to the remedy
and we give the committee a lot of symptoms which are due only to this patient.
And a lot of this information give information in the Repertory, which is reliable at all.
-But the committee will make the rules and will say that rule 1.
You send the information if the patient has been cured, that means felt much better
and these symptoms are gone.
Then there is rule 2. You can still send a symptom of a remedy but you will have to state
that this symptom was not out of a curative situation, rather from a suppression.
So this remedy suppressed that particular symptom which gives you the right to say
that there is an affinity between the symptom and the remedy
because it can suppress a specific symptom.
A remedy can not suppress a symptom which does not have.
For instance, in this case I would take note as new symptom desires bananas.
And next to it I would write aversion tomato, Tuberculinum and I would wait.
I would wait to see a new case.
I have seen Ferrum and Hyoscyamus, both these remedies have aversion tomato.
It is a little information but if it is confirmed, it becomes very important.
Because the person says, I hate tomatoes, I can't touch them.
Of course you have an individual who eats in this country tomatoes
because if there is a country where tomatoes are not known and the individual
never has seen a tomato and irritates, maybe he says I don't like it.
In the same way, if you go to China and they give you a snake to eat,
you will say, forget it. Aversion snakes.
They write it as a symptom, aversion snakes or aversion frogs.
You know in France they eat the frogs, it's very nice.
If you give me frogs and you tell me this is frog, I say forget it. I don't like it.
If you give me horse meat, I say forget it, I will not eat it.
But some people they eat the horse and people they eat the cats. In Italy they eat cats.
-In Thailand.
-In Thailand anyhow. The committee will have to decide on these issues.
Also the committee should set the rules for provings. What are the rules for provings?
We still have no rules and anybody can just collect a group of people
and just give a remedy and have a proving.
You are having provings like the saliva of owl and you give saliva of owl
and symptoms disappear. If I hear that, the person is out. He can not send information here.
Owl and whatever.
But who will be taking up the challenge I don't know.
If you have possibilities... For instance if in your surgery you have a secretary
who is not having so much work, you can always give this work to the secretary
and the secretary can write down.