We are quite close with the ideas of psychiatrists and psychologists and we would like
to hear their opinion and I would like to invite and have 1-2 hours of their subject.
A good person who is organized the subject and we can be learning.
I would like to give you, as you progressing in the knowledge,
to give you some extra exposure but I must tell you because unfortunate things are happening.
You know that in Greece there was a Committee formed by 6 Professors of Theology,
a few Professors of Medicine plus some medical people, a few priests and a few Judges
who studied my teachings in order to see whether this was a heresy.
Can you imagine the stupidity and the darkness and everything that goes with all that.
They invited some of my students to defend me and they did not invite me of course.
The fanaticism they said that was going on was unbelievable and it reminded the Dark Ages,
the Inquisition. They asked my students to betray my teaching.
They said do you agree with everything that George says?
They pushed them and they said, maybe he is wrong.
Their greatest problem was that some phrases which I had in the books reminded them
of Indian philosophy.
And this is really very bad but can you imagine 30 people, serious, Professors
of different universities sitting there and scrutinizing every word.
They need Mother Tincture.
This religion is good, no my religion is the absolute truth, the orthodox.
But another religion states similar things and another religion but this is nothing
to do with religion.
This is pure Medicine but you cannot talk about Medicine and forget about the human being.
You take this human being somewhere. Where do you take him?
What is religion and what is to be free?
You understand my problem?
If somebody asks this and we have to do some yoga exercises, I say please.
I had the teaching course last year, they said this is a meeting of the gurus of the world.
I honestly I never had a follower, not only I never had a follower but most of my students
they hate me. After they learn what they learn, they don't want to say good morning.
I always let everybody free. You go.
I never had this idea of guru. I don't want this.
In America when I was first going, they said George you are great.
I said forget it, not me. I sent them away. I don't want followers.
No you are a guru. You make me a guru. Why? Because you want it, because it fits you.
It's Greek Orthodox. Yes, I was born Greek Orthodox, I am Greek Orthodox
but after that I cannot think? I have to stop thinking?
But the society is built like that. Whoever tries to do something beyond the establishment
you have to be killed...
As I said I would like to invite a priest, a Greek Orthodox priest
but I would like to invite also a Catholic priest and I would like to invite also
a Jewish priest and I would like to invite an Islamic priest.
If this the idea discussing what is the higher purposes of life, which Hahnemann says?
What is this according to you and according to you, that would be a great discussion,
listening to different ideas.
And how this is connected with health?
How you can become more healthy or how you can become more sick?
And these are serious issues that a healer should understand very well
before he tries to cure somebody.
Because you are doing like that. You take away suffering and also to understand that
if this is happening, it is not you. It was given a system. It is Homeopathy. It is not you.
You deserve it because you learned, because you apply yourself
and you learned properly and you deserve some respect.
But to feel that I have resurrected the dead, that is wrong ideas that maybe
some of my students are getting into that trap. It is not me. The great thing is Homeopathy. It's not me.
The great thing is that we have been given that information, which we can utilize
and perhaps we can perfect it.
But I never felt that it was that I was doing something.
It is Homeopathy applied more correctly perhaps than others.
That's why you are here, to learn the correct way of applying Homeopathy.
So from that point of view also we have to be trained because the patients come back
and they tell you I pray for you.
Instead of praying to god, I pray for you. I say what?
You have to understand where we stand each one of us.
These are important issues that have to be discussed with spiritual people.
Because they will give you the dimension of you being very small and nothing in the Cosmos,
in eternity. They will give another dimension as a healer.
Then you are afraid to invite them in case some crazy people will say he is a heretic.
-Is there any way we can just help you, to write to somebody to tell them
we are better doctors since we learned from you? Is there any possibility?
-My students said it was so futile fighting with these fanatics. 30 fanatics.
Actually to their credit, the Theologians said wait a moment, we understand that
this is an issue between established Medicine and Homeopaths.
You better solve the problem between yourselves.
We don't feel it has something to do with us but some priests who have some interest on that,
on lower level, they said no, no, no we'll kill them.
One of these Professors wrote a booklet 50-60 pages which was published in 200.000 copies
and it was sent to all the Greek churches to be distributed by the priests
of these churches to the people, so they don't go near Homeopathy because it is a heresy.
Who pays for these 200.000 booklets? Never mind the church, who is behind the church?
So the Theologians said forget it, this is not our issue.
You seem to have a problem between yourself, you better find this
and settle the matter between yourselves.
-When was that? Last year?
-Not last year, last month.
-I have the feeling that the problem is information.
I am a practitioner and I wrote to the Association of practitioners and offered them
to inform them with a lecture about Classical Homeopathy.
I worked for four weeks and set up transparencies to demonstrate cases out of my clinic.
I went to the seminar room in a hotel, which was in fact quite big,
and the chair people of the practitioners Association were present at 9 o'clock
because in the beginning they wanted to talk for something about the prizes you get
for the things you do as a practitioner.
All and all 6 people were present and the chair people were speaking from 9 o'clock to 1 o'clock,
after that 3 people left, which leaves 3 remaining and I said I won't speak
if only 3 people are here because I think it's not worth anything.
The 3 people told me to speak because they had come extra for Classical Homeopathy.
So I spoke about Classical Homeopathy this afternoon for 3 people and I only had 2 hours given.
I then received a letter from a chair person of the Association.
He apologized and he said they had written to 300 practitioners
and that for this kind of event no people are interested.
He asked for money, I wanted to do it for free. He sent me a check over 300 marks.
-I feel the interest for Classical Homeopathy is increasing and in Germany it's going to explode,
very soon you will see an explosion.
What I was talking is a different matter.
Whether the authorities will strangulate us from really going into a discussion
in which we will really be free and productive.
You can ask now any question you like.
-I would like to stress on the point my colleague made.
I think since we are an international group, I just know from other things
that if letters come from Israel, from America, from Switzerland, from Germany, from Malta
I think this could be a chance we could stress on.
If you think it's a good idea...
-It's a good idea if you write letters and you send it to the Academy here,
a personal letter to me saying how much you are learning, appreciating...
Maybe it's necessary to show these letters and say this is what is happening.
I never care about these things but the attacks are coming as the Movement
is growing is unbelievable.
Can you believe that they were 6 judges,
Professors of Theology and Professors of Medicine discussing whether the church
must excommunicate me because I'm a heretic?
They wanted to make a proposal to the Synod to excommunicate me
and I said it's ridiculous even to think it.
They didn't go into that trap the Theologians because this trap was set by other means.
It's very interesting.
-I had 7 patients who are members of a free church and they were not permitted to come
and see me anymore because they were told that Hahnemann was a heretic.
-We have to be aware that they will not directly attack the people with whom they have problems.
They will go through that way.
The attack will come through religious groups which are manipulated.
There is a priest who has except of his children, he has another 15 children, 20 children.
He says these are my children. On the excuse of these are my children, he receives checks.
Nobody knows how much, never mind whether they are declared to feed your children.
Who is sending the check, a big check is also a big friend and says these fools
who are teaching this and that...
And then the priest of course becomes very fanatic.
Who sends the checks? Maybe the pharmaceutical company
and though the priest is very eager to fight this heresy.
Do you see how the idea is coming? And it's going to come more and more.
-I think there is one good side. If they gather like this they really seem to have fear
to lose their power and I think in Germany you would be even in more danger
because we have the pharmaceutical industry, very strong. I'm concerned about this.
-I think there is a big difference because if it's going by the pharmaceutical industry,
everybody knows what they want.
But if they do it in this kind of spiritual, it's another level and people don't realize.
And now I realize we can do something from outside, some pressure on these
stupid Greek people, excuse me.
Because one thing can really do something to them is to say you are stupid.
The whole Europe is very happy to have this possibility and Greeks...
You know this  is always the story with the prophet in his own...
I think we, as international group, from outside, we have much more possibility
to make some pressure in political or another way.
So we must find ideas or what we can do from outside.
-If you can ask your friends, especially medical doctors, who are sympathetic to write letters
and pressurize because the attack is very insidious. It's not direct.
You understand what they are doing. Influencing the people.
The moment that it was announced that I got this Award, in 15 days it came into the Press
that the Prime Minister of Greece most probably died because a student of mine,
a student of George Vithoulkas, has given him Arsenicum.
First pages all the news papers said excavate the Prime Minister and try to see if in his blood,
take him out of the grave, 5 months later.
They were saying to see whether he died from Arsenicum poisoning.
The issues are quite serious.
-Last month before I came here are published in Bulgaria a 16 pages book,
which is 'Homeopathy for the patient'. It has exactly 16 chapters.
Each one is just one page with very short and very exact explanation of what it is all about.
While we were listening about such leaflets which are distributed through the church,
it is our right to make something which will be better.
I think your first book 'Homeopathy for the New Man' was good for the time.
But now it is time for you to make something to explain to people what is Homeopathy about.
This is not at all difficult, you can do it and all of us we can market it.
We can distribute it in our countries, in Greece and elsewhere and so nobody will have the right
to say George Vithoulkas is telling nonsense.
This is what you are telling, it will be absolutely scientific, we can make an advisory board
of some doctors and that's it.
-What I wanted to say is you are not the only one they want to aim at.
What you spread is that Homeopathy is a Medicine of freedom.
They have always been movements and interests of certain groups of people
who do not want people to be in freedom. They want to keep them in a kind of captivity.
And so it's only logical that the more Homeopathy spreads, the larger the pressure is going to be.
What it really shocked me is that I heard from one participant of this course
that in certain States of the United States it is forbidden to work with homeopathic remedies.
The doctors would have their licenses away.
-There was only one State in North Carolina, as far as I know.
My student was the victim of this attack and we organized a counter attack.
I was the one who organized the counter attack and finally he won.
Actually in that State there is a law now practicing Homeopathy.
The Medical Association was attacking very much.
-I think the best that we can do for Homeopathy is to become the best possible.
I would like to ask you not to write lots of books in favor of Homeopathy
but to continue your beautiful Materia Medica to help us to become better homeopaths.
-I'll tell you something. In 1970 P. Smith of Geneva was in Athens visiting the Center.
At that time there were 10 doctors who were my students, myself...
And I said to him, at 1970 I had done nothing yet, I said to him
sir what can we do to spread Homeopathy?
Now I'm very tired from all these years but you can imagine in 1970.
The energy and the passion I wanted anybody who would come next to me to become a homeopath.
There was no chance.
He was an old man and by that time with his hat and his rings.
He had 10 rings and he was looking like a magician. I said to him what can we do?
He said don't do anything, just practice correctly Homeopathy and Homeopathy will spread.
Now looking back I was wondering if I had done nothing, I could by that time
be the magician of the tribe, as they call me.
Anybody would come to be treated, thank you...
If I had continue to do that without teaching anybody, trying what I tried
which the story is quite long, where it would be Classical Homeopathy at the moment?
I would be the magician of the tribe, no question but what about Homeopathy?
So you are right in what you said, from that point of view everyone
should become the best possible but at the same time we don't have to keep the knowledge
to ourselves but we have to give it out also.
Because that is the way it can spread and it can grow. And it is very difficult.
You won't believe that teaching is much more difficult than practicing.
Teaching takes a lot of energy and a lot of sacrifice.
Thank you.
I need your appreciation, there is no question in order to take some strength to continue.
Otherwise it is very difficult and if I see that the teaching is appreciated.
Then of course I'll have more energy to do more.
That's why from that point of view is very nice to hear this appreciation.
I take this opportunity actually to thank you also from my heart for coming
and takin this pilgrimage.
Because I feel it's a pilgrimage, it's taking all this energy and time and costs
to come here and learn something which I love very much and I try to inspire the same love to you.
I take this opportunity to thank all these people who are working in this set up
and especially those who are sweating even much more than me, which are the translators.