In Homeopathy we have impressive cures. There is no question.
But I want to say one more thing because a lot of problems have started
because of some wrong advertising of Homeopathy.
We cannot come out in the world, that means in the mass media,
and claim that we cure cancer, we cure AIDS, we cure multiple sclerosis.
We cannot and we must not do this.
The reason is that we cannot cure diseases. We cure patients.
Maybe a patient with cancer case we manage to cure but we cannot manage to cure
the other 9 cases.
Somebody can say, OK you said you cure cancer? Take these 10 cases and cure them.
The media attacks Homeopathy, especially in the English speaking world, viciously.
Guardian published an article against Homeopathy demanding from WHO
that denounces Homeopathy because homeopaths claim that they cure AIDS, they cure cancer,
they cure tuberculosis, they cure whatever. Even they say influenzas.
We are the only ones that we have big success in influenza, much bigger than Tamiflu or whatever
but still we cannot come out and claim, unless we stick on the main ideas.
We stimulate the immune system and the organism, if it has a possibility will cure.
The main thing is that we have to become more and more precise and knowledgeable
in order to have a better effect.
To have effect and then Homeopathy will spread.
In Germany you have a lot of people against Homeopathy. In Germany!
According to me you have the biggest brain ever lived in the world,
Hahnemann and nobody knows him or they don't want to know him.
That is something that really makes me sad to understand this situation.
It's not because we are unable to apply Homeopathy properly,
that it is the fault of Hahnemann.
Learn properly Homeopathy and then you will see the effect and then Homeopathy will be respected.
It is not normal that such a tremendous possibility, as we have, it goes to the gutter
just because the teachers, those who teach Homeopathy,
they don't know themselves Homeopathy.
This is unfortunate but this is true. We have a lot of theories and blah, blah, blah.
But when we have the patients in front of me I don't know what to do.
When the patient comes, they say give anything.
Give anything you go to the side of the placebo and then you have placebo effect.
Something will happen to some hysterical people who are thinking now I got my right remedy
and they are stimulated.