-On behalf of the Swedish Parliament I wish you all happy welcome to Stockholm,
to Sweden and to our old Parliament building,
which dates back to the beginning of this century.
Since some years ago it has become a tradition to celebrate the Prize Ceremony
of the Right Livelihood Award in the Parliament.
We have in fact a very strict policy concerning non parliamentary arrangements
in the Parliament building.
But I will be very glad and proud to welcome the Right Livelihood Award Foundation,
as one of the very exclusive exceptions also in coming years.
-The Right Livelihood Award Jury honors George Vithoulkas for his outstanding contribution
to the revive of homeopathic knowledge and for his tireless efforts in training homeopaths
to the highest standards so Homeopathy can claim a place in science as an effective
alternative to other Medical Schools and traditions.
As Director of the Athenian School of homeopathic Medicine,
George Vithoulkas has a team of 30 doctors who practice Homeopathy
while they study under his supervision.
He has established Homeopathy in Greece as a science respected by the medical profession
and made his country one of the leading centers for Homeopathy in the western world.
His books 'Homeopathy, Medicine of a New Man' and 'The Science of Homeopathy'
have been translated into 20 languages.
In the 'New Model for Health and Disease' he sets a new paradigm for the science of Medicine
and numerating the various natural laws that govern the phenomena of health and disease.
At present George Vithoulkas is spending most of his time writing a new homeopathic
'Materia Medica Viva' in 16 volumes, including all the contemporary knowledge
of his own homeopathic experience from cases which are mostly taken from the Center in Athens
which are over 150.000 cases.
His work with homeopathic teachers now extents to the New International Academy of
Classical Homeopathy established on the Greek island of Alonissos.
The first building in the world erected ex novo for the teaching of Classical Homeopathy
and stands as prototype for such Centers in other countries.
Today the use of Homeopathy is spreading all over the world because it is in many cases
more effective and cheaper than the alternatives.
The new studies in medical literature confirm its value.
But the medical establishment remains mostly opposed
because homeopathic principles do not fit inside the world view.
They need to be reminded that the Hippocratic oath does not say
I shall only heal according to the principles of molecular biology.
Through its practice, teaching and institution building George Vithoulkas has made
a major contribution of his generation to the establishment, perception
and dissemination of Homeopathy as a science that can have essential contribution
in human health and welfare.
It is with very great pleasure that I ask George Vithoulkas to accept the 1996 Livelihood Award.
-I'm very proud to welcome you up here. The floor is yours.
-Madam, your Excellences,members of the Swedish Parliament, other Award recipients,
Ladies and Gentlemen and friends I would like to thank the Right Livelihood Award Jury
for honoring me with such a great distinction.
In doing so they have primarily honored Classical Homeopathy itself as well as all my students
who have worked with such enthusiasm and dedication towards the proper application
and teaching of this therapeutic system.
I claim that diseases of the human race have never been tackled properly by conventional Medicine.
On the contrary they have been treated wrongly, suppressively
and therefore while the symptoms were masked,
the real disorder underneath progressed and finally was pushed to the interior of the organism,
which is the central and peripheral nervous system.
Let me give you just a few facts to judge for yourself.
Multiple sclerosis, a disease that eventually leaves its victims totally paralyzed,
is one which thousands of people are suffering from in the western world.
Yet it is entirely unknown to Africans, to Asians or to South Americans
who have not had the benefit of the excellency of western Medicine.
Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, a terrible disorder of the neuromuscular system
is also unknown to all these people.
Myopathy and muscular dystrophy is the same, known only to western world.
Parkinson, which is a rampant disease in the western world is seldom encountered
in these countries.
Anxiety neurosis, compulsive neurosis and in general mental disorders of a severe nature
from which millions of patients are suffering in the western world are almost unknown
in these groups that have not had the benefit of modern Medicine and vaccinations.
Chorea and the host of other nervous system disorders,like Tourette syndrome,
different other nervous disorders are also unknown to these groups.
The model suggests that all these chronic diseases
including hay fever, asthma, cancer and AIDS are the result of wrong intervention
upon the organism by conventional Medicine.
It claims that the immune systems of the western population through strong chemical drugs
and repeated vaccinations have broken down and finally admitted the diseases deeper and deeper
into the human organism, to the central and peripheral nervous system.
In short, this model claims that conventional Medicine instead of curing diseases is actually
the cause of the degeneration of the human race.
It's very simple for anyone to think that if conventional Medicine would really cure
chronic diseases, today we would have a population in the West
that would be healthy mentally, emotionally and physically.
Due to this model I had already in 1970 predicted the appearance
of new and incurable diseases of the nature of AIDS.
Saying to a group of medical doctors in Athens that if conventional Medicine
continue to use antibiotics the way they did, there would come a time
when the immune system would break down and new incurable diseases would emerge.
It was an unfortunate but precise and timely prediction of the appearance of AIDS.
Today I want to make another prediction that if conventional Medicine
does not take notice of what we say and drastically changes practices and its logic
in treating with chemical drugs, if it does not also change the direction of its research,
soon diseases will go to the center of the organism, which is the central nervous system
and most of the population on earth will be mentally ill individuals.