Dear Chairman, Dear Colleagues, Ladies and Gentlemen,
I would like to thank you and the organizing committee of the congress for the kind invitation.
It's my great honor and pleasure to be here and share with you some ideas and thoughts about homeopathy.
As we all know, the evolution of medicine the last 20 years is phenomenal.
In a similar way,the evolution of homeopathy is also impressive.
As everybody understands I cannot prove to you anything within 20 minutes,
especially that Homeopathy is a science, but what I can do is to present to you some propositions concerning
the homeopathic point of view and let you make your own evaluation.
Some of the ideas that I will be presenting may look familiar to you…
Some of the ideas that I will be presenting may look familiar to you some others may be surprising or controversial
and I am sure also that a lot of important questions will be left unanswered .
Please do not jump into conclusions before you have investigated the matter more thoroughly.
I want to make a statement from the very beginning so no misunderstanding could arise:
Homeopathy does not claim to cure everything, and more specifically does not claim to cure
cases with deep and progressed chronic pathology.
But where is most useful is in functional disorders and also in the beginning of chronic diseases.
So we have some dilemma in Medicine which everybody knows.
Signs and symptoms are the expression of the defence mechanism in order to keep the homeostasis
and should be respected and promoted rather than suppressed.
This may be a new idea but it is a basic idea for Homeopathy.
A typical example; fever should be promoted and allowed to complete its
mission in inflammatory processes, not suppressed.
The suppression of acute diseases may continue as a sub-acute inflammatory process,
manifesting the genetic predisposition of the organism for chronic degenerative diseases.
All chronic diseases therefore are characterized by parameters of a sub-acute inflammatory process.
Such chronic diseases are a substitute of the original inflammation and a continuation of the
acute disease that was never parted from the organism and never really cured!
For example acute tonsillitis, repeated tonsillitis, many times treated with antibiotics may end up in an
individual with cluster headaches acute rheumatic fever as heart diseases etc.
The basic law of Homeopathy is that likes cure likes. It means that the cure of a disease is
accomplished by remedies that are capable of producing in healthy individuals similar
symptoms to those of the disease. What are the remedies that are using? All these remedies
have been formed by provings. Remedies which have been given to healthy individuals and
provided a symptomatology of this remedy and all these corrected symptoms constitute the
homeopathic pharmacopeia called Materia Materia. At this point I may say that for instance
all the side effects of conventional Medicine drugs would constitute for us indication for a cure
for giving this remedy for side-effects this remedy causes, in very minute doses.
The minimum dose is another main principle for Homeopathy.
This is the most disputed part, as Homeopathy is prescribing remedies in infinitesimal doses.
You may have your doubts with such minute doses.
But if you turn to allergiology, where an infinitesimal dose of an allergen
can produce a devastating effects upon an organism which is sensitive towards this allergen
then you may also understand that the homeopath is searching to find what is this particular
remedy to which the individual is very sensitive and by giving them minute dose it can
produce an impressive reaction. The symptoms of the disease during the process of a cure,
this is another important law in which we have experience, disappear in the reverse order of
their coming. That means treating tonsillitis causes headache and the person comes with
cluster headaches. If you successfully treat the person with cluster headaches then the
organism will go back to the state where the organism was infected by tonsillitis.
The main difference between conventional medicine and homeopathy is the individualization of the
treatment. We don’t have remedies for diseases, we have remedies for patients.
The target is curing the patient in its entire pathology and not only in its local pathology.
This is accomplished by stimulating the defence mechanism by the similar remedy.
We collect all symptomatology, mental, emotional and physical of an organism and we try to find which is
the remedy that has produced a similar pathology when it was proved in healthy individuals.
By the term defence mechanism we mean the entire immune system and for Hahnemann it was called the vital force.
It’s equal to the energy complex of the organism according to to the last findings of science.
According to other experience there are several layers of health.
4 main groups and 3 levels within each group.
In order to define in which level of health a person is we have several parameters.
One of the main parameters is the condition of the acute infections.
Maybe it has not been observed so far but it is my experience that very
healthy individuals are seldom affected by acute diseases.
If the level of health starts coming down we see mostly staphylococcal infections.
If the level goes ever further down we see frequent yearly acutes.
As you go downer acutes by Proteus, Pseydomonas, viral infections,
fungal infections, lower down, very frequent acutes including inhospital infections.
At this point we see a cessation of acute conditions. The organism cannot raise high fever anymore.
Once this has happened there is a manifestation of chronic condition with mild acutes with
very low fever. As we go down very seldom mild acutes appear and in level 9 we see no acutes
anymore. In the last levels of health we see no acutes with high fever, yet when a fever
develops, indicates the end of life. It’s the last effort of the organism to survive.
In medicinal hospitals, before death some acutes are developing.
If the above concepts are correct, we may assume
that we have a new doctrine about diseases expressed as a “Continuum” of a Unified Theory of Diseases.
Whether the above “propositions” constitute a scientific system or not has still to be decided.
Needless to say, that these are experiences of thousands of medical doctors
whose belief is that a healing system has to rely on what is understood today as evidence based medicine.
Thank you.