Montagnier is Nobel winner and together with Gallo I think at the same time they found the HIV virus
and after that he followed the idea of Benveniste.
Benveniste was invited from Temple University in America in a meeting in Bermuda in which I was present
and he presented a research in which he said that the high potency of Apis mellifica
that means over the Avogadro number had similar effect with the real poison.
And what the real poison does when you are stung by bee there are some basophils which are considered to be the defense mechanism
and they are mobilized and breakdown and they are supposed to reduce the effect of this sting and it’s the natural defense of the organism.
He claimed that the high potency will do the same, will degranulate the basophils, like the poison does.
I was there and I raised my hand, I was the only one who understood because most of them were professors of different specialties
in the gathering, nobody knew Homeopathy he made this claim that a substance that contains nothing, no molecule,
had the same effect as a substance that has molecules and has chemical effect upon the organism.
I raised my hand and I said I am sorry but this cannot happen.
Most probable there is something wrong with what you say.
Benveniste was very angry when I said that and he started shouting and I am not a man that will fight.
I thought they may want to hear my opinion, he didn’t want to hear my opinion, it was ok for me, forget it.
And the episode was finished by Benveniste who was an allergiologist, professor of Medicine in France,
with high prestige and he asked all these very influential scientists that were present in the gathering to press “Nature”,
it’s number 1 scientific journal in the world, to publish his research. I was terrified.
But there is an inner circle with 24 of us and another circle outside another 150 people attending the meeting.
Between them there was a professor of Allergiology of University of Jerusalem
with who we had long discussions concerning Homeopathy.
He had been persuaded by Benveniste to repeat his experiments so when it’s published to say it is confirmed by Jerusalem University and this is so.
When he heard my objection he called me and he said, George what is happening, what don’t you agree?
I explained to him why I did not agree because it was very simple; a substance is given and produces certain symptoms.
Disease is given produced certain symptoms.
And high potency is given to alleviate these symptoms, neutralize, cure them not to create the symptoms
as if it was a real chemical substance.
If this was true when we prescribed Arsenicum it would have the effect of a poison.
When we prescribe hydrocyanic acid etc… If this idea prevails then it would be terrible for Homeopathy.
It would be the end of Homeopathy because they would say the substance produces the same symptoms as the high potency.
The high potency will reverse what the substance is doing, not cause the chemical reactions that are caused
by the disease or the poisoning by a certain substance. Is it clear so far? Cannot happen.
It’s impossible to produce with a high potency a poisoning of the body in the same manner that the substance will cause the poisoning.
The idea of Homeopathy is exactly the opposite.
That means the substance is causing a symptomatology and high potency if given the organism is making a reset and eliminates the symptoms.
I told him like that and Professor told me we tried it several times in out laboratories in Jerusalem
where we have very good instruments and I could not see what Benveniste was claiming.
Given the fact also that Benveniste was Jewish,  that means the same as the Professor, usually these people support each other,
they don’t go against each other, therefore from what you tell me I will withdraw from the experiment.
I said what I am afraid is if this paper is published will backfire for Homeopathy, like it was done.
Nature published the paper under the condition that they will send a committee and Benveniste would have to show them under the microscope
the degranulation of basophils when the 18th potency was put in the solution.
So, they went there of course nothing happened and the whole thing came in public and destroyed the reputation of Benveniste
and destroyed also the reputation of Homeopathy because they connected the failure of this experiments with the failure of Homeopathy.
That was happening by 1988-1989. In the meantime I was in America, teaching there,
and I had persuaded several centers to start research with Homeopathy.
After this scandal broke out all these people they had agreed with me to do research they would withdraw
because Benveniste lost his position in the university, he lost his laboratory, and he lost the support of Boiron,
who was financially supporting him, and he was in a terrible state. But what happened; a journalist from N.Y. Times
who took this from “Nature” he wrote most probably “water has memory”.
You must have heard “the memory of the water”. Who has heard it? Everybody knows and you believe it.
What actually happens is that the memory of the water was not the idea of Benveniste it was an idea of a journalist
which was taken later on by the media who wanted to show people how ridiculous homeopaths are.
The dilute one drop in the ocean and then they claim that this drop in the ocean can have an effect.
The whole thing was twisted completely because of this experiment that was wrongly presented and conceived.
It was a wrong experiment done by somebody who did not know Homeopathy.
And after that until today the media is talking about the ridicule of the “memory of the water” and all that.
All this has an impact on us, who support serious Homeopathy, we have to defend Homeopathy all the time
and explain what is wrong until people come to understanding but then this whole experiment
by single handed delayed the development of Homeopathy in the world. That is the truth.
Now comes Montagnier, he’s a Nobel winner and then he does not know become he didn’t come in contact with an homeopath.
He does not mention Homeopathy so much but he has sideways said that what he found out most probably is support for Benveniste experiment.
The Benveniste experiment was repeated by another group of people.
The BBC took part in that second experiment and they said we film all this but if this becomes negative you can forget even talking about Homeopathy.
The next group went there and tries to show under the microscope the degranulation of basophils and they could not show it.
And BBC comes and says forget it, after hundred years you may be start talking again.
You see how painful it is for me that I have seen all these cases, the effect, things that you cannot imagine to see
say that Homeopathy is nothing because Benveniste has his craziness doing all these.
And now Montagnier comes and he goes much further than Benveniste he would send a signal through the internet
and the signal would affect the DNA and I am terrified of what is going to happen if this becomes public.
Of course people have started ridiculing already him before he goes as far as this.
You see it is different the idea of energy medicine in which all kinds of ideas can be inserted because energy is an area
which is not controlled by microscopes, not controlled by devices so therefore there is ample possibility for mistakes and misunderstanding.
So I am afraid Montagnier is going to cause another shock for Homeopathy and another reason for ridiculing Homeopathy
and finally what is the truth…
Since a few months I am trying to write a paper together with two biochemists who know Homeopathy
and I hope to be able to complete the paper by the end of September or October
in which we separate the dilution of water from the state of potentized remedy.
It’s two different things when you simple dilution and when you have a potentization process
because there you have information from chemistry which shows how the molecules bond together
through free bonding electrons which exist and create a totally different environment in which the substance
gives its own identity as a structure of the molecules of the water and that new structure by bondage of the molecules
through potentization is a totally different situation than just diluted water.
We don’t dilute a substance in the ocean.
We potentize and we increase the energy and the specific energy which comes from the specific substance.
I am writing another paper which explains the Benveniste experiment and what was wrong with it and another paper
in which I will explain why the potentized water becomes biologically active water.
Forget about the memory because all these supernatural ideas make the things look ridiculous.
Of course if you put salt in the water the water will remember it but it doesn’t mean anything.
What we claim that this water becomes biologically active because it attains a form of energy
which is similar to the form of the energy of the body.
Some of you know more or less the facts and you be discussing these ideas.
I am thinking of writing a letter to Montagnier telling him to be careful because he is going for a big problem.
He is heading for breaking his own head against the wall with all these.
We hope this will not happen. We’ll see.