These people who have suffered so much, they can enjoy so much.
And then you give back health to the people and they say whatever cost it may worth.
It may worth but you know with what cost, you know what I have thought against Medicine,
against pharmaceutical industry, against homeopathic pharmaceutical industries,
against homeopaths who want to fight me and say George, bad guy, kill him.
And still I'm 73, completed 73 and I have this...
This passion to teach and to say 'world hear' there is Hahnemann who said this and that
and who gave to humanity the best possible boom.
But you don't want to listen but when it comes to high places, in Bohn University for instance,
in Medical School in Bohn they said to me my dear George come here
before you go to start teaching we heard that in Homeopathy you are believing certain things.
I said yes what do I believe?
You believe that if somebody looks like an animal, you give animal remedies.
I said no, wait a moment and not only that.
He says we hear that there is a remedy which is called 'the Berlin wall' remedy.
Not only that, we hear that if you see somebody who wears a shirt with stripes,
you must give him zebra the remedy.
And they tell me this, they tell me that...
They even told me things which I never knew by that time.
I had to apologize for all these things that were going on in homeopathic community
before this Professor of Psychiatry and Professor of General Medicine.
In the chair I was allowed to teach.
In the meantime they heard all these things and they were scared to death.
They said he is going to say all these things to the students, to the medical students.
And we are bringing him to teach.
I said sir not only I don't believe but fortunately I have the European Journal
in which I have written a critic about all this.
I said it's not that I'm telling you this now because I want to teach.
It is that I have criticized beforehand and here it is the proof.
I criticized myself all these things which are going on in Homeopathy.
This is not Homeopathy, it has nothing to do with what Hahnemann taught
and what I'm teaching is the pure teachings of Hahnemann.
They said OK, go to the amphitheater and of course they found out...
I presented some cases, I analyzed the cases
that I was in my logical mind, I was not totally crazy.
But again and again when you go to this level, in which people are serious you cannot tell
all these nonsense and because of these nonsense I had to receive all the repercussions.
These people who tell the nonsense they never deal with these Institutions.
They are just irresponsible, they tell whatever.
Put a water and write Lycopodium and because you wrote Lycopodium 10M,
the water will be Lycopodium 10M.
Drink the water and you will be well.
This kind...
Not only that but you play music and the music will be potentized...
Potentized the music...
But I try to keep quiet all these years.
Then one time I said that's enough, I have to come publically, to have the proof
that prove all these things and I wrote critics which are quite severe in the 'Links'
and some other magazines in order to separate myself from this nonsense.
And I carry on my back all these problems.
And still I'm fighting instead of saying all this world is useless,
you can forget about it, George go and enjoy yourself...
I have a little farm with plants, animals, the sea, fish...
nice life and why? Why you travel to teach, to inspire people,
to show the technique how you can handle these little potencies?