Have you heard the memory of the water?
Who has heard the memory of the water?
Who knows who brought this idea?
What was the name of the doctor who brought this idea?
Only one person knows? Do you know Benveniste's experiment?
Benveniste made an experiment in which he said certain things.
He said that if you give a high potency, you can cause structural changesin living organisms.
So he made an experiment and he took the poison from the bees
and gave it to cells and there was a degranulation of basophils.
Then he took a potency beyond the Avogadro's number and he put this
and he said that I found that degranulation of basophils is happening under this high potency.
The story was heard by the world and most of the homeopaths even today
they don't know what is about the real story. So I want to tell you the real story.
The real story is that in 1988, in Temple University of United States,
the biggest University in Philadelphia in United States invited 25 Professors,
different kind of Professors, not only from Medicine, Physics, Biochemistry etc.
in a discussion group, in which they talked about the frontiers of science.
This was the theme and the Temple University had invited these people to discuss.
I was also invited in the main group for the discussion.
So Benveniste came and spoke about his experiment.
He said I found something entirely beyond fantasy, entirely new,
it is beyond the frontiers of science.
Why? Because I did this experiment and I found out that a high potency containing
not one molecule of the real remedy, that means poison, had the same effect as the poison itself.
So 25 people are there, 2 of them with Nobel Prizes, all of them Professors in their specialty
but no one was a homeopath.
I was the only one I understood what he said.
I said my god. All these people stayed with the mouth open. They said is that possible?
I said wait a moment, I don't think that this experiment is correct.
The moment I pronounced this word, he comes out with such violence.
He says you cannot...
I stepped back and I said forget it, I don't want to fight here,
I just want to say my opinion where nobody heard my opinion.
But in the outside circle, there were several scientists observing.
One of them was a Professor of Immunology in Jerusalem University...
Zwei Bentuits was his name, whom I knew before because we had exchanged ideas
about Homeopathy and after the presentation was finished...
In which presentation, I must tell you, Benveniste asked these people who were present
to exercise their influence upon 'Nature', the most high scientific magazine,
'Nature' is called, to publish this paper.
Zwei Bentuits is hearing all that, he is hearing my reaction, he comes to me and says
George tell me why you had objections.
I said it's not possible this to happen and I explained the reason.
I will explain to you also.
He said I understand what you are saying but in our laboratory in Jerusalem,
we were trying to confirm this experiment and we were not able to confirm it.
I said sure because this cannot happen, what he says is entirely false.
So he says it's good that we discussed because I will withdraw from this experiment.
So he withdrew from the experiment.
But in the meantime in 'New York Times' in the first page there was the experiment,
the memory of the water, Benveniste found out that the water has memory
and that Homeopathy is correct because it acts...
I said oh my god. Then I call Zwei and I say it's going to back fire what he says.
'Nature' said I will publish your paper but I don't believe it.
So therefore I publish it under the condition that I will make a committee of 3 scientists
to come to Paris to your laboratory and show them the degranulation of basophils
under the microscope.
Benveniste agreed and the paper was published in 'Nature'.
Soon after 'Nature' sent 3 scientists and what they thought?
They thought that maybe he will do some under hand manipulation,
so we have to send together with these 3 scientists, a magician who knows all the tricks,
Mr. Randi, Randi the magician.
So they go to his laboratory and of course they could not find anything.
So he could not prove it.
There was a big scandal, he lost his professorship, he lost his laboratory,
he lost his clients, he was one of the best allergiologists,
he was reduced to nothing because in science,
in the scientific world if you make such a mistake, you can forget about existing.
They reduce you to pieces.
Later on I invited in Alonissos all the scientists they were doing some research
and I told them if you make a research on Homeopathy please have with you as an advisor
somebody who knows Homeopathy, so you don't make such mistakes.
In Homeopathy the potency cannot create the same effect as the poison.
Because if that is true, you use Arsenicum album and you give 200 potency,
I would be poisoned. Hydrocyanic acid we use.
You can imagine that I take a potency that may have the same effect as the real poison?
So what they were is that the potency had the same effect causing structural changes,
damages in the living organisms.
It was a crazy idea all together if that was true.
We would have proved Homeopathy anything.
We would say OK I'll poison you with the Arsenicum 200. Take the Arsenicum...
On the contrary the symptoms which are caused by the poison are eliminated
by the high potency. It's the opposite.
So I told them you can poison yourselves with Apis mellifica
and give a high potency of Apis and save, prevent from being degranulated.
Prevent them from being degranulated because they are sick now with the poison
and they have not completely died.
OK, give the high potency and the high potency will prevent degranulation.
Otherwise it is totally crazy to think that we can give Lachesis and all the poisons
and create the same effect as the real poison.
But yet a lot of homeopaths, even today, not knowing exactly what is happening
believe first of all that Benveniste was right, the experiment proved Homeopathy.
Actually all the attacks we receive was because of such experiments
which are proven to be false.
You cannot base your arguments in favor of Homeopathy in a wrong experiment.
That was totally wrong.
You understand the implications of even thinking or discussing about the possibility
of Benveniste experiment is a correct experiment? It was a wrong experiment.
Several years later, a group, the Anis group they call it, they said we found out
that the experiment of Benveniste was correct.
So this time instead of 'Nature', the BBC took the initiative and they said OK
if you believe that this experiment was really correct,
we will film what you found, your findings and we will tell to the world Homeopathy is correct.
So this group of 4 scientists agreed to do the experiment.
10 years later after all this...
Of course the BBC called again Mr. Randi and said you go there and see that
no trick will take place.
Mr. Randi was there and they could not show anything.
The BBC came in the Horizon program...
Has anybody seen this program with the Homeopathy?
You remember what they said to the end?
Homeopathy is rubbish and you may wait for another 100 years before we talk again.
I was mad, I wrote a letter to the editor and I said this experiment
on which you accuse Homeopathy was a wrong experiment from its conception.
And I have denounced this experiment from the very beginning
but you want to present that this experiment was an experiment
which never proved Homeopathy, in spite of claiming that proved Homeopathy.
You want to ridicule Homeopathy.
We had a kind of correspondence with the editor, Mr. Barrett and Williams,
I think was the name of the editor in the Horizon program.
He wrote if what you say is true, we have to rewrite science.
I said yes you may rewrite science, wait you may understand a few things about science later on.
So we had a big correspondence...
And the fact is that from this correspondence some of the skeptics came to me
and they said, you claim that high potencies have an effect? I said yes.
Can you prove that potencies have an effect on the human organism?
I said yes, I can prove.
They said do you agree to do an experiment with us, the skeptics and yourself with a group?
I said yes. They said OK we start writing the protocol for such an experiment.
The skeptics found 5 very reputed scientists together with me that we wrote
a protocol for proving high potencies.
There were papers signed and who was the head of the skeptics?
You can imagine. It was Mr. Randi.
Mr. Randi was signing the agreements with us.
Because he had put in his web site that if anybody proves the high potencies action,
he will get 1.000.000 $.
I said I want this million.
For two years we write the protocol to make it as perfect as possible,
that there is no possibility that we can cheat, under no circumstances
and then the next problem was to find a hospital on which to do the experiment.
Because we needed a hospital to do an experiment with human beings.
I put all my influence, all the political influence I had, in order to have a public hospital.
Finally we found a public hospital to accept with their scientific committees deciding...
it's a lot of work.
We found the hospital, we are ready and the hospital is the Municipality Hospital of Athens.
I said to them, we found the hospital, we have to start immediately
because the woman who was the Mayor was my friend and ordered the hospital
to accept to do the experiment.
She will go out in one year because new elections and we knew who was going to be
the new Mayor of Athens, he was a medical doctor.
I said we have to start. Once we start there is no way to stop us. Please start.
After a lot of correspondence, we are in the 5th year...
We receive a letter, they say we cannot start. Why?
Because Mr. Randi is ill and he cannot come to Athens.
I said for god shake, we have to start. What is the problem?
Mr. Randi is ill. I said we have to start until next June
because from there starts the new Mayor, he starts on September,
we have to have at least 3 months to have started the experiment.
We received a letter, Mr. Randi is sick and most probably he will be sick
until the 10th of July. I said oh my god...
I wrote angry letters. No, no that's it.
Mr. Randi can come after 10th of July where his energy will be good.
Then what happens? We had elections in Athens, the new Mayor
was the medical doctor, we knew.
We had no influence in this medical doctor. He was against Homeopathy actually.
I said OK, I will try to influence this medical doctor, the Mayor.
I put all the people I have treated on the government,
I put them speaking to the Mayor to say you accept to give an order to the hospital and to continue...
They pressurized and pressurized and eventually all things...
The committee which had changed already, the President of the hospital was persuaded,
the committee was persuaded, everything is correct...
Some of the skeptics were here, we were finalizing the last details of the experiment and suddenly...
We were here, the skeptics together with my team, we were arranging the last arrangements
and I'll tell you the last what it was.
That a robot could make the selection, so no human would be involved in who takes the remedy,
the potency and who takes the placebo.
50-50 would be there. 50 people would take the remedy and 50% would take the placebo.
And we had to point out that this and this and that person got the potency.
Not that they were cured or not, we had agreed that we will be able to spot
who had taken the remedies in potencies. That's all.
Which was very easy actually because we would give repeated doses of 30,
we had agreed on 30 potencies and some of the people would show some provings.
Some of them they would be cured, some would show some provings.
We had a whole strategy how to spot these people.
We had to spot 50 people who have taken the remedy.
We could see as many as we like but for 50 people we would have to say that
these 50 they have taken the remedy.
If we were correct in the 70%, we would get the one million.
I said fine, we are starting in two more months.
At this moment Mr. Randi sends a letter saying because George Vithoulkas
is an aggressive individual, I want to start the process all over again.
Not only that but you do it first yourselves, see that it is really active
and then we will repeat it.
That means 5 years of spending hours, spending energy, he just throws it out.
I said but you have signed and you have said I agree with all these condition.
Now suddenly...
If you go to our website www.vithoulkas.com and you put Randi, you will see the story,
you will see some of the letters that they were transpired.
So this experiment was the continuation of the Benveniste stupidity.
I don't want to say that he did it on purpose because that would be absolutely stupid
but his ambition to get the Nobel prize or what he thought...
breaking the frontiers of science with an experiment proving high potencies in such a way
it was a terrible mistake and you should denounce, when you speak.
You should denounce this experiment as a false experiment and say we know this experiment
as a false experiment.
You cannot base your attack against Homeopathy on an experiment that had no credibility.
All these fightings...
Of course you may think poor George, that is true.
Except of all other things, I had to do all this in order to save the name of Homeopathy.