I want to speak about something for the first time.
I have never spoken about this subject before.
I want to speak about the importance of the function of human imagination
and the role it plays in human health.
It is important for you that you are dealing with the health of the people
to understand that the function, the faculty, the possibility of the human brain
to imagine, to fantasize is one of the most  high functions of the human brain.
Imagining, fantasizing is also important for rejuvenating the human body.
Without imagination, if the faculty of imagination reduces to the extent
that a human being does not lose the possibility to imagine,
from that moment onwards it starts a process of degeneration of the human organism.
I want to give you some examples. For instance, in depression.
A stage of depression is what people call indifference. I'm not interested about anything.
And you know that when you hear that by a patient,
you are going to have a very difficult case.
If you examine such an individual, whether anything excites them, they will say nothing.
But in order an individual to be excited about something,
he has to have the faculty of imagining, the possibility of imagination.
Where is life in its fullest sense, there is always an area of the brain,
which is easily excitable and produces pictures, ideas and plans for the future.
You remember the other day I said that each area of the brain can be excited
in a positive or a negative way. Every area has both possibilities.
The same with imagination.
The area of the brain which is excited easily that produces the  phenomenon of imagining
can be positive or negative. Therefore imagination is a faculty that can bring a human being
in its highest possible spiritual stage.
It is through imagination, through this faculty that a human being is entering the world of ideas,
which is the highest area where we can enter as humans.
Through imagination also is that a human being can go totally away from the positive ideas.
It goes to the other side and then we have the problems that we call mental problems.
But I want to draw your attention to a fact which you all know,
especially those who are working with mental patients.
Mental patients usually you will see they have delusions, acoustic or visual.
That means they are living in a world of imagination.
They are living in - what we call - a not a real world.
By entering in this state what happens is that the energy that is experienced
by the human who is entering in this world, it is unbelievable energy.
I have seen and you may have similar experiences manic depressive people,
when they are entering the manic phase, their energy is increased unbelievably.
I have seen cases in a manic state for days and days to go without sleep, without eating
and yet the energy which they produce is unbelievable.
They can go on day after day, night after night with one hour of sleep or even less sometimes,
with very little food, no appetite but you see them moving around, talking, doing things,
live in the house, going out, asking people to have sex with them...
We have to ask where this energy is coming. What is the mechanism?
When an individual lives in a world of phantasy has such a big, huge energy
while at the same time the one who says in a depressive state, I'm totally indifferet.
What you will see in such cases? Lack of energy invariably, total lack of energy.
When the person says Phosphoric acid state, Picric acid state, Stannum state,
Carbo vegetabilis state...
When these people say I'm exhausted and I don't care about anything at the same time
you see tiredness, extreme tiredness in their organism.
They may be going to bed and though they are tired hardly they can sleep a few hours.
And they become more tired, sleepless and they never have enough sleep to recover.
This is what they feel. If I could sleep, I would recover my energy.
I want you to keep this in mind and I will go to another state when you were children.
You know how children use their imagination in everything they are doing.
Children live and do things through their imagination and what we observe with children?
We observe a lot of energy.
They go up and down, they play, they imagine things and a lot of energy is flowing.
I'm sure from your experience everyone will remember that in your young years more
and in the childhood but especially later on if you had problems to fall asleep,
you would have to imagine something pleasant and with this kind of imagination
the organism would be settled down and calmed down and eventually enter the state of sleep.
Then you will have to ask why do we have to fall asleep in order to keep on living.
They say according to statistics that 7days without any sleep,
if they wake up a person by force, if they wake him up for 7 days, the 8th day he will die.
If they don't allow him to sleep for one minute for 7 days, he dies.
Therefore the entering of that state is absolutely necessary for our existence.
Now we have to understand what is the connection between fantasizing and sleep.
Is fantasizing, imagining a kind of a dream state?
In medicine we have an expression, which says a person is day dreaming.
Therefore we have to connect this day dreaming, this imagination,
the possibility we have to imagine things with the very existence of life.
But at the same time we say this person is out of his mind, he is totally crazy.
Also we say this in cases of manic depression.
A manic state you see and you get frightened.
People are in a kind of ecstasy and imagination is in its fullest function.
And a lot of energy is coming in.
A mechanism happens in the brain that clicks and allows what we call our logic ability
to go to sleep and the organism is left without its ability to logically do things.
When you enter a dream state, you know that logic does not work anymore.
You say I want to leave, I want to go away but you cannot go away,
somebody is behind you and you cannot run. So you are left to what?
You are giving up your ego to another state of being without control anymore.
You don't have the control.
So the moment that you lose the control, the ego, the energy is flowing.
I have said something wrong.
I'm really examining things maybe that are a little bit on the beyond.
But I examine them in such an analytical way that maybe we can be reaching conclusions
about human health and find parameters to evaluate who is really healthy
and who is really sick, which is something very useful for us when we treat patients.
Many times I have received questions from students saying tell us
what is a natural symptom and what is a pathological symptom?
Where pathology starts?
I have been asked many times and I try every time to give an answer.
But unless we go into the depth of the issues to understand really what is happening,
we will always know half truths.
Didn't it ever cross your mind the question why do I have to sleep?
When I was young I was full of imagination. Unfortunately I don't have it now.
I was full of this, imagining the life of different things,
which are happening in the mind of a child who is very happy.
Tomorrow I will do this, I'll meet that girl, she is beautiful, I like her...
When it was time that I had to sleep, I said oh my god now I'm going to lose 7-8 hours
where I will be nonexistent.
I close my eyes and when I woke up it was 7 o'clock in the morning.
Sometimes my aunt was coming, get up you have to go to work.
I want to connect the possibility of the imagination triggering a state,
which is between sleep and awareness.
If you trigger that state, then imagination, imagining things comes.
Because usually children go to sleep while they are imagining different things
and as they imagine, they enter the sleep. And then the dreams come.
What are the dreams? Another question.
Jung says it's the collective consciousness, the collective sub-consciousness.
Different people have tried to explain what is this plane of dreams
and what is the connection between dreams and our lives and symbolic way of dreams
and how you explain them.
What is interesting for us as healers to know is that imagination can be triggered
and it's a good thing.
How imagination can be triggered?
In children you don't need much.
A child can find very easy ways to trigger his imagination.
As logic becomes prominent in our life, imagination is reduced and more reduced.
And maybe it will be totally reduced and that's a very bad state of affairs.
Because no more flow of energy.
The moment that you enter an imagining stage, which is pleasant, you have flow of energy.
The moment that you enter a stage where there is no imagination, the flow of energy stops.
Now the question is if this is so, fantasizing or imagining is the highest form of stage
in which the human being can enter.
You can enter the highest stage through imagination.
What are the people who go away from society and go to monasteries
or even worse by themselves and they live for years?
And they do praying, they do spiritual exercises, what is the purpose?
The purpose is to refine the imagination and to stop the logical mind.
To make the logical mind calm down and let the imagination take hold of the individual.
This is the experience that these people in the monasteries they have
because it comes an experience which is explosive. It's something beyond belief.
The energy that comes flows in. It is unbelievable.
And the sense of fulfillment is so great, so deep that they don't need anything else.
They don't need to communicate, they don't need to speak out about their experiences.
They are absolutely content with that divine state. How it came?
Through efforts, constants efforts to excite the imagination and to imagine
or to attain enlightenment - they call it - or to attain a unification with god.
Then suddenly the flow.
If you read the experiences of these people, you will see they are identical,
whether it's a Yogi or a Sufi or a Christian. The experience is the same.
They have entered a state of absolute bliss.
Who can do that? Here is the question. Be careful because a lot of people are trying.
Do you know the Beatles? The Beatles were some people who were singing...
Beatles were singers who due to the love they received from their audience,
they were entering from moment to moment such stage in the stage
while they were performing and everybody was getting the energy from that stage.
They were the first ones to realize this state is similar with yogis.
So let's go to India to meet the yogis.
They were the first popular people who left their country to go to meet the yogis.
They went to India but they met most probably the wrong yogis, the wrong guidance
and most probably they ended up taking some drugs, marihuana etc.
And trying to bring about that state through artificial means.
If you try to do this, to stimulate this area through chemical drugs what happens?
All the areas are of double quality, positive and negative.
You stimulate the area and the experience instead of being a fantastic experience,
it is an experience of going to hell.
I met a lot of people when I was in America with marihuana.
They came to tell me their experience and they were sick after that
with tremendous fear of going crazy.
So you have to be careful how we use all these chemicals
because we cannot stimulate areas of the brain in an unnatural way.
Because we're going to pay the price later on for sure.
The more you stimulate the brain and even if you get good experiences,
the more you will have the after effects.
So what is a healthy imagination? This is what we should concern about?
Who can have and to what extent our brains can tolerate,
where are the limits we can tolerate going into this area of imagining?
Many people have tried and they went in the wrong way.
Then we have the mental problems that we see today.
So a person of our western civilization who is today making the effort to become
a better human being, usually comes in contact with such movements, spiritual movements.
In which directions are given what you have to do in order to attain internal bliss,
enlightenment etc.
What I found out is that unless the whole organism is in a state of health as a whole,
if he pushes himself hard to attain states which are not permissible
because of his limitations of health,
he will go astray and he will develop mental symptomatology.
So the imagination is our door to whatever is the highest in our understanding
but we have to have healthy organism to try to open that door.
That is why Homeopathy which is bringing back a kind of balance in the organism
is so Important at this moment for a society which has gone astray totally to come back
to its natural rules.
If your brain has a problem in the area when you stimulate it,
it will open up the problematic area. It will not open the correct area.
It will not open up the positive side of the imagination.
It will open the negative side of imagination.
In this world in which we live today, the pornography because it's on the news...
Every day they catch people with pornographic stuff, with disgusting functions,
with children, with babies.
Can you imagine now how these people are driven to such unbelievable actions
because their imagination took the wrong turn?
What happened and our civilization is in such terrible state?
Because we lost the possibility to be children.
You hear Tomas, what he said was unbelievable.
He said I pray for the humanity, for those I love. He was very honest.
Because in the child's soul there is this element of purity.
We consider this child as non normal yet.
Yet some functions which he is experiencing from his brain are very healthy
and are healthier than ours as grown-ups.
He says I want to throw a bomb for the injustice. The way he means it it's all right.
He prays at the same time for the good of society. Fantastic.