What I wanted to discuss with you today
is an issue which I think is very important.
I think it is one of the issues that has made
me, has given me the possibility
to prescribe correctly in many cases.
It is very important issue but at the
same time is not very clear.
That issue is the issue of underlining. How we underline, why we underline a symptom.
Every symptom has a particular meaning
for the patient and for the doctor.
The meaning of a symptom is not always the
same between the patient and the doctor
and that has to be stressed from the beginning.
If the patient says a symptom with intensity
and clearness and it is self-produced,
spontaneous, then it is important.
Such a symptom we underline 3 times.
But many times I have seen a paper case
where we have this underlining and these underlinings are useless. What is missing?
So we said spontaneous, intense and clear.
If somebody says, I have a very strong headache. We get this description many times
in headache cases. The headache is
terribly strong and I have to take pain
killers and things like that.
And you try to get a description of the
headache and the description is not clear;
that symptom already takes second rate.
It is not an important symptom for you.
When it comes? It's so great. You ask,
when it comes and they say, it's so intense.
That means the information is not there. Therefore that information which is not clear,
though it is intense, though it is spontaneous,
is useless. Because all remedies have the
possibility to have headaches.
So, a spontaneous and intense
symptom has to be clear as well.
And if the main symptoms of the
patient are not clear, our experience
is that such cases are very difficult to treat
and most probably you will not be able to
find the indicated remedy, ever.
They will stay with their headaches the rest of their lives and you will be able to change
a little bit the intensity or the
location or things like that.
So in the underlining in which you do and
which corresponds to the underlining of the
Repertory and the Materia Medica, bold letters, italics, ordinary, there is a correspondence.
Bold letters very strong, you have to find a corresponding of this symptom of the patient
with the corresponding intensity
in the Repertory.
You understand this?
Do you all have the Repertory?
In the old times many Homeopaths thought
that they could work without a Repertory.
If you know the Materia Medica that
George has in his head, that's enough.
No, that's not true. I look at
the Repertory every time.
I have to look at least a few times and if one is basing his prescriptions only on the Materia
Medica which he has in his head
he is going to miss most of the cases.
So this work is very important
and it's the crux of the matter.
Whether you're going to find the
remedy or not it will depend
on whether you will pay special attention to certain symptoms.
This is, as an idea, where you pay most attention. This is the idea behind.
I give you a project. You take each other's case and you numerate symptoms, 25-30 symptoms.
I got 30 symptoms from the patient, I'm good, no. Because these symptoms are not evaluated so
they can become 3 dimensional,
they can become alive.
Symptoms which areflat, it's like a picture. You see a picture of a person on a piece of paper.
Once you put emphasis into different symptoms, then it becomes alive, the picture becomes alive.
In homeopathic prescribing this is absolutely necessary to do. You cannot give a case on a
paper and in this case there are only written
symptoms unless you have given an evaluation
your evaluation. Now, the evaluation is something very subjective, right?
I see it this way, he sees it that way.
That is the problem, where the problem
starts with the underlining.
Then you will see it when we take a case and
I ask you, how much you underline that symptom. You say 1 time, 2 times, 3 times.
In some cases the whole class or the
majority will say 3 times, it's ok.
But never everybody perceives the
symptom in the same way.
So there is a subjective element into underlining a symptom and when it is pathology, it is clear
for everyone, how much you underline headaches in this case?
3 times, it was very intense. But
headaches which have no clear
description, either you underline
it 3 or 2 or 1time,
you may even take the symptom
and throw it out of the evaluation.
A symptom which is very strong you can
take it and throw it out. Why?
Because, no modalities, no peculiarities.
Find in the Organon where Hahnemann talks about this subject. The subject of taking into consideration.
You take into consideration only the peculiar symptoms and the other paragraph in which he
says, even an intense symptom is of no value.
By the end of the seminar you will
know by heart, Organon.
I do not say things of my own.
For a period of time I thought I was telling
things of my own.
When I re-read the Organon, 30 years later,
I found out that Hahnemann
had noted down almost everything which
I thought I discovered or it was important
in the homeopathic practice.
It's very strange. People are saying, what is
this symptom, totality and you hear totality,
you read totality and then you come to the
point, the realization that it is not totality.
Sometimes it is yes. But most of the
time is not totality, it is peculiarity.
Perceive what is individual in the case,
perceive what is peculiar in the case.
In Homeopathy you take a case
and you struggle taking the case.
Unless you reach a point where you have
taken enough information that is reliable
well-underlined,which is peculiar and which is clear, you will not be able to have the remedy.
I give you a gross example,
it comes from my experience of yesterday.
I was looking at a case and the case was going for Silica because of constipation and chilliness.
Then it went towards Sepia because of the leuchorrea and constipation and chilliness.
And then the bloatedness came, chilliness, constipation, bloatedness: Lycopodium, eh?
And then came the symptom, better in the sea. My life is the sea, I can eat in the sea,
rejuvenate, so powerful, so strong that symptom.
If you ignore it, and they had ignored it the
previous Homeopaths who were giving remedies, if you ignore that which is clear,
spontaneous, intense and peculiar, then the other fit, constipation, yes Med. can have
constipation, leuchorrea, Med can have leucorrhoea, chilliness etc.
But many times, and this is the problem and this is a written question of the student who wrote to
me, something very important. He said,
dear Sir I have not understood how can
we recognize what we call the uppermost
layer? And this is a big question, not easy.
The picture will be like this; some symptoms of the third layer maybe coming up, as you know.
How do you recognize this?
This answer you have to couple it with this information to be able to perceive
what is most important in the first layer.
The same example I gave you, Sil.,
Sep., Med., I will give it to you
in another way,
in another context.
Chilliness quite strong, underline it 2 times. Constipation quite strong, underline it 2 times.
Brittle nails, underline it 1 time.
Leucorrhea, what kind? yellowish-white.
Underline it 3 times. Better in the sea, your
mind went to Medorrhinum and he says:
I feel fantastic in the sea' and then you
pursue this matter. 'Exactly how you feel?'
'Do you feel better?'. And the patient understands
that this information is important
and as you talk she comes out with the information that she used to be much better.
'I used to go crazy about this, not so much anymore'. Here, you have a different evaluation.
Let us say, here this blue is better in the sea. This symptom pops up on the uppermost layer,
as well, but when you take out the two other layers, you will see that this symptom
on the third layer is very strong.
So a symptom that was there strong and now
it is not so strong, it indicates, it's an indication
for a lower level which now has been
overcome by another remedy.
So you have to be aware all the time
what is the information that I have to evaluate.
Don't just rush to make a prescription.
Medorrhinum! Not this time.
Medorrhinum in order to be prescribed this symptom here has to be the better in the sea.
The most prominent of the symptoms.
It's not the symptom in the way we say it is
pathology but for us that we know the Materia Medica, it is very important symptom
and here comes the idea, how can we
recognize the symptoms?
The symptoms we can recognize
only if we know Materia Medica.
That means, a peculiar symptom,
it is not a peculiar idea.
It has to be recorded in the Materia Medica
and in the Repertory to be useful to us.
A peculiar symptom which has never been recorded in the Materia Medica
or in the Repertory is useless.
You can record it or you can say
that peculiar symptom was cured
by that remedy and from that onward we may have some information. But it is not useful for us.
You think you know all that but this
information is not simply information,
it is experience together with information.
Because as we learn the Materia Medica,
we know the important things on the Materia Medica or the peculiarities of each remedy,
and then we hear and some of the symptoms strike us as peculiar in that case
and we say which remedy has that?
That is important to search in the
Repertory, to search in the computer,
to search in the Materia Medica to find out.
Because the peculiarity may be said
by the patient in a passing way.
Because what he is concerned about is his headaches, his abdomen,
his colitis, his stomach pain. He is not concerned that by 11 o'clock he has an empty stomach
every day and has to eat something.
He doesn't even know he has it.
He will not spontaneously give it to you.
It will not be intense.
It will be clear, that means you will describe it exactly and he will down play it.
He will say,
'I also have it, what's there?'
But for you that you have symptoms of Sulphur already appearing, that is gold.
That symptom makes a prescription for Sulphur.
Because we know that 11 o'clock Sulphur
cases have an empty feeling and
they have to eat something.
Otherwise they will feel nauseated. Sometimes this symptom is a pre-runner of possible
ulcer and when it comes to the second stage
this emptiness becomes nausea and
they have to spit. They will say:
'every morning I have nausea'
and there is a word in Greek 'ligoura'
I don't know it in English.
It's an emptiness together with nausea, it's not clear nausea. They suffer quite a lot.
They may have also come because they have
cervical syndrome or periarthritis or whatever.
And with this symptom immediately
your mind goes to Sulphur.
As you progress now you become more experienced; I will give you some tricks.
For those who have listened to me during analysis of cases, in Celle
here and there and I come out in the class
and then I make the analysis.
What I usually do is when a patient says something like this, I don't investigate it too much
So the students will not understand that
I pay speciaI attention to that.
and most of the students lose the point.
What is the difference between me
paying special attention?
He said something, I noted down,
I passed it and let it be as the patient said it.
I went to the class, we analyzed the case, nobody mentions that symptom.
There is another symptom,
usually I ask the class,
I pressurize you and it has gone out
of your mind, the whole class
has not noticed that important symptom.
You see how important it is to connect the information from the patient to the information
of the Materia Medica or the Repertory.
Because unless you know that such a thing
exists in the Materia Medica, you cannot go and say that this may be an important symptom.
So going back in this case here,
the first is Arnica.
You may have a case which has Arnica first,
then Sepia, then Medorrhinum.
Some symptoms of Sepia maybe
appear here and there
and some symptoms of Medorrhinum also.
But what you are looking for is to make a picture of a remedy out of the most important symptoms.
Don't take this, don't take that. The most important symptoms.
and what is very interesting is to evaluate the symptoms which are most recent.
The symptoms which are the most recent and
more strong lately, this is the secret.
How can you find out what is the
uppermost layer?
You can not imagine how many times I have seen cases which have been treated by
Homeopathy and they cannot
spot the first remedy.
They spot the second, they spot the third
and you lose the first remedy.
You lose Natrum Muriaticum for instance.
This is the first remedy not Arnica. Why?
Because it has gone through a lot of grief.
And you have to take out that before
Sepia can act. But then in such cases you
cannot imagine how the main symptom
will appear that has not changed after
Nat-m (the headache).
Yet the headache will have slight
changes that will point out to Sepia.
The headache was more generalized,
has gone now more on the left side,
already is a Sepia sign, over the left eye.
Already you have confirmed Sepia
The patient says: 'I am the same'. His headache is the same or appears to be the same.
Actually in reality it has changed dramatically because of these changes on the mental-
emotional picture which is not so much Natrum Muriaticum anymore and has gone to Sepia.
You see a child that he has easy vomiting and has pains here and there like rheumatic pains
and you go to the mental picture and you see that that child is really lacking self confidence.
And the lacking of self confidence is strong,
what are you going to treat the nausea ?
Are you going to treat the Rhus-t
symptoms there are there?
No, you are going to treat this insecurity of the child first and let the nausea be much more
let the pains be much more but the self confidence will increase and then the
physical symptomatology will pop up.
And then you treat this symptomatology.
If you go straight...the mother says,
'the child is vomiting!' yes, but this is important.
What is prominent? A child who is Bar-c child,
let us say and is insecure and cannot learn
and cannot stand up and say her
opinion in front of others etc.
That child will remain in that range, that
means it will not become very self-confident
child, that is another personality.
Here in Bar-c we have to correct
in mental-emotional picture what is pathological
upon the personality. The personality of this
child is to be shy, it's a very shy child.
It may remain a shy child the rest of her life.
But the pathology is that she has absolutely no courage to get up and speak in the class and
say her lesson. The moment the teacher
asks a Baryta carbonica and says, tell us about
a history question, she looks like this,
terrified, searches.
She will answer but she will remain as a personality not like somebody who is extrovert.
And then what you will see later on,
for Rhus-t, you will see again a shy person,
a person who is not very forward but the symptoms of Rhus Tox now being exaggerated
a little bit, point out the next remedy.
All these theoretical aspects we have to see them in practice, to see them in cases.
I see some panic in some eyes, I understand.
How are we going to do all this? Not me.
I can not understand. I can perceive this.
This is something which can be learned. It is not so subjective as it might look at this moment.
It can be learned and you will be able to
perceive especially with the knowledge
of the Materia Medica.
With the Materia Medica we try to spot the personality of the pathology of the remedy.
We spot what are the 3-4 points that we need
for that remedy. So as you learn the Materia
Medica and you are looking at a case.
It was a beautiful case in previous seminar.
I taught a Nux Moschata. Some doctor has brought the case and she is using the same
expressions like the ones we have used in the class. Absolutely the same expression.
You see she comes back and the whole
class sees this is a Nux Moschata case.
How this happens?
I don't know by synchronization. It's very improbable that you may get such a remedy in
the same so the students one day are taught here and the next day are taught by the patient.
And then the patient was concerned with her headaches but she was describing the
mental state of Nux-m and then all the students said, forget about the headaches.That is obvious.
-To this last case I have difficulties because you said, take this Baryta Carbonica child and
it develops reumatism and nausea and just recently, do I still take the Bar-c state first
if it is acute rheumatism which goes
to Rhus-t do I still give Bar-c first?
-Yes, very good question. Magrit asks
these are acute symptoms of whatever.
Are you going to take the mental state
more important than the acute?
I did not say exactly that. You see what
I described is a child who comes for nausea
and the mother is concerned,
she gives you all that,
but at the same time she gives you
a picture of Baryta Carbonica.
Now you will notice that this acute
state is not so acute, it' s not
so bothering really. Maybe later on they will become bothering but the mother is concerned.
'She has this pain here', she tries to find symptms which are not important which are
not the really strong symptoms.
If the child comes with an acute rheumatism, you don't go to prescribe directly
unless it fits with the picture of the case.
You take into consideration the fact that the
child has been having an accident and she
has developed some symptoms of Arnica
and that will be the first. And this is the difficulty of course, when this and when that?
That is the problem really. Otherwise, it would be easy.  You are dealing with something alive.
The organism is something alive. You cannot
put them in boxes and say that box, no.
You have to deal in each case with such an understanding; the organism is acting all the time
An organism maybe one day has Phos symptoms and the next day has Sep symptoms.
And then it goes like this. Up and
down and changing all the time.
And then you take this case and you say,
neither Phos nor Sep,
changing symptoms all the time is Pulsatilla.
Many times after a remedy, you give a remedy and after the remedy because of the reaction
of the remedy, develops a picture
of a second remedy.
Don't go and give it. You gave a remedy
and the next day it looks like Sepia
or looks like Phosphorus, a lot of discharge
from the vagina or some nose bleeding.
Nose bleeding and thirst, next day. No, wait until it settles and if nose bleeding continues for one
month, two months,t hree months, that is the time when the picture of Phos. has come up.
The problem with today's diseases is that they are much more complicated than what
they were treating, Hahnemann, Kent
and all these big masters.
We are faced with a much more complicated
situation here because of vaccination,
chemical drugs, pollution, stress.
The pictures has changed totally.
And therefore we have more and more what Hahnemann called 'one sided diseases'.
We are talking here about what Hahnemann talks in one sided diseases.
This idea of underlining. I brought into the
picture but if you take and you read carefully
the writings of Hahnemann you
will see this idea coming through.
The idea of Repertorisation was always necessary because from the very beginning
the Materia Medicas and the Repertories
were evaluated in at least 3 grades.
So there is a need for us to go accordingly
and if a remedy has a symptom which
is even general symptom but which
is spontaneous, intense and clear,
it may itself give you the
direction of the remedy.
If I describe to you, she comes with headaches and it is mostly on the right side
and it is maddening, very strong headaches
and it is throbbing and the window is closed,
and she has to lie down, what you would
say is the remedy?
If I say there is a right side of headache,
it comes here and goes up to there
and when it's very intense she has
to vomit, what's the remedy?
This is one symptom, let's describe: severe headache, right side extended to right
occipital protuberance. Then second she says: when this headache is strong I have to vomit,
It is a matter only of knowing Materia Medica.
If this is strong, it doesn't matter now all
the other details. It's a case of Sanguinaria.
Right side, extending to right occiput,
nausea and vomiting: Sanguinaria.
You give Sanguinaria, forget all others.
Only on this symptom.
You get the other, right sided, very severe, throbbing with a pulsation he has to lie down,
cannot move, that is Belladonna.
You can not confuse this because it's clear
the description of Sanguinaria here and
it's clear the description of Belladonna
on the other hand.
You are not allowed, later on, to confuse this information because
it has been described very clearly
in the books and the person
describes it exactly in the way
that the provers have felt it.
That is Belladonna and that is Sanguinaria.
Now, in Belladonna case if I had said to you
that it's worse from jar; you lie down in bed and
somebody comes and sits in the bed
and you shout, Belladonna.
In Sanguinaria it does not matter. Then it becomes more clear for Belladonna.
Both they have photophobia.
Both they need to close the windows, dark.
With strong headaches most of the patients have photophobia and they require the
curtains down. That is not characteristic. The characteristic is the location and the throbbing.
Location and throbbing: the first
remedy is Belladonna.
Then you ask one question: 'how do you feel if somebody just jerks you a little bit?'
'Forget it, I can't stand it!'
You're supposed to understand what we're talking about and if you don't then you have
to ask questions to make it clear. Because maybe I omit certain things which I consider as
self understanding. So by your questions,
I can complete the picture, right?
Don't pretend everyone in here, he's an expert.
-You said before that you have to find a coorelation between the intensity of the
symptom of the patient and the importance
of the remedy in the Repertory.
Does that mean that I have to find a
rubric on the Repertory where the remedy
has to appear in the same degree
in which the patient desribes it?
-Yes, correct. That's correct. If the patient describes a symptom on the third degree,
you must find it in the Repertory
on the third degree.
But this is not always but most of the times.
-I wanted to just ask this question
because I went over all last year's notes,
I read again the notes from last time and mr.Currim -the specialist for Repertory-
said that the degree of the symptoms, the evaluation of the symptoms has nothing to do
with the degree of the symptoms
in the Repertory.
-That makes no sense. The degree
of the symptoms of the patient
is not the one that is going into the Repertory.
Most probably he said something else, yes?
-He said, it has nothing to do with the intensity
of the symptoms but only with the frequency in
which the symptoms appeared and the proving.
-Wait a moment. When a remedy has
been recorded in the Repertory,
it has been recorded in the third degree, why?
For several reasons, it's not one reason that it was frequent, no.
The first reason is frequency, the second
reason is clear, the third reason is intensity
and the fourth reason is that
it was found clinical verification.
So the degrees in the Repertory depict frequency, clearness, intensity and clinical
verification. So the Repertories are made out,
in their degrees, out of these parameters.
Of course, the original, the very original
proving will say, frequency, what happens?
We have a class of 50 people. We give Bell. and 10 of them develop right sided headache.
That is very frequent in all the provers.
That is strong already.
But the clinical verification shows that the headaches of Bell., are really very strong.
And you have to have headaches which
are on the third degree intensity.
And the throbbing nature is very clear.
That is why it is not only frequency.
It does not mean anything.
It means that this remedy has that
symptom quite strongly in its pathology.
That person has that symptom quite strongly in his pathology, then match it.
This is an understanding which he has maybe.
I'm not sure, I have to go and look on the video and I'll see under what context he had said it.
-Currim also stressed that we also should pay attention on the first degree in the Repertory.
He did not mention that there is no importance
between the degree of the Repertory and the
degree of the symptoms of the patient. But you also mustn't forget the one degree symptoms.
-Sure, you must not forget. The one degree symptoms is something relevant of course.
Because if you have a small remedy and in this small remedy, you have recorded that symptom
It is most probable that you have seen
it in that small remedy very few times.
So the remedy has not been
raised to the third degree.
-It was in connection with a child who
has his face covered with warts
and Lyc only appeared on the first degree.
-You give Lyc. why?
Because it was his face with warts, no.
Because the child has another symptom of Lyc which was pointed out that this is a case of Lyc
and not of Thuja and not Medorrhinum.
I have exactly the same case with a child
whose whole face was covered with warts.
It was ready to be operated, it was terrible.
The case was cleared with Calcarea Carbonica.
It doesn't mean anything just saying an information like this apart from a context.
The thing is when in a case you have certain symptoms of Calc, are you going and on
the pathology you just prescribe Thuja?
Of course not.
You need other supportive symptoms. So if
these supportive symptoms point out clearly
to Lyc give Lyc, give Chel, give anything,
which may never had that particular symptom.
-The other symptoms of this child was
dictatorial to his little brothers
and desire for sweets and flatus.
-And when you go to warts on the face you
don't even see Calc. It doesn't matter.
I didn't care whether it was there that pathology or not, the moment that the child is a Calc child.
-But what was important in this
case we mention was that this symptom
in a low degree led
them to the right remedy.
And I think that is what you wanted
to stress that sometimes a remedy
on a very low degree may
lead you on the right way.
-I'm not sure because if the remedy was prescribed on dictatorial, on desire sweets etc.
that means he took this whole picture
he saw Lyc and he saw also that Lyc
has warts in the face but not frequently.
How many times you have seen warts in
the face and you give Lycopodium, ok.
So therefore it is there. It is recorded.
Sometimes it is not recorded at all. The pathology may not be recorded in the
Materia Medica but when you
have symptoms of Calc
symptoms of Sep and the pathology
is not Sep, it still does not matter.
I have given Sepia in a case when the
vagina was dry. No discharge at all.
On the contrary it says, dryness.
I said yes, it doesn't matter, Sepia.
You see I don't necessarily have to
have the leucorrhea of Sepia
if the other symptoms are Sepia.
-Who is smoking in this class?
-You see with the Italian group,
the real smokers if I go over an hour
they go and sit outside to listen.
I see nobody does it here.
-Of the things you mentioned last lesson, to me the most complicated appears this question of
when to change remedy if you can see several layers. To me it seems especially complicated
when there is a nosode. A lot of Homeopaths say if a nosode appears picture in the
symptomatology you have to give it first but
with your Med. example this is not always true.
Are there some rules for this?
In my experience I have not been able to find rules like give first Sulphur to clear up the case.
Give first Nux-v to do what's called in French, they call it 'drainage' Nux-v and some remedies.
Give other things, nosodes or the big ones:
Syphilinum, Medorrhinum.
I would be afraid to do that not only because
it may not affect the case at all.
But because it may affect the case on the wrong way. I mean change the case,
change the symptomatology. Because in
this case you give Medorrhinum first
it may have some effect but the effect will
be to confuse the case, not to cure it.
So there are no rules. The rule is what
you have as symptomatology at the moment.
The organism brings out certain
symptoms and they are speaking to you.
Saying: I suffer from this, this and that.
Then you take that information and
then you evaluate it properly
and then you give the remedy.
It doesn't matter what it might be.
-This thing with underlining and the bold letters
is very disturbed in the heads of the people
and I think it is a fault of Mr.Currim
because what he really said was
the intensity of the symptoms do not relate with the grade in the Repertory. This is what he said.
He says that Kent said this in his lectures
22 and 23 and Schmidt said that the grade
has something to do with the intensity. So would you explain it to the people again please?
-Ok, this is very simple. When they start
making the proving of a remedy...
Ok, out of a 100 people, 20 had
that symptom, that was frequent.
Frequently appeared that symptom. The idea was that if we had a repeated symptom,
then we put it in bold type. in the beginning.
In the beginning it was God, you know.
Later on we have developed Repertory
and the Materia Medica.
In the beginning we did not have Repertory, we only had provings.
The Repertory developed out of
several things. One was the proving.
The second was the clinical experience
that we have upon these provings
and then we saw that in this clinical
experience, intensity was also important.
So if we have frequency, clear and intensity,
we put it on 3 degrees. 3 underlines.
Bold letters means as when you take the case, that you have underlined the symptom 3 times.
Italics 2 times and normal,
you have underlined one time.
This is more or less, it is not an absolute
rule that if you have a symptom in bold,
you underline 3 times, necessarily
you have to find it in bold letters.
It is not an absolute rule but as a general
idea. The general idea is:
when you have an intense and clear symptom
usually you will find it in bold letters.
Usually you will find it strongly in the remedy.
So a symptom which is strong in the patient,
is strong in the remedy.
Frequent in the patient, frequent in the remedy, intense in the patient, intense in the remedy,
clear in the patient, clear in the remedy.
Is it clear now?
So the underlining is important to match the case you study with the remedy you are going to find.
Let's take a symptom, you say great exhaustion.
Underline 3 times, 4 times.
This great exhaustion you will find
it in the remedies which are bold.
Other remedies have also exhaustion. If you see rubric, generalities, you say weakness.
It's a big rubric.There are a lot of remedies
in bold, almost 50 remedies which are in bold.
Out of these remedies Stannum
and Muriatic acid are also in bold.
Now we are making the Repertory.
This is not the final Repertory.
We are making the Repertory all the time.
In the next Repertory you will see Mur-ac
and Stann in the fourth degree.
That means we have out of clinical
experience elevated the Mur-ac or Stann
to the 4th degree. So when you
have underlined 4 times the weakness
then you go and say 4 times is only Mur-ac, Carb-v and Stann, something like this.
This is a tool which is improving constantly. Currim is a person with the books.
He read in the books, he came
and gave you his experience.
When somebody tells you something
is not God who tells you the truth.
I tell you something, I maybe wrong.
It's my perception, my experience.
You do not take it as, George said, Currim said.
What about your brains?
If we could have such boxes in
which we can say, ok, 3-3, 2-2, 1-1,
if we could have that then we would not have human beings, we would have robots.
Only robots, machines can
be put in such boxes. Not human beings.
Especially human being who are evolving.
We don't have the brains of our
ancestors 2000 years ago.
The Greeks were very bright people, philosophers but most of the other population
had a totally different mentality
than what we have today.
Today we are all Socrates and Plato,
we are big brains.
We have evolved from the state of instincts in which we have acted for thousands of years,
to control.
That's why we talk about Lill-t.
Lill-t is a person who controls. Why she controls? Because she wants to evolve
she wants to feel that she is one with God.
She wants to be one with the truth.
Socrates what he did? They say that he was walking in Athens and suddenly he would stop
and it doesn't matter if you talk to him or anything, he would not answer.
For half an hour he stayed like this,
immovable and then started walking again.
That means, he had to solve a problem so
he wanted stillness to touch God, truth.
The same is with diseases. They come and they evolve you. The say, suffering makes you better.
The instinctive people are very aggressive,
very nasty, killing each other.
Not that we don't kill today but we think it
twice or we discuss it, shall we kill or not,
which is an improvement. Still we
are evolving as human beings.
So a case of Sepia today is totally
different than a case of Sepia 2000 years ago.
Sepia 2000 years ago, she was
having a lot of leucorrhea.
Now she has this idea with God,
shall I find God etc.
It's similar things which are
happening but on a different level.
The disease has gone on a different level for Sepia. But at the same time there is a change
in structure of the human being. You can not have the same Repertory 2000 years ago
and have it today. It has to improve.
So Currim said, yes but 200 years ago
this is what was said.
It might  be said, not exactly.
I don't think he's even right that but
doesn't matter I take it as if
he is right in what he says.
Still in 200 years of evolution
we have come in different concept today.
And what does it mean? Frequency, frequency,
if you take intensity and frequency
you will not see much difference.
Somebody who suffers a lot with headaches,
he doesn't talk about frequency.
He says 'I have a terrible headache', ok.
And you have terrible headaches twice a year. But when you have crisis, it's a severe crisis.
So you go and see Belladonna in capital.
What is it? The intensity that makes you
go to Belladonna, not the frequency.