-Hahnemann states that when a medication is given, the latent miasm breaks out.
Is the disease pushed in or is
it then revealing itself?
Hahnemann states that when we give repeated
doses they we must be further potentised.
Why do we give repeated doses
of the same potency?
And another question is: can you please tell us your point of view about vaccination?
- I can discuss a little bit about this
suppression which is legitimate question
for someone who is a new
comer for Homeopathy and
taking as an example several cases which we have seen already in this group.
We have noted several times that old
things that they were there that means the
disturbance that was there, 10, 15, 20
years ago, is slowly coming
to the fore again, bringing their symptoms out.
That means for our understanding that
this type of disturbance was there before
and then it went deeper into the organism and
then created another disease situation,
syndrome, disease or situation,
whatever you may call it,
but in effect it's not
different than the beginning.
So when we have a case, where somebody mentions skin eruption
like the case we have been seeing, a severe
skin eruption, if it was not treated and cured
and if it is suppressed by creams, cortisone etc. this disturbance will go inside into the organism,
into an organ, into a system or it can be distributing itself into the 3 levels, not physical.
If the organism is strong, a physical
disorder will stay on the physical level.
But if it's not strong enough then some of
these disorders will go in the emotions
and the emotions are closing up
and they are becoming negative.
And if it is not strong enough it goes to the mental. So it is a distribution on these levels.
As we treat, then this is becoming
better and this is becoming better,
the whole thing goes back to the physical.
Then we say that the original
problem was suppressed originally
and diffused within the
organism into 3 levels.
If the organism is strong, it will keep the mental away, it will keep the emotional away.
But as the organism is breaking
down, it is first the emotional.
What is the first appearance
of disturbance in this level?
I have some diagrams in the
book where I show that here
we have a hierarchy of different organs.
The organs on the mental level.
The organ of irritability, of anger.
In this level there are organs as well, concerned with irritability, concerned with anxiety,
concerned with depression, concerned with suicidal depression, concerned with apathy.
So the first disturbance we will see if the disturbance goes to the emotions,
it will go to the lowest level of
emotion which is irritability.
And the lowest level of mental
which is affection of the memory.
If this organism is tired and it has the cortisone cream, and it is tired because of several
stresses that happen in life, my family problems,
my work is not doing well etc. he will find out
that his memory is breaking down.
He starts forgetting.
And if the problems become more and
more the organism can not handle it,
then you will see confusion starting. Then I cannot concentrate, then I can not think, then
I have confusion between reality and non-reality.
And then eventually the non-reality breaks
down the mental and you go to schizophrenia
and severe mental disorders.
So we have in each case, every case of us
has a history and a progress of disease.
There is a basic disorder of some magnitude.
That basic disorder will appear in the physical body as long as the physical body is strong.
If it is not strong, then it will go into the
emotions, then more deep in the emotions,
more deep in the mental.
And as you treat wrongly homeopathically or allopathically and primarily allopathically,
because all these people are treated allopathically, the millions and the billions
are treated in an allopathic manner.
So you get a case of cystitis in a little
child and you give antibiotics,
then you find out that after 2-3 months
there is a relapse. Cystitis again in the child.
You give again antibiotics; then you find that
after 2.5 months (not 3) there is a repetition,
you give again, after 2 months there is a repetition, then after 1,5 month.
The children who come to us they say,
almost every month she is having a cystitis.
That means the treatment given for the
cystitis originally was wrong,
breaking down the immune system so it cannot function anymore, it cannot defend itself.
That breaking down of the immune system is
not necessary to bring out cystitis again.
If the organism is weak instead of
cystitis it may bring psoriasis out.
If the organism is even less strong
then the child becomes irritable
and then we'll have a Vertatrum album
case, mentally disturbed.
So the cystitis or the tendency
of the organism to get cystitis here
and treated wrongly and what we call suppressively then it changes into restlessness.
Cystitis into restlessness. So the child
comes to us because it is hyperactive child
and we treat hyperactive child and in the course of treatment we get back the original cystitis
then we have to treat correctly the cystitis.
In these cases that we have been treating,
you remember the case with
the severe skin eruption?
Then you remember the other case that she was having rheumatoid arthritis diagnosed?
Then the terrible headaches, day and night.
Headaches all the time.
The original disturbance is the same; manifesting itself one time as rheumatoid arthritis,
the other time as severe lumbago with
sciaticaand then as headaches.
And you will see headaches which are treated correctly, then they go away from here
and then the lumbago starts. I think that was
the case also that you have seen live in here.
They go like this for months, for years, having lumbagos and you treat correctly the lumbagos
and then it starts going out from where it started. What it was there? Leucorrhea, originally,
that it was closed. It can cause a lot of problems, hormonal problems, mental problems,
emotional problems. And leucorrhea
which is treated with antifungal drugs
or leucorrhea which is suppressed, then this suppression of leucorrhea it will cause that.
The suppression of tremendous perspiration; that means there is a disturbance, the organism
cannot process the toxins and it has to
take them through perspiration.
You don't like this, you put anti-perspirants, you stop the perspiration. You are going to have
problems; that means that offensive
perspiration with a lot of toxins.
That means that the kidneys are not able
to clean the blood as they should.
That means you have a weakness
already in the kidneys.
You stop the perspiration, the kidneys break down and you see stones  after 10 years.
And you have the kidneys colics.
Eventually through treating the kidneys colics,
you have to arrive at a stage where the
organism is strong enough now
through perspiration to get rid of the toxins.
Then if you are lucky as a patient and as
a doctor also, you find further the remedy
and then you even treat the
original problem that was there.
This is what we call suppression and
we see it again and again and again.
What I wanted to say, apart from that,
is that in her case yesterday,
we decided we don't know the
remedy because it was not clear.
Nobody could say that this
is a clear case of Puls.
because she had some opposing symptoms.
She had 2 keynotes of Sulph, 2 keynotes
of Puls, 2 keynotes of Phos
and you say now, 'where am I going?'
What happened is that she took two drugs
like Nat-m untimely and also Nux -v.
These two remedies they have disturbed
the development of the case.
Every case has a development and this
can be disturbed by even a wrong potency.
It is not that our remedies will create side effects.
They will not create side effects; that's why
we say these are innocent remedies.
They are not so innocent as they appear.
The moment they change the pattern
and they disturb the development then you
are not able to continue with the case
Like in her case and you say, 'I don't know'.
So don't be in a hurry, take this, take that.
Even if you have and accident, take Arnica.
No, I don't believe in that.
You have to have a reason for taking the remedy. If you have a reason and the remedy is correct
then it helps the correct development
of the case, even if it is an acute remedy.
An acute remedy is not
apart from the whole case.
Because you have to imagine a basic disturbance in the organism;
then it changes expressions.
Then one time, the expressions of this basic disturbance it might be continuous,
acute conditions, pharyngitis, pharyngitis.
She gets to a point where she
gets bronchitis, bronchitis.
Mental cases that are treated,
they are going to state of bronchitis.
Vertigo, severe vertigo, then you treat
these vertigos and she wakes up
on mental level and then you see bronchitis.
Now treat wrongly the bronchitis, the vertigo
will be back. Treat correctly the bronchitis
and the person gets better and better.
That is what we are learning here and that
is why we try to be as careful as possible.
I know it's very difficult, I know it. Don't be disappointed because it's very difficult.
I admit that but it is very rewarding in the end.
There are laws which are revealing
themselves; otherwise we are in the dark.
You see in 1974, in the International
Congress in the Liga, in Washington D.C.,
out of my pushing behind the scenes, (because
I was always working behind the scenes),
I tried to persuade the Liga to put some standards in education, back in 1974.
The English who were dominating
the scene by that time,
there was a certain doctor, after he heard standards are going to be imposed,
he was very sharp tongued,
he got up and gave a speech.
And finally concluded that each country
should have its own laws for Homeopathy.
I said, that's very interesting, ok maybe, I said,
in England the law of gravity does not work.
So doctor T. can jump in England from the fifth floor without anything happening to him.
In England the laws do not work, what is this?
And then it was said in a
meeting of 300 medical doctors
and nobody got up and say, why don't
you jump from the fifth floor in England.
Don't do it here because in America the laws
are working; so we don't need to have a funeral.
When you do something and you
enter an area where you're understanding
the laws and you apply the
laws the sense is totally different.
The confusion starts disappearing. It does not mean that all the confusion will go out.
I want to answer also in the other problem with vaccination.
I have written my ideas in the
Science of Homeopathy.
By that time, I'm talking about in 1970
when I was writing the book,
I had understood certain things theoretically,
I had understood them on a practical manner
because I could see what was
happening, I was observing.
Theoretically I made a model which I have written down and it says that in vaccination
you have several groups of people.
The first group is the one group which is very sensitive to that particular epidemic.
This group during the epidemic will get the disease because it's very sensitive.
It has a predisposition for this disease.
This group will get it.
Now this group gets the vaccination because
it's very sensitive to that particular vaccination,
then the reaction is very
strong and what it does?
A percentage of this group is dying or has permanent side effects from the vaccination.
This group is in danger. Not everybody
dies from that group with the vaccination.
The rest of the group will have
permanent side effects.
That means the organism is so violated
that in order to counteract the vaccination,
produces antibodies which in consequence
have severe side effects like encephalitis,
encephalomyelitis, nephritis etc.
So apart from the deaths, we have
severe problems with side effects
or the long term effects.
The long term effects mean you get chronic headaches, you see a smallpox vaccination
created a lot of problems that usually were counteracted by Thuja and that's how
it came to our book the idea of vaccination
and Thuja. It's a smallpox vaccination that was
many times counteracted by Thuja; that means these people they had effects that stayed for life.
That means they became sick for life.
Therefore they were protected.
Because now after the vaccination
they were too sick to get it.
That is why they were protected.
The second group in which you will see
a superficial reaction but strong, fever,
the organism reacts against it, raises the fever
and then these people counteract
the effect of the vaccination.
These people are not anymore vaccinated.
They don't have antibodies,
because they are the group who have
less predisposition for that disease.
It's a disease which is not very
sensitive for the organism,
therefore the organism pushes out
and takes out the effect of the vaccination.
So this group will develop an immediate reaction and will be spared of the chronic effects.
And there is a third group
that has no reaction at all.
They are vaccinated and not reaction.
That means two things.
One is that the organism is too sick
already to have a reaction,
therefore because it's too sick,will never
get the disease during the epidemic.
this group will never get the epidemic. This group stays without any effect,
the epidemic comes and goes and this percentage of population remains
untouched either because they are very sick
or because their organism is strong enough
and has no predisposition at all towards this disease. It's like nothing, they don't pay attention.
The vaccination doesn't concern them.
From this group maybe some people will get it, (esp.those who had the strongest reaction)
during the epidemic, might had gotten
the epidemic in a mild degree;
these people will get the
epidemic in severe degree.
Some of them they will die during the epidemic.
These are the facts according to my understanding and I have recorded them,
I have written them down, back 20 years ago.
And I was talking about these ideas 20 years
ago when nobody was talking about this.
Then the question is what shall
we do as a medical society?
What are the decisions to be taken,
who is going to be vaccinated?
What I said, always publically
when I speak about it,
it is that first we realize that this is the problem.
That by vaccinating this group you are
risking the life of certain of the people
and you are risking also the
life becoming miserable.
You make side effects that will last a whole life.
From this group also several people
will also have long side effects.
From this group we are concerned,
they are very sick.
Have you ever seen a schizophrenic
to take an epidemic? Never!
Have you seen any person on last stage
of diseases to get an epidemic? Never.
An epidemic the children usually get or grown ups who have a strong organism
and who have a predisposition.
It's very interesting, I will give you an example
to show you how the organism is working.
Here we discuss everything.
My nephew, my sister's son got diphtheria
at the age of six.
He was in the hospital, I was outside of the country, I did not participate at all.
About a month ago, my sister developed a very severe pharyngitis with severe pain.
She was in Athens and one of the doctors
said, look at the...
and she was depleted of energy totally
and she started having some kind of dyspnoea.
I said to one of the doctors look and tell me.
He looks and says, she has white membranes.
Then I remembered the incident with diphtheria;
I said to my sister, take Diphtherinum 200.
The next day the doctor said, I couldn't believe it.
She was totally exhausted, the next day the membranes are gone, almost
the pain 80% better and the strength is back. What happened?
.......She did not fall sick because there was
not a total predisposition.
If she was predisposed to diphtheria, she would
get it at the time of the child because she was
nursing him etc. I remember they did not
allow her to go into the hospital and she
was so anxious, she climbed a tree to be
able to see through the window
whether the son was alive.
She belonged to this second group;
that means a little bit of predisposition
but not enough to break out the epidemic in this
organism but somewhere the antibodies were
left in the organism and when the organism
went down andwas exhausted,
then she came up with the idea of diphtheria.
You see, there are such observations
which have brought me to these ideas,
and I made that model and
nobody of course pays attention
to that apart from the last few years where people are finally becoming aware that maybe
vaccinations is not such a great idea as we
may have thought. When I was bringing
these ideas back in 1970, 72 etc.
and I was teaching the doctors in Athens
they were looking with great skepticism and the pediatricians always would come up and say:
'what do you suggest?' I said 'I don't know'. Because if you suggest,
don't vaccinate this group, this group will
get the epidemic, if the epidemic comes.
That is another story because several of the epidemics they don't come anymore today.
They have a trend, they come and go.
We have to recognize the trend.
Is the trend for smallpox? Wait it's gone,
don't vaccinate for smallpox, of course.
They think they have vaccinated for smallpox
and they have eliminated it. That is totally wrong.
Small pox has been eliminated
not because of the vaccination
but because the population is too
sick to get it today.
Only strong population can get
an epidemic and then the epidemic
has to have conditions like uncleanliness.
So such epidemics will break out in India, in Pakistan, and in these countries.
Not here because the population in the West
is too sick to be infected by smallpox.
Raise the health of western population and
let them be in not a clean condition
and you will see it coming back.
So more or less this is the model for
me but here what I say,
let's come and discuss, can we find out
through the means we have today
who might be over sensitive to this epidemic?
Maybe there are some parameters,
we can do a research to find out
who are these people who are proned to get
the epidemic and then see what we can do.
How we protect them and why we
vaccinate these people?
Or maybe another idea will come up if
it is understood by medical researchers.
Hygenic measures, better
food, better conditions
raising the health of these people to the
extend you bring them to the second group.
-George, what do you think happened few years ago when the plague came back to India?
What made them healthy enough to
get that disease back?
-Indians according to my understanding,
because I lived in India, as you know,
the Indians at this moment they are still
suffering a lot on the physical level.
They are not sick in mental-emotional.
The Indian race is healthier than the
European or the American. They are healthier.
The Chinese also are healthier, the Malaysians are healthier and therefore they get
these epidemics in these countries. The African people are healthier; that's why they will get these epidemics.
You will say ok but during these epidemics, in cholera you have so many people dying etc.
But you cannot decide to make the whole population sick in order to prevent an epidemic
from breaking out. This is not the right way
of thinking, this is my concern,
and this is what I'm saying. Is it true that this
is a true model? Do you accept it?
I have written once to the W.H.O.
and discuss these matters,
of course I did not receive any answer.
I say, we discuss.
Bring your experience and we from the homeopathic point of view,
we bring our experience and then we conclude.
What are you doing? The whole population have been vaccinating, bringing it down, down, down.
And you see old people at the age of 25.
I tell you, people at the age of 25
they will not be able to have sex, they will not
be able to function properly, their mind will be
twisted and all kinds of crazy ideas will
jump up and flow all over the places.
-If we have a very good immune system we could not get any effect not only in epidemic
but even in tetanus and rabbies.
This occupies my mind always.
-The rabies is a very virulent organism which is like putting hydrocyanic acid into the blood.
If you put hydrocyanic acid into the blood, you cannot say I give you a remedy and save you.
Forget it. The process of decomposition is so
fast that you don't have chance, you will die.
Or you take strong poison whatever it might be.
A strong poison is a different thing.
and rabies or tetanus once you get it ok.
But Vangelis was there by the time,
a rusty nail went into my foot,
so deep. Here on the island
there are a lot of goats... and some
Greek doctors were here.
Vangelis was one of them and they saw
this... 'you vaccinate, you vaccinate'.
I said I don't know, if I get it I will see what
I will do and I did not vaccinate and of course
nothing happened because I'm still here.
But suddenly everyone was waiting 48 hours.
Ok, 42,43, 45, 46 they created a
situation around me, it was terrible.
If it's my karma, my fate to die from tetanus
I will die from tetanus nothing can save me.
How many people are vaccinated and
what is the effect of tetanus?
Somebody was telling me in this seminar,
he was vaccinated for tetanus. Relapse.
-What about rabies?
-Rabies? If you are bitten by a dog
who is proven to have rabies,
you have to have the treatment,
it's not a vaccination.
Once you have the rabies, there is a
treatment, I believe there is today, I don't know.
By that time there was a treatment in the
peritoneal cavity where they put a lot of
injections and shake the organism
very very strongly.
So once you get rabies, you have to be
treated of course, I don't say don't be treated.
But there is no vaccination for rabies.
You see when I was in India I heard of two
cases from an older teacher whom
I had there, that he had two rabies cases.
That he claimed to have treated
with Homeopathy, I don't know.
I did not see any, either tetanus or rabies.
But from the description of tetanus it's a terrible thing to see. Who have seen a tetanus case?
Three. How many were saved?
Two died. Who has seen somebody
saved from tetanus?
How many deaths? 2, 10, 5, 1, 1.
From this little statistics we show that
the rate of death in tetanus is more than 60%.
I don't remember what the books say.
The disease Farber granulomatosis is called. Has anybody heard of that disease?
Deficiency of ceramidase.
It is in children, they die within a few years, affecting the joints, the vocal chords
and some spleen or liver eventually affection.
It was the case I was talking about as being diagnosed as rheumatoid arthritis.
-During my work in Peru I saw a lot of cases of poliomyelitis, people that have been crippled for the rest of their lives.
-Can you repeat?
-During my work in Peru, in South America,
I've seen a lot of cases of poliomyelitis,
who couldn't walk anymore and I think it's high risk to say just let the people get this illness.
-Now coming back to this idea.
She says in Peru she saw a lot of cases
of side effects of poliomyelitis.
In Peru, not in here.
Here you will hear one or two cases.
Even that they were vaccinated,
belonging to this or to this group
but in our societies you will not
see these epidemics anymore.
You will not see because we are
not as healthy as the Peruvians.
The Peruvians are very healthy people
I can tell you.
In our society we are mentally-emotionally disturbed and we cannot get these diseases.
That's why the children get them
because they are strong.
You saw some cases in Peru or in India and then what happens with us? It's a different matter.
We better bring up our organism to
the state where we can get it again.
and you will see also the same diseases will
be returning to us but in a modified way
and then we will have a problem
treating such diseases.
You will see Tuberculosis coming
back with a different species of bacillus.
And then it will be much worse
and much more virulent.
And you will see a breaking up of tuberculosis that kills thousands of people by the year 2005.
These are questions that we have to be aware.
-Is it a sign of health or a sign of sickness
that so many people in Africa die from AIDS?
-Ok, my theory for AIDS, you know
if you read the book, is that AIDS
is the result of breaking down of the immune system because of repeated antibiotics
in cases of syphillis and gonorrhea. In Africa there is a fantastic sexual liberation.
The structures of tribes living under
certain laws are breaking down,
they go to the cities, they get
extreme syphillis and gonorrhea.
How do we know? If you go to
the statistics of W.H.O.
you'll see that deaths from syphillis and gonorrhea  are tremendous.
They are dying from syphilis and gonorrhea
in Africa more than anybody else,
that means they get a lot of
syphilis and gonorrhea.
They get the worst of antibiotics coming from the West, that have the worse side effects,
that means breaking down the immune
system, instead of throwing them into the sea,
they go over the sea, to Africa.
And then people go over the counter,
they don't have doctors,
'give me this medicine' and take, take, take
and they broke down the immune system.
AIDS is nothing but a disguise
of venereal disease.
Whether it is syphilis or gonorrhea it
doesn't matter, it's not important.
It is the organism who can get syphillis and gonorrhea and treated repeatedly by antibiotics,
their immune system breaks down
and they will develop AIDS.
That is why in my understanding, AIDS is so exposed because they broke down the
immune system by taking a lot of
antibiotics and a lot of venereal diseases.
Go to the Arab countries and you see no AIDS because the moral structures  are still very strong.
You go with the wrong man or the wrong woman and finished, no AIDS, nothing. Cut and finish.
In BBC I saw a man who went with a
princess, they cut his throat because
he had an affair with the princess. I was in London and I remember the Saudi's
were trying to influence the BBC and
say not to show this, not to show this.
They offered money not to show this.
The BBC said forget it, we will show it.
I have seen it with my own eyes.
They had a hidden camera and they took this and they had the video and they showed it.
But in Arab countries, no AIDS.
Because sexual liberation is not yet there.
Go to the Haiti, near New York where
Americans go there, you understand what
happens there, it's the highest level,
why? Because men are bi-sexual.
They go with homosexuals,
then they go with prostitutes
then the prostitutes go with normal
men and they have this explosion.
Because the homosexuals from NY
they go to Haiti to have a nice time.
In '83 when I saw the statistics, now it is covered up, in '83 it was very clear for every researcher
that the high risk group was the group
of male homosexuals, why?
Because I could see in their history several times infections from syphillis and gonorrhea.
Now the whole issue has been covered and nobody knows what is going on anymore.
Not for me; I still say this the truth, this is what has happened and I will insist that this is
what happens until they can prove to me something else.
That rings me a bell, Farbry's, Farbry's.
So you challenge my memory !
There was another issue with her again,
exactly the same, where I said,
amyotrophic lateral sclerosis has severe cramping pain, there was Vangelis
who is a psychiatrist and neurologist
and Alexander. They said no, no, no.
Alexander did not say no. But he said
'no in ALS you do not get severe pains'.
I said, ok Alexander go to the lexicon and Alexander comes, she reads no pain.
I said, 'no'. You are reading wrongly.
Because ALS is called Charcot
and there is another disease
Charcot Marie-Tooth
which is another type of disease totally
different than the Charcot, the ALS.
And then she was reading from there and I said, 'no you are reading wrongly, give me'
and then we read the ALS and of course in
the progress stages you have severe pain.
I knew it because I had several cases
which I treated for tremendous pains,
never mind what the books tell. I have seen it.
And then she made a mistake,
you made it for a second time.
-If I may say so concerning the Peruvians the answer is not satisfying for me because
we cannot risk so much for these people. I also remember measles epidemia which killed
whole tribes which have been living in the Amazonian forest and they did not have
any contact with the civilization.
- Which disease?
- Measles.
-With measles it killed the whole tribe?
I don't believe that, no. A whole tribe?
-I mean I have to imagine that genetically
they have all the same defect
which I don't believe this is not according to
the law of nature because of the selection.
-When the Spanish people came to Mexico,
the Indians died of plain coryza,
thousands of them. Of plain coryza!
-They died.
-And they said it is because our population
they get antibodies immediately
and they did not have any of these antibodies.
-Most probably instead of coryza they could say, influenza. Most probably it was influenza.
-But for the whites it was a small
thing and they, died of it.
Maybe with the measles in those populations
which are healthy populations, is similar.
-Anyhow what is a fact is that immunization
is not a simple issue and it should be seriously
discussed by medical authorities and governments and take different decisions than
the ones that they're applying and they are forcing the population to take this immunization.
I don't agree with this practice and I believe that we should sit down
and discuss about these issues
and find out really what happens