We're going to talk about acute prescribing during chronic treatment.
I'm going to give you today something
which I have never taught so far.
I'm going to give you my
experience of all these years.
On this subject I have talked about,
20 years ago and I gave general
lines but as the years went by,
I have made different observations
and I came down to exact situation: what we should do when we have a chronic case
going on and a treatment is
necessary for an acute condition.
Usually what we do, the patient telephones
he says I have a cold, give me my remedy
and we prescribe. We do this but it is better to know what we are doing when we do that.
We have to know the possibilities of spoiling
the case to what extent we may spoil it,
to what extent may help when shall we prescribe, when we shall not prescribe.
What are the questions that you have
when you had cases that are under treatment
that need some acute prescribing?
What are the questions that you are having?
-What's going on at the moment and what are the symptoms prominent for the time being?
You see first of all we have to put the right questions to understand what is going on.
Which are the right questions?
You are in a position now to think for the
different problems that we are having.
-Most important for me is how severe the current disease is and how much the patient is suffering.
If he doesn't suffer so much and it is
not so severe I will wait with them;
if it's getting severe I will look for the prominent symptoms and treat along these symptoms.
It could be a sign also of changing the
chronic case and I have to combine it.
-I think it's important when did I give the last remedy. Did I give it 3 days ago or is it 3 months?
-I would ask him if he had known those symptoms already before, long time before.
-An aggravation of the symptoms of
the chronic disease in the acute exacerbation.
If the symptoms of the chronic disease
just became aggravated now.
-What would you do?
-Then I may consider to give the same
remedy and not change to another remedy.
-For me the question would be: is the
acute disease part of the remedy
I have given for the chronic case?
-Very good questions but not all the
questions that you have to ask.
There are a lot of questions
to be asked in that situation.
I want to give you a general idea
according to which we shall be working.
First of all I will separate
4 groups of diseases.
You remember the levels on which we have
been working which are 12 levels symbolically.
I will separate these 12 levels in 4.
So each level which we are going to talk
will contain 3 of the levels
we'll have been talking about.
So this first group between 1 and 3rd
level, has organisms
which are quite strong and in
these organisms acute diseases,
first of all are not frequent and also not severe.
A strong organism is not in danger
of having pneumonia and die.
A weak organism there is a possibility
That is why they say for old people be
afraid of pneumonias
because the organism of the old
people usually is weak.
As the organism gets weaker
and weaker what happens?
Here in the next group where we have
organism which are weaker and weaker,
number 4,5 and 6 level,
then in this group of diseases we observe
acutes are becoming frequent and more severe.
Now see the general idea I want you to be
very clear of this general idea because all
we're going to talk about is based on this idea.
As the organisms are becoming more
and more deeper disturbed,
what happens is that the acutes
which the organisms used to get
eventually disappear or if
they appear they are mild.
So on group 3 where we have 7, 8
and 9 we have mild acutes or no acutes.
And then when we go to the 4th group
where we have the severe chronic diseases,
the end states of diseases, the severe mental disorders, we see no acutes for years.
So here in these levels, no acutes.
As a general idea we are talking, I have not
given you details. We'll give examples etc.
-Do you consider children between the age
of 6 months and 2 years that have a lot of
virus infections, do they belong
to the 2nd group?
-Second, yes. Children with acute frequent cystitis, otitis, frequent whatever it is,
they don't have a strong
organism and as they will grow,
they will go either one direction or the other,  depending on the treatment.
Children with so many acutes, depending on the treatment, they may go down to these levels
and eventually stop having acutes
but we have personality disorders.
We have some kind of severe, epilepsy, asthma.
-But a child of this age have frequent
disease but very often not severe.
-Not severe.
-Very often they don't need any treatment at all.
-I don't know such cases but if you say frequent but not severe, still they will belong to this group.
What I want you also to be aware is this: When the children belong to this group, in this group I
In this group consider for instance normal
for a child to have the epidemic diseases.
These are good organisms and these
children they get the vaccinations
and we observe the child has no epidemic diseases. They have brought the child actually
to a group which is quite lower and
most probably if it goes right down
here with no acutes at all, that's very bad
but the child's defences are going down
and usually they bring the child
down to these levels where they start
having all kinds of different acutes
and most probably they will develop
allergic conditions or hay fever etc.
So you have in your mind this idea
when you treat and then in the history
of the case that you take, you see
how the child was developing
from what kind of acutes to what kind of chronic conditions which bring the child to be treated.
Then in the very beginning
you see frequent acutes,
you know what type of
a person you are treating.
If the child was healthy had his
epidemics and went over them
the child belongs to upper groups and he will react very well to the homeopathic remedy.
Of course, here in this group we have easy success and in this group also.
From this group onwards we will
see what kind of successes we have.
When we are talking about acute conditions during chronic treatment,
we have to be very careful in evaluating
what is going on when an acute comes.
In this group the meaning of an acute, the evaluation of an acute has a totally different
meaning than an acute in number 3 or 4
group. The evaluation is totally different.
So weaker and weaker, more and more
acutes then eventually less and less acutes
then no acutes finally. That is the idea.
The second factor that you are
evaluating in a chronic treatment
is whether your remedy has acted or not.
If your remedy has acted, what it means?
It has boosted up the defense mechanism
of the organism. Therefore, tell me
what will happen in the 1st group
if you give the correct homeopathic remedy?
These people they get an acute once
twice the year, right? They get a few acutes.
You give the correct remedy, what happens?
The acutes should not appear anymore
because the organism is strong
enough and even the acute is mild.
So therefore in these upper groups, the acutes after your homeopathic remedy are lessened.
They should not have neither so severe
nor so frequent acutes under
the correct homeopathic treatment.
But what we observe in group
number 3 and number 4.
Here we have an epileptic child
who gets some colds, usually mild.
The appearance now, after your treatment,
the appearance of an acute in these groups
has a totally different meaning. The appearance is a sign that your remedy has acted in depth.
It doesn't matter whether the patient
says, 'I'm better, worse', they're complaining.
The moment that in these groups where they had no acutes in the last 6 months or the last year,
here usually the story is:
'I used to get acutes but not lately'.
'How lately?' 'Since one year I don't.
Since two years, mild'.
In this group when you see
after your remedy an acute appearing
then it's a very good sign.
What you have to do?
It's different what you have
to do during the acutes in these groups
than what you have to do in these
groups during the acute condition.
It doesn't matter that we are on
the telephone and we prescribe, right?
Unless you know very well what is going on,
you are bound to prescribe.
They will tell you 'I have a terrible pimple',
' Ah, you have a pimple, take Calc-s'.
'I had a little accident and I turned my finger',
'Ok, take Arn. this, that, Rhus-t, Bry.'.
' Ah I'm better, thank you very much'.
Yes he is better but what happens in
the organism is another story.
So we have to know when to give. We make mistakes, there is no question about that
but we have to know we made a mistake and why we made a mistake and how to correct it.
Because you will see treating cases
and they will do beautifully and
suddenly the case will be spoiled
and then you don't know why
and then you try, you say 'did you drink coffee?
They say, 'no I didn't drink coffee but
I went through a coffee shop and it was
smelling very strongly, is that possible?', 'Yes!'
I mean you know it's a lie. It's a lie, the
smelling of coffee cannot affect the organism
but you find an excuse for your mistakes.
It's a good excuse.
You have told them not to take the
chewing gum, 'did you eat chewing gum?'
'No, but I ate an ice cream and it was
moca ice-cream', 'That's the problem'.
That's not the problem, the
problem is that during the acutes
acutes you have prescribed
the wrong medication.
So you think now is more clear?
-In the groups 3 and 4, if I have severe acute disease, do I have to prescribe a remedy or not?
-We will be discussing that, I didn't finish,
this is the beginning.
And I can warn you this is the most
interesting information for you
to prescribe correctly but it is
complicated and when we finish
maybe you will feel your head go like this.
That's why I go slowly so you can
digest what we are talking.
And I would like to hear
your feedback at the moment.
What do you think? What questions
are coming to your mind so far?
-George, I give a remedy and the remedy is acting and the patient is coming 2 days after
the remedy with a cold for example.
-The first group will shall be
discussing will be from 1-3 days
after your prescription of the
remedy, you have an acute.
We shall be discussing it into
the different groups what it means.
It's a good question, you give the
remedy and the next day they phone
'I have a cold, I have an acute,
a cystitis this, that'.
What does it mean? Correct question.
-If I have a child which has been vaccinated and it has not had any of the usual children diseases,
can I then be sure that it is
due to the vaccinations?
-No, you can not be sure. Never you can
be sure of anything in the human body.
The human body is so complicated
that it can change course of action,
as I have said, from many many factors
but we give general sign posts, guidelines.
As I said many times that: we give
a stimulus to the defense mechanism
and the defense mechanism
is bringing up better state of health.
That stimulus could come from different
quarters. There are different therapies
but I can tell you something which
can be every day experience,
for instance you don't have money
and suddenly you win a lottery
and your health may improve in general. Because all this heaviness,
'how do I get money, how do I feed my family',
then the lottery comes and all this stress
is going away from the organism and the organism by itself, an organism that belongs
only to these two groups, not to that,
such stimulus can affect problems
that belong to these two levels.
Another condition which makes you feel much better, I mean you are tired and you don't want
to live, you have some kind of depression,
your liver is malfunctioning and the digestion
is not so good, different foods are affecting you.
This is a syndrome which cannot be
put into a category of a pathology,
yet you don't have chronic fatigue syndrome,
you don't have an ulcer etc.
But there is a syndrome where you feel
rotten and suddenly you meet one nice night
a woman or a boy and there is a rapport and suddenly you wake up in the morning and you
are not tired. You wake up and you want to
go to work and in the night you want
to meet and if this continues that stimulation
from both sides, this is a therapeutic state.
In the same way I have seen many times
people going into a revelation from God,
whatever they maybe, and then this stimulation that God is with me, that I'm with God
this stimulation is strong, I have seen
in the American television,
you see people getting up and say I feel great.
It is a similar stimulation of the defence
mechanism but remember if this happens
then your patient belongs to these 2 groups.
In this group, what is going to happen?
Can anybody tell me what is going to happen
under such stimulus in these two groups?
-The people easier get infections?
-No.
-The acute disease gets its stronger expression.
-I think to these people it can
lead to an aggravation.
-No.
-I think you have an amelioration
for a short period of time and
then you have an aggravation again.
-That is going to happen, very good.
You see little ones are sometimes....
In these conditions the underlying pathology
is such that will not allow for a constant
or complete amelioration, it will
allow for a short amelioration.
You see the idea of ahhh, then it is relieved
for a period of time, then, back again.
Here in the last stages actually such stimulus is very very difficult to bring any kind of reaction,
in the very last stages I'm talking about
11,12, near death, I mean hope is lost.
-There are reports about cancer cases who have cured themselves with autogenic training
and can we say that these cancer
cases are from the second group?
-No, the cancer cases, as we have discussed many times there are different types of cancer,
the cancer cases which are curable
belong actually to this group, the 1st group.
What kind of diseases you will see
in this group here?
What are the conditions for which the patient
will come to be treated in a homeopath?
Just mention a few, just to know if you understand the meaning.
-Like smallpox and also might be
frequent cold in winter.
-No, for common cold nobody will ever
come to the homeopath for the first time.
Just forget it. Usually they will come
for a chronic condition.
What type of chronic condition you will get?
-I think skin diseases.
-Diseases of the skin, yes.
-Cases of chronic mental state which they never had an acute disease like autism for example.
I had a case with a child who had
autism and after the homeopathic
remedy he developed frequent acute diseases.
-No, these cases do not belong to the first group.
I'm asking what type of pathology
you will place in the first group?
-Migraine headaches?
-Yes.
Acute tonsillitis?
-Tonsillitis is an acute condition. I'm talking about chronic conditions which come to be treated,
tonsillitis is an acute condition that may
appear. Still my question is not clear.
-Allergic diseases? Conjuctivitis,
if it's deeper like asthma.
-Yes, chronic conjunctivitis.
-Chronic rhinitis?
-Yes.
-Any kind of pains without
pathologoanatomical correlation.
-Yes but give me some examples.
-Back pains for example.
-Lumbago, yes.
-Duodenal ulcer, a mild one yes.
-Warts.
-Sinusitis.
-Irregular menstruation and
premenstrual syndrome.
-Hay fever?
-Hay fever I will not put it on this group.
It will be coming down.
-Affections of the joints?
-Yes like arthritis, rheumatism, rheumatic
pains, arthritic pains, not osteoarthritis.
Osteoarthritis will come on the lower part
of the second group or on this group,
even in the third group.
-Disorders like diarrhea and constipation.
-Chronic diarrhea and constipation. Simple.
The moment they become chronic
severe spastic colitis or ulcerative colitis,
they enter into this group. Spastic colitis
and uncreative colitis will come here.
Give me some diseases which belong
to this second group like hay-fever,
spastic colitis, asthma, asthmatic
conditions but not severe.
The moment asthmatic condition becomes
really severe they descend into the third group.
Fever convulsions like epileptic conditions
with all kinds of convulsions yes.
-Chronic cystitis, chronic bronchitis.
- Yes.
-I think palpitation goes to the first group.
-Simple palpitation can go there but once the palpitation becomes more complicated
where we have arythmias and functional disturbances of the heart, it will go to 2nd group.
Where you will place the chronic fatigue syndrome which we see today quite frequently?
Who says second group? Who says second group? Who says third group? Good, ok.
-Hypertension I would put on the second group.
-Hypertension once it is simple idiopathic hypertension, no real cause,
we may place it on the second group here.
But if hypertension, esp. if the lower part is
very high indicating most probably sclerosis
of the arteries then you go to the third group.
You will see it is very interesting what
I tell you, you will see it in your practice.
For instance the person will come with hypertension and I say the peripheral blood
pressure is high indicating arteriosclerosis
and you will ask them if they get acutes
and you will see the acutes have minimized. Anyhow as a rule, the moment you hear that
'I was having frequent colds etc. and since one year I don't get so frequently', you calculate
from that time the organism has gone down
to level three. Pathology is more strong
and you are going to have a difficulty in treating such cases, it's not going to be an easy case.
Whenever the acutes have minimized while they were there before, you have a difficult case.
Can you mention a few diseases that
you will see in this fourth group?
-Schizophrenia yes, manic depression,
juvenile diabetes.
-Depression with severe suicidal tendencies
it will go to the lower part of the third group,
it is manageable but sometimes it is quite deep and you can say it belongs to the fourth group.
-Difficulties in concentration and forgetfulness.
-Difficulties in concentration is curable and it belongs to the 2nd, at the most the 3rd group.
The 4th group we have deep pathology and you have to understand what is deep pathology.
-What about the autommune diseases like
the Chron's disease, the multiple sclerosis?
Ok, the Chron's disease where we have ulcerative colitis, where it'll be?
Third group.
-Multiple sclerosis which group?
-Fourth.
-No, multiple sclerosis belongs to this group initially as it is left to go on for years then
it drops in the fourth level and
it becomes incurable.
In the beginning state of multiple sclerosis
it is curable with Homeopathy.
I try to give you my experience
but it is not possible to give it.
That' s why I put the questions
if you get the ideas.
-The functional deterioration of organs.,
ex. when kidneys are deteriorated.
-Yes, severe nephritis in which heart diseases,
in which cases we don't have the possibility to
bring about a cure, belong to this.
But nephritis in the beginning belongs
to number 3 group, it's curable.
Heart conditions in the beginning stages
belong here. When pathology is established,
in the beginning stages if we catch it most of them are curable and belong to the 3rd group.
Either the first level 7,8 some times
9 which is very close to 4th group.
- In number 4 Alzheimer's disease?
-Alzheimer's definitely belongs to
here last or it is going there.
I think it's the same for other diseases like
CHD -can drop from 3 to 4- and cancer.
-AIDS?
-Lower 3 to 4 and what you will see
in most of the cases of AIDS,
at least in the beginning stages
where AIDS was developing as an
epidemic what was the observation?
That these people with strong organisms,
they were getting gonorrhea, syphillis
and sexually transmitted diseases
very frequently. And they took antibiotics and more antibiotics and they treated and treated.
Most of AIDS cases have come down from
no.1 to no.4 due to excessive treatment.
Have you digested this?
We're going to a new idea.
If no.3 group gets an acute which is not mild,
sometimes they can get an acute
which is not mild, then this acute
be life threatening, it's going to kill the person.
Here is the confusion of Medicine.
You see we had this example with the last President of Democracy of Greece, Karamanlis.
He entered the hospital with
bronchitis at the age of 92
and immediately jumped with
antibiotics, what happened?
The organism went a little bit up
and back again, then more antibiotics,
a little bit up and back again.
More antibiotics, the kidneys
start breaking down, then more antibiotics
the heart started breaking down.
Actually in two weeks you had him supported
for his lungs, for his kidneys,
supported for his heart, 10 days later he died.
Now because his organism was 92
he was belonging to this group.
If we were called to treat him
homeopathically there were more chances
of surviving than allopathically. Of course the chance was also to die under homeopathic
treatment but since his organism was strong enough even in 92 and not having much acutes.
But the moment he gets an acute here,
it is serious.
So in these groups in 3 and 4, if by chance an acute becomes very strong it's life threatening.
In the mental asylum you will see a schizo-phrenic getting a high fever 40-41 degree,
got a pneumonia, he's going to die.
What will happen if we give homeopathic treatment to such a case?
Maybe there is a chance because all
these people they have a chance with the
correct homeopathic treatment, one remedy,
the second correct, the third correct.
To raise eventually and to have
what we call miracle cures,
it's very difficult, not always you can do.
That's why we cannot say, ok leave it
and we'll jump into the picture and
we'll cure the person.
You have to know where he belongs this person and to know the severity and to know how much
serious the condition is and not superficially.
People having seen some cure of
cancer they say, we can cure cancer
and of course the person dies.
So we have to understand really what is
going on before we claim anything.
Where will you place rheumatoid arthritis?
-In the second group if
is a healthy organism.
Third group?
-All collagen diseases, like ulcerative colitis, like lupus erythymatosus, like rheumatoid arthritis,
like psoriasis belong to the third group.
Difficult to be treated and
really bring them to total cure.
-In which group would you place
a progressive paralysis?
-For instance to talk more specifically,
ALS, severe neuromuscular disease
belongs to the fourth group, forget the cure.
Myasthenia, myopathy, they are coming
lower third group to the fourth.
Neuromuscular diseases of
any degenerative kind,
they belong to the lower 3rd
group or even to the 4th.
You are going to battle in such
cases keeping them in this level.
Even if you keep them steady or you
improve them a little it's a big success
but to expect that you will cure
Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, forget it.
-The hyperactive children do
they belong to the third group?
-The hyperactive children belong to the 3rd
group but the autistic children belong to the 4th.
-Neurofibromatosis belongs to the third group?
-Lower third to fourth.
You are getting the idea?