If an organism belongs to group 3
and he has asthma is different
than an asthma case in the group 2.
This is the reason why you give a remedy in an asthma case. It's clear and it's cured.
And in another case you don't see
the remedy and you need 3,4,5 remedies
before you can cure such an asthma. And asthma in group 3 will take for a cure
it may take, depending on which level 7,8,
or 9 from 6 months to 3 years of treatment
before you can manage to cure an asthma.
In group 2 with one remedy the asthma is gone.
I had recently a friend who is here and she
was taking allopathic drugs for different things
and eventually she developed asthma.
I asked her how it was in the beginning?
In the beginning it was a hay fever, in spring
time. What type of a hay fever?
It was of the type of what's called, Allium Cepa.
I said that 'if I give you the remedy'...
it was very severe the condition
and she had to take anticongestants
until she developed the asthma.
For the last 2 years she was having asthma, strong organism. You give the remedy and then
after 2 days it was severe rhinitis,
nose running etc. and then what you do?
-Wait?
-She said the asthma was there, the first day even worse, together with the running nose.
Then what will happen?
-If it was the correct remedy then the asthma probably will go away and the rhinitis will remain.
-So the course of action was like this:
First was the asthma, very severe asthma,
to use a few times Aerolin.
Then the third night the hay-fever was reducing and the asthma was reducing and severe
coughing kept her awake the whole night and fourth day the asthma had almost disappeared,
the coughing was going on quite strongly.
Then what happened?
In the meantime the hay-fever was gone.
The hay-fever appeared the first day very strongly and the third day it was gone.
The cough was remaining. What you will do?
You will give something for the cough?
-It's easy to say no here and
when you have the patient is hard.
-She says the whole night could not
sleep; then she took this Aerolin,
Ventolin to get a little bit more air and I waited.
The remedy I gave her was Sulphur to a woman who was very fastidious, keeping clean,
my wife knows her she is a friend of my wife,
she is very particular in cleaning,
cleaning herself and well-dressed and
all that. And my wife objected to Sulphur.
Sulphur to her? Because she
criticizes me, you know?
Every time I give a remedy if she knows the person she says, wait a moment.
She is so neat, so clean, so this, so that.
What is the answer to that?
It's not an acute, it's a chronic condition,
for two years asthma was going on.
What's your answer to that when they
say: this person is so neat, so clean,
why do you prescribe Sulphur?
You cannot give me the the answer?
-She came into the diseased state of Sulphur.
-To the disease state?
To the pathology she means.
-Sulphur has a strong polarity.
-And she is not sick on the emotional level.
-Yes, who said that?
Not every remedy which we prescribe
has to have the mental-emotional picture because on mental emotional level,
the person may be healthy. There is no need for all the Sulphur cases to be dirty or to look dirty
and to be indifferent to cleanliness.
There is no need;
if the other pathology indicates Sulphur
you can give it to a person like that.
There is no problem. Do you understand?
You expect to have the mental-emotional
picture of Sulphur if you say that.
It doesn't have it. On mental-emotional
she's healthy, why she should have it?
She goes like this with the coughing several days. What do you expect has happened?
What will happen? Do you wait?
For how long you wait?
Most probably what is going to happen?
She is aggravated all along. Then the aggravation starts coming down with asthma
then there is the aggravation of the coughing
where the hay-fever is reduced and
you have the coughing.
This is the level we have to bring
her down. What do you do?
The hay-fever is gone, that was
originally 4-5 years ago, very severe.
It appeared very severe the first day,
running everything,
'now I have my hay-fever as well, I have my asthma, my coughing'.
Then asthma was reducing but cough
was remaining strong.
I'm talking about a cough which
she could not lie down at all.
In the middle of the night she had
to walk or stay sitting the whole night.
-If the cough brings the asthma
out and the mucus out is ok.
-No, it was a dry cough.
-Then I must treat after the new symptom.
-I would have to check if the new symptoms appearing give a clear picture of the remedy.
That's what I have to look for.
-Yes, this is what I did. Because she said
she was suffering a lot and it appeared to me
that these symptoms of lying down the coughing was worse, getting up the cough was better.
I gave a remedy which
has these characteristics, which is?
-Cactus, no.
-Coccus Cacti. I gave Cocc-c knowing what? What did I know when I gave this remedy?
-Complementary?
-No, it was not complementary.
I knew that this prescription is wrong.
What I'm doing is wrong but in my
effort to relieve the symptoms
I thought ok to relieve the symptoms.
But then what?
Fortunately what happened?
-Sometimes you give such a remedy
because otherwise the patient
would use some kind of cough medication.
-Yes, she was using the cough medication
but the cough was continuing.
It was very severe cough.
So what happened fortunately?
-She came back to asthma?
- No.
-Probably the hay-fever and the
asthma came back?
-Fortunately no. Fortunately it did not act at all.
Did you take the remedy? Yes I took
the remedy. What happened? Nothing.
It's not a matter of placebo here.
She has been up for 3 nights, coughing.
The fourth night you decide maybe
I have to do something.
And then I did this. I took the main characteristics of the cough and prescribed the remedy.
Fortunately it was totally out
and it did not do anything.
-I want to say that perhaps the
Coccus cacti didn't work
because the vital force has been so stimulated
that it was pushing out the pathology.
-Yes, it could not be suppressed.
That is true in one sense; on the other sense
if the remedy was close enough
would do something. It would suppress a little bit the cough with the possibility of bringing back
the asthma of course. Now fortunately
it didn't do anything and the cough
continued for that night and it
continued for a few more nights
but already from the second or third night
she could say, 'maybe I am a little bit better'.
Even before the Cocc-c. Then it continued
this amelioration of the coughing
and then the sixth or seventh day the
cough was better and then what happened?
- What would have happened if instead of giving her Cocc-c, I would have repeated Sulph?
-Well the answer is difficult because
we had not given Sulphur.
So what I suggest is only a suggestion,
we cannot substantiate it.
Most probably it would not have
done anything. The second possibility is,
it might have helped in case the
organism needed another dose.
The third possibility is that because the Sulphur picture is not anymore there,
it could have disturbed the case.
So the best thing in this
situation is wait and observe.
If you see even a little bit of
improvement, wait, hands off.
Actually this was a mistake,
fortunately not a big mistake.
Otherwise you could change the
case and then you lose the thread.
Then the picture of Pulsatilla will come up and the picture of Hyoscyamus will come up,
you prescribe Pulsatilla, a bit better, you prescribe Hyoscyamus, a bit better and then
you mess up the case. Because we are in a hurry, in one week we must finish the case.
Seventh day she started again with hay-fever.
While this cough was reducing the
hay fever started coming up again.
Now, as I said, the picture of hay fever originally was like All-c. Would you give All-c now?
Fortunately I have told her, if I give you a
remedy you will have back your hay fever.
So when she had the hay fever,
she knew that it was a process of cure;
so she could be more tolerant.
Because the moment they see what you say comes true, the patient is willing to wait.
If they don't know that this comes back,
they are so aggressive in asking medications
that you are pushed to prescribe for the
hay fever and then that is again very
dangerous because you may be pushing
back the whole situation into the asthma.
It's now almost a month, she is well.
She had the hay fever for a few days
and now which is the worst period
for her, May-June she is well,
no medication allopathic or homeopathic.
Just because we know the theory.
If we don't know the theory it is most
probable that we spoil the case.
I, that I know the theory,
I could also have spoiled the case.
That's why I excuse you when you are pressurized and say, give me a remedy.
-May I ask, did the hay-fever come back as severe as before?
-In the beginning when she described the first,
it was worse than even before.
She said, it was terrible. 24 hrs the nose, the eyes, the itching was running and she had
the dyspnoia, why is this? This is interesting.
While she had the externalization with these discharges, still she was having the asthma.
So the organism needs some time because
you say 'ah, it has aggravated the case'.
And I get sometimes people saying 'ah that was an aggravation therefore I give another remedy,
remedy because the asthma was worse'.
It doesn't matter that the hay fever was there.
The hay fever, the asthma,
the coughing, all was worse.
The moment that you see the hay fever, wait.
The appearance of the hay fever makes you believe that the remedy is correct.
- Even when the hay fever
returned after the cough,
was it still so severe as the
first time she had the asthma?
-No, when the hay fever returned it was
milder than the original hay fever.
-Did you prescribe Sulphur after
how many days after the All-c?
-No, I never gave All-c.
When she described to me,
she gave me the impression
that her hay fever 3 years ago was ...
-The asthma which stayed when the hay fever returned might be due to anatomical reason
because when the nose is blocked with
all this discharge and the person is breathing
through his mouth the lower
respiratory tract is in trouble anyway,
so asthma might be part of the blocked-nose.
-Yes but the thing is that the asthma
was worse, the coughing was worse.
You can understand this situation, she didn't sleep at all, just coughing, sitting up, walking,
nose running, it was a terrible situation.
And she was using the sprays during
the whole night. She used them 4 times.
-Could I return to the cough? If it is hard
like you told, strong for several days
it shows up Sulph. symptoms. Could you give Sulph. lower potency like C 10, 12 for one time?
-You may give but as I said, if you give you
have to expect either of the 3 observations
that I gave you; she will become
better, she will be worse or
she will be suppressed or change the picture.
-George, I have an asthma case of
somebody who developed asthma
at the age of 3 years old after measles,
just after she had the measles
she started having the asthma. This person
is 43 and she has the asthma for 40 years;
the asthma is better now but
still it has to be treated.
If you start treating the asthma you will get back to the cause of this? What will happen?
We are not talking about hay fever,
we are talking about measles.
-If the measles were treated by a suppressive measure, that means if during the measles
she took antibiotics and due to this suppression was the asthma caused, then in the process
you will have a similar condition like
measles reappearing and going over.
-You said she had this very hard
cough and hay fever at the same time
and eventually the cough got
lesser and the hay fever came back
with the original symptoms.
But then there was no more asthma there.
- No asthma.
- Then it's clear.
-Excuse me, I have difficulty understanding between group 1 and group 2.
Group 1 apparently has the highest vitality.
I would therefore think that the acutes would be
very severe as opposed to the second
group which we have less vitality?
-Yes they can be severe if you want to
say that 40 degrees of fever is severe.
But in reality it is not severe,
it is not endangering the life.
40 degrees of fever in this group no problem.
40 degrees in this group there is a problem.
40 degrees of fever in this group,
very severe problem.
40 degrees of fever in this
group, they will die.
-I've got one more question
referring to Cocc-c again.
My impression is if you give high dose of the correct remedy and it's acting, is it possible that
the patient goes through states of former remedies which have been necessary?
-Yes it is.
-Just for some days or weeks you see Stannum or whatever and then again, it goes on working?
-Yes.
-Then it doesn't need it? I wait?
-We will be discussing the
reactions in different groups.
The different groups have different
evaluations and different treatment on our part.
We will be discussing because we are
in the beginning of the discussion.
-Did you understand? Severe or serious.
Serious is more correct word.
Here the acutes are not serious. Here,
acutes even they may not appear serious,
they are serious. That means an acute mistreated here, can lead to a chronic condition.
I will give you examples. The case where somebody is treated with antibiotics for sinusitis.
He goes to the medical doctor, he sees
sinusitis, inflammation and gives antibiotics.
This inflammation goes away,
the headaches and all that go away.
After 20 days it appears again.
Again he takes another antibiotic.
After 20 days again sinusitis, he goes
again. This cases eventually will end up to us.
If you see this history you place
this person in this group here
because the organism cannot get
rid and comes back again and again.
The same condition, in this group you
will see little children with cystitis.
Most of the children with cystitis they
will take antibiotics, they will get over it.
They belong to this group.
There are some children with otitis or cystitis, they will get some antibiotics and after a while
the otitis is back, the cystitis is back;
then again antibiotics.
And then you realize that the
organism is going down and down.
The parents are usually worrying,
where this situation goes.
Almost he takes constantly antibiotics
and still nothing happens.
In the meantime changes on the mental-emotional level start where the child
shows disturbances. He
becomes restless, anorectic.
These are the cases that will come to us.
These children do not belong to the first group.
You may have, in treating a cystitis, to take
much longer period, in treating the cystitis or
treating the whole person of course, you take much longer time than if it was on the first group.
You will give a remedy and there is a relapse,
not in one month as it was before but
the relapse comes after 3 months. Then
you see the picture of the cystitis is not exactly
as it was before and you need to
change remedy. You give a second remedy.
-In this case the development of the first
reaction seems very good development.
I don't understand why shall we change the remedy or think about something else because
from asthma to hay fever and then
to cough is a very good development.
And I think when it is so severe this cough maybe we can try another high potency for
example but not go away
from the right development.
-Wait a moment because we will take step by step to see what happens and to evaluate
in each group what happens if the acute after
1-3 days immediately after the remedy develop.
Then the other possibility is after a week,
after 7 days, so there is some lapse of time
of 7 days and then they develop
the acute. Or there is after 1 month.
Some periods of time, just an indication.
The ideas have to be understood;
it doesn't mean after 3 years exactly,
it can be 2,5 years or 1 year and 3 months.
Just as an indication I take these periods of
time to analyze the reaction of the organism
after the chronic case has been treated
by a remedy for his chronic condition.
I go to the first group. If you don't follow something and you don't put a question,
you stay with a block there which is empty. Forget it, you will not be able to follow up.
You have to ask. It is much better if we clarify because somebody may have a question
and the other one says, oh my god I never thought of that and I also have this question.
It is important that we clarify all the
questions before we go further.
It is a complicated issue, I told you from the beginning, and we have to understand it
very well if we want to do serious Homeopathy.
-In America besides indulging in kinky sex,
we have little tolerance for pain.
Often medication is given because the patient can't tolerate it and frequently the pediatric care
with children, parents will give medication while the child can tolerate the pain. But parents can't
tolerate the child's discomfort and
so they give allopathic medication to ease
some of the suffering. To what degree in the terms of the case that you just mentioned,
does the Ventolin interfere with the action
of the Sulphur and can we assess that
so it may be necessary to
give additional remedies?
-You see for the cases we are discussing,
this allopathic medication is in any case
a palliative treatment;
it's not a curative treatment.
So therefore will palliate for a
certain period of time
The Ventolin will make the person able
to breath for 1 or 2 hours, whatever
and then the whole condition
comes back. So therefore,
I would prefer this palliative way of
treatment during the initial aggravation than
me interfering with homeopathic remedies.
I would prefer that if it is not possible to
withstand the pain or the dyspnoea
or whatever that the palliative should
be given, a chemical palliative, instead
of a potency, instead of a high potency.
-Does the palliative ever interfere with the
action of the remedy and in those cases
is it necessary then to reassess the remedy?
-I understand. There is a possibility
that the palliative may interfere
but it will interfere less
than a homeopathic remedy.
Most probably, if it is used
wisely and not aggressively,
it is most probable that it will not interfere.
- I always understood there is a difference between an acute and an aggravation.
Now at the moment I get the impression that it is confused and I would like to have this clarified.
-Very good. When we talk of an acute in this condition, we are talking of acute conditions,
not acute exacerbations of chronic condition.
Today we are talking about acute conditions
but as we go along we have to mention
the acute exacerbation of the cases as well.
For instance in the case I mention to you,
there is no acute disease going on.
There is an acute exacerbation etc.
If this case later on, let us say in 2-3 months,
gets an acute, that means an influenza, a common cold, a cystitis, I have to evaluate
that acute in conjunction with the
acutes she used to have.
I have to evaluate why she
developed this acute now.
To what group she belongs and
why she developed the acute.
Let's go to the first observation,
1-3 days immediately.
You have a case of lumbago,
you treated here and you gave Calc.
And the next day or the day after he
telephones you and tells you: 'I have a cold'.
'What do you have?', 'I have some f
ever, my nose is running' and bla, bla, bla.
What is your evaluation for that situation?
The first thing that you have to think.
You have to ask yourself
several questions first.
You have given Calc., a deep remedy
and he says now he has a cold
and the cold is Ars. or type of Ars.
Are you going to give it?
- No.
- Why not?
The why you don't give it is
important because if you understand
the why then you do the correct thing.
-Normally in the acute you see the remedy. Actually when you have an acute,
normally if you see an acute, you can see
the remedy in the acute because everything
comes up so nicely.
So why to give Arsenicum here?
-So, what do you give?
-I would give nothing.
-In this situation I would always consider a process of discharging as amelioration.
If the person discharges I would
take it as an amelioration.
-As amelioration, yes. Next?
-If the cold is not life threatening?
You can wait and see what happens.
-Yes but nobody gave the correct
answer so far. Try something else.
-Lumbago becoming better?
-In the first 2 days you do not know.
-The lumbago is on a higher physical level than the secretion from the mucus membranes.
So if you have the secretion or some process on a lower level is not as dangerous.
-You have to be very careful because such questions will be put during examinations and
if you don't answer these questions I'm afraid you have a problem. The correct answer is this:
That this group of people have strong
organism, they get acutes sometimes.
This time they got an acute
immediately after your remedy.
What your remedy should have
done in case it was correct?
It should have prevented the person from
having a cold. First, this is general idea.
The second thing: I gave Calc and today
he has a cold. The cold most probably was
preparing from the day before when
he came already to my consulting room.
You gave the remedy, he gets the cold.
Then you have a cold which is starting
before your remedy and it's developing
during the action of your remedy.
Then what is your evaluation? The first evaluation is that the remedy is incorrect
because it allows the cold
to develop immediately.
Therefore it is incorrect, the first thought.
The second thought is: if the cold was developing from the previous day
and now it's going to continue for a few
more days what you have to do?
-I think if the remedy was correct the cold would end sooner than it would have done normally.
-Very good. Again this small one is correct.
If the remedy is correct then what you
have to do is ask this man or woman.
'When you get usually a cold is this cold the same as this time or this time is very mild?'
If the answer is, 'the same', mathematically
your prescription was wrong
or the remedy was not well potentised
or not potentised at all.
You gave a remedy that's nothing.
If the cold is the same as usual
it is as if you have not given a remedy.
But if he describes this time
his cold is much milder, he will say,
'well usually it is by that time it
would have gone down my throat
and now it has only stayed in my nose'. Immediately you wait, don't prescribe.
The chronic remedy which you are giving,
is acting and it will take eventually away
the lumbago and it will take
away the cold as well.
Clear. But to be clear you have to ask
the right questions to the patient.
Your cold was the same
as before or is it better?
This is crucial. This type of things
they have to become automatic almost
because all this is dealt on the telephone.
The patient is not going to come to your
consulting room giving you all this. So you
are busy with a new patient, you get a
telephone call and you have to know
exactly what to ask and what to decide.
We go to the same group of people
but the cold develops 7 days after.
What are the questions that you have to ask and the information you have to get for this condition?
-One more question concerning this cold.
In the case we were talking before,
the asthma with the hay fever,
there it was a chronic treatment.
In the beginning the hay fever reappeared stronger than it had ever been before
but the remedy was correct.
In this case now we have somebody who develops a cold which is worse and
assuming that it's worse than before.
This would mean that the remedy was wrong.
So do I differentiate between reoccurring of
old symptoms in a chronic case and acutes?
-Yes because on the first case with Sulph, we are treating asthma with cough and then appears....
In this case we are treating a lumbago,
during which treatment appears a cold.
It's not an aggravation of the lumbago, it is not
an aggravation of the situation which we treat.
We treat asthma, asthma is aggravated.
We treat lumbago, lumbago is aggravated.
I will give you, if we have time in this course,
if we don't have time in the next course,
I will give you the possible reactions of the organism under the homeopathic remedy.
What we are dealing with now is acute conditions different from what you are treating.
You are treating epilepsy
and you have a bronchitis.
You are treating rheumatoid arthritis and you have development of cystitis.
You are treating sleeplessness
and you develop severe cystitis.
It is not the condition for which you are treating is aggravated. We are talking mostly about acute.
But it may happen, it's a little bit of
confusion when you treat hay fever
which looks like a cold. Hay fever
is not like having common cold.
and when you treat a hay fever and
there is an aggravation of the hay fever
it's different than developing
an influenza or a cold.
So we go back to the condition where we
treat a sciatica or lumbago and 7 days
after your Calc develops his common cold.
What he knows to be a common cold.
What does that mean automatically?
What do you think?
-The remedy is wrong.
-Correct. Immediately assume that the remedy was wrong because the remedy is given
some time to act; therefore it should have prevented the appearance of the cold.
This is almost a sure sign that
your remedy was wrong.
-But you also have the reappearance of
old symptoms and almost every patient
has sometimes a common cold. So you have
to differentiate if this is the appearance of
former symptoms or if this is a real acute?
How do you do this?
-Ok, I will explain very good. We say, we
have the reappearance of an old symptom
if there is a sequence. That means
a bronchitis has been suppressed
and then there is asthma and
then there is suppressed and then
there is depression and there is a historical following of one condition after another.
Here in this group we don't have that
sequence. We have somebody who is
getting his lumbagos from time to time
and his colds from time to time.
So there is no connection between lumbago
and cold. Not because he had a cold last year
that now has the lumbago. If that was the connection, that's a different story
but here we don't have that case. Later on
we'll see. We have this in the lower groups.
So 7 days after you gave the remedy,
he has a cold and it is very improbable
that this will have the same reaction as this.
I said for this cold here that was immediately after, that the cold was developing before
your remedy. That is why it will
appear but in a milder degree.
Here having given for 7 days your remedy
for a cold to appear is almost a sure sign.
Therefore we don't treat in case it is milder.
We can treat in case it is the same.
Here, we have two possibilities. Shall we
treat or not treat? This is the question.
Where on this group the cold is developing immediately after, it is milder than usual,
treat or not treat?
-Not treat.
-It is the same. Treat or not treat?
Treat. You can treat, it is as if you
have not given any remedy so far.
Here, 7 days later, he develops a
bronchitis. Treat or not treat?
-Treat.
- First of all I know my remedy has not acted, secondly I know I can treat because
it is an acute, I can treat it as an acute and
next time trying to find the correct remedy
for that person. It doesn't matter what
excuses we tell to the patient.
We have to know ourselves what we are doing.
We know that the remedy we gave to
that person was incorrect, it was wrong.
-What should we assume if in a case where we have given a remedy and within the first 3 days
this person develops an acute disease
which he has never had before?
Then in this case we can't ask is it worse,
is it the same, is it less than it used to be?
How do I make an assessment there?
-If that is the case then you
immediately have to treat.
You assume that if the person under constitutional remedy, develops an acute
even a new acute, does not have an
effect from the constitutional remedy.
-But if the lumbago has ameliorated after
3 or 4 days and the patient then develops
a bronchitis in the 7th day, what then?
-Well that cannot be the case but if that
is the case, you wait. I mean it's obvious,
you understand that. This will not happen but
if it does happen, that means you have to wait
and also, to be more exact, there might be
an immediate amelioration of the lumbago.
Not well, better 30-40%, by 7th day his
lumbago is 40% better and develops an acute,
again points to the fact that the remedy was wrong. The remedy was simply acting on a
superficial level and suppressing the organism and then develops more easily the cold.
But if by chance you had an initial aggravation the first 2 days and the 3rd day is 40% better,
then the 5th day is 60% better, then this
will never happen. If it does happen,
then you still wait, you don't give. In these
cases the amelioration is impressive and quick.
So in 7 days you know what has
happened but with the wrong remedy
let us say, you have given for the
lumbago Rhus-t where he needs Calc
or the opposite and you see some
amelioration, 'yes I feel better', but the cold
develops, be sure that the remedy
was incorrect, search for another remedy.
Concentrate now on this first group
of people. Don't mix the other groups
because we have totally different
observations there.
-For instance, it could be two
different things as I understand.
You can give a remedy which is
completely far away and by chance
he got some acute disease, it could be this way. And it could be also that you give a remedy
which is close and then the acute comes.
-Yes, both cases indicate that
the remedy was incorrect.
-I'm sorry because you made a distinction between the lumbago getting better 40%
with or without an aggravation. But if you have the right remedy and exactly the right potency,
could you or not have the aggravation?
Do you always have an aggravation?
-In this group if you have correct remedy,
correct potency, in 7 days you have a cure.
If during that time you have a cure and then you have a development I say it is almost impossible.
I don't want to say absolutely impossible
but almost impossible.
-Is it possible that the constitutional remedy doesn't act just because there is acute condition
in process? I mean first to third day there
is an acute condition that has started
before that and by the time the patient
takes the constitutional remedy, there is
an acute condition in process that
indicates another remedy.
-Yes, that is the case in which we say the
acute starts 1-3 days after the remedy.
The acute was starting before your remedy and you give the remedy and the third day you see
the development of the acute. In such a case you have to evaluate and say, the acute is like
usual or is less? It's milder, then you wait. It's the same as before, your remedy is not correct,
you can treat. In this case if you have
the appearance after 7-20 days,
the remedy was incorrect.
-I meant the constitutional remedy
is correct but it doesn't act just because
there is another remedy at present
by the time the patient takes it?
-No, there is no such case.
If the remedy for the chronic condition
is correct then it will not develop
an acute after several days.
But let us say, you have one month
of observation,  after a month,
he comes to the office and says,
'I have a cold'.
Usually we wait for 1 month of observation and after a month he comes and he has a cold.
Then what you have to
investigate in such case?
There is one more factor
that enters into the picture.
-You have to ask whether the
remedy might have been antidoted.
-The first question we have to
ask is how is your lumbago?
-Very good.
-Or perhaps there was another stress on the patient's life that has brought on this situation.
-Very good, yes. You see now the answers you are giving are within the corect context.
The only thing is that we have to put
them all together and understand.
Ok after a month you have time for
observation and his lumbago in this case
in this case you expect to be
cured, to be much better.
Now he says 'the lumbago is better but I have developed this cold', what you will say?
You will treat or not treat?
-Check the well-being, how he is mentally.
How is the general well-being.
-General is better, lumbago is better.
The person is better and he has an acute.
-I would not treat.
-If this acute is strong, is an acute with high fever as usual or even worse, treat or not treat?
-When the disease has the same
strength as usual,
I would treat him because
then the remedy is wrong.
-The remedy cannot be wrong if he is better.
We assume that the remedy is correct
but he has developed an acute in one month.
It is not usual; in a month after the correct treatment that he will have an acute.
It is not usual. People will remain for
a long period of time without an acute
under the correct remedy if they
belong to these groups.
That is the idea, that is
why we have a problem.
This person should not have developed an acute since the remedy was correct and has acted.
We don't go to the possibility of the person being the same with his lumbago after a month,
I don't even examine. If the person
after a month comes and say,
'my lumbago is the same but I have an acute',
you treat the acute, no question.
The question will rise if the person says,
'I'm better all this time from my lumbago and
I have an acute', then you have to understand this acute and take decision at the moment.
-I was going to say to look at the symptoms
and see if there is another remedy coming up.
-Yes you'll look at the symptoms in any case but what I ask you to think is the theory behind it.
This person I treated, he was doing
so well but now he develops an acute.
You thought he is in level 1
but he is not in level 1.
I assume that this is level 1,
he was good for one month,
now he has developed an acute.
You gave the answer.
The first thing that you have to know is
whether this person by taking your remedy
has continued to take his coffee. After
a month it is possible even under correct
homeopathic treatment to have the organism coming down and come back to the
condition as before. That is one.
He went to the dentist? It is possible.
He took coffee? It is possible.
He took antibiotics?
I had somebody who was bitten by a
wasp and it was swollen and was given
antihistamine drugs so this
condition developed.
The first thing you're asking, did he do
anything to antidote your treatment
to bring down the organism
so it could develop again the acute.
That is the one possibility
that you have to investigate.
-But if he had antidoted he wouldn't have
the lumbago come back immediately?
-No, it can be antidoted and not having the lumbago back. He's going to get the lumbago
after a particular movement he does, he goes and picks up something but not that time.
That time you have the indication of the acute and you have to say what is going on?
My treatment was correct but he has developed
an acute? Something he has done to bring
down his organism, what? Dentist, coffee, antibiotics? No, no, no.
Then there is a possibility of a stress
on the mental or emotional level.
A strong stress on mental-emotional
level can bring down
the organism to the point
where it was before the treatment.
Then you decided, there is a stress, medicine or mental stress that brought back the condition
but you don't have the lumbago,
it comes with acute.
The question therefore is ok you decided
there is an antidotal influence.
Are you going to give the same
remedy for the cold,
that you gave for the lumbago
or you give another remedy
according to the acute condition?
-Of course I have to look at the acute disease and the symptoms but if I would have
a complementary remedy I would have
the tendency to take a complementary
remedy in this case.
-Another one? Think.
-First you can try the same one to see if it works and if it doesn't work you can try another one.
-Give the same.
-You could see and wait if the remedy recovers.
-You must see if he recovers from
the acute without any remedy?
Now this is obvious I don't want to
repeat again and again certain things
I consider as obvious.
What is obvious here?
If he is better here in his lumbago
and he has an acute,
if the acute is mild, forget it, don't treat.
If the acute is strong and you
see an antidotal influence
you expect that you have a relapse
influence due to the antidotal influence.
Then what you do? You repeat the
same remedy, as you gave
to the lumbago for the acute or you
take the acute and you treat the acute?
You see you have to have the policy
in your mind quite clear
because if you start thinking all
these things by the time he is
phoning you, you lost it. These ideas
have to come almost automatically;
it's like you have a computer inside your brain.
-I think if the remedy is antidoted
and there is an acute case,
I have to look if there is a clear picture
of another remedy and I have to give it.
-You have to give it, ok. Here in this condition, matters are very very difficult to decide.
Do you know why? Because
you don't have enough time for
observation and actually you do not know exactly what happened. That means you know
there is an antidotal influence. Does that antidotal influence is 100% or is it partial?
If it is 100% and you are sure that the
organism is exactly in the same state
but you don't have time for observation, you
will not be able to find details to know that.
If you know it is 100% then most probably
the remedy that you gave in the beginning,
will act for the acute condition. But if this
is due to a partial dropping of the organism,
not a complete relapse, then most
probably you will need another remedy
which will be indicated by the
specific symptoms of the acute.
-But how do we know if this is total or partial relapse? We only know this from symptoms.
-Yes, that is why I said because we
cannot know, it is 1 month only
and you don't have enough
time for observation.
That is why it is difficult when
that situation happens to your cases
and of course the best is to try not to give
any remedy and see what happens.
Then what might happen is this. The acute
will further deteriorate the organism
and eventually will bring him to a total relapse and then you can repeat the original remedy.
Trying to treat here in this situation is quite dangerous because most probably you don't
have a clear acute remedy, you repeat the constitutional remedy and it doesn't act,
then you give another and it does not act and you are ending eventually treating this acute
with 3-5 remedies. Then the case
starts being confused.
That is why I'm really upset when I have
given a correct remedy and people say,
'I drank coffee, I took this', they take
it lightly. Because then I have to do
10 times more work to understand
what is going on now what shall I do.
In the meantime you wait in the class....
but what I know,
things that I have not told you so far,
now you know how my mind goes.
I say what shall I do now? There is no total relapse. He says, 'I still have this and that
but I don't have this and that
particular symptom is missing, and now
I'm developing a cold' and I say, 'my god'.
Most of the cases we are not satisfied with,
are these cases that could be beautiful
and they are spoiled by antidotes
which are interfering in the treatment
in the early stages of treatment.
-How is the situation if I have the patient
with acute after one month
and I know the patient has
been vaccinated and this acute
is appearing now after 6
days after he got the vaccination?
-It is a sure sign that you have
an antidotal influence.
Vaccinations many times will antidote
the action of the homeopathic remedy
many times and you have
relapses after the vaccination.
-What is your opinion about if you
have the impression that the remedy
is not totally destroyed by
the antidote that you push
on the remedy by giving a C12
of the same remedy?
-Well we have tried this and
usually does not work.
With partial relapse giving
a 12 usually does not give an effect.
Sometimes it gives an effect but then you
say, most probably it was a full relapse.