He's doing well for 6 months. He gets an acute.
Maybe the acute is going to pass by itself,
you don't need to prescribe.
If the acute becomes really bad, then you
think of prescribing of course and
if the acute symptoms do not point to a clear remedy you repeat the original remedy.
Because in 6 months the remedy should have lasted longer; it has not exhausted its action
normally but in case that the acute is quite
strong and requires treatment, it means that
something has happened in between here
which has depleted the organism and the
organism has gone back. So most
probably after this acute
you will have back the chronic
condition and you will have to
repeat the remedy. But if the symptoms
of this acute are not clear
you can always give the Calcarea carbonica which you prescribed originally.
And most probably that will go away and
the person will continue to be well.
But if it is mild you just wait.
In one year, most probably the
remedy is antidoted and again
the same observation  with the 6 months.
I was in the office the other day and by chance the camera was there from the German
channel and a woman approaches me and
she said, 'do you remember me?', I said, 'no
don't remember you'. She said, '20 years ago
I came with a thyroid problem and you cured it
within 2 months. I came twice she says, 20
years ago'. 'How are you doing all these years?'.
I'm doing quite well, I came to see you.
She was 65 perhaps by the time I met her;
I could not remember anything but this is the experience from a good homeopathic remedy
if belongs to this problem. She had a
thyroid problem but in the beginning;
you take the remedy, the thyroid
will not progress to go into malignancy.
Now here things are a bit different in this group; because in this group the organism has gone
down because of some chronic pathology
and the acutes are becoming more frequent.
The organism is affected much more by
different bacteria, viruses, etc.
Then you start having common
colds, influenzas, cystitis
together with some anxieties
or rheumatic conditions etc.
You give a remedy and within the first few
days you have the acute which they usually get.
What does it mean?
He has come to be treated for thyroid problems and she says at the same time that
'frequently I get cystitis'. You give
the remedy, you give Thyroidinum,
the second day, the third day she
says, 'I have the cystitis'.
Are you going to treat it?
-No.
-What does it mean?
-It should be a little bit more mild than usually.
If it's milder then the remedy was
correct and you have to wait.
-Again we can see if it is better than usual.
It may happen, as I said, that the cystitis has
started already before the treatment and if it is milder, you wait. Now what happens in this
case here is that because of the acute the action of this remedy will be exhausted much earlier.
So the acute seems to take a lot
of the action of the remedy
and seems to shorten the duration of action.
If this remedy you have given, 200 was going
to act for a year or two, it may act only for 3 months due to the fact that you have an acute.
The acute brings down the organism in any case.
The acute comes after 7 days, what it means?
- The lady has a thyroid problem and
chronic cystitis at the same time.
And if I give the remedy and the
cystitis comes back I would rather
think it is an aggravation of the remedy
than an acute, so I wouldn't give anything.
-You would not give anything. Somebody else?
-In this case I would give a new prescription because I think also there is a deep aggravation
of the cystitis; I think it's a normal
aggravation of the working remedy,
I would do nothing for the first month.
-If we assume that there was no cystitis
in the beginning of the treatment
and after 7 days, she gets cystitis
then the remedy was wrong.
-Here, you have the possibility within
the first few days to get an aggravation,
a cystitis which they will call it very bad
cystitis the worse they ever had.
If that is the case, instead of being milder, the cystitis is much worse, what it means?
Nobody wants to answer this.
-I still wouldn't treat because we don't know the history. Well you might have taken the history
if she had many episodes of cystitis that
has been suppressed with medication,
then one of the reasons that it make flare up very violent is because the system is
to clear itself a bit. So I wouldn't treat.
-You see it may happen that with the correct remedy the cystitis has started one day before
and you give the correct remedy
and you give a high potency.
It may happen that you get a very violent aggravation in the first few days. Then wait.
Here in this case where she gets immediately after the remedy a usual cystitis,
you assume that your remedy has done nothing. If it is better than usual, the remedy is acting,
if it is worse than usual the remedy
is acting, if it is the same,
your remedy has done nothing. And of course you may be treating or not treating the cystitis
here per se or the best is to try
and find another remedy.
You go after 7 days and the cystitis appeared.
It has to be milder in order to assume
that your remedy has acted.
The cystitis is the same or a kind of worse,
your remedy has not acted.
After a month, cystitis, your
remedy has not acted.
Definitely here, your remedy has not acted because the organism has enough time
to recover from the correct remedy,
therefore it will reduce the frequency
and the intensity of the acutes.
So acute here, forget it,
your remedy was incorrect.
After 6 months an acute, if she is
doing well for several months,
it means a relapse and it means
the remedy has been antidoted.
-I have a patient with a lumbago and
I give Rhus-t or Bry or whatever is indicated
and he tells me, 'I frequently get colds' and the lumbago vanishes and after 3 months is totally
gone and he gets a really bad cold.
Would you say the remedy didn't act or
how could I interpret it?
-You remember we have said, we
can be treating a case on a level.
Rhus-t which is the lumbago which has been upon, it is like something upon the basic
underlying remedy which is
Calcarea carbonica.
If this is the case, this remedy will have
touched only upon the lumbago, nothing else.
The person himself does not feel different.
I'm talking about the remedy which has
been given for an underlying condition.
The same thing can happen with Ignatia.
These people here, they can come with a
concussion, you give Arnica, it will be cured.
They come with grief. You give Ignatia, they
are cured. I'm not talking about this. I'm
talking about a remedy which goes deeper
and affects the whole of the person not
the symptomatology of a super imposed
condition. Because with this we are clear.
He has an otitis, you give Cham., it's gone.
In children you have dental problems
you give Cham, it is gone.
The child who is suffering at the same time with chronic otitis, the otitis will not be affected
when you give Camomilla for her teeth.
But if you have given a remedy for the
underlying condition which is the otitis,
now teeth are coming, the child is crying
you give Cham, the child stops crying,
the teeth are growing, the otitis continues.
You give now the Mercury which is for the otitis and you want to observe what is happening.
People can have something acute or
temporary that creates on top of it some
pattern of a remedy.
You will have to give that first.
These people here, very severe pathology,
they still can feel grief and they can still have
an Ignatia or a Natrum muriaticum symptomatology.
You give first this, you take out the
grief and then you start treating.
Still these people may have some
mild form of acutes. You may be treating
because the mild form of acutes
gives you the idea of Bry; you give Bry,
you treat and after that you start
treating the multiple sclerosis,
the neuromuscular disorder, the severe
thyroid conditions, the leukemia etc.
- For this temporary acute illness
of it there is no past existence at all,
it is a totally new unconnected disease
that the patient hasn't had before.
If we are treating a chronic case
and we've just given the remedy,
would be the acute and then how long
will be for the action to exhaust
before we resume the previous
prescription of the chronic illness?
- Now in these two groups you have to
pass judgement whether you treat or not.
If you have done a good work in studying your case and you have seen some action of the
remedy as I said, mostly you will not treat the acutes in these two groups, as I said, unless
after a month it gets cystitis again.
Most probably the idea is
your remedy has done nothing.
But in this group as a general idea the appearance of acutes is not a good sign
and it points out to the idea that your
remedy is not working properly.
An acute after a year, in this group  for a year the person goes well, your remedy was correct.
Here you have a relapse, the first
thing you think is repeat the remedy.
A person who stayed well with his chronic condition plus their acutes and went better
in general, you don't change the remedy, the remedy was correct, you repeat the remedy.
In 3 years, the same. Repeat the remedy.
It means also that in 3 years,
this organism is on the upper
level of the second group.
If the person stays well for 3
years with your remedy and
does not get colds, influenza, cystitis etc.
you can assume your remedy was
acting very well and you don't leave
that remedy and then you repeat the
remedy in the same potency, it doesn't work.
You go higher, it doesn't work, you go higher.
You don't give up the remedy in such
a case. The remedy is going to act.
I told you it's a little bit difficult that subject,
that's why I left one day to go
down and digest the issue.
Listen now how different things
are as we go down the scale.
Here, group 3 where you have mild
acutes or no acutes, the person says,
'well sometimes I have acutes'
or 'last acute was two years ago'.
That' s not a good sign. You give your
remedy and the next day or day after,
within 3 days, here pops up
an acute. What does it mean?
It means a very good reaction,
a fantastic reaction!
You cannot have anything better than that!
Therefore you say, wait don't touch this acute.
Not only that but most probably the acute
in this condition will be quite severe
but not deadly, not endangering
the life of the person.
In this group also belongs a reaction which
we see sometimes with Homeopathy
which is the appearance of high fever,
sudden high fever without any reason,
40 degrees fever. 1,2 days, the 3rd day is
gone. It appears usually in asthma cases
it is a very good sign and in epilepsy cases.
I have seen in both of these cases, many times
that type of reaction. Now, if you get
upset and you try to treat the fever,
you give Acon., you give Bry., this, that, within 2 days you can spoil your case.
So the information about acutes will always give us an idea where the person finds his organism
a in gross pathology or not and whether our treatment is going to be easy or difficult.
You get the cases with ulcerative colitis and this is usually aggravated with a lot of antibiotics.
Why? Because they are getting frequent
acutes, a lot of antibiotics, eventually colitis,
eventually ulcerative colitis. For the last year no acutes. You give the remedy and the 3rd day
you have the appearance of a cold, of a bronchitis, of a pneumonia, of whatever.
Very good sign, there is possibility for a cure.
The organism in spite of the fact of having
deep pathology, with the first remedy will have
a beautiful recovery, with the first remedy.
As long as the acute comes
immediately after your prescription.
Now you treat these cases and the acute
comes on the 7th day, what does that mean?
-I think it's also a good sign of an
aggravation because you don't know
in what state exactly the
patient was when he came.
-Very good. It's also a very good sign.
One week after your remedy,
it doesn't matter whether
this person is better or not.
This colitis might be the same
or a little bit better or worse.
It doesn't matter once the acute appears
in 7 days, the person is getting better.
You can predict the cure.
-I take this case of the ulcerative colitis and you give the remedy and after 2 days
she has pneumonia or high fever,
you will not treat?
-Well, there is one general rule, when in
danger always treat, nevermind what.
Treat with anything that will
save the life of the patient.
You give antibiotics, you give
cortisone, whatever you like
as long as the danger goes away,
if there is a real danger.
That is why it is important to know quite well clinical medicine, to understand pathology.
So you know when a case is really in
danger and when it is not in danger or
you think it is in danger. So the
problem is even with the  young doctors
who don't have experience,
you know how many people
they send to the hospital without reason?
Because they are terrified, they cannot
evaluate whether this case is dangerous or
if this is normal case. I have noticed here in Greece because we have the rule that
all young doctors have to go to rural cases like in villages, don't stay in cities to do their practice.
They go out of the University, they send them without experience to treat
the rural population of Greece.
What has happened?
Greece was having one of the
highest life expectancy until 1970.
If you look at the statistics,
now it's going down, down
because the young doctors
without knowing.... what do you have?
A cold, give antibiotics. Influenza, antibiotics.
But when you have a virus antibiotics
are not good. They say, 'yes but
he had some coughing,
I heard some wheezing and
you go to the hospital.
You know how many people
were sent to the hospital?
Until 1970 here there was no pharmacy. Population would live long time.
Today we have two pharmacies doing
a lot, the same population.
Two pharmacies are selling a lot of medication.
Who is taking all this medication?
The population. Why?
Because everybody feels I'm sick now
and they have to take medicine.
There are cases that are serious but you have
to have experience to realize that this is a
serious case, to realise that you have
given a remedy and has not acted.
Myself I have treated several
cases of pneumonia.
In some of these cases we are not
successful, then after the appropriate time
you give antibiotics though I claim that Homeopathy can treat even severe cases,
even meningitis. Meningitis?
Ah, give me antibiotics, cortisone
yet Homeopathy has proven that
can treat even severe acutes like meningitis.
-In this case that Margaret mentioned when
you have in group 3 a dangerous acute
a few days after you have given the remedy
would you prefer to give antibiotics
rather than treat homeopathically?
-In this case you have an acute,
it is quite strong, quite severe.
Usually if you have acutes here
they are going to be strong, quite severe;
you give antibiotics you just return
back to the original condition.
I was in Italy and I was explaining
to them that situation.
Two of the doctors got up, one says, 'I had a
case' - at the moment the teaching is going on.
He said, 'I had a case of severe
depression of a medical doctor',
he himself was a medical
doctor, the patient.
So the other doctor prescribed
for him Lycopodium.
After 4 days there was a severe
pancreatitis appearing.
Which pancreatitis he had five years ago
and by the time I was teaching them,
the patient doctor was in the hospital  and
they were trying to treat him in the hospital.
He was not responding to the treatment
and he was in intensive care unit.
I said, try to repeat to give Lyc. again.
Because it is endangering the life
you have to treat. The best way to
do it is by the same remedy,
by a repetition of the same remedy.
Let us take the example of yesterday
with the Lachesis case.
After Lachesis, he develops an acute.
He says, 'I have a sinusitis'.
This sinusitis if you leave it untreated,
it will become quite severe sinusitis.
Now he takes a repetition of the remedy Lach., and the sinusitis disappears beautifully.
That is the case that belongs
to the upper third group.
-I just wanted to tell you about a case
that I had and I think it was the same.
Actually it was my mother so
it was quite frightening.
I gave her about a year ago, Bryonia.
She had rheumatic problems,
problems with all her joints,
she used to take cortisone for
and slowly she dropped the cortisone
and I gave her Bryonia which she took for
a day or two, low potency and
then she started having symptoms of
crying, fighting with everybody
and I told her to stop.
But within 1 month or 2 everything finished.
All the problems she had with rheumatic
which was for a few years, finished.
Then a year later she said it's starting a little bit again and she started the cortisone
and finished and I told her to
take the Bryonia again.
I said, 'take it' because mentally
she was a little bit... and she took it
and next day she had a strong pneumonia,
it was really difficult and she didn't take nothing.
She let it go but then she had
to take very strong antibiotics.
I asked her: 'do you think it was because
of the remedy, just after the remedy?'
She said, 'no I think a had a
cold a little bit before'.
So I felt a little bit better but I've seen her before she took it and I didn't see that she had a cold;
so it puzzled me and it really gave me cold
feet to treat people especially at this age.
But now that you say it, I feel a little
bit better and since then she is very good,
she is fine with rheumatic and
everything. It is a few months already.
-Your mother belongs to this group here or maybe even to the uppermost here, the 3rd.
The appearance of pneumonia, shows that
the ground, the organism is on another level
all together that was before. Because we
have in our organism all the microbes.
Why don't we get infected? Because this particular streptococcus or staphylococcus
does not have good ground to develop.
The good ground is actually
many times a good sign.
Once you bring the organism to the point
where now the staphylococcal infection
can be developing, then you have
brought up a level the patient
and then you have to treat
homeopathically and then you will
realize the difference which
is tremendous in the level of health.
I say that these cases which they
belong here, if they are treated correctly,
because there are severe reactions in this
level most probably you will need to treat
and if they are treated correctly
the organism is really released.
And I will go further. You see the
further you go from the reaction,
the more severe and most probably
the most dangerous will be the reaction.
-Question to the patient with pancreatitis.
If you repeat the remedy do you principally
give the same potency or would you
go higher with the potency?
-Yes you give the same potency
and you repeat it every 3 hours.
It is a severe case endangering life, therefore the force of the disease is very strong.
It is very interesting that the suppression of the pancreatitis 5 years ago, brought about what?
A state of deep depression,
mental depression
and the man was really suffering,
tremendously and then the pancreatitis
comes and you see it is really
dangerous, you have to treat.
As long as you feel that the
person is able to support that,
you wait until you see the remedy is clear.
Once you see the remedy
is clear, you prescribe.
-I've seen twice children whose parents
were medical doctors and both of them,
one Tuberculinum child and one Medorrhinum child and it was in the beginning and I wasn't
sure about the remedy and both developed pneumonia 11 and 10 days after the remedy.
Severe pneumonia and I had to treat them because the parents wouldn't accept it.
Both of them had very severe behavioral problems. 3,5 and 4 years old.
To both of them after I finished
the antibiotic treatment,
I repeated the remedy one potency higher.
One of them got pneumonia back
homeopathically and it healed wonderfully.
So then afterwards I was sure,
it had been the right remedy and that was 3 years ago and they are ok, they are much better.
-Very good. These are the examples that you will see again and again in your practice.
But whether you give antibiotics
or you don't give antibiotics
the idea is that you have to
know  what is going on.
Don't say, 'oh they gave me the wrong
remedy or I gave the wrong remedy'
when the remedy is the correct one.
I've heard that many times,
'ah it was the wrong remedy because he developed pneumonia'.
Here in this group has behavioural problems.
They belong to this group and children with behavioral problems do not develop acutes
or develop mild acutes. The moment you
treat them they will start with the acutes,
they go to this level. Where they
get acutes one after the other.
And if you treat here in this group autistic children, the acutes can be devastating
during these acutes if you manage
to treat with the correct remedy,
you will see miracles.
If you don't you just lose everything.
Everything comes back.
-What would be in the case like group 3
you have that severe depression and
I give the remedy and now I get the acute pancreatitis and I have to treat that pancreatitis
because it is so severe. The acute symptoms of the pancreatitis which show different symptoms
not the symptoms of Lyc but for
example the symptoms of Phos,
do I give Lyc nevertheless
or do I give Phos?
-No, you give Phos if you have the picture.
But usually in such severe, quick reactions
of the organism, you don't get
clear symptoms of the acute.
What are you going to do? If you have
clear symptoms of Phos, give Phos
but if you don't, then you just repeat the
potency that you gave, repeatedly.
Don't do that unless it
is endangering the life.
For instance the pneumonia child
when it was given Tuberculinum.
You give Tuberculinum,
next day you have pneumonia.
You don't have symptoms, there
you can repeat frequently the Tub and
by that they get over the acute. It is
very interesting in this group also that
when they bring you the child, the child
is restless, they complain about being
hyperactive, it's a good
child, clever child etc.
Then you give Veratrum album and after
that for 3 years you see the child is battling
with all kinds of acutes, epidemics etc.
And you have to treat every time correctly.
You will say why don't you give one remedy
here and one remedy here and it's gone.
It's not like this. Because once it's gone
on these levels you will need a series of
remedies before you can really cure,
to bring balance in an unbalanced child
which has deep behavioral
problems, it is not easy.
-I have two questions. The one is if a disease from the 3rd group gets more acutes,
then it is a good sign?
-If a case which does not have for the
last year acutes, starts having acutes,
yes it is a good sign.
-The other is, I have a case of a woman
of 60 years old and since 4 years
is very weak and her legs
and back are very heavy.
She has a feeling of weight and they had
made the MRI and they saw some lesions
in the brain but not inflammatory signs
and all they said she has multiple sclerosis
without any signs in the spine. She gets
frequent colds; so in which group?
-Does she take colds which
are severe or mild?
-In case you treat this, most probably
she gets some acutes.
You treat this case and you treat with the
correct remedy, that woman will develop
a very severe acute like
pneumonia, like meningitis.
You get a person that goes slowly
to high blood pressure state,
you see less and less acutes.
If they enter diseases like lupus,
you see the acutes are less and less.
It is not that they may never have
an acute. They may have an acute
but the acutes are usually mild.
Here in group 4 if you have
an acute, it is so severe
that usually they cannot
survive by themselves;
if the organism reaches a point where
it manages to bring out an acute
a very severe acute, they will die.
Unless they have a support. Usually
what happens during the acute,
they get antibiotics, they get suppressive treatment and they go back
to their normal state. Here, where
we have schizophrenics,
for a schizophrenic to get high fever it means either meningitis, meningoencephalitis, pneumonias,
very severe. During that state of the fever,
you will see they come back to their senses.
The schizophrenics start talking normally.
If you manage to treat during that state,
you can even save a schizophrenic.
We say, we cannot treat schizophrenia,
it is very difficult but if you have a
schizophrenic, you give a remedy
and immediately after a while you
see an acute, it's a very good sign.
The longer you see the acute,
you have to be treating
a case on that level for 3 years
before you see the acute,
the further you go here, the
stronger will be the acute.
That means if you treat correctly,
the person was here and you treat
you raise his level.
You treat, you raise his level.
and eventually you bring him here. You
have given 1,2,3,4,5 remedies in 3 years.
You bring him here,
he starts with the acutes;
then the acutes are very severe.
Then you need to treat the acutes.
They are very good signs the acute
in this level but you have to be very careful
what remedy you give during these
acutes. That's the whole secret.
Here, they are dangerous and you have to be
on the telephone all the time. How are you?
This man with the headaches he developed sinusitis. In order to treat this sinusitis
you have to take a case even on the phone
for one hour to be sure about the remedy
you are going to give. Does he need a repetition of Pulsatilla? Does he need Belladonna?
This decision is very crucial for the
further development of the case.
I believe that if he had called me and
have said that I have this symptomatology
and I had given the correct remedy,
you would see a totally different
picture now on the follow up.
But you see the difference between
knowing and not knowing what is going on.
When you have also an acute
immediately after the remedy,
it means that your patient was on the
uppermost level of the third group.
As the reaction is going further and
further from the beginning of the treatment
you will have to face the fact
that this case is going to be
more and more difficult,
it needs more and more treatment.
-I have a question to a case of mine.
It was a boy of 4 years with behavioral
disturbances and he was
hyperactive and he was born with
atresia of the colon (anal atresia).
No connection of the colon and the rectum.
Stool couldn't go through. So they had to operate him immediately after birth.
Then he had a blockage of the lacrymal duct going from the eyes to the nose so his tears
were always coming out and he had
an hyperactive esophagus.
He would get cramps in the esophagus
with chokings and they had to bring
him into hospitals about 3 times per week because he was threatening to choke.
He came for homeopathic treatment
and I gave him Tuberculinum.
And the tear problem went away
completely, he got much calmer
and he had a neurodermatitis on top.
So the tear problem was getting better,
the neurodermatitis was getting better,
the choking stopped completely
he never had to go to hospital and the
parents were pretty content for over a year.
Then he developed a
carcinoma, hypernephroma
a kidney tumor.  And he had to be operated,
it was pretty big already he was passing
blood in his urine and got chemotherapy.
Unfortunately I never saw him again
but we have been discussing a lot
about how to interpret this and I don't know
how to interpret this. What would you say?
Did I suppress with the homeopathic
treatment, what was going on?
-No, you did not suppress. If the
child had behavioral problems,
had genetic disturbances obviously and had different kinds of symptomatology which was
quite severe and you treat and everything
goes well and the whole force of the disease
stays in one level, this is a case
which belongs to this group.
You give Tuberculinum and he
had that reaction which is good
but it might be that you did not find
out the next remedy during this year.
There is a year and in a year I believe
they came several times to see you.
And this child needed another remedy
or a third remedy or a fourth remedy
before he could be raised to the point
where his problem would be externalized
and I believe that we see this many times.
The force of the whole disease concentrates
in one point and then this is what it
appears as cancer or tumor or whatever.
This is not the end of the world, it means
that if you give correct homeopathic
treatment, this child can survive.
If the child now takes chemotherapy, most probably returns back the whole situation.
Then he will stay as long as he can live that
child in that condition with all the suffering.
The disturbance on the mental-emotional level, as I said, is a diffusion of the disturbance.
Some is on the physical body, some on
the emotional, some on the mental.
You cure and this is cleared, mental-emotional
is cleared and then everything goes to
the physical body. The organism
does whatever best can do
and says ok, everything I put it in
the heart or the liver, the colon etc.
-I also have a case which I don't know
how to assess it. It is about my nephew.
He was born 5 months ago,
he was in a very bad state.
He had to receive antibiotics right away
because he had an amniotic band syndrome.
Then he was discharged from the hospital
and 3 weeks later he developed a stenosis
of the pylorus and had to be operated on. Afterwards he had problems with drinking and
he also showed symptoms that he did not
like to be looked at and he did not want
to be touched. I then gave him Antimonium crudum and the drinking problems which
have been very marked got much better.
He could only drink very small amounts and
always with pains. He was already crying
after 20 ml of the bottle and it took him
1 1/2 hours to drink 70 ml and that
at the age of 3 months.
After birth he received Carbo-v, after
this remedy the weakness disappeared
and he became much more lively
and for the vomiting I gave him Aethusa
which helped a lot for the vomiting
but still on the X-ray you could see
that the pylorus
still had a strong stenosis.
After I gave him Antimonium crudum,
the drinking problem got much better
and he developed
neuro-dermatitis in the face.
Then he developed bronchitis for
which he was hospitalized.
But in the hospital he was treated homeopathically and he did not
receive any other medication.
He then was discharged from the hospital.
His drinking problem was 80% better, the breathing problem had improved very well
and then I gave him Graphites
for the neuro-dermatitis.
After Graphites the drinking problems
ceased completely, he can drink fine now.
Last remaining breathing problems went away and now after 2 weeks of giving Graphites
he is now is developing some problems with mucus in the respiratory area and fever of 38 C.
So now I feel insecure what is happening and whether I maybe made a mistake with Graph?
-Most probably there is no mistake
with the Graph. Graph was correct.
Because it ameliorated the
esophagus stenosis and
the child can drink much easier. So that
means it has acted on a quite deep level
and brings out an acute. The problem is now
to treat that acute with the correct remedy.
-The acute situation now is very mild,
my sister says he is a bit cranky
but otherwise feeling well,
the night was ok, not bad.
So I feel at the moment there is
no necessity to treat him at all.
-Yes, that's correct. This is a correct sequence
of events. You don't have to worry about it.
Anybody else wants to state some of the experience so for the whole class
to listen to examples?
-I would like to say some words about
cancer because I have 2 interesting cases.
One of them had carcinoma of the posterior nares in the nose which was inoperable
and he received radiation for that and
the cancer improved through radiation
but afterwards he had massive
problems with his salival glands
and I treated him homeopathically.
Under homeopathic treatment
the salival problem ameliorated
as well as his emotional state
but after a while he then developed a
melanoma. And I have another case.
He had a melanoma also which was
operated and this man then came to my
treatment in a very reduced general state.
He had paralytic problems and heart problems
I treated him for 3/4 of a year, maybe even
one year and during the treatment
he improved very much but then after
one year he again developed a melanoma
and I would be interested to know
whether I made a mistake in my treatment
or whether it can happen that
if you give the correct remedies
that this carcinoma situation
does reappear?
-If there is a suppressed situation by
allopathic medicine, by radio-therapy,
you may have with the correct
treatment, you may have
a reappearance of the original focus of the disease. That is something you cannot avoid.
The progress of the disease will go backwards and therefore when the melanoma reappears
after the heart problems, paralysis etc. that means the organism is in a better state
with the melanoma than with the
heart problems and the paralysis.
The organism is not interested to live long,
it is interested to live good.
We are interested to live longer and
good yes but in spite of the organism.
You see you say, do anything
so I can live longer.
Take out my heart, put another one.
Take out my liver, put another liver.
Put me in a machine so I can breathe.
There is somewhere some kind of insanity we are living. Because we have not accepted the
idea of death as a natural phenomenon which is going to happen whether we live 356 days or
whether we live 316 days, it's going to happen. Therefore the human mind trying to avoid the
death situation, has devised all this kind
of very expensive equipment to prolong
the life for 6, 3, 5 months in spite of the
fact that the person may be living in hell
while he is still here, in heaven.
Because you talk to these
people, they say, 'let me die'.
Why the idea of euthanasia came up?
Because so many people are living in
such a state saying 'please take out
all these, I don't want them, I want to die'
and they don't allow them. They are
in the hospital and tell them
we gonna do whatever is necessary
and keep people alive with the quality of life
which is terrible, it is living hell
while we are here on earth.
Put injections, put tubes and the poor patient...
I know this to be true for the
Prime Minister of Greece, Papandreou;
they kept him alive for 4 months, 5, 6 months
they kept him in that condition
and the poor man was saying,
'please stop pricking me with the injections'.
We kept him for 6 months more, what for?
In that state. 'We took him out of the hospital'
and in 20 days, he dies. Is this Medicine?
Homeopathy of course
cannot go against nature.
Homeopathy can only help you if there is possibility on this organism to live so long
and to live as best as possible. That's all it can do. It is not possible to keep you in life, alive
in spite of the fact that the organism says, I give up, I have no more energy, I am finished.
Sometimes the idea is there, with Homeopathy he will never die. That's nonsense of course.
-I had a terrible thing, he was not my patient,
he developed cancer of the seminal glands
and after all kinds of treatment
they took away the testes,
and from there on started dying,
he never recovered again and he was
in the hospital for 4 weeks in a terrible
situation and they put all kind of things.
He was not my patient, the daughter was
my patient and she was very sad about it.
So I said ok, I give you Arsenicum,
you put it under the tongue.
They even wanted to transport him
to another hospital the next day.
After 3 hours he slept. The doctor said
he never saw a patient out of such a
terrible situation
to die so peacefully.
-We can try, we can do whatever is together
with nature. We cannot go against it.
That's the main thing that
you have to understand.
Because expectations from Homeopathy are much more than we can really deliver.
And we can say this is the limit.
We cannot go beyond that.
Everytime there is such a patient
that says 'I want to do chemotherapy,
radiotherapy' and all that. I have
never seen such a case going well.
I've seen them going fast
down the gutter and finish.
But it is the decision and the choice
of the patient, what can we do?
We have to know our limits and to explain
to the patient our limits. You have cancer?
I cannot cure you. Who can cure you? If there
is somebody who can cure you, please go.
I cannot cure you. What I can do is maybe
I can help you in feeling better and better
and die in less suffering,
alleviate the suffering.
But if the cancer is in the beginning,
I have seen cases,
colon cancer to live 20
years with Homeopathy.
Of course if there is an obstruction
you have to take out the tumor,
otherwise you have peritonitis and
you will die from the obstruction.
You take out the obstruction and you don't do chemotherapy, you keep on Homeopathy
I have seen living many many years.
-One question for cancer cases. We have often the problem the patient cannot stand for
a cancer operation or allopathic treatment and put the question 'shall I have suppression
by operation or not or can you promise
or try to treat cancer with result.
What's the advice generally?
It's very dangerous I think.
-When the tumor endangers the life immediately then you have to surgically remove it
and follow it up immediately with homeopathic treatment. That is the general statement.
If you go for chemotherapy and radiotherapy
and all together, it is the choice of course
of the patient but in my experience I have
not seen good results from such treatment.
On the contrary I have seen better
results when tumor is removed
and good Homeopathy follows, I have
seen people living for quite long years.
-I have a friend, they found last April
metastasis in the liver.
The liver grew within a
month she felt very bad,
she has always been healthy and
suddenly she felt like she's pregnant
she was 42 years she checked
that she was not pregnant
and the liver grew and grew. She is a
nurse so she was scared to go and check it.
By the time she checked it, the whole
liver was full of metastasis.
I took the case, I was afraid to do anything
so I sent her to Vega in United States
and he treated her with Kali-ars.
At the beginning with 9C every day,
during this period she did the check-up,
they were thinking that it came
came from cervical cancer
but they were not sure.
Anyway they gave her 3
sessions of chemotherapy,
she was afraid not to do it, she was hysterical and during this time, after the second CT,
nothing was there. The metastasis
wasn't there, the cancer wasn't there,
they were thinking that maybe
it was not there originally.
They gave her the third one and then it was
a miracle and they wanted to check better.
So they opened the stomach and looked
inside. And then they said maybe there is a
little spot still on the liver and they
wanted it to cut it off but they didn't and
we will give you therapy directly to the
liver, not involving the whole body.
So far she had this treatment.
But all the time she is with Homeopathy
and when she has treatment she
is much higher, a few times the day.
She is already on 100 or 200 C every day
and so far even the blood test
that they check, is clean
but they still pushing her to do the stupid treatments. But I can't tell her don't do that.
-Of course, it is the choice of the
patient whatever he wants to do.
You can explain but leave the patient
to decide. The patient has to decide himself.
They have to have the responsibility,
they have to investigate,
get different opinions and then decide.