Actually we are arriving at a stage
where you will discover why
many times when I see a case
and I see a follow up
I say, this case is doing well where the
whole class is saying, we don't understand.
The knowledge of this understanding actually, will make you a real, professional Homeopath.
Because most of the cases
that have been lost so far,
it is because of the ignorance of this
part of theory in Homeopathy.
We have arrived at a stage where we have actually categorized the diseases in 4 groups,
12 groups we have reduced them to 4. So we
get some ideas where a pathology belongs.
According to these categories,
we have the reactions.
You see Kent was the first one to
have noted that the different reactions
after the homeopathic remedy,
indicated certain definite things.
So he gave his observations.
In my experience I found out
that the observations basically
were correct but not complete.
That was the reason why
many times you will say,
'but it's getting worse mentally, it's getting
fears, why do you say it's getting better?'
And Kent said of course that when you
give a remedy there is an aggravation
on the mental-emotional and an amelioration
on the physical symptoms, then you absolutely
know that the remedy has done some
harm or has done some suppression.
Is this correct, do I speak fast for you? No.
I want to give you an example of a situation. When we speak about pathology,
we speak about real pathological cases
where the problem is not only functional.
In such cases we need the observations.
The other cases are simple cases where
the problem is functional, you give a remedy, there is initial aggravation, amelioration,
then it's finished, it's beautiful. This cannot happen, impossible to happen in a deep
pathology. A deep pathology follows its own
rules which we try to discover in these lectures.
Let us say that pathology starts at a
point here. The person here is normal,
then he gets some kind of pathology.
This pathology is transferred later on
to another type of pathology. That
means here he has a duodenal ulcer
or at this moment as a child
he gets frequent otitis.
At the age of 22, he gets
some rheumatoid arthritis
and at the age of 42 gets some depression.
At the age of 60 he gets cancer.
So when you treat such a case and
you prescribe correctly here
where cancer is on the physical body and
has physical symptomatology alone,
You prescribe correctly and you will get him in deep depression, if it is correct prescription.
this depression is gone, the depression is
gone by the time the person develops cancer.
You pescribe correctly and you will get him in deep depression. If it is correct prescription.
And then you prescribe for depression
and he goes to rheumatoid arthritis
and unless you bring him back to
the point where he starts again
having frequent otitis, there
is no possibility for cure.
What happens usually in this kind of treatment
in which you just give one remedy,
some symptoms, another remedy, some
more symptoms, you don't evaluate,
you don't know what is going on. Finally you go on and you play in between these two areas.
Never pushing back the problem. Why?
Because you don't know how to evaluate.
You don't know which remedy actually acted.
If you cannot evaluate which remedy has acted,
what you do? You give up this remedy,
you have a few new symptoms
and you prescribe for the new symptoms
and you lose the correct remedy
what you should have done,
we shall be talking about it.
Anyhow this is a gross example
of what usually takes place.
Now I want first to go through the Kent's observations and we discuss a little bit
on Kent's observations and then we go through my observations and we'll make it very clear
eventually what it means every time you give
a remedy and you have that reaction.
Also remember that you have to ask
questions and say, I don't understand this
because if you let a gap in the
process of understanding
you will not be able to follow it up. So every
time you don't understand something or
your experience says something else, you
have to ask so we make it very clear.
Don't leave things in the air.
What Kent says as a first observation,
what he had observed
it was a prolonged aggravation and
final decline of the patient.
That for Kent meant that the case was incurable, that the remedy had to be antidoted,
you have to antidote the remedy he says because the patient is going to die.
If you want to place this observation in the
4 groups in which we have been talking
in which group you will place it?
-Who says 4? Is anybody else who has another opinion? Everybody agrees that it's group 4.
Group 4 very seldom will give an aggravation.
In group 4 with the right remedy,
he is supposed to have given the
right remedy here.
Here the aggravation is with the right remedy. And group 4 has very deep pathology
and very seldom you will get an aggravation
until you bring up a case from 4 to 3.
Then there is a possibility of the organism
to have a reaction and show some force.
Otherwise here we have cases where
we ameliorate with the correct remedy.
But what was the observation
of Kent? Why he said,
long aggravation and no
amelioration and final decline?
You have to understand that these are
cases with deep pathology, that is true;
but pathology which has not
reached yet incurable situation.
Once the organism has given a reaction, if you observe during the reaction the symptomatology
usually you will be able to
handle correctly the case
and slowly bring it back after
long periods to normality.
Otherwise if you don't find the correct remedy after the first, of course there is a problem.
There is a problem that the patient may
die or the peson may go worse, worse.
But the observation is not correct as far as
I am concerned with my experience and
once you have an aggravation,
you have the possibility of a cure.
Kent himself did not realize that in
his observations he said something
that was opposite to this. Can
anybody tell me what was that?
Some of you have read Kent.
What was opposite to this observation?
Kent has said that if you have a dying
patient and you want to make him comfortable
in the end of his life, you can use a high
potency of the right remedy and then has,
what he called, euthanasia. He spoke
about euthanasia, that means
the end stages of diseases. He, himself
accepted that there is only amelioration,
that means the person becomes
more comfortable but he dies.
So this is the correct observation, not
this one. You see it can't be both.
He has an aggravation, he dies.
He has an amelioration, he dies.
No, if he has a possibility of aggravation then there is a possibility for a cure. Is it clear?
-The question is, you have a severe
case and you get an aggravation
and you say, ok, ok
there is something going.
And while the person is getting worse and worse and worse whilst he is having that aggravation,
what are you going to do then?
-That is true when you say aggravation
is ok, ok, in a deep pathology
you are going to face later on a big problem. Unless by observing the case you perceive
the picture at a certain moment of the
remedy which is needed and then you give it.
Otherwise of course it will go down, down
and most probably you will have to resort
these are the cases in which
you resort to allopathic medication.
There is also a possibility that you may not be able to find the remedy during the aggravation
because this is a severe case.
That means the remedy is not clear;
so therefore you are not going
to find easily the next remedy.
That is absolutely sure and that's why
and where you need the information
from the Materia Medica and you need to
know how to work with the Repertory quite well.
I'll give you another example. You start here with a severe case and you have some aggravation,
cancer is very general.
I'll make another example,
here is colitis, spastic colitis, here is
depression and here is ulcerative colitis.
You treat the ulcerative colitis and the
person is having an initial aggravation
and you give a second remedy and you
manage start bringing some results
and you drive the person back to fears or depression or mental-emotional problems.
Slowly you bring them back here
and during this time,
there is a shock, a stress,
somebody dies, his father, his mother.
During that shock, it's very unfortunate situation, you will find that the colitis will go back
and will erupt because this is a very
sensitive situation, in which you treat.
By the time the organism is trying to
recuperate, it receives a big blow.
Where is it going to go? It's going to
go towards this direction, worse.
That is the time where you may have to resort back to cortisone, back to antibiotics,
and then you will have
to start all over again.
But it is not possible in this type of
cases that you get strong aggravation
and then after a few hours, a few days, the patient will be well, you can forget about that.
Usually these cases you will get them
under heavy allopathic drugging.
If this is a case of schizophrenia
and you undertake to treat this,
then you go back to ulcerative colitis, then
to depression, then to colitis, then to otitis.
So what you are observing all the time
is how the disease was formed,
produced in history and how the
organism is behaving now.
Is he going towards the previous state?
Does it give you indications that some fears
are developing, it is good. Well if you take Kent's observation and say, ah fears now it's a suppression.
So you see how careful you have
to be with the observations.
-Lower 3 group yes or middle
3 group, this type.
A long aggravation but final
and slow improvement.
How long? It is very important that you
are able to see the totality of the case
and pass judgement on
the totality of the case.
What is your case in front of you?
There is an aggravation, what is the case?
Can you feel comfortable by allowing this case to go on without endangering the life of the person?
This is the question you have to ask all the time and this case belongs to which group?
You are afraid now. It belongs to the
upper 3rd or lower 2nd.
What Kent means is with one remedy,
the one remedy you gave
there is a prolonged aggravation but
finally you see some improvement.
Even then you have to remember that
these cases will need eventually,
in order to improve further,
a second or third remedy.
But the first remedy if you wait long
enough to see the effect,
will show you eventually the improvement
and will show you the next remedy indicated.
So the long aggravation means that
the life of the person is not in danger.
This is another point where
we make a lot of mistakes.
You see the aggravation and you want
to stop it and then you start giving
one after the other the remedies and then
you nullify the effect of the correct remedy.
The aggravation is quick, short and strong
with rapid improvement of the patient.
This is very good. This is the best you can
have. Now where these cases belong?
These cases belong from here upwards,
1 or 2 group. It doesn't apply to these cases.
You may see this even in cases of cancer,
even in cases of ulcerative colitis,
even in cases of systemic diseases.
You can see this reaction in every possible, almost every possible, nosological entity.
That means that the cancer
of that person is curable.
That is why we see some cases of cancer cured. Because they belong to the uppermost layers.
Here you have Parkinson, here you have
M.S. and you can have this type of reaction.
So from the type of reaction that you see
in a case you conclude about the depth
of the pathology. Don't go and say
we cure cancer therefore
because if cancer comes with these levels
you can forget about cure in cancer
or you will have a big problem. A cancer here maybe is still curable with several remedies
and as you go down more and more
cancer is incurable of course.
But definitely each one of us have cancer
cases cured and then we generalize and say,
Homeopathy cures cancer. No it does
not cure cancer unfortunately.
We have example in the litterature
and our personal experience
where we have severe and chronic conditions.
We can have encephalitis, meningitis which
can be cured with Homeopathy but there
are cases which are going to belong here
coming with a case of meningo-encephalitis
a case belonging to that group, forget it,
most probably will die.
How do you see that a case is undermined?
Do you have some indications now
that you can say, that case I don't like.
What would be some indications?
Give me an example.
-I think if you have a severe case and you try to find the remedy and you are not quite sure
if this is the right remedy and
you don't have any reaction.
No aggravation, no amelioration.
-Before giving the remedy and before
knowing the reactions from your remedy,
do you have any indications to say,
when you take the case?
Before the remedy to say, I don't like the case.
-Yes, for example when you have
cancer case and the person says,
I have not been sick for 20 years.
-This is true but there are some more
indications to point out that your case
is not really a good case.
-When you take the case and
there is no normal symptom,
everything is a mess,
you can see nothing.
-That is also true but presupposes that
you know well your Materia Medica
because I may feel confused,
you may feel very clear.
So it depends on the knowledge
of the Materia Medica.
I still ask some indications where you say,
I don't like this case though
the case may not look, after all, so bad.
-Maybe somebody who had many remedies
and everything was mixed up?
-No.
-Maybe if the pathology only manifests on one level and it's not diffused on 3 different levels.
-Very correct. It is the opposite actually.
When you have the ulcerative colitis in
a case where you have mental-emotional
symptomatology. Ulcerative colitis
with a deep depression, you don't like it.
Ulcerative colitis where mental-emotional is ok then that case is curable and maybe easily.
When you have severe chronic headaches
20 years, malignant headaches
in a case where you have severe
mental-emotional symptomatology,
the person is closed, depressed and
fears and things like that,
then you are going to have big
problem in curing this case.
Because the idea with Homeopathy is...
you are going to cure the whole person,
you can not cure only ulcerative
colitis only and leave the depression,
you have to cure both.
But what it means to cure both.
It means that the disease is not going to
have this aggravation and then go,
it means the disease is going to follow a track. Therefore if the depression or the fears or the
mental pathology is strong, you give
the remedy and the colitis becomes worse not
because of the remedy but because
of the direction of the cure.
The depression becomes colitis as well,
so it adds up to the colitis.
The person has come to be treated for
his ulcerative colitis, it doesn't matter.
The force of the depression will be transferred, will be transformed into ulcerative colitis first
and then there is this prolonged aggravation
and then you watch and see what is happening?
Then during this tremendous aggravation
you may have to change 2,3,4 remedies
before you can bring it around.
The cases in which you have physical
pathology and at the same time
the person complains or you see the person with mental-emotional pathology, these cases you
don't like, you say, my God. And then
you have another case it comes with
severe pathology, you give the remedy,
and then aggravation, it follows very well.
But these mental cases which have
together physical pathology,
you have to be very very careful.
Also we shall be talking about repetition of the dose, and we will see how to manage this,
when to repeat, when to repeat
high or low potencies.
So if this aggravation number 3 is perfect. Aggravation is quick, short.
Quick, short means from a
few minutes to a few days.
2,3 days aggravation and then
the amelioration comes beautifully.
Also it is interesting to see here for instance,
the aggravation might be very severe,
it might be more severe even
than the prolonged aggravation.
And inspite of the fact of being severe,
you see the 2d or 3rd day
everything disappears and the person
feels very well. That is very good.
-On the physical level I thought we have
always the cause on the mental level before?
-Not always. There are a lot of cases where
we don't have mental-emotional pathology.
It is not necessary to have mental
pathology in a case, not at all.
For instance, a person suffering from arthritis, severe osteoarthritis, rheumatism, psoriasis,
very seldom in such case
you will see mental pathology.
In case of psoriasis he comes and shows you
the knees and the elbows, I want to be treated.
You take the case and you see this person
is full of fears, anxieties, pathologies.
If you say ok I give you the remedy and you
don't understand these principles, the person
will kill you because after a month
he will be full with psoriasis.
He will come back and say,
what have you done to me?
You say what about your anxieties,
he says forget the anxieties,
I came to be treated for this,
what are you talking about?
But if you know what are you doing and
you see the case, you say anxieties,
fears, you inform the person that if I treat
you correctly you may have that reaction.
Then if the person understands, if he does
not understand he will leave you right there.
The other thing that happens many times is
what we call mild suppression or placebo effect.
In Homeopathy we have a lot of placebo
effects, people are coming and go,
yes I feel a little bit better, I feel this and that.
We have this a lot in Homeopathy like in every other so called complementarty, alternative.
But we know that we have not done anything
to that person inspite of the fact he says,
I'm feeling better. Where do you feel better?
What is happening after feeling
better is important to understand?
-One question to this point. Is it possible
in chronic cases that I have a cure
without any aggravation or
only in acute cases?
-Sure there is an immediate amelioration,
we will talk about it later on.
In the very upper parts of the groups,
group 1, you don't have aggravation,
you don't perceive the aggravation,
you just see the amelioration immediately.
The amelioration comes immediately when you belong to the uppermost and to the lowest.
Then in both these cases you have ameliorations, immediately after the
remedy in the uppermost group you see amelioration, after the correct remedy.
In the last group 4, you give the
remedy, immediate amelioration.
In the one case you say incurable, in the
other case you say very good health, curable.
This is going to be for the whole
week, prepare yourself.
This is the most difficult, the most
heavy part of Homeopathy.
I warn you so you are aware of what is going on. And unless you get hold of this information,
you will be treating superficially and
you will have some effects on first group,
on the second very few cases,
on the third and fourth group, forget it.
You will just throw remedies here and
there without knowing what is going on.
-I haven't yet understood how long is a
long aggravation concerning point 2
and short aggravation concerning point 3.
-For short aggravation I said, from 1
hour to 3 days about.
A long aggravation is from
1 week to 5 weeks about.
There are cases they may have
even longer aggravations.
-We did say that in the fourth group
there are certain cases that are curable.
Which reaction do we expect
after the correct remedy?
If one case from the fourth group is curable?
-Then you give one remedy and he is
better, 2nd remedy he is better,
3rd, 4th, 5th remedy and he is better.
In the 6th remedy he has a reaction,
he has an aggravation. That
case might be curable.
-So in the 4th group we always
expect an amelioration?
-No you don't expect, you
will see an amelioration.
From the right remedy
you see an amelioration
and usually the case comes
back or changes the symptoms
and again is aggravated. So it is aggravation, amelioration, aggravation, amelioration.
And if you prescribe correctly in such
cases, you may reach at a certain point
a time when there is a
reaction of the organism.
And then there is the danger of
having a long aggravation
and then finally decline
or the possibility of a cure.
But here if you see this,
there is a possibility of a cure.
Otherwise you keep the patient
in a comfortable condition until he dies.
-There is a question in a case with deep pathology, you give the remedy,
there is severe aggravation,
you could think that it is incurable,
because aggravation is difficult. What
about if you didn't give the right remedy
and producing a deep aggravation
without having amelioration.
-With the wrong remedy you cannot give
an aggravation which is important.
You will give an aggravation
which will be little.
-It's not very good to have an amelioration
on the deep fourth level.
-It is not good, that's why the amelioration comes first and the aggravation comes afterwards.
Kent says either this remedy was
wrong or the case is incurable.
It can happen in both cases
where you give a wrong remedy.
Many times this observation is in your
practice and in our practice.
The person comes and says I'm better but
for how long? For 1 week, 2 weeks?
And then he says, I'm worse again. That means it is the right remedy and either the case
belongs to deep pathology but the case has no deep pathology and then he comes and says,
I'm feeling better. He has some
anxiety, you give Phosphorus,
he says I'm feeling better from the anxiety.
Nothing else, no aggravation,
the organism is strong, you see no
aggravation, you see amelioration.
You wait and in 2-3 weeks the whole situation will come back and he says I have my anxiety again.
This is the case where you will give from Phosphorus, you will go to Arsenicum,
from Arsenicum you will go to Nit-ac,
from Nit-ac to Calc and finally
you give Agaricus and
he says now I feel good.
The other types of amelioration was when
the remedy was close but not exact.
That's why you have this reaction.
-So if I understand you give the Phos for
the mild anxiety, the person's vital force
seems strong. The anxiety then returns
and you start with the Ars., the Nit-ac
and the Calc and then the Agar.
Are you saying that if you had given the
Agar. first, there would have been no result?
-No, if you have given Agar. first
it would be cured immediately
but you give a close remedy, not exact. The Agaricus is the similimum but you missed it.
Instead you have given this remedy, that remedy, there is an amelioration and again back.
3rd remedy, no amelioration at all. 4th remedy, no amelioration, Kali-ars nothing happened.
Then Agar., now I'm well. That means this
case needed Agar. from the beginning,
it belongs to the uppermost layer and we
have been prescribing wrongly all along.
-Are you saying that the presenting
symptoms when the patient comes in,
can be seen as Agar. symptoms or as
masked, it mimics Phos. symptoms?
-No, for an expert will be Agar. symptoms.
-No problem.
-When we analyse the case here in the
class, many times I say the remedy,
the whole class has another idea.
This is between the difference in knowledge.
So why happens this?
Most of our patients stay with us
because of that observation,
first amelioration and then aggravation.
A case I received they say, I gave Nat-m
he was better, I gave Ign he was also better.
Then I gave Phosphorus then he was better.
But finally after 3 years he comes back
to the same state. He is in the same
state as he was in the beginning.
Then we analyse the case and say
'this is a case of Cajuputum'.
You give it and the case is progressing.
-I haven't quite understood the point 5.
First amelioration and then aggravation.
Do you only observe it when the
remedy is close but not exact
or do you have it in the group
4 when the case is incurable?
-Yes, that is also. I'm giving these
observations by Kent just to show you
that they do apply but they are not complete.
Afterwards I'm going to give you the
complete reactions or so called complete.
We still have questions but at least I have
found out through these observations,
I was also messing up cases. Because in the beginning I did not know all of what I know today.
So I messed up a lot of cases. I saw some
fears developing and then give this remedy,
give that remedy just to get away from the fears.
The fears are in a process of curing.
Fears appear or even depression appears.
-I stick to another point. You said if
you give the wrong remedy,
even you don't have real
deep severe aggravation.
But I remember the case of S., she
made a proving of Manganum I think
and afterwards she had 2 years
of deep depression she said.
-Mild suppression by the wrong remedy.
Mild suppression means a suppression
which will last for a period of time. This is
true, but if you know what you are doing,
then you will know that this is a suppression.
If you take the whole case and you
will see the totality of the case and especially take into consideration the fact that
the person has mental-emotional symptomatology.
Unfortunately today with the western population there are very few people who are really
balanced in their mental-emotional side.
So when they come to us to be treated
for something of the physical body,
always there is something behind
which is mental-emotional disturbance.
There are many times in the population
of the western people, not in Asia,
not in South America, not in Africa. Only in America and in Europe we have this problem.
There, the population is much more
easy to treat because it is physical
pathology mostly, the remedy is clear,
you give the remedy and it is gone.
-But just before you said that it is quite
frequent that it is only physical pathology
and not mental-emotional
pathology behind it.
-If you take the whole population of the
earth, the most is physical pathology.
-So you draw a distinct line between
East and West population?
-Not distinct because there with
the vaccinations they get.
The Arabs get vaccination now,
the Africans all these people get
vaccination, antibiotics, they are going
to enter in the state in which we are.
But as a whole if I see the population
of the earth, the pathology is mostly
on physical pathology
and people are balanced.
In our countries, you come from Germany,
do you want me to give you percentages?
-Only if you see this frequently or
if it is always mixed up?
-I will tell you something. We see and
everyone who treats, see the sick people,
does not see the healthy ones.
That is one thing that you cannot make
very easily. Amongst the sick people,
the population which is affected
mental-emotional is 80-85%.
-In most cases even when you treat
physical cases and people come to you,
you look for something behind it?
-Yes mental-emotional pathology.
Not in Greece so much.
You see for me it was much more
easy to treat the Greeks.
When I treated the Greeks, as
I said, I have treated them
with a group of medical doctors
that they were taking the case.
I would go and see immediately the
remedy, I look, I read a few things
and then I would go to the next.
Very seldom I would stuck to a case,
confused. Then when they come for
feedback, much better, much better.
Then when I go to America to treat,
that was a different story all together.
I said my God what is going on here?
Then when I saw people of the
North hemisphere,
I saw this phenomenon where
diseases have being affecting
mentaly-emotionally
a lot of the population.
In India I wouldn't see mental
emotional pathology.
Practically, you see somebody who is totally crazy, it's ok. But here it is different.
-Could you please repeat what you said
before about the patient who has
ulcerative colitis and also depression.
You had said, if I remember correctly,
that the depression ameliorates
and the colitis aggravates.
What am I doing in such a case?
Do I have to change the remedy then?
-I have to repeat again and again a few
basic things so you get the correct ideas.
This is the physical,
this is the emotional.
We say, in this example, ulcerative
colitis and then depression.
Ulcerative colitis is very severe
that means endangering the life.
It is more high, it's here. The depression
which comes with that intensity,
severe depression, suicidal depression.
Now we have depression which comes
here also which is not so severe.
When you treat here the ulcerative colitis
and then it goes down to depression,
that is a cure, why? The person tells you,
I'm going back to the depression
which I had 10 years ago.
That depression is on a level lower
than the ulcerative colitis.
But you are treating now a colitis which
at the same time has a mental problem
which is quite high. Now he comes for the colitis, his mental problem is not so much bothering him
or maybe it's covered or not so aggressive. You give the remedy and if the remedy is correct
here, this force of the disease is going to be added to that and you will see this.
While this is getting better or lesser,
the more this is, the lesser this becomes.
If this is deep and severe, this aggravation
is going to be very, very strong.
So there are two different cases.
I talked here about a depression
that is in the process of the
developing of the disease.
Here we have a combination, at the
same time when you take the case,
a combination of mental-emotional symptoms.
You have emotional symptoms here,
mental symptoms there
and physical symptoms on that level.
What is going to happen?
The balance will be that this will even
come up there. Once these are reduced,
then the physical symptomatology
will come very high.
-In these cases it seems possible that this condition can be very serious on the physical,
eventhough mentally and emotionally
there is amelioration.
What in terms of case management can be done so that the patient doesn't fall into decline?
-Well here in such cases for a period of time you may have to rely upon allopathic medication.
-So in that case you treat ulcerative
colitis and the patient is getting into
depression back and
it's a good progress.
So the question is what are you doing?
Are you waiting, not changing the remedy?
-This case will need several
remedies before it can reach here.
This case belongs to this group
we have said, several remedies.
Once the depression is there you have to be careful not to be in a hurry to prescribe a remedy.
Wait, give placebo until you are certain
that this is the remedy for the depression.
Then you give it and then
you see beautiful things.
-Before, you just said that there is
some cases that it might be that one
has to take allopathic remedies
for a certain period of time.
But what about if that leads to relapse
that he has more problems
on the mental-emotional level again?
-This is true, it may end up to a relapse
so you may have to start all over again.
That is a possibility. The other possibility is that inspite of resorting to allopathic drugging,
still once the bad period is gone. Because
in the life of people there are periods
which are good and bad. For a person who is really sick, a bad period makes a big difference.
So if you try to cure this person under
this bad period of time and still insist,
you may have a problem eventually.
But if you pass this bad period by relieving the
symptomatology through chemical
drugs, then you try again.
This is the cases of severe asthma.
Severe asthma under cortisone
or in general cases under heavy
cortisone you will never be able
to manage to take the cortisone out in one
time. You take out the cortisone, you treat,
you take out, you treat and then
you resort again to cortisone.
The third or fourth time is before
you can take out the cortisone.
There are periods, for instance, for asthma
bad period is spring and autumn,
during spring and autumn even without any other stressor, this stressor makes very bad situation.
Then you resort to cortisone, then
you take it out and then you treat again.
Then it comes September, October,
again there is an aggravation,
you resort but everytime you will see
that with less amount of chemical drugs,
you will be able to manage such cases.
We are talking about really severe cases.