-Point 4. We try to discuss point 4.
-Group 4 yes. But it can be group 1
in case of wrong medication.
The same observation, group 5. The amelio-
ration comes first and then aggravation,
it can be either group 1 or whatever group with the wrong medication except of group 4
which is the right medicine gives a relief
but then the symptoms come back
or symptoms are changed.
This can be group 4.
In group 4 where we have
usually incurable cases,
we see an amelioration with the correct
remedy. If the amelioration comes
first and the aggravation comes
afterwards, in other groups,
that means the remedy was
close and not exact.
-What about group 5?
-There is no group 5.
-Concerning point 5, when the aggravation comes is this the point
when the patient changes
from group 4 to group 3?
-You are talking about 5?
-Yes, first the amelioration comes and after maybe a second or third remedy,
then there comes an aggravation.
It shows a reaction on the remedy.
-The amelioration comes first and the aggravation comes afterwards,
it is a usual observation if you
treat a severe pathology.
If after treating several times, the aggravation comes first, that means that patient
may have come up to group 3 and
maybe there is a possibility of cure.
- Is it real aggravation or is it only back
to normal after the amelioration.
-What Kent means here is actually worse,
that means he had a kind of anxiety,
he was better, now he has
some panic attacks also.
That means aggravation afterwards.
Wrong remedy, he says, or incurable cases.
-So that means you can push the
patient even into worse state?
-Yes exactly. Too short relief of symptoms.
You give a remedy and for
one week he feels better.
Again, the idea is that either the
remedy is incorrect, is close
or the case is incurable,
the case is on group 4.
Here is an observation which says:
a full time amelioration of the symptoms,
yet no special relief of the patient.
What does that mean? Can anybody tell me?
-Maybe in this case we have taken off
one layer, so there is an amelioration
but there is still one or more layers of it.
-I think it's only a suppression, it's not a cure.
-No, it's not a suppression. Here when you
talk about suppression you have always
to see that some deeper
symptoms are worse.
Here the observation says:
a full time amelioration of the symptoms
yet no special relief of the patient.
-The pathological symptoms are
better
but emotional is worse.
-Emotionally or mentally or energy wise,
the general state is not affected.
What it means, I will tell you. This is
something also that happens many times
in our prescriptions because you are
treating a level with Nat-m here.
You take away the upper layer
on which pathology?
He comes to you and says I have a
lumbago, I have a cold, either an acute
or a chronic condition and you prescribe
a remedy, with the lumbago.
And the lumbago goes away but the
deeper layer, there is no change.
That means the remedy was correct
but did not touch the underlying,
the deeper layers of the patient.
That means that you will have to study the case further to discover what is underlying in this case.
The first remedy is correct
but it is the first remedy.
You need a second remedy to bring
about deeper changes in the patient.
This is a case where for instance after
grief you have spasms of the muscles
of the back, the whole back becomes stiff.
You give Ignatia and the muscles
are released, nothing else.
The same thing with lumbago,
the same thing with whatever acute,
a cystitis, sinusitis. You prescribe the
remedy but does not touch the deeper layer.
These cases are not easy to treat.
In the cases where immediately
with the first remedy you give,
you touch the deeper layers
of the person where he feels
rejuvenated, this is a case
which we call an easy case.
The remedy which appears to be
first is indicated on deeper level as well.
For instance here comes a person with gastritis and he has to take anti acids all the time.
You prescribe Robinia and the burning
goes away and comes after a while, back.
You prescribe Nux Vomica, he is better,
back. Both Robinia and Nux Vomica
are close remedies, observation number 5,
Rob. and Nux-v. are going to touch
the case, without having any effect.
There is another possibility.
You give Nat-m and the
burning of the stomach goes away
and we have a full time amelioration,
no effect of the patient.
Third possibility, you give Ars
because the person is restless,
he had a full picture of Arsenicum. You give
Ars. and not only the gastritis goes away
but you have a rejuvenation of the organism.
That means Arsenicum was indicated
on the lower level as well.
So you see the possibilities?
In all these cases there is some
effect from the remedy.
If you want to add also the possibility
of placebo as well, here.
Because with the placebo you may
have an amelioration of the burning.
-It might be that I missed something
because you give 3 points
and you say first Robinia and Nux Vomica...
-Rob and Nux-v touched the case for
1 week, 2 weeks, the burning is better,
it comes after 3 weeks and he says
I' m better. The 3rd week says, it's back.
That means the remedy is wrong,
try to find another remedy.
You give Rob. or Nux-v and they
will be better for a while.
Then you give Nat-m, a third possibility,
the burning goes away but no change
at all on the general state of the patient.
Constipation remains the same, anxiety
is the same, fears, whatever pains he
has is the same, only this layer is gone.
Full time amelioration, no
special relief of the patient.
That means the remedy is correct, Nat-m
but you have to find the deeper layer.
-But what is the difference between
the first and second group?
-Between Rob and Nat-m?
Nat-m cures the gastritis; the other two remedies ameliorate for a while and comes back.
Now the third possibility is that you
may be prescribing a remedy that
not only will take the gastritis away but
will cure the headaches, the constipation.
That means you touched upon this layer. This layer and that layer is the same, it is Arsenicum.
The layer was encompassing,
including the acute situation, is it clear?
-I understood point a and b and then when
you said, when you prescribe a remedy that
covers 2 layers, you lost me, sorry.
Can you explain that bit again?
-You prescribe Arsenicum which takes away
the gastritis but the person also says,
' I feel great; my headaches also are gone.
My constipation also is gone
and I had some anxiety; this also has gone.
That means the gastritis picture was Ars
and the deeper layer was also Ars.
So Ars touched both layers.
I'll tell you something that as we go along
with information you will have to encompass
and to include the previous
information in the observation.
What we said in the previous seminar
concerning the follow ups
and what happens with the chronic etc.
has to be encompassed now
as information which has been digested
and included now in the observation.
In order to make a correct observation,
you need the whole information;
you don't need this fragmented
observation as we put them down now.
You need to come back and to take
into consideration all the possibilities
that we have talked about and then
find out what is really going on.
-If I understand correctly, what you say
is when we give a wrong remedy
or you give an incomplete remedy this is
what we can expect: a full time amelioration
of the symptoms and yet no
special relief for the patient.
-No, no, no. I said in case this
happens the remedy is correct.
Full time amelioration of your
lumbago, you get lumbagos all the time.
I give you Nitric acid and your lumbago
has gone away but no special relief.
That means the remedy did not touch
the underlying layer of your case.
-I'm sorry I rephrase what I say. It's not the
wrong remedy for the presenting symptoms
but not the correct remedy for the patient.
-No, it is still the correct remedy. This is something which is my observation.
What is happening actually is that:
in case you have a situation like gastritis,
that you treat and it's going very well. That means your remedy was correct for that layer.
The idea is, I try to find the constitutional remedy; so this was not the
constitutional remedy, therefore it
was wrong. This idea is wrong.
This idea is a wrong idea in most of
the cases. We have slowly to understand
that we have to be talking differently
between the different groups.
When we talk about group 1 then we can be talking if you like about a constitutional remedy.
That means a remedy that will cure
acute or chronic conditions all the time.
This is a case of Sulphur, ok. He got an influenza, I give Sulphur and comes back.
He got pneumonia, I give
Sulphur, he comes back.
He got lumbago, I give
Sulphur and comes back.
This is only valid for group 1. There is no
such thing when we go down the groups.
In the groups you will see most of the times this situation where you have to give a remedy
which takes away a host of symptoms
without relief of the patient.
That means you have to go deeper and
find out what is the underlying remedy.
-But can I say perhaps in group 3 if
I gave always the correct remedy for
one layer after the other, then at the end
I will find the constitutional remedy?
-You may call it constitutional
remedy if you like, yes.
-But not in the beginning?
-Not in the beginning and then always
you will have the question,
which was the remedy which
mostly helped this patient
to be able to call it constitutional remedy?
Because don't forget also that the search
for the correct remedy never ends.
Because you go there and you take these layers away but always there is an underlying layer.
As long as you are alive you will
have a layer staying with you
where this layer may take
you up to 90 years old.
Because now it's not a severe layer but it's a layer. Still you may be able to go deeper.
Even in cases where we say in group 1
that we have a constitutional remedy,
Sulphur is indicated. This is theoretical,
this is rather speculative.
In reality what happens is that under Sulphur there is another remedy which we cannot see.
Therefore the relapse all the
time comes to Sulphur picture.
But this shows a very strong
organism, that's very good.
So we call it constitutional remedy, why? Because the organism who is strong
is going to bring out always the same picture.
This is a very good sign for an organism
but this organism has a better possibility,
if we can say, if we find what is under
Sulphur level, maybe it is a Calcarea level.
But we don't see it. We cannot find it.
So in the search for such layers we
prescribe a lot of wrong remedies, why?
Because in order an organism who is strong enough to give underlying layers clearly,
that means he is going
to live up to 200 years.
If an organism gives me all the time
what is underneath, clearly and I prescribe,
I will keep him young for the rest of his life.
For 150-200 years I don't know how much.
That's why it's difficult for me to accept
that this is the constitutional remedy.
The idea of the constitutional remedy is only
to point out that a person is strong enough
to give repeatedly the same picture
of the remedy. That's all.
In group 2,3 and 4, this, I say, is
almost next to impossible.
-I want to ask one more time
and I beg your forgiveness.
-I don't know how the presidential
crisis affects you
except that you are
connected with Lewinsky.
-I hope everybody is enjoying the show.
I guess the point that I like clarification on...
-What about Lewinsky? She kept the cloth
there, she said the time will come I'll get him.
Nobody talks about Levinsky.
-That comes later.
My question is if we go back to the illustration
of the gastritis giving the Nat-m first
and then underneath with the Arsenicum.
Is it the case when the patient first comes
that the gastritis is representing symptoms,
is it the case that the Arsenicum remedy
and the picture is not clear or is it there
and the homeopath doesn't see it?
-No. In case of Nat-m the case is clear.
The prescriber has seen the layer and
has prescribed the correct remedy.
- So there is no Arsenicum picture?
-No, no. Wait a moment you have
to be very clear about this.
Many times I have said, when you have
an underlying layer and there are some
symptoms going through the layer, you
just have to ignore these two symptoms,
the restlessness and the fear of heights
and prescribe the first remedy
which is this. This is the first
remedy we have to prescribe.
We didn't prescribe on totality.
We prescribe on Picric acid.
By the way she has the highest mark
in the class, not due to Homeopathy.
This remedy is necessary to be given as the
first remedy to uncover the underlying layer.
Now if you go and give Calcarea carbonica straight from the beginning, you do nothing.
Because Calc is here. You have to
give Nat-m, Ars., Sep., then Calc.
Now Calc is going to act. You give
Calc in the beginning: nothing, Sepia
or Ars in the beginning: nothing.
Therefore in this case I say Nat-m is the
correct remedy and is a remedy
which has been seen from the
symptomatology. It's clear for an expert.
Here it's never clear for one who
doesn't know of course.
If somebody comes outside
the class and hear, will say
"what are you talking, they are crazy
people talking about these things".
But one who knows follows and understands.
The main issue here is burning in the
stomach. I will concentrate on that gastritis
and I have a picture of Nat-m,
ok I prescribe though underneath
I have symptoms of Sepia. I can see that
this man is disinterested in sexual matters,
I see also that he has some slowness.
So Nat-m and then Sepia.
So if you give Sepia which is the second
remedy you just disrupt the case,
bring some aggravations and some little disturbances. Not the right sequence.
In this case Arsenicum was the first
layer and underneath was Arsenicum again.
Sepia is underneath and you
give Sepia and it works.
Is it still possible that Arsenicum
comes up again and again?
-I don't understand the question.
-Ars layer is so strong that comes through
again and again throughout his life time.
-Afterwards yes, sure.
Ars maybe a constitutional remedy.
Maybe this case is here, up there and Ars
will come back again and again.
Wait a moment, maybe it is not
clear what I said about Arsenicum.
Arsenicum is not two layers.
Still Arsenicum is this layer.
these are the acute symptoms of gastritis
and these are the general symptoms
and these are the general symptoms of the patient. They all fit to Ars; this is what I said.
The acute symptoms plus the general symptoms and what we call the constitutional symptoms
of the patient all fit in the picture of Ars.
Because here we have been talking
about 2,3 different layers.
When the Arsenicum touches the deeper level, that means the general symptoms of the patient
and also the acute symptoms of the patient, belong to the same remedy.
That' s why it touches on a deeper level.
It cures what is on the uppermost
and cures underneath, as well, is it clear?
-If I give the Ars the first time instead
of the Nat-m will it work or not?
-That's another case. In case there is
a Nat-m layer, you have to give Nat-m.
Under Nat-m, don't use the word
Arsenicum use the word Sepia.
First you need Nat-m and then Sepia.
In case of Ars., the Nat-m
layer does not exist.
If you give Nat-m nothing will happen.
I see some big questionmarks in the eyes.
-I think there was a misunderstanding
with this, a little bit.
From her question what I understood
in this example was like when you
take away this layer and it's gone,
then you go to the next one,
can it be that this comes back again?
-This Natrum Muriaticum?
-After you've gone to the next layer?
-After Sepia?
-No. Normally once you've given
Sepia, the Nat-m layer should not come.
When there is a relapse should
be the relapse on Sepia.
But there are some cases in which we
may observe that they need a rotation of
the remedies what Kent was talking
about a rotation, like: Sulph-Calc-Lyc.
What that means is that you gave Sulph, then you needed Calc and then you needed Lyc.
Then again you need Sulphur. In such
a case your observation should be that
the new cycle now that starts, on the whole,
is a much better state of health than original.
You may start again but it's on
another level the cycle.
It's not a coming back of the original
situation.It is a much better situation.
So you may need actually Puls. here
and you may need Puls again here,
when you are quite well actually. The
picture may come back to Pulsatilla
but you are in a much better condition.
- In a case I have given a remedy and
physical symptoms got better first
and besides that the emotional
symptoms got better as well.
Then the physical symptoms come
back and the emotional stay good;
so the patient can cope better
with the physical symptoms.
So this is whould be
really a success you say.
But then the physical symptoms get worse and worse and the energy goes down as well.
So we really should look for
another remedy, is that right?
-Yes, you go here and you see
the last remedy, the Calc or that or that.
What I say is that when you have
ameliorated the state quite well,
still the original Puls case
may come back as Puls picture.
-We don't talk about the potency.
-I don't want to mix the subjects because
this is quite difficult. We'll talk later on.
-Is it right then to prescribe a
remedy as long as it is acting?
Even if I already see some
symptoms leading to the remedy
of the next layer or the deeper layer?
-If the remedy which you prescribe
is acting that means that still the picture
is the original picture even if you think that
maybe is going towards another remedy.
Actually the picture is still the original.
When it stops acting and you have some
indications for a new remedy, then
you prescribe the new remedy,
you stop the previous one
and you prescribe the new.
-I would like to go back to the description
you said about Sulphur
that all the time comes again and again.
Then in the end you said something about,
there is another layer underneath and
if you give this layer the person will die?
-No, he will live for ever, the opposite.
I said, if you have a good case,
Sulphur case, and you prescribe for years
and you treat everything with
Sulphur and he's doing very well
I said even in this case there is a possibility
to find what is underlying Sulphur,
so the relapse will not come anymore
to Sulphur, it will come to Calc.
In such a case the person lives forever.
I said, in such a case the person
will live for a very long time.
It is necessary to take this information
and process it and keep it in your mind
in order to be able to
make a judgment finally.
-If I understood right what you said,
then this means that you cannot make
big mistakes by repeating the same remedy. Either it acts if you are on the same layer or
it doesn't act and then you have
to search for a new remedy.
-Big mistakes, no. But you can make a mistake. It can do some damage in the picture
if you repeat unnecessarily for long
time depending also on the case.
Because you will see the repetition of a
remedy on group 1 has no the same effect
as the repetition of the remedy in
number 3 group.When we can repeat or
we cannot repeat and do damage as little
as possible, this is a big issue as well.
We can not make a general idea. With the
first group you repeat as long as you like.
With the second group by repeating too
much, you can change the picture.
On the third group you
can change the picture.
The 8 observation of Kent was that:
some patients prove every remedy they get.
What are you going to do with this?
These are the sensitive patients, usually their cases are mixed up by too many remedies.
The management of such cases is
that you will have to give placebo
as long as possible until you
really see a good picture
of the remedy and then prescribe only
one dose and only in lower potencies,
up to 200 the highest. Don't repeat the remedy
if you see somebody is proving, really proving.
You give a Nat-m and he comes back with no amelioration, but with some symptoms of Nat.m
Then you give Ignatia and no
amelioration and he comes back
with some symptoms of Ignatia, Sepia etc.
Be careful, start giving placebo, make a
good study of the case and when you give,
just give a dose of 30 and see,
observe and a lot of placebo.
The action of the medicines upon provers.
-A point regarding some patients prove every remedy they get and this is Kent's observations.
I have found and this is my experience that when I have a patient who has that kind of sensitivity
even to very low potencies, I found
that by administering LM potencies
they have much more tolerance
and they do much less proving.
And because Kent didn't have
access to the sixth edition,
he had no knowledge
of water administrations.
-Maybe. The LM potencies are milder
and therefore you can use them.
The action of the medicines upon provers,
what is this? Is it good or bad?
-Kent writes that every proving that is good
for the prover comes towards health.
-Why? To prove a remedy is a good
thing for the organism, why?
-Because it stimulates the organism by repeating, it brings the vital force higher.
-I think everybody has a little bit of
things and it brings it up as he said it.
At my point of view it does something even if
you suffer so much it brings you up everytime.
-I think he said, provers have to be
quite healthy. Otherwise it would mean that
people who got a lot of remedies
must be very healthy.
-First of all a lot of remedies is no good.
A proving has to be done
according to certain laws. A prover
brings out some symptoms.
These symptoms have to go away before
he can start proving another remedy.
If you start proving one remedy and a week
later you prove another and another,
then you can cause a confusion.
The symptoms of the proving have to go out,
wait and then you can prove another remedy.
But why is it good to do a proving?
-I doubt a little bit. I remember when
you talked about Kent and you said
he was gone at early age in the other land
but he has taken too many provings.
So I don't know if the proving has really damaged him or the provings give really a better condition?
-What happened with Kent, I think, Kent
did not trust anybody else to treat him
because he knew better than anybody else. Therefore whatever symptoms he would
give to anybody, he would first
think himself about the remedy.
So a person like that is very difficult
to be treated by somebody else.
So Kent most probably was treating himself
all along, all the time and when he came to
the point where he had this pneumonia,
most probably he mistreated himself
and in the end some friends or
disciples who came to treat him,
could not find the remedy as well.
That means that Kent had taken a lot of
wrong remedies for himself and also he
had taken some remedies for provings.
Kent had bad experience from what he writes.
He had bad experience with high potencies.
He says, don't use high potency just
like that, it is quite a serious matter.
From his own experience he
had that information.
But at the same time he wrote that a prover
can improve his health by doing provings.
What is the logic behind such a thing?
-He already explained to us, a prover
can only develop symptoms
if he is in the same frequency like the remedy.
This frequency is going to improve his health,
it's going to stimulate his health and
so his health is going to improve.
If he is not in this level of resonancy, of frequency of this remedy, he won't produce any symptoms.
-It is an exercise of a primary action.
Because the organism is supposed to intake
that influence of the so-called given
material and do something with it
and the primary action is basic reaction of the organism; so any exercise with it is good for us.
-So an exercise of the organism. You see my understanding of the proving is like this:
Take the idea of vaccination.
In vaccination they had this idea that
if we give the vaccine the organism will react
in a positive manner, producing antibodies etc.
The problem that they did not calculate
was that the vaccine was already
a too strong substance for the organism.
And the reaction of the organism
it might have been actually pathological.
They didn't take into consideration this fact.
With Homeopathy we have the same idea
of vaccination but in a much milder form.
If the organism is prepared to get diseased
after a year or 2 or 3 but if this organism
is stimulated or strengthened maybe
he will not fall sick after 3 years,
he will fall sick after
10 years. How is that?
Because the remedy brings out symptoms
which most probably he was going to
develop in the future, the sensitive
to this particular medicine.
So most probably those symptoms
he was going to develop
and this is a kind of a protection
like prophylaxis.
So if you cover by doing a lot of provings,
if you cover a lot of the possibilities of
the organism to develop symptomatology
you prevent, it is a preventive
medicine, you prevent these
symptoms from arising at
least in the near future.
You don't understand?
-But frequently we said it's not
possible to make a kind of vaccination
with Homeopathy to give as
a prophylaxis if some people
are travelling, at malaria, to prevent
future symptoms. But now you said
it's a kind of prophylaxis you can
do to prevent future symptoms.
So in fact it would be
possible what you said now.
-What I say is, if you want to make a
prophylaxis for yellow fever or
smallpox or things like that and
then you give Thuja for prophylaxis
of smallpox this is wrong as an idea, why?
Because by giving Thuja to all the population
and say everyone who may get smallpox,
all of you get symptoms of Thuja,
this is wrong as an idea for Homeopathy.
When the whole class develops smallpox,
some will develop Thuja symptoms.
For those who will develop Thuja symptoms
maybe Thuja might be prophylactic.
But only for that small portion of the population
but you cannot come and say,
ok instead of giving the vaccination
I will give you Thuja to protect you for smallpox. This is wrong idea, this is what I have said.
-But the rest is not prone to
smallpox anyway, so it wouldn't get it.
-I said, let us say everybody gets smallpox
but the whole island will not get it.
In the island 200 people out of 2000
will get smallpox.
Now these people, these 200, they get
different remedies, not only Thuja.
Some will get Belladonna,
Lachesis, Calcarea etc.
Now for the small group that would have needed Thuja, maybe Thuja can be a prophylaxis
but how can you know who needs what
to distribute and say I will protect you
with the homeopathic remedy
instead of getting the vaccination.
You cannot say that. I have said this is
wrong as an idea, theoretically is wrong.
Now we come to the provers and we say, if you are a prover and you develop some symptoms
out of the remedy, this might
be your predisposition.
You develop headaches, frequent urination, burning in the stomach with the remedy.
This is your predisposition. By doing this
proving you cut short this predisposition.
It's like strengthening your
organism towards this direction.
Then you do another proving and still you
have some reactions on another remedy;
still you cover symptoms that
you may had developed naturally
in the course of your
life as a disease, clear?
You have to ask these questions because
when I speak I do not speak in every detail.
I think that you understand everything
else which maybe is not true.
-One question. Proving or to take
a remedy is artificial disease.
Every remedy I take gives me energy.
I think that everybody has a lot of energy
more or less and every artificial disease
I give him, brings him down to energy level.
And therefore when I make a lot of provings I have to ask when he comes back after the
proving, if he has the same level of
energy as he had before this proving
or if he has better energy.
And I have a lot of energy,
I can spend or not; I spend a lot of energy
in this way and I can decline earlier
than if I had not done these provings.
This is a kind of prophylaxis because I have
a need to do it. I take a
prophylactic remedy when it is possible.
-Just a moment when you say
the remedy gives or takes energy.
This is wrong as a perception. The remedy
does not give or takes energy from you.
The remedy frees your energy
in case it is blocked by disease
or the provers are stimulated in their
energy to produce a certain symptomatology.
In such a case even if the prover
says, 'I feel tired', it is one symptom,
he feels difficult to wake up, it's another
symptom which he did not have before.
You think it took away energy;
no it didn't take away energy.
It has produced the picture of the remedy.
You wait, the picture goes away and
he comes back to the state he was before.
It's not a matter of taking away energy or giving energy. The remedy cannot give energy.
It cannot boost your energy.  Your energy
is there and it is unblocked, it's freed.
and then you feel the energy. When your liver
is not working properly, your energy is low
but the remedy will cure your liver and
then the liver will produce more energy.
-Mr.Vithoulkas there is a total mess now in
my head and I believe not only in my head.
May I ask a question regarding these things
which you wrote about the predisposition level.
Let's suppose that this prover he is
almost in perfect condition of his health
and there is a certain defense lines like this Arsenicum and more and more deeper,
some level layers where the defense mechanism would go back under some short of stressors.
In that case we start giving the person
some remedies and look for his reaction
and see the results of provings.
We use this person for provings.
-Not different remedies, just one
remedy you give for the proving.
-First you give one remedy, then
you wait for a couple of years,
you remember that he was healthy,
let's try him again.
In that case if we give him some remedy which has nothing in common with his defense line;
after a couple of months we can
use him again, am I right?
It will be some reaction in his
organism but not really deep one
and he will recover very
fast after these provings.
-Wait here I will explain to you something
so you may understand more clearly.
In a proving we have this
person with these layers.
If he has so many layers it is better
not to make a proving but anyhow.
Let us say, in spite the fact he says,
'I feel ok I do a proving'.
You give him a remedy which is not his first
layer. This person has symptoms now.
This person is not really healthy but
you give a remedy that is not
his own remedy of his first layer.
Either it is too far, produces
nothing or it is quite close,
you give Arsenicum, close but not
exact and produce symptoms of
Ars in this person. Now the fact that you
gave Ars and you did not cure him
but it was close so it can stimulate his defence and you wait until these symptoms go away,
we still say, this is a process which
is quite safe and actually it may still
improve the health of such
a person. Is it clear?
-When is anybody healthy enough to
be able to participate in a proving?
The most people I know are in
some stage of a chronic treatment
of their diseases and go backwards layer
by layer but they all take remedies.
-That is true concerning the
population in which we live;
we do not anymore have a state of
health which used to be with
Hahnemann's times. For instance the
best people to do provings would be
the South Americans and not the
Argentineans so much.
They started already to be degenerated
but the middle South American people,
the African people and some Asians
like Malaysians, Philippinos,
these races are good for
provings at this moment.
What happens here in a person like this,
with 5 layers, you give the similar remedy,
then it may change some of his graph
up here. And you take these changes
as belonging to the remedy. Where
the pure remedy effect is different.
Here you have apart from one or two new symptoms, you have also managed
to distort some of his original symptoms.
And this distortion you call it a proving.
That is what is happening with some
provings which are happening today
where a dose of C30 was given to
the whole class and everybody
develops from 100 symptoms to 3000,
it's not possible. This kind of proving
with one remedy to the whole class and
the whole class developing all these symptoms
which are published today in books,
are useless information and I would say
misinformation and we have to
be very very careful.
But you will say, the remedy does
not have some symptoms?
Yes sure but out of all these symptoms
published, who is in a position to tell
which one of these 3000 are the real
ones that belong to the remedy? Nobody.
So this misinformation is worse than
no information. You have to redo
again and again before you refine
the real symptoms that belong to
the remedy and do not belong
to the fantasy of the provers or
to the distortion of their own symptomatology.
She is right when she says there are
very few people on which you can do
real provings today, very few.
We have to be careful. Many times you
make a lot of mistakes with this.
-I have question about the lack of vitality or healthy provers for provings in western
civilization, how do you account for the
fact that recent provings that are conducted
in a strictly classical homeopathic basis
as Hahnemann ...when these remedies
are proving and are written up, how do
you count for the fact that do help
many patients that seem
to be indicated for it?
-I can give you only sac lac and tell you
that this remedy has these symptoms
and you give it to 1000 cases and
I'm sure you will find 5 cases
who will come back and say, 'I'm better'.
This is not a proof that this remedy really was helping because the fact that the patient
comes and is suggestible and the fact that you are strong personality and say, this is going to help you,
the patient may come and say, 'I'm better'.
That does not mean anything for me.
Unless you see the process in the cure
which I would like to see according
to these laws the fact that you have
published some cases, saying
'I gave this, he saw this dream and
because of the dream I gave
this remedy and he was cured'.
If this was cure it is a big question mark.
But every remedy has some symptoms
and within the provers maybe one prover
is producing the real symptoms
but these real symptoms are
masked in the bulk of nonsense
which is going into the proving;
how can you find out? They are definitely
some symptoms belonging
to the remedy, but which ones?
This is my problem and this is what I have criticized very severely to everyone
who is doing proving. Either you do it
properly or don't do it at all.
Because all this misinformation goes
into our books, goes into Repertories.
That is not science.
With the provings, many times you
give a remedy and you have typical
symptoms of the remedy,
is this a proving yes or no?
-It's a proving.
I will tell you not only it's not a proving but
it is a sign that the remedy was correct.
It is a seal that the remedy you gave
was correct. In which case?
In the case where the general state of the patient is better and his condition is ameliorated.
You cannot say just because he had some symptoms of the remedy, this is a proving.
The person is getting better, his disease is getting better what do you mean is a proving?
On the contrary, that manifestation
of the symptoms of the remedy,
is a seal that your remedy was absolutely
in the center and creates of course
some extra symptoms of the remedy, for a little period of time and it will go away, don't bother.
In the other case it is when you have these symptoms of the remedy but no amelioration,
no difference in his condition, that is
a proving. Only then it's a proving, clear?
-Would you say that in contemporary provings, provers who are from western civilization,
that if a significant number of the provers had similar symptoms, that that would give
validity to those particular symptoms?
For example if you have 20 provers and
in the course of proving there was fatigue
at 8 o'clock in the evening and 2 o'clock
in the afternoon and out of the 20 let's
say 8-12 had those particular symptoms,
would you then agree that those would
become legitimate symptoms of
that particular remedy that has been proven?
-As long as the proving is conducted properly.
-Yes according to Hahnemann's rules.
-Because if we are in a group and we talk each other and you say, today I have a headache,
we have taken the same remedy.
I think also I have a headache and then it
starts like this, of course this is not a proving because one affecting the other you come
and you have 80% with a headache
on the right side. This I don't agree but
if it is conducted properly and 80% of the provers, I doubt if that can ever happen,
can have one symptom, definitely
that belongs to the remedy.
-Under this aspect how can I judge
the value of our Materia Medica's today
and also of the Repertory? If you look at synthesis for example it is constantly being
updated with all this information of contemporary provings. How am I supposed to judge?
-Exactly. 25 days before we had a meeting
here which we call the teachers meeting.
In this meeting we discussed the subject
of reliability of Materia Medica symptoms
and the Repertory symptoms. And we tried
to find a way to clarify this information and
to reevaluate and to find a system to
confirm every symptom that exists
in the Materia Medica and the Repertory.
We came to different conclusions,
maybe we can meet and I can give
you the rsum of the situation.
It is a very complicated matter to clarify and to confirm the symptoms of the Materia Medica
and to say, that symptom you can rely, that symptom, forget it. It's a very difficult issue.
That's why I say, please don't do superficial provings that will bring more rubbish
into the Materia Medica, we have enough.
If we keep on bringing rubbish into the
Materia Medica or the Repertory we reach a point where the rubbish will be much more
than the reliable symptoms, and then forget finding the remedy, especially the younger.
That is why it is so serious if we do
provings to do it in a serious manner.
How can we know? I'm not able to
know, what about a new comer?
How can he differentiate? He sees
there something written and then
he takes it into consideration. And that
is why in this teaching I brought you
back to the basics of the Materia Medica.
These are a few things on which you can rely.
Because of that danger. The danger is
so tremendous that you may be giving
remedy after remedy and the patient coming back and say, I'm better and better with any
remedy you give and really staying in the
same state in which he was originally.
There is a big battle with scientific Homeopathy.
Because maybe I have information in my
mind and my experience but how to give it,
how to organize it and give it out to make
it usable by the students, is a big issue.
You see now as we go more and more into
the theory, you will make a head like this.
The previous group were the Italians here
and the Italians like to go in mathematics
and they came out with a head like this.
If this is the experience, you have to learn it,
you have to accumulate in order
to be able to treat properly;
otherwise you stay on a superficial
level and you give many times...
If you can not evaluate the effect of your treatment, forget the real cure of the patient.
You take him after 3 years and he is
in the same state in spite of the fact
for every remedy you gave
he said, I'm better.
-I want to come back to what happened with
S. because I'm not clear about this.
How can it be that in the proving, it was Magnesium, and she gets a depression?
-I don't know the situation. If I had examined
by that time S. and we had talked
about her life at the moment, what has happened outside of the influence of the remedy etc.
Maybe I will give you this cancer case to
show you how the cancer came to a cure.
She was dying, she was in the
last stages with metastasis.
She comes here and says, now 'I have
a depression' and then I said,
'did you have depression before?',
She said, 'that is how the cancer started'.
The class did not know yet this theory.
She said, this is how the cancer started.
'It started when I had an affair with
a man older than me whom
I trusted very much, whom I loved,
whom I gave everything and
he left me and I could not get
out of that depression'.
So the depression continued until
cancer developed, in the ovaries
and then metastasis to the uterus and when
I found the case it was in a terrible state,
not moving anyway. We treated for 2
years and then she comes and says,
'I came to a point when I entered into
depression and then I took Aurum
and I am better'. She is better yes.
But the treatment of the cancer
if it was not correct would not bring
back the state of the depression
in which she was 15 years ago. Now we
can say she is really better once
she has come back to the state where she was, that state of depression was also treated
and now she says, 'I feel very well, no
pains, I have energy, I have everything'.
No chemotherapy, just Homeopathy.
-Is it the only possible course for a cure
to bring back the chronological order or
is it also possible to develop another way?
Is it necessary always to go back?
-Necessary as long as we have
cases on lower groups here.
Here, we have cancer which can be
cured without bringing back anything.
-If you have a case of tinea capitis
which then goes to tumor in the brain
and then goes to depression. If you want
to cure the depression would you expect
the tinea to come back again?
-Yes because the tinea was suppressed
and caused the tumor.
Otherwise if it was not suppressed
would not cause the tumor.
Maybe the organism with the right remedy
would just go to the tinea straight away.
Is it clear what you hear? Ask.
-I don't know if I understood the case
she was presenting, the tinea case.
You get tinea, then you get the tumor
and then depression.
If you treat depression, then you
expect tinea to come back first?
I expect the tumor to come back.
-If the tumor was a natural development
of disease, yes. If it was a suppression
because of some cortisone or whatever
if it is the result of the suppression maybe
you will not get through this phase.
You will go to the original disease.
Everybody is depressed.
General depression of the class.
-If for example an old person gets back through all these phases and finally got well again
and then for example, the surroundings, the
whole family doesn't accept this new state
and this person falls into a deep
depression because of this, then the patient
will need a new remedy to stand up towards the family or does the family need to be treated?
-Both. It is a matter of what I have
called, 20 years ago, family dynamics.
Family dynamics develop within a family once there is a person who has some problems.
Family dynamics develop between a woman
who is Staphysagria and a man who is Nux-v.
They develop a family dynamic which
if you treat one of the two persons,
especially the woman, this
dynamic is going to be disturbed
and you are going to have repercussions.
That means the woman suddenly stands
up to the man who is a Nux-v and says
'I had enough, I can't stand anymore
you shouting' and the man says,
'what is this now,
how do you dare? '
And then there is the family dynamic where
the woman comes back to Staphysagria
and then the family dynamic is re-
established and everybody is happy.
The other possibility is the woman would not be able to stand this and just leaves the marriage.
The third possibility is treat the
husband as well and then of course
if the chemistry is there,
they will not separate.
But in the same way a family that has a child
who is sick they develop a protectiveness,
the mother, they have a mission now they
have to protect the child and the child
gets big enough and becomes independent
and the mother says, 'where am I?
What am I doing now? I'm lost' and she
goes into depression and she will try
to bring back the state of the child to be sick, subconsciously, you have to be aware
of these issues. You see the mother really,
she does not support the treatment.
She says, 'why don't you give it
some cortisone?', She knows cortisone
is going to bring back the situation. 'Do you
think maybe we have to give some cortisone?'
And you say, my god I have explained,
I have done so much work and still
she comes back with
that cortisone idea, why?
It's family dynamic, she does not want to
lose the mission. She has the mission of
protecting that child. She took that role because
of the child being sick and now she does not
know what to do, she is lost.
'What is my mission, what am I going to do?'
So family dynamics is a big
issue that we have to take into
in consideration when you treat
somebody especially chronically ill people
and at the same time educate the parents
or treat the parents or treat the husband
or the surrounding situation in order to keep
the best possible balance in the family.
-I still have question to point 9.
What I found difficult to understand was,
if I am a prover who is not really ill, as we had
it before like different levels and then he does
a proving and he does more than one proving and he changes the symptoms all the time,
in the end what is the difference between such
a prover and a patient who takes too many
homeopathic remedies
that don't really fit?
-It's the same. If you are ill, and you take the wrong medicine, you create some symptoms
that we'll talk about now, new symptoms appearing after the remedy,
a general rule is: if the patient is not
better and you have new symptoms,
that means you have given the wrong
remedy and this is a kind of a proving.
The case is different, in that case, the
patient is getting much better
and you have new symptoms.
That means the remedy was correct
and the new symptoms
indicate the underlying layer.
The second case is when the patient is getting better in general and we have new symptoms
that indicate the remedy was
correct and the new symptoms belong
to the next remedy,
to the underlying layer.
But there is another case in
which we have new symptoms
for the patient but if the patient is really getting better and the new symptoms fit exactly
with the keynotes of the remedy which
you gave, that is a confirmation
that your remedy was correct, this is
the explanation of this observation.
-What exactly is new? Does that mean that
the patient never had these symptoms before
or that they haven't been there when
you took the history last time
but he had had them in his past history?
-They were not there when you took the history.
-Hahnemann talks about the one sided
diseases where they have few symptoms.
Is this the case number 10?
-All symptoms are observed .....
not this is not the case.
-What about the possibility if somebody does
not get better, he is in the same state,
but he develops a clear
picture of a new remedy?
For example a Sulphur case, if you give
Sulphur and it opens the case.
-If this is the case, belongs to the next remedy,
as we said, it belongs to the underlying layer,
that means the remedy you gave but you
say, in case even he is not better
but there is a new picture, then if
this new picture is really clear...
that means even if your remedy might have
been wrong, it pushed out the correct remedy.
So actually you cannot say the remedy is wrong.
Old symptoms are observed
to reappear, this is a bad situation.
I just wanted to see how conscious
you are when you write down.
When you write down, you have at the same
time to be conscious of what you are writing.
This is a very good sign and it means
that your remedy was correct
Provided of course that
there was a reaction.
This happens if there is an initial
aggravation and amelioration
and then all symptoms reappear.
It is a very good reaction.
I go quickly with Kent's observations because
I want to go through my observations.
-You said that it must be an aggravation
and then amelioration? You wouldn't see
old symptoms reappear without that?
If the potency is right?
-If the person is getting better it's ok
but usually this phenomenon is seen
after a good initial reaction;
it doesn't happen like this.
That a person says, 'oh now
I have old symptoms'.
Symptoms take the wrong direction.
This is a good reaction?
That is a bad reaction.
That means the remedy is similar, is close
but is wrong and the defence mechanism
of the patient is weak, you have to
be careful of these reactions.
It means a weak defence mechanism
of the person and maybe there is
the possibility that the case is incurable.
Also with the right remedy.
-So George that means that if a person is in
a good state and we give a remedy which
is close to him, you see getting symptoms
going into wrong direction?
-If the organism is strong, even if he
gets it in the wrong direction,
it will be for a very short time and
then it will re-establish order.
But if it stays, it shows that bye, bye.
These cases can stay for years,
it doesn't mean that they are going to die,
you keep them for years but you never see the initial reaction, you never see the aggravation.
You see amelioration of the symptoms and something else appears which is on a different
level and then you give, and then you
give and more deep, more deep.
It is the same thing which
happens with Alzheimer's.
They have a weak defense mechanism,
it goes deeper and deeper and deeper
and then goes into the brain.
Everything goes finally into the brain.
These people don't take homeopathic
medicine but still the process is the same.
The defense mechanism accept
deeper and deeper the problem.
-We said that in this case there is a possibility that it was a similimum but it's an incurable
case and I heard that in cases of 4 group if you give the similimum then there is an amelioration.
-That's the same. That's the situation with
the 4th group. The 4th group will go on like this.
Deeper and deeper and will come back.
It will never bring out a reaction and then
you may keep them for years in a kind of good state, tolerable state but never really cured.