Let's see now these reactions in a more precise manner, taking into consideration the mental-emotional side
the physical side, plus the energy.
What happens?
You see Kent's observations were gross observations that he gave as an indication in general
and they're quite correct in their general idea.
But let us see more precisely what happens.
Here we separate the energy, the mental-emotional and the physical and we have 3 lines.
Of course the first reaction, an aggravation on the mental-emotional, energy and then recovery which is quick, is the best reaction.
In this case we may see also an aggravation
of the mental-emotional state.
An aggravation on the energy level: he feels weak the first days, he has to sleep a lot of hours etc.
An aggravation on the mental-emotional: he says, I was crying for 24h and the pains
were worse,
this is very good reaction.
And this is the reason why we say, we don't accept the idea of placebo in Homeopathy.
When they talk about placebo in Homeopathy and they say, everything is placebo, you tell them,
you come and I take your case and I give a remedy and see if you feel better after a while, and then you give him
the correct remedy and you cure him but
before he has the aggravation.
Let's see now a little bit more complicated case. The patient says, I feel much better, amelioration with little or no aggravation.
Better in every respect.
What it means? It means that the case belongs to A group, the uppermost.
These are the cases where the pathology is very functional, it's very mild though the suffering may be strong
the pains maybe strong the pathology is minimal. Therefore you don't need to see the initial reaction.
Of course in such cases you have a very good prognosis. The person is going to live longer, free of disturbances etc.
These are the cases where you treat today and after 20 years you see them again and say, do you remember me?
I say, no. I was the one who came 20 years ago and I was suffering so much and you treated me,
Very good this is the best case you can have. Come here, I treat you again.
Here we have the possibility where the patient says, I feel much better but I still have some symptoms.
This is the case where these minor symptoms either will go away by the time, if you wait long enough,
or they'll constitute the possibility to find the underlying remedy.
In any case these symptoms are not really bothering the patient. He says, I can live with them.
In such a case the best tactic is to wait, not to give a remedy for such symptoms. You can wait for 6 months, 1 year.
For instance the case we saw yesterday with the headache, if she goes on with mild headaches which can be treated,
can be ameliorated by aspirin
we will wait and wait.
But if these headaches become worse and worse, we go back to Lac caninum
not to Causticum, not to Phosphorus. Phosphorus maybe after 3 years will be indicated, I don't know.
This is a case again where he has some
new symptoms that belong to the remedy.
If you make a mistake here and you treat these symptoms, these new symptoms that they develop
belong to the remedy you gave.
Such a good reaction, initial aggravation, amelioration and then new symptoms and you treat these symptoms,
this is the biggest mistake you can make.
Why we have this condition, do you know?
Because the organism is very sensitive to the remedy so it may give out some of the
characteristic symptoms of the remedy.
This person is the best prover for this remedy but with an amelioration it means a cure is going to
take place and the symptoms will vanish,
don't bother, don't touch them.
I think these mistakes were made. You know this book we were writing together with Bill Gray
and he was in Athens staying there for 2 years with me and left his patients behind. When he saw these observations,
he withdrew the remedies he was giving all the time. In the end of the year he went back for 1 month
to see all his patients and see what
happened and then he came back.
He said, George you won't believe my success was fantastic this time. All these years I was battling with the cases,
now I left them alone and in 1 year most
of the cases were cured, I can't believe it.
That's how, he, himself saw the
results of that strategy.
You have the aggravation of the physical symptoms and then amelioration of the physical symptoms.
But energy and mental-emotional remains the same, unchanged.
It means that the remedy was correct as a first remedy but there is another underlying remedy  which you have to find.
If you wait you will see some physical
symptoms appearing as well,
which you have to take into consideration together with the mental-emotional
and see whether you can find the next remedy. In any case you will have to wait
because you may see that after 3-4 months a general amelioration may take place as well.
This is the case where mostly happens in the practice. This is what you get really, I'm better but not really well.
Better without aggravation,
no change of energy.
Now here you have to be careful. If this happens with a pathology which is not severe,
if this happens in group 1
that means wrong remedy.
If this happens in group lower 3 or 4 this might be the correct remedy but the organism does not have enough
energy to recuperate. You get some deep cases in which you prescribe very carefully and there are changes,
there are ameliorations without an initial aggravation and this amelioration brings the case more and more
to a possibility of a cure.
Eventually when you will give the last remedy,
then you will have a reaction, then you will see deep changes and possibility of a cure.
In all these possibilities there are a lot of questions that I don't see you're asking but anyhow it doesn't matter.
-Can you repeat it with the groups?
-When this reaction happens in group 1 patients when there is no deep pathology
it means the remedy is wrong, it's close but wrong definitely.
If this happens in group 3 or 4, it might be the remedy is correct, that means the symptoms are ameliorated
though the whole patient is not affected.
Then you will see later on another remedy, later on another remedy, until you reach a point
where you hit deep and then there is a reaction.
With the Italian group these lectures took 5 days because they had a lot of questions which I don't see in this group.
-You once said that if you take more and more remedies then you're going to be confused on an emotional level
and that you're drifting towards an emotional sickness and that no remedy picture is clear anymore.
-Not only emotional, it can be physical, changing the symptoms of the physical body can also happen.
Not necessarily that you drive the disease in the mental-emotional, you can confuse it also in the physical level.
-But where is the point that differentiates this from the provings? Where is the healthy part in this?
-She is talking about this case?
-No, in general.
-The question in general is what is the
difference between a proving and what?
-Making many provings?
-Yes, I did not make it clear. The difference is that if you make a proving you develop some symptoms,
you wait until the symptoms go away
and you make the next proving.
When you confuse the case you don't wait the symptoms to go away by themselves,
you want to push them out by a remedy,
so you give another remedy.
Then there is another remedy and then there is more confusion, more symptoms, different symptoms.
Then you give a third remedy, a fourth remedy and therefore making this confusion. This is the difference.
-Does this have a positive effect in the whole?
-Which one, the proving?
-Anyway both because they are similar.
-No, they are not similar.
-But you said it has a positive effect to take provings.
-If you make a proving correctly, it is positive. If you confuse the case, it means you cannot find finally
what is the remedy so the person
will remain in that confused state.
Here is the difference between order and disorder. When you have a proving and then you let it go
and then you have another proving and you
let it go. Now in this you have this and then on this picture
you impose another remedy
and you make it like this.
And then you impose another picture and you make it like this. This is the final result.
You don't know anymore what is the order in the organism. That is why it's very difficult to cure.
This happens with specialties. They give mixtures 20-30 remedies where they try to cure, let us say,
chronic headaches and you ask the person what is the problem now? Now the problem is I can't think,
there is something which is between
headache and vertigo.
You try to find the remedy, no picture.
This is what has happened.
In the first years when I was treating Krishnamurti and I went to Switzerland and a lot of people
were coming to listen to him from France, Belgium, Germany all the countries of Europe,
patients that they would come to me to be treated, invariably all those cases that they were treated
by the homeopaths they were all polypharmacy. They were all either specialties
or mixing 20, 30 remedies and give it. Invariably in such cases I could not find any remedy. It was a confusion
and the confusion was in the mind. My mind is not functioning.
Maybe the initial problem or pains they have disappeared but it has become something else which has no order.
So that is why all the pharmaceutical
companies wanted to kill me during that time.
They said, what are you talking? Instead of giving 30 remedies, we give only 1 and only 1 time?
Do you believe that we can exist by selling 1 remedy to this patient and cure this patient with 1 remedy?
And then they started putting doctors to attack me but it's ok, I am a hard indigestible object.
Now they have put the church against me and say, he is the high priest of a new religion.
I did not know that, maybe, this is ridiculous.
-George, in such a case where it is confused in NY I get people who've seen many different types of Homeopaths
or people where don't even study Homeopathy, they read a book and they take many, many different remedies
and then they come to my office. What do you do? Do you wait and you say, just come back
in 6 months and see if your picture is clear?
-I tell you what is the best policy. First of all you explain to them that you have to have time, to give you time.
The second is to study very well the case and find what is the best indicated remedy.
Once you give it then you wait, and wait and watch until you see a picture of a remedy coming more clear
and then you can give the second remedy. In this way eventually you may take them out of the confusion.
This is a very bad state for us, it's not so bad to have side effects from allopathic drugs as much as when they have taken
20-30 remedies before and they come to us to be treated. This is more difficult because this order has been disturbed.
The chemical drugs do not disturb the order.
Cortisone disturbs the order which is taken every day, there is no question and psychotropic drugs disturb the order.
But for someone to take for a period of time antibiotics or to take pain killers it's not so bad
but for someone all the time to take wrong homeopathic remedies...
Because here in the 20-30 remedies maybe he takes the correct one also but the person not knowing
how to evaluate he does not know that he gave the right remedy and continues to give other remedies.
This is the tragic.
-I have a question to the picture 6 and I think we just go too fast so I can't pose any questions and it's so interesting.
What you said before is that in group 1 is the wrong remedy but in group 1 when the health
is so strong and the organism is so strong,
how can wrong remedy suppress ?
-Not suppress, ameliorate. I don't say suppress. He is better on the physical symptom, it's not suppression
but I have other symptoms like some anxiety etc. and my energy is low, it's not improved. But my chronic cough is better.
In such a case if this is on the first level, that means strong personality, the remedy touches only upon the physical symptoms.
What they used to do in old times, they knew some keynotes and they used these keynotes and gave the remedy
according to the keynotes only. And this was the result. Better the symptom without the patient getting better.
The correct reaction on the first group should be either aggravation and then amelioration or a general amelioration.
That is the correct reaction. If you see this reaction you know that your remedy has acted partially,
only upon a portion of the patient.
But as you go down the scale, this reaction may mean, if you go down to the groups, may mean that the organism is not
possible to do any better. It does this and then you have to search for the underlying remedy.
-Concerning patients in group 3 and 4. If the emotional and mental sphere is getting worse, how long can I wait?
You said, the physical is getting better but the mental-emotional is getting worse, this scares me to be in my office
and watch people getting worse in mental-emotional, how long can I wait?
-For which observation she is talking, which number?
Number 6 doesn't say that the mental-
emotional is getting worse, it's the same.
If he gets worse, that's another observation. I'm better but not really well, she complains she's better
without aggravation no change in energy
or mental-emotional.
This observation does not say that the
mental-emotional becomes worse.
- One example is somebody coming in my office, he has inflammation of the skin and some others which is a Belladona picture.
I give Belladona, the inflammation disappears. I have no time asking about other things. Later on he comes,
and he says the inflammation is away but now I feel emotionally or my energy worse than before.
If I had asked about other things I would find another remedy which is better fit?
-Better yes but that is different from this observation. This says that the physical symptoms are better,
and we're talking about chronic conditions.
The physical symptoms are better but the mental-emotional energy no change.
That means your lumbago is better but mental-emotional is the same. If it is worse is another observation.
If it becomes worse the mental-emotional
and the energy then it's another observation.
We see it later on.
-But this inflammation could be a
sign of an underlying chronic disease.
-Maybe, that's possible but if there is aggravation on the mental-emotional while the physical is better,
this is not this observation. This observation we say, no change on mental-emotional or energy.
-But in this case I said, would you
say then that it was a suppression?
-Yes.
-I would like to know how long I would
have to wait when such a disorder the
way you painted it on the blackboard has appeared? Because this is a very common case in practice.
In this way you can start retaking the case from
a month later.
If you don't see another remedy, then you wait. You give placebo you come later on, then you find out eventually
you have the right picture. The basic idea is don't rush to give a remedy when you are unsure in such a case.
Don't rush. Or I made a mistake,
I'll give you another remedy, no wait.
-George can I ask one more question about the previous graph? If the two parts of the graph were
the other way around that the mental-emotional had improved and the physical symptoms
had remained the same, am
I right thinking that wait...
-Then you have to wait.
-For the physical symptoms to start
to remove at some later stage?
-Yes correct.
-I have a case, the patient comes with a complaint, I give him a remedy, the physical gets better
and then soon he comes back half a year later and has a relapse. And then if I give him the correct remedy
I have an amelioration in all three levels.
Is that what you mean with this graph?
-Yes, if you give another remedy and has an amelioration of 3 levels, then it is the correct remedy.
But this cannot happen in group 3 downwards. Next time he comes or 3rd time he comes that you find a remedy
that will ameliorate all the situation, mental-emotional, energy and the symptoms.
In these lower groups you will not see that. In the upper groups it means it should be reacting like this, is not reacting
is reacting only partially, that means your remedy is acting partially, therefore you have to search
for another remedy which is deeper. You will see this situation, you have a bronchitis and the person calls you,
the first night I haven't slept the whole night
I have been coughing, coughing with sputum.
And you say, was it difficult to lie down? Yes,
I had to get up, lying down was very difficult for me.
So you think quickly, Coccus cacti, take 200, 3 doses. He goes through the night and he says, the cough was
not so bad I still cough quite a lot, the fever was higher, the sputum does not come out so much so
it's rather dry but the cough in general was better.
What is your assumption?
Partial action of the remedy. Then my head was very hot and my feet were cold and you say,
my God this was a case of Belladona not a case of Coccus cacti. You give Belladona
and you have initial reaction and then he feels better.
This is applicable to a small scale like in a severe acute or to a larger scale where you're treating chronic conditions.
Now if you treat an acute condition upon a patient who is sick chronically, that's a different story.
Because if you take the acute condition as a physical symptomatology and you give a remedy and you treat this,
you may give the correct remedy, the condition goes away and the underlying chronic condition stays.
In that case the remedy is correct. Why?
Because during the acute, he has physical symptoms but at the same time he feels tired
and at the same time he says, I feel lazy.
Do you have energy? No, I'm lazy.
So in the acute you have the effect upon the mental-emotional, the energy and the physical.
When you give Coccus cacti, you ameliorate the cough but these two remain the same,
that means partial action of the remedy. When you give the correct remedy, all this has to come down.
The underlying chronic condition will be untouched; still the remedy is correct because there was
no connection between his
acute and his chronic condition.
If there was a connection, if the remedy fitted his chronic condition as well, you will see a big reaction
and when he comes out of the acute condition, he says, I feel much better, my heart is better,
my liver is better, my stomach is better.
My original problem is better but now I have another one. Better without aggravation while deeper problem has emerged...
You see whenever you do not see aggravations, you have a big problem actually. You like to see the initial aggravation.
This is the case in which you suppress and you have the appearance of a new condition which is deeper.
You treat for instance arthritis of the joints of the fingers. You give Caulophyllum because it has pains in the finger joints
and the pains go away but after two months the pains appear in the wrist or in the elbow.
This you know that it is a suppressive effect, the patient does not know because he feels he is treated well
but now it's a new condition, the pain in the elbow, but you know what you have done.
It doesn't matter if the patient knows or he understands.
But the same time in such a case you do not see any change in general condition of the patient.
Or you treat psoriasis which is in the palms or the hands and then psoriasis appears on the face.
You know that, I've done it.
What do you have to do?
How you handle this case?
Don't be in panic and start throwing remedies and start antidote. Don't worry because if the organism
is strong enough will by itself return to the original state. So if you don't know what to do, you give placebo
and the original state will come back.
But if you want to do something then you retake the case and you may find out that they were symptoms
that were there in the case but the patient did not mention in the first place
or symptoms that you did not take into consideration.
And if you take now these symptoms, the remedy picture becomes more clear. Many times we think that
we know the remedy and by the end of the consultation there is one or two symptoms added and you change the prescription.
This is the case where you would have given the wrong remedy which would be close, would have
this effect without the last moment information.
It changes the whole picture.
And then if you are lucky this will happen in time, otherwise it will happen in the next consultation,
or the third or the fifth consultation, I don't know.
-I have a question to case 7, the one before.
If you have given the wrong remedy and in the next consultation
you see a new remedy, also through the new symptoms that appeared, when is the correct time to give this new remedy?
-If you see a new remedy picture after this, that is the next observation where it means that you did not have
originally enough information to prescribe
but you prescribed close enough.
The organism then gives out new symptoms which then have a clear picture of the new remedy.
That is what we call the one-sided diseases where they don't give enough information to prescribe,
you prescribe and there are some changes but there are new symptoms even worse than before.
The person may feel even worse after your remedy and this worse will stay for years if you don't treat
but this new picture is clear that means your first remedy though it seemed that brought about an aggravation
and new symptoms, it's a correct remedy.
Which gave you a new picture now which is more clear, you prescribe and you have a beautiful cure.
-A question on 7 again please. A new symptom that comes up on 7, do I take that into
consideration when I'm relooking at the case?
-The new symptoms which they have appeared after the original, have gone.
You may take it into consideration.
You may have to ignore it.
-How do I know?
-There is a rule. If these new symptoms make the case more clear, you take them in consideration.
If on the contrary these new symptoms do not fit your remedy picture which you already have, ignore them.
-If I understand correctly that in case 7 there are two possibilities of interpretation.
The main interpretation was that the remedy was incorrect and acted in a suppressive manner,
in some cases this could have been the remedy
that was correct which opened the case through producing new symptoms and cleared it.
-We did not put this in the same. What you say is in the next observation, where it makes the picture clear.
New symptoms but with the new symptoms you have a more clear picture. The remedy was good.
-I have a question concerning special case. A case where we were circling Natrum muriaticum for a long time
and then a picture of Ignatia became clear. How do I differentiate the following?
After taking Ignatia she had an amelioration which lasted for a couple of hours and afterwards she fell into
deep sleep going on for days, extreme tiredness and then she came into a state which seems to be Natrum muriaticum.
I think it is an aggravation on mental-emotional level, she is closed to herself. Now the question is:
was this the wrong remedy, was it a proving
or was it indication for the next remedy?
And is it possible that there are some
people who react so quickly
to a remedy and produce a new remedy
picture within short amount of time?
-The reaction which she describes, which she had an amelioration and then she fell into a deep sleep.
This is a very good reaction. This we consider an aggravation on the energy level. So it goes to the first reaction
where we had aggravation on all
levels and then amelioration.
So she had to wait without any other remedy, so after Ignatia eventually she would be better and better.
In any case she would be better, she may need after a month Natrum muriaticum to complete the action but definitely
that kind of reaction where the person falls asleep for 20-30 hours after the remedy, is a very good reaction
and points to the fact that the patient is going to be well if you wait long enough to see it.
The problem is that even in the older times when they gave a lot of mixtures, many times they had cures.
But these cures brought out some reactions. Now that was the time when everybody was spoiling the case
and bringing back everything good
that was done even with the mixtures.
You have Calcarea carbonica in the mixture, the person is Calcarea carbonica, then you have a reaction,
and then they break out with an eruption.
And then as soon they see the eruption they say, oh my god Sulphur, Rhus tox until you suppress,
back again the whole situation.
This is not Homeopathy, this is not understood the basics of Homeopathy.
If you know this theory I'm absolutely sure that you can predict a lot of things that happen in your patient.
And then you are not afraid. You see the fears coming and you say, don't worry they'll go away.
Now I have this, now I have a depression. Don't worry, but you know when you say it. You don't say, don't worry
to anybody who comes. You know when to say don't worry and when to worry.
If you know the theory you know what's going to happen.
-In the observation 8 if you see some new and more severe pathology compared with the original one,
was this patient anyway going to go to this pathology or is due to the remedy?
-He was going to go but you speed up the process. There is no pathology that will develop to a patient because of the remedy.
It is because is the course of the disease and he was going to get to that state, 3 months later or 1 year later.
Then you give the remedy and the organism accepts the furthering of the development of the disease but
we cannot say that with Homeopathy
we give a disease, no.
It is only when there is possibility in the organism, then this possibility will develop.
-You mentioned new symptoms. Are these, symptoms that have never before been presented
in that case or are they symptoms that the patient revealed...
-Yes, never before presented to the case. New symptoms, I give you the example. You have the psoriasis
in the legs and then you see it in the face. Did you have it in the face before? No.
Now it's the first time you have it?
Yes. That's a suppression.
If he had it before and it was taken away by cortisone etc. and then reappears in the face, that is different.
-But if it starts in the face and moves down to the hands ...
-It's a very good reaction.
-I have a question about suppression. I have a case with arthritis in the fingers and then happened exactly what you said.
But this arthritis in the fingers lasted for several weeks. Then it went away with Tuberculinum.
Several months later was an inflammation of the elbow but this went away very fast, only 2-3 days.
-By what remedy?
-Again by Tuberculinum. Now was this suppression or was a cure?
The second of inflammation was for the patient much easier to stand.
-It was a cure. Why? You remember yesterday I put the 3 cones and I said it will depend on the intensity.
We have depression here and we have depression here, it's a different kind of depression.
A depression here will be treated with 5 remedies for 5 years or 10 remedies for 5 years
and this depression here will be treated
with 1 remedy in 2 days.
So if you treat a condition which is here with arthritis or is here severe arthritis of the fingers and it goes well.
Then you have a milder form of arthritis on a place which supposed to be deeper but the arthritis is milder,
it's on this level now. It's deeper but immediately went away, so the person develops arthritis here
but he comes into that level
and develops arthritis.
All these things were not known before, I'm treating depression
I'm depressed, I took the remedy and I'm depressed, I took the remedy and I have fears,
I took the remedy and this and that, total confusion.
Now we're trying to clarify this confusion and to know what we're doing and why we're doing something.
-A patient from a different country which I only see every 4 months, and she had severe asthma,
had a remedy 4 months ago and then it
changed into very bad eczema on the hands.
This person is a singer and school teacher for rock music and she keeps calling what can I do for her hands
because without cortisone cream she can't do anything. So what I give her Silica or something else?
I'm really mixed up. I'd really love to give her Graph or something else but I know I shouldn't.
-What is the original remedy you gave?
-I think it was Sulphur.
-If the itching is Sulphur again, it's
worse at night, worse with water...
-It has blisters and she said it's opening,
I haven't seen it yet.
-Maybe it's still on Sulphur level and by giving a higher potency of Sulphur it may help her as well.
It is necessary to see her. If you treat asthma and immediately you have the reappearance, this is a very fortunate thing.
That means the remedy was correct, the organism is strong, she could be saved this person
but you have to be careful not to drive it back because with the wrong medication you will drive it back.
-What can I do because she is playing guitar and she can't do this because she has audience and concerts.
She should wear gloves and
have a little cream on it.
-This is a practical problem, you have to ask her but theoretically I tell you what you have to do.
You have to see the case whether she is still Sulphur or maybe another remedy and then you give it
but even in such a case I would say, wait and see whether the original Sulphur would clear up the eruption as well.
-I saw children that were treated in their childhood when they were 2 years old for neurodermatitis
and after about 2 years, they return and showed signs of spastic bronchitis. How should I evaluate this?
Does this have to do with wrong homeopathic treatment or do they just come years later with a new disease?
-No, this has to do with wrong homeopathic treatment unless the eczema was very bad and the asthma was very light.
Unless you have this difference and then in such a case if, let us say, you have given Calcarea carbonica
2 years ago and now you will see again Calcarea carbonica picture, you will give it for the asthma and the asthma
will go away beautifully and maybe will
reappear some eczema but mild.
But if you have given a lot of remedies to cure this and now the asthma is really bad, that is wrong treatment.
- You say that the difference between 7 and 8 is that the appearing of the new symptoms is on the one hand going
on the opposite direction of the law of Hering where in 8 the new symptoms appear
independently from the law of Hering.
-That is true. When we have the opposite of the law of Herrring we suspect a suppression.
But even then, if the new symptoms present a clear picture then still the remedy,
I would say is correct and you give it and
then you see the final cure.
But usually when you have the opposite of the law of cure, then you have a suppression and the remedy is incorrect.
Going opposite to the law of cure, usually is wrong unless there is a new picture which is clear.
You see even a case of asthma in which you give a remedy and then you produce symptoms on the mental level
which are Sulphur symptoms. I become lazy,
I don't want to work, I don't want to wash, this we consider
the remedy was correct because it produced a clear picture of Sulphur on the mental-emotional and physical level.