This is a type of a reaction which many times is coming to your office; that is a correct reaction in the beginning.
Short aggravation, amelioration,
then he comes after a month and says,
'I was better but the last week or the last
days I feel back the symptoms'.
What happens in these cases is that the initial reaction  is so good and the patient feels very
well,
the day after or 2-3 days after.
He feels oh my god that's like a miracle
and then they go into a state of euphoria. But after a few days or weeks
they start getting back a little bit of the symptoms; they get into a panic state thinking that the whole thing
is back and they will pressurize you for
giving another dose or another remedy.
You have to be very careful because if
you start giving another remedy, forget it.
The moment that the reaction was correct in the beginning it does not matter that they complain
as long as there is no full relapse they can complain and they may even go into hysterics
if you tell them I don't give you another medicine.
You see how bad they were in the beginning? Now they say, I feel 10%, 20% worse, no medicine, wait, give placebo.
Otherwise you will spoil 100% the case, if you repeat the same remedy yes. Even with the same remedy,
you may be lucky and no spoil the case
but you don't go by luck you go by law.
And the law says, you should wait
otherwise your luck will finish one day.
Patient after patient will come
back and say, I'm not well.
The idea is that you will see the patient after a year or two years becoming really better.
Not make them better the next day. I have this headache, give me a medicine so my headache will go away.
No, take an aspirin if the law says you
must take an aspirin, take an aspirin.
This case is happening quite frequently, the people feel so good, the feeling is exactly like
the one who gets
out of prison and the first days he enjoys freedom and says, my god I can go here and there.
After a few weeks he gets used to it. We don't appreciate freedom because we have not being in jail.
The same way he will start not appreciating the fact that he is well now and the least thing will bother him.
And the organism cannot stay in a straight line, you get back the organism and the organism stays like that.
No because there are stresses all the time; so the organism will fluctuate, it cannot be perfection for ever.
Therefore with the stress and especially if you get a little bit hysterical persons they can create by themselves
symptoms or augment the symptoms, increase the symptoms. And then you are forced,
take the remedy and then no effect.
This case, never mind how much you may repeat there will be no effect because there is no real relapse.
In this case you just either give placebo, placebo, placebo, I'm better, I'm better, I'm still better. Are you back? No.
Ok I'll give you a good medicine, give placebo, one month, 2nd month,20 months, 25 months until you will
realize that there are symptoms of a new remedy, then you give.
-I was wondering if these instances...I have experience with a patient who has done, she said, miraculously well
and after about two and a half months,
symptoms begun to slowly return.
My thought at that time was that the remedy had exhausted and I repeated it the same remedy
slightly higher potency, no response at all and the symptoms continued to get worse and worse, again repeated
little higher thinking that the potency was not high enough, again the same symptoms continued
to get worse and then I
started giving different remedies.
-That is a usual story where you start
spoiling your case in this way.
-How do you differentiate between when the remedy is getting thin and exhausted and symptoms
begin to return and when they are at this
level, how do you distinguish that?
-There are different ways. One way is that you have certain keynotes of the remedy on which you have prescribed.
Let's take one of the cases we saw with Medorrhinum, she said I had sensitive soles and the sensitivity
is not there anymore. Then placebo, placebo.
Then one day she says, I have my complains and the keynote is back. That is the time where you can repeat the remedy.
The keynote on which you had prescribed originally and which was minimized or gone during the treatment,
it comes back that's the time you can prescribe the remedy and it will have an effect.
-Higher potency?
-The same potency first and then higher. Now there is another case in which you will see the whole case is back
and if the relapse is 85 %... But if she says, I'm 80% back but the two keynotes on which you have prescribed
originally are not back, be careful. Don't repeat that remedy. If the keynotes are not back don't repeat the remedy.
That means I'm 80% back without the keynotes of the remedy, it means most probably it needs another remedy.
Try to find another remedy. We do have some laws, some principles on which we go along.
The problem is that even myself which
I'm teaching you I make this mistake when I'm pressurized by the patient;
You are going to make the mistake,
you are going to fall under this condition.
That's why I told you when Bill Gray left the patients, the patients could not say, I have a little headache, this, that.
He came after a year, I'm very well, of course because he left them alone with the remedy to act.
Get away from the idea: whatever you have, you take a remedy. Because I have seen cases where
you have a little accident and there is a little bruise, oh take Arnica, take Arnica. This is wrong, let the organism.
You have to be black all over and really have a shock and things like that and then you take Arnica.
A splinter is painful, 'oh I take Ledum', no.
This is not good for Homeopathy.
A little cold, my nose is running, let it run. Why? You don't have a picture of the remedy if your nose is running.
What are you going to take Allium cepa, Arsenicum, Natrum muriaticum, Thuja?
All these remedies they have nose running. Fluoric acid is running like a tap.
When you have that, you may think of Fluoric acid. In that case, this is very frequent case,
and it is unfortunate if you prescribe and
you spoil such a case.
If the case is doing much better, I'm 10%, I'm getting 20%, 30 % back. You say wait, wait, give placebo,
don't worry, it's not going to come back when
he has this reaction, is not going to come back.
-Can you please explain what happens in the organism if you repeat the remedy too quickly?
In the beginning you gave the body a kind
of surge so it can start the curing process;
if you then repeat the remedy too soon one
could say that the body gets another surge
to continue the healing process but this time
it doesn't work anymore but what I don't understand
is why it doesn't work this time?
-Because we don't have the original picture of the disease. That means we have a partial picture of the disease,
the remedy partially fits the case. Therefore it's a remedy which is close to the case and not exact.
Therefore it's going to have an effect because
it is close to the case but not exact,
So it's going to have an effect but the effect is not going to be curative, it's going to be disruptive.
It is a different thing when you don't have this reaction in levels here when you repeat every day and it's getting
a little bit better and a little bit better and the more you repeat the more better it comes. You don't have the reaction.
Once you have that reaction,
don't touch the case.
It is different when it comes
down to other levels of pathology.
There you may have to repeat
in order to promote health.
That means the organism stays on that remedy and needs every day a push or three times
the day a push,
until it really brings out a reaction.
-This situation what is the best way to handle? Having made the mistake, what is the best way to handle the case
from that time on? Acknowledging that the first remedy was correct, we had this reaction
and then the case was disrupted, what we do?
-The best way is to continue with placebo. Forget about the remedy and it will come back. It's like
a proving.
But if you start, oh I made a mistake, another remedy, another remedy, eventually you may have
a real relapse because of your remedies and not because of the organism. In which case when the real relapse
comes then you have to come back
on the original remedy and repeat it.
-My experience with this is that when I gave a placebo in such case, the patient came and said, I'm doing much better.
-Sure, many times. They just need the reassurance.
-Patient who was suffering from ulcerative colitis and with one dose of Natrum muriaticum C200 she was free of bleeding
for half a year. Now the situation is that she would like to apply for pension in earlier time
due to her disease and she now, shortly before
I left for Alonissos, again she had bleeding from the rectum
and just like when she came for the first time, she had that facial expression which gives you the feeling
she already has been touched by death, I gave her a dose of Natrum muriaticum C200 again
and it had no effect anymore. What is now the situation? Should I leave her, let her go her way that has to be gone
or should I still go and look for another remedy? My feeling is that she wants to go and has to go.
-To die you mean? No, no. How old is she?
-She is 58.
-58? No. If with a remedy was better for 6 months and now she has a relapse in which the same remedy
does not have an effect it means that the organism has changed into certain aspects and needs another remedy.
So you have to try to find the next remedy, most probably Sepia or whatever remedy, it doesn't matter.
-I have a patient who is still in treatment with me now. She came for the first time when she was 19 years old
and complained of an extremely fast heartbeat which kept her from doing things. For example she could not
take care of her household anymore due to this fast heartbeat. I found out that at 19 she had an attack, she had been touched
by a man whom she felt repulsive and many years after that she repeatedly had such attacks.
While she was still in my office I gave her Natrum muriaticum in C30, just put it on the tongue
and the fast heartbeat was gone immediately. She took this remedy for a long period of time, later on C200
and the intervals grew larger and in the end she only had to take a C200 about every four weeks.
Then she entered the next layer which was Silica. She is now 89 years old and doing very well.
- And all these years she had the problem?
It is also something else that I have to tell you again, I have mentioned it before.
You get a case with headache or with palpitation and you give a remedy and acts correctly and reduces the headaches
and then there is a relapse. This actually might not be a relapse but might be the same headaches
or similar headaches but on a much milder form.
Then you have to be careful that the modalities are the same as the original headache or now she needs
another remedy though she says, I am in a relapse, she may need another remedy because the headaches
are milder and the modality is different.
Then you have to search for another remedy.
It's very important when you re-examine a case to see whether the keynotes on which you
had prescribed originally, are gone and are not valid anymore for the present situation.
-In this case when you change the remedy and then you are afraid that this doesn't work, then what you do?
You repeat the old one or you give the placebo?
-If this is the case as we saw, you give placebo. You repeated the remedy, did not act, give placebo.
Here we don't have a full relapse, we have a partial relapse or maybe the person is feeling like this, it's not really a relapse.
-Then I want to ask if you give the remedy to the patient and she feels better, for instance, I have a patient who got
arthritis and I gave her a remedy and she felt better and she felt so better that she hold something very heavy
and then she got the problem again. Does this mean that the first remedy was not good enough
because it got her in stress and carrying something heavy she got the problem again?
-If that was the reaction, aggravation and then amelioration and then she gets this accident, most probably
during the time of the accident which she calls relapse, it is not needed the same remedy.
She needed a new remedy for the accident. Because this is considered as an accident; it's not a relapse.
-We discussed with Geukens such cases and as you know Geukens repeats remedy more frequently
and he said it can be situations with a severe disease where you do not have the time to wait until
a full relapse appears but you must give
the remedy in more frequent intervals.
What do you think about that ?
-No, I feel that if you have a case with an initial aggravation and then amelioration, then it is much better
not to repeat the remedy. If you have a severe pathology in which you did not have this reaction initially
then you gave the remedy and the remedy made the person better. And then you repeated every day,
it's getting better and better. That case belongs to the lower levels and needs a repetition
of course and until it reaches a point where you will have this initial aggravation from the remedy.
But every time you see in a case this very beautiful reaction and the person says after a short period of time,
I have a relapse don't believe it unless she says 'I have been drinking coffee, I have been taking antibiotics,
I have been doing this and that', if he has antidoted the case this is a different story. But even if he had antidoted
the case you have first to stop the antidotes, see that there is no relapse but if after stopping the antidotes,
still you see that the relapse continues
then you repeat the remedy.
This situation can happen with coffee,
let us say somebody drinks coffee,
it cannot happen that within 2 weeks
he has a relapse.
He got the right remedy, he is quite well now, he drinks coffee, it will take a few months before he has a relapse.
-Does this mean even not to give
nothing is the same?
-Not to give nothing, yes, give placebo means to please, it comes from the verb 'placeo' and means to please,
so to please the person is ok and feels content. So the element of hysteria and reactions from
hysteria and fear subsides. So you don't
have the implications of hysterics
or the fear I'm getting back, you give the
placebo and then it goes down.
Homeopaths must understand more in depth human nature. That's why we are much more tolerating
situations than others. We are not severe. We cannot say, this is correct, you have to do this, because we know
that diseases make people act in a
way which is not very social.
Here you have a real relapse after a month.
After a good aggravation, a good reaction,
it is back in a month. This is not normal.
Something abnormal is happening, it is not possible that the organism within a month after such
a good reaction by itself and without any
reason will come back to relapse state.
Search for antidotes like going to the dentist, taking chemicals drugs taking marijuana, LSD, ecstasy, crack,
all these antidote homeopathic treatment, coffee also. If it's so fast, three times the day you drink coffee?
Three coffees a day can bring within a month a relapse but the organism needs a shock.
What other shocks may have the organism?
Then you ask whether it was a big stress,
somebody lost his fortune, lost a very
dear person, grief of whatever type.
This grief may bring back that situation.
But grief may not bring back a relapse
but may bring back a particular syndrome
which we call Ignatia syndrome or Natrum muriaticum or Aurum syndrome.
So you may not see the relapse but you see the syndrome, in which case you will prefer to give the Ignatia
instead of repeating the remedy.
-I wanted to ask what is the difference between the case I said before and this. This is taking something very heavy
is stress as well or do you mean only mental stress and not physical stress?
-Physical stress as well but I said if the physical stress gives out symptoms different than the relapse
then you prefer to give the
remedy that covers these symptoms.
That means if you lift something and you have given Calcarea carbonica and then now you have symptoms of Rhus tox,
you prefer to give Rhus tox. If you have another grief in which you have symptoms of Ignatia,
you prefer to give Ignatia or Aurum during the stress. Don't consider it a relapse of the original state.
-My question regards some chronic cases, severe chronic cases like I had a case of a man 50 years old,
he had a severe arthritis. Big swollen joints.
It's in a state of suppurating, it's coming out of his skin, it looks like cream, it's not pus, it's quite strange thing
and he was for 5 years on medication.
I gave him Ledum 1000 and he was much much better
but the problem was that all his symptoms start to come from his ankles to his knees up
and then after this remedy he feels a great relief but symptoms come back and he cannot stand.
Because his ankles became
more swollen than the knees.
He started to use these allopathic drugs in which he was on for the last 5 years. Of course he became much worse.
I tried to follow what we had here and I started
to give every week the same remedy a C30
because he insisted that he must
use these allopathic drugs.
What would you do in this occasion, when there is a chronic case and the patient cannot give up
taking allopathic drugs but there is a
certain good progress with the remedy?
-You repeat the remedy every day. You repeat the remedy every day, perhaps 2 or 3 times the day,
30 or 200 you repeat it every day to
counteract the action of the allopathic drugs.
-I have a question about drugs. I know a woman who has taken LSD 20 years ago and it triggered claustrophobia
since then and she's going to Homeopath but has no results. Do you think this is irreversible?
-Claustrophobia by itself only it is not irreversible. It can be relieved by the correct remedy.
-I have a question again to antidoting. I had to antidote the effect of my remedy last week because otherwise
I would be in an narcotic state throughout the seminar and I took this Ignatia and then this sort
of narcotic effect was following. And I had to antidote it otherwise I wouldn't be able to come here.
-One week, two weeks then she rejuvenated.
-She antidoted with camphor and one hour after antidoting with camphor she had a very beautiful effect.
She felt very high and now she is like intermediate between very good and bad. What shall I do now?
-Very good question. I don't know.
You see now what happened is she
tried to stop the reaction of the remedy.
If she let herself sleep another 10-15 hours, these states do not last very long, she would have the full
benefit of the remedy. Now she cut it and I don't know. That's why the organism goes back and forward now
and she has to wait now, to go back to the original state in order to repeat. Otherwise if she repeats now Ignatia,
forget it, she will have no effect. She will
feel a little bit agitated and that's all.
Now she has to wait and see either there is an
Ignatia again situation or maybe another remedy.
But now she has to wait, don't touch it
now because the reaction is very good.
Initial aggravation like this. If the aggravation takes the form of sleepiness is one of the best.
The organism takes all its energy
to relax and rejuvenate.
And he comes out of that sleep in a very very good condition. When you see that you say 'sleep'.
I had a case of Aurum, he slept for 20 days,
day and night. He would just wake up, eat
and go back to sleep. He says, I had to give up my work, I cannot work. Very good.
Stop working. He was pushing himself working and working and then the organism broke down
and then you give and he slept and slept.
He was a man of almost 60 years old.
-One short remark to the case. I think this is a good working remedy and now he resists on taking allopathic drugs.
I spoiled my remedy in this case instead of insisting the patient to slow down his allopathic drugs.
-As long as there is amelioration then
you have to take out the drugs slowly.
But I am not sure your remedy is correct. From what you said, I have some doubts but anyhow try it.