-This is something that we see many times. If somebody comes here and you hear 'I took this remedy
and I was better for a while I took that remedy and I was better', 3, 4 remedies have good reaction
but very short time. We hear that many times and usually it means that the remedy was close but not exact.
So the patient also does not discriminate exactly what he feels or how he feels better.
I have noticed something. I know a doctor who does it every time he sees a patient.
If you give Natrum muriaticum to every case almost invariably they will say, I feel better psychologically.
The reason is that everyone goes through some kind of stress and grief and Natrum muriaticum has an effect
on this emotional level, I feel better. But the complain actually is not the physical complain or the headaches.
I feel better psychologically but the headaches are the same, I feel better psychologically but my stomach is the same.
That kind of reaction you don't like.
As I said yesterday, you give a remedy
and the person says the next day,
'I'm much better thank you very much'. You don't like this because either the case is incurable
in which case we have group 4.
Any remedy you prescribe in group 4,
any correct remedy will bring an immediate amelioration. Then you don't like because this is group 4
or the remedy is close but not exact.
What you like in Homeopathy always is to observe an initial aggravation from the remedy.
And this is natural according to our understanding of how the remedy acts because many times
they ask us how you don't have a
theory, how your remedy acts.
I always say, we have the most logical theory possible. It cannot be more clear and what is more clear is,
when the organism produces five symptoms and through these symptoms is trying to bring balance
and you find a remedy that produces also these five symptoms and it pushes the symptoms.
The organism produces symptoms, you give a remedy produces similar symptoms, what it does?
Aggravation. It makes the symptoms more strong and then we have the amelioration. What is more logical than this
by saying that the organism is trying by itself to bring about order, it cannot. Therefore every day
it produces a headache, 10 o'clock the
headache comes. It comes to bring about order.
What has happened? Different things, one is that the person had a rupture in their love affairs
and after this the headache stayed and it comes 10 o'clock in the morning. Then you give the Natrum muriaticum
what do you expect? The next day she will say, I went to bed with headache, I never had such a terrible headache.
It's perfect. But if she says, she has this headache for 10 years and you give the remedy, and she says next day I feel better....
You expect that after a month at the
latest you will have a relapse.
Of course such prescriptions they can
keep your patients coming.
Even for a few days I was relieved, the patient will come back to you but you know the remedy is incorrect.Why?
Because there was no aggravation. You may say it might be correct and the remedy was antidoted after 15 days.
That is a possibility also but in such a case where the person feels quite good immediately after the remedy
without real aggravation it belongs to that.
The headache cannot be strong,
really strong, malignant headache.
I started having a headache some days ago. Why? Because I got some grief.
You give Natrum muriaticum and the grief goes away and the headache goes away without aggravation.
That is group 1. Do you understand?
These observations have to be seen according to the groups because these observations do not apply to all the cases.
We have to make different
observations for different cases
and we have to make a very detailed
description of the possible reaction.
It will be too many that's why we try to put together and generalize and give the main ideas.
Then you have to think for yourself but in a case
where there is a relapse after two weeks,
then you know that your remedy was acting superficially, that is the most probable.
The second probability is the case is really incurable and these cases that are really incurable
may not have such a severe
pathology at the moment when you prescribe.
At the moment you prescribe it doesn't seem to have a very big pathology, forget it, you may try for years
and you will see the organism is never going to pass a threshold, why? Group 4, it feels weak, it feels exhausted.
'I have a pain here, my head is not clear'. If you hear this abstract symptomatology, you don't like.
You like to hear I have cancer but every night I perspire here and I like sweets and my feet are cold and I have cancer.
You say, thank God take Calcarea carbonica and the cancer is gone and you get the other case where he feels
exhausted, tired, 'my head is not clear and sometimes I shiver and this and that', you try, you try and no picture is formed.
You give a remedy, you have this reaction, even the best possible prescription will have this reaction,
better for a while, then back again. Better for a while then back again but stays on the same level, there is no movement.
-I don't understand one thing. You've said
that in incurable cases from group 4
if you give the right remedy there
is only amelioration.
-Only amelioration and then aggravation and then a relapse or a different remedy.
-But now you have said that also
there we expect an aggravation.
-Where?
-In group 4.
-Let us take the possibility that this case is incurable. Then if you have a relapse what you are going to do?
You are going to give the same remedy. This is the case where you have pains from cancer, you give Sulphur
and there is an amelioration on the pains and then there is a relapse, you give again Sulphur,
and then amelioration and again a relapse.
Second time and then the third
time he says, 'I'm not anymore hot'.
Change the remedy and you have to find
the next remedy, it is Calcarea carbonica.
Better, relapse, Calcarea carbonica.
Better, relapse, Calc.
And I said, there is a time that maybe even in such cases, there is going to be an aggravation after treating
the person for 2-3 years. Then there is a possibility for cure, because it jumps from group
4 to group 3.
-Could that be a possibility that you have a patient and you give a remedy, you repeat the remedy and after
taking the remedy for example for
the third time, there is an aggravation.
Is there a possibility afterwards
that the body goes up?
-That's a good question. That is another possibility also where they don't belong really to group 4.
This is a case where there is a possibility for a cure for that person, he is somewhere here
and what happens sometimes is that you give the remedy and there is an amelioration.
And you give again and there is an amelioration and the organism by these 2-3 times repetition is already strengthened.
The 4th time there is aggravation with the same remedy, that you wait, you wait because this aggravation
being in this group, is going to be long aggravation, 2 weeks, 3,4 weeks. You let it go, don't stop it.
-I had a patient and I gave him a remedy. At first he had an aggravation, then amelioration and then he was alright.
But what is the case when I repeat the remedy and every time he has an aggravation, is it ok or I don't know?
-There is no such case but let us say that there is an aggravation and then what? Tell me, after the aggravation what?
-Every time when I repeat the remedy he had aggravation and then always amelioration.
-It's rather improbable but it shows that the organism comes back to where it was originally.
Even after the amelioration there is a kind of relapse but this relapse gets the patient
to the same level as he was originally.
Where usually it does not happen, we see that
with an aggravation and then an amelioration the patient stays for a long period well
then there is a relapse, then you give the remedy again the same, group 1, then he stays well
for a long period of time. This can happen. So if you treat a group 1 case, you may have this
but in a very long time, in years,
you just prescribe a few times.
You see a Natrum muriaticum case, constitutional in this group,
because here in this group Natrum
muriaticum will act superficially.
It will take away, better psychologically
and then we'll see what happens.
In the upper groups, Natrum muriaticum which is indicated as a constitutional remedy, will have
a big reaction in the beginning and then an amelioration for long period of time. Here, Natrum muriaticum
will act for a while, then the person will go to some other remedy. In the upper case, the person is structured
to be sensitive in its very structure. Therefore a grief on that Natrum muriaticum constitutional person
will have a deep effect where a grief on these levels will not have such deep effects.
A grief here can bring a relapse on the Natrum muriaticum state. In the same way that Calcarea carbonica
which has a sensitivity on their back or the glands, if they lift something they will bring back the sensitivity
but again as a Calcarea carbonica situation.
Where here in this group, there is some grief,
there is some amelioration after Natrum muriaticum,
there is again some grief and the reaction goes towards Staphysagria, towards Aurum, different.
In this group the reaction on the grief will go back to the same condition.
- About what you said about Nat-m in group 1 or 2, if you have a relapse after grief and you give Nat-m
again, does it mean that she will
not have an aggravation?
-She can have an aggravation in case the organism is on the lower group 1.
If the organism is here, she may not have an aggravation.
You're having this reaction immediate but never in a month you will have a relapse in group 1.
-I was only relating to the question she said. She said if you give a remedy you can have an aggravation.
-This can happen a few times where the remedy belongs to this here, where you have an aggravation,
then amelioration, for a long time but this organism actually if you look through, you will see the next remedy.
Because already on this group the lower 1 there is a possibility of another remedy, Sepia, let us say.
If you give Sepia then it stays
for a longer period of time.
The idea is we make as less
as possible, mistakes.
Not that we don't make mistakes, this is not possible because there is the human
element and there is this driving force on the
part of the patient who is pressuring you.
You get in America and they get in the telephone and they demand that something will be done immediately.
They are not patient, they have not learned that this waiting, as an idea is not conceivable in the American people.
They have to do everything fast, everything efficient and everything should have been done yesterday.
This is a rule so why not my headache? Why even to have a headache? You told me you are going to cure me.
They pressurize you. If you don't know the rules you are going to make mistake and mistake
until you are disappointed and then you say,
let's go to Vithoulkas to see what is he doing?
-To have it clear in my mind, do I have to decide is this a case finally incurable or not?
I got a remedy which has slightest
aggravation how can be sure that is curable?
It's not group 4. The slightest aggravation after the right remedy excluded the group 4 on all levels, that's right?
-I don't understand your question. If he has a small aggravation....
-I have to decide between group 4 upper level
or group 3 lower level. And I have a slight aggravation.
-So you say, there is some aggravation and after that you have an amelioration, then it's not group 4.
-You acurately described the American mentality regarding their treatment. I was wondering
whether you might suggest in those cases where
it's very clear that treatment I have given out
many liters of sac lac to patients and have found out that this only works for a little period of time
they threaten, they want to call their lawyers, their headache is still there etc. What would you recommend
in terms of any short of palliation so that eventually the pathology can be tended to.
-If anybody tells me that they will take me to court I will eliminate his symptoms within 24 hours.
I can do it very easily. You give 3,4,5
remedies and all the symptoms are gone.
For a period of time bye, bye sir I cure you now. What is going to happen next month I don't know.
I mean if they are so stupid as not to understand, then it's not your problem.
If somebody wants to die, he wants to die.
I know cases where inspite of the fact they
have been so well,
when they are under a crisis they will rush to take allopathic drugs, what can you do? It's your karma, follow it.
I have said many times 'I can do nothing anymore for you'. Actually this was a case
where he came with very high blood
pressure and I gave Adrenalin to that case,
you remember the case you were
taking the blood pressure.
There was some effect but then there was a relapse, the blood pressure started going up again,
I prescribed Sulphur, no effect. I said, the blood pressure is too high, I'm sorry you go back
to your pills or you go to the cardiologist
to prescribe new pills.
She resisted, she did not want,
try for the last time. I said ok.
I have given before Belladona with little
effect, then I changed the remedy again.
After Adrenalin now I thought this is a case of Belladona. I prescribed Belladona 30, repeated doses.
She has a party now for the last month she says, the blood pressure from 1.80-2.10 it has come down to 1.40 steady.
She couldn't believe it. She sent faxes.
Her karma is good, this is the only reason.
I said, now I'm going to try again Belladona which I have given before and it did not work, how many
possibilities you have for success? Yet as I told you, if you don't find the right sequence of remedies,
the second remedy or the third will
not bring about the desired effect.
You have to find the first remedy which may appear to do almost nothing but it says now the case
is a clear case of Sepia, a clear case of Belladona, you give it and the effect is there.
Many times I have done this and people insisted, No. With Krishnamurti I told you, he was dying, he could not breathe.
I said, finished, I cannot do anything anymore,
a man 75 doing like this. You can die today, tomorrow,
forget it let him take the antibiotics. I said, we
call a doctor from Lausanne from Switzerland.
'Is he going to help you?', 'I said no, he is going to give you antibiotics because my medicine
does not seem to do anything, as you see'.
He said, 'no, you continue'.
He puts you a lot of responsibility because one more wrong remedy and the whole thing is finished.
And I don't know by the will of God, who
wants these things and you find the remedy
you prescribe and he was out the next afternoon. I tried in the morning Phosphorus and in the evening he was up.
I went there, I didn't see him in the room,
I thought he died and they took him away,
he is not in the room,
it's not possible that he got up by himself
to go to the bathroom and I was trembling.
I saw him coming from the bathroom, 'what did you give me', of course he was still very thin
but you could see the action of the remedy immediately.
If he had taken antibiotics he would have died right there, no way. He lived another 20 years from 67-87.
It was 67 in Switzerland and died in 87 in Switzerland or in England I think. This is their life.
You say, do you want me to take away your symptoms? Ok I take away your symptoms.
Of course in a case where there is danger of the life of the person you don't think about this or that. You say, we do this to save
the life of the person and then
you try again that's a different story.
But in America for little things
they can take you to court.
This is a continuation of what we have been talking before where the patient says,
I am better but for one week or two weeks and then comes an aggravation or change of symptoms,
more aggravation, more change of symptoms.
Then this is an indication that you do not have a good case in your practice and it's going to give you a lot of headaches.
Something else also that I have to tell you is that these observations, are observations of 20 years, I wrote them in 78,
they were published in the science of Homeopathy. 20 years ago I made these observations
which were based on a gross understanding not on a finer understanding of what is happening
with the human diseases and in conjunction with the remedy. So we have now to adapt it
to the new understanding of having the different levels on which these things apply.
-Is it possible that a patient with panic attack who belongs to group 3 can be treated with 3 remedies
and within 6-8 weeks she changes to group 2?
-Yes sure it's possible. The thing is that it was not a panic attack so deep. You have panic attacks,
it can be of different depth. This panic attack in which after short period of time it goes to group 2,
this is not such a deep anxiety state to bring panic attacks of such type that belong to group 4.
In Group 4 you will see panic attacks
which they will drive you crazy.
You give remedy after remedy, very good prescriptions and better and better and another remedy,
better, back, another remedy. I have battled
with such cases for long periods of time and
you may need careful prescribing for 5-6
years before you can get them out of
the panic attacks and you get other panic
attacks which belong to the upper 3 group.
With one remedy they go back into group 2.
And in these panic attacks you will see
the hyponchondriac element so strong.
'I breathe some air'. 'What do you mean?
Air is to be breathed'. 'Yes but it was a little bit different
so I can not breathe now. The air
was different', 'What was different?'
'I don't know something was in the atmosphere'. This, you don't like to hear. This kind of descriptions
you know you're going to take a long period
of time before you can handle such cases.
-Can you answer for me if it's the action of the remedy that brought the intensity of the symptoms
so high or is it that the patient was
going this way, anyway?
-He was going this way anyway. There is no question. In incurable cases the patient is going to die.
And it's bringing out the direction towards
which
he would be developing his pathology.
The possibilities of course, if you are careful, that you see the new symptoms and a little bit more clear and a little bit more clear.
And you will have time to do this with deep anxiety states. You have time because there is no danger of life there.
What it has died, has died and it's part of the emotional side and the fear has overtaken and replaces everything.
They cannot feel any joy. All the emotions are replaced by tremendous anxiety.
-I'm still bothering with this group. When there
is after the remedy no aggravation,
and amelioration and
then deep aggravation.
Then it must not be possible that I find the remedy to take care of the aggravation before the amelioration.
When you see the case and its sequence
you see the body is in a state where
it can have a heavy aggravation and then
I found a remedy and this aggravation .....
-This we call it wrongly aggravation. This is a deterioration of the situation. It's going worse you can see everywhere.
New symptoms you try to find and then you prescribe again. It's not a matter of aggravation of the initial symptoms.
-In this case is there not the possibility that in the beginning we gave a close remedy and then there was an
aggravation, first amelioration then aggravation but to bring up this aggravation the organism has to have strong vital force.
-It could be, we have discussed about this previously and you can explain it in this way.
If you can explain it in this way that means there is an aggravation but now the remedy is clear.
The aggravation then is good but usually in
such a case it doesn't precede an amelioration.
You give the remedy and gets the aggravation, and the aggravation brings out another picture which is good.
But this preceding by an
amelioration is very doubtful.
-May I ask one question? Sometimes it is difficult to decide what is the aggravation. Is my case deteriorating
on its own or is this an aggravation? It is a
child who is very backward mentally but is presenting
to be a very difficult child in behavior. He has a grandmother who is in bed, he would put fires in the room,
she's aphasic and he would stuff her ears and her nose so she doesn't breathe, he would lock her
in the bathroom, he would create difficulties for his mother. You can see that he is physically over grown but mentally...
-He is a real devil. How old is he?
-He is 14 but from the size of him you would think he is 21. He was abusive, he used to throw tantrums
whenever he is contradictive, he would burst
out with anger and he would break things.
I gave him first Anacardium which did not seem to do nothing and then I gave Bufo because sexuality
coming up but I was waiting for some reaction to the remedy. But if he aggravates he would more violent?
-Yes.
-The only physical pathology he has is tonsillitis and he does develop acutes, it's not like he is in group 4
where nothing comes up and only mental happens. So if I have given him Bufo 1M and he was violent
but it was not sustaining this aggravation
he seemed to go back and forth.
-I will tell you in that particular case, for instance you gave Bufo because he has a symptom which is characteristic.
He is angry when he is contradictive. If you
go to the Repertory you see, this is Bufo.
In spite of the fact that Bufo
has to have masturbation a lot.
-He had this.
-A lot ok. Now what I expect from this to happen, if Bufo is close enough it will give an aggravation on mental level
and the child may become even more nasty.
And then the picture of Stramonium maybe will develop.
Then you give Stramonium and the child will come to normal and then the possibility of Tuberculinum later on.
Even if Bufo is correct, most probably will not cure the nasty, this child is very nasty,
it has criminal tendencies. Criminal tendencies as pathology we think of Stramonium,
we think of Belladona, we think of Hyoscyamus.
But in this case if Bufo makes it even more aggressive then the possibility of Stramonium will
rise and think of Belladona
and Hyoscyamus as a possibility.
-I have a question. I have a child who is very aggressive and the physician says that it may be that this child
is schizophrenic. He has severe ear infection. How can I really differentiate to which group he belongs?
-Schizophrenic? I don't think that he is schizophrenic. You see the fact that some doctor calls somebody
schizophrenic, it doesn't mean he is really schizophrenic especially if the child is autistic. How old is the child?
-12 years.
-12 years a child should be called autistic, not schizophrenic. Even by the diagnosis I see that
it doesn't come from a specialist.
It comes just from a doctor.
This child is curable unless he is autistic.
Autistic is different, he doesn't understand what he is doing at all.
-Yes, he is very aggressive,
he takes a knife and attacks his mother.
-Very good.
When a child has impulses to kill
and at the same time he has otitis, the remedy is
Mercurius Solubilis 50M and then the child will be better in everything. It is not a schizophrenic child.
-Do you really take the risk if the
child really kills his mother?
-He will never kill the mother.
-But there is aggravation on the
mental level. What does that mean?
-No, no it doesn't mean that he will kill the mother. If a child 12 years old kills his mother, it is by accident most probably.
-How do you treat such a patient?
-You see the organism, let us say, has these 5 symptoms. It has desire to kill, this is the highest but
it has this, this, this and that symptom as well.
So let's say you give the correct remedy to
give you more graphic, more vivid example.
Let us say, this is high blood pressure
23 and you give a remedy
and you say you have aggravation
but not in this symptom.
The organism is strengthened so it decides this symptom is very dangerous for me, I bring it down immediately.
So what I will do? I will raise this one, I will raise this one and that one but this dangerous one I'll bring it down immediately.
The same way, you have a child he is in convulsions, he has 40,5 fever and he is in convulsions,
you give the remedy Belladona. The convulsions stop; then what is aggravated,
the urine, the perspiration is aggravated, all the other symptoms which are not dangerous to bring
a reaction further and you see
immediately the convulsions come down.
The fever may go 40,7 but without convulsions.
-George, Bufo is in none of the contradiction rubrics?
-Misunterstood, angry, irritability
when misunderstood.
This is quite frequent also and then there
are several possibilities even in that.
Don't give up the remedy which you have
studied so well. Try to find out what exactly has happened.
Maybe he took the remedy and put the remedy together in her bag with her aromas and maybe the remedy
from the pharmacy was spoiled, so she did not take a remedy. You may find out that the pharmacy ...
We had one pharmacy in Athens by that time I was prescribing. I had several times told the pharmacy that
your Rhus tox 10M is finished, your Phosphorus 1M does not work, replace it. The pharmacy should have taken action
to replace that but he has a bottle, it opens every time, he gives from that bottle; then there is a time
when the bottle doesn't work anymore because the remedy has been antidoted in the bottle.
And you don't give a remedy actually. How did
I know? If it is a case of typical Rhus tox,
I know the typical Rhus tox case
it's not possible that it doesn't work.
Give 10M, ok give 1M, ah beautiful. Of course you telephone and you say, your remedy Sir is not working anymore.
So it's not always that your remedy is far off, of course it can be that your remedy has no effect at all
and the patient also is not sensitive to produce any kind of changes, therefore you have to change the remedy
but otherwise you be careful.
-Do you remember the case of the farmer we saw first time in Lindau and after 6 remedies he had always this reaction?
How can we explain such a person?
-No effect?
-No effect, nothing. He was here.
-Ah the Ignatia case.
-Yes and everytime he doesn't ameliorate, doesn't aggravate, like taking sugar, it doesn't
do anything.
Six remedies I think he took until now.
-That's true it's a puzzle for me also. It's a puzzle why? Because I think there are two things happening.
One is, that the problem is quite deep. The second is he doesn't want to admit of any change.
The reason is most probably that if he admits of any change he's afraid you will say, ok you are good now, go.
And he wants somebody to hold on. In this
case I don't believe he has no change.
I believe he is much more calm but how much?
If he doesn't tell you, if he doesn't give you the information?
If he always say, I am the same, I am the
same, it had no effect, I don't believe that.
Of course you will tell me maybe there is a remedy which needs this kind of attention,
maybe we need to give Pulsatilla because of that and maybe one day somebody will just give him a remedy and he may admit it.
-I wonder if he just want to keep the symptomatology. That was my impression after the Ignatia because
we found him a little bit better but somehow he keeps it. He doesn't want to let lose, is that possible?
-It is possible but we can not excuse ourselves by saying that. Because even that is pathology, wanting to keep
his symptom is pathology. So if we find a remedy which needs to grasp somebody like Agaricus, like Pulsatilla,
like Baryta carbonica, weak people who want to rely upon others. If we decide this is a problem,
then we may go to that direction and prescribe.
Still I feel that we have not been able to find the correct remedy.
Unfortunately this is one and the other
is that he does not want to cooperate.
He does not want to state any kind of change.
It's not possible with all these remedies that
he does not have any change at all,
it is not possible.
-If you have given the right remedy and the patient says, there is no reaction, is it sensible
to give remedies in different potencies like C200?
-Yes, you can go higher and higher and higher. Who was in Munich? In the house called Natura medicine?
In this case, in this hospital I was presented a case of lupus erythematosus, in which I prescribed Pulsatilla 200.
Then I got the report later on from the doctor who was treating the case and he said: we gave Pulsatilla 200
and there was no effect, at all. Then we gave Pulsatilla 1M, waited one month, there was no effect at all.
Then because we believed that the analysis was correct we insisted and we gave Pulsatilla 50M
and then there was a beautiful cure.
You see somebody says, 200 no effect,
1M no effect, 10M no effect. You give 50M.
These people did it by themselves
they did not consult me but they thought ok,
if Vithoulkas made the analysis and he said
this, then we have to insist. They insisted.
-I have the experience that if the patient wants to get better, he gets better. I had once a patient who was Rhus-tox
in C30 and she was taking this continuously and it was acting and when it finished they put new on top of it
but it was just different pharmacy and it didn't work and she could differentiate and say, it doesn' t work anymore.
-If you find out that one potency doesn't work, how long would you wait?
-One month. Sometimes you have reason to wait for longer but in one month you know if there is any change.
Actually those who read this case, Lac Felinum. We had here a meeting and there was a case with suicidal disposition,
a very peculiar behavior, he was acting like a cat. He loved the cat, he dressed like a cat, he would go out
in the street, he was a homosexual. He would climb a tree and stay there and say, 'I am a cat'. He would climb
on the roof of the house and stay there.
'Come down'. 'No, I am a cat'.
We discussed this case in a teachers meeting and I suggested actually Aurum bromatum because
it is a very peculiar person antisocial, with suicidal tendencies. Then somebody else says, Hyoscyamus
and then one man following the idea of Sankaran by that time, he said, this is a perfect case of the signatures
which is a cat- Lac Felinum.
Why don't we give Lac Felinum?
There was an arguement.
And the doctor who presented the case was a doctor who worked in the center, a Greek doctor.
In the end of the discussion he
said to me, what shall I do?
I said, this is an interesting case we have to try
to see whether Lac Felinum will have an effect.
Shall I give Lac Felinum?
I said, ok give Lac Felinum.
I asked him after a month, he said,
no effect. I said, give again.
2 months, no effect, 3 months passed
and I kept this case, I wanted really to see
whether it will give any reaction and I kept
it long and the child committed suicide.
I mean there was no effect. That's why I am so angry with these ideas which come as a fantasy
and have no base on real symptomatology.
-I want to ask if you can antidote a remedy with your mind. I have a patient who is only curious
about Homeopathy but she
really doesn't believe.
-Then there is nothing to be cured.
-And I found the right remedy and she says there is no effect. If you want to give a higher dose, she says
I don't want I rather take allopathic medicine.
-I will tell you something which is very strange. For a person to do this, it must be quite sick in the very beginning.
He comes to you and says, 'you give me a remedy and I will prove to you that it doesn't work.'
This very fact...why she comes? You see the twisting of the thinking of the person,
I go there and I prove that the remedy is incorrect. That means he is already quite sick,
he is already in group 4. Therefore, in group 4 the remedy is not clear, the reaction is not going to be strong etc.
But let anybody come who has a clear cut remedy and let him tell me, 'I don't believe' but as long as I'm satisfied
that the remedy is clear. I say, very good don't believe, take the remedy you will see.
I told you with the CIA man, he was a very strong, hard man. He was looking at me,
'this child of 22 he is going to cure me?'
He didn't believe, he was very strong.
'It is not possible, I've been to the best doctors
all over the world and I came now in the basement,'
it was in a basement by that time in Athens. He had come from America, he has a huge diamond factory in NY.
He was coming in the basement of Athens, he said to me later on, he comes after a month and says, 'I am the same'.
'You are the same?'. 'Yes'. 'Take this', but I noticed some hesitation in his voice in certain symptoms.
Very good, placebo.
Second month he comes, 'I am the same'. He admits that he is 'maybe better in that symptom, maybe I don't have that.
But this is nothing. My main symptom is the same'. The third month, I told you the story many times,
he comes with a ring, a diamond ring.
He says, 'I want to see you privately'. I knew he was an agent, a CIA man. I said, he is going to kill me.
He says, 'I bring you a present for your wife because you made me free', the third month.
He doesn't believe, he says, it's not possible. He confess to me all this negative thinking. He said, 'I could not perceive'.
I said, you almost misguided me in the beginning when you said, you are almost the same. You almost lost
your possibility to be cured, you know that? He said, 'it was not possible for me to think that I was going to be cured from you'.
He still telephones me, he is 80 years old now and he still calls me. Hello George, do you recognize my voice?
I say, yes how are you? I am ok. He never had problems with panic attacks. Terrific panic attacks.
But the other case where the mind is really deteriorated and it is twisted and things like that;
they can do anything, they can tell you lies. These people will not give you a feedback, which is correct,
how can you proceed. It's group 4,
how can you proceed?
-And the problem is the fear is so big that
maybe she is afraid to take a remedy.
The fear of pain and fear of the remedy.
-If she is afraid to take the remedy you
cannot do anything. What can you do?
-If you have another case that you gave a remedy, I had a case of Carcinosin. Physically she hardly had
anything but she thought she had ruined her body because she used to put a finger in her mouth to vomit
whenever she had a big meal. But she saw her parents who used to do it before, as a child she saw her parents doing it,
so she adopted it and today she is 40 years old. Now, the last two years she is afraid that she will get cancer
because she used to do it but actually everything is fine with her. And I gave her Carcinosin because she is duty bound,
she is exactly Carcinosin and she told me that she had a little bit aggravation, she slept for 2 days
and then she felt the best that she felt ever in her life. And she kept calling me every day and I gave
a placebo because she needs to take something and every time I leave the country, she develops a headache,
very strong headache with migraines but she never had headaches before in her life, that's what she says.
-She has changed levels; she produces another symptom out of insecurity because you are her security
so you maybe thinking of another remedy like Agaricus, like Phosphorus, like Pulsatilla, like Arsenicum
all these remedies can have such a reaction.