This is a case where the patient will come and tell you, everything is bad. I have this, I have that
and they relate all kind of symptoms which
they had before, even new symptoms now.
And they will not admit at first any amelioration. This can happen with certain remedies like Thuja, like Staphysagria
like Natrum muriaticum, closed patients, not communicative, they are suspicious, not exactly
but they don't believe what you're doing
and little changes mean nothing to them.
Before you go and give another remedy, make sure that really your remedy, I'm talking about a month time,
has really not brought about any change. This is a case like Richard's. We investigated it is not this, not that....
Finally you make sure that the remedy is wrong, you give another remedy but there are some patients especially
those who are really closed, as I said, that they will not admit that in the mental-emotional there are changes that take place.
In such a case you give placebo.
Why I say that? Because this is totally different from a patient who comes and says
immediately, 'I feel better psychologically
but my ailments are the same'.
This is totally different case I'm talking about here. You have to differentiate. Here the patient says,
'no change' and he is really holding to this
idea and by examining subtly you say,
'what about your irritability?
Are you as irritable as before?'. 'Yes'.
You have to observe in the voice, there is a doubt. That means if the person thinks
and at the same time says something but
he's not sure the tone of voice changes.
Because you can see he's thinking, but he does not want to admit. The first thing he says is no but this no
you can perceive that he is thinking.
And then you insist, you try to find out
'in a similar situation how you behaved?
Did you throw the plate to your husband?'
You get this kind of reaction with this patient. If he's going to tell you, it's the same
and finally admits he's better mental-emotional, not better, he will not admit better, maybe a little bit.
Immediately be aware of such a case
and don't run to prescribe another remedy.
You will be surprised that such cases may
tell you the third month, I'm totally cured.
Actually what is taking place is a kind of aggravation in their physical symptomatology.
Even if they are a little bit worse they will not even say. 'I'm the same, what is the difference',
but admitting mentally or emotionally there is a difference, you just wait and you will see the next month.
If next month they will say, it's the same, the third month forget it, you're going to give another remedy.
I want to make you aware of this type of person and you will see this type of person because he will not establish contact.
Nevermind how much you try to be nice, they will keep to themselves, they will not come out and communicate really.
There is a trick also here which you can do and many times it works and saves the patient's life and your life also.
What is the trick?
I've told you before but you forgot.
The trick is to tell: 'listen you have to tell me the whole truth because we have 2000 remedies and if what I gave you
is the right remedy, I'm going to try 1999 more possibilities that we have. That means 1999 months of observation.
So if we lose this remedy which is going to be good for you, forget it we'll never find the correct remedy
and there you see the reaction. They go back and they start excuse themselves and then they open up and say,
'oh no this I don't have, but you know my
stomach is still in pain'.
'Yes I understand'.
The prescription is placebo.
You have to be a very good judge of human nature.
And some people also like to be sick and this is part of their sickness also. They like to say, 'I'm sick '
so the others will pay attention. The husband will look after or the wife will look after the husband.
Usually is the woman.
What is this reaction?
You did not like it but why? Usually is the woman who says my husband wants to rely on me, this is what I meant.
The feministic movement is very strong
in the class. It's ok, here we like objectivity!
To admit that you are weak, that means you are strong. Nobody who is really weak will admit, I'm weak.
If somebody says, I'm weak, you watch out. If they admit publically, they say it very easily,
you know I'm very weak person watch out.
This is a particular type that I'm talking about for this reaction, it's a group of people that you must not miss.
Otherwise they will mislead you every time. You give another remedy and another remedy and eventually they will leave you.
-But in case the patient now, after you made the trick, tells you things which he didn't tell before
and a new picture comes up then
you still give placebo?
-Yes you still give placebo.
-Why?
-If he admits that he's better in certain areas which he hided before, even if he says
'I have also this and that, I'm also impotent'.
Did you ever ask a man whether you
are impotent, he says no, I'm normal.
You liked it? Objectivity!
Then he comes and says, you know also I have to tell you something, I just remembered it. The last 2-3 years I'm not....
You see it's difficult for a man to admit because it is connected with the symbolism, I'm a man.
So even if he says a new symptom but he admits I'm better in especially mental-emotional, you don't give another remedy.
-If he is worse?
-If he is the same or worse yes,
you give another remedy.
If he has an aggravation really,
if you think it's an aggravation you wait.
-Never mind if the patient is closed
or not, he shows any reaction to the remedy?
-If there is an aggravation?
-If the patient is closed or not, there should
be a reaction in the form of an aggravation.
-Is he asking or he says, it should be?
Is this a question?
-It's a question. You didn't put it as a question. No, it should not be when the patient belongs to
either first group or last group
there can be no apparent aggravation.
In 1976 I presented a paper in the LIGA meeting which was published in the American Journal of Homeopathy
around that time and we looked at the file, me and Irini Bachas, my first student, it must be 76, 78 around that time.
In this paper we made a statistic and we found out that we had 80% of the patients that were coming,
initial aggravation in 80% of the cases. We published this. During this period it was unheard, the aggravation.
A whole congress didn't want to hear about it. Everyone who was in the congress by that time, was a polypharmacist
and they could not have seen or if they have seen, they never attributed to homeopathic remedy.
They say, what is this and it was fought very badly. We had very bad critiques and I was surprised that Ortega,
he is a very good Homeopath, very old also, he's about my age. He is a bit older, maybe 12 years older.
He was more experienced at that time, he had 12-15 years more experience than me at this moment where
I had only 15 years of experience,
he had 30 years of experience.
He said 'what is this? An aggravation? We have never seen'. So he gave an interview to Allen N.
which was published again in the Journal of the American Institute of Homeopathy in which he stated that there
is no such thing in Homeopathy, as aggravation.
I could not believe it. He said, if you find the right remedy, the right potency, no aggravation.
He was supposed to be somebody who followed Kent etc. and I said to his student Rosa Belendes,
she was a very clever Mexican woman, short
one but devil, her mind was going like this.
I said to her what about Kent? You studied
Kent what Kent says about that?
She brought some arguments to cover up the idea of Ortega but for me it was really happening.
Everyone would come saying, what did you give me? And we never said to any person,
you are going to have a reaction.
We never said it.
Because if you say it, it's different, they may produce it but during these times
practicing under dictatorship an illegal medicine in a country which was very conservative, the army people
were taking over, they were leading
Greece, I was not  a medical doctor, it was terrific.
You could not say to the patient you're
going to have an aggravation.
It would be another revolution for Greece. But almost every patient would say, they're having an initial aggravation.
The cases were much more easy than they are today. The people were much more healthy than they are today.
30 years later people have gone down,  the real health has gone down. You may live 15 years with Alzheimer's.
This is a case where the patient admits
an amelioration on a physical symptom.
Is that possible, one or two symptoms are better?
This is also a possibility of slow reaction of the organism and it is good if you wait, you give them placebo
and you wait one more month. If this was the beginning of an amelioration, then the next month you will be better,
the third month will be even better etc.
But if the second month comes and he says,
'that symptom that was better, now is 50% back', that means your remedy was only partially acting.
For instance, a constitutional symptom, physical, which is better for a while, is not a good sign. Unless it's an acute.
But if it's a constitutional, ex. a woman had several times inflammation of the vagina and she was treated with antibiotics.
Then she comes to you and as you treat
her the vaginitis comes, then you prescribe
and the symptoms go away, only these symptoms go away. That is probably the wrong prescription.
But if she comes and for the first time
she has a cystitis she was infected
and you give the remedy and the cystitis
goes away, that is the correct reaction.
-I think it's a very good reaction,
in group 4 I think it's a very good reaction.
-No.
-George, could you explain that again, it was not totally clear I think. The first possibility with the antibiotics.
-The woman comes to be treated for something you understand is rather a constitutional reaction. If the woman gets cystitis
5 years she has cystitis, she comes to you,
you give a remedy and the burning goes away
without any other reaction aggravation or improvement. This is the wrong reaction.
But if she comes for the first time as an acute, she has been infected for the first time and you give a remedy
and the symptoms of cystitis go away, that is treating an acute and they have to go away with the treatment.
In the other way you have to take into consideration the whole picture in order to prescribe.
She has a cold now, you don't have to take into consideration all the picture, you can prescribe for the cold.
You prescribe for the cold, the cold goes away, that's ok. But if this is a hay fever, this reaction what you consider
to be a cold that means an allergic condition which comes every spring or autumn and you prescribe
and the symptoms go away without
any change, that is wrong.
Here, these groups, they can get acute infections. These groups as you go down, the acutes either
they are minimal, they will get the idea of an acute, not a real acute and as you go down you don't get acutes.
But if here they get an acute, it is going to be very severe, that means that when you have a person in group 4
with schizophrenia, one day such a person develops a very high fever with pneumonia, he's going to die.
The pneumonia is to bring death in
this group. It's a very serious acute.
It is more serious than the schizophrenia.
What is more serious? Death. Then what you do?
Sometimes in the mental asylums they see these reactions and immediately they come with the antibiotics
and they bring back the person to
delusions and mental aberrations.
Instead, now here there is a possibility if you are a Homeopath, during that period to prescribe and get him out
of that mental condition. If you prescribe correctly during the acute here, you get him out of the mental condition.
-To this point, do you prescribe for the
acute or for the constitutional?
-A good question. In this case actually, you must take into consideration some of his constitutional except that the acute
is part of the whole picture. Here, it's part of the whole picture. It's not an acute like here that comes upon.
In a schizophrenic is very difficult to
put an acute, to imprint an acute.
In these groups you imprint an acute, how?
What we call an Ignatia state. They lose somebody
and they develop Ignatia symptoms.
Here a schizophrenic loses 10 people, he does not realize it. You cannot imprint, put it on top.
Here, the case is Calcarea carbonica but in the time of death or separation she becomes Ignatia.
Supposing she comes to you after a stress and for the first time you see the patient. You see Ignatia symptoms,
you give Ignatia. After Ignatia, you will see Calcarea carbonica. That means the person was not constitutional Ignatia
but Ignatia was imprinted because of the
stress of the grief. Here you cannot imprint it.
Here you can imprint a Bryonia on top of Calcarea carbonica. You can imprint Allium cepa or Euphrasia
upon a Sulphur, an underlying constitution.
That means if the person had come to you before the cold or the acute, you would have given Sulphur.
He comes during the acute and you prescribe Euphrasia, you have to prescribe Euphrasia, unless his symptoms
of the acute are coming together with his chronic symptoms. Then in his cold you can prescribe Sulphur
and then you relieve him from both,
acute or chronic. It is a very good condition.
Despair of learning.
-You said something very interesting to us. In a chronic state where the person gets an acute illness,
this acute will show the underlying miasm. It means that in group 3 or 4, I would have to take the totality of his symptoms?
-No. You don't have to take the chronic symptoms together with the acute.
We say, in some cases which are few, not many, the chronic conditions will be falling into the picture of the acute.
That means the acute is a picture of Arsenicum but the chronic symptoms of the person are also symptoms of Arsenicum.
That is a good case where your remedy will take care of the acute and the chronic. But this is not frequent.
A person is restless, he is very cold, he has gastritis, ulcer, he is drinking water by sips.
That's his picture and he comes to you and he says I have a cold and every time I have a cold
I feel it in my chest.
And I have a running nose and the discharge is watery and acrid and I'm always restless.
You drink water like this?
Always I like to drink sips of water.
Thank God. That's a case of Arsenicum. You give Arsenicum and his ulcer, colitis, whatever it might be,
will go away together with his cold.
But not always.
-Sometimes in a case of acute in group 3 or 4, we first treat the acute symptoms
unless by luck you have the same with the chronic.
-That's it, by luck. Here, group 3 and 4 there are acutes you can ignore. The people will say,
I get some acutes but I don't treat. My nose
is running, a little bit this, a little bit that,
if they get some acute is mild, the organism does not react really to an invasion of virus or bacteria.
My theory is based on observations. My theory
is that you take these people here and you inject them
with tuberculosis bacillus, no effect. The bacillus will be killed in a few minutes later in the blood of these people.
You inject them with syphilis; the spirochete will die in the blood of the schizophrenic. It is very poisonous.
I don't know but these are ideas that can be researched, proposals for a research.
But here, there are some bacteria which affect these levels but then this is very very serious.
We have different types of pneumonia. In older times we used to have the streptococcal pneumonia,
the staphylococcal pneumonia. Today we have fungi which are producing pneumonias.
This is different kind of pneumonias,
much more aggressive, much more deadly.
These are general ideas and the interesting thing which I maintain is that when a person, a schizophrenic of 10 years,
who never came to his senses, during the time
of the pneumonia but not in the beginning, in the end,
when the pneumonia is bringing him near to death, this person will come back to his senses,
for a few days before dying he will be sane.
Why? Because the force of the disease
has come all upon the physical body.
The mental-emotional is left and it is
upon the  physical body.
-Is it possible to treat this kind of pneumonia?
-Theoretically it is possible,
in practice is going to be very difficult.
The defence mechanism is in a state, people die from pneumonia, there is 60-80% who die with or without antibiotics.
What it means is that their defenses are just to the point where they fight the last fight and then they collapse.
Some of these cases, I believe, you can save. How many I don't know.
- I've seen a case of 30 year mental patient, schizophrenic, paranoia, everything and they tried to give him
Lithium and another new mixture of drugs and he completely collapsed. His kidneys collapsed,
he got very high sugar in his blood,
he was completely finished.
And this time they had to take the drugs off and he was sane, he was beautifully sane and in the minute that
everything stabilized, the physical, then he became crazy again.
-These ideas I teach for years and years, nobody is listening, the medical authorities. You don't know,
you are charlatans and you are dreamers, all kind of things but they don't see the facts.
I have seen a lot and I have heard a lot of this kind of reaction and anyone who has an idea of these laws, takes notice.
Because if you don't have an idea of the laws, you say he has fever, we have to bring down the fever.
That's all they know. They don't connect.
-I did not understand quite well which symptom of the chronic state you can take.
In a schizophrenic you take pneumonia
and then some chronic?
-Which one? Everything that is possible.
I said you have to take, in these low groups, you have to take in consideration the symptoms of the patient
as a generality not only the pneumonia.
On the first group you take the pneumonia symptoms, you give and you treat.
In the lower groups you have to take in consideration everything that was going on.
It is part of the whole disease. Pneumonia on these upper groups is a remedy which is imprinted,
added upon his miasmatic condition.
Here, pneumonia is a part of schizophrenia. Diabetes is a part of schizophrenia.
-Could you relate to that point of psychotic etc.
in terms of primary and secondary action?
Because I have the understanding that
when the psychotic has a primary action,
has accepted the disease but
he faces the secondary action.
-We didn't understand.
-Ok, I will repeat.
-My understanding is that the primary action according to Hahnemann...
-Ok, you use the word primary, secondary reaction in comparison with something else
which happens in the mental case.
He says, in a mental case you have a person who receives some impression from the outside world
and these stresses he cannot process and he develops schizophrenia. He develops mental symptoms because
he cannot cope with the stresses around.
Is this primary or secondary action in comparison with what Hahnemann says? Is that your question?
-My question is would you agree that the problem with the psychotic is the secondary action,
he cannot perform the  secondary action which is coming and re-establishing a state of harmony and health?
- You see the idea is that every symptom is a defense towards something which is worse.
The symptoms of schizophrenia are a reaction towards a stress that will bring death.
The organism decides that if I keep and I try to fight that stress, I'm going to die. Instead of this I divert it
and I make a mental aberration or delusion. These delusions are the result of the defense mechanism
to get away from a reality that will bring death.
What I say is now, here is a diversion towards the mental. Now the organism by whatever happens,
has another diversion, instead of death and this is pneumonia, this goes to the physical body.
It diverts this whole thing. This whole thing goes away and you have a strong reaction on the physical body.
That is going again to bring death.
Why this does not bring death?
Because we know that all mental aberrations they allow the rest of the physical body to perform its actions.
We say, this old man is so healthy, he never gets sick. Because the old man suffers from Alzheimer's.
So the death has come upon this mental-emotional part and allows the physical body to live.
Here, by your medicine, by environment, by whatever, this person develops diabetes or develops
a physical disease like strong diabetes that
takes the person away, or tuberculosis.
While he develops tuberculosis, the person is going to die here, but his mental will be clear,
the force of the disease will come to the physical body and will allow the mental-emotional to function more freely.
And this is the problem we face as Homeopaths because when we prescribe correctly,  we clear up from the
mental to the physical and the physical gets all the stress. And the person has come and says, 'what about my ulcer?'.
The ulcer we heal much later because first the mental-emotional has to be rearranged and the ulcer is going to be worse.
This is what you are learning
through these observations.
-Pneumonia is actually a desperate
try of the organism to become healthy.
-Absolutely, it is a reaction of the organism to become healthy. There is a big fever, a turmoil,
a crisis and then you go out of
this and maybe you will be saved.
-This reminds me a long time ago when
I first started my practice as a chiropractor,
I had a patient who was psychologist.
And he sent one of his patients who was very
classic schizophrenic but he was under
control with the medication, he was functioning in the world.
He was getting a lot of headaches and a lot of shoulder pain. So as an experiment he said
I send my patient to you to see what can happen, if you can help him. So he came to me for maybe two months
and his headaches were getting better, his shoulder pains were getting better but then all of a sudden he got very crazy.
I started taking letters from him, I hear your voice coming from the Empire State building, I feel your fingers in my brain.
So we had to stop the experiment because he was getting much worse, emotionally.
-Actually what you were doing, you were just bringing him back to this level where the level of the disease
started going down to the physical body, and then back again in the mental aberration.
That's very correct, the observation.
This is something that I believe everyone who practices medicine of whatever form should be aware.
-I have seen your observations; in the States I used to work in a mental institution for the State and these were all
severe schizophrenic individuals with severe mental-emotional disorders and every winter, being in NY
the flu season would come around but the medical treatment was very backward, even by allopathic standards.
Hard to believe, double contradiction but the patients would all come down with the flu and they would start
having very interesting conversations. They would start interacting in a much healthier way,
and their behaviour improved, they would
start being much healthier in every way
and then the physician would come and he would administering antibiotics and they would go back again.
-In the same way, some psychiatrists give allopathic drugs to mental cases and then they see some
skin eruptions tremendous skin eruptions and they send them immediately to the dermatologist, he pushes it back, finished.
Simple things like that and they're not observed by the medical profession and they don't want to listen.
-We should not tell the patient about bad reaction, initial aggravation, you said before we should not tell.
But if we don't tell there might be a bad reaction like skin eruption, they run to the dermatologist
so we have to instruct them
but you said, we should not.
-No. If somebody comes and says, I have this problem but when I was 12 years old I had severe skin eruption,
you say my dear sir if I give you for your headaches a remedy, most probably,
you will get back your skin eruption,
would you like to start the treatment?
-And when before he never had a skin eruption?
-No, he will not get.
-I would like to ask a question. I've got a case, a Lycopodium woman, she had a lot of colds
and sinusitis and cystitis and took a lot of antibiotics.
I try to cure her and I give Lycopodium, not many things changed and suddenly she has a cystitis.
I tried to repeat Lycopodium at first, it didn't act. So she had pains in the kidney and she felt very bad.
What to do? I can't take the responsibility.
She had a lot of blood in the urine as well.
She had the symptoms of Berberis. What am
I supposed to do at that point?
-Give her Berberis and then wait. If there
is no effect, give another remedy.
-It had effect. It went away in one day.
-Then you wait, then you will see the
sinusitis coming most probably.
-It already did.
-There is a series. In the beginning there was an order, first it was a cold and then the sinusitis,
then the antibiotics were given and the flora was spoiled then eventually she started developing cystitis.
She was treated for cystitis, then back the sinusitis, and then finally she came to you.
You are going to re-establish the order. How this has started and you ask, how this whole thing started?
I remember I had this severe cold and that developed a severe sinusitis and then antibiotics
six months later I had cystitis.
Then you know that the last thing you have to treat is the sinusitis. It will come or maybe the opposite way
because the organism when you give a chemical, may kill the bacteria, this is what they do.
If we have an infection with virus, antibiotics will do nothing but if we have a bacteria, it will be killed by penicillin
or other antibiotics; at the same time some useful bacteria are killed and if the organism is not able to rearrange what it lost,
it's going to develop another condition. And the next condition is going to be worse than the first
and the next is going to be worse than the previous one. Then if you take the history when they come finally
they are wrecks and we slowly take them back.
In your case it was going to develop quite severe kidney infection unless you give the right remedy.
And then you will say, now take antibiotics because I cannot do anything for you anymore.
Fortunately the Berberis was really indicated and acted and stopped the process. Now this person either it's going to be
cured and stay for 20 years well or it's going to go even further back, to the original cystitis or sinusitis.
-It wasn't a suppression then at that time when I gave Berberis because you said with the skin eruption,
nothing to do but when the illness is severe
then I have to act in any way.
-Absolutely.
-George, I just wanted to make sure if I got you right. It's about prescription in acute cases.
If you have an acute, as far as I understood you, you have to look if the patient belongs to group 1 or 2, then you can
prescribe on acute symptoms. If he belongs to group 3 or 4 then you have to look at the whole case and try to find
the remedy that covers up the whole
case and not take only the acute.
-Right.
-Thank you.
-Let's say there is a patient in group 3 or 4 and he is a mental case and because of his mental state he needs Hyoscyamus.
He gets a cold but the symptoms for the cold
are for Phosphorus or let's say, Belladona.
Then there is a great discrepancy between the chronic symptoms and the acute symptoms, what shall we do?
-Wait a moment. You have not treated at all yet. He comes and you take his case and you see that his
chronic symptoms belong to Hyoscyamus and his acute symptoms is Phosphorus. You give Phosphorus.
In any group if you have a clear picture.
The problem is when the picture is not clear and then you give the remedy and then you just suppress it.
-I wanted to mention an observation, I don't know if anybody already mentioned this. I was working in a anthroposophic
psychiatry and when they had clients that were going so mad, they would have to rise the allopathic remedy
so high and it wouldn't have any effect, they would give them injections which would produce fever,
high fever to 40 degrees. Afterwards, they could go down very much with the allopathic remedies,
the people were pretty clear but it was very exhausting and very risky thing to do but they do it.
-This is what I say exactly but it's very risky of course.
When you get this kind of acute it's going
to be between life and death situation.
There is in recurrent ear infection,
a damage somewhere on the defense chain.
Somewhere that defense mechanism has a loop, has a hole. A link is broken, that link is the possibility
at this moment of the organism to be cured.
The infection invites the bacteria, the organism reaches a level
where the bacteria or the virus can
affect it now. That level is good.
Primarily as an idea is good. It gives the organism the opportunity to heal and the organism fights
and does not heal and comes back the ear infection. Until the Homeopath comes, he gives the Mercury
and the infections are finished, then he raises the defense mechanism and there is no recurrence.
Otherwise with the antibiotics you are going not only to allow this healing but also to degrade the possibility
of the organism and then you open the possibility of the organism to develop something even deeper.
That's why when we see cases and they say, as a small child I had repeated ear infections. Now what you see?
It's a mental case terrible, originally started with ear infections, and then treated again and again
and then finally it comes to you and you have to unravel the whole thing until you bring it back to the ear infections.
-One more question concerning the procedures of the patients in group 3 or 4 when they have a severe acute infection.
You have said in these cases you also have to take also the chronic underlined symptoms into consideration.
Can you give an example because for me I can not even imagine how to treat a pneumonia or a cancer to a mental case.
-I gave already the example. You have a pneumonia which shows symptoms of Arsenicum.
When you inquire about the chronic symptoms, you see the restlessness etc.
Now this is an easy case and because
it's easy we place it to these groups.
Now you want to know what's
happening in this group.
Here things are not as clear as in these upper groups. Therefore you will have a problem
to find the indicated remedy,
that's why we say it is difficult.
It means that symptoms of Arsenicum, let's take the same example, will be in between other symptoms
and you will see the possibility of Phosphorus, the possibility of Hyoscyamus, the possibility of Stramonium,
the possibility of this and that.
The symptoms of pneumonia also will not indicate a clear Kali-c picture or Bryonia or Arsenicum.
This is why it is very difficult to treat this because you have to select what is fitting best to the whole of the picture.
That means you have to take into consideration the mental picture of the patient, if possible.
Together with the pneumonia.
And you say this pneumonia could be a picture of Phosphorus or a picture of Belladona but he was so violent,
ah Belladona is best though he
has thirst for cold water, repeated sips.
You select the best remedy
which is Belladona, then you raise.
But it is difficult, that' s why we call them incurable cases. You have to have a lot of experience
but imagine if Homeopathy was practiced for 2 centuries correctly, the experience that we would have
at this moment and the tradition that we would have, instead of taking hundreds of remedies, throwing them to people.
That was a tradition, when I came to Homeopathy. In the congresses I wouldn't dare even talk.
Now they invite me, please come. I don't come anymore, it's finished. There is no use. Now I have students, I can tell.
Why do I need to go to a Congress to speak for 10 minutes, to say what in 10 min. to explain all that? Is that possible?
-Who has done this? They made Hippocrates with blue eyes? Even Hippocrates must be German.
-I want to ask for the grades, in this group
3 or 4 and if you give to the chronic symptoms,
grade 3 or to the acute symptoms grade 3?
-If the symptom is clear and strong it doesn't matter which group, you underline 3 times, any symptom.
It has nothing to do with groups. The underlining of a symptom, 1, 2 or 3 is not connected with the groups.
It is connected only with the intensity with which the patient will tell the symptom. She says desire for oysters 'I ate hundreds'.
You underline it, this is a symptom.