As I had promised you, we're going to go through the difficult part of Homeopathy which is our failures.
Where and why we have our failures. We're going to go deep into the matter and examine with details
what is happening while when we prescribe
there is no effect in many cases.
We have to be aware where the problem might be and then we may be asking some help
from different other functions
or parts  of therapies.
We go through the different causes that create disease. What can create disease in a human being?
First is the bacteria and viruses and microbes
and of course all the poisons and these are
all the external causes of disease.
But in Homeopathy we don't accept this statement as it stands all along in the allopathic teaching.
We claim that even in that case when we have an external stimulation by microbial agent, still in order to
have a disease to have a reaction from the organism, we need to have a predisposition in this organism.
So here we need a predisposition.
You will say what is the problem,
why you say that?
It is very simple because we see in an epidemic that only certain part of the population falls sick under the epidemic;
That means those who are much
sensitive to that particular epidemic.
That idea is very prominent in the homeopathic teaching, as you know, and mostly this section concerns acute diseases.
The question is: the predisposition for acute diseases has anything to do with chronic diseases?
Is it at all connected with the idea of chronic diseases? Here in the acute conditions we see that there is
the prodromal period there is the crisis and then the lysis when the lysis is either death or recovery.
So we don't see a connection between acute and chronic diseases but in certain cases we see
that actually after an acute disease
a chronic condition starts.
Many times you will see cases where they say, my asthma started after an influenza, my colitis started
after a viral disease which was treated but not completely gone. So therefore this suggests that each organism
has a different degree of predisposition
towards a particular bacterial agent.
If you are a Homeopath and you have looked upon a wide range of diseases, you have seen a lot of possibilities.
You have seen this happening, after an acute, a chronic arises but also you have seen that
without any reason you have the appearance of a chronic disease or you have seen that there is some reason.
The patient will relate to you that after
this shock my condition started.
So here as Homeopaths we have to understand first how the disease is produced and why to understand that?
It doesn't matter, we have a disease, we treat and it's better, why to understand? No.
It is important to understand because this will give you a better idea of prognosis of the case whether the case
you're treating is possible or not possible to be cured; up to what point is going to be cured.
And we shall be seeing what are the main obstacles to cure and we have to have all this in mind when we treat,
otherwise we just prescribe remedies,
one after another without real effect.
We have a second cause of diseases which is mostly chronic and which comes from frustration of what?
The individual gets frustrated out of three
basic things, the first is self preservation.
I have to exist, I have to continue existing. I must stay alive, this is a very strong instinct which if it is frustrated
then we have the development of
a host of symptomatology
which will depend of course again upon
the predisposition of the individual.
That is why we see cases where people are struggling really to survive, they change job, this and that and no problem.
They go ahead, they change job, they take another but this individual who is having such a resistance
to this self-preservation instinct he feels not threatened. This individual gets into a relationship, very personal relationship
and there is a shock, there is a stress there is a divorce, there is a death and this individual is destroyed.
So we have an instinct.
The idea of two people coming together, if we see the idea why we're attracted to each other
and I'm not talking about homosexuality now, this is apart; I'm talking about the natural attraction between male and female.
There is an attraction which we call sexual, erotic attraction, we call love, you call it whatever you call it.
For what reason?
For continuity. So frustration on erotic or sexual with predisposition, can cause a very strong symptomatology.
And this symptomatology can be from simple symptoms to death.
Here, a lot of people die from heart attack during a divorce, I lost my partner and I cannot survive,
so they just have a heart attack and they die;
so it's a very strong instinct this.
The third is frustration on what?
Today this third frustration, the cause of disease, is something which happens primarily on
"developed" individuals,
"evolved" individuals. They think they have solved these two problems. They have survived
and they have a good relationship, they have overcome the need of that, this instinct has been lessened.
Somebody, Platina, they think to marry is no good because in this life to bring a child and to put this child
into war like Kosovo this holocaust is not good, so they cannot have a strong reaction on this level.
They find a partner, he is not good, we find another one, it doesn't matter, it's like this.
So the third part of frustration for the western people is the spiritual frustration.
I go very fast in these matters. These matters need you to meditate upon, to think about them aetc.
Otherwise we have to stay here
and discuss for days.
Spiritual frustration we have to stay a little bit longer in order to understand what we mean by this.
In this way, if we really understand the frustration, first of all we can prevent certain tragedies which may be happening.
This portion is something which keeps the mind of almost all the people, to a greater or lesser degree.
For people in Africa this part is not very strong because these two other frustrations are very strong.
Therefore the question why we're frustrated in this level does not arise so much. They still have their deliberations,
their thinking what is this world, why we have come here, what is our purpose, what is our mission,
they still think from time to time but we, the more evolved we are spiritually, the more we're frustrated in this level
because the self preservation
level is already difficult to solve.
The erotic and sexual is quite a source of pain and suffering and I believe because of that frustration
on this level we have escapes, not to say deviations.
You see here on this level which is even a deeper level, because this one is physical survival,
this one is psychic survival and this
of course is spiritual survival.
So they correspond this frustration to the physical world, to the psychic world and to the spiritual world.
The more we try to solve the problem as human beings on these levels, this is difficult but we have managed,
this is more difficult and either we have managed or we have escaped from facing the problem.
But escaping or suppressing or whatever, still we have frustration, still we have disease.
Now solving for ourselves, each one of us, the big question is why I am here, because this is the spiritual frustration.
The main question is why the hell am I here? What am I doing? There are times where we're shaken by this deep question
and then we take some action because there
is a time, the moment of enlightenment.
And this is the time that we take some decisions, I'm going to India to find enlightenment or I'm going to ...
-.... to Alonissos
-To Alonissos to find some enlightenment or whatever. This changes your life it is so strong.
Like you decide here, I'm going
to get married. You don't like it.
You get married to solve this problem many times, to solve this frustration on this level.
You say, after all it's not perfect but it's good enough, ok.
You will see that such decisions
actually foretell the possibility of disease,
foretell that at a certain moment
you're going to get sick.
If you make concessions... you see here
self-preservation is so strong,
you say, I'll sell this product
and I know it's nothing.
I go to the Media and say, there is a fantastic product to grow your hair, whenever you put it, your hair will be growing.
Millions of people buy the product, you are rich, you solve here your self-preservation but you know that
you have actually cheated and this is going to stay and this is going to cause disease and
this is going to cause war within you
and this war within you is going to manifest
as war outside killing the others,
don't care about the others.
You see that's how things start. This war that is going on, does anybody understand why it's going on?
Nobody, they bombard, they have flatten the whole country but if you see the construction of society
how it has been developing on this level, you will absolutely understand why we have the war
today, why we want to kill each other.
If I kill the others, I will survive.
This is the idea behind which of course is the opposite than the truth, it's absolutely the opposite.
You are not going to survive here, you're going to be sick, more and more sick. Why?
Because you did some concessions on your conscience here to satisfy your self-preservation instinct,
you did concession against your conscience and you're going to pay. How? By becoming sick.
That's why today we have societies which are basically sick in these levels.
You see the suppression of conscience is not going necessarily to manifest symptoms on the physical level.
It will manifest symptoms on the psychic level because all these three levels are together.
So the spiritual frustration comes to us because we have mishandled these two other instincts.
We misunderstood how we should act, how we shouldn't act and we lost our health.
The payment is you lose your health, finished.
Now of course is not only very simple that
you do something against your conscience
because there are subtleties which
they create these inner imbalances.
Here, in the erotic-sexual, I give you a very common escape from that level which is
instead of having a correct education in this
level, if we knew what we're doing we could
foresee the problems which are coming and prevent them.
Now here what is the first escape that we see?
-Masturbation?
-Yes masturbation. The first escape is masturbation, why? Because there is no health,
in a child 3,5,6 years old there is masturbation.
Is he conscious of what he is doing?
Of course the hormonal balance is unbalanced and therefore  the child has to have it.
Otherwise it will go crazy.
We have created more and more problems for ourselves and then more and more problems start from very young age.
First escape is masturbation because the societies which we created did not educate properly the children.
And what is a proper education?
We are talking about basic things
in health. So what you tell your children?
I'll tell you something; it doesn't matter what you tell them. If the children are unbalanced in these levels forget what you tell them.
Now it's too late to tell them. It has to be told a few generations before to prevent all this happening
but even then some children are still
quite healthy and they can listen.
And if you educate them and you say to them that having a relationship on a sexual level is a very great,
a very interesting thing, a very interesting experience which they have to wait until they reach such an age
that they can enjoy it. Otherwise they will misuse it and they will be dying in this level. You will be dead.
It's like you tell a child, don't eat Arsenicum
it's a poison and the child knows it's a poison.
Here, on this level we let the children totally uneducated. The mothers they don't want to know what the children
are doing the fathers are very busy and then
you will see how all this comes to you as a
Homeopath and they say, take the problem now.
All this problem, all this generation say, take the problem and fix it and then you are in despair.
Because you understand that this child is sick and they say, oh he has some personality problems.
It's not personality problem only, what type of personality? Ah the child wants to be by himself,
alone and plays only with his toys. The other child is aggressive and hits and fights,
the other one is restless and the other one is the superman that will fly with the batman.
This little deviation is actually the end result of generations of wrong doing.
Then you give Cicuta or Bar-c. You have to understand the depth of the problem.
For me, when I realized these things, it was a cause for deep despair because you realize how much you have to work
with that child, how many years before you can bring him more to the healthy side and
you have to understand
what you're doing with the child. Otherwise you just throw remedies here and there. It's not the idea.
The idea is where is he going? Towards health or is it just removing some of its symptoms?
You want to really know, you want to understand because on the way to cure, you will see very frightening situations.
You treat a child and then it goes into severe pneumonia, take antibiotics now and as we have said
this is the time where you have to be careful, you have to prescribe correctly to take him
from that state further and then you will see.
What? The spiritual frustration eases out.
I don't say spiritual quest.
Spiritual quest is different than spiritual frustration.
Spiritual quest is something quite healthy.
I would like to know why I am here.
This is a legitimate question but it doesn't
torment me, it doesn't make me make the
wrong decision.
The spiritual frustration on this level will take somebody suddenly wake up and say, I would like to go and find God.
Where? In Indonesia. I heard the -whatever it's called- is there and they put on some special clothes
and they fly to Indonesia to solve their
spiritual frustration.
This is a decision which comes from already a diseased mind. You have to know because some people will come and say
'shall I go to Indonesia?' Why? 'Because something inside me tells me to go there to find answers.'
You understand that this is a
wrong decision for the boy.
I remember a case in India. A very rich family from Paris. His father was an industrialist and left a lot of money.
He was wandering about in India, we met
when I was a student there and treating certain people.
And he came to Krishnamurti's lectures and
he was there eating only that particular food
cooking that food which was vegetarian, he had a cat who was also vegetarian. It was terribly looking,
but my cat is also vegetarian. And he had this very spiritual look and talked very slowly and we talked.
And he said: I think I have on my right toe a pain here, can you prescribe something for this pain? I said yes, sure.
Nothing else?  Nothing else.
In the meantime we have discussed quite a lot and I perceived what was happening with him.
He was going with a very heavy cover where the people living in Himalaya have this and he was going with it.
He had a caravan, he was travelling up and down in India and then I started prescribing for him.
I prescribed for about a year and a half,
several remedies.
The man came out of that situation one day and he said to me, you know what? I am the son of a very rich man who died.
My father died, my mother also and they left us a lot of money. What happened with the money?
The money now is with my brother-in-law. And how do you live? He sends me every month some money.
Then, I don't remember he asked for some money or wrote a letter and there was a denial,
we cannot give you more money.
He was talking about millions of francs that was left on his account and he was taking very little money to survive in India.
Finally to just finish the story we went together back to France to meet his sister and his brother-in-law
who was handling the money, to find out that he had no money at all. The brother-in-law said,
we lost all the money and we don't have any money at all.
He suddenly became a very poor man and he was realizing that he was trusting his brother-in-law who took all the money.
I said, you never controlled? No, he was sending me some money for years.
He was roaming about in India trying to get enlightenment.
He had solved self preservation by thinking he was rich, he had solved the erotic-sexual
by suppressing it and reaching the
spiritual frustration on the wrong path.
You cannot reach the spiritual quest.
You reach spiritual frustration.
Self preservation, I'm rich now I have
enough money, it's finished.
Erotic-sexual, I don't get along with the girl,
it doesn't matter, I will suppress it and then I go for spiritual quest;
this is not possible because when you reach here, you are crazy, you have the sperm of craziness.
Not balanced, imbalanced.
Therefore you have to go through these steps in a very natural, normal way. You cannot just wake up in a day and say,
I want to get spiritual enlightenment,
let me go to India.
You see all these people who went to India to meet the yogis, what happened? Most of them became crazy.
Some others of course were disillusioned, they went to India and they came back, like myself.
If you persist on the idea that in India I will find spiritual enlightenment and this you're forcing yourself,
you are ready for a very deep disorder
which will be mostly on mental level.
So what happens with our societies today, the western societies, a lot of these people are
within this realm,
struggling without having solved this frustration, they are trying to solve this level.
As a result we have the diseases
that we see today.
-Isn't possible George that after going through the first two levels, then you reach the third level?
At a certain age you feel that now you have important questions, that it will be a phase that you also have to struggle
because you also want to go through the third phase. So wouldn't be normal to have such struggling and questions?
-As I said, it is different between having to struggle, having to work and being frustrated.
Frustration is when you have an idea that if I go one year in India I will get enlightenment. One year passes
and nothing has happened, then you start getting frustrated then a second year you're in a big frustration,
the third year you are destroyed. I have seen around Krishnamurti a lot.
What I teach here is absolutely experience
and nothing else. It's not theories.
I was around Krishnamurti, I saw hundreds if not thousands of dead people. Dead emotionally. When I say dead,
I mean dead there was nothing there. You can't move them. Treat me. What to treat? What can I do?
Almost you can do nothing. You can not bring them back to life. We have for this level several remedies.
The main one is of course Sepia. Sepia is the main remedy for this frustration where the individual
has given up the idea of having a relationship.
I was just told yesterday there is a documentary on Sepia
by National Geographic where they show the Sepia mating and he told me that it is so colorful, so playful, so full of feelings.
This mating is amazing where in the provings Sepia is actually exactly the opposite of playful, of colorful, of participating.
A Sepia woman, oh I have to do it again, she doesn't move, she doesn't do anything, she just waits for the man
to finish and that's it. This is the Sepia,
she doesn't feel anything.
The whole idea is against some notions that if we know the qualities of the fish or the shellfish,  from that we can induce the
symptomatology of the remedy. You know this movement?
There is a movement where they don't do provings anymore, they take the habits of an animal
and these habits transfer them into symptoms of Materia Medica. This exactly proves the opposite.
-I just want to know, is it necessary that we move easily from one to the other?
-With treatment or without treatment? With treatment the answer is different.
Without treatment what may happen is, maybe you can be saved by entering into spiritual frustration,
by accident, by somebody telling you a few things, then you realize but most probably if
you reach that stage
then nobody can save you. Unless you have a good Homeopath and he takes you from here to here to here.
The disturbance on this level is going to be carried here and it's going to be carried to the sexual
and on the physical and then it's going to become on the outside of the physical.
Here, if you are very frustrated here and I give you a remedy, you may have a heart problem of  course
but if by yourself you're there
and you try to find balance here...
find balance here is nothing less than connection with God, that means me and God
are one and the same, we're connected.
This is solution of this level, this only very few individuals and very healthy individuals can attain.
If we are sick and through our sickness we try to solve this level, forget it, we're creating problems.
-I was asking a different question. If someone is growing and they solve their preservation problem and they now
are moving, they start solving the erotic problems and they start moving into the spiritual but they are not yet finished with
the second level, do you keep going back and forth between levels or you just finish with one level and go to the third?
-The idea is when you are in this level, are you in a healthy manner or you are unhealthy?
You are frustrated yes or no? If you're frustrated, that means you have followed prematurely a path of evolution
which is not yet right for you. This whole idea comes to the idea of truth.
What I mean by truth? I mean seen in myself what is true in me here, here or there. Really.
On the spiritual level if you know that I still have these incapacities, I still have these shortcomings,
I still have these wrong doings this is very good, there is no danger. But if you think I have overcome all that
and now I'm going to become God, this is very dangerous.
Now I'm going to become very spiritual person. This is very dangerous for the health of the individual.
There are a lot of individuals living
of course with their madness, these fantasies.
You will say, what is wrong with
them? Let them continue.
This is not for me to decide whether they continue or not. For me to decide is, can I cure
and what kind of disturbance
he has?  Is it the nail?
I have to know what is the level in which he is suffering and to know can I cure such a case?
Yes or no?
Somebody comes and tells me, 'ah, I admire you so much, you have so much and we're working together in an inner level.'
It sounds very interesting, ok what am I doing? He says, bla, bla, bla and can you give me some
concrete information of  what is this cooperation about.
And these people are living in spiritual frustration. She comes to me and says, 'from time to time
I have a little pain in the stomach
can you give me a remedy?'
If she has given me before this idea, that she lives into her fantasy so much, can I cure this little pain? No.
Because if I try to cure this little pain, this pain will become an ulcer and you have to know this and I have to tell her.
I'm sorry it's not possible for me to cure you.
Otherwise you give a remedy for the little pain and what happens the pain may even go away
but the woman goes deeper into her delusions.
Why do we deal with such cases?
The percentage all together of such cases that we may have, in different countries is different.
The more you go to the North, the more
we see this spiritual frustration.
The more you go to the South, to Africa, to South America, they enjoy their life, spiritual? We have time, next life.
Greece is in the middle, it's
neither South nor North.
-You mentioned before that if somebody comes with spiritual frustration, he has tried to tackle this issue too early.
So for me the question is spiritual a matter of age or is it also possible to have it in very young years ?
It is possible that even very young age you see some people who are very spiritual, balanced
they don't go and do crazy things,
this is not definitely a matter of age.
But it depends on the mission of the individual. If his mission is to transfer some knowledge to others then he needs age.
He needs experience, even very spiritual young people they don't have the experience,
so in order to transfer to others
they need experience, they need age.
I would like your feedback on these ideas and questions to see whether this matter is well understood or misunderstood.
So please give me your feedback, even if you have a different idea, it doesn't matter we discuss and we find out.
-I think that in the United States there is a very high level of spiritual frustration and perhaps
we should be moved up geographically
towards the North Pole.
We have such high incidents of new age psychology that people are living in their fantasies
about what spirituality is to a degree
which is quite frightening.
My question is since I am in that environment, in the northern part of North America, can you recommend
any course of treatment so that the delusional component can be disolved without bringing about
the angina or the colitis and so forth. I haven't, in my experience, seen in these cases which I agree with you
this is a beautifully represented portrait of what the human psyche is at least in my experience in U.S.,
I've seen that by giving even LM potencies, even when people are apparently very healthy because there is such
anxiety about their health; so they eat healthy, they are communing with animals, with higher nature.
And if someone goes against their belief system, immediately they turn to hatred toward the person
which obviously conveys theirself of not being spiritual. So in seeing this as a very deep pathology without
tissue change I would say it's on the lower level 3 or upper 4, in terms of using your levels of health.
I found that in treating these individuals are in the same level with those on deep pathological tissue change.
Using low potencies, as LM for example, do not bring about such a strong physical reaction but it is a concern of mine
and it's also very deep concern to them that they will start to aquire physical pathology.
-We will be talking in detail because during this course we're going to see how we handle these cases.
Not only these particular frustration cases but cases that present special difficulty for homeopathic prescribing.
There are a lot of categories, a lot of groups of people that present special difficulties for us.
I don't want to give you the impression
that most of the cases are difficult cases.
And I can tell you from my experience, about 10% of all the groups that we will be talking, is the percentage
that presents special problems for the Homeopaths. This gives you another 90% possibility to be successful.
-My question is, is not the idea in front of the spiritual frustration?
Wanting to approach God, to become like
God is that not the point?
and having an attitude of humbleness
that will solve the problem.
-That is quite correct, the spiritual frustration comes almost together with a spiritual arrogance.
I remember a case, she was a woman, that I treated unsuccessfully for many years. Her attitude was like this.
One day we met some people that were really very spiritual people. She met them first and then she invited me
to meet them also. After a while she says, yes the theory was that these people were the number 1.
A unity, it's God but one day she says, but I'm zero before them, so I have created them.
To hear these things, you know I was trying to cure such a person, I was giving remedies to no avail.
The idea was that beyond any spiritual activity that was happening on this planet, she was behind
and she was the cause of that activity. If this ego is so great, the frustration is so much that has become
almost like a stone inside the person, it cannot break. You see everything else revolves around that hard core
and then it doesn't matter what remedies you may be giving, there will be no effect.
Maybe some symptoms will shift here and there, but no real effect, no change.
-Can you put the same 3 levels of frustration, can you equalize them through the levels,
physical level, emotional and spiritual level?
-Absolutely, this is the idea. This comes together with the general idea who is the human being
and what levels within which he's living etc. These 3 levels of frustration correspond to frustrations
on physical body, emotional body and
on the mental body, spiritual body.
Definitely, but they are interelated. A frustration here, may stay a frustration only on this level.
If it is a frustration here and some of the impact of the frustration can go here or there or even there
this is quite hopeful. So if you see somebody who is struggling spiritually, but at the same time
he has physical problems, he is in a much better state than a person frustrated here, without physical symptoms.
-If somebody has such a big delusion, which possibilities do we have as practitioners, to explain them
that for this pain in the stomach, we first have to solve his mental problem and then the physical problem?
-For the case I mentioned to you I have tried everything; it didn't work. Nevermind how much you can explain,
they cannot because it's a belief system that is crystalised and if it breaks, it will break out in a very malignant way,
that means this stone here, if it breaks, it will create a malignancy on a physical level.
-I have the impression that in Germany the spiritual frustration is accepted. With patients that suffer from psychosis
and they get physical symptoms and the psychosis reduces, then the patient has no understanding for this.
He rather wants to be psychotic again and not suffer from the physical disease. Because people
don't want to suffer any physical pain.
-That is true sometimes. What I speak here about spiritual frustration is not
the total destruction on the mental level. Total destruction which is schizophrenia is different,
the individual could not anymore retain
reality and escapes totally.
Total escape from everything; then all these levels were not concerned anymore with the frustration on these levels
because we have a total destruction
of the core of the human being.
So therefore it is an escape. Now you bring back this man who has escaped, and you show him reality.
And he comes to reality and says, 'still I don't like it. I'm going to escape' but don't forget that the escape
is the result of a body which is quite diseased.
With homeopathy actually we try to build this body to retain the reality
so he will have a relapse, what you're saying actually is a relapse and then you try again and you try again
until and unless maybe there is a little possibility that you may bring him back eventually
with strong physical symptoms and he will be able to accept the symptom and live with this suffering, with this reality.
I have seen cases where as a young man he's 20,21,22 goes off and he has electroshocks
and comes back in a way and at the age
of 40 there is paralysis.
You see this history, there is multiple sclerosis, gives you an idea of the depth of the problem in this organism.
So when you start treating such a case, you don't say ah I found the remedy. It doesn't matter;
you found the remedy but there is another layer, another layer because you're dealing with a very deep destruction
of the nervous system, central and peripheral.
So it's different the prognosis of this case.
This case you don't like though you may be able with good prescribing to keep them walking for years
for 10, 15, 20 years they keep walking, they
don't go to the chair, but that's all you can do.
They're stuck there,
they cannot progress anymore.
Because the progress in further, will mean the destruction of a main organ, maybe the heart.
-Again a question about spiritual frustration. Could you perhaps say some words about what for you
would be a healthy way of developing in that level?
Because more and more patients come to us with physical problems and more people are getting
spiritually interested and in this and in that, at least in my practice. To differientate is still healthy or is it frustration?
-I will not like to say what is the healthy way to go but what I would like to give you as information is how
you handle such cases and how you differientate between one case and the other.
When the patient comes, you have to make a discussion on these levels so you understand his degree of craziness, delusion.
If you see this degree of delusion is very deep and it is deep when? The deeper it is, the more you will see
the egotistical element. I am the greatest. When you see this element you have to be careful and then you have to expect
that if your treatment is correct you will have to have severe problems with the physical body.
Now what you tell them, how you advise such individuals. You have to advise very carefully
and say,
why don't you take it more easy, why don't you give up this? Because usually such people they have followers
They are weak individuals who like to see somebody who says I'm God and they follow God.
But you have to be careful because we're
talking about diseased individuals here.
We're not concerned with real spiritual people. There are some real spiritual people that
have gone through this in a quite nice
manner. And they have arrived at a point
where they feel that they have a wisdom which is substantial and love which is also substantial
so they are able to give to others because people who have reached this level are always creative.
They are not destructive, they don't do something to destruct.
A wise man with love, always creates, never destructs. So if you see that, without the claim
I'm God...because if you see that claim immediately you have to be aware that
something is wrong with the individual
and maybe quite seriously wrong.
You have to advise and tell them be careful, if you continue in this way maybe you'll have much more problems.
-What about the catholic priests? They are not allowed to have any normal sex.
Is it a possibility to them to reach any spirituality?
-It's a good question.
There are certain individuals, very few,
who are able to go through this level without much frustration.
They are able to really overcome the level,
it's not a suppression, it's an understanding.
They need their organism to take and give love on a much higher level, higher than the physical.
That means the exchange is on psychic
level, so it feeds them in a nice way.
People who go for advice to them, give them love, they give love to the people who they advice
and in this way they find a balance inside themself. There is no problem.
Now these people, have solved this problem, especially because the self-preservation is ended,
they have a security. If they have an organism which can do that, they have overcome this level.
Their struggle because being a priest that means you target yourself to the unification with the divine.
So their struggle will be here and it will be in
a natural way but the majority is different.
They have to suppress and they have to escape.
By having an escape the individual is frustrated because he knows, I use masturbation or I use homosexuality.
Immediately there is a consciousness which puts them in an anxiety state; that is going to be a problem for this level.
-I experience that children who are for instance in terminal stage of cancer, they become very wise and they have
very smart remarks. I would like to ask
what has happened here?
If I would ask the question in a provocative way,
I would say that the cancer has been educating them
in a wrong way or they have a predisposition to develop this disease or not?
-Such children have a very bad health in
general but due to certain circumstances,
all the force of this imbalance, comes on the physical body.
And then destroys the physical body, leaving
the mental-emotional very clear.
That is why we see this behaviour in these children. Because they are so healthy, so perceptive, so balanced
in their last moments, it is amazing. I have also observed the same thing. The reason is that all the disbalance
has been concentrated upon the physical body and the mental-emotional has been left, intact.
But the overall health of such child is very
bad. I'll give you some percentages.
Mental-Emotional-Physical. In order for someone to die and to die suddenly, it needs to have out of 100 points,  90 points of disease.
These 90 points can be distributed in this way. Mental 20, Emotional 20 and Physical 50.
This person is going to live for many years.
Given now that something happens on the mental-emotional which clears up these points
and M is 0, E is 0 and all 90 come to the physical, the physical body can not withstand such an impact and dies.
0 disease here, 0 disease emotional, 90% on the physical body, cannot survive but M 40 here,
E 20, P 30 mentally deranged.
But let us say, M 80, E 10, P 0 this person is schizophrenic, he's going to live for a long time.
The physical body is left intact, no symptoms. It can live many, many years with destruction on this level.
That is why the child is here, on this line, when he dies.
-If you solve the problem of self-preservation of the first level, when you didn't suppress anything
on the second level, is one then
protected from spiritual frustration?
-He is protected yes. As long as the general health of this individual is in quite good condition.
That means out of 100 points, his total points are 30. If his total points are 30 points of disease, then such a person
who has solved the problems on these two levels, can go to spiritual quest or understanding without much danger.
There is a little danger, as long as this goes down, less, as it goes up, more. Because here the energy is very powerful.
I have met people that they had what we call, spiritual enlightenment. During these points,
during these moments, the energy which goes through the body is so strong, the real spiritual enlightenment
is so strong that if these points are a little bit high, it burns out the body. It can destroy the physical body.
The physical body cannot stand this much of bliss of enlightenment, of understanding, it is something beyond
the capacity of us to understand
these strong spiritual experiences.
So unless you have a body which is quite strong, it will be destroyed. That's why I was reading the other day in a book.
He says, if this experience remained for more than a few minutes, I would be dead. They feel it.
I was reading a book from one
of these monks in Mount Athos.
- There is some measurements for spiritual development because if you're on a spiritual
way, love grows.
And if it's the right way, love for others is growing and if it's the wrong way, love for youself, egotism is growing.
I think that even if you have solved the 2 levels you can still get sick on the third level.
-I agree.
-We said that we like more to have disturbances on mental-emotional and physical than just having mental.
Here is a person with 50 points of disease. One has 10 points on the mental level, 20 points here and 20 points here.
This case is better than a case that we have
40 points here, 5 points here and 5 here.
We have mental problems but at the same time physical. It's better than to have mostly mental and very little physical.
Of course it is much better not to have any problems here and have all the 50 points here.
This case is a limit case which we can treat with success. These people here, you will see that inspite of their pathology,
they are very happy people. They have a lot
of energy, they are happy, they like to live.
You will see a healthy attitude towards
life but they suffer quite a lot.
This is a case in the limits. You have to very clearly understand these points.
-Before Margaret said something about love and egotism. I don't think you should put these two together at all
because egotism is not love. People use love for egotism but a person should love himself in order to love others
because if you are not full, you can't give nothing.
-It's the same. It doesn't matter how you say it. What you say is the same thing. If you love too much yourself
is wrong but you have to love yourself.
-In order to love others.
-So it doesn't mean because you love yourself is wrong. No. You have to love yourself but not only yourself, this is the idea.
Because if you love only yourself, you don't care; then you throw some bombs and you kill.
-I have one small problem understanding the example with the priest or the monk or somebody else.
I think there is no problem that somebody can get spiritually elevated and perhaps not having a relationship
but also being able to love the people and getting his pressure off the hormonal system escaping with masturbation.
Why this should be a problem? Because he also could be very creative and much loving the others.
I don't see any problem.
-Ok, I'll tell you where is the problem and what is the problem. The problem is with his own conscience
in understanding how he tries to avoid a natural phenomenon, which happens in nature.
It doesn't matter whether the individual understands this, the nature, attraction etc. Still with the children,
when they practice masturbation, there is the idea they do something secretly.
Have you ever seen a child, unless it is mentally disturbed, to do masturbation in front of the class?
No, he will go secretly. Why? Because he knows it is something not allowed, not proper, not correct etc.
The idea of doing something wrong is
there already even if it is not strong.
I may accept that a spiritual person may go into spirituality, having to practice masturbation from time to time,
to release the hormones. I even go as far
as that but still the problem will remain.
There is a draw back because of that function.
Big or less. Somebody else who is priest and has homosexual contacts has a bigger problem, definitely.
And someone who is a priest and goes with married women here and there, he has even bigger problem.
And he who is a priest and goes secretely to have sex in the brothels, he has a problem.
I have seen and I have talked with monks who could not retain. I treated them and they confessed
what they had to do. They were in a terrible state spiritually, there is no question. My God.