I would like to point out more specifically what we may encounter as problems and obstacles in homeopathic prescribing.
So we have to be aware of such obstacles. We're talking about physical obstacles. Mechanical.
You have a sciatica and you prescribe the correct remedies which either act for a very short time or they don't reduce the pain.
The pain is severe, you prescribe, they don't act. Most probably what happens we have a mechanical obstacle.
For instance we have a herniated disc and this is pressing upon a nerve.
If we try to cure such case with Homeopathy, forget it, we just waste our time.
We need some mechanical means which are either you put him in bed or you call a chiropractor to see
if he can reduce the pressure or you operate.
It's not possible to reduce the pain in such cases.
There is an old woman 74, 78, she comes to you with severe constipation and you prescribe correctly and there is no effect.
Suspect always that there might be a tumor which is just obstructing and still not giving symptoms,
not giving blood, not giving pains it just gives constipation, very little stool and general discomfort.
If you try to reduce this tumor without an operation, most probably you will have a dead case.
So you have to investigate to find out whether there is an obstruction, a tumor, then you operate, then you prescribe.
We have such cases which are living quite many years after such operations, there is no question about that.
But if you try again and again to give one remedy after the other and there is no effect, no effect and
no stool is coming out and you insist without thinking that you may have a mechanical obstruction,
this is a serious mistake that you may have problems also legal.
There was a case with tremendous irritation of the eye, the eye was red. You give remedy after remedy
and the redness stays there and then it goes and be examined by an ophthalmologist very carefully
and there is a very tiny splinter of metal.
So always when you prescribe and especially if you have a clear case and there is no effect, suspect
that you may have a mechanical problem
and try to see if there is such a problem.
Another obstacle to cure is chemical drugs in general.
The most common is?
-Antibiotics?
-No, coffee. Coffee is one of the main obstacles to cure homeopathically unfortunately.
We have this problem because many people are used to drink coffee and they don't want to stop it
and we're in bad terms with such patients.
Of course if you go further than that we have the recreational, so called, drugs especially heroine and cocaine,
also marihuana is an impediment to cure. If somebody regularly takes marihuana you cannot cure.
If they don't tell you, what happens is you prescribe a remedy, they do well for certain time, then there is a relapse.
Then there is a different remedy, then you prescribe again, then there is a relapse. You can go on and then
at a certain moment you ask, are you taking marihuana? He says, yes why? It's not a habit for me, you know these theories.
I don't care whether it is habit forming. It is antidoting an organism which tries to reach balance,
unbalances the organism.
You give a remedy, again marihuana. Of course cocaine is much faster in doing this and of course heroin.
But it is not only these non-prescribed drugs, also the prescribed drugs of that type which is
the valium, the Tavor, all these
antidepressants, tranquilizers.
This was with severe headaches
with some problems in the stomach.
He was taking something with
codeine for the headaches.
We gave a remedy, the headaches went
away but he kept on taking the pain killer.
He says, I feel so good if I take this. He even felt better than before. And then of course there was a relapse.
Cafergot etc., which are very strong drugs and that's why the research they did on chronic headaches
in Germany was a total failure because they allowed the patient to continue taking the drugs
while taking the homeopathic remedy.
They gave one potency and then they allowed taking Cafergot and the painkillers and of course it was a disaster.
I don't know how these Homeopaths, some of them were my students, they've heard these many times
how they kept on doing these things.
There are some other cases which I call miasmatic cases.
-There are some people proclaiming that you can drink coffee during homeopathic treatment and then it antidotes
only few cases. What do you think about that?They say it antidotes only in a low percentage.
-I don't agree.
-What is your percentage rate?
-My percentage is 100 % depending on the length of time. One will be antidoted after a week of coffee.
Another after two weeks, another after 2 years.
If 1% stays without being antidoted with coffee,
I will be still doubtful. I know only one case.
If you stay well for 3-5 years and you have a strong organism, that means you were a clear Tarentula case.
Strong organism, you gave Tarentula 50M, 3 years, you didn't drink coffee. Most probably after 3 years
you can drink coffee. But while you're taking Tarentula to go and drink coffee at the same time, forget it.
The coffee issue is a big and difficult one.
-One practical question. After the patient
has come back to health and then
he starts to drink coffee
can he antidote afterwards?
Can he get a relapse afterwards?
-Yes he can. He may not but it can be antidoted, even after 2 years of being well if he starts drinking coffee, he can.
-Most patients immediately if I tell them not to drink coffee they come with tea. What about this issue?
-They can drink tea, it is true. If you drink tea there is no antidotal influence unless if one in 10.000,
they are sensitive to tea. They drink tea and they have palpitations. In this case stop it.
If they tell you a reaction
like that, you have to stop it immediately.
-Otherwise they can.
-Otherwise it's ok. Also cocoa, also milk with cocoa. Also decaffeinated, no problem.
I have seen some problems in cases where they have gastritis and they drink decaffeinated.
These chemical things which contains of course can create a problem, more burning and pain but not antidoting the remedy.
-So you are saying that in all instances or most instances, drinking decaffeinated coffee,
woll have no effect in homeopathic treatment?
-No, in all cases they will have no antidoting influence but it can irritate the stomach.
-What if there is no gastrointestinal irritation then it's perfectly fine for patients to drink decaffeinated.
-Yes, in my experience.
-Because I have patients who have both antidoted with regular coffee and also antidote it with decaffeinated coffee
and don't seem to have any kind of previous gastro-intestinal sensitivity to coffee, both decaffeinated or regular.
I will make my patients extremely happy to tell them they can drink decaffeinated coffee.
-They can, as far as my experience is concerned. But there might somebody who will tell you,
I smell coffee and I got a relapse.
I don't believe it. I believe that my remedy was not correct and it was a placebo effect and
with the least provocation the person says, I have a relapse and then I try, most probably, to find another remedy.
I have a case of Phosphorus and you tell Phosphorus, don't drink coffee. Phosphorus accepts this
and it's always in his mind because he's suffering a lot with anxiety. Then they offer him some ice-cream
and he takes the ice-cream and suddenly he tastes the coffee and in front of everybody he spits out the coffee.
He can't be antidoting. He can tell you, I antidoted the treatment.
The fact is you have not given Phosphorus to him, you have given Arsenicum or Nitric acid
and then you think about Phosphorus.
You better give him Phosphorus now
because he is very impressionable.
He is very auto-suggesting patient and with auto-suggestion you can do a lot. They say 40% you can cure.
It is amazing how many of our patients come and tell you how well they feel even with the placebo.
We have to have this in mind very well. A cure is not, I feel better. A cure is you have to have certain things
happening in that organism. Then you know that this is a cure.
I remember a woman who came here in Alonissos, she was very nice and she was a Homeopath and we discussed.
Suddenly I find out she says, I don't
use remedies. What do you use?
I have my own potentiser which I potentise.
It is a machine in which I put a sugar, I turn and it says, Pulsatilla 10M because the machine vibrates.
You turn it a little bit more and it's Sulphur 50, you turn it a little bit more and it's Calcarea carbonica.
And your patients are doing well? She says, yes all my patients. All is an exaggeration always.
This is clearly a placebo effect, she was very nice. There is no question about that, don't even think for a second time.
What is the problem with the placebo effect? There is no problem. Well good but don't claim you cure cases.
These are for simple things and to feel better for a while and the patient comes back again and again,
he has this and that etc. Not that you're really touching the case with the indicated remedy.
Miasmatic obstacles is in certain cases. I see the well-indicated remedies do not give an effect and you struggle
with these cases and you go through their histories and their parents etc. and you try to find out
if there is a kind of a miasmatic layer which prevents your remedies from acting.
What is this miasmatic layer? For instance is a case which I remember, a quinine case, a China Sulphurica case,
quinine was taken by the parents of a woman.
The woman at a very early age, 12-13 developed headaches.
She came to us at the age of 28-29 with
severe headaches and she was a wreck.
We prescribed several remedies, no effect. At a certain point her case indicated a little bit of China Sulphurica.
I said to her 'have you taken quinine?'. 'No'. 'Your parents?', 'No'. 'How do you say no? Do you know your parents
before your birth what they were taking? I said, I will not give you a remedy. You go and ask your parents whether
your father or mother took a lot of quinine before your birth'. She went back there and said, 'my father lived in Africa
where he had to take quinine every day before I was born'. China Sulphurica opened up the case and then she was cured.
Another case I will tell you. A doctor lost his voice totally, he says, I have to give up my practice, total paralysis.
I gave this remedy, this remedy, this remedy, no effect.
I said, what about diphtheria?
Did you have diphtheria as a child?
He said, yes. Very good, take a dose of Diphtherinum 200. Of course it opened up the case and then Gelsemium.
Before he had taken Gelsemium, Argentum nitricum, Causticum, Phosphorus the whole lot, nothing, no effect.
With Diphtherinum which has stayed as a miasmatic layer for him, which can go on in the children also.
His children may at certain point need Diphtherinum.
The same thing I found out with Penicillin,
people who have taken penicillin a lot
and created a kind of a miasm,
it can block your prescription
and unless they take Penicillin 200, 1M, then it opens up the case. The same with cortisone.
We have certain chemical drugs which can create a kind of a miasmatic layer and we have to be aware
if no remedy is giving effect,
to investigate on these levels.
Permanent organ damage.
You see when I did this explanation to you before nobody asked me about the Down syndrome.
These children, as you know, are mentally retarded. Mongoloid children, mentally retarded very strongly.
Yet they have many times severe acute conditions which are treated and the mental condition does not change.
What happens here is that, we have to separate between permanent damage of an organ
and a process of inflammation,
a process of degeneration.
The permanent damage is a calcification, you get for instance in these old tuberculous patients, treated
or non treated and then you see in the X-rays calcifications in the lungs, areas which are calcified.
These areas are permanent organ damage.
Such permanent organ damage, the organism does not consider them as a process.
It considers it as dead tissues. Therefore
it is not considered as a process of disease.
So if a brain is born with a damage which
is permanent, it's not a process, it's not
a blow and then hematoma and then tumor forming but it is permanent as it is in Down syndrome,
then the organism does not take
it into consideration in these points.
-A hysterectomy ?
-A hysterectomy no, because once the hysterectomy is out not because of a process but because of
calcification of fibroids that means the process has stopped before the operation,
the organism does not consider it as a disease.
But if you take out the uterus but the uterus already has started a process of, let us say,
developing cancer, then this will be considered not obstacle but as difficulty in curing.
Dead tissues, a process happened, an inflammation happened and there is calcification
and there is even encysted, there is no interference of the organism with this process.
The organism takes part in anything which is alive, which is going on, degenerating,
the organism takes part in this.
-One question. What about
calcification of lymph nodes?
-This calcification is not taking part in the process. That means you give a remedy,
you don't expect the calcification to go away.
You don't expect that these dead tissues will be alive again and if these dead tissues are in the heart,
it's a permanent damage. You don't expect
to cure, if these tissues are in the nerve sheaths,
this you don't expect to cure. The dead tissues for instance in Multiple Sclerosis of several years,
there are the plaques which are formed and are a permanent damage, this is an impediment to cure.
You cannot proceed further than that point.
- Is it a proof that there is a Tubercular miasm? Because of the calcified lymph nodes?
-Yes it is a proof that we have Tuberculosis and Tuberculinum or Baccilinum can be used, there is no question about that.
What I say is when you have a permanent damage you cannot overcome it. It is an impediment to cure.
You cannot push it out of the way. Sometimes this calcification in the lungs doesn't do anything, it's ok.
But if it is calcification on the brain, that portion is finished, you will never get it back.
If this calcification is on one kidney, this kidney is not functioning anymore, you cannot get it back.
The organism is going as far as working with one kidney, working with one lung, working with half brain.
You cannot overcome such impediments.
-I just would like to correct you because I am a friend of a patient that did just now MRI and she suffers from M.S.
and most of them are gone, the plaques, we don't see them anymore after treatment.
-That means they were not permanent. They were in the process of inflammation. You see before they reach
this dead level, they inflame and there is a kind of edema around it, inflamed edema, then the edema goes away
for instance if you give cortisone and then you see the symptoms are going away.
If you catch the M.S. on the process of forming the plaques, then you can reduce it and you can cure it.
But if this has been formed already, you will have this impediment, the right leg will go always like this.
You just stay, you cannot progress it further. That's what I say.
-There is a question for the situation of myoma. If you have a woman which she has bleedings from myoma
and it's still active process and you take away the organ, then it will be an obstacle after treating?
-No. If the myoma was calcified and this calcification prevented certain functions of the body,
these functions you cannot recover. But if operated in the process of inflammation etc.
still your remedy can act and can
prevent a lot of things that would happen.
Let us take, not the uterus, because it's not so important, let's take the brain or the heart.
In the brain you have a tumor forming.
Then if you catch it at the process of forming, you can reduce it almost totally. If you catch a valve in the heart,
in the process of inflammation, you have an acute rheumatic fever and you have heart problems.
That means there is a valve which is inflammed and it's going to be destroyed. If you catch it during
the process of inflammation, you can cure it.
If you catch it after the inflammation is finished
and the damage is permanent, you
cannot anymore overcome this problem.
The heart will remain with
an impediment.
-So I can understand that as long
as a dynamic is going on is fine.
-No. As long as the body is alive, the dynamic process is going on in general
but in that particular point it has stopped.
All action has stopped. This is a dead part and we will see what it means in the emotional level.
A case is suffering from an undefined general weakness of the physical body. This can be an impediment.
You have a difficult case.
You have an impediment to cure.
Somebody comes and complains of lack of energy, the main problem is lack of energy.
That shows that there are several miasmatic blockages which do not allow the free flow
of the vital force and the vital force cannot produce an inflammation, produce a process.
It stays under heavy pressure the organism; it never feels free. These cases you can only palliate to a certain extent.
The patient will never say, I feel great. This,
I feel great you will never hear from such cases.
These cases are the Chronic Fatigue Syndrome cases. These are such that will not give you a picture of a remedy.
You try and try and you give this and that remedy, no effect and the fatigue stays.
It's very interesting that they call it
Chronic Fatigue Syndrome.
The patient says, I'm chronically
fatigued and the doctor says,
you have a Cronic Fatigue
Syndrome and everybody is happy.
Now I have a diagnosis but we can do nothing for you. But Homeopaths also many times we can do nothing, why?
Because due to the low energy we do not have a real symptomatology. The symptoms are undefined,
non specific and the general sense
of the patient is one of chronic fatigue.
Also this chronic fatigue syndrome is new, the last 20-30 years, a new disease. They did not know this disease,
it was not known 50-60 years ago and then with the introduction of antibiotics into the stream, that is why
CFS is a syndrome that we see ourselves, in the western world; they don't see that syndrome
in Africa, in South America very seldom.
Now that they are shifting the antibiotics and the cortisone and all the chemical drugs, now we're going to see such cases.
CFS is a syndrome of the western world and most probably, not exclusively, due to use of chemical drugs.
CFS I've also seen starting from using marihuana. She said, 'after that day in which I used a bigger amount
of marihuana, I started feeling this weakness and paralysis etc.'. It can also put a person in a wheel chair
together with the mental confusion and the
emotional indifference which produces.
We go now to blockages on the emotional level and the first blockage is what I have called, the husband syndrome.
It will go to the medical books very soon.
It is very interesting, also for me, that this
woman who has married a particular man
because they thought, this man is good for me not as a lover, not as a sexual partner
but as a husband, that means somebody who can protect me, somebody who can give me security,
who can give me prestige, position in
the society and all this taken together,
counteracts the fact that I am not
really interested in him, sexually.
If they make that compromise, they are going to develop that syndrome which is going to elude any Homeopath.
Any Homeopath will fall into the trap of giving remedy after remedy because the symptoms will be shifting
from one side to another, this, that, this, you get totally confused. These are the cases that will follow you
because they understand you are their only hope.
They are not sick enough to be diagnosed as diabetes, now you have to take antidiabetic drugs,
they are not diagnosed as heart problem or this or that. They are undefined what we usually call functional
or neurovegetative symptoms. Palpitations, headaches, dizziness, one day they cannot walk, she says
'I can't walk, what happened to me?', you give Piper methysticum. 'Ah, now I can walk but my headache'
'Where is your headache?', 'On the right side', you give Belladonna, whatever and then the left side starts...
I should have written down, maybe I sit down and write all the symptoms that can be produced
and finally you say how are
you doing with your husband?
Sometimes they will be even surprised with the question and they will deny it from the beginning.
I have a very good husband, they have persuaded themselves that their husband is the best in the world.
It's not that they really understand what is
going on. Their husband is the best!
'And how frequently you have sex?
'If I feel well, we can have'. 'How frequently you feel well, once the month, once the year?'
You get the story and the story is very clear every time. There is a transference of the aversion to the husband,
actually there is an aversion to sex. That's
all they hate, everything else they love.
They love to discuss, to go out with him, to go socially, no problem as long as this time
when you have to come in the bed and I have to do this, this is terrible and then the headache starts.
'Today don't talk to me' and the poor husband, almost invariably I have seen that the husband believes
this syndrome and believes that his wife is very ill and supports her all along. They don't force the woman.
But the woman says, 'I have to be well today, it's almost two months. Maybe he will go with another woman'
that's the idea that they may lose the husband by waiting too much, right? So they will force themselves
to do it and then again the symptoms will start.
And then there is a shifting of symptoms and you get crazy.
I have managed only very few cases to treat, at least two of my cases which I have battled for years,
ended up taking psychotropic drugs.
After treatment of 10-11 years, they
It was not possible to handle
the situation anymore.
The one of these cases I have discussed it with you, I think several times, where she was vomiting,
vomiting in one night because they had set the date of marriage. They have put a date of marriage
that they agreed finally, they said, in 3rd of June we marry. The same night the woman felt so sick that she was vomiting
constantly from the morning until 11 o'clock
when they telephoned me they said come,
we have to take her to hospital because she was vomiting constantly. I went there at 1 o'clock in the morning,
we finished with another doctor and we went there and what we found out? She was exhausted totally
and I gave one remedy, Ipecacuanha, I gave another, until 3 o'clock I had given 10 remedies, no effect.
I said, my God I have to go to sleep also. Tomorrow I have to start seeing cases from 8 o'clock in the morning,
what shall I do?
And then suddenly the idea came to my mind. Oh my God, they must have set the date of marriage.
I said to the husband and to her mother, she was in the room, can you please go out, I want to ask her something.
She was lying there exhausted, you won't believe, she was giving you the impression she was in coma,
I said, Louisiana did you arrange
the time of your marriage?
She opened her mouth, she said, yes.
For when?
For the 3rd of June, in one month. I said, do
you understand why you are in such a state?
In 5 minutes she was up, she said
to her mother, make me some soup.
She ate the soup and in half an
hour we left, next day she was fine.
But this case though she knew the
problem, she understood the problem,
she didn't want, the insecurity was
too much to leave the husband.
And she ended it up, I think 10 years later,
she ended up taking antidepressant drugs.
In spite of the fact they know the problem they are aware of the problem, they cannot overcome it
and it is so deep, and so it is such
an impediment
for your treatment.
You cannot imagine because their false symptomatology, you see the organism
out of the desire to escape, they will produce anything.
So what they produce is not a real symptom
of an organism who works properly,
it's an organism who works under
the pressure of the emotional level.
And then you battle and in the end most
probably you will lose the battle.
-Did you realize from experience that people
who have been under homeopathic treatment
found the strength to get out of such a relationship?
-It can happen both, either they get out or they get their problem fixed because it's not always
the problem of relationship. It's the problem of the person and if we have a Sepia case,
constitutional Sepia, with strong aversion,
how to manage? Under homeopathic treatment,
they can bring about a good relationship, especially if both are treated.
Usually in such cases there is a very good rapport on all matters except in this sexual sphere.
In the sexual sphere you need a discussion.
In Greek the sexual act is called genetic discussion, "genetissios omilia". Omilia is the discussion
because each one is expressing
himself to the other person.
And if this is acceptable, then we have a good match. If this is not acceptable, either you talk cacophony
or you talk nonsense or you talk irrelevant subjects, you have sex and you're thinking of 'I went to this nice shop
and I like this ring..', in the meantime you have sex. This is not a discussion, this is going away from the real discussion,
you're thinking of something else while you're having this relationship. In such a case there maybe pathology
and the person comes in contact with himself through Homeopathy and says, I like to have sex, finished.
Why to avoid it? She accepts she likes it. It is
not as simple as I say it because you will see
with this woman, usually they're not impotent.
I don't know if it is the right word.
-Frigid.
-They are not frigid because if they confess to you, they will confess that they like somebody else.
That means they are not frigid. But that does not mean if they go with somebody else, they will be able to function
because they may start all over again the same story. That's why they need to be treated.
In order to see whether after all, once I am more balanced, do I like my husband or I don't like him.
Take a decision after all.
But taking a decision when she is out of the Sepia state, out of the Phosphoric acid state,
out of the Natrum muriaticum state.
You see if she is on the Natrum muriaticum state fearing that she is going to be over dominated by the husband
or over riden by the force of the male, they resist. You give Natrum muriaticum, they open up, they enjoy.
But again what you see in such cases, relapses all the time because the old fashion comes back
and again comes the insecurity and again they close up and again they are hurt, 'oh my husband was so rough yesterday,
I don't want anymore to see him'. But they try again and again and then other symptomatology develops.
It is like an instinctive imagination
of the defense mechanism.
They imagine so many symptoms, you cannot anymore keep track of them, they're so much in variety.
Such cases are very very difficult to cure.
Next we're talking on the emotional level like deep emotional insecurities.
You see here also there is the responsibility with the mothers and parents who have certain fixed ideas
concerning man-woman relationship.
Do not ever lift your clothes in front of men, do not do that because you will become pregnant immediately.
Now the child fixes that in the mind, another child will go to the mirror, it will look at the mirror and say, I'm so ugly.
This creates such a deep insecurity, she comes to be treated and you prescribe remedies
and you cannot get to the depth of the issue.
Neither you can overcome this insecurity, 'I'm ugly therefore I cannot have a relationship'.
These cases are going to torment you. They are going to stick to their own fixed idea, 'I'm ugly'.
The same can be implanted upon a child, you're ugly, you look so terrible and she comes to you
with symptomatology and you
cannot get to the depth of the problem.
Especially such cases you will see with very religious families. They put into the heads of the children
that they are sinners if they look to another man, If they think of a man. This becomes a fixed idea to the child
and the child cannot have a relationship anymore and from that point onwards depending on how many points
is sick in general, then you will have an impediment.
Even with people who are not very sick in general but because the sickness is all on the mental,
it's like putting a stone in the brain a callus in the brain which does not move with anything. You give a remedy,
you give another remedy, you discuss, the idea is fixed, it cannot get out, then you are going to have a problem.
You can go so far with such cases,
you cannot go further.
Another obstacle we have can be the inescapable family situation, a situation you cannot run away from.
A tragedy happens within a family, it is a tragedy which is inescapable, it is like karmic,
it is there and it is going to stay the rest of the life, like having a retarded child, an autistic child.
This is a situation where nobody
can get away from.
In certain cases this affects the organism in such a way, the grief is so deep, that cannot get out.
Not all people who have retarded children are in that condition.
On the contrary I would say some people who have retarded children, they are very much attached to them,
giving a lot of love and in spite of the fact they are very tired in looking after them, they are still very happy.
They have no problem. But there are some others who feel it as a karmic stigma in their family.
Such cases you will have an impediment and you can treat these people and you can reach them
up to a certain extend, no further.
You will never make these people feel joy, you will never make them feel I have another level of health.
They will come for their otitis, you treat, they're better, they will come for their lumbagos, they are treated,
the lumbago is better there is no problem
but the level remains the same.
-Would you say this inescapable family situation would also be the result when both parents are working
and the child does not have any full time relationship with the parents? The parents have enough time to
wake up the child in the morning, put it to bed at night, both parents work throughout the week and on the weekend
the parents want go and have fun, so they leave the child with another baby sitter, so the child has no relationship
with their parents, as if they're an orphan. Would you say that is another inescapable situation?
-I would say this situation is escapable, not inescapable because if you explain to them this is the problem
with the child they may change their attitude,
I say in situations where it is really karmic.
The situation is there and nobody can change it.
This creates a kind of deep grief, deep pain which is beyond the possibility to go over it.
Sinful habits.
What they call, themselves, understand
as sinful behavior?
It may not be sinful for the general
public but for them it is sinful.
Therefore they will stay with this idea inside them.
'I'm doing something wrong and I cannot overcome it and this, this is wrong and I cannot overcome it',
This is not taken away by the remedy easily neither creates a situation where you will have a clear picture.
It is like having underneath the surface, a fixed condition, like the layers are like this and there is a layer which is like this.
Much more strong, this is a background
situation for the individual where he feels
'I'm doing that' but he doesn't tell anybody.
The individual feels 'I have this sinful situation
I'm a bad boy or a girl', this will create resistence to the treatment and you will treat and the result will come back
as constant relapse or constant changing of remedies.
-Can it be an imaginary sin?
-Yes, imaginary but based on something which has been exaggerated by imagination and it has been exaggerated
it so much so to create this underlying,
deep, thick layer which cannot be moved.