I have been asked to speak about certain topics,
one of which is for experienced practitioners.
And to underline the difficulties that exist in homeopathic prescribing
and blockages that may exist during homeopathic prescribing.
Before going into that subject I would like to discuss a little bit the origination of symptoms.
How symptoms are originated.
I do this because in my lectures on Materia Medica I'm going to discuss
about the different levels of symptomatology in the human body,
which is the mental level, the emotional level and also the physical level.
We see a symptomatology arising in all three levels, especially with people of today.
People of today seem to have a symptomatology, which is mostly on mental-emotional levels
and not so much on physical levels, as it used to be in older times.
So the symptomatology that we see today arises from stresses on different levels.
Apart from the symptomatology that arises from specific agents like viruses,
microbes, bacteria etc. that they may attack the human body
and the human body can react apart from these stresses,
we have symptomatology arising from conflicts, which are on 3 main areas.
The main area that is it is stressed, when it is conflict, it's the area of self-preservation.
When the instinct of self-preservation is in danger, then we have a symptomatology,
which may appear in all three levels.
What do I mean by self-preservation? I mean mostly...
What preserves life? Food. When people cannot get food,
food in its more wide sense, then this instinct is in conflict, it's in stress.
You don't need examples.
Somebody is very poor, he is living in a very stressed situation, cannot find a job,
cannot find a way to support himself or his family
and eventually he will come down with heart problem, with stomach problem
or with a skin eruption. The second area is when there is conflict in the space we live.
We need our space and if we lose that, we may have a conflict
and out of this conflict a symptomatology may arise.
That means I lose my house, I do not have a space to live on,
I lose my possibility to have a space, to pay a rent and to have a space,
this can be a stressful factor that can again produce symptomatology.
And the third possibility is losing the possibility of survival on a continuous level.
That means losing the children that in a way will further our existence into the future.
Losing the children or losing conditions under which this continuation will take place
can create a great conflict.
In general this conflict is very strong when there is a possibility of death,
a possibility of the physical body being killed.
The second area from which symptomatology can arise is the sexual sphere.
The sex life with all that it contains.
I will not go into many details, I will just say a few things.
What is sex need and when there is conflict in that area, then you have problems?
What is the need? To have sex is not to have sex actually.
The deeper need is to give yourself and be accepted.
To unite, as an idea, with another individual.
This is the deeper need to unite and be accepted, to lose your identity,
to lose your self-awareness, with all the repercussions that exist in this level.
What we see today as diseases are frustrations on these levels we are talking about.
Symptomatology is arising through frustration on this level
with all the emotional repercussions that we have concerning this issue.
The third level of frustration, when we have frustration on conflict, is what?
There is a third area from which frustration really rises?
Can anybody tell me because the other two are quite well known.
The spiritual question, the spiritual conflict, the spiritual frustration.
What we have here as an idea behind that, the need of the man to unite with the cosmos.
The individual is not anymore satisfied with the unification of an individual
with another individual, man with woman etc.
You know what I mean by etc.
It's not that enough. Frustration is too much.
People don't feel satisfied, there is something else, something else.
What is this something else? That something else will drive them
eventually to a search to find out what is beyond that physical world
and what is beyond what we call god, the divine, the cosmos, the super intelligence.
Whatever it is that for everyone makes sense.
In this area we have frustrations again, frustrations arising,
diseases arising from frustration in this area where man needs to be united with the cosmos.
In the beginning man is very simple.
He needs to be united with the environment, the nature.
This is the unification with nature, self-preservation.
The primitive man must have thought that this nature is my own, it is my house,
there is no threat and then the man came to take his land and frustration...
We have to see now humanity progressing through these eras
where frustration was very much on physical level on self-preservation instinct,
my space, my food, my children and man tries to solve these problems
and to give solutions to these problems.
He says democracy, people must have the same rights, they must equals.
They found solutions on these problems and then the era of sex came...
I mean the era of a deeper need now of an individual to have a satisfying union,
satisfying communication with another person, the era of love.
Men most probably didn't know anything about love before.
They did not understand, it was on a very animalistic level.
There come cries with the idea of love and then people take that idea
and they start thinking about love and about your neighbor etc.
As the human beings are progressing in time we see more frustration
on this level as well. More frustration, more diseases.
What kind of diseases? More complicated.
More we have the frustrations that came upon misusing all what we had conquered.
We have conquered the idea that we have the right to have a house
and then we want a second, a third, a fifth, 20 houses.
There is something unhealthy there.
Then we conquered the idea that we want to have a sexual partner and we have a second,
a fourth, a fifth, 25, 250... Why not to have experiences.
We are going to pay for all that and we are paying already.
I don't want to frighten you but I have some very frightening ideas
concerning different diseases that are going to appear.
I was lecturing on those topics in Greece 15 years and I was telling
that humanity was going on under the bombardment of antibiotics and chemical drugs
to stimulate and to counteract diseases, especially the venereal diseases
which exploded because of promiscuity we are going to have a new type of diseases very soon
that will be so virulent that nobody will be able to treat.
Now we have come to these ideas and nobody knows why.
But for me it is very plain and I hope I will be wrong.
That by bombarding the human body with antibiotics and all strong remedies
we are producing a defective immune system that can receive now,
it can develop a lot of new diseases which are very virulent.
I believe soon we will be finding out that AIDS is the main disease, let us say,
that came upon the conflict on the sexual level, on sexual frustration.
It's a venereal disease transmitted through sexual act
but it will come to those who are bombarded with antibiotics for 1,2,3 5 years.
What we see in the homosexuals, it's not the homosexuals.
It's all the people who have repeatedly taken venereal diseases
and they have treated these venereal diseases with antibiotics and penicillin.
It is these people actually, never mind who takes syphilis five times.
In Tahiti syphilis was very prevalent and this is very well know.
People have taken a lot of antibiotics there.
Of course anybody who takes antibiotics for a year, two years constantly...
What we see in the AIDS patients is a history of 2 syphilis, 5 gonorrheas
or 4 syphilis, 6 gonorrheas or 3 gonorrheas, 4 syphillis.
That requires constant antibiotics.
The immune system is totally bombarded.
This is the appearance of the disease on a conflict on sexual level.
Man actually seeks unity because he is afraid by himself, he is so much afraid.
And women also, it's not men only. I see men and I see the women laughing.
Seeking unity is the idea in spiritual frustration and conflict.
What do you want really? Do you want a spiritual (?)
Are you going for the experience of a spiritual 'kick', what they call
or are you searching sincerely to find out the truth?
These are basics questions.
Do you really want just a home to stay or you are like Onassis,
one ship, two ships, 25, 35...where do you stop?
You conquered the whole world, all the ships of the world to belong to you to do what?
A friend of his told me that when he was dying he had 75 doctors
from all over the world in Paris around him.
But he still died and perhaps quicker than somebody who would have only one doctor.
Because 75 doctors are 75 opinions, you can understand.
One says take the kidney out, no, no the other one says take the liver out.
I believe he had several operations except from his bladder that was taken initially out.
Several operations at a row, then of course you die.
I want to give you now the idea of where we stand.
What as healers we are going to achieve.
What is the problem? Realizing, facing the real problem and then say now how shall I proceed,
what shall I do?
Before go further I may also say that as the two other conflicts,
that means self-preservation and sexual, are minimized in us, the more they are minimized,
the more they become vital for us the more the spiritual conflict arises.
That means an individual has to overcome his insecurities, anxieties and quite a lot in order
to go into the other conflict, the third conflict which is the spiritual.
He has overcome certain things, he says I'm not interested about having a fleet,
I'm not interested about having 20 houses, this is stupid, I don't want that.
What do I want? Sex. He has sex and he says eventually I'm not interested in that.
I had enough, 250 cases it's too much. I had enough.
I still need this feeling of fulfillment which is not there, the feeling
that I belong somewhere in the cosmos and then he goes into spiritual search.
So today we are faced with a crisis, which is mostly on a spiritual level.
When I see people where almost every one of them is on this frustration level,
the spiritual level, I'm really amazed that the world has gone so fast in the last 20 years.
Here we are to treat and to say OK, what is your problem?
He comes there with his problem and he says what is the remedy
that will give him back everything?
He expects from the homeopathic remedy to have a complete balance of that individual.
Do we expect also to solve the conflicts which were responsible for bringing
that individual into that state?
Do we expect to do that and to what extend?
These are questions that have tormented my mind for many years
and I would like to give you my ideas, my thinking about it.
You know that we have the Organon of Medicine written by Hahnemann?
Sometimes people are practicing Homeopathy without even knowing the existence of that book.
In paragraph 252 and 255 there are some hints and note 140...
there are some hints of what I'm going to talk.
I like to be as clear as possible, as concise as possible.
That's why I would like to give you before going into blockages an idea of what I think
we are doing when we are treating a human being.
From that point of view a human being is something which is there,
which exists and which is the deepest, the most real desires.
What is a human being? It's his most deep desires.
That is what he is, that is what he wants to attain.
What is the deepest in him, the deepest being, the deepest existence, the deepest desire,
that is what he is.
The question arises by homeopathic treatment can we change that? No.
Disease changes that?
No but what disease changes then?
A person that was very bright and he had a lot of possibilities in developing a life
and then he goes into drugs...I know something about drugs here in Holland.
He goes into drugs and then this fine mind starts to become dull.
Why he has a fine mind, why he has fine tools to work with?
He was going to attain certain things in life.
What happened by going into drugs?
When I say drugs I do not mean only the hallucinogenic drugs,
I mean the whole industry, official and non-official.
There is an official industry as well, which is the Valium, the Tavor, the barbiturates etc.
This is the official industry, prescription drugs and then there is an unofficial industry.
I don't know which of the two are bringing more money but then there is there.
And then you are injecting in the human body all these drugs.
As a result this mind that was going to attain whatever he was going to attain, it is destroyed.
This is the deepest part of man which cannot be changed.
That deepest part now it's going to be expressed through a harmonious kind of expression -
I don't know how harmonious is...
I've broken my elbow a few months ago.
This was going to be a harmonious expression of what it was there.
He had the means to express and the means were his qualities in mental level.
He had logic, logical mind, he had discriminative mind,
he had the ability of abstract thinking, he had the ability to classify correctly,
he had the ability to analyze, all these positive qualities of that human being
that was expressing himself in this way.
What disease does is that match, affects these abilities to his no longer able to express
in a harmonious and creative way that that was existing in him.
That means he will never be able to attain the highest purposes of his existence.
This is paragraph 16 in the Organon, 11 or 16.
What disease does is to affect these qualities and take them mostly to the negative side.
Between complete logic, total logic and total insanity there are grades.
So disease will take these means of logic towards its opposite, its negative quality.
From somebody who had discrimination, he will have now no discrimination at all.
Where he was able to have abstract thinking,
which is the highest kind of function of the human mind, now his thinking becomes dull,
there is no reflection and there is no ability to abstract thinking.
He was able to classify things, now things are coming in a mixed way.
He was able to analyze, he is not able to analyze anymore.
That is what disease does.
What we see finally in disease, expression of that individual is very confusing
but the inside of the human being is intact.
Now what happens is that he will not be able to really attain
what his innermost being wanted to attain.
And he comes to us to be treated and our work is to take away these confusions
that disease has imprinted upon him on the means, on his tools for evolvement.
We must take away these confusions and let the most inner self express itself
in the best possible way.
This is what we have to do when a person presents himself into us
and says I used to think quite clearly and I cannot. I calculated and I cannot calculate.
You are all familiar with the idea that there are 3 levels
and also the idea that those 3 levels are connected with the defense mechanism here.
That is the mental-spiritual level, this is the psychic level or emotional level
and this is the physical level.
Every stress will be taken by the defense mechanism
and the defense mechanism will decide what will do, either he will present symptoms
on the mental level or he may present symptoms on the emotional level or on the physical level
or on all 3 levels.
Actually what is going on is always in that background
where the defense mechanism decides at all moments what he will do under stress.
When we're dealing with an individual we take always in consideration
what is on the mental level, what is on his emotional level, what is on the physical level.
On the mental-spiritual level what we see is that from positive qualities,
the individual goes to negative qualities.
The same on the emotional level.
Disease will take positive qualities to negative qualities.
Trust is a positive quality, mistrust...
Joy, depression, sadness...
Calmness, irritability, anger...
This is where diseases are taking the individual towards its negative side
and when we study the Materia Medica we have to study what a remedy can do on spiritual-mental
and psychic-emotional and on physical level as well, in order to have a science
which is really complete.
We cannot be talking about Homeopathy and give remedies only for the physical level.
If we want really to have an effect with the homeopathic remedy,
we have to take into consideration all the disturbances that exist under conflicts
and frustrations on that individual on all 3 levels and find that remedy
which has produced similar disturbances on all 3 levels.
That's why when I'm lecturing on the Materia Medica,
I'm lecturing in a 3-dimensional way.
We cannot anymore afford what the old masters sometimes did, the 6X, 12X on the physical body.
By this time all these frustrations were not so intense, as they are today
and especially on spiritual level, which creates mentalities that are quite different today
that what it was 100 years ago.
It's interesting perhaps for you to give you a little bit of information
what is going on in Greece concerning Homeopathy at the moment.
Just to show perhaps that Classical Homeopathy, the way the every medical doctor
who is in Greece is practicing, it is a very practical thing, it's not an idealistic situation.
I introduced Homeopathy in Greece on 1967.
On 1967 there was no a homeopath in Greece at all.
In 1985 that was about one month ago, the Minister of Health in Greece
sent a letter to the Hellenic Homeopathic Association asking them to propose ways
that the homeopathic doctors wanted to work on the National Service.
That means paid by the government to serve people homeopathically
and that is purely because of the results and the prestige that Homeopathy enjoys in Greece
at this moment. For no other reason.
I don't believe that the government in Greece is more enlightened
than any other government in Europe.
But they have been seen results and also the medical establishment of Greece
has a great kind of esteem for homeopathy.
That is within 18 years what was attained through purely Classical Homeopathy.
In other countries, let's take France where Homeopathy is very widely spread.
There they are practicing a kind of Homeopathy, which is mixopathy, that means mixtures.
It is a kind of Homeopathy but there is no prestige in France for Homeopathy,
the government is not interested.
They are making enquiries what is this mixture that you say it's good for rhinitis?
You have to prove that it is good for rhinitis or for bronchitis.
What I'm talking to you is not spiritual idealistic kind of ideas,
they are very practical ideas that have very practical application.
Of course today I'm going to talk about blockages, that means excuses we have...
I'm going to give you a lot of excuses today that you may have
and give your patients if your treatment fails.
I gave this lecture in Norway, a few days ago and somebody said that's very good lecture,
I liked it very much because from now I shall have a good excuse
why my treatment has failed.
Going in the same idea of 3 levels, we shall be talking about blockages
that can exist in all 3 levels, starting with the physical level.
What is that which maybe blocking a homeopathic treatment on a physical level.
That means you give the remedy, which is correct and yet it does not work
or does not deliver fully the effects that you are expecting too.
Before I go on with the excuses I have to give a percentage of cases
that may be coming under all these groups of cases.
The percentage should not be more than  between 7-10% of your cases
that may fall under these groups.
On the physical what can be blocking the effect of a homeopathic remedy.
Of the correct homeopathic remedy, not just a remedy.
You have given the right remedy and it does not act.
I will give you an example first.
What may happen is that you have a case with severe, very severe sciatic pains
which are constant and which are tremendously intense.
The person does not find any position that relieves him.
If you take his reflexes you will see some effect on the reflexes,
you will some effect on the sensors, his sensation of the foot are not perfect.
You take the picture and you give a remedy.
This is the picture of Colocynthis because he has to go up and down, he has his pains etc.
You give Colocynthis 1M and it seems to work for 10 min or 15 min,
a little bit better the pains for 1 hr and then back the pains.
I made a mistake, that was not a Colocynthis, this is a Kali Iodinum case.
You give Kali Iodinum and you see some kind of effect perhaps
and then you go from one remedy to the other and no remedy will hold. Why?
Because we have a slip disc in between the vertebrae.
There is a disc that breaks sometimes and makes a hernia.
That comes out and presses one of the roots of the nerves constantly.
It's a mechanical pressure upon the roots of the nerves that will not allow
any kind of relief neither your remedy is going to work.
Or a big dislocation of a vertebrae, it's mechanical.
What you have to do? In the first instance you will have to know Medicine,
to know how to recognize such a state, then you have to put your patient into bed,
complete immobility.
He must not get up because the minute he gets up the pressure on the vertebrae
makes this hernia bigger and if he walks up and down makes the pain worse.
So you have to know that this is a mechanical pressure upon the nerve
that has to have other treatment as well.
In a case of hernia with the slip disc, you have to put your patient into bed
without moving at all, not to have pressure.
In a case of a big dislocation on another part of the vertebrae,
then you may have to apply other measures apart Homeopathy,
before the homeopathic remedy can affect the case.
If the dislocation is great, there are people who are dealing with the vertebrae.
They call themselves osteopaths in America or chiropractors in Europe.
They deal with these issues and maybe you will be needing a physiotherapist or chiropractor
or osteopath to deal with that problem.
So giving one remedy after the other will not help in such a case.
You are dealing with a case- I remember in India in the hospital where I was,
I remember a severe case of typhus, last stages.
They have been prescribing different remedies but at a certain moment
you touch the pulse of the person and you see the pulse going.... You can't count.
And the heart is pumping so fast, why?
Because there is a perforation, there is a breach in the colon and the blood is coming out.
Finished, you have to apply surgical measures.
The same thing may apply to some surgical cases where you have a kind of tumor
that presses and creates symptomatology.
That mechanical pressure can create symptomatology but maybe the tumor has to be removed.
Of course there is a case where a tumor can be minimized or even treated
and cured through Homeopathy.
I'm not talking about these cases where sometimes are very impressive.
Especially the women develop in the ovaries cysts
which they can become very great creating a lot of symptomatology.
And this cyst can be treated with Homeopathy and can be reduced.
But you have to know what you are treating
and whether the symptoms are from a tumor that cannot be removed or cannot be treated.
It's interesting also that if you are dealing with Homeopathy really,
if you are really caring about the disturbances in the human body,
you will reach a point where you will be able to diagnose better
than if you did not have the knowledge of Homeopathy.
Homeopathy gives you the possibility to be a very good diagnostician
but you have to have the background to become that.
I'll just give you an example, a very interesting example.
A woman was bringing her spastic child we were treating.
I knew the woman, she had come many time with the child to be treated.
One day I saw this woman and I say what is wrong with you, there is something wrong.
She says yes but I've been examined by different doctors and they say that nothing is wrong.
But I see you are in very bad condition.
She says yes I have some fever and I have different symptomatology.
What are the symptoms you have?
She says I have a pain here, going back, all around my waist and extending to my thigh...
I said this is an inflammation on the right kidney, it must be a cyst inflamed
and you have to be examined it quickly. Go to the gynecologist and find out.
She went to the gynecologist and he hospitalized her immediately and operated her.
She had been to several doctors and they said nothing is wrong with you.
The pain is because you are nervous and because your child is problematic.
It's a spastic child, that's why you bring up this fever.
So Homeopathy gives her the possibility to be diagnosed better
than if she just had an allopathic knowledge.
So in case you have a mechanical dislocation, you have to deal with that
and then give again the indicated homeopathic remedy.
Another condition which can block homeopathic treatment
it is an ingested chemical on a regular basis.
Here what do we have?
For instance somebody who drinks coffee regularly, three cups the day,
you give homeopathic treatment.
It may act for some time but not for long.
The chemical which is ingested, the caffeine will bring about a relapse
within a period of one month, two months, three months depending of the strength
of the individual.
The person who takes drugs, any kind of drugs official or unofficial, you cannot treat...
I'm sorry, you cannot treat individuals who are taking hashish or hallucinogenic drugs.
Your remedy may act for a short period of time but the relapse is absolutely sure.
Forget the possibility that you will say OK take this remedy and keep on with your hashish,
or LSD, or heroin and cocaine-I'm not even talking about that- these hard drugs.
I'm talking about the milder drugs that we intellectualize and say no,
this is not a habit for me, this is not, that is not...
These drugs are quite habit forming and quite dangerous for the system
and you will see the effect. Why?
Because the moment that you give a homeopathic remedy, if it is the right one,
what it does is to bring the organism into a state of balance.
Do you understand what that is? Balance.
It is somebody who is walking on the street and keeping the balance,
neither to the left nor to the right.
If he takes drugs this person may fall down and he will stay in the ground.
Never mind how many drugs you give, after he is in the ground, it does not matter.
This is the idea. But once he is balancing there, going into a sensitive balance state,
a little bit of chemical drugs may over take him.
And then he falls back into his sleeplessness, his sciaticas, his stomach pains etc.
Once he is in that state again, it does not matter whether he drinks one coffee
or five coffees. That chronic state of his will remain.
But once he is coming on a sensitive balance, then you have to be careful.
I remember one case with Natrum Muriaticum I have given in an intercostal neuralgia.
That was coming on a student that he was having students of mathematics in India.
He was having this attack usually when he was in the class between 10 and 12 o'clock.
Severe pain, intercostal neuralgia on the left side,
which is one of the main remedies Natrum Muriaticum together with...?
Which is the other remedy that has intercostal neuralgias mostly on the left side?
There is a remedy which looks like Rhus tox.
Ranunculus Bulbosus. So Nat Mur and Ranun Bullb are specific.
If you want to treat intercostal neuralgia, always you give...
It won't work always, only sometimes.
This boy had Natrum Muriaticum 1M.
He did well for a few days and then suddenly the condition was back.
He had an aggravation in the beginning, then well for a few days, then back.
That's very strange. Do you do something? Do you drink coffee? Nothing.
I give again Nat Mur 1M, better for a few days, then the situation was back.
So I went again to the enquiring list, what are you doing, what are your blockages,
with what you are blocking the treatment? You are doing something.
I was absolutely sure. I couldn't find nothing except from one thing.
He was washing his teeth with a menthol toothpaste.
So I said OK stop this and take for the third time Natrum Muriaticum 1M.
The boy was cured.
From that day onwards we don't allow menthol in Natrum Muriaticum cases especially.
And you must be careful with toothpaste that have menthol,
you have to be careful with Nat Mur cases.
Another group is certain cases that have been...
A chemical that they took many years ago has implanted the miasmatic kind of condition
upon the organism and now before that is antidote the treatment cannot be effective.
What do I mean?
A person who has taken for instance a lot of streptomycin or a lot of penicillin
at a certain point and from that point onwards it starts a kind of disturbance.
You treat the case and you think this is a Sulphur case.
You give Sulphur, it does not work, you give Arsenicum, you give Calcarea,
you give all these remedies, they do not work until you give a Penicillin 200
or 30 to antidote the effect of Penicillin that was there 20 years ago.
Then this Penicillin opens up the case, the symptoms become cleared,
sometimes are reduced in intensity as well and then the next remedy Sulphur again
is given and it acts.
So we have a possibility of a kind of disease of a chemical imprinting
its own picture upon the person.
I'll give another example. A case of asthma.
Severe asthma, you treat it very carefully, no effect with any remedy.
Then the person says I have this asthma since that flu.
We gave a dose of Influenzinum, the virus of flu, different viruses together in a remedy
which is called Influenzinum, we gave 200 and from that moment onwards
there was an improvement and eventually a cure.
Another group on the physical level, what can be?
Permanent damages on a certain organ that cannot be corrected further.
I will give you an example.
In the Down's children, the Mongolic children, we do not have a possibility of a cure.
We do not have a possibility to bring these children into health back.
There is a permanent damage.
Any permanent damage on an organ will prevent the cure to be complete.
You will have an amelioration but not a cure. I will take different diseases.
For instance multiple sclerosis.
In multiple sclerosis you will have the plaques forming and these are permanent distruction
on the nerves that cannot be replaced.
So when the inflammation takes place in the beginning, that you can correct.
The homeopathic remedy will take away the inflammation
and also the disturbance of the disease and you may have a complete cure
if you get a multiple sclerosis case within 6 months
or within a year from the moment it started.
Multiple sclerosis is an up and down disease.
It appears with certain symptomatology and then it appears to be better
and then again more symptomatology and as year by year progresses,
then you see more and more permanent paralysis.
After a few years, 5, 6 years you see the permanent paralysis
which is establishing itself in the body, then you cannot anymore treat these cases.
Don't struggle to treat cases of multiple sclerosis of 6, 7, 10 years long.
What you will do? There is an effect yes. What is the effect?
During the inflammation there is an edema, because of the inflammation there is an edema.
Because of the edema, there is pressure on the nerves
and there are symptoms of paralysis quite strong.
These symptoms will be reduced but whatever has happened up to the 6 years
when the plaques have formed and the nervous cells are dead, then you cannot replace them.
There is a permanent damage on a particular organ.
Another example.
You are treating rheumatoid arthritis of 15 years standing.
And you see the arthrosis have become deformed, they are still inflamed
and the inflammations are going on from one arthrose to the other.
That damage which has produced the deformity of the arthrosis, you do not expect to be reversed.
It is not going to be reversing.
What you can expect is to treat the inflammation and the disturbance
and to stop the disease up to a certain point, yes.
And take the symptoms of the inflammation away, yes.
And have the positive RA test (Rheumatoid Arthrites test) with very positive (three crosses)
You may have it to 1.
You have the sedimentation rate which is characteristic of that disease from being very high,
coming down.
In the beginning actually of that disease you may see the sedimentation rate shooting up.
While the pains are going down, the sedimentation rate may go up in the first months.
Then you see it comes down.
So the inflammation can go down, the positive ra-test can go down
but the deformities that have been formed all these years in the arthrosis will remain.
Retarded children, you will have very little space to work with.
There is a kind of improvement but not the total improvement that we may expect.
In cases of arteriosclerosis, very progressed arteriosclerosis,
you do not expect to clear up the system and bring back the elasticity
on the vascular system.
To expect things like that from Homeopathy is to have the wrong expectations.
I can give you more... Vitiligo. You know vitiligo?
There is a dyschromia, the melanin goes away from the skin and becomes white.
These are permanent changes which unless you catch them within  the first 6 months...
I've seen vitiligo to be treated and cured within the first 6 months in children especially,
totally cured and in growns-ups also. But as soon as it starts.
Give it a time and then it spreads and while it spreads, you can do nothing.
You can only arrest it, not cured it.
It is good for the homeopathic practitioner to know these things.
To be able to give the right information to the patient.
You will say yes I can arrest, I can help you with the pains
but I cannot reverse the deformities that took place.
And then you have another group of cases where they come with a general weakness,
undefined general weakness of the physical body.
Great weakness of the physical body without much symptomatology
will indicate a weak defense mechanism that is not producing symptoms,
it is not giving you out symptoms to guide you as to the right remedy.
So what you see is weakness, weakness, weakness...
These cases can also be produced by a lot of wrong homeopathic treatment.
By giving too many remedies for too long periods of time.
Finally instead of improving your patient, you leave your patient
with a kind of general total weakness that he complains all the time.
He will say I used to have some pains but now I don't have.
But now I'm more weak.
That means that the disease now is on a deeper level and it's very difficult to treat such cases.
These are more or less the groups of people that you will find difficulty in treating.
Now what you will do with these last group of cases.
You have to be very careful.
If this group comes as a result of homeopathic treatment,
I saw many such cases in Europe 20 years ago.
In 1965 I was in Europe treating some people there
and I saw cases treated by French homeopaths.
They came to me with prescriptions of 50 drugs taken for the last 2-3 years every day.
It just leaves them in a state of weakness that no other symptom
is available for you to prescribe.
In these cases the best thing is not to prescribe and to take away the prescriptions.
Take away the homeopathic prescriptions, not to prescribe and wait if they have the time.
Now these people if they have to wait, they will start having pains and discomforts etc.
Then you have to wait long enough as to see clearly what is the next indicated remedy.
If this person complains about weakness but he has not taken homeopathic drugs,
usually the case will be by taking with some allopathic drugs.
It has come to that state of weakness.
He takes some pain killers, he takes some laxatives, he takes something for his heart,
he takes something for his blood pressure and by taking all these drugs leaves him
in a state of weakness.
I wanted to speak about the defense mechanism a little bit, how I understand it.
The defense mechanism is what we have,
the most valuable thing we have within our bodies.
The defense mechanism will tell me walk!
I have to satisfy that. Otherwise I'm going to have a stiffness in my neck.
Then you have to do this.
Your defense says do this. This is good defense.
The defense will say wait, don't move because the sciatic nerve is affected.
Don't move, don't move and you don't move.
This is good defense.
What you do is just sit slowly, you sit there, ah it is relieved.
Sitting relieves, then you have symptoms, you develop symptoms, you give out symptoms.
Your defenses are in good condition.
You have very little of inflammation on your toe, you may not be able to move.
Good defense.
Your defense also can produce much stronger symptoms
which maybe they don't look so good but still is to protect you.
But if you damage this defense system, then you will have no symptoms at all
except of one and that will be weakness.
This is what we get in AIDS today.
That is why it is very difficult to treat AIDS people because what they will say weak, weak...
their defenses have been broken down completely by bombardment of the drugs
and they don't give out symptomatology.
That's why AIDS cases are going to be very...
This is the group where AIDS comes, weakness.
You will see the main symptom, weakness. What else? Nothing else.
I took a case last year in America and my students in America
have dealt with certain of these cases so far.
Everyone has no symptomatology, the only thing is weakness, tremendous weakness.
They feel weak but the defense mechanism does not produce symptoms.
They don't suffer, they just feel weak and more weak and they die.
All they produce is an inflammation which is a kind of pneumonia which takes them away.
The defenses are not able to cope with this situation.
We are going to be facing with such cases of that group more and more
and these are one of the worst type of group that we'd like to see in homeopathic practice.
I don't care if somebody is coming with excessively dangerous symptomatology.
I wouldn't mind to treat that case and to show results and to show effect.
A person who is collapsing, who is in a coma, he still has symptoms.
A person with weakness, no symptoms.
Such cases are going to be very difficult to cure.
This is the worst group from the physical blockages and this is the group
that I believe AIDS belongs.
In spite of the fact Homeopathy I believe, in spite of all that Homeopathy
will be the best way of treating AIDS because Homeopathy does exactly
what these people need.
Stimulates the immune system, the defense system.
Homeopathy does exactly what these people need.
And I believe that we can have with Homeopathy a result of 30-40% of these cases.
These cases are going now all to death.
Now we have stages. They classified all these people, stage 1, stage 2, stage 3.
The stage 3 they die, all of them.
From these people I believe a percentage of 30% may be saved for quite some years
with of Homeopathy. Because Homeopathy helps the immune system to recover.