-So the next stage we go into blockages on emotional level.
Here we have, as a first group, we have a group of symptoms
which I call I've given a name to that group, it's not known to allopathic Medicine
but I believe it may become a group of sick people in Psychiatry,
I call them "the husband syndrome".
Usually these patients are women. I've not seen yet a man with the situation
I'm going to relate to you, the husband syndrome. What is that syndrome? What happens?
Can you tell me? Every woman I see here, they say, I know.
The husband is responsible, not me!
The husband syndrome when a woman has married a man not because she loves him
but because she feels with him a kind of security.
The woman feels he is a good husband, not a boyfriend, he is a good husband.
She calculates the pros and cons and she says I don't feel attracted
but I think he's a good case.
I must not lose that case.
These thoughts are kind of breaking ... the laws of nature, a woman is attracted to a man
and a man is attracted to a woman. The man does not have the possibility to pretend
that he likes the woman, for physical reasons, on sexual relationship the man can not pretend;
either he likes a woman, he wants to have sexual intercourse with a woman or he doesn't.
He can not do otherwise.
I do not like that woman but still I can have sexual intercourse with her.
He is impotent. The woman is not in that condition. The woman can pretend.
Therefore they're thinking OK, sex is not a big deal with me, I can pretend.
You can pretend in sex but in a woman that functions are natural still,
that means she will need the outlet of the sexual climax and she does not have that,
she will not have that, she will not have an orgasm because she is not excited,
she is not chemically attracted to this husband.
What happens to such a woman?
There is no outlet and at the same time this woman must be a kind of moralist;
that means a woman who says I can not go with another man.
So she does not have the outlet of an extramarital affair outside of her marriage
she does not have the possibility to have that and that builds a pressure in her
eventually so big that what she does is, she develops a kind of symptomatology
which is not typical.
I can not tell you now this is the symptomatology, when you see it, that's the husband syndrome,
you be careful. I can not tell you that and I will tell you why.
You treat these cases because they come with chronic headaches.
You say, since when? Since 10 years.
And you give the right remedy and then she comes after 2-3 months, maybe I'm better in that,
not even saying I'm better but she will not mention anymore the headaches
but what now is important is the heart, the palpitation and I feel dyspnea
and everything is in the heart. What about the headaches?
Yes the headaches are there but these aches are now. Are they so strong as they used to be?
Not so strong but this is now, the dyspnea.
And you say, what have I done here? Have I given a close remedy, have I given the wrong remedy,
the right remedy and then you search for another remedy and you prescribe in such a case
and what happens after a few months she comes back with another set of symptoms.
Every time there is another set of symptoms almost, why?
Because she must be sick, why? Because she must have an excuse
not to have sex with her husband.
That is the only way she can get away from a situation which is very adverse to her.
So she will say today I have a headache and she makes a whole scene.
She is so sick and the husband says, forget it.
How do you recognize such cases? You can not recognize them from the beginning
as I said. You will recognize them after you fail again and again
and after you've seen the symptomatology changing all the time,
from one symptomatology to the other.
This situation you may discuss it with your patient and she will tell you eventually.
You put a direct question. I remember a case when I was called to treat a case
of that type at 12 o'clock in the night.
And we went together with a psychiatrist, we went together to see the case.
Vomiting all the time, we arrived at 1 o'clock in the house.
She was vomiting, exhausted completely and she was hospitalized.
She was completely exhausted from vomiting, dehydrated, the heart was very weak
she was almost collapsing, no blood pressure, very weak in general, a frightening situation,
not knowing what to do.
And I gave, I don't remember the remedies, I gave one remedy, Ipecacuanha,
I don't remember what it was, nothing and then another remedy, nothing and then another one
nothing and we were there, it was about 3 o'clock in the morning.
But knowing more or less the situation and how she felt about her husband,
intuitively I had an idea.
She was not married yet. She found a husband, he was very good
and she was developing these symptoms.
But when she had this severe symptomatology she was going to be married,
they were going to be married, they were engaged for 3-4 years.
Then when this reaction happened what I thought was that most probably
she had fixed the date of marriage and that was final and she could not go back.
So I asked this lady, did you fix the date of your marriage?
She looked at me and said yes, I said, within a month? She said, yes.
I said, do you understand now why you have this reaction?
She said, yes I understand. Her mother was there, I said bring her a soup,
it was 4 o'clock in the morning.
In a quarter of an hour she was eating the soup.
Now you will say that in such cases that you need psychotherapy.
Or you need to give an advice which is very simple. What is the advice?
Do you think these people will take the advice? That's why I call it the husband syndrome.
They will not take your advice. They will say, yes I don't like him but he is so good,
he has this quality and that quality, they will try to argue with you.
There is no way you will persuade them to leave the husband.
Now this is the husband syndrome when I have sent cases to psychiatrist.
After I've discussed a little bit with the case I said, well I think
that that's what you have to do perhaps, find somebody else, divorce etc. What can you do?
And then producing symptoms, I've seen these cases going into fainting and anxiety
that are unspoken. They will feel dying. They would call me and say, come I'm dying.
The husband would call in the night, she is dying.
And I have the woman calling, bring the ambulance.
One day is this, the next day is that. I have sent these cases to psychiatrist.
The psychiatrist immediately sees the situation without me telling him, be careful
and within 3-4 sessions he will say, OK you have to divorce.
They will leave, not the husband, the psychiatrist.
That is what I call the husband syndrome. It's very difficult to treat,
I have treated such cases, 4-5 cases, with my students we have seen several cases,
and we have not been able to break through these cases.
To break through and to make a resolution of what is, no homeopathic remedy
will not bring about the cure of such a case.
On the other hand of course you give some Staphysagria to a woman
who is married you expect 40 % of the cases, she will get a divorce.
Why? Because Staphysagria is a type that is easily suppressed.
So she has been very suppressed all these years, she cannot speak back, the moment
that she takes Staphysagria the organism becomes strong,
then the husband gets in the house and says, give me this and she says,
wait a moment do you shout?
You are talking very bad to me and there is a fight. One fight, two fights, ten fights
and then eventually if Staphysagria keeps on acting,
because there maybe a relapse on the Staphysagria
and goes back to the suppressed state but if she keeps on acting,
you may see many times a divorce under Staphysagria.
And when we give Staphysagria in a woman that has been suffering with suppression
from the husband, we always have that possibility and you have to know that.
That once the organism is acting now in a natural way,
the reaction is going to be natural not unnatural that was there, not talking, shut up.
She can not shut up anymore. She will speak out. So advice.
Don't give Staphysagria to your wives.
If you want to keep them of course.
The second group that we have are deep, emotional insecurities
that establish a new way of life. I will give you an example.
The previous cases, as I said is only women.
I have seen at least such group of people I have not seen men and you understand why.
It belongs to the woman's liberation.
Deep emotional insecurity is like a man or a woman may find themselves looking in the mirror
when they are still quite young by the moment of the first sexual instinct comes up.
They look and they find themselves not as attractive, very ugly, unattractive.
That shock gives a deep emotional insecurity, which is there every time.
They see it in the mirror. That insecurity establishes for them a new way of life.
What do I mean by that? In order to replace the happiness or the joy
that is given through relationship, they find other ways to replace that which are unnatural.
It can be different ways. We can have all kinds of deviations but if you see these patients
if you catch them very young you may be able to reestablish order with them.
But if that is left 30 years, 35, 40 there is a state of mind that it can not be changed
and they have a particular way of life that will never allow the organism to function naturally.
That's why I said, it is frustration on the self-preservation level and frustration
in the sexual level.
This is a frustration on the sexual sphere because you have an appetite and you have to eat.
This is a natural desire that you have.
If you say to your body, I'm not going to give you food, you're going to be sick.
Everybody knows that. But with the sex is not as simple as that.
Though the desire is equally strong and equally natural, you may say for that desire
forget it I don't want to give you food.
As a result you will have some disturbances on that level, especially when
and if the outlets which are seeked out, are not in the natural order of things.
You may have some possibilities, some cases where another turn of mind will come
when the person really does not lose touch with the reality and his deeper reality
which is a deeper communion with higher states of consciousness comes and you may have,
because of the sublimation of sexual desire, you may have a mind
which works on another level of consciousness.
We have then the enlightenment mind, the super-conscious mind functioning.
That can be a natural replacement on a deep sexual instinct but it does not come easily
it's not a state that you can find easily.
What you will find is a religious minded people, very narrow, which they will say,
only from here to there; once they put these barriers, from here to there,
there is a natural function of the body which does not function anymore naturally
and you're going to have problems that you may not be able to solve with homeopathic remedy.
You may not be able to break through and get this person away from these ideas,
these narrow ideas that he's putting himself into because of emotional insecurity.
Because he's ugly or because of other emotional insecurities.
These are people that you may see them having ticks and people
that they have a level of depression that you can not reach ever.
They have spasms, very difficult to break through these cases.
Now you will be treating these people and what is going to happen is that,
here in this level, these are their kind of chronic condition
that you will not be able to touch with a remedy but once they develop some acute condition,
now this level you're going to treat but always she will turn back to that level.
So acute diseases that will manifest grieves, a grief for that person
may take the picture of Ignatia.
You give Ignatia and it takes away the sighing, the extra grief but underneath
there is that kind of depression which is there, you can not touch, you can not reach.
It leaves a deeper disorder mostly on central, peripheral nervous system,
that you can not touch.
Another group is people that are living under a state of permanent calamity,
which is they a retarded child, they have deep economic depression constantly,
they are very poor.
These people are very difficult to really make the jump and to give them
the joy of another level, of what we call in Homeopathy, a jump in level of health.
Now such people are of quite sensitive character, because not everybody
who has a retarded child is in that state, only very few parents
will go into permanent depression because of that situation.
Now in such cases you may have some successes, especially after helping them
in a round way, I mean finding them a job or advising them to have another child
and have the joy from the other child etc.
Another group that you will find very interesting is a group of people
that have a habit which they consider a sin.
Which is for instance homosexuality, drug addiction, alcoholism, masturbation.
What do we see in such cases? When we treat such cases we see the result
of the homeopathic remedy.
It really makes them feel very well, they enjoy the relationship but back in their mind the sin,
the sin, I'm not doing the right thing.
That is going to catch them and eventually bring about a relapse.
So what we see in such cases are that remedies are acting but the relapses are easy.
Because of the pressure on the emotional, spiritual level.
The pressure is too much for the individual and overturns his balance.
The sixth group is emotionally dead persons that have suffered tremendously through life
and come to the conclusion that finally there is no love, there is no friendship no companionship.
They become very closed, to themselves and remote from the society.
The loners, the people who have suffered a lot, the sensitive people, the people
that have been mistreated in life, the people that have been rejected and if you get them
at the age up to the 30s you may be able to break through that situation.
After that age again this belief that in life there is no love, no affection,
no companionship all this belief brings about to themselves a state of illness
that you will be reaching with great difficulty in breaking through.
These cases will make you suffer very much because you see the suffering,
almost a living suffering, in front of you and much will depend in such cases
on the real affection that you may be able to feel for such cases.
What they need most of all is somebody to understand them.
You see, we homeopaths, we have been accused many times that
what we're doing is just showing some sympathy to the patients and get better.
I say, only the homeopaths can show sympathy?
Everybody can show sympathy but there is no effect. Never mind you show as much sympathy
as you like to certain
individuals, they like it, everybody will like it but not everybody will get better
because of that.
Now this group of people is a special group that if you want to have an effect on them really,
you have to reestablish their belief in life. The suffering of life has taken away
every possible belief that something good may be felt.
So by your contact, by your expression of understanding them, you may be showing them
that after all, cruel is not as cruel as it appears to be.
And the responsibility of the doctor in general, I feel, to be human
and have understanding to the patient and that's why orthodox Medicine has failed
as it became mechanistic and industrialized.
They thought that they could bring pharmaceutical industries into the consulting room.
And that is the failure of allopathic Medicine.
That is why Homeopathy is spreading like fire now and is going to spread so quickly
that I'm telling you for those of you who are practitioners that you have to learn quickly
because the demand will be so great in the next 10 years
that people will go crazy with Homeopathy.
I tell you, prepare.
This was the great anxiety, I had it Greece, when people saw the result
they crowded in the consulting rooms and then I had to train one doctor,
then two, then 5, 10 but the impact was always greater than I could train doctors.
From 1970 there were big, influential people coming, that they own big magazines
and say, we're interested to write a piece, no I don't want, I said please don't write anything.
In newspapers, you can not imagine in how many newspapers I said no.
Because I wanted to prepare the ground for the impact.
Now the impact is happening but now they are enough doctors here in Greece,
since two years I'm not teaching anymore in Greece, because I'm all over the places
but my students are teaching a big group of students.
Now they can write in newspapers. And you know how fast it happens
and if you can deliver it and you can show the effect, then Homeopathy is going to grow
and is going to take the place that it deserves.
We come now to the blockages that may exist on mental or spiritual level
that can prevent homeopathic remedy to act.
The first group, that I found it difficult to treat and to penetrate in deeper level,
as we have said. To bring about a real change in health, not to take away simply the symptoms.
I hope you understand what I'm talking about.
To bring about a change in health, which is as if the person has jumped a level in his health;
he has been regenerated. The person that will say, I feel 10 years younger, I feel much better
as I felt 20 years ago.
This is the kind of jump that we are talking about now.
You may be treating all these individuals, that we have mentioned in the different groups
and you may be having some effect but not that effect.
So the first group that you will find difficult to find such an effect will be a group
which is becoming more and more prominent in our society.
It is the group that mostly will come to you to be treated at this stage
and they will say I understand Homeopathy. This group is the spiritual seekers.
The seekers after spiritual truth, not all of them, don't misunderstand me.
There is a type of person that has been frustrated, has gone through a lot of frustration
in his life and eventually he has decided to become a spiritual person.
This person does not go through a kind of spiritual evolvement
but he becomes very soon a kind of spiritual person, which is having
a specific kind of behavior, a specific kind of talking, a specific kind of dealing with problems.
He has a prototype, a model, which he wears and he acts. It is the spiritual person
which he will be attaching himself to a guru. You know guru? I want to see hands. Everybody.
A spiritual teacher. You know I can make my statistics also.
When I speak to so many audiences in so many countries I have to know what is going
on, quickly. This is a quick way of knowing what's going on.
So everybody knows the guru and has an idea of what spirituality is,
especially eastern type of spirituality and this is a kind of a disturbance
that has been prevalent in the western world because people out of frustration,
out of problems, that have arised because of the way that we live in our societies
in western world, they will turn towards the eastern and further religions trying to find out
a resolution to their problems.
Because the frustration is too much, because the urgency of finding a solution is so great
these people many times, I'm talking about a particular group, they become spiritual suddenly
from one day to the other, talking to a particular kind of voice, the voice is very low,
you don't have to disturb the environment and then you have to be very humble
and everybody who is humble, is spiritual.
And you have to eat the right type of food which is yin and yan.
Never eat together raisins together with almonds.
This is a kind of person that will come to you and what you feel is that they have lost the life,
the life is gone away from them. When they come to you they are so humble
the idea of humbleness is there, not that they are humble.
Because you can not become humble from one day to the other.
To hold above the selfish and the egotistical element, which is in us,
within one month or one year?
Forget it. People are struggling their whole life, in monasteries,
serious people are struggling to hold this monster which is inside us,
which is called the egotistical and selfish element, for years. It is very systematic work.
Now suddenly they have reduced it so much that there is nothing there,
there is no life actually, left in these people. This is a shock to the immunity system,
to the defense system.
The defense system does not have anymore the possibility to produce symptoms.
Do you understand what they do to themselves?
And they come to you, they are your best customers.
Because they are the people who first of all will understand Homeopathy,
the truth of Homeopathy and they will say yes.
It is an ecological, the most natural way of healing.
But they are not saying it in the way I'm saying it, of course.
They will say it in a very humble way. I've understood.
When I see these cases I say, oh my god what can it be the remedy?
Because they will not give you symptoms but general fatigue, general weakness symptoms
and general absurd.
You see the symptoms, when somebody has a headache, my god I have a headache.
Where is the headache? Here. That's very clear symptom.
You ask them, do you have a headache? Yes. Where? Well, I think all over.
You are going to have and to treat these people and to help them also.
And then the symptoms are so much subdued almost, you feel that there is no district symptom.
You see, what you would like is a definite symptom in a case
on which to base your prescription whether it's a local symptom, it's a pain,
a severe pain it's a good symptom. You can base your prescription.
In these cases you will find no concrete, definite symptom on which you can prescribe.
What is always is a little thing coming and going, I have this and I have that
and that kind of indigestion. What kind of indigestion?
Well if I eat vegetables with ... I mean to hear that you say, my god.
Even if he tells you that you can not feel that you have a symptom,
that you can rely on that symptom.
These cases are very difficult to treat and not only they are difficult to treat
but they will drive you to despair because they will come again and again and again.
And they are the same, almost no change.
I found that Sepia produces this kind of state very much. So you just remember.
You see in these cases, you will see the basic instincts of self-preservation
and sexual instincts They are so much subdued that they don't exist.
You will say, do you want to eat? I don't know if I want to eat. Do you have an appetite?
I don't know if I have an appetite. They have cut down their appetites
whether it's sexual or physical, for food.
This is an imposition of the intellect upon the human body looking upon a model
and making that model himself and acting as if he is that model, that spiritual person,
that spiritual man.
Spiritual seekers, they have to be the most aggressive.
I want to find the truth and I want to find what is going on is the most aggressive thing
that you can ask.
You can not be like that and find the truth.
Because what you will find is somebody who will tell you certain things
and then you believe and then you become the follower of [name].
You see statistics again. Who knows [name]...?
In the newspapers had written about him. Everybody must know.
Now this type of persons have come to me to be treated and I found it very difficult to cure,
to penetrate, to understand what is wrong with them, with their system.
They are so careful also, eating this and not eating that,
that the organism has the least possible reaction to this diet.
Once I was treating a French boy, he was a very rich boy and he invited me to his house
and then I found out how he was living. I was trying to find his remedy; it was not possible.
He was a vegetarian, he was such a freak concerning the food. Don't eat this and that.
His cat was not eating all kind of food, his cat had to eat one day yin and the other yen.
His cat! I said, give it some fish.
You know cats like to eat fish or some meat, not vegetables.
It will become sick with the vegetables. He said, no, no.
So you understand this type of person. To say I'm not interested about truth,
about why I'm here, what's going on, what is happening?
These are legitimate questions that everybody should ask. I do not talk about this kind.
I'm talking about a specific type of person that has most,
99,9% has gone through an aggressive period of drugs.
Doing a lot of drugs, taking the marihuana, the heroin, taking LCD and all these
and then breaking down his mind completely. And then you see a broken down individual
because of too much drugs.
Who was in Alonissos in the course? Was anybody there 2 years ago with the American group?
You must remember a case, an American woman was brought to me to treat in front of the class,
so I did not know the woman.
I just looked at her and then I looked again and I said, have you been a hippy? She was shocked.
She said, yes I have living a hippy life for the last 10 years.
Of course I could see it in the completely broken down constitution. This type.
She reacted very well to China. She did very well actually but the imprint of drugs was there
and in America when we are in a class, I would tell the class,
do you want me to tell you who is taking drugs?
And everybody says, as you understand, no. So I'm talking about that particular person
who has taken drugs, has become a seeker eventually, a seeker of truth,
a seeker of experiences.
He has some experiences because these drugs will give you some experiences
but they are artificial, they will not stay there and they will leave you with the sense
of dissatisfaction and incompleteness.
A yearning for something that is not yours.
And these drugs can also give you some bad experiences as well.
And that person, he is spiritual, he will produce symptoms.
It comes when a person lives to the top of its possibility for happiness.
Everyone of us has a possibility of happiness.
Some have bigger possibilities, some have less possibilities
but when you are at the top of your possibility for happiness, this is a spiritual state.
In that state you can not do harm, you can always be creative.
You can always have clear mind, clear ideas, that's a spiritual state.
And this state can come about by playing a nice piece in the piano
or having a good conversation or having a love affair.
I mean any such situation can bring about such state.
You don't have to bring it artificially by drugs.
A second group of people that you will find difficult to treat is people with fixed ideas.
Now we didn't say how you handle this first group, what are you going to do with this group
and what is the possibility for changing them.
There is very little possibility to do anything with this group. You don't try to change them.
You don't try to talk to them. They are going to be through their experiences.
And they are going to find out in a very bitter way what is to be pretending
and what is to follow a guru, who is not a real guru, who does not know anything.
Who knows perhaps less than his students.
Then, when they find out, then they will react, they will become angry,
they will have big symptoms, strong symptoms.
Then it's the time that you may be able to interview and treat and perhaps help them.
Or if you are lucky and strike the remedy in spite of the lack of symptoms,
there might be a possibility that these people will see the truth,
will see what they are doing and they will change their style of life.
Unless they change their style of life, there is no hope.
So these fixed ideas like sex is bad in general.
Now this comes in certain cases of people, men or women especially women,
who have the psychology of a spinster.
They have the psychology of a spinster, it's not that they are not married.
Many women today are living without being married.
This has nothing to do with what I'm talking about.
The fixed idea that sex is bad and therefore changing the hormonal system within the body,
it's going to give a state which most probably you will not be able to penetrate
with your treatment, you will not be able to change this hormonal system
that has been suppressed by such ideas.
In this category come all the hypochondriacs and also those people
with fixed ideas concerning diet. That' another kind. They have very fixed ideas concerning diet.
Their whole life is what will cook and what will eat.
If a person has become from morning till night will thinking what am I going to cook for eat,
that is an unhealthy state of mind that is creating an unhealthiness in the body,
which is not again penetrated by the homeopathic remedy.
You will not be able to find the correct remedy.
These people seem to have immobilize a flow of life which seems to be necessary
for the natural functioning of the body.
The third group will be the intellectuals. You see with the intellectuals, what has happened.
They have thought out everything and they know the explanation for everything that has happened
and they can explain away, everything.
And they have planned their whole life and they are going according to that.
They have planned what they are going to do whether they have a dinner or a sex etc.
On Friday we are having sex and Saturday they have dinner with people.
I mean everything comes through the mind. What happens with these people?
They come for the consultation and this group of people they will be either very much
in favor for Homeopathy, because they read something and they know about Homeopathy
or they will be great skeptics and they will come and will tell you, I'm not convinced.
So you have to convince me or they will say, I read your books and I find it very correct.
But when you try to take their symptoms, it's another story.
You're asking a simple question like do you feel cold or do you feel warm?
Are you aggravated by heat or by cold? And they will not be able to answer.
I mean the answer is either I'm aggravated by heat or I'm aggravated by cold or I don't care.
Too much heat I can take, too much cold I can take. These are the three answers I can give.
Do you think an individual like this will answer you like this? Never.
Or you can say, in the beginning I think I' m aggravated by cold.
Then you proceed in your examination and you cross examine because you're going to prescribe
a cold remedy. You think it's Rhus tox or Calcarea carb. or Arsenicum for the intellectuals
that fits very well with the fastitudeness of Arsenicum and you want to confirm
whether he is really cold or not.
And then you say, you have said to me that you are aggravated by cold,
you don't look at him, you say it just casually.
He understands now that you are thinking seriously of what he has said and immediately will go back
and will think, wait a moment, not exactly I didn't say I was aggravated by cold.
OK, what now? I think, I tell you the situation in which I can be aggravated,
if I am in a room and the third window on the right is open and also there is a door
which is half open on the other side, I may feel the draft.
But if I'm sitting on the corner where two windows are open and one closed...
Then you ask, what about being outside, do you feel warm, do you feel cold?
Do you wear more clothes than other people etc.? Well, it depends where I'm going.
If I'm going to a place where I had to go with a car, I wear light clothes,
in other case I wear warm clothes and then they go on like that with every symptom, and no answer.
Do you like in your food salt?
No. Don't you like salt because you've read in some book that salt is bad for health?
It maybe that but still I don't like salt.
You read that it's not good; therefore you stopped eating salt. Yes, I'm not eating salt.
Since when did you stop eating salt? Many years ago.
Before reading the book or after reading the book?
In the end of such case you have no symptom to rely upon.
They have given you an information which they change it in the course of the interrogation.
Now what kind of symptomatology you are taking to base your prescription
and what type of a person you have in front of you?
Another thing. They will give you their case usually with the exact words of the different doctors
that have been consulting before you.
They will say that I have a duodenal ulcer or an ulcer on the stomach
and it has been diagnosed by such and such doctor, the explanation is this,
this and that and the examinations, they pull out all the examinations.
And you will say, what are your symptoms? What do you feel?
You have the ulcer but do you feel anything?
And then it starts, when I eat this and that together with this
in order not to have these symptoms etc. you go on and on. Finally you have no symptoms at all.
What are you going to do with such individuals? What is the strategy?
Because in the end for the case you have no information to prescribe upon
except of the pathology.
So what you do is you tell them to come back again for another consultation
because you did not understand his case.
Do you think they won't like it? No, they will enjoy it very much.
They will say, ah I' m a difficult case and I understand I'm a difficult case
and that's why he understood.
He starts to understand me, therefore he is quite good.
He will come again and again and unless you have really the information,
do not prescribe in such cases because eventually you're going to lose your case.
He will go away and say, he did nothing for me. Tell him I still don't understand your case.
Either you will answer me straight or I'm not going to give you a remedy.
I want to find out what is going on. And they will love it. They will come again and again.
Also these individuals will have peculiar symptoms that they will not tell you from first
or second consultation.
They will tell you after they have established a very good contact with you.
And then they open up and one day they are going to give you their cases.
They will speak from the heart.
But when they come from the beginning is impossible for them to speak from the heart
from what is happening, simple facts.
They will give you everything which is in the mind but not what is happening really in the body.
During their treatment also, it will be interesting to find out that in such cases
you will have anxieties and fears coming up during the treatment,
that they were not accepted in the beginning.
A lot of fears and a lot of anxieties that were kept under control by sheer intellectual power.
As they are loosen up, they start more to feel their fears, their insecurities, their anxieties
and then they will give out the symptoms and then you will be able to prescribe more correctly.
There is a fourth group of patients.
That's a peculiar group that they don't want any kind of dependency upon the doctor.
So when they come to give you the feedback of what happened with their treatment
they will tell you, even if the treatment is correct, that maybe I'm better
but most probably I'm better because somebody else has done something else on me
or I have done something and that's why I'm better, not because of your remedy.
So you have to be very careful with these individuals because there is an inborn fear
that they may depend on somebody, if they tell you that I'm better
with this remedy you gave me, that they will depend on that.
It's a sick state of mind again because after all what is more common,
more natural if you want to get food, you go to the bakery and you buy some bread.
You depend on the baker who makes the food. Of course you depend.
If he closes, you will have no food. It's the same. You need a remedy,
you go to the doctor, you ask, the doctor gives you, you pay him and it's finished.
These individuals take it completely different.
It is very important that they will not depend. They will not feel the dependency upon.
Therefore when you gave the remedy, they took it, they felt better
but at the same time they were drinking some kind of special water.
So maybe it's the water I was drinking.
That special water that made me feel better and not your remedy.
Maybe somebody else gave me a remedy and that remedy or I went to acupuncture
and I think the acupuncture did well and not you.
Now he goes to the acupuncturist and he tells the same story about you.
I went to a homeopath and he gave me a remedy and I'm not sure exactly
that the acupuncture did it or the remedy.
That group of people feel a great insecurity to have this kind of dependency.
Now what may happens with these people is you don't tell them, don't contrast them
and say, it's the remedy I gave you. Let them believe whatever they think.
And eventually they will become so much convinced, that they will really depend upon you.
And then you can handle the situation and you can take away that inborn fear.
And you can tell them, you don't owe me anything, this is my job.
This is what I have to do. I have to cure people. You don't owe me anything.
You pay me a visit and that's all and go away now.
Whenever you need, you may come again.
And then there is a healthy kind of transaction.
This group of people is a very small group but sometimes you will see it.
So all these cases I gave you represent about 70% of your clients.
Actually the rate of success of Homeopathy should be between 80-90%.
It should be. It's not.