I have promised you to discuss the possibilities of taking away people from drugs
and how you take them
if they are under chemical drugs.
So in this category of people under
allopathic druging we have two groups.
One group and a second which we treat differently. If you want to really treat somebody who is
under constant allopathic druging you
have to put them in one of these two groups.
The first group is a group where if you stop
the medication, there is danger of their life.
Such cases are asthma cases, heavy asthmatics who are under cortisone, you don't stop their medication ever.
Children under cortisone, don't stop the medication. You know George from America, what happened to him?
He had one such case, he tried to stop
the medication and the child died.
He had for years problems, court cases etc.
and the court case was not from the parents.
It was from the hospital, from the
doctors of the allopathic hospital.
And the medical association took his license.
So why you should as a Homeopath go to such extremes
and endanger the life of the
patient but endanger your life as well?
The second group which is
dangerous to stop is.....
heart cases.
Heart cases with high blood pressure at the same time heart case is very dangerous to stop the medication.
Third group which is quite dangerous to stop is the epileptics.
Grand mal epileptics which are taking antiepileptic drugs for years and you try to stop the medication,
they could go to status epilepticus and then you will see permanent paralysis or permanent damage
which you will be very sorry to see. I will tell you a few ways of dealing with such cases but let's first categorise
and clear in our mind all the cases that
are dangerous to stop the medication.
-What about petit mal?
-Petit mal goes to that group, not to this group.
Which is another group?
-Diabetes?
-Diabetes is belonging to this group
it's more easy to stop or to get involved with the diabetes case because you have the possibility of insuline
and reducing the insulin and control it.
But if you go and stop immediately the insulin and then try homeopathically,
but we'll see how you handle it.
Here the danger is imminent, you're going
to be definitely in big problems.
-People who have got transplantation of vessels and who have taken the medication, not to get them rejected.
-Immunosuppressive. It's very interesting but they don't come to Homeopathy.
-Psychotics?
-The psychotics, the deep psychotic cases which they have started around young age, around 18,20
and for 10,15,20 years are under heavy drugging if you try to stop such cases you will have a lot of problems
not only the danger of him dying but the danger of other people dying because of them.
They can kill somebody or they can be very aggressive and a problem for the society; so we don't want to create such situations.
-Chronic impediment of organs like
failure of the liver or kidneys?
-In the kidneys when they are in kidney dialysis in blood purification, you don't stop them from being to the dialysis
but with let us say, beginning stages of liver cirrhosis where they may be taking interferon
they don't have anything else to do. Either interferon or transplantation of the liver
in such cases you can interfere with Homeopathy and if the interferon is giving some results, you wait.
But if the interferon treatment is not giving a result, then you can stop and you can start with
homeopathic treatment without having
the eminent possibility of the death.
-What about AIDS?
-AIDS in the last stage where Kaposi sarcoma has appeared or they get these pneumonias,
pneumonia Carinii one after the other they have reached the end. You can do very little but I don't think
any treatment can do anything.
But in this stage I would not suggest that you get involved with such progressed cases of AIDS.
Just out of experimenting more you can do it but when we have a prodromal syndrome like the AIDS related syndrome
where we have lymphadenopathy, where we have some types of diarrhoeas, exhaustion etc.,
at that stage you can interfere with Homeopathy and Homeopathy can have some good results.
I don't know how far they can go because the cases we have treated so far they have shown an improvement
but not a cure which will be established
by laboratory examinations.
If a case of multiple sclerosis is under cortisone, do not stop the treatment to start yours. Wait until the patient is himself
disillusioned because in multiple sclerosis cortisone will show an immediate effect and the patient gets some hope.
Once he sees that the relapses are coming back and even more frequently than before,
then they get disappointed then that is the time you can enter. Otherwise you will stop here, they immediately
go into paralysis and then they blame you.
MS under cortisone.
In these cases here, insulin here, here thyroxine, these especially whatever is a replacement
of the natural hormones it is not very
bad for the homeopathic treatment.
That means they can continue having the insulin but you will have to check immediately after your remedy,
you will have to check the levels of sugar because they may go the opposite way, they may go under normal.
In such case you can reduce the insulin immediately and see whether you can actually get away from the insulin.
So in these cases you reduce immediately
after your presciption, after checking.
Now in petit mal you cannot check but you can reduce and see whether the frequency of the attacks is increasing.
If that is the case then most probably your remedy is incorrect and you have to search for another remedy.
With liver cirrhosis, liver disfunctions in general fatty infiltration, degeneration in all these cases
the allopathic therapeutics do not have a solution.
So whenever there is no solution from the allopathic point of view, you can interfere there is no question.
If you want to try to get away the remedies from such people as these ones here, the strategy should be
to try to see if there is still the picture of a remedy. If there is a picture of a remedy
and you feel quite sure about it, then you
can tell them that you will start treatment.
Otherwise you tell them, 'I cannot do anything'.
If you take their case and it is totally confused,
it is best to tell them 'we can do nothing, Homeopathy can do nothing'.
If the case seems clear,  then you use a medium potency like 200 and you use it frequently, every day 3-4 times the day.
You use this for, let us say, one week. After one week you advise the patient to start reducing the cortisone.
If by reducing the cortisone the condition remains the same or even better, then you continue frequent repetition
and at the same time, slowly reducing the doses of cortisone.
In such cases you will have the problem that the case may look is going well and it may also reach a point
where you got him out of cortisone
totally and his condition is tolerable.
But these cases are very sensitive and let us say, they find themselves in a polluted city like Athens or in Kosovo
where the pollution is tremendous,
then the crisis which arises suddenly
is going to be very dangerous and very severe and sudden and you have to be prepared for that.
It's not a case where you can just forget it,
ah now it's out of cortisone, it's doing well.
With the least provocation the
reaction is going to be very severe.
And therefore you have to be in contact and to be lucky to give immediately now the new remedy
or the old remedy in order to stop this crisis.
Otherwise they will go back to cortisone
and then they will start all over again.
The more this happens, the more times you get them back to cortisone, the more difficult becomes the case.
That's why in these cases we say,
it's better to not get involved.
With heart cases it's different. It seems that the heart has better possibilities of responding in homeopathic treatment.
And also here with heart conditions we have the possibility to check with a cardiogram whether the case is doing better etc.
Here, we don't have much control of the case; it depends only on the subjective symptoms of the patient.
Also in asthma cases where you see emphysema, where the lung has expanded and cannot
anymore function, it is very improbable
that you're going to help such cases.
Here in the heart is different. I believe that Homeopathy can help most of the heart cases.
Now if they are under allopathic drugging you have to do the same but not as high as 200.
I would go the highest when I start with 30, repeating 3-4 times per day or even less than 30.
The heart does not respond very much to high potencies but I have seen cases which are really amazing, with heart conditions.
A remedy excellent is Aurum iodine,
Kali-arsenicum also.
I would say it would be easier for
Homeopathy to show results in heart cases
where we have gross pathology than a
malignant type of high blood pressure.
Malignant type of high pressure where pressure stays up, whatever you do, is more difficult than
showing an effect on heart conditions. It would be very interesting for us if we could ever do this
experiment where people
are prepared for heart transplantation.
And they can give us the possibility to treat half of this group which is prepared for heart transplantation
and say what is your possibilities to live with transplantation? Ok, 3,4,5 years, ok let's see with Homeopathy.
I believe that Homeopathy could have better results than heart transplantation.
It can act even in progressed gross pathology of the heart.
I say that because I have seen unbeliavable things.
-George I had a question about the frequency and the dose in the cases of the asthma.
These are patients who are on cortisone or steroid drugs and you are recommending 200C potency
several times a day for a week. And at that time you expect to see some stability on the patient
after receiving the homeopathic treatment? And that's why you begin to wean off the cortisone?
-You see in these cases, you see first improvement and then you start reducing.
If you don't see improvement, you don't reduce. If you see improvement then you start,
that means your remedy is correct and most probably you can reduce the cortisone.
-A question I have from the theoretical basis is,
if you give that kind of repetitional 200C potency,
is it not possible to get an aggravation
first before amelioration?
-Yes it is possible you may see but you continue through the aggravation, you continue.
-If the patient lets you.
-Yes.
With the epileptics this is a quite
tempting situation for Homeopathy.
We have seen that children with epilepsy are responding quite well to Homeopathy.
Especially if they come before
starting the allopathic drugging.
I have seen cases where children have
received all kinds of allopathic druging
there are several drugs which are given and sometimes they combine the two drugs together
in order to have an effect on the children.
Still the children they go and have epileptic fits.
In such cases where the allopathic drugging does not have a real effect it has a partial effect
then such cases are good to try Homeopathy. Again you will have to try repeating the potency.
Here in epileptics you can go up to high, even higher, up to 1M and you repeat 3-4 times per day
until you see some improvement and then you start cutting down; the improvement in such cases
you cannot see before a month. At least one month you will have to continue and then check it
and then of course you have the possibility to check it with an electroencephalogram it's even better.
Because if the encephalogram shows some improvement this is a very encouraging thing.
If it starts coming back after a few months, you may see the encephalogram becoming better and better.
-George just before I came to a case of a woman on 4th stage of breast cancer but she has not taken any chemo etc,
she just tries to go very natural with it.
What's happening now, I examined the breast
and she has mushroom-like growth coming out of the breast and from time to time the breast just bleeds.
And now with the chemo the bleeding has stopped but I wonder is this a case that can respond well to Homeopathy?
-If the chemotherapy has started it's better not to interfere during chemotherapy because most probably
you will be wasting your energy.
But after chemotherapy it is necessary to start homeopathic treatment if she has any chance.
Because there are two possibilities, if the type of cancer is the metastatic one, the one that makes fast metastasis
forget Homeopathy, it can give a few months more from other therapies but that's all.
The fast metastasis is a lost case, forget it, nobody can do anything. But the other cases they can last very many years.
And even if they have operation or chemotherapy or both and afterwards they have homeopathic treatment, it's even better.
But it depends what type of cancer it is. I remember a case of a woman who had her brother, he was a doctor,
her father was a doctor and her other sister
was a doctor and they examined her.
One of these examined her and they found in the very beginning a little gland, immediately she was taken to Sweden
and she had radiotherapies and in 3 months she died.  And it was very early diagnosed.
The main thing is, especially in these 3 categories, you're going to have a lot of problems
if you stop suddenly the medication.
Now there are other cases like Lupus erythematosus, Rheumatoid arthritis, Psoriasis
Diabetes, in all these cases if they're under cortisone, these cases may be under cortisone,
these cases maybe under hormones these maybe under interferon, these maybe under antiepileptics.
In all these cases you can more easily decide to reduce the medication even before giving the remedy.
Reducing the medication in such cases will give you a better idea of the defense mechanism.
So it is better in such cases if you reduce first the medication for a period of time, let us say 15 days,
and then take the case again. Of course if you take the case and see the remedy is clear, then you can start immediately
and immediately you can start,
at the same time, reducing the drugs.
In such cases there is no imminent danger. There is a danger of course of worsening.
Here also in these cases we should put ulcerative colitis under cortisone which is a very dangerous situation to take away.
You have to be sure about the remedy so the remedy can reduce the impact of the disease and then, as I said,
during crisis you may have to go
back to cortisone like with asthma.
Back to cortisone, back to homeopathic treatment and it is quite a dangerous situation.
-I had a case also of ulcerative colitis a few months ago a patient came to see me from the other side of the country.
Before she came to see me she was hospitalised and put on cortisone and steroids and after leaving the hospital,
I took the case, put her on a remedy she did very well. Her blood level was very low, it went up for about two weeks.
Frequency of stools and texture and consistency had improved and her blood levels went down again
but when she went to see her internist, her internist had doubts whether she had to put her back on cortisone and steroids
because she looked so healthy. She started engaging in sexual activity again, she felt a new feeling for her boyfriend,
she started writing a book for the first time in many years she is olympic athlete and so my question is
why would her well being seem being
so strong, her blood levels go down?
- She starts having a relapse and the relapse starts with certain signs and symptoms and whether
you will be able to control the relapse with the same remedy or another remedy,
that is a question and how long she is going to remain well. This is a question depending on whether
the remedies you prescribe are correct or not.
But ulcerative colitis we have different degrees.
There is pain and the stool is bloody but it's a difference between somebody who has five stools per day
and twenty stools per day. There is a big difference between these two people.
And you have to understand beforehand the severity of the case.
Especially you have to be more careful when these cases are from ulcerative colitis and they have also
mental-emotional symtomatology. Strong mental-emotional symptomatology will show up with the colitis eventually.
As the mental-emotional is getting better,
the colitis will go crazy.
And you have to be aware. If the ulcerative colitis people you see them healthy, don't be afraid.
If you see disturbances on mental-emotional here, be very careful.
Because a lot of these people belong to hypochondriacs and the moment you try to treat them,
instead of reducing you see the increasing
of the colitis. Then there is a big problem.