You see the ideas of Hahnemann concerning the miasms were correct. There is no question about that.
The only difference is that they are not complete. That means we may not have only 3 miasms,
as Hahnemann said, but we may
have more than one miasm.
I consider the tubercular miasm as a miasm in itself. I will give you the general characteristics of a miasm.
In order to have a miasm you have to have an infective agent whether it's Syphilis, it's Gonorrhea, an infective agent.
That means an agent that can be infecting one another.
That is the first condition.
The second condition is that you have to have the evidence that such a condition, infective condition,
when it is treated or not treated it leaves some
after effects. It leaves problems with the health.
The third condition in order to have a miasm is to have proof that this infective agent that was infected
the primary organism is passing to his offsprings, a predisposition which is similar to the original infection.
So three conditions are necessary.
First you have to have an infective agent.
Second you have to have the evidence that this infective agent does not necessarily goes away after treatment,
that means leaves after effects, and the third condition is that such infective agent,
such disease can pass to the next generations.
This I have said several times but still my students, like everyone wants to bring
a new idea and bring a lot of miasms now.
Unless the three conditions are there you cannot be talking about a miasm. In cancer there is an infective agent.
Can anybody be infected with cancer? Therefore cancer cannot be considered as a miasm,
it is different the predisposition that
can come from different diseases.
Predisposition, I had psoriasis.
Psoriasis is infective? No.
Nobody can be infected with psoriasis. Yet
when the mother or the father had psoriasis,
there is a huge probability that the
child will develop psoriasis.
That is not a miasm with the idea of a miasm. The idea of the miasm has to have an infective agent.
When Hahnemann was talking about "psora" he means about scabies. Can scabies infect each other? Yes.
Can scabies, when they are treated,
have side effects? Yes.
When they're passing through
to next generations? Yes.
The problem is that unless we have some principles, some understanding of what is a miasm,
then we cannot be talking about miasms in general. You see, everything is a miasm.
A cortisone miasm, penicillin miasm, God knows, everything can become a miasm because all diseases
that we have in this generation, all chronic conditions are coming from our parents who were having some problems
and they pass it to offsprings. So all diseases
are hereditary. The idea of a miasm is different.
The idea of the miasm is something which,
as I said, has to have a starting point and
can be infecting primary the organism.
Syphilis yes, Gonorrhea yes, Psora yes, Tuberculosis yes. Why we say Tuberculosis can be a miasm?
Because we see a person who had Tuberculosis, he develops a kind of sensitivity upon his lungs
or gets easily an acute frequent colds etc. He has children and the child is born with sensitivity towards the lungs
and then from the very young age the boy or the girl start having infections, lung infections, respiratory infections.
You inquire whether your mother had Tuberculosis and he says, yes the mother had Tuberculosis
or the grand father had Tuberculosis. Then you give Tuberculinum and the predisposition is gone.
All this story together makes for a miasm.
Now I will talk about the miasm with sycosis. You see from the very first observations I had made concerning
this disease and this miasm, it was when patients were coming and I was inquiring, did you have a Gonorrhea?
They said, yes. What age? 20-22 etc. Ok, how did you get it? We went to a prostitute. Who went to the prostitute?
We were five. And you went all to the same woman? Then what happened?
Two of us got the gonorrhea, the other three were free.
What protected them?
Unless you inquire you cannot find out really?
To solve this problem it needs long periods of observation in order to come to a conclusion
what actually is happening and why one is protected and the other gets it immediately.
When I was in United States, in 1983-85, when the AIDS broke out, you remember for the first time,
and I was there and I treated a lot of young men with AIDS, I don't know if that is true anymore but during that time
when the first victims of AIDS were coming
I found out almost invariably that this young man had been infected
by Gonorrhea and by Syphilis.
Because mostly the group that was in
danger were the homosexuals, why?
Because they were practicing sex without any protection. Wild sex, when I asked them their practices
it was unbelievable they were describing to me  they were doing. I remember case who said,
'I had sex three times this morning and in the night I could not get sleep and I had to go out to the bars
in which they had sex inside the bars, something like that. Baths, they had sex there without protection
and then he said, I got Gonorrhea and I got Syphilis and I was treated with penicillin and again penicillin.
It was very interesting that every time they were taking antibiotics, they were cured. The moment they were cured
they could get it again, be infected again because actually penicillin was able to cure in a lot of such cases
and let the organism free, especially those organisms that were strong organisms and they could overcome
the disease plus the antibiotics.
Then one time, two, three, five times, some of them told me finally we decided to take
constantly antibiotics to be covered.
So every day for 1,2, 3 years constantly antibiotics in order to have a protection.
In the end of such practices the manifestation of AIDS came so with my knowledge of what is happening
with these infective agents etc. I realized what was happening in their organisms.
What was happening was that the organism because they were strong young men, with a lot of vitality,
very high sexual desire something very seldom here in a normal man-wife situation; it seems that they are over sexed
to the extend that they are driven
completely to have sexual contact.
Therefore in the end they came with Kaposi's sarcoma, with pneumonia Carinii, in a terrible state of depletion
and of course I was battling to help them, it was not possible because they would start over again the practices.
But the interesting thing was that I said to them, since when it was the last infection.
The last infection with gonorrhea I had it 3 years ago. 2 years ago. From that time started the depletion of the immune system.
Once the immune system has been totally subdued due to the practices of infection, antibiotics,
infection again, antibiotics, the immune system gave up and the manifestation of AIDS appeared
and it was interesting that AIDS means exactly the suppression of the immune system.
The immune deficiency. How came? They didn't want to investigate and it was left to me to write eventually the book
" A New Model for Health and Disease " in which I explain all this idea and what it was really happening.
And how could they prevent it. In Africa Gonorrhea and Syphilis are killing most of the people,
because of the infections because it seems that in order to reach that state of immune suppression
and having the AIDS syndrome,
you have to have a predisposition.
This predisposition is created through repeated infections with sexually transmitted diseases in general.
What is happening, for instance, if two parents were infected in young years by gonorrhea.
What do you think the child born will have?
The question is the child is going to be born with a severe pathology or is going to be born with a predisposition
for getting the infection or is going to be born with deep predisposition for a chronic condition?
If you're going to treat a case of parents having primary gonorrhea and you're treating the child,
the child is going to be very very sick.
I mean in comparison with the levels of health. It's going to be on 7, 8 level of health, 9,10 cancer, what do you think?
Nobody can answer ok. I tell you.
In order to get gonorrhea, some person
has to be on high level of health.
Let us say, on the second, third, fourth level around this area; so therefore both parents were actually
quite healthy when they got infected and now their health has been diminished because of the infection.
So the child is going to be born with some pathology which will appear severe pathology but which will be
manageable to Homeopathy.
Like this man has severe pathology but we consider it as manageable to Homeopathy because the remedy
will be clear and in spite of the fact that the pathology may be strong, still the person will be able to raise fever.
Different is the case in which the parents of the parents, grand mother, grand father had both gonorrhea
or one of them had gonorrhea.
They pass the pathology to the child but also they pass the predisposition to the sycotic miasm.
The child may not have been infected with gonorrhea himself but it has the predisposition and comes
with a woman who has the predisposition
for a psychotic miasm.
The third generation is going to be born
with predisposition on a deeper level.
As long as the predisposition is such that as soon as it comes in contact with Gonorrhea,
gets Gonorrhea, the health is good.
If the predisposition is such that when it comes to the Gonorrhea does not get it, the health is bad.
It is the opposite of what we may be thinking because the predisposition of the Gonorrhea which
is running through the generation, protects
the person from getting infected.
Likewise the AIDS people once they start getting the immunosuppressive syndrome, they stop being infected.
They cannot be infected anymore with either  Gonorrhea or Syphilis or whatever.
Now they are infected with pneumonia Carinii. This is a kind of pneumonia which is considered as a kind of
pneumonia which is of a weak type, yet it undermines, eats up the organism to such an extent
that does not allow the immune system to recover.
It's like an immune system which has been totally suppressed and accepts not powerful microbes anymore.
Because powerful microbes or viruses etc. the organism can not deal with them. It says, just forget them,
I have another problem now.
In that state we see the development of infections which are of a low type infections, like the pneumonia Carinii.
Once an AIDS person starts having the infection by pneumonia Carinii, then it is in the last stage, his life has actually finished.
All kind of medications they are given, whatever is the treatment, the life of such person is over. Why?
Because as long as they were strong the organism, they were infected. Again they were treated
and got better and infected.
Until the organism gives up and his
immune system is suppressed;
it is very interesting that the syndrome is
called immunodeficiency syndrome.
This is what we have been saying and we wrote an article with a medical doctor who is an expert in immunology
and she said to me when she was sitting there, she is a Greek doctor, she said, immunology has found a lot of things
but it can not put it together.
Your system, your model is putting
together all the findings of immunology.
We wrote together an article which is
going to come out, will be posted as well.
We connect Homeopathy and immunology, the findings of immunology because what I said was that I found out
at a certain moment when I was examining a case and I was asking, when it was the last time you had a fever?
This was very long.
Oh God, I have a difficult case.
If the person had a high fever and it's very interesting to us, the last high fever was a year ago only
but very strong and a lot of drugs were prescribed and after this the problems really had aggravated and started.
You see all this makes sense for Medicine in general, which the conventional medical people do not want
to take into consideration.
They will be forced to take them into consideration because what we're saying is really the truth
and they will be forced eventually to admit that we are creating a population which is sick by suppressing acute diseases.
We got so many cases of children with severe chronic problems and you take the history of such children
and you see before infections, infections, especially little girls, they were not infected by sexual things,
they started with cystitis, antibiotics.
After 6 months again cystitis, again antibiotics, after four months cystitis, again antibiotics,
after 3 months cystitis, antibiotics,
after 2 months cystitis, antibiotics.
So when the parents come, say we
almost have to give constant antibiotics.
She is relapsing all the time
with the cystitis the girl.
But the girl which is now coming to us
is not getting anymore cystitis.
Since when finished the cystitis in
certain cases? Since 1,2 years.
Some of the parents here about us and they come in time because if they come in time, the child can be saved easily.
When they come and they say, 2 years ago it was the last cystitis, but now the child has
mental, emotional problems that is difficult case.
You understand how important it is to know these things and to understand how diseases are developing?
These are not known things in the general kind of Homeopathy which is practiced. These things are kept secret.
Don't go to Vithoulkas, he is old kind of Homeopathy and now we have modern Homeopathy
where we give the new drugs we have
proved and all that kind of things.
The core remedy, the vital sensations,
what is the vital sensation?
It's one symptom in a case unless you put together all the other symptoms, forget the vital sensation.
Is that possible? The vital sensation is insecurity ok, so what? You go to the Repertory you give a new remedy
that has been imagined or so called proved. Because who is doing a correct proving today?
Very few people know what is a correct proving.