There are two requests here for constitutional remedy, to talk about the idea of constitutional remedy.
In Homeopathy we talk many times about what is your constitutional remedy etc. as you know it very well.
My experience is like this. If you take these groups, then the only group which you can talk about constitutional remedy is this group, the A level of the first group.
Why? Because the remedy is very clear and when you repeat the remedy, the remedy acts. All along his life almost with one remedy you can treat acute or chronic conditions.
This was the idea of Kunzli and another one who was influenced and he was teaching this way. He was an Argentinian, Mazi.
They claimed both that each individual has one remedy, basic remedy which you have to find and this remedy is going to act the rest of his life and only with that remedy you can cure.
As I said this holds only for that group. All the other groups and levels they need more than one remedy. Now the more the pathology and the complication, the less the idea of constitutional remedy goes away.
The idea of constitutional remedy also is wrong from another point of view. Let us say, you are Sulphur and you are given Sulphur.
If you are Sulphur, you are given Sulphur, that means you're cured. Then what you are? Are you still Sulphur? The next day after I gave you Sulphur, are you still Sulphur? If I give you Sulphur, I will spoil your case.
So what is the constitutional remedy? The idea of the constitutional remedy was an idea that came in the early years of Homeopathy when cases were quite simple and most of the cases belonged to this first group.
And this is what also confused Hahnemann because he would see, he says, he would see relapses and brought out the idea of miasms.
The idea of miasms came to Hahnemann because he prescribed a remedy and then there is a relapse and then prescribed another remedy, Rhus tox and then came Calcarea carbonica and he produced the idea of the miasm.
These were cases of this group or that group, of Hahnemann where Rhus tox was the first indicated remedy and then the second was Calcarea carbonica but needed both remedies.
If he had given from the beginning Calcarea carbonica, I doubt whether he would have an effect.
A person who needs Rhus tox as the first remedy, needs to get Rhus tox as the first remedy.
Then in what they call relapse with certain differences, he needs Calcarea carbonica and then he has to take Calcarea carbonica.
Now which of the two remedies is his constitutional remedy? The first one or the second?
You can not say, already you are confused. The moment that you need two remedies for an individual you are confused to what is his constitutional remedy.
That's why this idea is not valid for real Homeopathy. Also don't forget that even if a person gets a remedy and is cured, he is not cured because if you are really cured, you're going to live for ever.
But everyone who gets even the right remedy, he is going to die. Therefore he's not really cured with the meaning of the word cured that means you have no problem at all.
Or at least you live 150 years old and you die from old age.
But this is not true. Now what is true, what is happening? It is that even this group, the A group in is quite healthy group, which you give Calcarea carbonica and they do well or you give whatever remedy
and they are doing well, underneath this remedy, there is another remedy but you can not see. So you allow this person to go into relapse and relapses always lead to the original remedy.
As we have said, here we have Calcarea carbonica and here we have Lycopodium. And here maybe you have Arsenicum.
And because they are quite healthy, you see the case is not mixed, these layers are separated actually, they are not mixed, it's a clear case, you prescribe and goes away.
It stays with these two levels. The moment these two levels are stimulated they bring out a relapse. What is a relapse? Calcarea carbonica.
You give Calcarea carbonica, then again is better. But these two layers remain untreated. If we had a way to constantly find out and treat the underline layers we may had prolonged the life of a person quite a lot.
But here why we cannot find? Because the symptomatology is very mild.
-But it's still a lot of times constitutional remedy or constitutional treatment is called something which is not acute. So anything which is not acute would be a constitutional treatment. So it doesn't necessarily mean that you give one remedy. As Kunzli said, he was giving
a remedy for 15 years and finally he saw an effect. He was giving a remedy without effect sometimes but he was so stubborn, he said that it must be his constitutional remedy.
-Yes but that's what I said. This is an idea, a fixed idea but not reality because we had here in a teachers' meeting, one of his students who expanded this idea and he said, it doesn't matter effect or no effect
you continue giving the remedy.
Of course, also there is a secret perhaps that I can reveal to you now.
If you give a remedy constantly for long period of time, you create finally a layer which is this remedy and the last time you give it, the remedy will cure this layer.
Eventually you bring up this to the point where he really have now Calcarea carbonica layer and this can be done also in cases where you have prescribed a remedy repeatedly and in the end
you jump a potency and the case is cured.
- Yes but this was the old definition of constitutional treatment. But still you have the opposite of constitutional or acute treatment. Somebody gives a lot of acutes and the decision is to treat him constitutionally or to treat him with main focus on the acute symptoms.
-I see. Maybe we have to say what we mean by constitutional treatment. Maybe we mean different things.
-Yes, the terminology about constitutional.
-The terminology has to clear, yes.
For me constitutional treatment is when you give a remedy which fits the mental-emotional and physical symptomatology of the patient.
And covering his picture, chronic or acute, all together. You may have a person with acute symptomatology and with chronic symptoms on the side.
You treat somebody with cystitis, with pneumonia and then you have Arsenicum. At the same time you see this is an Arsenicum patient. And you can give Arsenicum for the acute and you can treat also constitutionally.
So whatever chronic symptoms he has, they go away at the same time. This is a treatment  which you can call constitutional. The problem arises when you want to apply this idea to all these levels.
And then you make the mistake which I think Kunzli was doing in believing that we have to find one remedy, the deepest remedy.
Here the deepest remedy is Arsenicum. He says, find Arsenicum and then cure the patient. I say, no. When you have Calcarea symptoms, you have to give Calcarea first.
And then reach at a certain stage the Arsenicum which is the third. But there is no end. The human body is naturally degenerating, that means is creating an imbalance which is going to end in death.
So therefore at any time there is going to be a different remedy, if you can see it.
So the idea of sticking with one remedy...
-This idea is completely out of question. I mean this was an old idea about constitutional treatment to go on with one remedy. But you use the term of consitutional treatment in a completely different sense.
You say either you treat constitutionally or you treat acute.
-This expression is wrong. It's a wrong understanding of the idea of constitution. Constitution is when we say, this person is Sulphur, this is Calcarea carbonica, this is Phosphorus. Why do we say that? Because Phosphorus is open, etc. etc.
Natrum muriaticum is closed. We say, his constitution is Natrum muriaticum. The moment that you gave Nat-m, he becomes Sepia.
And we stay on the fact that the person was looking like Nat-m. So therefore you can not stick with an idea which says that anyone of us has a constitutional remedy. That idea is wrong.
On the other hand if you treat only local symptoms is also wrong. But sometimes you have only local symptoms and you have to treat only local symptoms.
The person mentally-emotionally is quite balanced. Then the local symptoms indicate Phos. but you say, this person is not Phos.
I just heard a discussion with my students and one was relating a case and he asked me an advice to which I said, give Pulsatilla. He had given other remedies, they did not act, he gave Puls. and did very well. He said, this was the opposite of Puls.
as a constitution, as we know Puls. She was very strong woman, very authoritative, it was her character, her personality. For me this was normal, on this level.
What he described to me and the pathology was very severe, it was a Pulsatilla pathology. And he was amazed. How George thought about this case of being Pulsatilla.
I thought because the local, physical symptoms indicated Pulsatilla, ignoring the fact of the character, her personality. He described to me the personality, it was not Pulsatilla at all.
That means Pulsatilla has not affected the mental or emotional side of this patient. But if he had told me for instance that she was so strong and harsh and things like that but lately she cried one time.
That means Pulsatilla has started touching now the emotional level as well. Such a person can become Puls. emotionally and physically but you will see the changes from her personality.
So therefore sometimes you can treat only local symptoms and still treat correctly, treat on totality, treat on the way that you mean constitutional. Constitutional treatment, if you want to say between wrong treatment and correct treatment
you say, either constitutional is the correct treatment and non-constitutional is the wrong treatment. But this can not be separated.
-For example yesterday somebody... I'm sure a lot of Homeopaths would have called yesterday's case constitutional Sepia in an acute or chronic state of Aconite. You could say, you could give Aconite but the constitutional symptoms of Sepia are stronger than the Aconite symptoms.
A lot of people would make this opposition of acute symptoms of Aconite and symptoms of Sepia being a constitutional long term remedy.
-Yes but in case she needs Aconite first, you cannot avoid. You have to give Aconite first before you give Sepia.
-Because the terminology, I mean it sounds logical but a lot of people, also you, you use terminology of constitutional treatment in another way.
And say, long term symptoms or acute symptoms if you take into consideration, you will treat constitutionally.
-Well if in this idea of Kunzli they will take symptoms from the birth to the time and collect all this information and find which is the remedy which is mostly running through etc. and give it and they call it the consitutional remedy.
This can be valid only in very healthy individuals. The other individuals they change the remedy. I have seen and individual who is Sulphur becoming Aurum under stress.
Under stress becomes Aurum. You give Sulphur, it doesn't effect him. And he had a disappointment, he is in depression, he sits there and you see the depression. You give Aurum and it goes out.
He has changed in the same way that a Calcarea carbonica patient when he goes into bronchitis, it will become Bryonia, it will become Rhus tox, Belladonna, whatever.
- What you say now that one is acute and the other is constitutional remedy or you wouldn't use these words?
-No, I don't like to use the idea of constitutional remedy at all in the homeopathic understanding.
-Or constitutional treatment?
-No, I say the remedy which covers the best possible totality is the remedy that should be given but this remedy can not be called constitutional, unless we find out later on in life that whatever happens to this person, Sulphur is the remedy.
With acute condition Sulphur, with chronic condition Sulphur, has a lumbago Sulphur, he has an influenza Sulphur. In this case we can use the word constitutional but only in this way.
Many times they have approched me, people in congresses and say, what do you think is my remedy? I say, I don't know. How can I know what is your remedy.
This thinking that there is a constitutional, there is a type which you look and you say, this is Calc. type because he is fat. He is not always, sometimes it is but most of the time it is not, why not Graphites.
Why not Ferrum or Opium or all the other remedies which have a tendency to get obese. You can not differentiate just by looking at a person.
Of course some signs are there and I can look if somebody is sad, is closed etc. but I take this little part as one information together with all the other information. My observation comes together.
So the idea of constitutional unless we arrive at a stage of very good health, the whole of humanity, then it will be easy to discern the remedy and even if we imagine that the whole world can come to that level of health, the individuals are quite healthy, they need one remedy
still I say, underneath that remedy will be another one, always. There is no end and who will discover that secret he may stay alive for ever.
-George I remember about one and a half year ago the case of S. She had very inflamed elbow and the local symptoms was very prominent. It was red, it was swollen, it was terrible. She had lots of pain and you didn't ask even one question about the local symptoms.
You asked her, you don't like certain people? She said yes and you gave Natrum carbonicum.
-No, it's not like that. Don't give me qualities which I don't have. She has given me enough information to think of Calc. at the moment.
It is not that she did not give me other information, I just saw it and I asked this question. No, she had already given me hints and most probably she is going towards Nat-c., then I asked the question.
You see many times especially in the beginning when I was treating Krishnamurti and I was with these people. The people around the gurus are quite fantasy people and they thought that I had certain supernatural qualities.
So everyone would come and would say to me, oh you are a special individual and you had intuition and that's why you can find the remedy.
And I was mad when somebody is coming and say, 'this is intuition' I'm mad because I know how much work I have put into this "intuition".
I know myself how much work and study and battle and all that. This is not intuition, it is information which of course comes very fast, I analyse very fast a situation.
That is true because I have the information. I can analyse very fast.
-In this case it was very impressive for me that you decided not to focus on the local symptoms but you had to go one layer deeper. I would like to know which are the reasons? How can I see it?
-I will give you the reasons. When I see something which does not give me information, a local situation. If you say, I have cystitis, burning, when I urinate I have a burning.
When do you have the burning? Before, after? I can not make out. Then immediately I will go to the general symptoms. Do you feel cold or hot, do you drink milk etc.?
I know Natrum carbonicum has burning pain in the end of urination but this patient has burning before, during and in the end of urination. But if she does not like milk it's very important.
I say, do you like milk? No. Ok, Natrum carbonicum, go. That's also how you make mistakes.
-Thank you.
-You see what you know as information is that no other remedy has burning in the end of urination with aversion to milk. That you know as information. So if you see two strong symptoms of that type and you know
that no other remedy has these two symptoms, you prescribe on the two symptoms. But if you can not, then you investigate more and more.
Don't get ever the idea that I ever prescribe a remedy on intuition. Forget it, for me it's something unbelievable that I will say something which I don't know why but I think. This is something beyond me.
I will always have an absolute reason and basis on which I know why I prescribe that remedy. I don't know if it was your group with a case where she fell down and almost unconscious and she was lying in the bed inside there
and very excited, I think it was the Italian group, and her husband was there holding her and I touched her knees. I saw it was very cold. I put my hand a bit higher, no cold. The knees were absolutely cold.
I said, bring a dose of Phosphorus without asking any question. With th Phosphorus she came back immediately. She came back, got up and she left.
This is not intuition, this is knowledge. I put together all. She was afraid of the whole situation that she was almost unconscious. But the husband was there holding her hand
she looked as a very serious condition but it was not. It was a hysterical kind of reaction and a fear more than the actual damage of the accident.
And Phosphorus brought back the whole balance.
You may say why do I touch the knees. Because I saw the situation with the husband and I thought of Phosphorus. And I said ok if this is a confirmatory symptom and it was, ok give it.
-One question. Hahnemann calls his first five editions of Organon, Homeopathy and Science and in the last edition, the sixth, he calls it Homeopathy and Art. I think it must be something of intuition in all these.
-I'm not inside the brain of Hahnemann to answer you this question but what I can say is this that Hahnemann realised that things are not as simple as he thought in the beginning.
He says, give the totality of the symptoms. The similar remedy will cure and he was very sure about it. He was so sure that he would attack anybody who will ever challenge his ideas very viciously. He was absolutely sure.
Eventually as the years went by he found out, the first he finds out that yes there is a cure but there is a relapse. What shall we do?
We bring the miasms, the idea of the miasms. He found a deeper remedy. And then eventually he found out things were not as simple as he thought in the beginning. So he understood the complexity of the human nature and human disease.
He understood that and once he understood that most probably thought, well to find the remedy is really a difficult task which requires something more than absolutely scientific rules.
And he called it the Art.
-It's very nice what we say today about groups and levels and it's very simple but when the patient came to us and she had a few symptoms of Calcarea, of Lycopodium and Arsenicum how do we know what to give him as the firsts level of remedy?
The first is not very apparent. And I saw yesterday with the case of anxiety and fears, I can't sleep all the night. All the time I think how you came to the Sepia remedy because the main symptoms were fear.
And she came for that to ask help and we gave Sepia.
Two reasons. The answer is very easy. The moment I asked her about her sexual, I immediately if I show you back, you will see a remark of mine. Before she speaks about her sexual condition there is a remark I have made which you must have heard.
I said, forget it there is no sexual desire. I realised immediately from her face, there is nothing. That gave me already the idea of Sepia and the leukorrhea which was there. These two symptoms gave me the idea of Sepia.
Because if you have aversion sex or indifference to sex and at the same time you have leukorrhea all along, that means this case most probably is a Sepia case inspite of the fact
that we dont' know Sepia has that kind of fears but still it was very interesting the symptom which has been recorded of fear, of imminent death. She used the same word and it was quite confirming what she found.
But for me I did not mean this confirmation because I could see this symptomatology had a lot of Sepia together with two keynotes.
-I had a question about the constitutional remedy and my question regards information that we get from the Organon, par.9 where Hahnemann first says about restoring the organism to harmonious operation with regards the sensation and function, the purpose
of which is to allow the individual to use the organism, the physical body to fulfill his/her high purposes. I am wondering is it now possible, if we think of the organism
the physical body as material and think of it as a fabric, like cloth. That over time this cloth wears thin according to nature. The spirit does not have to wear thin, the emotional state does  not have to wear thin,
and the intellect does not have to wear thin, they can evolve, they can move higher. However the physical body must involve, it must be destroyed at some point. It is according to the laws of nature.
Is it not then possible to find a remedy which most closely allows the physical organism to fulfill as a vehicle away from the higher parts of the organism?
-Ok I will tell you what you want to ask.
-Ok I'm glad that you can do that. Your intuition understands this question.
-Most probably you want to ask, is it possible to find a remedy that will make the body in such good condition that will allow the higher, which is the mental, the spiritual to function better.
Is this possible to find a remedy which directs itself to the physical body mostly?
-Harmoniously with all the parties.
-The answer always is the same. You have the three levels and the disease is distributed, a part here, a part here and a part there. Or a big part here, a little here and a very little here.
Or very big, little here and very little here. Whatever is the combination, you as a Homeopath what you have to do is only to give the correct remedy and the organism will decide how this will be modified.
You see this person here with this problem on mental, is not possible to evolve spiritually. Why? Because he is bothered, he has fixed ideas, he has fears.
He can not evolve, he can not dedicate himself into spiritual evolution. But you give the remedy and the organism decides to take this, to take this and to reduce this to here. But here it makes a big depression.
And then you continue to treat until here you have a physical disease which is quite degenerating. So once you reach that point the person is degenerating, there is no way to be saved but
saved physically but it can be saved spiritually.
It has the possibility to evolve as a human being and it has the possibility to be useful to the society where here it was a danger to society, was a negative part of society.
Here he can be useful and we had cases where a mathematician who is suffering a lot with a severe neuro-muscular disease, I don't remember his name. Hawking right, who is supposed to be a genius and a lot of other people
who are having cancer, Rama Krishna for instance. He is known to die from cancer but emotionally-mentally was very clear.
I know several other spiritual people who their physical body is deteriorated very fast, yet their mental-emotional was in quite good condition.
Now once you reach this, when the disease is so strong, the Homeopathy the only thing that can do is to clear up the higher levels but not this level.
This level is gone because of hereditary, of misuse of the body etc. whatever reasons. This physical body must go. Of course here comes the conventional Medicine and say
ok I change your heart, a put you a new heart, a new this, a new that and the whole world is looking. But when we present cases like the one I presented you yesterday with the gangrene
the two legs were saved 1000 times. At least we have 1000 cases of gangrene treated with Homeopathy, ready to be amputated and did not.
The whole world is saying nothing about that but say about putting a plastic heart or a plastic kidney. They admire very much and what is the quality of that individual living with this heart?
You see how twisted is our mind?