We're talking today about the meaning
of homeopathic consultation.
We're going to talk about
preparation of the Homeopath.
I will just give you some basic ideas which have come out of my experience.
What does it mean that an individual decides to go to a doctor and in particular to a Homeopath? What it means?
First of all it means that the individual is suffering; that's why he decides to go to see a doctor, to see a Homeopath.
And what is your position? Your position is that you come to me and I will cure you.
So here we have a phenomenon which has two faces. One outside face where the person appears and you are there
sitting in your room and an inner phenomenon which is the expectation of the patient that he will be well
and your expectation that you will give him health.
Actually this meeting has a necessity for a double preparation. An outside preparation and an inside, inner preparation.
The outside preparation is that you went to a school, you learned certain methods and then after you felt good and secure,
you open a clinic or a practice and you got nice furniture, the best possible furniture and a nice atmosphere
so when the patient comes, feels that he is comfortable and that you are a very important person.
Because you have a big throne on which you
are sitting and this can impress the patient.
So there is actually in everyone who is doing this an outside preparation, as I say, starting from the day where
they decide to learn this method and the preparation, the main thing of it ends when he has opened his office
and he has furniture and things like that. These are important things but what matters in that whole preparation?
It mattters how much study you put on it,
from the very beginning.
One wants to study, one says one more, one less. So it matters how much preparation you are doing really
in order to meet the challenge. What is the challenge? The challenge is something which is actually
so beyond to your human capacity that you can say it does not matter how much preparation I may have, still I may fail.
You know all that. In Medicine is not so strong this. You don't need this because you know that in an duodenal ulcer
you will give an anti-acid drug, you will give this and that, even your nurse knows what to give.
So everybody will give the same once you have learned what the medical agents that come from the pharmaceutical companies
have given you the latest information
this is the best remedy that you give for rheumatoid arthritis;
then the next day you take the remedy and you give it to all the rheumatoid arthritis cases.
In Homeopathy is a totally different story. The preparation is quite on a different level.
Because you have decided that this method, the conventional method is not satisfying, is not cure.
I like to find a method which really gives back health to the people.
And then you search and you prepare yourself, you go to different seminars, one seminar after another seminar
and finally you end up with Vithoulkas in Alonissos and then things look very, very difficult, very challenging.
And the question is what kind of a mind is that which can take up the challenge. What is the right frame of mind?
What is the right frame of feelings of a student who wants to bring about cures that almost border into the miraculous.
You are not prepared to cure little colds, warts and the after effects of a bump. You give Arnica or Thuja and you have some effect.
You are prepared here to meet real challenges with severe pathology, people who are suffering very deeply
and they come eventually to you to be relieved from their suffering.
So who comes to you? The more famous you are, the most known, the more difficult cases will come.
That means those cases that have been
rejected entirely by all other therapists.
So you can imagine the expectation, the inner preparation of such individual. Such individual has done some research,
he found out that Mr Jonh D. is the best
and he makes all the effort to go there.
The expectation is there and you
are Mr/Mrs John D. how do you feel?
It is of great importance how is your inner preparation.
Do you feel I am the greatest and
I'm going to cure everybody?
It doesn't matter what you show outwards.
The outwards appearance, as I said, is different.
The outward preparation, the outside preparation, what you look like, you put the most expensive collars,
you put ties, you put these impressive
clothes, you do whatever you like.
Eventually what is going to matter is the inner preparation. I can tell you, you are very good and you are in a little room,
you just have room for two chairs to sit sometimes you don't have a third chair when a family comes.
You say, you stand all the time and the other
two only sit there and see what happens.
But there is something which happens
when your inner preparation is correct.
That these people they don't care whether you stand, you sit, where you sit what clothes you wear etc.
There is an atmosphere which is created inside that little room which gives confidence to the people.
You think that if I have an impressive room, this will give confidence to the people. No. What will give confidence
is your inner preparation. Your outer preparation has started with study and what you needed for this,
the number one of what you needed, is enthusiasm to overcome all the difficulties that will come in your way.
Great enthusiasm and great one pointed mind, I'm going to learn that. Where is a book?
I read it.
Where is a new information? I will get it etc.
Enthusiasm and relentless gathering of information.
But if is missing the idea and the
desire to help the other person,
if you're not interested, if you say,
I'm good, I know, take Phosphorus,
if you have this attitude where you don't really care what is going to happen to the individual,
as long as you cover
some symptoms, you pretend in any way that you have done something for the individual
as long as there is this attitude,  forget about the success in Homeopathy.
For a time being you can be successful, you will be getting very tired of yourself and of listening to patients.
Because if you have the right preparation
which is enthusiasm and the desire to heal,
it is a great thing to see somebody who is suffering come back and say, I'm not suffering, so much at least.
It is something which is almost bordering to the miraculous. It's beautiful and every healer is really filled with energy
and with satisfaction when he gets this feedback. Now if you take this feedback and for one moment,
I tell you for one moment, you think really in yourself 'I'm the best or I'm good or I'm very good' or all these things
which you attribute to yourself, things have happened and you attribute to yourself, to your abilities.
It doesn't matter how you show outwardly, inwardly you should never believe that what you see happening
as a kind of miraculous cures are because of you.
You should not think, not for one moment because the next moment another case will come,
the moment that you say, 'oh how great!' it will be a disaster.
You don't know what to do. You are losing your mind, then the patient is dying. What shall I do?
Call the doctor, give all the antibiotics,
give cortisone, anything, you're lost.
Why? Because you had the impression what you're succeeding to do the day before, you could do it all the time.
Not with Homeopathy. Homeopathy demands from the individual to be very much aware of what is going on all the time.
Even a thought , I've done it. You talk to yourself, eh be careful.
The next challenge is going to be much worse than that.
So the desire is there, the enthusiasm is there but the idea that 'I'm doing it' should not be there.
There is a kind of almost fear, I would say fear, when you take the simplest case, there is a fear that you may fail.
The idea is like somebody who makes miracles.
Will I be able to do something supernatural?
It is almost to that extent, the difficulty of treating with Homeopathy is to the extent that you are doing some kind of...
it's so difficult attainment as if you perform a miracle. Is it possible to know that you can do it everytime? No!
Especially when you have the attitude that I can do it. Because the moment you have the attitude you can do it,
I tell you what happens to many of my students. They became very famous and then eventually..... Why?
I am famous now. Then I relax. Now I can sit back, I can have a boat and go sailing in the seas of Aegean.
Then you start losing the information. It's something very peculiar that happens in such cases where you start
losing the information. The Homeopath who
felt 'now I'm good' starts going down the gutter.
And as I said, there are a lot of my students who they, inspite of being very successful in the beginning,
because information is information. Information is fresh, you take it, you apply, you see the results,
immediately the fame is augmenting, becoming more and more.
There is a time when you feel 'now I'm secure'. That is the time when your fall starts as a healer, as a homeopathic healer.
The reason is that in a homeopathic consultation from the moment it starts to the moment it finishes,
after 3 years of treatment or 5, 2 years, 1 month of treatment whatever there is another inner phenomenon taking place.
This person is suffering, 10, 20 years and suddenly he comes there with the idea I may become well.
But what is to become well for a person who is suffering 20 years? 20 years of suffering and suddenly
somebody will say, 'ok be well, just whisper Pulsatilla'. It's finished the problem. He says, my God this is a phenomenon
if you really see the whole thing it is a phenomenon. It is an idea which is beyond the logical abilities of the human being.
This person is suffering for 20 years and now is going to be released. What needs to be done?
Certain actions have to be done. Certain functions have to be done in order to arrive really at that state
where the person says, I'm not suffering anymore. What are these functions, conditions that have to be fulfilled?
You know that we have been acused of having placebo effect in our treatment.
Is it true or not?
Of course it is true. What is the placebo effect for us. The placebo effect is mostly the fact that you spoke to an individual
who felt that you really understood him/her.
She felt at ease and she felt that this person is really listening.
Why she felt that he really listens?
Because you are interested. Why you are interested? Because you have the desire to help.
So you have the desire to help.
Really the desire to help.
I don't mean a logical desire to help. I mean a real inner desire to help. My God I wish I could give him back health.
Oh my God he is suffering so much. What can I do? And then you battle, you battle inwardly. Anything else you forget.
My secretary says, you have a very good memory, eveybody who knows me says you have a good memory.
I don't have a good memory. I have a good memory only for the cases which they were suffering very much
and I remember them. Then I can remember for years what was happening to that individual.
Otherwise I don't have a good memory. I forget my keys, my car, I walk back home and the car is there, you know all kind of things.
If you really look in this interview it is a meeting point and a very important point in your life and in the life of the person.
It's almost a love affair. Can you forget a love affair? No. That's why I remember all my cases.
But on the outside what you show it is different and should be different than the inside. The inside
should not be revealed. I want to cure you. I love you very much and you hug the patient, you touch.
Forget all these tricks, they don't work.
They work for keeping some clientele because they say, oh what a nice doctor etc. but the real issue which is,
can you cure me, will never be realised.
What happens is different than the external way of behaving towards the patient. You could say nice words
when you feel that the person is in real distress, of course.
You can be nice but also you should be
detached from the person itself.
You are attached to the idea of helping him,
not to the person.
Because the moment you get attached to the person, what a nice woman, yes come in, what's your problem?
The woman also looks at you, what a nice man. Well, she forgets the problem and she starts little things.
What you think about this pimple here?
Terrible! I must cure you.
And the real issues if you get involved on a personal level, you will never discover what is going on inside the person.
Because you are looking on the outside. You're looking at a person whom you like. But what you like?
You like the outside, her physique,
nice hair, the style etc.
And this is attachment and it has as a result not being able to see clearly what is going on with the individual.
So therefore a Homeopath should, on top of everything else, be a master of his own feelings. You can imagine also when
you have given the right remedy to this nice woman, let us say, you like her and she comes back and she thanks you.
She looks at you like you are a God or a Godess.
It is an admiration and then you receive this admiration and you believe that you have beautiful eyes or whatever.
Don't get attached to this.
It's ok, I know I'm beautiful but what about
the follow up. Let's come to the follow up.
Let's come and see, can I further help you? Can I further investigate what's going on inside?
If you have this attitude then the phenomenon of healing starts happening. The real healing is a phenomenon.
We say we give energy, the remedies are energy. It is a phenomenon that is happening on another level than the physical.
And this phenomenon may start, as we say, with a placebo effect and continue and go deeper and deeper with the correct remedy.
Also the fact that you sympathise with the patient can augment, it can increase the placebo effect because it is homeopathic.
When somebody cries and you cry because of sympathy, it's like a homeopathic remedy because you sympathise.
That's why you should not sympathise.
Outside you should not show.
Especially the first years of my practice I have tried to control myself not to cry in certain stories that were so distressing
and so outrageous what was happening to the individual.
One tragedy after another to come to that condition. You hold yourself there and you say, I'm not going to cry
because the moment you start crying you cannot listen anymore.
Can you imagine? The person cries and you cry and you embrace each other and you say, oh, oh.
Then you go back to the Repertory, what to look?
You don't know what to look. You are upset.
You are out of your mind, you're sympathising. You have entered the state of the patient.
Can you imagine somebody who is just collapsing in front of you? You're collapsing next to him.
I remember a case in the center in Athens, he was a rather mature doctor and he comes while
I was looking
in different cases, in different rooms. He comes in the room, he says, George can you come?
The patient has collapsed. I go there and I saw the patient had collapsed and he doesn't know, he is a psychiatrist,
he is a neurologist and he does not know why the patient has collapsed. I go and I just see somebody
who is lying down there. He should be able to give me some information but no information, he has collapsed.
I said, ok don't collapse, wait. Tell me what happened, just a few information to know why is this,
because there is a shock,
there is a hysteria, epilepsy?
You lost, the moment you
got involved with the individual.
You don't sympathise, he is not sympathising. It doesn't matter.
What you know, you know. It is your problem whether you sympathise or not. It is not the problem of the patient to tell you.
Your job is to try to bring about the phenomenon of healing. That is where your energy is. I like, but don't ever say it.
Don't ever say it even to yourself, this is a state of mind. It's not something that can be brought about by logic.
The more you want to cure inwardly, the more your success. These are the rules here in this science.
If we go to the side of the preparation of the Homeopath, has to be an all round preparation.
It should not be a one-sided preparation. The Homeopath is going to advice in many, many issues of the patient.
The patient gets attached to the Homeopath. He sees that he found relief of his symptoms, he is attached to the doctor
and the doctor becomes his advisor. So he
will ask you, what to do with my daughter?
I have a problem with my daughter. She is a hippy. She is going out. What shall I do? And you have to advice.
And you are young, you are 35 and the man who is asking you for advice is 57 and he is the Dean of the University.
And he is asking you what to do. And that requires an open mind to learn, to listen.
To learn to listen.
Somebody has to tell you something. Ah you stupid you listen to this man or woman? Because I'm learning something.
Even from very simple people you can learn. Ah you are a Christian Orthodox. Why do you speak with the Catholics?
Or why do you speak with Jewish? When some Jewish man wants to tell me something about his religion,
I listen very carefully because I would like to know how they think, how they eat, how they feel.
If somebody is Muslim I listen. There is an inner teaching of Judaism, I'm interested, the Kabala etc.
There is an inner teaching of Muslims, it is the Suffis, I listen, I don't close. And then I receive the information
and that information makes me an all around person.
Somebody is an artist, he wants to give me
his point of view. I will listen, I will learn.
But I will never read junk, I will never go to a theater or cinema which is just a junk thing.
Cowboys, killing each other, what is there to learn?
So a Homeopath has to be an all around educated person that will be able to really give advice
but always that advice is not...I'm telling you.
It is almost a suggestion.
Almost the person does not know
that you have given a suggestion.
You have to be careful about these things  because sometimes we can become very hard
without understanding what we're doing.
There comes a girl, she is 26 and she confesses to you that she has never had an affair. She goes to a psychiatrist.
And the psychiatrist says, you want to be well? Ok, make sex. This is killing the patient, not helping the patient.
To a girl who never had, you say go and have sex. What is this? She has no idea what is this experience.
Don't be stupid, do this, do that. This is very dangerous to feel that you have the answer and you can give it.
There is no such answer because each individual is unique and you don't know all the factors all around to advice.
Because you expect that individual will listen and will never do so.
Because you don't know the factors, you don't know the 25 different parameters for the individual.
Again what I found out is that, whenever you try to give a direct advice, almost never worked out.
That's why I almost never give an advice. I give the remedy and then observe what is happening.
And the opening up of the individuals, how they slowly open up and they find by themselves, the way out from the problem.
And the only thing you can do is just encourage. Later on, after 2 years of treatment, this girl of 26 says I found a nice man
and I'm interested, you encourage. You say yes, why don't you... you encourage them.
But in the very beginning to say, take that advice or you are homosexual, stop being homosexual,
be a bit on the other side or whatever. This is
not your job because we are not advisors.
We are Homeopaths and we rely mostly upon the remedy which we give. So therefore after all this,
what is the meaning of the homeopathic consultation? Conclusion.
You see how difficult it is to cure a person
who will not give you information?
Or he will give you some information and some other information he thinks it's not your job.
Then it becomes very difficult or impossible to cure such an individual. Another comes and opens up and gives you information.
That is something like somebody admitting his weaknesses, admitting that I am a person with all these weaknesses
and when a person does this when somebody is full of heavy conscience, he has stolen things, he has killed people
and then eventually says, I will go to the priest to unload what is inside me.
That desicion is similar to the decision
of the person who goes to a Homeopath.
And the patient may not know exactly what
he has to do but your interest will show him
that it is to his benefit if he tells you what's happening inside and you can come to a conclusion.
So the meaning is the starting of
a clearing up of detoxification.
I don't want to use words that can be misunderstood like confession.
It is the beginning of cleaning the inside and then it happens that when he gives you out this, what is happening inside him
which bothers him and makes him suffering, then you are able to decide on the correct remedy and help him
by giving the correct remedy.
And then the miracle takes place.
So you have to see the homeopathic
consultation as something almost mystical.
You cannot really have success if you see
the patients as people who are going to
give you so much money.
Actually my belief is that this service which we call Homeopathy, should not be given against money.
But the Homeopaths should be
supported either by the governments
or by very rich people who don't
know what to do with their money.
-I disagree with that statement.
-Sure. I don't say all that in order to agree but just to think about and sleep over and in a few years time you come back
and you tell me if you agree or you disagree.
From all these people here you agree the most. You don't know it.
I say in an ideal society, in which society certain people have been given the privilege to have a lot of money,
some others have been given the privilege of being able to cure people, this has to be distributed.
The good has to be distributed so there is eventually an equality, real equality, not the communistic idea
that there is a group of people sitting on a government decision and all the others are slaves
that they have to work for the governement. This is not the idea. My idea is much more idealistic than this one.
Somebody was telling me that I have a problem, this morning, she was telling me I have a problem charging money.
I had a problem for years. I said, how shall I charge money for that thing. It was something which was giving me
so much pleasure. I was working as an engineer in the morning and in the evening I was curing people.
For years I couldn't think of taking
money from any person.
But when it came to the architect for whom I had worked previously and then he had arthritis.
-The Ledum case.
-It doesn't matter what is the remedy. The story is more important, when he said I have a uric arthritis
and he couldn't wear his shoes. He said, can you cure me? I said, yes but you're going to pay me so much.
He thought, if he does it I will do it but I don't believe he will do it. Well he paid suddenly for all the other people
that were coming and I was not charging anybody for my services I didn't even feel were services.
I thought that actually it was, you may not believe this but the pleasure was so much that I really did not care.
There was an incident where I treated a man with a tumor in the brain. He had to be operated and I treated him for quite some time.
He was coming, going, coming, going, I was even giving the medicines myself, the little powder.
In the end he makes an X-ray the tumor was not appearing anymore. So in the end of the treatment he comes
and gives me 100 drachmas. 100 drachmas
by that time equals to 1000 drachmas today.
Let us say, 5 marks. Actually the amount
where you can buy a beer or two coffees.
He leaves these money and he says 'I just give you something to have some beer' there is an expression in Greek.
And I was for 2 days I could not close my mouth.
I said God, what is my mistake,
what have I done?
The man was serious. He thought he was paying me back for the services I have done for him.
And I kept on doing the same thing of course until, you don't know the story? How I started charging?
-No.
- I started charging from 59 to 69. For 10 years I did not charge anybody, anything. In 69 during the dictatorship,
it was all kinds of spies were giving information
to the police and most probably
somebody gave the information that there something was going on that was very suspicious.
And the chief of the police got interested. What is this? Is this a kind of "yafka" where they prepare a revolution
to overturn the government or something like that? Secretive people who will not speak and the chief of the police,
like the secret police of the area came together with a man in civilian clothes and they had a kind of X-ray.
He came to be examined by me and the young man had a duodenal ulcer. I said, where is your pain?
The pain is here. Where it extends? I investigated and at a certain moment I said,
what is this?
Either he is stupid, he doesn't look stupid, or something is wrong.
At a certain moment I was with one of my first students who was a psychiatrist, next to me,
but she would not talk, she was just learning.
And I was doing all the investigation and at a certain moment they said, some things that didn't make sense at all.
I said to him, 'why are you here'? He said, 'I have ulcer I want to be cured'. I said, 'are you sure you have ulcer?'
'Yes, yes'. I said, 'no you don't have ulcer. Forget it. When I ask you this, you answer this.
When I ask you again later on the same question, you answer the opposite. Which one
is the true?'
There is an excitement. They said, 'give me the medicine'. They expected to give them the little powders.
I said, 'no I won't give you the powders, just go out'. The chief of the police sitting next to him without speaking until that time.
He brings out his wallet to pay. 'How much we owe you'? I said, 'nothing, go out'. 'No, we must pay'. I said, 'out'.
When he saw me in that state, he pulls out the ID and says, I'm the chief of the police. I said, ok what do you want?
He says, 'are you a medical doctor'? 'No. She is a medical doctor'. She pulls out her ID card and gives it to him.
He was in a state of upset. He said,
'come with me to the police'. We go.
On the way he walks next to me, he says 'she is a medical doctor'. I said, 'yes'. 'Then why don't you charge money'?
Very suspicious because people were there and they were cured and did not charge money.
I said, 'under these conditions I cannot explain you why we don't charge money'.
We walk a bit further. He says, 'she is a medical doctor'. 'Yes'. 'Why don't you charge money?
It is very difficult for me to explain. What to say now to the chief of the police who takes you there to investigate?
And you will say, I pretend to be a saintly man who would like to cure people.  He will say, he is crazy.
He will grasp me and put me inside. I said, 'no I can't explain'. Then we go to the police. They had got all the patients
that they were coming before. They had collected all of them. So there is a conspiracy.
Most probably against the government or against anything. Then they investigate and I'm sitting on the other room
and I'm listening to the investigation of the different patients.
Did they charge money? No, they didn't. Did they charge money? No. They could not understand what the hell was going on.
I remember also I hear an old woman who was investigated last. So she said, 'listen my son if you are sick,
you are always go to to go to him. Because he cures the people'. But in the meantime they have caught all the sugar pills we gave.
'What is this white stuff?' They sent it for examination and then he comes to me to investigate.
He says, 'do you smoke'? I said, 'no'.
He said, 'what is this Homeopathy?'
'Well it's a system you don't know yet. Maybe in a few years you will know'. In the meantime I hear the telephone.
They were several people because my student who was left behind she calls influential people who were cured
and these people were just calling
back and saying, let him go.
The biggest suspicion was because
we did not charge money.
If we were charging, it would be no problem because we're living in a society which believed in charging money.
And I belonged most probably to another society and I felt like coming from the moon.
And I remember a story from Dostoyefski where somebody was doing something similar. All the society was suspecting him,
it's not possible that he is not part of all
of us and he does something very different.
Since that time I said to her, now we're going to charge every patient who comes, he will pay money.
Of course we charged very little. And
the whole thing continued very well.
Actually the man got promoted, he became the general secretary of the Ministry of Justice and the Ministry of Health
only put a fine on me and the doctor
because we gave the medicine ourselves.
There was a rule in Greece that the
medicine should go through the pharmacy.
The doctor did not have the right to dispense medicines. So they fine 5000 for me and 5000 for her.
10000 was a big amount for the time. So I went I tried to find him in the police, they said he is in the Ministry,
the General Secretary. I asked to see
him. I said, 'Sir what have you done?
You said all this for the investigation, this and that. Now we have to pay 10000. Where can we find them
since you know that we had no charged anybody. Where can we find that money to pay?' He felt like a fool.
He says, 'I have made a very good report for you and in case you need it, I can give you a good report that you are a good man'.
I said, 'thank you very much. Are you prepared to pay the 10000?'. Of course he was not prepared because
his salary was less than 10000. He had
to pay all his salary to pay the fine'.
But from that time we are forced to charge. That's why I say, I don't believe in charging for these services
because first of all these kind of services have no price. You cannot say you pay me this or you pay me that.
These services I don't think they have a price. First of all they cost nothing from an ethical point of view
and they cost too much from a material point of view.
Because if you can give back the health to some people who have lost it, it's something which is absolutely precious.
You give them some very very precious
thing for which they can pay what?
That's why my idea is...but you hear her
saying 'I cannot charge', of course.
Anyone of you, when you started
you have similar experiences.
So these are a few things which concern the homeopathic consultation and the inner and outer happening.
-I've always charged because I feel the most honest thing you can do with a person is to charge him for your services.
Because this way they don't owe you anything, there is no sense of gratitude in the wrong way.
Of course when we restore health is a priceless thing for which you can never really pay; there is no way of
figuring out how much money will be but I really think that by charging the person you keep the relationship
very clean and very professional,
that's why I believe in charging.
-You are right, absolutely right when you say that they have to pay something to feel that they don't owe you.
But if you feel inside you that they don't
owe you, it doesn't matter what they feel.
If I forget, today I received a telephone call from Israel from a student of mine. He said, there is a department in the hospital
for which I am now in charge and I have invited 40 medical professors and one professor from England and different places.
And do you remember the name of a professor so and so. I said, no I don't remember. He is a professor from England who says,
'ah George will be the speaker, that is great because I was his patient and he cured me and all that'.
I don't even remember his name. For me, he does not owe me. For him, still after 20 years
he may feel gratitude. But for me, inside, I don't feel that because I cure him he owes me something.
So from your point of view it is correct in helping the patient and the society is such that we have to imply this method at this moment.
There is no other way. They have to pay because you have the rent, your secretary and all these expenses.
You need some money to do it. That is true but
I say in a society, in an ideal society then in order to equalize things,
so the poor people do not have the stress. I hear for instance, today again, that one of my students is charging
3 times the money that usually charge. I told her to just go away from the center because she over charged certain people
and all the other doctors are working, you cannot have a doctor suddenly saying, no my price is that.
I said, alright you did 2,3 times, 10 times out. Now I hear the story that there is a very poor family from Skopelos
and they have to pay double the price. So they come here to be treated and they pay all this price and the story is told
by another man, friend to the family. He says, they're doing very difficult to pay all these money every month
to pay this doctor who says she is your right hand. This doctor says, I am the right hand of Mr.Vithoulkas.
I said, not even the left, nevermind the right.
But this kind of exploitation, you see
how easy it is to start the exploitation.
Once you block your conscience then
you start all these kind of things.
Forget about finding the remedy. You will battle and battle and battle and nothing will happen.
-George, I remember that Hahnemann he loses his license by the beginning of last century because he was charged
with giving the remedies himself without payment to the people. They found this reason to take his license.
-Also in the life of Hahnemann, if you read it you will see his students ask these questions repeatedly.
And then he says, you charge, you make sure that they pay. And then he comes to America with Kent he says,
not only charge but when anybody shows the least doubt for your treatment, just stop the treatment and go out.
As soon as they doubt you, leave them. And he was a giant. Because he felt that people should have
a very great estime
and his integrity was put into question.
Like they acuse us all of us, you are charlatan. I'm charlatan? Goodbye.
-I didn't charge when I started and I noticed that people didn't take me seriously. I put an awful lot of hours and hours
and gave them medicine and next day they did whatever they like. That's why I decided well, they are going to pay
and then they take me seriously.
-Sure. All these issues are in a society which has a lot to learn still. We're living in a society with a lot of weaknesses
and a lot of misunderstandings.
And we have a lot to learn.
There is all over the world Homeopathy beyond border. There is a group of people called "Homeopathy beyond border"
and they work and they're doing quite a nice thing. It would have been nice if each country  would do it for her poor people,
for people who can't afford and it pushes the Homeopathy and the knowledge about Homeopathy all over.
-The first thing is to learn good Homeopathy
and then everything can be done.