In the program which I see here, I see a few things which we have not spoken about and
I would like to touch upon these matters.
One is handling of remedies that means many times you have the remedies yourself and you're dispensing
the remedies and you have to be
careful how you do it.
First of all it is good if you handle the remedies yourself, you don't give a prescription, not to touch the remedies.
When it comes to the point where you have to do it, empty on a piece of paper with a little bit of sugar powder,
so the little pills won't run away
but don't touch every time the remedy.
At this moment we don't know whether touching a remedy means you have been affected already by the remedy.
So if you are a Homeopath and you're doing every day this, you have to be careful not to touch the remedies.
The second thing is that if you keep the remedies in your house, you have to keep them away from the sun.
It  has been recorded that remedies that stay exposed to the sun many times are spoiled.
Another point that you have to be careful is when you open in the room the remedies, where you have your bottles,
you don't have any kind of perfume or when you have shaved and then you put some cream and your hand is still
full of this perfume don't handle the remedies. You have to wash your hands totally so there is no perfume at all.
Because perfume may sometimes spoil the remedy, so you don't give a remedy and your bottle is finished.
We know such cases quite a lot that they have been spoiled even in the pharmacy.
You have also to be careful and to demand from the pharmacies that they keep their remedies away from the camphor
or certain medicines which have
strong perfume in the pharmacies.
You have to tell them that the remedies should not be opened and closed in this environment.
Another thing, that we don't know yet whether it will affect your remedies when you travel,
the remedies pass through these X-rays.
We do not have yet information that the remedies are spoiled but it is good if you travel and you have your kit to say
'I don't want to pass it, this is what it is, it is homeopathic remedies, please let me go without passing through the X-rays'.
How you administer the remedies?
The best way is to dilute your remedy into a little bit of water and let the person drink the water.
This is the most immediate action.
Sometimes the remedy is given in a capsule and before this capsule is dissolved in the organism, there is no action.
If the pharmacy will give them a capsule and you want immediate action, like the case with acute insanity
I had to put it in water and you see the
moment that you throw the water,
(in cases where two people are holding someone in an acute state), the action is immediate.
So this is the best way, in water.
Now if you have one dose, 10 pills, 20 pills and you dilute in some water and you start giving a little bit of that water
every one hour, that is the same as if you have given everytime a new dose.
That means the original dose which you diluted in water, given 5 times it is like you have given 5 doses.
Exactly equivalent to 5 doses. There is no difference between this and every time giving some tablets, pills or whatever.
So water is a repetition, if you need a repetition you can do it this way, by diluting in water and repeat.
In severe cases almost invariably
you have to repeat the potency.
Also in acute cases with high fever, repetition
will be needed. You can do it through water.
This is the best, it is the most immediate action.
Now of course you can give remedies through tablets, through pills, through liquid, there are remedies
you buy them in liquid. If you take one drop of this liquid and you put it in water and you stir it,
you have a remedy which can be used 20-30 times.
Of course it is good not to put a full glass of water and to put one drop.
If you just put this, then you put 5-10 drops.
Here also you may be using low potencies, medium potencies or high potencies.
For high potencies, the best method for preparing them will be not the continuous flushing of water,
where they flush water through a bottle. But anyhow forget about the negative. I will tell you the positive.
When you want to prepare a remedy, the best way to prepare a high potency is through one bottle in which
you have put the water up to that point and here you have used this cork and then you shake this bottle
at least 10 times and the best way is to empty this bottle and refill it with twice distilled water and start again.
Now what happens is, when you empty this bottle here on the sides are some drops staying. This is the Korsakov.
I want to make you understand why this method is better than what they call, the Hahnemanian method where
sometimes they put a pipette here and they draw one portion and then they have another bottle
and then you put a new bottle with distilled water that has been taken from the middle of this bottle.
In this case where you use several bottles, 100 bottles, 1000 bottles, in this method you may not at a certain moment,
you may not be taking potentised
amount of distilled water, why?
Because as you dilute one after another, they form small clusters, which is an entity, a very minute.
These are molecules of water coming together because of the solvent. They have proven that these tend to
stick around the sides of the bottle.
So emptying this bottle and refilling it, you are much more certain that what has stuck here are those clusters
that have been formed because of potentisation.
So the Korsakov method is the best, as long as they do it properly of course; it will be the most effective.
The Hahnemann potentisation, as you may understand, is taking from these molecules around here the water,
you don't know whether these molecules contain these small clusters on which the information is carried.
In any case experience has shown that the Korsakov method gives reliable results.
Another question that we may
discuss is the placebo question.
Do we give placebo? Must we give placebo or we must give just one dose and forget about it?
I will give you my experience.
In Greece at least, in Athens, invariably we give a series of placebo after the initial potency.
And it has been proven that even people who they know about it they like to take it. It doesn't matter.
The issue has been discussed and a lot of people may know that they take placebo, still they will take it regularly.
This issue I was discussing in America and my students in America said, the American people are not as gullible
as the Greeks, so we cannot bluff them.
We only give them one dose, nothing else.
That proved to be a bad habit. The reason was that the patient did not really understand that maybe
the effect of the remedy he took, will be after a month, as a result asking within this period of time for another remedy
and the doctors would give him
another remedy and another remedy.
It was very surprising to Bill Gray who came
in Athens and stayed with me for two years.
He left his patients for one year, we were prescribing a remedy and said ok and they could not find him anymore.
When he came back after a year to take follow up's he said, George the results were phenomenal.
I said, do you see now what you're doing? He said, yes I realize I was giving remedies after remedies too frequently,
spoiling the cases. When I left them for a year
I see almost everybody...he came in an exciting state he says,
'you're right we should have given placebo'.
What is the idea of placebo?
The idea is to buy time, to make the patient feel he is taking a medicine, therefore you wait.
This is the message we're sending through placebo.
The message is that the effect can't be immediate. You have to wait to see the effect.
The longer you wait, the best you
will feel that is the message.
And why not using the placebo.
So I would recommend to give placebo in all your cases even if you're treating the Prime Minister of America.
When you treat anybody, it doesn't matter how clever may be, these issues they cannot know, it's a terra incognita for anybody.
It's an unknown area so you can tell this is my way of treating. Do you like to do it? Yes. You don't like, bye, bye.
There is no kind of 'shall I give, shall I not give?'.
Because the patient will perceive that, he will understand your hesitation. Somebody I give, somebody I don't give.
You just make it a habit, either
yes or no. If no, don't give.
A lot of people they will not attribute
the cure to yourself.
Later on I got a massage and
after the massage I was better.
But you have been taking massages
for 5 years, nothing was happening !
You know the story with the little boy and his father who said, George does not have to give you a remedy.
He has to just bump with the
hand and you will be alright.
I said, why did you say that ? Because when I brought my son with asthma you just made like this and said,
you will be alright and next day he did not have asthma. We brought him from Germany, he had asthma for 3 years,
you bump like that and the night
did not have asthma. He said, you don't remember?
I asked him to open his mouth and put a powder and he says, I can't remember and he was
circulating the story in Athens. I telephoned
and said, what are you doing?
He says, George honestly I don't remember.  I was absolutely sure that you did like this and the boy was ok.
He said, he was cured, you finished his asthma right there. I said, yes but with the powder.
You cannot persuade but if
I have given one month the placebo!
Many times you give a remedy and placebo for a month, nothing happens. And you continue to give placebo
the second month and the third month with the placebo he says, now that was the best remedy.
Why they say that? Because it took
3 months for the organism to come back.
Therefore you need this placebo,
otherwise you face a lot of problems.