I must say I'm very glad I'm coming back to Amsterdam after my experience last year which was very positive.
And I'm very glad that I see this year much more people attending which is a very encouraging fact.
I'm afraid that I will start this congress with some news which are not very good.
The news concern exactly that portion of the human body with which Homeopathy is dealing primarily, which is the immune system as you all know, it is the defense mechanism of the body.
And Homeopathy just tries to strengthen the immune system, the defense mechanism in a more general sense.
As you know, all the breaking down of the immune system is the cause today of this
very severe, fatal disease, AIDS.
You see, I don't believe that I can teach you anything in two days and I see some old students of mine coming here and expecting to have some new knowledge, I don't know if I can provide that.
But what I wanted to today, is to make you
aware of what is happening in the world
today concerning health in general.
I start by giving you a story which took place
14 years ago in Athens, in 1972 while I was lecturing in a group of medical doctors in Athens.
Based on my experience so far, an experience
of about 12 years at the moment, cases that
I had seen in depth, cases that I had taken
all the history and see what happened and
why had happened, why that person was
sick today and he was coming to see me.
Based on that experience I predicted, in this particular night, that if antibiotics were kept on pumping in the human body in the way that they were pumped through the allopathic profession,
soon we shall see that the immune system breaks down and opens up into a new set
of diseases that are going to be very severe
and most probably incurable.
In 1979, I read an article in Times magazine that they were about 15 new diseases appearing at the moment, the legionairres disease and many others.
That they were entirely new and their cause was unknown and of course it was 1981 or 82 that the question of AIDS arose.
And in 1986 we have very bad news concerning AIDS and I would like to read a little bit from
a report published in an American magazine.
That report comes from Dr John Seale,
a British expert on AIDS and it says that
the first question that an ABC reporter asks Seale it was why all the medical authorities disagreed with him and Seale pointed out that
in 1983 he said that AIDS could be transmitted to woman.
All the medical authorities disagreed and now he is proven to be right. He said that AIDS could be transmitted to babies. Everyone disagreed and now that has been proven to be true as well.
In 1984, he said the blood supply was tainted and the Red Cross said it was impossible. The authorities have been wrong on every issue before Seale said, so why would they be right now?
Doctor Seale made an appearance in television in October 2d, last October. There he immediately clashed with other panelists who denied the possibility of transmission
of AIDS amongst children.
There is no doubt, he reported, the scientific evidence has now been published that AIDS can be transmitted from one child to another. I'm sorry but it has been published in the Lancet
the very important scientific journal from England. The case just published two weeks
ago of a 3 years old boy who had a blood transfusion and died of AIDS a few years later.
He infected his brother by biting him. It's all
been published and this incident was in West Germany. There were about 7 doctors who
wrote these articles they checked with their
governments because of the implications of this before publishing it. This is like a famous case of the first known infection by blood transfusion. It was supposed to be impossible until the end of 83.
It was denied in the U.S.A. that this was possible and now it's a well known fact. As we go to
press, Dr Seale was scheduled to give a
press conference at the National Press
Club in Washington in October 3rd.
The following are excerpt from the testimony of Dr Seale before join hearings of the Californian Senate Health and Human Services Committee, an Assembly Committee in Sacramento, September 29th.
Dr Seale is a member of the Royal College of physicians and runs a private practice in
London, specialized in genito-urinary
Medicine and sexually transmitted diseases.
In early 1983 he started studying the epidemiology, pathogenesis, prognosis and transmission of AIDS, virus infection and has published numerous articles and letters on this subject.
He said, 'I'm honored to have been invited by the Senator of California to testify before your Committee today. This is the second time in 4 months I have been invited to the USA to speak about AIDS. In May, the Governor of N.Y.
asked me to speak on the impact of AIDS on public policy. Today I have 15 minutes to explain my endorsement. Some of you are old enough...' and then he goes on and he quotes Professor William Haseltine of Harvard University
and he says that this Professor believes that 100% of people will die within 20 years or so of the infection, that means nobody will escape.
He calls him a pessimist. This is why he testified before in the Committee in Washington, a year ago that AIDS was species threatening. In simple english Professor Haseltine believes that AIDS virus has the capacity to spread and to kill every man, woman and child on earth.
And the optimist Professor L. of San Francisco believes that nearly 50% will die from an infection with the virus, the other 50% will come to little or no harm. This optimistic vision makes AIDS twice as deadly as small pox and as deadly as
bubonic plague because of the plague death in the 14th century which killed 1/3 of the entire population of Europe.
What are the prospects of a cure? Once the pro-viral DNA is placed into your own genes, no product of the pharmaceutical industry will ever get it out.
Any drug which blocks the replication of the virus, which is the most that can be expected,
will have to be continued for life.
And the prospect for vaccine. Few of the antibodies that are naturally produced, are neutralizing.
Some of those that are, get knocked out by antigenic shedding. Most of the in vivo site
of pathology is immunologically mediated. Intracellular spread of the virus,
during membrane contact invades antibodies. Antigenic drift is continuous in every infected host. All these factors combined make an effective vaccine, theoretically impossible.
And then he goes on, he proposes that Mr. Reagan and Mrs. Thatcher and other leaders
of the world they come together and take measures.
In 1974, I started writing my book "The Science of Homeopathy" and in there I have seen the effect of Syphilis treated by antibiotics.
And in the first edition of this book I've stated
that Syphilis is not really cured by antibiotics
but it is rather suppressed and it will appear
in other forms, eventually.
The same I've seen with Gonorrhea where
the numbers of non-specific urethritis were enormous as side effect or a consequence
of Gonorrhea.
We have people infected chronically
with the secondary or tertiary stage of Gonorrhea.
When I wrote this in my book I was attacked by especially English doctors and they claimed that
I was wrong saying that Syphilis was not cured; Syphilis was cured by antibiotics, especially by penicillin.
When I examined the cases of AIDS, as you remember it was attributed to homosexuals.
If you were homosexual, then you run high risk of getting AIDS.
It proved to be nonsense. Why it was homosexuals in the beginning?
Because homosexuals, especially in America, became very promiscuous. They were people that they will have excessive sex with anybody, under any circumstances.
As a fact, they contracted Syphilis and Gonorrhea very frequently. So if one
would examine the history of such people,
they would see that have several infections
of Syphilis and Gonorrhea the last few
years and all these infections were treated constantly with antibiotics. Not only that
but this specific group  would take antibiotics
as a prophylactic, because they would go and have sex with somebody they never knew, they just met the other night and prophylactically they would go and get antibiotics to prevent
themselves from getting Syphilis and Gonorrhea. From getting venereal disease.
But what is AIDS? AIDS is a venereal disease. Its mode of transmission is exactly the same as Syphilis.
The difference is that AIDS virus is much more subtle and much more deadly than Syphilis.
We have to ask what is happening with the question of AIDS?
Was it really the homosexuals or the way they perform sex? Or it was really another factor?
Very soon it proved that other groups were in risk. Which groups? The promiscuous ones.
Those that they will have sex indiscriminately.
But what was involved in this group as well? It was the same factor. They would get easily venereal diseases. And they would have to be treated again.
And then what was the next group from women? It was the prostitutes. Of course the prostitutes because again in the prostitutes the risk of getting a venereal disease is very high.
So I was talking with a group of Professors from the University of California, last year. And I was expanding these ideas. So they said, wait a moment why the Tahitians have such a high number of AIDS?
Well I said, it's very simple. Because the homosexuals from N.Y. they will fly to Tahiti
and find a partner and have sex. And then
they will give to them their venereal diseases.
As a result they have to be treated with antibiotics over the counter. And these people were getting very frequently venereal diseases.
He said, what about Africa? In Africa AIDS has become an epidemic, why? I said, because in Africa the last 10 years there is an epidemic of Syphilis and Gonorrhea.
It's breaking up, tremendous epidemic that infects almost everybody with Syphilis and Gonorrhea.
In the end of the discussion
they went back to their computers.
And they had a lot of objections in the beginning but in the end they said, well it makes sense, let us see. They went back to the computers and they asked the computers,
how many people of the subjects of AIDS
they had antibiotics the last six months? The percentage was tremendous. It was 85%.
Do you realize what is coming? If venereal diseases are not really treated or if they are treated they break down the immune system and they bring the immune system to such a state
where the AIDS virus can live and exist
and thrive, can you imagine how many thousands of cases you will be expecting
to die within the next 5 years?
And the whole question of AIDS is not tackled properly. Because they say an Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome. Acquired by what? The immune deficiency they described it as acquired. Acquired by what process?
And when we come to Homeopathy, we have
the theory of miasms, the miasmatic theory in which all these ideas are based. And we have been talking about the miasmatic effect of Syphilis and Gonorrhea for years.
And we have been shouting that these venereal diseases are not really treated but they are going through the human system and undermine the system. And here comes the prophecy of Homeopathy to be frightfully true.
I'm afraid that nobody at this stage has realized the importance of AIDS and unless we really understand the cause, I mean do you understand that if that theory may be true, I don't say it is true at this moment.
Though I collected the fact and together with an assistant Professor in the University of New Jersey. We collected the facts and sent this paper to be published in a scientific journal.
But if this theory is true, do you realize
what we are heading on as a human race?Breaking down the immune system by pumping into the human system tons of so called allopathic drugs.
And I believe that it is every chemical substance that goes into the human body that can cause a compromise in the immune system. It's not only antibiotics, it's not only cortisone, it's not antihistamine drugs. I mean it's every drug.
Also the hallucinogenic drugs. They cause a compromise in the immune system and they prepare the system for that disease which we call AIDS. AIDS is nothing else but the last stage that the human organism can reach. After this stage there is no hope.
And if you ask me Homeopathy can really cure AIDS? I would say, no. There is no hope. I don't believe that any drug will ever be effective
in that state. Homeopathy cannot cure AIDS.
What Homeopathy can do? Homeopathy can be used to strengthen the immune system. There is no question about that. So that the organism will not eventually reach that state in which the virus develops.
Therefore Homeopathy will become very important in the very near future in treating diseases in general.
And that's why I said it's great hope to see so many numbers interested in Homeopathy at this stage. Because I believe that this is the only system actually together perhaps with Acupuncture and some other  natural methods that they may bring some hope into the human race.
The doctor concludes here that it may be that it's already too late. The virus may be unstoppable everywhere, he says. I don't know.
I don't think that at this moment people in general realize in what state the general health of the human race is, at this moment.
This is a very important message because if that is understood, then Homeopathy may be will be taken its right place. And maybe Homeopathy does not have to be taught in this way.
In weekends or in seminars of 15-20 days or even 4 or 5 weeks that I was giving the seminar in the US. It has to be taught in a University setting in a course of 3,4,5 years.
So I know you are all interested to hear my ideas about skin eruptions but you understand my position? When I read this, I am at the US and
I feel what is going on.
And I see in the television almost everyday discussions about AIDS that have nothing to do with the real issues. And the real issues are never discussed by anybody.
And I tremble, I say what is going on? They try to accuse different things. They say why virus is now in Africa?
They don't realize that in San Francisco or NY are going to become deserted towns in a few years. Everybody will fly out in hysteria, out of these towns. Because of the fear of contracting AIDS.
Unless something is done quickly. Something which is essential. We have an immune system which is compromised. What can we do for that system?
This is not the question at the moment. If this is not realized people keep taking antibiotics all the time. Keep on taking strong drugs to treat diseases with the hope that they will become well.
And when AIDS comes to the last stage,
they still give antibiotics. Sending much
faster the people to their next stage.
Skin eruptions.
According to the model I have presented and I believe you are all familiar with that model and the model of Homeopathy in general, skin eruptions is a very good state to be.
To have skin eruption now is like a "boom".
Give me a skin eruption. This is the idea of Homeopathy. If the disease is on the skin,
it is outside, this is great.
Everybody who takes homeopathic, give us skin eruption, give us skin eruption!
Now you are asking me to tell you how to get rid of this.
How do you get rid of the skin eruptions? I mean tell to your patients, fine you reach that state where you can afford to have a skin eruption.
That is fine, keep it. I'm not joking.
If it was to be seen the state of health in which we are, I mean if we had a way of projecting the inner disturbances mental, emotional and physical into the skin, into the outward part of our bodies there would be nobody without skin eruptions. Bigger or lesser.
So once the body under homeopathic treatment, reaches that state of producing, bringing out skin eruptions then there is a great hope for that organism to live considerably healthy after that, even if his skin eruption remains for good.
Here I want to make a correction concerning Peter. Peter said that I have said, that in Athens we cure 100% of the skin eruptions. That is totally wrong, I'm sorry.
What I said was that, you know in Athens are about 30 medical doctors working in the center,
4 of them are pediatricians. So they did a statistics.
They took all the cases of psoriasis in children. That specific skin disorder, psoriasis in children. And they followed up the cases, they telephoned, they saw the people and they said, ok we had so many cases
this was a paper was prepared for a congress in Greece. So they brought the result and they said that according to the statistics, every case of psoriasis that we had in children, it was treated successfully and the paper showed 100% results.
And this paper was prepared to be read
also, later on, in the International Congress.
And I said to them, forget it. Bring the results, less because nobody will believe.
But it was only in psoriasis in children.
So after this introduction I would like to clarify
this issue. Because it's very important when an issue is misunderstood in Homeopathy.
We have to consider actually in skin eruptions, we have to consider 2 big groups:
The one is that the people they come to be treated initially come to be treated for a skin eruption. That they have this skin eruption for years and they come to be treated for that.
Though, as you know, very few people still have their skin eruptions because their skin eruptions will usually be suppressed, go inside through cortisone mostly and mainly. They put cortisone and the skin eruption disappears.
You cannot see it anymore. You stop cortisone and the skin eruption reappears. And that goes on for a few years depending on the strength of the organism and one day the last applying of cortisone is the final and the eruption does not reappear.
And the patient usually will say, 'I don't know if cortisone did anything really because I was using it and the eruption was coming out and using itand it was coming out and I'm not sure that cortisone really cured my skin eruption'.
The fact is that the immune system, as long as it was strong, it was bringing out the skin eruption in spite of cortisone, the skin eruption was out.
Until such day that the immune system was damaged and could not anymore have the strength to bring out the skin eruption.  And that's why the skin eruption finally stopped coming out.
And that is usually the story. They will say, well after a particular year, I do not have my skin eruptions anymore. Because you are asking all the time the history, did you have a skin eruption somewhere back into your history?
Yes. How much it lasted? 2,3,5 years. Depending on what? Depending on the strength of the immune system. Now if that skin eruption is pushed inside, is going to create a lot of problems.
And I hope to be able to show you perhaps tomorrow a case where you will see very clearly what happens with the skin eruption. When the skin eruption is pushed inside into the organism.
So it's a good prognosis when somebody will
tell you, 'I have a skin eruption for 20 years'.
That means he has a strong organism.
That is not admitting suppression very much.
If somebody tells you 'I had this skin eruption,
I put a little bit of cortisone and it was gone',
that's not a good thing to hear.  That means the defenses of the body are already too weak.
And the stories that you hear usually is when they come to you, that the skin eruption was there, was suppressed or "cured" and the person now is suffering with a, b, c symptomatology.
Once you treat successfully such a person, you may expect that the original skin eruption will eventually come back.
Now this is the second group. The first group came for a skin eruption, the second group is cases of skin eruption that they came after
your homeopathic treatment.
You treated somebody homeopathically and he developed a skin eruption, what are you going to do?
Somebody came and said, 'well I have my skin eruptions for 20 years', what are you going to do? There are two different groups.
On the first group where the person comes to
be treated for a skin eruption, you may try immediately and find the indicated remedy.
And this is a whole process, as you know. You
go to the general symptoms, mental-emotional symptoms and the local symptoms of the skin eruption taken all these into consideration and
try to find out the best possible remedy.
In the second group where you produce after giving a remedy, the organism brought out a skin eruption, that's a different story.
Now if in such cases you try immediately to treat that skin eruption, you are going to have big problems.
For different reasons.
The first reason is that once the organism has been stimulated by the right remedy and brought out a skin eruption the remedy usually is not apparent. You cannot find the right remedy.
Now what are you going to do then? Then you have to let the organism fight it itself. You have to let this patient go on with the skin eruption. For how long?
The how long depends mostly on the severity of the skin eruption because sometimes the skin eruption is very severe.
Then you may have to act. Much more quickly than another skin eruption that is not a severe and can go on for 6 months, 1 year, 2 years.
A skin eruption can be left for 2 years.
Another skin eruption has to be treated in
2-3 months but not earlier than that.
Because once you give the indicated remedy and acted beautifully in bringing out the skin eruption then you have to allow  the system to do its best under that remedy.
If you try now to treat such a case, very quickly, because the patient comes and say, 'I can't sleep or I can't have these eruptions in my face or in my body' and they press you and you try to prescribe for these cases, most of these cases are spoiled.
What is the worst that can happen? It's that the skin eruption may again be suppressed, back to the original case.
Sometimes it is impossible for a homeopathic remedy to suppress the skin eruption entirely.
So what will happen is some of these skin eruptions will go inside and some will remain on the outside. So it will be a distribution of disturbance.
Don't forget that diseases are not material entities. Diseases are in the mind, diseases are in the emotional and diseases are on the physical body.
Now the total, if you add up the disturbances of the mental-emotional and physical body, if you add up these numbers then you have the final number of the disease of the individual.
So when you have a skin eruption, if you have every disturbance of the human body that it has appearing on the skin you're going to have a very severe skin eruption.
In such a case, do never give a remedy, at least immediately. Wait until the indications of the organism in general give you enough information to prescribe on a new remedy.
Do you want to spoil your cases?
Try to cure these eruptions.