The father of a cousin had cancer and the brother of a friend of mine in NY developed at the same time cancer of the lungs.
So my friend said 'what about my brother, can you do anything?' and at the same time my cousin said 'what shall we do about my father?'
I said 'forget chemotherapy. We'll treat him as long as he lasts'. To the other man, the rich man in NY, I said 'it's your decision, I cannot promise anything'. He went to a known clininc in NY.
The doctors promised him everything. Chemotherapy will take away this mass. We have to prevent metastasis, therefore weekly the strongest chemotherapy.
Therefore I had two cases. The one was 75 and he was 57.
I haven't seen the x-rays but they said that in a few weeks this mass will almost not show there through chemotherapy. In my case in few weeks that mass was almost or more than double.
In 2 months the other case showed a metastasis on the brain. In my case in 2 months the lungs was almost occupied. In 4 months the man had a stroke, paralysis of one leg, his hair was falling
out, he was a complete wreck. The other man in the meantime was well, working. He brought out some blood and this was taken care with Kali-c.
That was coming bigger and bigger but no blood was coming out. After few months I asked him if he had blood and said 'blood? me? no!'
He goes out every day, has a good appetite and in 6 months he develops wheezing and constriction and cough. Another dose of Kali-c and the wheezing subsided within 24h.
The x-ray today is completely full, there's no lung. It's completely occupied. The last thing I heard was that there's again wheezing.
Again a dose of Kali-c and the wheezing and the pain went away. But there were no blood, no clots of blood.
The lung appears closed up completely. He feels well. The doctor says that the general state is remarkably well. The other man died on February.
In this man, it did not disappear but the man is very well. This is the difference.
I've seen what happens with chemotherapy. Because he was my uncle I said ok. Why it speeds up? You call that speed up? I don't know.
The organism appears to have a bursting out but may arrive at a point where this is enough for the organism. It does not need more aggravation.
So this person may live for one or two more year. One day he's going to have hemoptysis, great amount of blood coming out and he will die.
Without the pains, the suffering, the humiliation going on with this kind of drugs and chemotherapy.
Now they will tell me when they see the x-ray: what you've done? But what  you have done?
In 5 months you send him to the grave through humiliation, making him a vegetable finally with tremendous pain? Because he eventually developed pains on the bones.
When they said that 'we do that in order to prevent metastasis', when the metastasis came they say 'now we have to radiate to prevent
metastasis on the bone. But metastasis
on the bone came.
I have seen another case of cancer where it had metastasis on the brain. With one remedy taking away the pains of the bones and also the
metastasis on the brain. The whole force of the disease came back to the lung. You will say 'how long the lung will last? If you don't touch, I don't know. It's almost one year since they discovered it.
It's a cancer that goes fast. In few months can occupy the whole lung. Do we speed up really?
I'm not sure. But if they touch this man, they open him they'll see the whole situation.
These are my experiences and experience of any good homoeopath.
We take two parallel cases and we compare.
I had x-rays every 3 months. I wanted to show the changes.
Yesterday I had a telephone call from Boston,
a cancer case. We cannot take the responsibility and say to the person 'come from Boston I'll cure you'.
These cases are not everyday. Otherwise we may find ourselves with legal problems.
-What about Iscador treatment?
- It's not my experience but I've heard certain cases treated with Iscador that did not do well.
But it appears to arrest for a moment the tumor. Arresting the tumor is not the idea for me.
One of my doctors who works in the hospital said that in the hospital came a woman with cancer in both breasts. The breast was open, discharging. It was a terrible thing to see.
Immediately they said operation but the woman said 'i don't want operation, just do something about the oozing'.
She didn't accept operation. Two years later the doctor saw the daughter on the street. He asked 'you had a mother that came in, how is she?'
'She's still ok'.
'The breast cancer?'
'The same'
'And she's doing ok?'
If they had operated, how it would have been?
If the tumor gets on the brain would you suggest surgery?
Surgery in the brain for the cancer? No.
My point is that you have only one brain but two lungs.
If it starts in the brain forget it!
-I was thinking about this Iscador thing. It's a parasite. Grows on big trees. One reason why Iscador in some cases seems to have an effect,
might be that it has an element that has some similarity to cancerous road itself.
I wonder about that case, could it be that the organism was enabled to collect the disease from around the body in the lungs?
So helping the situation by collecting
the cancer cells in the lungs so leaving free the rest of the body.
That's the idea. The whole force of the disease
is concentrating here (lungs) and the organism tries to leave it there, not allowing to go to more important areas where is more dangerous.
- Have you treated a person with a cancer area that is supposed to have healed by chemotherapy or radiation?
I think so yes. People who have been
operated say 20 years ago for cancer
and they come to be treated, yes.
- I had such case my own. She had cancer 4 years ago and had tremendous colic pains in stomach after x-rays.
And I wonder, should I treat her or not?
I treated her with Veratrum album and the
colic pains went away.
If the question is whether you can treat after chemotherapy: Sure you can treat.
You have no hope of being able with the remedy to take this thing away, to clear up the lump?
You see in his family, none went ever more than 75. That's my mother's side. All died before 75.
I studied his case quite well I came
down to kali-c. I gave it and worked.
Maybe you give a remedy and does not work.
It took away immediately the coughing and the blood clots, and then the wheezing and the pain.
He does not know until now what he has.
Neither he suspected.
His brother has problems with his lungs also because it runs in the family.
He had dyspnoea. I said 'you don't
have any dyspnoea?' 'Me? no! The other
one has dyspnoea, me no.'
It's also a characteristic of people who have cancer that they don't suspect, they don't
feel it at these stages.
They feel quite well and they don't suspect. If you have fear of cancer, pathologically, then  almost 99% sure they don't have cancer.
As long as they have the fear of cancer, tremendous fear. The cancer is on the
mental level.