Generally the patients are painless in Opium cases. I've seen 12 cases of Opium, they are sensitive to pain.
But along with that they also have this peculiar intolerance to certain heavy pain but they can bear it.
-What happened with this girl it is not only that I based the presciption in what you wrote.
Because, if I remember well, you wrote that this girl can really tolerate the pain but the pain is felt.
And she actually tells her mother and aunt how painful it was. But at the moment she could not express it.
Opium in a state, I have said, maybe I confuse the groups; maybe I have not said to this group.
Did I tell you that each remedy has levels? I said it in this group?
-No.
-Levels of health, like the organism has levels of health.
It seems that I'm half out of my body because I'm jerking with this noise.
So be careful because if I'm out of my body I read your minds.
They call it intuition, nevermind what they call it.
I will talk about the levels of remedies.
And then I come back to Opium.
Each remedy has certain levels on which can be acting.
For instance Calcarea carbonica can be acting in level 1, it can be acting in level 8 or 9.
The symptoms will be different. In level 1 Calcarea carbonica will be a person who is feeling very cold
feet are cold, desires sweets, desires eggs, perspires in the occiput.
In level 9,10 Calcarea carbonica will be there but all these keynotes will not be there.
Some idea of the keynotes may be there. That means you may have a tumor, you may have a cancer and in the cancer case
you may have some.... even the feeling of coldness will not be there.
The desire for eggs may not exist but there will be other symptoms, especially if the effect is on the mental or neurological level.
Then you don't have to have the symptoms. For instance Calcarea carbonica level 7, you have already fear of insanity.
Fear of insanity quite strongly. Anxiety about health quite strong. Fear of death quite strong.
So these fears you will not have in group 1 but you will have the other keynotes.
Another example. Phosphorus has fear of thunderstorm, thirst, great thirst, desires ice-cream, cold, upper group.
You go on mental-emotional level the thirst is gone, no thirst, no fear of thunderstorm.
But it has increased very much the sensitivity to pain from others. They cannot tolerate at all pain around them.
The sensitivity is so great that cannot go out and see people suffering at all. They remain closed in their places. They don't go out.
In this stage all the main keynotes of Phosphorus will be gone.
In Opium case, the typical Opium case would have been that opiates, will be produced in the brain and make you feel no pain.
Like when you are in a stress, in a situation that you may have a broken arm, leg and feel no pain.
That moment there is a flood of opiates, that makes you feel no pain.
The shock of the organism creates a defense, a lot of opiates that flood the areas of the brain and you feel no pain.
Later on when the shock is over, then the pain starts.
So we say Opium in the upper group, they don't feel the pain. They don't feel the pain, not they suppress the pain.
But the main problem for me was that immobility of the nervous system, total sleep of the peripheral nervous system
it was not moving at all. The bladder, paralyis. It was not so much the typical tolerance of pain that we know in Opium.
Because when you wrote to me, you wrote that she is not tolerating she is suppressing the pain and later on
she would admit the situation
was very painful. You remember?
But mostly lead me to this the idea of the effect of Opium. Because Opium we say is one of the main remedies in constipation.
So that means constipation which is due to a paralysis, there are no the peristaltic movements of the colon.
Bryonia has also constipation but is due to dryness. The glands do not give out enough liquid, mucus.
Opium is this. Also Opium is somebody who seems to be quite patient.
Especially in pneumonia, they're lying down there, the lungs are full of water, there is cough, you expect they feel something.
They go into a state of ecstasy, kind of. We give Opium when we see somebody into a comatose state.
That means they don't feel. Why they don't feel? Because of certain reactions on the body, right?
And then we give Opium and we see
it's coming out of the comatose state.
That is the idea that led me to Opium in this lady.
But really I don't know why I said 2 months.
No, no I tell you the truth.
She had some reactions which I evaluated as correct reactions. So I knew if she had these reactions the effect is going to be sure.
So I said wait 2 months. Because you kept
on writing all the time. Give a remedy.
But at certain point the reactions were such that
I said, ok 2,3 months she will be much better.
-How necessary is the keynote sleepiness in Opium? If you don't have sleepiness?
-Sleepiness is one of the uppermost levels. Later on when the nervous system is affected you don't have it anymore.
Also this is something which I have seen many times with novice, with people who come and know very little about Homeopathy.
They say, how you give Phosphorus she
does not have fear of thunderstorm
or how you give Nitric acid if she does not have cuts.... .
It depends on the level of the remedy, what level you are treating and when we describe remedies,
we describe remedies on the upper levels
where the remedy is clear.
In the lower levels the remedy is not clear anymore. You have to "smell" the remedy in the lower levels.
You have to perceive even little changes
which look like the remedy.
In the lower levels of health when somebody is seriously ill, you do not have a typical picture as we describe it usually.
When we describe the remedy.
It's very strange, I remember a case that
you may not even remember.
When you brought me this case of businessman, 38-40, with duodenal ulcer. Natrum muriaticum, yes?
-Certain diseases like diabetes etc. which have genetic predisposition, is it possible to modify the genetic predisposition
of the next generation if the mother takes
other medicine during the pregnancy time?
- There is quite a lot possibility of improving the health of the child if the mother takes in time correct homeopathic treatment.
It's not a matter of, I took Homeopathy. It's a matter, of: did you take the correct sequence of remedies?
If you have taken a lot of homeopathic remedies you may stay just at the same way as you were 10 years ago.
So the idea is, did the mother get correct homeopathic treatment? The child is going to be born much healthier.
That's why I suggest that all pregnant women should have homeopathic treatment.
But not the wrong treatment.
-What about the father?
-The father as well, oh yes.
You have to remember we
participate in the game.
Now you don't need. You go to the bank
and say give me a sperm, how much?
I know children have been born with sperm of unknown parents. They show the picture, oh yes good guy, give me his sperm.
It's a big issue. In India they don't need yet,
but I tell you a prediction for India.
Especially for the effluent society of India. They are going to have such problem quite soon.
In 20, 30 years all rich people of India will
have women with sterility, quite a lot.
-Because they are adopting a
western style of life and diet.
-Exactly. Diet and treatment especially.
Diet, treatment and freedom.
That is the worst I can tell you. Because they contract all kinds of venereal kind of diseases
that have a direct effect upon the
reproductive system, genito-urinary system.
Because of infections which are spreading like fire now in Africa, in India, in China and God knows what.
-I'd like to ask a question about placebo effect. Do you think is the vital force which is actually producing
the placebo effect or do you think it's something else? If it is the vital force, have you seen patterns of symptoms?
-I tell you what is my opinion about placebo. Placebo effect has a mechanism of how it is produced.
In Homeopathy we use the same mechanism exactly. We stimulate the organism as the same way exactly
is stimulated by the person himself by his belief that now I'm going to get better. So the mechanism is the same.
What is the difference? The difference is that the stimulation by the person himself can have a limited effect. Up to here.
That means you will feel better 1,2,3 weeks. 4 weeks has a relapse, faith is gone, effect is gone.
Here we have the possibility to raise the potency and to stimulate more and more and therefore
we have cases in which we can confirm that this is in fact because of the remedy. Why?
Because all symptoms come back. Because skin eruptions are coming out again, because diseases are going
from up, downwards.
We know that this is the effect of the remedy. We do not see this effect on the placebo.
But now if the person though is suffering very much belongs to the group 1, level 1,2,3 it can be
completely cured through a self-suggestion.
Completely, it's gone because he was quite healthy already. So whatever you give him they say, I gave him Aluminium...
whatever, you just give it to him and it will affect him.
And that is why a lot of homeopaths don't realise that when they give a remedy made by the machine
or when they give a remedy which they think it contains something, a peculiar remedy whatever it might be
and then they report in the journals that I have such a case and I gave this remedy and the person was cured.
Just simple placebo effect or insincerity.
Not sincere report because the person may have said, 'I was better for 1 week-10 days' and you reported, he was well.
-In these people in the top levels...I treated yoga therapy including the 12 tissue salts the usual yoga thing,
all the yoga diet as well at many cures. But then I saw people on the lower levels and I had to send them to a homeopath.
But the cures with these very healthy people it might the yoga therapy worked for real because it's what they needed.
-Yes, they needed very little stimulation and they are better.
-I have a question in continuation of a discussion this morning regarding when you go at ascending potencies
and for example, give 200 there is no effect
1 million there is no effect and so on.
What if you're giving not a similium remedy but very close remedy. And you continue doing it and
you don't see effect and so on. At one moment you get 10M and you have an aggravation.
-No amelioration.
-No amelioration, it's really aggravation. How do you know is it really
aggravation, is it similar aggravation, what are your guidelines to see if you're on the right track?
-Your guidelines would be that a strong aggravation could not last very long. After a few days,
he must report I am much better. If he does not do that, that means there is an aggravation
which continues it's his disease which is aggravated. An aggravation is good and therefore
has to give an effect after the aggravation.
Aggravation is not good because of the aggravation.
It's good because after the aggravation he must be well.
If he is not well....this is the guiding.
-But you actually give already quite high level of remedy.
If you give already10M and there is no effect first and then it's getting 10M and there is aggravation.
And it lasts not 1,2 days, it lasts a week. What you do next?
-You wait. The 8th day he will be good.
Like his case, in 2 months he will be alright.
-A question about the potencies. As far as I remember Kent made this rule from 30, 200, 1M, 10M, 50 M.
You give some potencies like 31, 32 and this was really puzzling me somehow.
-It's a matter of experience, out of many, many, thousands of people I have seen. I have seen that sometimes
I had to repeat not to go jump from 30 to 200. But if I went slowly up it would be better
especially when I had serious conditions.
-I was just thinking of a man who was getting much better with Lycopodium 1M and he has a continuous
infection of the bladder with blood in the urine and he has also stones, little, little stones in the urine.
-A case here you are talking?
-No, a case at home one of my patients.
-You gave Lycopodium.
-The only thing that had an effect was Lycopodium.
Lycopodium 1M and I was in doubt to give it so high because he has infection with HIV that could lead to AIDS later.
I don't want to damage his life forcing too much by giving him the next step from 1M to 10M.
So I repeated Lycopodium 1M but has no effect and I looked for other keynotes and I came always back to Lycopodium.
-You never tried higher. You couldn't damage him.
-No. How do you know?
-How do I know?
I don't know.
-Is the possiblity to give 1M and one more?
Like 1001M.
-Yes, 1001 you could do it and then you tell me the results.
-Yes ok.
-Because that is how we learn. People like you who are afraid, they try this or that, then they give me feedback  and then I learn.
What can I say? If I knew your case, you say it's an AIDS case. If he is positive in HIV.
-He has not a clinical AIDS related complex but he is a carrier.
-I would like to ask about juvenile diabetes,
if you have made any conclusions about possible factors
that have created this disease in children? And if there are some emotional common elements in these children?
-No, I have not made such observations. I have not seen too many cases either.
-Just to come back to the Opium case. I'm still not clear about the particular symptom when
she was sensitive to the pain but was not able to express it.
-I did not base my prescription to that. Mahesh said that this was the reason, he made it up.
When I remember the real facts he sent me it was not that. Mostly I based my prescription on the fact
that was paralysed all the system. But he made
it sound differently than the reality a little bit.
-Last days we had two patients with thyroxine hormones for metabolism. Could you comment something
upon patients taking these hormones? Does it influence when you treat with Homeopathy
or can they continue regardless of these hormones?
-Hormones which are missing out of an organ, for instance sometimes you have a total extraction
of thyroid and a replacement with thyroxine. In this case this problem does not prevent you from giving a remedy.
Neither insulin is preventing you from giving a remedy because it's a substance which replaces the normal output of an organ.
If this is a replacement then it does not matter, you don't have to say stop it. You can give, you can go ahead and give the remedy.
If the organism is missing the organ all together, of course you don't expect that the organ will grow again
but the whole organism will be in a better condition. But they have to continue with thyroxine.
You can be treating such cases and can be quite deep cases and you improve them.
But the thyroxine will always be there. You will give thyroxine, you have to replace what cannot be produced.
-One of my friends wants to ask a question, she is afraid. So I'll ask the question.
She wants to know the effect of infertility treatment, allopathic infertility treatment, the effect in the woman
and the child and the next generation,
how it manifests?
-The effect of artificial insemination,
treatment or the drugs?
It's a difficult subject and I don't have enough information to tell you what happens in the chilldren.
But according to my theories of the children of love, you know this theory?
I have out of some observation and talking with a lot of parents and seen their children, noticed many times
the first child of the family is very sick, a lot of problems. The second child is quite healthy.
Or the opposite, the first child is very healthy,
the second child, the third child, very sick.
I used to ask the parents what was the condition of conception time for this particular child?
And what was the difference between the first child that was conceived in a state of love,
you know the first love how powerful it is?
The first love affair is fantastic.
If a child is born under this condition, is going to be a complete child. A complete human being.
That means a human being which will have .... these are signs that I should not talk about this subject.
Anyhow I don't listen to such signals to my detriment.
I will give you some examples so you may understand. My theory is when two young people are first in love
and then they come together to have sex and with this force and energy is so powerful that what happens is
that each one has given up his ego. And they can merge to each other.
This merging of the two people due to the love they have for each other, this merging makes the ego disappear.
And therefore complete connection is there. If there is a complete connection, you have a child who is born
as complete as possible. That means with the best possible qualities from the mother and from the father.
Of course the perfect child is not born yet. The absolute, perfect child but you know young people can fall in love
much more easy than older people who say, 'ah I know'. That state is terrilbe if you overuse it especially.
First time is very powerful the connection and then the quality of the sperm is different.
You have a quality of sperm which is different than when somebody goes to masturbate to take some sperm and inseminate etc.
So this is my theory.
The moment that you have lost your ego consciousness, then you are in touch with the cosmos;
that's why people who are in love they come together and they feel, 'oh my god what an experience!'
That experience is a spiritual experience. It's similar than the experience the yogis are looking for.
You know common people are given the possibility to live the state of complete consciousness,
of enlightment, whatever you call it, during the time when two people in love come together and they have sex together.
That is the highest point. If a child is conceived during that state, is going to be a child complete,
is going to be happy, satisfied with whatever he has. But usually the society says, the woman is 19, you are too young,
you cannot have a child at this age. You are the shame of our family, you must go and have, you know what I mean.
This child is gone, another child is gone, third child is gone and then the woman is studying, she becomes a scientist.
Now she has to marry. She will find somebody to marry who has certain requisites, certain parameters.
He has to be a bank manager, a doctor in the hospital, a lawyer bla, bla, bla.
This is a concession already that has taken away the idea of total love. It's gone.
You cannot do it anymore.
Because you enter logic into the factors and therefore you cannot.
But in India they have arranged marriage. Arranged marriage means people do not know each other;
they meet almost one week before marriage. The first child is going to have a problem if the attraction is not immediate.
But now what happens, because of the Indian tradition they decide we have to live our life together
and they start loving each other.
The more they live together after a year, two years the second child comes, then love has developed.
The second child is going to be better than the first one.
On the contrary if the woman says, no I love this man and he loves me and I will marry him.
They go ahead and marry. The first child will be in better position than later on when they are used to each other
you know, let's do it and bla, bla, bla is becoming habitual. The moment sex becomes habitual the sperm is missing the information.
You will not believe it but the sperm gets all the information you are giving at the moment of conception.
What you think, what you feel, the most nice feelings, the most ideal feelings, the most sublime feelings
they are given to the child.
But you may say, ok the woman will ovulate two days later and then the conception will take place.
It doesn't matter; the woman also has given the qualities to the ovum. She has given the qualities of herself as she has
given in this connection. And I'm sure that if they can use the sperm of those who are in love during the sexual
contact and use the same sperm when people are just masturbating and get it, they will see a difference
if they can examine the sperm in its very subtle consistency.
I say this because this is going to be proved about 30 years later but it will be written there.
Therefore if you have ideas like these I have, if you ask me if artificial insemination is a good thing
I will say well it is concession, it is a compromise.
It is not the perfect thing. What could be really a perfect situation.
Crazy ideas.
-Can you tell us your experience on treating obese patients?
-Treating obesity?
Sometimes you will have some good effect if the assimilation is not good, the absorption is not good
is not correct with the remedy being corrected, you may have an effect. But treating very obese people like
the one I saw 457 kilos! About that big. 35 old.
In America you see quite a lot of them.
I doubt whether we can do really something
about it. I really very much doubt.
The organism I think is totally destroyed, the immune system.