I want to talk to you and clarify certain issues concerning homeoprophylaxis.
There is a general idea of Arnica being used before an operation and after an operation.
Many people say, I'm going to have a tooth extraction; ok take Arnica first so you don't have much bleeding
and then take Arnica afterwards.
This is entirely wrong. Why?
Because we use Arnica as a blood thinning. Thinning of the blood so if you have a clot of blood,
Arnica dissolves this by thinning the blood.
When you have a blow and there is extravasation of blood and there is blue, the blood has created a clot, you give Arnica
and like miracle, this is dissolved. This is dissolved why? Because Arnica is acting like coumarin.
You know coumarin? Coumarin is a blood thinning, anticoagulant.
That means Arnica is contra-indicated before operation. Because once you have Arnica and you operate
you are going to have more blood.
You see the craziness of some people?
Not only that but you may get some people say, we had tried a research and we found out that Arnica helps.
How they found Arnica helps is another story. You can make a research and prove whatever you like.
The fact remains that when you have a heart attack, that means a blood clot is closing an artery
the first remedy you will give is Arnica. To do what? To act as an anticoagulant and faster.
Do you understand some misunderstandings?
Now the Times of London wrote an article 3 months ago.
They say, Homeopathy "voodoo medicine", why?
He writes the journalist: homeopaths claim that they can give a remedy as a prophylactic to the different epidemic diseases.
How comes this? Of course because some people they have written books, articles etc
saying, we have the possibility to give a remedy as a prophylaxis.
That means I give you a remedy and if an epidemic comes like small pox, you are protected.
Can you believe? You are protected. How is this?
And when I ask what is your reason for writing this and saying this and the Times take this and write that you are voodoo medicine?
What is your reason for believing that giving a remedy, let us Thuja or whatever, Morbillinum
that it will protect you when the epidemic will come?
He says, yes but Hahnemann said that when was an epidemic of scarlet fever during that time
he gave Belladonna as a prophylactic so the people would be protected from scarlet fever.
See now the misunderstanding of what Hahnemann said and how this has been
misinterpreted and presented as a
possibility that we have for a prophylaxis.
What happened with Hahnemann's idea?
Hahnemann saw that a lot of people were getting the scarlet fever, needed Belladonna.
So he thought why not giving Belladonna to everybody so we may have less casualties.
He thought he was doing a prophylaxis. What he was doing was giving a remedy in the beginning of the scarlet fever
so the scarlet fever will not develop fully. It was a curative action of Belladonna during the epidemic.
During the epidemic, the genius of epidemic that means the remedy that was mostly indicated in that epidemic, was Belladonna.
Now the epidemic is ranging and you give Belladonna, you know the epidemic, you know that the remedy is very much indicated
those people who will develop symptoms of Belladonna, only these people will have a milder attack.
That means the moment the symptoms come, the remedy comes and cures.
It cures you from the beginning. This is totally different than saying that we give you a remedy
and you are protected from smallpox, from chicken pox, from whatever you like.
Or, we can protect everything by some people.
This is not so. Why? I will explain to you immediately.
You see the action of a remedy is when only the symptoms are similar to the remedy.
So you give a remedy, symptoms are similar, they are gone, cured.
If the symptoms are not the same and you give a remedy totally out, what you give?
It's like giving a wrong medicine to a patient. What is going to happen? Nothing.
The patient comes back and says, I feel nothing. So this is the second possibility.
This is the second possibility. You give first, cured because it fits. Second possibility, you give, no effect.
How many patients will come back and say, I do not feel anything because you have given the wrong medicine.
Third possibility is that you give a remedy that was close to the case and in such a case, you create a little bit of a disturbance.
That means either the symptoms have gone away for a while or you have a proving what is called proving of a remedy.
But when we say a proving of the remedy and we say to the people, come and have proving, don't be afraid.
What do we say? We say that this effect of the proving will go away within a month or two, finished.
You have no problem in doing it. We accept from the one side therefore that the action of a wrong remedy
you do a proving, is not your remedy. The action of the wrong remedy is only passing away if there is any effect at all.
So how can one maintain, claim that by giving you a remedy today, the next year when the epidemic will come
you will be protected? And I said to them,
if you have said this to some people
and the epidemic comes and the child dies, what are you going to say?
We're going to say that all vaccinations are not 100%. So our vaccination also is not 100%.
You see how easy it is to get away from very logical arguments that can cause tremendous problems
for the prestige of Homeopathy.
By having these crazy ideas circulating.
I say ok, you want to try to protect. Wait until the epidemic is there, then find after your 10 first cases,
which are the remedies mostly running through the epidemic and you find out, oh this influenza is Gelsemium.
If you like you can give  Gelsemium, during the epidemic and if people develop symptoms of Gelsemium
then it will have very little effect because they will be taking the Gelsemium. But you cannot say, I will give you today
a Gelsemium and the influenza will not catch you next year or next month or whenever the epidemic comes.
Listen now the Times wrote: listen what these crazy people, voodoo people are saying that we have an alternative to vaccination.
Now let us come to the idea of the vaccination as it is practiced to the general medicine.
What is the idea? The idea is we introduce the vaccine, whatever is the epidemic and the organism is producing
antibodies which then can fight the real
epidemic when it comes. This is the idea.
In my book "The Science of Homeopathy", not everybody knows the book but it doesn't matter, you can read it later on,
there is a chapter on vaccination. I have written this book in 1976 and still this idea is valid today.
What I wrote during that time? I made a full analysis, who is going to be protected and how he's going to be protected.
I let you read it but I say only this. That if a person is really protected that means the vaccination brought down
his immune system. It broke down the immune system and brought down his health and therefore
after that the specific epidemic cannot affect him.
Why? Because now you have made him chronically ill.
If you make a person chronically ill according to the teachings, he cannot anymore develop any infectious disease with high fever.
There is no power on the organism. Therefore when you take a case, you ask the patient
when did you had last time a high fever? And you will see invariably in all these chronic cases,
they will say, 'a high fever I don't remember.
10 years ago, 15 years ago, 7 years ago.
Since that time the person who had the last high fever has entered a stage of chronic condition.
You may be surprised to see, this is an entirely new idea for Medicine. I understand.
Medicine does not know these things but I have seen again and again, when I treat a chronic case
when the chronic case is really deep, severe, the person has stopped producing high fever many years ago.
A person with high blood pressure, what they call idiopathic blood pressure, that means a high blood pressure
without knowing the cause. Not real cause. If this person you treat, tells you that last year I had a flu with 39 fever.
There is no danger and you can cure him. If the person with high blood pressure says, since 10 years ago
I had my last fever then you're going to have a problem treating his blood pressure.
Because there are mechanisms inside the organism which we do not know that they allow or do not allow
the immune system to react to nosological,
to bacteria, microbes etc.
Not only that but you know the old times children, in the 60's in the 70's, the tonsillitis that was usually developing
in the early stages were tonsillitis out of staphylococcal or streptococcal infections and the children
were bringing very high fever. Now these fevers were treated repeatedly by strong drugs
to the extent that today if you go to the intensive unit care, if you by chance something happen to you
and you enter the hospital, the intensive unit care, they will give you a triple antibiotic to prevent you
from being infected from hospital microbes etc.
What the hell is going on? Nobody is inquiring.
But according to my observation after 50 years that I'm practicing Homeopathy is that the organism has defense
on different levels. If you break his defense on the upper level he will bring a defense on the lower level.
What we have managed to do with conventional vaccination? It is to bring down the general level of health
of the western world, we brought it down and we do not get epidemics. The vaccination saved us from poliomyelitis,
from smallpox, from all these diseases. The problem is instead of this what do we have today?
What kind of chronic conditions?
Instead of acute poliomyelitis, we have multiple sclerosis, we have neuromuscular diseases appearing.
Instead of smallpox we have autoimmune diseases.
And you say, ok George what shall we do, stop the vaccination?
What I want you first of all to understand is that Homeopathy does not have that possibility.
To make you so sick with the remedy that you cannot get the disease. This is a mechanism, a simple mechanism.
If you manage to bring down the organism then you will be protected  from acute diseases.
But you have to bring him down, to break down his defenses. You have to do it in order to protect.
Can Homeopathy claim to do this? Oh no. The only thing we can claim is during the epidemic to give a remedy.
The other is total craziness, nonsense and should not be publically claimed.
Where are the double blind tests to find out who was protected, who was not protected etc.
And that makes me very angry. Why? Because it comes back to me. I'm dealing with Universities
and Medical Schools and say, what are you saying there?
Then you have some people who they say:
if we have a group we all agree to do a proving. Ok, I give you one dose of a remedy you don't know what.
And I collect afterwards the symptoms that this one dose has produced. And there are some people
who bring out a book with symptoms. Out of one dose of 30, they have been created 2000 symptoms!
Wait a moment.
We give wrong medicines every day,
the patients come back, they say no effect.
How it was that your medicine produced in everybody so many symptoms? How is this?
Don't you understand that this is a mass hysteria?
If I give you a remedy which is placebo, pure placebo, sugar, and I tell a friend:
'you know what I gave them is radioactive material'.
And everybody hears, whispering, what's the remedy you took? Radioactive !
Oh my God! Oh I have a pain, my head, this, that, it's natural.
You take all these stupid hysterical reactions and you write it down as reactions to the remedy. For God's sake!
I said him, what are you doing? He said, you don't like provings.
I don't like provings? I like very much to have a proper proving. A proper proving is done properly.
That means first of all you prove a remedy with material doses.
Whatever you want to prove first you have to give it in material doses.
Hahnemann never gave a high potency. All the provings are toxicology, poisonings and sub toxic doses.
In the Organon, Hahnemann wrote in par.146
I can't remember the Aphorism.
'If you give a remedy and the person is sensitive to that remedy, you can give it in potency'.
But the person has to be sensitive to this particular remedy. If it is not sensitive, it's not going to have any symptom.
So you give a remedy in 10 people and all of them were sensitive to this remedy? For God's sake.
And then you bring out diamond, chocolate, whatever and then this is taken as information, put in the Repertory
confusing the whole population of homeopaths. Totally confused because they believe in all these crazy things.
So you may ask, these substances do not have an affect? Yes of course they have an effect.
But if you give 2000 symptoms and the effect of this you have to chose the right symptoms.
Which out of the 2000 are the correct ones?
Total confusion.
This is why I'm fighting again and again. George is against the new age and the new modern teachers.
I'm not against anybody. I'm against any nonsense which is going on in the name of Hahnemannian Homeopathy.
This has nothing to do with Homeopathy.
So coming back to the vaccination question.
My idea is that certain people are prone to have a big reaction with the conventional vaccination.
And a lot of autistic children that we have today is the result of vaccinations.
Therefore my idea is that before you vaccinate, find out whether that child complies with the parameters
that should tell you don't vaccinate that child. Because it's going to have a tremendous problem if you vaccinate it.
If we do research, we have the brains, we have the means to find out which are the parameters that will
not allow for a child to be vaccinated.
Otherwise the child will have a problem.
And then let these children, because the after effects of vaccinations if you weight them in the general population,
let us say you vaccinate the whole 6 billion people living today. You manage to bring down their health.
What are you going to do? You are going to do a kind of creating a race which is going to be forever
chronically ill more and more and more and more. And not healthy people will ever be left on this planet.
But they live longer now. Yes they live longer but what is the quality of life which we live?
Is this quality of life that will live longer which brings us all these wars? Crazy minds?
They say we go to liberate Iraq from this big, satanic man, Sadam. Very good.
Put from CIA two people, shoot him and finished. No, we are going to conquer, we are going to throw bombs, clever bombs.
Kill hundreds of thousands and then put them one against the other to bring democracy.
Are these minds healthy minds? Can you imagine if you have a child and somebody plans to send a bomb to kill your child?
This is what a healthy mind will think. That when I say bombard them and kill them, Rumsfeld or Kissinger,
the big master Kissinger says, ok bombard them, kill 300.000 of them, we don't need them.
Where is this bloody world is going and why?
If you search really in depth, you will see minds which are sick.
Sick minds. Can you imagine you have a neighbor who has two very nice children and you are thinking
how to kill these children? Can you imagine? Can you say such a mind is healthy mind? It's not.
If somebody thinks in this way, everybody is sick, is mad. We don't say it for Rice, for Bush, for this or that but this is how they think.
They have a think tank and what they think is how to create wars, how to put each other against the other,
put the French against the Germans. Put the Germans against the Americans, put the Russians against these.
This is what they're thinking all the time.
Vaccinated, they are going to live very long for the glory of the planet.
Why do I say that? Because some of you, you are going to say, wait a moment. What are we doing?
We don't want to vaccinate until we find out if my child can be vaccinated.
Because if my child is going to be vaccinated and become autistic, I don't want it.
If the epidemic comes and if it is his karma, let it have and then you treat the child, once the child is sick, you treat the child.
The argument is but the poliomyelitis was
killing a lot of people and paralyzing etc.
Yes but they did not have Homeopathy.
They did not have any means to fight.
But this is not homeoprophylaxis, it's homeocuring. It's curing with Homeopathy.
-This makes me very pessimistic because they are actually vaccinating the whole world there are big programs going on all the time.
Even in the fishing industry they vaccinate even every single salmon. Each salmon is being vaccinated.
-The salmon? The fish?
-Yes, every one.
It's total craziness.
-I tell you something. One day you will eat a salmon and you will die. Because it's totally poisonous.
Just listen to the news. There is a fish which is appearing that if you eat it, you die. In Mediterranean is appearing,
I cannot remember the type of the fish. They say it's so poisonous that if you eat the fish,
if you fish and you catch this fish, throw
it back because if you eat you will die.
A few years ago there were these oysters and one person, a friend of mine, he was looking and he saw all these open, dead.
What are we doing? Now they have Al Gore, he promotes global warming and prevention and they say,
in 10 years the world will be destroyed.
We reached 10 years out of 3,4,5, 30.000 along, in 10 years we're going almost to disappear. Why?
Because of such things that we have admitted without thinking.
-Al Gore got the scientific facts mixed up I think, when he produced this film. It is estimated that human activity
is only producing about 6% of the global warming.
The rest has to do with sun cycle changes and general heating up of the environment.
And the globalists are anchoring these talks about global warming caused by people to promote global carbon tax.
And I think in science, I've done some research, the fact is that carbon dioxide follows temperature change,
it isn't the other way around as Al Gore claimed.
-If I understood you well you say that it is a natural cycle in the earth, one factor which is warming the planet
and the second is the activity from humans. And they calculate that this only 6%. How they can calculate it that it was 6%?
I mean all this of course, Bush was in Kyoto 2 years ago and everybody agreed to reduce the pollution.
He said, no. America does not agree. Why?
Because he has been given an order from the industrialists in America. If you promote this, we are lost.
Our economy will go down. So we cannot bring any measures. All the statistics for me it's organized by those people
who can organize and promote these things. What I see when I go to Delhi, to Athens, to Bombay
you see what happens, you can't even breath.
But anyhow until we understand maybe it will take some time.
-Knowing what you have discussed today and definitely I wouldn't want my child to be vaccinated
and if I take a stand, I'm not getting vaccinated and if it comes down with a disease, I'm going to prescribe.
And then you see that if vaccination is given, there are certain signs which will tell you that the child will react,
what would be those signs? Do we know which child is favorable to vaccination and which is not?
-Yes, that is what I say. We have to find out whether a child could be vaccinated and not have a dramatic effect on his health.
There are certain signs that we can observe in a child, in which we say if the child has these signs, should be excluded.
There are some signs that we can find out if we really do research on this.
Find out which are the children. For instance, take all the autistic children which came after vaccination.
Take a very detailed report from the mother how the child was behaving before.
This is one research.
And you may find out that all these children had a common factor.
So you say let's see if this is responsible etc.
But today genetics have progressed quite a lot.
If in the genes, in the DNA you find a predisposition for a neuro-muscular disorder like etc. etc.,
you must say this child should not take polio vaccination.
These kind of things, there are a lot of measures that can be taken.
-So what are the rules of the remedy that we say, after effects of vaccination?
-To bring back the balance, that means the person whom you treated it can be again infected by the disease
from which he was supposed to be protected.
If you really can cure him then you make him again
sensitive to the original epidemic disease, from which he was supposed to be protected.
These are facts. Whether we like it or not it's another story. These are the facts.
You imagine a world with healthy people and some of them have to die because of some weaknesses,
deficiencies in their immune system. Some of them they have to die, perhaps early. And all the others live in a healthy state.
If you analyze why this phenomenon has happened? Save me, save my life, give me an injection.
Now is coming the bird flu. They sold out all the vaccinations, give me a vaccination to save my life from bird flu.
Nobody was actually falling down sick because we cannot be infected actually.
Behind all this is the fear of death.
Our fear of dying. Why?
Because we have not been educated at all what is the meaning of life and what is the meaning of death. We don't.
We know the unknown, 'I'm going to die, where I go?' and all these kind of things. Then you rush to save your life
and on the rush you kill yourself.
Sometimes the patients rush to save their lives. I just had a person dying in Sweden and they wanted me
to treat and I said, come here but he is in the last days, he cannot travel because cancer is exploded all over.
This person tried to save his life. He took chemotherapy. Within a month he was finished.
He would be able to come here, if he had not take chemotherapy. Maybe Homeopathy could save him.
They want me to save his life till 19 of June because he wants to marry a woman with whom he was in love.
And they have said, 19 of June will marry. And the wife said, please keep him alive till 19 of June, that means 3,4 days.
He is lying in bed exhausted and all that. And my e-mail was out of order for 2,3 days.
I could not answer because I only had his e-mail. But anyhow the rushing of taking the chemotherapy
many times has exactly the opposite effect.
Does not save you. It just speeds up your end.
-But there are too few Homeopaths in the world.
-That is correct. That's why I'm trying to create more.
-I'm a veterinarian and I have stables with different horses to treat and it might be interesting
that there is one man who keeps about 40-50 horses and he does not vaccinate any of his horses, none.
And we have other stables, the horses do competitions all over the world and these horses are vaccinated every 6 months.
It is very interesting for me to see the man with the 60 horses, who never vaccinates, he never has a problem with his horses.
Sometimes a little ulceration or wound but even there the horse heals. So we never go there.
He is doing nothing, just puts the horse on the field and we are almost never there.
With the other horses we have to treat them against cough, against bronchitis, against many, many different diseases.
This is very interesting for me because there is always problematic with the vaccination, what to do and what not.
People come and say, what shall I do, I have to vaccinate etc.
-So you can see. I wrote a bird flu idea, in the website you can read it. I have chicken myself.
Once they were outside, no chicken ever died. How I decided to breed my own chicken?
Because in previous years somebody was coming selling little chicken, we buy the chicken and we put them in.
All of them died. First year, second year, third year all of them died. I said, forget it these people they keep alive
the chicken by giving constant antibiotics. The moment we take them, we don't give them anything, they just die.
I produce my own chicken.
Some of them may die if you close them.
Last year they made us close the chicken, cover them, you could not have them outside.
Well, half of them died because they were closed.
The facts are coming cataclysmic. They are there all the facts to see.
But the big companies who are dealing with all these issues do not allow us to do anything.
Profit is the new God. The God of Americans is dollar and the whole world is stuck in this idea.
If you have a lot of dollars, you made it. It's stupid. I have seen very unhappy people with a lot of money.
And I have seen very poor people, full of light, energy. In India their eyes are full of life and energy.
You know the story they propose to me millions to give prescriptions, just give 10 prescriptions for headache, PMS.
Just give us this combination and we'll give you 7.5 million. I said, no. He said, what car do you have?
I had a VW, a small Volkswagen by that time. You should have a Rolls Royce.
I said, forget it. I don't want to go in my grave and have lots of dollars pressing me down.
This is crazy idea totally.
- Arnica is routinely given to women in childbirth, before childbirth. Can you say if that is also wrong?
-Before childbirth may have a meaning in reducing the rigidity of the uterus.
I would have suggested something else of course which is according to each organism, the remedy that needs.
Many of you know that in Aedipsos where a Greek doctor was giving birth to twins and an American midwife
who was supposed to be very good approached her and is started the dilatation of the uterus and during this time
for stupid reason, he says, take Sepia 10M. From 10 o'clock in the morning who took Sepia, the uterus stayed like this.
It didn't move anymore, it did a very nice proving of Sepia, because Sepia paralyses the uterus.
It makes the uterus collapse. 11, 12, 1, 2 o'clock, 5 o'clock and then we say, what shall we do there is no action.
Then I go there and I find out Sepia 10M was given at 10 o'clock. I said for what reason?
She was a homeopath also. She said because she saw a mark here in my thigh and said this is a Sepia mark.
And she gave Sepia. By 9 o'clock in the night we were in a place where there was no surgery room
and only what we could find was a scissor of a woman who was doing stitching clothes.
In the hotel with the scissor and fortunately a German gynecologist.
I said, what shall we do? The helicopter could not come, there was no near any surgery and she had to deliver
when the uterus would not open. In the meantime I was teaching and the whole class knew.
Was any present at that time? George, you remember the dramatic moments?
I was informing the class, this is happening. At 9 o'clock I said, ok tell me the symptoms. She tells me the symptoms
and I see the remedy. Clear Pulsatilla symptoms. I give Pulsatilla and say, by 10 o'clock you will deliver.
At 10 o'clock she started the spasms
and at a 10.15 the first child came out.
The second was coming like that. He was putting his hand inside, trying to turn the child.
And at a certain moment he tells me the child is finished and I was drenched in sweat.
This woman because of pain she was contracting the uterus and his hand was caught inside. He said, my hand,
give a remedy, give a remedy. I said Cuprum, I gave Cuprum and he takes out his hand. Then the woman
because of pain she was fainting. He said, don't let her faint.
Give Carbo vegetabilis, she was coming back. Give this, give that. It was a terrible situation, why?
Because of stupid Sepia 10M at the wrong time for the wrong reasons.
The second child was saved.
Anyhow it's very dramatic things of my life.
-Back to homeoprophylaxis. I get a lot of patients who travel to Africa and Asia and they ask me about
travel vaccination and homeopathic prophylaxis. What is the best policy for these situations? The best advice we can give?
-The best advice? Don't go.
You know I have gone to India back in 63 I was going to India and everyone was saying, you go to India,
you have to be vaccinated. For smallpox, yellow fever, cholera, 3-4 vaccinations. I said, forget it, I like to die in India.
I went to a doctor, can you give me a certificate that I'm vaccinated? He says, yes 10 pounds.
Take 20. He gives me the certificate. I mean who is going to die. The fear that you may die but if your karma is
to die in Africa or in India you accept this was your destiny. What is there so important about each one of us?
We are so important we think the whole world will finish?
Some people will cry for a while, nice man. That's all we are nothing. Why we should be afraid?
Maybe it's my character but I have not felt the fear. If I feel the fear because of some pathology will come to me,
I speak differently but at this moment I don't understand this fear which comes because of pathology.
Because when I give the remedy, they say the fear is gone. So that fear is only pathology.
And people in India are not afraid of dying. I remember a case, the man left Bombay in order to go to die in Benares.
He says, good bye to his children, to his friends. Father where are you going? I'm going to Benares to die near Ganges.
The man who was telling me was his son. He said I had to go with him and we arrived in Benares,
he was in good health, no real problem. We arrived and in Ganges
there are big steps going down to the river. As we descend down in the middle of the steps he collapsed and died.
What is better death than this? Because no fear,  because he was healthy he perceived I'm going to die.
I remember my grand father, I was very young 6 or 7 and I heard him saying to my mother 'Maria
I'm going to die in 3 days, don't worry'. She says, 'father what are you talking?'. I was listening.
I remember no doctor had come to the house, I couldn't remember anybody because he didn't have anything.
He only knew after 3 days he would die, he was 82, 83 I can't remember.
2 days passed, the 3rd day he was actually praying, he was kneeling next to his bed, praying most of the time.
The 3rd day he collapsed, he is finished and I heard the same story again and again. People who are healthy
they are not afraid. Healthy in mental-emotional.
And they can predict when has arrived their time.
Ok I accept and they go. Nice death.
- About the wrong Sepia 10M, can you give us your idea of antidoting?
- In case you have given a wrong remedy, the wrong remedy cannot be antidoted immediately.
Unless you do something very violent. You give some chemical drug very violent.
They say, drink coffee yes. But if you drink coffee you have to drink coffee for 1 week to antidote.
But if you wait the effect will pass away by itself.
I could not wait in this time therefore I had to take the case and give the right remedy.
Once you give the right remedy is antidoted immediately, the wrong action.
-Back to vaccination. Allopathic doctors and medical students have to be vaccinated, it's compulsory to hepatitis B
and University students have to have meningitis. Otherwise you cannot go. So there is an alternative?
-There is no alternative, no. Unless we all agree to bluff and say we have an alternative. If you give sugar
nothing will happen. They will not be affected.
Because there is no epidemic. Why?
Because we are very sick to have an epidemic. Very few people are really healthy to get the epidemic.
And once I am the one who is healthy but all the other cannot get it, if I get it I cannot give it out.
Because most of the population is unhealthy and cannot spread. So the epidemic will be of a limited number.
But watch out if we continue in this way, giving continuously a lot of vaccinations and changing the immune system,
it's going to be a time when it will appear some microbes, bacteria, viruses which will be so virulent
that will take the life of millions, suddenly.
AIDS is one of them. The interesting thing is they say, broken down immune system.
The AIDS means an immune system that has been broken down by what?
By antibiotics, vaccinations and then AIDS comes.
I was treating a case of AIDS in Germany, some of you may remember and he was doing quite well.
Actually I treated in London, who was in London? You remember this German man with Thuja? AIDS, I gave him Thuja
and I said to him 'when did you last have Gonorrhea?'. He said 3 years ago. This is when it started,
the immune system developing AIDS. I gave Thuja and I predicted that this man will again be able to be infected
with Gonorrhea because he would continue have free sex and after that we will not be able to save him.
I said it to the class, it's recorded in the video which they took all the videos and I don't know what they did with these.
And it was exactly like that. One year later he came for a follow up, he had been infected with gonorrhea again,
he took antibiotics and back again.
That means the immune system was uplifted by Thuja and now he was again prone to be infected with an infectious disease.
-Just to clarify the Arnica story. We don't recommend Arnica before birth because may make the cervix less rigid
but then we have at the same time the risk of bleeding.
-Yes, yes. Unless you chose the right remedy, you cannot make Homeopathy massive treatment.
You have this you take that remedy,
you have that, you take that remedy.
-Back again to this man with AIDS. What would have happened if you had treated the Gonorrhea homeopathically
and not with antibiotics?
Maybe he could have been saved?
-He could be saved, yes. Because I knew his way of living, I said do you continue have free sex? Yes.
How many times? Lots of times. With one, with another, I knew his mode of life so I said to the class,
I give him the remedy but this is going to happen. He will continue in the same way and he will be reinfected with Gonorrhea,
he will be treated by antibiotics, he will not tell me and then we're going to have a big problem again.
I treated this man, I continued to treat him in Celle, he was coming for a few years until I brought him to a state where
he broke out with a very severe skin eruption.
That was in his face and body.
I said to him, this is very good. No medicine, wait. He said, yes but what about my face?
He wanted to look nice to continue with the sex behavior.
I don't look nice. I'm sorry I can do nothing for this at this moment, come after 6 months again.
He went, took cortisone and died in 6 months.
He suppressed this, 6 months later he died.
I want to read you something. It's very short from the British Medical Journal. This is British Medical Journal
14 of June 2007 concerning the vaccine
Gardasil which is given to young girls.
To protect them from having cancer and this is a summary from a report in the British Medical Journal
and I would like read it to you very fast.
The HPV vaccine which is being given to girls age 11-12 to prevent cervical cancer in later life maybe a killer.
So far 3 young girls have died after being vaccinated. And there have been 1.637 adverse reactions reported
in less than a year. Nevermind the unreported and continues: in Australia 25 girls at the same school
who had been given their first HPV vaccine last month, experienced headache, nausea and 4 of them
ended in the hospital. Otherwise there are no side effects.
The vaccine Gardazil has controversy since it was approved for use last year.
Some States in the USA have decided to make the vaccine compulsory which has caused an outcry among
parents who see the vaccine as a license
for sexual relationships outside of marriage.
The theme I was talking yesterday, sexual liberation and I will add a few things now.
Gardazil is supposed to protect against human papillomavirus type 6,11,16 and 18 which cause most
cervical cancers and genital warts. A public interest group discovered the extend of the adverse
reactions only when they make a request to the Food and Drug Administration under the freedom of information act.
Presumably the FDA would have preferred to have stayed silent rather than alert the public about a vaccine
that may need more safety trials. I will give you a copy in each one of you, you will get a copy to have it
and give it to your patients when they ask you about .
You say the British Medical Journal they say so, we don't know, we don't know anything.
- In Texas the HPV vaccine is being given in 3 different shots. Each shot is almost 300 dollars. Merck has produced
this vaccine and a lot of people tell me that Merck win thousands dollars from this.
They've been sued for billions over Vioxx,
and I think they're trying to regroup with Gardasil.
-Exactly this is the idea. This has been written in the Internet.
-One more thing George. There are over 120 varieties of HPV. It only covers 4.
-But the selling of the vaccine will cover all the previous loss of the pharmaceutical industry.
-We were talking yesterday about ways to find symptoms to help parents to realize if their children are sensitive
or not to the vaccines. If we go to the Repertory, general vaccination elements after, we find a few remedies.
Could a homeopath help a parent by saying your child looks to me Silica for example. The parent brings the child to the homeopath.
-No, no, no.
-I'm saying could we use the picture of Silica to say to the parent...
-No. There are Silicas which are very healthy, Silicas which are very ill. You cannot say Silica.
The Silica can be a very healthy child, just needs some perspiration and that's all and there is
another one who cannot drag her feet.
-I say if we can say that Silica children are more sensitive than others.
-No we cannot say that. This is what I say.
-I'm so happy that you mention this today because I was going to bring it up yesterday.
In Denmark one of my patients she is 22 at University and she was paid to be vaccinated.
And after 3 vaccinations where she made money for studies, she was in a steady relationship the whole time,
they say this vaccine is wonderful, it works.
You have not got Chlamydia in the past 1,5 year
But she got 3 cancerous cells in the uterus during that time. And Homeopathy took it away again.
-Are you a medical doctor?
-No, I'm just a classical homeopath.
-So you have to find a medical doctor to send a report on this case and say she was there,
she was paid and this is what has happened.
-Yes I will when I go home but the horrible thing is that the marketing is saying 'you don't want your
child to die of cancer do you?' but it's the chlamydia thing.
-We know the tricks. But people are becoming more and more intelligent.
Before we go further I wanted to clarify one thing about yesterday talk.
You maybe thinking that I'm coming from religious family or religious dogma or whatever.
I have nothing to do with any kind of religion. What I understand from experience is that sexual power is a very
powerful energy we have and if we misuse it, if we overuse it, if we don't use it with wisdom is going to have
an effect on the health. You cannot imagine how many times the misuse of this power has brought about the
demise of the individual. I will only give you an example. In Africa if you take world statistics, you will see the deaths
of the African people first are deaths from venereal diseases due to sexual liberation. You see this idea of being liberated
or being democratic or being not suppressive what has brought about? The demise.
The African people are going to disappear. Do you know that? From AIDS, Gonorrhea and Syphilis.
Deaths from Gonorrhea and Syphilis a few years ago were the highest in Africa.
And it is not a matter of preaching here, it is only a matter of health.
What I know I tell you. This is my experience. You do whatever you like, you advice your patients,
your children the way you like.
But this is what I know.
And then if you tell me by suppressing this energy, are you going to have also side effects? The answer is yes.
But the side effects from suppression is going to be minimal in comparison with sexual liberation  where you have all this.
HPV, warts and Condylomata and Chlamydia and all the sexually transmitted diseases.
It's not only that. It is that if you allow your child, your patient from a young age to go into having sexual relationships,
they cannot anymore fall in love later on and enjoy. They lose the enjoyment of being really in love.  That's all.
I say don't do that because you will never enjoy life. You say 'I want to kill myself.  I don't like to live' etc. Why?
Because you abuse this power in very early age. But the mentality of mothers  sometimes is why don't you become a whore?
Go out, find a friend', 12 years old girl in America go and find a boyfriend. 'You don't have a boyfriend? You are sick'.
12,13,14 years. I say, what are you talking madam? But this is the education.