-She said that she was a Reiki master.
I remember one time you said to us
that these kinds of energies are not necessary the best thing to go with homeopathic treatment.
-Who is a Reiki master? Can I speak freely?
-Yes.
-A Reiki master is somebody who deals with the energy. They put their hands or something.
Putting hands it's nice. It can create a good atmosphere, a good feeling.
That's all.
You can be very nice to somebody in the same way like touching.
You have to have a lot of energy to be able really to infuence the energy of another person.
Just by coming near to this person. You have to have a lot of energy, spare energy.
That you are infuencing really in some way the energy of another person.
The problem is that when you do this, when you approach your hands and you try to do what? You don't know.
You just hope that by approaching your hands something will happen. You don't know what is happening.
This is something so much in the dark that anybody can claim anything.
I had a lot of students claiming that I am not a Reiki master but a master of treating with hands, a spiritual healer.
To be a spiritual healer that means you have an energy which is so much in relation to the cosmic energy,
that you can manipulate this cosmic energy and specifically make that person well. What is this? Is that possible?
Is there such a person? You see Christ is considered the highest of the different leaders.
Still when he was trying to do a healing he said, do you believe?
So he needed the belief of the person to trigger the mechanism.
He said, do you believe? Yes.
If you believe you will be cured.
If you believe, you will be cured but to have a strong belief really, very strong to trigger this.
If Christ needed the faith of the person in order to do a healing, how can a normal human being do a healing
without the other person believing 100% in his abilities?
It's a very dangerous thing for me to deal with. Because you get the impression sometimes is acting, is helping.
And then you get a case where is not helping and another case is not helping and then the people
these spiritual healers become quite disturbed.
-I'm married to a Reiki healer. She is a Reiki master, she doesn't call herself a master because the energy masters her.
She works not through the energy but through universal energy. She studied for 3 years and she is practicing
since November last year. She's had phenomenal success. Wonderful success and my memory from the Organon
is that Hahnemann spoke about mesmerism and I tie that in with Reiki energy.
-I have also said that there is such a thing. The difference is that it's so rare to find this.
It's so rare that it's not something to be taught from one individual to another.
Because there are stories we hear, like miracles happening with saints.
These are what we call the placebo effect. The faith on the person gives this triggering
which is similar to the idea of the remedy and the person gets better. If you manage to do that, it's a good placebo effect.
-I don't think to be anybody particularly great. I am a vet and I had one case of hands using.
The dog was dying, it was about 14 years old.
-You are American?
-Yes.
The dog was dying and he was about 14 years old, he was in a cage, he was 3 days and after that he was going to be euthanized.
-Calm down. It's very nice hearing everbody
likes you. There is no hurry.
-So I asked my boss if I could try something, I just wanted to meditate.
-He said, do whatever you like. The dog is going to be killed in half an hour.
So I opened the cage and I hold on to the dog's paw and I'm not a very strong person but I just tried to open myself up
and to pray in God's energy to come through me.
Within 5 minutes it was a huge electric shock that passed from my hands
on the dog's paw and I jumped up and screamed and the dog jumped up and got up and ate a ball of food
and went home. And I found that it didn't have any follow up for 3 years. A man that worked for me said, 'I heard what you did
with that dog he lived for another 3 years perfectly well and died a natural death in a storm'.
-What was the pathology with the dog?
Do you remember?
-Just wasting away. I had to keep looking to see if it was breathing, it was bearly alive.
-His boss was there? He was alive or he had lost his master?
-The master went the dog to the hospital because he was dying and he hadn't eaten in several weeks.
All I knew was that the dog looked like it was dead, I don't know the pathology.
But I did this and it was amazing, it went back home and the dog was totally normal.
I tried to replicate that afterwards and I would never take any money for that and I was never able to do it again.
-Thank you, this is what I was expecting. I would ask you could you replicate that?
This was a special occasion in which you felt very much sympathy to this dog. You really wanted to help.
-I don't know if it was that, I think I was very open.
-Yes, I understand this. This is mentalising. Actually you felt very great sympathy for this dog and you wanted to help this dog.
And you transferred the energy needed for this dog to come back. It was like giving him a homeopathic remedy.
-But it was not a placebo.
-It's not a placebo, this is not a placebo. This is transferring energy through you to the dog and this is what made the dog come back.
-And I really wanted to replicate because I said this is a lot easier than Homeopathy.
I don't need to study anymore !
-That is nice. Before I answer I have a similar experience.
Some of you, you know the story but it doesn't matter, most of you, you don't know.
I always in my backyard had chicken and I did not have a cock and my neighbour gave me a cock.
So I can fertilise the eggs, so the cock was the master of the chicken.
In the meantime some other patient of mine knew that I needed a cock and one day he brought me a cock.
And I put the cock of the neighbour inside a glass house and I let the new cock coming, with the hens.
It was evening, night I can't remember but I left the cock safe. Otherwise I knew they may fight and could kill each other.
Next day, 11 o' clock Sunday I go out to the glass house to take the cock and return it to my neighbour opposite door.
I go inside the glass house and the cock is dead.
So I take the cock and say, oh my god what happened?
I take the cock and I don't know what to say now. Yesterday he was in perfect health, now he is dead.
You know the dead cock, you hold him like this. So I go to my neighboor but I'm trying to understand
what kind of a disease is this affecting the cock? The bird flu or something.
I proceed and before I reach the house, it was only 30 meters, I realised what has happened.
I realise that the cock that was inside the glass house was seeing the other cock with the chicken
and he was charging against the glass until he had a head injury and he died.
So I realise this and I take the cock, go to my neighbour and I say, ok the cock has died recently.
Would you like to eat the cock?
He said, no, no, no.
Nevermind how he died. It's something disgusting. You cannot eat a dead cock.
She says, no, no, no throw him.
I said, either you eat him or I will resurrect him.
She couldn't believe what I said. How can you resurrect a dead cock?
That cock is dead, how can you resurrect him? I said ok keep him here, I go and bring a medicine.
I go and bring Arnica, high potency. I put it in a little water and I open his mouth and put 1-2 drops in his mouth.
And you won't believe it but the moment I put the drop there is a slight movement of one of his  wings.
Just a little jerk. I said, ok I cannot stay with the cock all day but if you want the cock alive, you keep on giving
every hour, you give 1-2 drops. By the evening the cock was up and was going around. She couldn't believe it.
This is a fantastic medicine George, we have to have some medicine, give us this medicine.
In case some brain stroke happens so we can use the medication. It's like this you know, the energy which is synchronised
it can resurrect. The cock was not entirely dead, it was bleeding, it was having a brain stroke.
Arnica dissolved this, because it was recent, within a few hours and the cock was resurrected.
I do not deny this. This is a real experience and it's amazing.
For me it's not amazing I can understand it. What she did it was really synchronising the energy.
-But I really would like to replicate it.
-I know, I know but this is what I say. If you try to replicate forcefully, I mean by doing it, you can damage yourself really.
You can feel out of balance. At a certain moment you may find out that your mind is going "cucu" that you're going crazy.
It's a dangerous thing so you have to be very careful in dealing with this.
You see with homeopathic remedy is totally different because you give the remedy and you're detached from the person.
If you're attaching every time yourself with your energy to another person, you do not know
the transference that can happen the other way around.
And how much influence this can have.
For instance if a homeopath needs Phosphorus
and he does not know it, they are very sympathetic with the patient.
The patient comes, they feel almost what the patient has, they feel it in themselves.
This person either you take Phosphorus or you give up the job. This is dangerous if you are so sensitive.
You see I remember a case of Phosphorus in America, she was so sensitive
she would perceive every feeling of any person.
She had a painful experience and she had to close herself up in the appartment, for years
staying inside to the appartment, without being able to associate with people.
Because of the painful experiences, the receiving. You know what it is?
I mean we are protected, we are closed up. Otherwise whatever happens to somebody, you perceive it.
If you open up completely, you see like some people who are able to do this, they call themselves mediums or whatever.
They are suffering quite a lot and they can go into bigger problems and troubles.
Because they open up and they cannot close.
I know quite a lot of healing books. A lot of claims about healing, I'm very reserved into believing because
in my life as you may understand, I have seen a lot of people, really honest people who believed in such things.
Which when we try to put it in examination, it didn't work, it failed.
It's so easy to say I can see the aura, because there is such a thing as an aura. We all know it.
But who can see it?
And who can see the aura and through the aura recognize that this is an aura which is affected in the liver?
This is another story. So a lot of people can say it because it's a secret, it is closed from investigation
and anybody can say whatever they like or they can project their imagination. They imagine they see an aura.
If you talk about Kirlian photography, I would say I'm investigating at this moment Kirlian photography
in a way that can show me to my satisfaction, whether Kirlian photography can really photograph the aura, yes or no.
-Some years ago a German documentary maker he was visiting the "who is who" all over the world of healers.
He was for 6 years, was going to United States, to Indonesia, to all over and he made 80 hours of recording
'Healers in action'. And then he made a movie for the movie theaters which was only 1 hour so you could see
different healers and at the end he says, it's all the same. All that they do it stimulates the life force,
it doesn't matter if they dance around you, if they paint you blue and they send you to get diarrhoea to Peru,
but they stimulate your immune system. Very interesting film.
-Yes, that we accept that can happen sometimes.
I will tell you so many stories with the pendulum. People believe in pendulum.
I'll tell you what's your remedy. That's your remedy because of the pendulum.
Whenever I tried I've never seen any real effect, any true.
Hundreds of things. I was in Holland and a medical doctor came to me and said, there is a woman
who will hold this and will know if there is a potentised remedy in the bottle.
I said, is that true? Any bottle, she will hold and will say, yes this is potentised.
We were in Amsterdam, she was in another town. Can you call the woman? Yes, we call the woman.
We make an experiment. What was the experiment? 10 bottles, 3 of them contained potentised remedies.
Ok, find these 3 potentised remedies. Find them. You know all the students were around, I did not know which are the potentised.
It was written in an envelope. Potentised number 1, 9 and 10.
The woman comes, takes 1, 2, 3 this potentised, this is potentised. Ok see the numbers. Number 2,7 and 8.
Potentised number 1, 9 and 10. Not one. I said, ok maybe she was a little bit excited because there was a lot of people around.
We repeat the experiment. We repeated 3 times.
The doctor who was bringing this patient was swearing that this woman can feel when a bottle
is having a potentised remedy. I said, I don't believe it but I'm really interested very much.
3 times she could not get one
By chance she could have got one.
He said, 'I'm surprised', ok but what you're saying is so unbelievable to have such a sensitivity to feel the potentised remedy.
We need that woman to check whether the remedies are potentised. We use her as a check up.
I will hire her, I will pay her to tell me if the remedy is correct.
Lots of other times, the same thing with the machine which is potentising.
Scientists of the NASA, no, no, 'George this machine can potentise the remedy'... but this is not possible.
'No, no, no George you are closed, you don't understand this machine will potentise if you turn it in such way', Pulsatilla 10M.
I said, I was exasperated, I said forget it.
Then after some time he felt ill with Hepatitis B, severely ill.
This was in India, I was not there. After a few days he calls me, he was in a terrible state. I went there to see him.
I said, ok now it is time to really have an experience. I will put the remedy and you take it, to see if you have an effect.
Now is the time. Take the remedy. He takes the remedy. Tomorrow I come and see you.
Tomorrow, 'how are you'? 'I'm terrible, exhausted'. I said, 'no take another dose'.
'We may have to wait because you tried to persuade me that this machine can make a potentised remedy.
So this is the time that your test is here'. I left him for 3-4 days but he said finally, 'give me the remedy'.
I said ok, go to the pharmacy, brought it to him. Because the remedy was clear.
Within 2 days, the next hours he was feeling his energy coming. The next day much better.
2,3,4 days later, he was free. I said, ok what shall we do with this. He says, I give it to you.
I said, you throw it to the dustbin.