We start with a little bit of theory. Today I have chosen par. 210 of the Organon.
I think there is a confusion and we will see what is the confusion concerning this paragraph.
There are some teachers who have translated this paragraph 210 as meaning that in every case you have mental symptoms.
This is what Hahnemann says. In every case you have mental symptoms.
Therefore you search for every case for these mental symptoms and find a remedy that fits these mental symptoms in every case.
And here is a kind of misinterpretation of the Organon. And I will tell you why.
I will read the paragraph 210 on which Hahnemann speaks about mental diseases.
He says, most diseases that I have previously described as partial, belong to psora and this appear
to be more difficult to cure owing to the partial development. Where all other symptoms of the disease
are obscured by the presence of one great prominent symptom.
Actually what he means here is when we have a mental disorder, the mental symptoms are becoming very strong
and all the other symptoms
disappear or are suppressed.
The so called diseases of the mind and temperament are of this kind.
These however do not constitute a class of diseases strictly distinct from others.
Because the state of the mind is always altered in so called physical diseases.
And this is where the misinterpretation comes.
The state of the mind is always altered, modified.
So those teachers who read this, they say here Hahnemann says that in every case you will find mental symptoms.
Therefore you have to find a remedy that fits the mental picture.
Is this correct? You're reading this paragraph 210 and Hahnemann says, the state of mind is always altered
during any disease physical or otherwise. Therefore do you have or do you not have mental symptoms?
If Hahnemann says so, how can we think otherwise?
Here Hahnemann has a sub-note 121 which gives an example of what he means.
He says in painful diseases for instance, of several years standing, we frequently meet with gentle dispositions
commanding respect and compassion on the part of the physician, for the patient.
But as soon as the disease is conquered and the patient restore to health, a possibility of frequent occurrence
under homeopathic treatment, the physician will often be amazed and shocked at the frightful changes
in the disposition of the patient. Ingratitude, obduracy, refined malice and the most disgraceful
and capricious are often seem to reappear all of which were peculiar to the patient in times of health.
Is this a suppression? The person was cured from a long standing disease.
And you cure him and while he was nice, then he becomes malicious, irritable.
Is Hahnemann talking about a suppression here?
And he goes on in the same paragraph. He says, persons who are patient in health are often found in sickness
to be obstinate violent and hasty or intolerant and woeful, impatient or despairing.
Those who are previously chaste and modest, are then found lascivious and shameless.
A bright intellect is not infrequently found to be dull, a person commonly of weak mind on the other hand,
will be more sensible, while one of sluggish intellect, sometimes shows great presence of mind
and promptness, resolutions etc.
So what he says is, both are possible.
A person who was malicious etc. during a severe chronic
disorder he changes his disposition, his temperament, his mental symptomatology  and becomes very nice.
And the opposite is true. Some people who were very nice during the disease become irritable, angry etc.
Our question that we were examining is whether in all cases, we're going to search for mental symptoms?
Are we going to search for mental symptoms in all cases? Do we have mental symptoms in every case?
Hahnemann seems, according to the interpretations these teachers say, there are.
But Hahnemann does not say that the mind is always diseased; he says that the mind is always altered.
And in paragraph 253 he makes a distinction between a healthy mind and the diseased mind.
Although not visible at all the condition of the mind and the general behavior of the patient are among the most
certain intelligible signs of incipient improvement or of aggravation in all diseases especially in acute ones.
You see, if you read this paragraph in connection with 210 and the sub-note of 210 you will think that either Hahnemann
is contradicting himself or he means something else. Hahnemann actually was a great observer.
A man who had great thinking powers and could observe and then put things in order, put things in the right context.
So he says, incipient improvement however slight is indicated by increased sensation of comfort,
graded tranquility and freedom of the mind heightened courage and return of naturalness in the feelings of the patient.
The signs of aggravation, however slight, they may be opposite of the preceding and consist in an embarrassed,
helpless state of mind while the deportment attitude and actions of the patient appeal to our sympathy.
This condition is readily to be seen or demonstrated to a careful observer but not to be described in so many words.
Hahnemann says that if you have these feelings tranquility, freedom etc. you are healthy.
So he describes what is health and he describes what is disease. In par. 210 he says, the mind is always altered.
And he explains in sub-note that the mind can become tranquil etc. and the opposite can be true.
During the disease the mind can be aggressive etc. The issue seems a little bit complicated.
In par.211 he says, the state of the patient's mind and temperament is often of most decisive importance
in the homeopathic selection of the remedy.
Before he has said, the mind is always altered. In next paragraph he says, the state of the patient's mind
and temperament is often, not always, of decisive importance.
Of course we all know that when we have mental symptoms, these symptoms are important to be taken
into consideration for our homeopathic prescription. They are important often, not always.
What that means?
par.212. The effect upon the state of the mind and disposition is the principal feature of all diseases and seems to have been
especially ordained by the Creator of all healing powers. There is not a single potent medicinal substance
that does not possess the power of altering perceptibly the mental condition and mood of a healthy person
who voluntarily tests a drug. Indeed each medicinal substance affects the mind in a different manner.
He says that all medicinal substances affect the mind as well. That is different.
If you keep on hammering a person with a substance, it will affect his mind as well, one time or another.
This is different from saying that in all diseases, you're going to find, in front of you, you have a patient
you're going to find mental symptoms. Here in these paragraphs says something else also.
The question is, have we proved all the substances available?
Therefore if we haven't proved all the substances, we're going to have some mental states
which are not covered by the known remedies.
You may get a mental state of a patient belonging to a drug that has not been proved so far
and therefore it is not available. What are you going to do?
We have already small drugs for which we do not know the mental symptoms of the small drugs.
So if a mental case belongs to that drug about which we don't know the mental symptoms, how we go about
finding the mental symptoms on that case.
If we really try to say, no he has mental symptoms, therefore we're going to base our prescription
on the mental symptoms alone and we're forcing a solution according to these mental symptoms that belong to Arundo,
we don't know Arundo's mental symptomatology but it's similar to Phosphorus.
So we fitted and we give Phosphorus.
And of course we fail.
Most of the so called diseases of the mind are in reality bodily diseases.
Certain mental and emotional symptoms are peculiar to every bodily disease. These symptoms develop
more or less rapidly in a state of most conspicuous one sidedness and are finally transferred like a local disease
into the invisibly fine organs of the mind where by their presence they seem to obscure the bodily symptoms.
What he says here is very interesting.
He says, you have bodily symptoms?
You suppress them one way or another. You suppress them and what you see?
Mental symptoms.
And this has become a one sided disease.
And he gives an example in next paragraph. He says, is a common observation that a dangerous physical disease,
such as suppuration of the lungs he means Tuberculosis, or other destructive and acute affections
have certain mental symptoms. These are subject to rapid development and often degenerate to insanity
melancholy or raving madness where by all threatening bodily symptoms are going to vanish
and seem to be replaced by perfect health.
He has observed that when the Tuberculosis was doing better by suppressive measures, we see insanity.
That means the disease goes into the mind and then when we treat, we see the reverse order.
We treat insanity, we see tuberculosis developing.
During the period of tuberculosis, you will not be seeking mental symptoms.
You prescribe Veratrum album for a mental case.
And after the remedy you see the tuberculosis developing.
And now you have in front of you a severe physical problem. Now you are going to search for another remedy most probably.
Are you going to take into consideration again the mental symptoms that were before?
If you do you will have to give the same remedy but this is not the case in most of the times.
Most of the times you need another remedy and you will base the prescription, for that second prescription
you will base it in the physical symptoms of the patient. I'll give you an example, a real example
which I'm handing at this moment.
A severe anxiety with phobias 'what is this, what is that, I'm dying. This is cancer, no this is my heart'.
They run to cardiologist, they run to oncologist, they run to one doctor after another, something is all the time
there that is happening. They are going to die, you know this anxiety which is terrible to handle.
And then you battle with 1,2,3 wrong remedies. The 4th remedy hits the mark and then she's calmed down.
What you will see in most of the cases if it is a severe anxiety neurosis, in most of the cases you will see two things.
Especially in women I'm talking. Either you will see skin eruption or you will see severe leucorrhea.
Discharge from the vagina with itching. The vagina becomes irritated and then it's fast discharging.
During this itching and discharge, which they will call mycosis or whatever maybe the allopathic diagnosis
during this time the person feels better and better.
The more the discharge, the better she feels. So you say, 'now you don't have any fears?'
'No, I don't have any fear'. But you see now something very severe. Before she could see nothing.
She would imagine only. 'I have a pain here, a pain there, a knob here, it's developing to cancer, can you see?'
I said 'I don't see anything'. 'But it's something I get here. No, I don't see anything'.
There it comes with a severe discharge, itching, the vagina is irritated and she says 'no I don't care'.
That means the mind has become healthy now and we have to treat the discharge.
Are we going to force her to find mental symptoms during that state?
I will tell you. I tried to treat this case for 6 months and I failed. I gave 1,2, Sepia, Carb-ac, different remedies. Failed.
Actually I was more and more aggravating the leucorrhea, the discharge. So she got fed up with me and she went to
a gynecologist and he says it's quite easy, it was not easy. She had to take treatment for a few months
and the discharge was really suppressed. For a period of time 3,4,5 months I can't remember she had no discharge
no anxiety. She was happy. Ok.
6 months later she comes again. She does not come to me, she starts going again cardiologist, oncologist,
makes the whole rounds paying all these money and then finally after she gets the same answers as before,
take tranquilizers, take this, take that, then she comes back to me and I said ok, you start again.
Take this remedy. I know now the remedy, it's more easy for me to cure her, her anxiety.
Anxiety goes away, again the discharge is there. Now this is a case where you are treating now the discharge
and you have to treat according to the physical symptoms.
These are the guiding symptoms now but the case may come to you, straight as a case of leucorrhea.
In which case even Sepia will not have the mental picture of Sepia. You will not see the mental picture of Sepia.
In spite of the fact you see the Sepia leucorrhea, so in this case you will have to base your prescription
upon the physical symptoms alone. You do not have mental symptoms anymore
and I will tell you my experience of 35-36 years in treating severe diseases, the systemic diseases,
what we call the collagen diseases lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis etc.
you get these cases which are severe and you see no mental symptoms, no mental picture.
Do you have fears? No. You have anxieties? No. You have some kind of depression? No.
They are quite healthy in the mental state.
How are you going to find mental symptoms?
She is so sick, you will not find mental symptoms.
You have to prescribe on physical symptomatology.
If you want to be realistic, if you want to be professional, if you are going to treat cases on a professional basis
that means every day you have to see 10 cases and you have to treat them, you have to be successful in 7-8 of them.
Being successful once a year and having a beautiful case which you bring and present on video is not professional.
Professional is to benefit at least 8 of 10 cases. This is professionalism.
And this is what we are aiming at when we say students need proper training.  Proper training is to attain that state.
So this is clear. The mind is altered it means it can be altered towards the right direction.
It's altered, it's modified, it changed towards the right direction. Hahnemann knew what he was writing.
Now we come to the last question where we say, what does he mean when he says that after
a severe disease you cure, the bad character comes up again.
Is this suppression? How do you know?
There are certain factors which I will give you to judge if it is a suppression or not.
First of all suppression does not last for very long. The organism will bring back.
Secondly a suppression will make the person who has now the mental symptoms, feel much worse
than before when he had the physical symptoms.
The person will feel much worse now. The limitation on this person will be greater.
He was not able to work before, he was not able to function socially before, now when his physical symptoms
are suppressed and he has mental problems, now he is worse.
But if the limitations of the person who has been cured, are less than before it means that he has come up
with his either personality traits, qualities and everyone of us has qualities as a personality.
One of us is born with a phlegmatic personality; it doesn't matter whatever happens, it happens for the others not for me.
Another one is born with much more excitable personality.
One is born with the idea that the world must be like this and acts according to this idea.
Another one is born with another idea and acts according to this idea. So there are unique personalities.
Each one of us has a different personality. That's why we can never agree totally in everything.
Each one of us has a different personality and this is how it should be.
These personality qualities they will never change.
If you try with Homeopathy to change the personality of the person, this is totally wrong.
What you can change upon the personality?
You have some pathology.
My personality is to be excitable. What happened to you?
You listen this is your personality. Now pathology comes.
I become mentally disturbed, instead of saying what 'happened to you?' and I listen the anxiety overwhelms me
and he says 'my God!'. It becomes much bigger this trait of the personality. It becomes pathology now.
My natural qualities become much bigger. I cannot handle it. It's something beyond, cannot control myself.
'Something has happened to my child! My God save it!'.
Helleborus will act in one way, Phosphorus will act another way, Arsenicum etc will act in another way upon the same problem.
Before they could control, there was some kind of balance in this personality trait.
Now, if pathology hits the person on this level, then these qualities become accentuated.
One is phlegmatic, he says it doesn't
matter. Tomorrow it will be better.
And then something happens outside and he says 'I have no feelings. I don't feel anything'. This is pathology.
Before they were some feelings. Now there are no feelings. It is like a stone inside. Total indifference.
They say, what do we need, why do we live? This is total indifference. It's pathology.
It's not a phlegmatic state. A person is serious and studious it is duty bound.
But when this duty bound quality is accentuated, then you will work, work, work until exhausts himself and totally collapse.
This is pathology. And then it needs treatment of course. But you will never change the basic quality of the person.
That is why sometimes the persons looking upon themselves they don't like some of the traits which they have.
And they come to homeopath and say 'what can you do for my excitability? I'm very excitable. What can you do? I'm fast'.
You see people are fast, people are slow, born like this as a quality. You cannot change that.
Pathology can change it of course. For instance, a Veratrum album child. The Veratrum album speeds up the mind
of the child and the child is crooked thinking.
Then don't think anymore straight. They think in a crooked way. They make a question here, before they know the answer
they put another question which is towards that direction and that direction. And you feel this child is very intelligent.
You know people have brought me the child from abroad. Our child is very intelligent, actually too intelligent.
We are afraid because he is very intelligent. And they were right. He was in a specific school for intelligent children
and you could see that the child was keeping up this over excitability of the mind and soon the child would just
break down and will become nothing and leave the school all together. You could feel that.
The parents could feel also that. And they said, on the other hand emotionally the child is totally beyond his age.
Mentally, this over stimulation of the mind. Emotionally, immaturity. And they brought the child and they were worried.
The child was not interested in girls. He has no interest and little things which show the emotional immaturity
but the parents got really worried. I said, well if
I prescribe for him, what are you going to see, not anymore first in his class.
He will become second or third. Maybe fourth.
But this will be good, don't worry. They understood.
They said, 'you are right we are feeling the same thing that the child is going to break down very soon'.
It was 12,13 years old when he was brought to me. Now he is a healthy child. He finished his school with Veratrum album.
If Veratrum album was not given to that child, God help. He would have an insane person at the age of 18.
He would have insanity definitely.
In this particular case according to my evaluation, they were several factors.
There is some hereditary predisposition first of all for a child to go towards that state.
Then this predisposition is triggered or excited by several factors. One, very early one is the immunization of the child.
The child gets immunizations which stimulate the defense mechanism. They force the organism to produce antibodies.
You produce antibodies of that type, of that type and then the child gets his first bronchitis. And there come the antibiotics.
There is a family, this was a very rich family of a European country
you know in these families how the children are treated. You are the king. The child has to perform.
So that stimulated mind feeling the obligation that had towards the parents to be good, he forces himself to stimulate
his mind and to become first or second in his class.
You know in Veratrum album children you will see a kind of indifference towards attainment.
It's natural for me to be like this, forget it, it's not serious, yes I'm first it doesn't matter.
The Veratrum child thinks very fast but you will see, you will perceive there is something wrong.
Even in the way they make movements.
The legs will not go straight, they will go like this sometimes, they will have round kind of movements.
I just remember one case; I was trying to treat the child of a friend and they have visited us here in Alonissos.
The child was very intelligent and very active. They have come to my house. In my house I have these things
for the mosquitoes in the doors and in the main door the net was a little broken. And I watched the child looking
at the door and saying to his mind - this is pathology - what a nice thing if I kick this and it just opens a big hole.
So my eyes caught him on thinking that and I left him, forgot it. One hour later I look and it's a big hole there.
Lefteris come here! I said why did you do that? Lefteris did when nobody was looking of course.
He was sure nobody was looking. It was 5-6 years old but what I caught is the crooked thought, then his restlessness,
then the intelligence then I put things together and say, oh my God this is a Veratrum case.
Before I arrived at that state I called the child and said 'why did you do that?', I was very nice.
I wanted to know if he can explain to me his thinking. I said 'why did you do that?'.
'I didn't do it'. I said 'yes but I saw you'. He wanted to leave. I said 'explain to me why?'
'No, I didn't do it, he left'. I called his mother, I said, because this is an imagination, I have imagined I saw him
but maybe some accidental thing has happened
I called his mother and I said 'please find out this is what has happened'.
And this is important for me to know. And I started putting things together for the patient. Then the mother called
and says, well he always says the truth.
All mothers! So he will tell me. She asked Lefteris, did you do it? So the mother comes to give me the feedback.
She says 'he did not accept but he did not deny it either. Which gives me a suspicion that he has probably done it'. I said, ok.
Next time he comes and as soon as he comes 'hello Lefteris why did you do it? Why did you do it?'. No answer.
2nd day, 3rd day, 4th day, 5th day he says to his mother 'why are we go to George again?'
He says 'I feel a heavy load because he asks me about the door'.
But then I could observe how he would move, how he would do and then it's an interesting feature on Veratrum children
how they have a heroic type of personality. The persons who would stand for others and all that.
One of these nights they were 10 children playing around my house and they got excited and they were shouting,
playing around and we were talking. I shouted, 'shut up'. All the children were just frozen. Lefteris comes
'why you shout? You will not let us play even?' He stood up.
We have given Phosphorus to him because he was nice so intelligent, Phosphorus...
And of course that was one of the doctors in Athens and then they come to me and I observe this and of course
observing the mental and the disposition, really there is pathology in this case. Now Lefteris is very intelligent,
he is one of the first in his class but he is not active like this. Since then, 5-6 years now I needed to repeat
the remedy 2-3 times I can't remember. Within the 5 years whenever he has a relapse he goes again to that state.
Restlessness and the mother knows again he has been in that state, give him. Within a few days the child becomes calm.
This is a little bit for Veratrum.