Thank you.
If the Germans applaud that means the job is done.
I received this morning at about 4-5 a.m. an email which I’d like to read it to you.
You may be surprised I was working at 4 a.m. but I have remained so much back with the emails that I have to get up very early.
So, I don’t have much time for sleep.
Maybe some of you remember that according to the model which I presented to you I said that fever is a good sign as long as there was no fever before, now there is fever.
But also you remember that I have said that in the very end stage of life of a person usually appears a high fever which is the final stage.
Who remembers that? Who heard this for the first time? I want to see some hands! Only 2 people? I will tell you now the story.
One of the students, an Indian lady, she is the oldest of the group from India, she got up during the lecture and she thanked me very much saying that for 2 years her mother was treated by me without me knowing her, the information was sent to me by her.
She was treated and how happy she was because the doctors 2 years ago had given her mother a few days more to live.
So she had lived another 2 years.
Her mother must have been around 80 I can’t remember now the exact age and she thanked me and she was crying…
What was interesting with this case it was that every time she would give me some information about her, symptoms changed and I prescribed another remedy.
That means in 2 years I had prescribed 10 remedies or more because symptoms were changing so as you know in the end stages of diseases there is no possibility for a cure.
What you can do is ameliorate the symptoms so the lady was suffering because she was full of cancer in the lungs, couldn’t breathe,
terrible situation in the beginning but got better and better. But still no cure.
This morning I received this email, I am going to read you.
She says on Saturday, 4 days ago, I came to know my mother had fever of 40,3 C.
When I read this I did not need to read the rest.
I knew what would follow. Now you listen what followed.
The lady was taking care of her told me the fever came suddenly and she was given Belladonna 200C.
I reached Hyderabad (the Indian town where her mother was) on Sunday evening.
No fever after Belladonna but she was not breathing well.
She had a person fanning her and gave Carbo vegetabilis.
She settled down, the lady became quieter.
She checked on her at 3 a.m. she found that the old lady was restless and there was burning pain with some eruption.
The treatment had brought about some eruptions.
Gave her Arsenicum 30C and on Monday morning, listen to that, she enjoyed her hot drink,  brushed her teeth, went to the commode,
washed herself and after the bath asked for something to drink.
By 12.00 in the noon breathing became very difficult with great restlessness, gave her Arsenicum 200C she felt good and said to her that she was feeling better.
Slowly, with full consciousness and peace she passed away at 3 p.m.
I sat with her holding her hand and she asked me to pray for her.
It was a beautiful moment for me.
Your teaching prepared me to know that the high temperature meant that the time had come. Thank you, sir.
This is a different kind of medicine that we are teaching here.
It’s another aspect of medicine.
Let us suppose the lady had antibiotics for this high fever.
What would antibiotics have done? Would have sent her straight to coma state, become a vegetable and live 10 more days in comatose state
instead of being peaceful, understanding what was coming on, she said to the daughter please pray and left.
This is the beauty of Homeopathy as long as we understand what to do, how to do it and don’t think...
it’s difficult, I cannot do it.
Try and you will see the difference between all kinds of medication.
They’ll be soon talking about that and classical Homeopathy according to the symptoms.
Carbo vegetabilis. It soothed her down and then Arsenicum 30C and then 200C.
Every case that I have seen going through the last stages they have the same story.
Peacefully passing to the next state which almost never happens under heavy drugging. There pains.
Some suffering is there because a lady with metastasis where she is ready to die and they say she has 3 more days to live, take her home
and she lives for another 2 years quite comfortably. It’s what Homeopathy can offer in the last stages.
For those who have read my book “The science of Homeopathy”, it was written in 1976- 1978.
There is chapter on euthanasia, go back and read this chapter and you will see what I had already realize during that time concerning Homeopathy
and how Homeopathy could help the dying patient to go on the transition with maximum awareness and minimum suffering.
I have already written a chapter in 1976.
It took 40 years from 1976. I waited. The world would understand.
You are responsible now because you are the ones that know.
I will see your actions. I want to say a few more things.
This is an idea which shows the necessary conditions for the potencies.
When a potency has to be high and when it has to be low.
Many times people who are accusing me say that George doesn’t accept any other therapy or anything else.
That is wrong.
George simply knows what each therapy can do and I have been giving this information.
In this diagram it shows in the bottom part “Herbs, vitamins, minerals, allopathic drugs” and all kinds of medical drugs,
all kinds of substances, anyone who comes up with any idea. “Lemon is good for this” etc.
All these ideas with material medicine belong to the physical, material part of the body.
It’s a material medicine which affects the body materially.
So if your body doesn’t assimilate well the magnesium, you may give magnesium or selenium or zinc or a mineral as a supplement.
You may give a vitamin.
You may give a supplement when the thyroid is not working, you give thyrhormone and the person continues.
When your body cannot produce insulin, you give insulin so digestion can continue.
In the same way cortisone is also a hormone of the body which is needed for defense and they misuse that.
They don’t even know how to use cortisone.
I think they are giving huge doses of cortisone suddenly.
When you give a huge dose of cortisone in somebody you stop his own production of cortisone totally.
Instead of giving a supplement and wait a little bit, give some time to the organism, the organism doesn’t produce enough cortisone,
give a supplement, give a little bit and then increase the doses slowly so you let the organism produce as much cortisone as it can
and supplement just a little bit more if it is needed and then you will not have this tragic cases of cortisone poisoning.
I think they are using their own tools in a bad way.
Enough with cortisone.
It’s drug we do not like because it is very powerful because it concerns itself with the defense mechanism.
The moment that you strengthen this you suppress all other symptoms, you have no other symptoms to go guide you to the remedy.
Therefore stay away from cortisone because once
the organism is used to have external cortisone
replacing our own suprarenal glands stop working
and they do not produce cortisone anymore.
So you have to give it for the rest of his life.
That’s why they say once you start cortisone then you have to take it constantly.
All these drugs and supplements will act on the physical body that means on the electro-chemical structure of the body.
Because they act on the material body they will act with everyone.
If you have a problem with your liver and somebody tells you the liver needs this supplement, herbs, makes up 4-5 herbs and give it to persons
who have liver problem, everyone will be affected.
The idea of this diagram is that here on this area whatever you are giving it will affect everybody, in this area, right to the top, there, there,
there’s only one remedy and has to be absolutely correct.
You have no place to play around.
You have to be absolutely correct with the similimum.
Then you can give a high potency.
The picture is clear, the pathology is not gross, you can go and give it.
But you have to be very accurate, to the point.
As you go down the limits to which you are limited are broadening.
There’s a big secret here.
The secret is that as you go higher and higher you have to be more and more accurate in order to have an effect
but at the same time if you have a 12X or 6X these will work on this area.
So it will catch a lot more people that a high potency.
So the people who are giving mixtures of remedies, polypharmacists, low potencies, they have some effect
and this is much easier that trying to find the uppermost remedy.
What is the problem? Chronic headaches, liver
cirrhosis or fatty degeneration, kidney problem
then we know a few remedies that affect more
or less the liver or the headaches etc.
Put them together in low potency and we have a specialty and we sell this and we say that it is a good specialty for fever or for whatever.
This is easy and it is effective.
That’s why they tell me George please leave us alone, we are happy, we have some effect with mixtures of remedies etc.
Why do we bother? The reason is when you have a case like this, when you have 3 or 4 layers already when you started the case,
try in such a case to give mixtures of remedies.
What would you observe in this case? Something which is very important; you observe that the red line which is the uppermost, its peak,
it represents one symptom, but what you observe is from the second layer, the yellow, there are 3 symptoms coming from the lower level
which is underneath and these 3 symptoms (which may be not 3 but 10 or 12) will manifest after the first layer is gone,
then when the second layer is coming up they will manifest much more clearly together with the rest of the symptoms indicating a remedy.
But still there are few symptoms coming from the third layer pointing through the yellow and also from the fourth layer.
From the fourth layer there is a symptom that stays all along.
I’ll give you an example; you treat somebody with obsessive neurosis.
One of his/her symptoms is severe constipation.
It may have started when the patient was 12 years old together with her menses and after this the patient was treated for an acute,
a bronchitis or pneumonia, with antibiotics, the constipation became even worse, the antibiotics affected the person
and anxiety started developing, it was treated when she was 17 or 19.
The anxiety was treated and with some anxiolytic drugs and eventually the panic attacks manifested and the panic attacks presented
and treated with drugs and then the person became psychotic.
You are treating this person and as you go along from depression and mental confusion then it comes to less confusion
but once the layers are the one on the top of the other then as you go and take out the layers you find out that the original constipation remained
till the end and after the fifth remedy together with some other symptoms… But as you take away the layers the whole organism is on a higher level.
You take the third layer out… You cannot take it out.
It’s difficult.
So you have treated the 2 layers correctly.
The person is doing quite well but here is coming a stress.
While you have two layers remaining for treatment there comes an acute.
Somebody lost her boyfriend, a love affair, somebody had a severe acute, some others had some stress
because the condition in their environment became very intolerable, they are suffocating and somebody has lifted a very heavy weight and a new situation was formed.
Then you cannot go to treat the third layer.
You first treat the damage that was done by the stress and get rid of that so that the third layer eventually will appear.
Another example.
Let’s say you have been treating an endogenous depression, deep depression and you gave one remedy Aurum,
it’s better Natrum muriaticum, it’s better and there is a stress on that person and you see the vertigo starting which looks like Meniere’s disease.
And the third layer was supposed to be Calcarea carbonica and it has this vertigo but the details of the vertigo look more like Conium.
So you have to give first Conium and then Calcarea carbonica will manifest again clearly as a third layer.
But first you have to give not Calcarea carbonica but Conium.
So eventually you treated the third level and there is a jump in the energy, happiness and joy of life.
If the joy of life comes you better stop treating! This is the deepest, the most important for the human being.
You will understand what I mean.
Can you imagine a person who is really in love, full of happiness, thinking of her boyfriend and the meeting is fantastic.
Can you imagine such a person doing wrong, having hatred, negative emotions? That joy of life doesn’t allow you to think.
You forgive even your enemies… You don’t even think about it.
Most probably some of you have been through that period when you were 12-13-14 because it’s a state of innocence.
Joy is state of innocence.
You have to be innocent in order to feel joy.
Unless you are really innocent the conscience which is always there watching says you are not clear there,
you cannot be happy, you are not allowed to be happy, you are not allowed to enjoy because you have done this and that.
Usually they don’t know.
We have done so many bad things that we don’t know we have done this and that.
If we knew we could do something.
We do so many wrong things in our lives that we are overloaded with negative experiences and emotions and the joy is lost.
So you  get the remedy and then the joy comes.
Then you say be careful now because you have to replace all the damage you have done in your life in order to keep it otherwise will not remain for long.
So Homeopathy will give you the possibility to clear up the subconscious which is overloaded with all the negative experiences
but during the time you are feeling so happy then you can do no wrong.
Can you imagine the world with happy people? Do you know the think tanks there exists? Do you know what it is?
A think tank is a group of people who are constantly busy thinking how we will enslave others.
How we can make other work for us but they will not get anything but bread, football, movies etc.
My football team has won! They can kill at this moment.
They have so much energy generated and they feel a rude happiness.
It’s not subtle happiness.
For a moment. And they next day they’re back to depression.
If Homeopathy can give the possibility of somebody to be in a happy state that’s the end.
You have done your duty even if there still is some pathology that remains.
In incurable cases people can be happy that means in the mental/ emotional site a person can be clear and cured
and all the problems can come to the physical body.
You see a pathology which is quite heavy but then the joy returns.
Let’s get back again. Red line.
You have made a mistake because you took into consideration 5 symptoms that do not belong to this, like the green, the yellow
and the blue because some symptoms are peaking up and you pick them in the taking of the case.
So you pick up symptoms from underneath and you gave a wrong remedy but you are a good prescriber so your remedy is quite close.
This good remedy that you gave what will do? Will modify the uppermost layer that means some do the symptoms will go away,
some others will stay but actually no progress. It’s a modification.
Then you give another but you know what happens.
If you insist on this way of treating, the wrong remedy that you will give or it will appear to be the wrong remedy will push the symptoms of the right remedy
more to the fore and the next time will give you a clearer idea of the layer and then you give the remedy and then the layer is gone.
During this process of taking away a layer actually there is a possibility that one of these layers
which has been created by the genetic predisposition of the parents who gave you this predisposition, this uppermost layer
which comes from what we may call predisposition to tuberculosis it may go away not with one remedy but with 3 remedies.
3 remedies to take away the tubercular or the syphilitic or the sycotic predisposition.
If you are observing carefully you may have given Aurum as the first remedy which is mostly a syphilitic remedy and the next thing
that you will find is again a syphilitic remedy which is Mercury as a second remedy or Syphilinum.
After Mercury or Syphilinum then you see the sycotic remedy; Thuja, Medorrhinum or Nat-s.
You don’t have to think in this way.
Because if you think according to miasms, it’s mechanical, most probably you will make a mistake.
You have to go by the symptoms at the moment.
This is the greatest secret. Don’t use mechanical ideas.
Detoxification of the organism, we find a formula to detoxify you… This is nonsense.
The detoxification formula contains Nux-v., Sep., Calc….
Of course, one of these remedies may be your remedy so it will have some effect.
The more the whole organism goes higher the more you are allowed to give a high potency.
In the beginning when you have a deep pathology, it’s not clear, it’s better to go with low potency.
It will do something because it will catch much more 12th potency will act more or less on these levels.
Your remedy that is very low will affect quite a lot of cases.
You do not have to be so absolutely correct.
When you are on the box there you have the supplements everybody will be affected but also you have to be careful
because maybe the person who you think needs this supplement has it in excess.
If Kalium is in excess and you give it you will damage him.
That’s why from time to time people come out and say do not give a lot of vitamins, maybe it’s dangerous.
Don’t give a lot of cortisone because it’s dangerous etc.
If you give a lot of insulin you’ll have a coma state.
It will affect everyone who has a problem with his pancreas.
But if you give it too high you send him in hypoglycemic coma.
Even in this basic box there you have to be careful, if you want to use such supplements.
Who is perspiring here? Who feels comfortable? This is the idea when you take a case.
You have to find what the normal is and whether the symptoms are much beyond the norm.
Because a person under heat situation will perspire but how much will he suffer from that? It’s important to write down.
Don’t write it as a symptom of mine.
I don’t know myself so what about you…
- I have a question related to this chart about the potencies.
What about LM potencies in this chart?
- LM potencies are low potencies.
I consider them as low potencies and I do not consider them as powerful ones.
Therefore the first law is you have to repeat them every day 2-3 times in order to be effective that means the potency is not very strong.
LM1, LM2, LM3, LM5 but the difference is very small I believe.
I don’t have much experience but I would consider them to have the same position as low potencies on the centesimal scale.
All low potencies need to be repeated.
All vitamins in order to act have to be repeated.
Every day you take your vitamins.
Every day you take your mineral that you need because you say if I take it I feel better.
That means you take the vitamin or the mineral but you’re not cured.
The basic mechanism which is damaged is not repaired because you don’t take the vitamins for 10 days and then you are fine.
You have to take vitamins for the rest of your life.
If a mineral is good for you that means the organism cannot absorb this and you replace it you take it for the rest of your life.
If you need thyrhormone you take you for the rest of your life, insulin etc.
This is not a cure but after all if we cannot do otherwise what shall we do? Yes you can give.
The thing is that you have to have in mind that when you give a vitamin or you give several vitamins, herbs, minerals then you mask the overall picture.
You don’t have the real picture on which to prescribe the remedy.
If you do that then you start losing the clearness of the picture.
In order to be sure about yourself and what you are doing you have to study quite a lot.
Some people think for Homeopathy that you go in a seminar for 1-2 weeks and you learn, 3 weeks and you’re an expert!
4 weeks you are flying! This is nonsense. It’s a very difficult because this science is so precise.
You have to learn it. You know what this is? I’ll tell.
It’s a mixture of the most powerful drugs in the world! I put them all here so just one sip and I’m back!
I don’t to play tricks but… I played these tricks once just to show you what the fantasy can do.
When we say we need new provings and the provings are done the way they are usually done today then what happens in these provings is almost imagination.
If tell you in this I have put the most powerful drugs in the world, take one sip.
Everyone takes one sip and then I have a proving and then I ask what did you feel and I collect all the symptoms
and then I write a book on taking a sip of the most powerful drugs.
But if do it seriously you will believe it.
Because I am your teacher I have some authority over you… In the previous seminar we had the aphorisms concerning provings
and then people realized what it means to make a proving. Not this kind of nonsense.
You take a drug, you take it over your pillow and you dream in the night the effect of the drug…
- I have question about that graph.
Can you put it back.
I have been trying to figure it out for 3 days.
Is there a relationship between the horizontal axis to the levels? What is the relationship?
Does it mean when the level is low we can catch, affect more people with low potency?
- Yes.
Will affect more people.
– So when a person is on level 1 and you give them…
- You have 10 patients that are in the lower part and they all suffer of their liver.
You give low potencies to them and all of them will have some effect.
– But the people on high levels will not?
– But the people on the higher level will not unless the remedy for them is there, included.
In this case you have 2 possibilities; one is that the person will feel good for a short period of time or the other remedies
which are not the correct ones may also do a kind of a proving because you have repeated them for a longer period.
So you will have proving symptoms of the rest of the remedies.
The correct remedy will make him feel quite good.
The other people will feel an effect but it will be a modifying effect not a curative effect.
There is a difference between curative and modifying effect.
I can modify your structures by a remedy but I cannot cure you unless I give you the correct one.
But because I l know that everyone has gone through a lot of grief, I can see in your faces all of you have struggled with grief situations…
If I give you Nat-m. 200C 50% of you will feel for a while a bit better.
It’s a modification of your uppermost layer which may need Ign., Caust., Staph. but still Nat-m.
will have some similarity that will modify your layer so you will have some kind of an effect.
This has a lot more to say but I don’t want to confuse you now, at this moment, by giving you all the information.
– This morning you lectured about Homeopathy and drugs like coffee.
In our society we are surrounded by drugs and many times patients take drugs and they don’t admit it.
So this might have some effect on the dosage.
How would you adjust the dosage if you have a patient for who you know that he takes drugs?
– You have to repeat much more, everyday sometimes or every third day.
He drinks coffee, sometimes 5 cups of coffee a day, you have to repeat every day.
If he drinks one cup you have to repeat every 3 days if he cannot stop.
You can still have an effect but still coffee may finally win.
That means the caffeine will overturn the balance which your remedy created.
It will finally do it.
Whether it will take 1-3 years.
– And in the case of cannabis?
-Same as coffee as excessive alcohol intake as cocaine.
All the recreational drugs, LSD, speed etc.
Every day the find another drug to speed up the brain.
All these drugs that have an effect on the brain they demolish the effect of the homeopathic remedy.
Do not allow any effect to take hold and to stay.
But these do not go to the extent that if somebody drinks one cup of coffee you use it as an excuse that is why my remedy has not acted.
No! One coffee will NOT antidote the remedy.
You know I had a center with 30 medical doctors working in Athens and one time I heard one of the doctor,
a woman, shouting I could hear her outside the consulting room, there were about 10 consulting rooms,
as I passing on the corridor going from one to the other I heard her shouting to the patient you are stupid!
What happened? He drank one coffee and it stopped the action of the remedy!
I said to her to come here and tell me what is the remedy, why you gave this remedy.
This is incorrect remedy.
There is no reason for giving that remedy, no justification.
But she was making such noise that the patient was totally terrified.
– About clear picture I hope it’s not a rude question.
– I can take a lot of rude questions without problem.
– If the organism is wise enough to produce the symptoms and he gives us picture according to my understanding
always the organism gives a clear picture but maybe I don’t know enough the M.M. and I say it’s not a clear picture.
How can I know that the picture is not clear or that I don’t know the clear remedy?
– That’s not a rude question.
That’s a clever question! Nobody knows the answer to this question.
The question cannot be answered because should be in conjunction with the experience of the homeopath.
The more the experience is the clearer the picture is.
But not all cases have a clear picture.
Still, there are pictures never mind how much experience you may have you may still not be able to see the picture.
But it is in conjunction with the experience and the knowledge of the homeopath that can see a clear picture now in this case
while an inexperienced person cannot see it.
Many times due to my experience I can see the picture more clearly than a student.
– I want to ask something for the diagram.
What if wrongly you don’t pick up the symptoms of the first layer but you see the second layer, the second remedy and give it?
– She always puts clever questions and brings me into a bad state of not knowing what to answer.
You can give your own self, stimulate the second layer that means you increase the symptoms of the second layer
because there is an aggravation.
What is the person going to feel? He is going to feel a kind of confusion more than he had before.
You hit by chance the second layer then the person feels more confused.
Wait and things will settle down because it is like a proving.
You wait long enough and the symptoms of the provings will go away.
If you give one dose of one potency in a person and you create proving symptoms don’t worry they will go away.
But if you give one dose of a potency and the person feels good as far as his own symptoms are concerned and he has more energy
and joy but at the same time there are some keynote symptoms of the remedy appearing which he did not have before
that means the remedy was correct and this is a seal that the remedy was very close, similar remedy.
It created in the person who had such similarity with that substance a few of its own symptoms that we know as produced in its provings.
It’s a confirmation that the remedy was correct.
At one time when new symptoms are created and no curative effect then we have a proving the other time the remedy has done quite good
but created some symptoms. That’s good.
– I wanted to ask a question about things you told before.
If I understood well, 15 minutes ago you
said if you prescribe wrongly in the
beginning when things clarify after a while
the first layer will be even clearer.
And now 2 mins ago I understood that it will actually be a confusion if you prescribe the second layer.
So , wrongly again. So will you please clarify this issue?
– This is different. When you prescribe a remedy which is close to the uppermost layer will modify it and make it clearer.
If by chance you hit an underlying layer it cannot come up to the fore, cannot get out, and therefore changes the symptoms
but not in a curative manner.
A lot of times the cases which I receive here are cases in which the remedy has been given before but did not act
and then I give a remedy first and the second remedy is a remedy which has been taken by the patient before.
What’s here remedy? Caust.
Take a dose of Caust.! If by chance you strike the underlying layer you will have more disturbance.
If you strike a close enough remedy to the uppermost, will modify it but still the organism will push it towards the right direction.
Many times people have come and they have taken Calc.
And yet I treat here and take Alum., Sulph. and then comes the time for Calc.
But they have taken Calc., no effect. Now Calc. came to the uppermost. Beautiful effect.
Thank you! Bye!