So, you're 41 and you had developed a tumor 3 by 3 in the left side of the skull,
in the base of the skull. What kind of tumor?
- In medicine they say schwannoma , it is not a bad type of tumor.
- Benign tumor of nerves sheath by several neurosurgeons,
they recommend us urgent surgery, 5 months before.
- When did they discover this? November 2011
- Accidentally, by chance.
- Why did you go?
- I had a pain on my neck.
- Both sides.
- Yes.
While I was sleeping I had a neck pain, therefore went to hospital because my wife is a doctor,
to one of her friends she is a surgeon, brain surgery, she's our friend,
she said "Ok, go make an MRI". She suggested to take MRI,
she said while you are here let's have a full scan of your brain as well.
- Did you find any hernia?
- Yes, I put it under 3. Number 3 is the hernia.
- Cervical hernia, most probably the pain was from hernia.
- They said exactly the same thing. This is from the hernia.
This kind of tumors, did not make any pain.
Fortunately there is no any effect because this tumor, we have been told,
this is touching the nerves of hearing and nerves of talking, speech.
We've asked what is the risk if we make an operation.
They said if we make the operation there is a chance of 20% I might lose one of my ears
or I might lose some vocabulary, my speech might be changed.
There is also risk of facial paralysis. Because it is on the left side,
there is a risk for the hearing on the left side, speech on the left side,
also facial paralysis on the left side.
Then we started to look for different solutions
because also my wife was taking some lessons of Homeopathy.
We said ok we will not make an operation, we will try different solutions,
if there is no solution after 1-2 years, if we have to make an operation we will make the operation.
Because as of today this was found out 5 months before, in 5 months we don't see any effects,
we are not losing any hearing, we are not losing any speech
and there is no effect and what we have done 5 months before we had this MRI,
one month before we took another MRI, we made the comparison between the 2 MRIs.
This tumor became 1mm smaller than it was. It became smaller.
We don't know if there is a difference because of the machines.
- There was a very small difference, but still there is no growth.
- Exactly. There is no growth in 5 months. This is out luck, let's say.
The second good news is there are no symptoms, no signs.
- So gastroenterology; burning sensation in stomach and esophagus since 2005, why is that?
- I assume it is because I was too much under stress, I'm very nervous.
- Are you a businessman?
-Yes.
- You started your business during that time?
-No, I started it in 2002.
But 2004 and 2003 was like difficult years.
There was too much concern, there was too much risk in the business...
I'm thinking these are the reasons.
- That's right, correct. And since then you are taking regularly medicine, every morning.
One anti-acid?
-No, pump inhibitors, for protection.
- 2 pump inhibitors
- Lowers acidity.
- You have to take it every morning with empty stomach,
before you eat you have to wait half an hour at least and the food is not affecting.
- And you don't have side effects from this, you don't feel any discomfort,
any other symptoms?
-Not much.
What we have tried, every 3-4 months we are changing the medicine
because there are like 3-4 different kind of medicines.
If there are side effects we are changing it
because I have been told especially for the one I am taking right now, may effect erection.
The doctor told you might have less erection in your sexuality if you use it regularly.
Therefore I'm changing it but I didn't see any side effects.
- Does this contain any kind of hormone?
-No hormones.
- It's the first time I hear about that medicine, I don't know what it is.
- It stopped acid production of stomach.
-That's quite strong medication.
-Yes. What I'm using is Nexium now.
I ask if she had one with her to show you what is inside.
- These are quite deep remedies, not simple.
Because you could manage with a little bit of soda water, it would be the same and very simple.
That is quite strong medication.
If it manages to suppress the production of acidity of the stomach
that means it acts very deeply in the organism and you will have some side effects
maybe you don't realize, maybe you don't feel less energetic.
- I feel less energetic, this is true.
- And seems when you have this pain here in the neck, since how many years?
- Since November 2011.
- It's not 5 months it's 7 months.
- But in the end of November, 20th November. 6 months total.
20th November exactly, we went to the doctor for MRI.
This is the day we learned we got the tumor therefore I remember the day exactly.
- And then pain in the root of the neck, both sides, there are two trigger points.
One is the left and the other is the right side of the neck.
Why you call them trigger point?
- Because if I press here it's something like walnut or hazelnut.
If you press here, I'm feeling the pain starting here and it goes here, it goes up,
deep inside, it goes like this.
If I press this one the same  from this side starting from the back side of the neck
goes inside deep in skull like this. If I'm nervous, stressed or angry the pain starts itself.
- Do you feel tired?
- I don't know.
- Aggravated by stress, anger, in some positions, during lying.
Pain can wake up through the night. And what do you have to do?
Do you have to move your neck and crack it?
- What I do to have less pain, I'm making massage to both sides with analgesic gels.
- What kind of analgesic? Mesulid?
- Voltaren , I'm massaging from this side to this side... for 20 minutes
and then it is less and I can sleep.
And while I am sleeping, one pillow is not enough this is new
because of this I have to put the pillow double
- You want your head to be high?
- Right, for comfort.
I used to sleep with one pillow but of this pain now I'm making double pillow.
And I'm putting sometimes my hand under the pillow so it gives height...
- So, you sleep quietly or you turn a lot?
- Turn a lot.
- But you don't keep one position when you want to sleep you always lie on right side, abdomen...
- I lie in the right side and knees inside. This is the starting point of the sleep.
- But then you turn during the sleep.
- Always starts like that. Behind, always.
- And also something between legs a pillow maybe.
- Touching your genitals?
-No, just between two knees if she's with me I'm taking her leg, if not I'm taking a pillow.
I don't like my knees touching each other. It's kind of reflex, I put something, a pillow...
- For ventilation?
- I just don't want two  knees to bump, touch each other, if no pillow I put her leg. No pain.
- Just the idea bones are touching. I just get used to it.
- How did you get the first idea.
- I have no idea, since I was a child.
- And you have also allergic rhinitis.
- This has started last year, first time.
It started itching my ears, inside of the nose, throat.
Like feeling of itching in the throat. Ears.
- Only the right ear?
-No, both ears itching, and here both sides itching and inside of the nose itching.
I am starting series of sneezing.
2-4 and after 40 minutes it comes again and then through the night I am also coughing.
Dry cough. But nothing comes. During the night there is a liquid coming from here to my mouth
and in the morning I have to go to the bathroom and take this liquid out.
This is generally more or less still the liquid which normally we have in the nose.
This is like goes from here to up. Last year a friend of us and my wife
because she was taking homeopathy lessons, they were working together in the hospital,
they are both doctors, they gave me a remedy.
- What remedy?
- Arsenicum, and the day after it stops.
- No, they gave me 3 Arsenicum. One of them was 200CH, the other ones 30, 30.
The first day when I took 200CH, I felt dizzy, I thought I am dying because it was too much,
I was really dizzy. This was Friday.
Saturday I took another 30CH, stomach was slowed down, the feeling was 80% bad,
the next day it became 40%.
Saturday I was still dizzy, didn't want to go out because I was dizzy.
Sunday I took another one, the last 30CH, and the stomach was ok and the sneezing
and the liquidity everything was cut immediately.
Monday when I was going to the job there was nothing.
It stopped this year 20th April, one month ago it started again.
We were thinking of taking Arsenicum again but we said because we are coming here,
we didn't take anything.
Because our friend, she is an homeopath, but she's a learning homeopath.
But last year it cut immediately.
- The only homeopathic remedy is Arsenicum? No other remedy?
- No, just Arsenicum.
- It was what she gave to me. Only Arsenicum. One 200CH and two 30,30.
- You are the only child? You have brothers or sisters?
-No, I'm the only child.
- Your parents, they are alive?
- Yes, they are here in the island.
They are drinking greek coffee somewhere in the Patitiri.
-But they are healthy?
- My father has a stomach problem.
- Duodenal ulcer, stomach ulcer?
- We don't know.
Two years before he got a bleeding in the stomach and they took him to the hospital,
they operated him...
- You have bled sometimes from the stomach?
-No, never.
3 years before I went to a doctor and they made endoscopy.
They look inside the film of this thing and they find several red points,
but small points which were hurt, they say ulcer.
There was an erosion in the surface of the stomach, they were like 7-8 small points
and they found second thing that the stomach changed it shape.
They said this is a hernia of stomach and the third thing they said in the esophagus
it becomes loose because the acid pushes this up...
- Did they speak about Barrett syndrome?
- No.
- You know Barrett syndrome?
- Yes, but no.
- One year later, I went to the same doctor and I did the same endoscopy again.
He said more or less nothing changed...
It was more or less the same number because I was taking the same medicine, one year time.
It feels good during the day.
You don't have a burn, you don't have a mass coming out, but it is not healing you.
Because I took endoscopy 3 times, every year one endoscopy and it doesn't heal,
it doesn't go worse, at least I can eat because if I am not taking medicine
I cannot eat hot, spicy things, sour things, I cannot eat chocolate, coffee,
I can't eat almost nothing.
Acid things, hot things I cannot eat, drink. If I take the medicine I can eat anything.
Cold milk and yoghurt is releasing pain in the stomach.
For example I forgot to take the medicine today,
I went and eat during the night 6-8 o'clock, it started to burn.
I am taking one glass of cold milk, it releases.
If I cannot find cold milk I am having yoghurt like 4-5 spoons of cold yoghurt it releases.
When I eat milk ice cream it releases.
- You like ice cream?
- Yes, I like ice cream.
- But excessive desire for ice cream?
- When I was a child I was eating a lot. But not lately.
- When you were a child, did you ever have nose bleeding? Your nose opened suddenly, bled.
- No. It was broken twice
- But not spontaneously.
- No. I had some friend that had it, not me.
I know what you mean.
- In general you are affected by weather?
If the weather is cold, you like it, or it's hot, you don't like it...
- To be honest I live in different part of the world.
I live in Turkey, I live in London, Austria like Vienna, I live in Australia Sydney,
therefore I've lived in different conditions
- Because of your job?
- Yes because of my father's job and my job I have to travel.
I live like 2 years in London, 2 years in Australia, 6 years in Vienna.
Vienna is very different than Istanbul. Istanbul is very different than London
but I don't like too much grey weather, raining weather.
If it is grey and raining it is boring.
- But are you bothered by hot weather?
- Not really.
- By cold?
I can tolerate because my father was a soldier, a military officer,
therefore when I was a child we lived aged from 2 to 4 in the Russian borders.
It was -40C. Then we went to the greek borders it was average like 30C.
Then we moved to Antalya, the south of Turkey which was 40-50C. I get used easily.
-40 C in Kursk +40C in Antalya.
-Do you like sweets?
- Yes I like sweets.
- Eggs
- Yes.
- A lot?
- Sweet a lot. I like omelet, bacon omelet.
I can eat every day in the breakfast eggs without any problem.
- Actually, you eat every day 2 eggs in the morning?
- We are trying not to eat much. But I can eat one egg every day.
But sweet every day. In the lunch time I can eat a profiterole,
I can eat a chocolate cake, in the night I can eat another one.
I always like sweets. I also like salt, very much.
I like salty things. I always put extra salt.
- Before tasting your food...
- I always put salt.
I like salt, I like sweets. The salt that I am using for most of the people is too much.
They say I am going to get blind because people believe salt makes you blind.
- You have a nice character. Very communicative.
- I'm very communicative.
- And you want to cure what? The hernia, the stomach or this?
-All of them! The first thing which is disturbing my life right now is hernia.
This is giving pain to me, that is what makes me up at 4 0'clock in the morning.
The second thing, it's like 6 months before I was really scared about this thing
because I've been in several doctors in Turkey they wanted to operate, but 3 months later
because I took the second MRI we saw it was not getting bigger,
it was getting less but the stomach is there since 6-7 years.
In the future I believe I will have an effect because of the medicine,
therefore this will need to be fixed as well.
- The hernia was in 2011.
- Yes, we recognized it in 2011.
-When the pain started?
- 6 months ago.
- How did I know it was 6 months ago?
- Because I just told you!
- No, I meant something else. On 2011 you discovered you had hernia. But the pain..
- 2 weeks before, maybe 1 month ago.
-Now the allergic rhinitis... when it started?
- Last year April.
But it was just one month.
- Last year April, that was the first time.
- First time in my life, in my 40s.
- Now the medicine for the stomach, when did you started it?
- I started 2005-2006. But I got 3 different medicines, they are similar,
but because I am afraid of side effects I was changing them.
- The first remedy you started for the stomach was the same age to the pump inhibitor?
Or you started with the anti-acid?
- Yes, same medicine.
- I'll tell you know a secret.
The problem of hernia and also most probably of the tumor is because of this remedy.
Of the stomach because it suppresses the acidity of the stomach.
- Ok, it might be.
- Maybe it's not so simple. You see, now in order to...
- In order to fix one thing, you have to fix many things
- Yes...you have to stop taking the anti-acid remedy.
- Ok, if I have to I have to! I have to change my eating style.
- Eating habits.
For a time because if the remedy is correct, it will heal the problem with the stomach.
- Perfect.
- Your problem, what you have in the stomach is quite serious. And this is the most serious
because it tends to become what is called in medicine Barrett syndrome
which means that the cells start being differentiated
that means they may become eventually unhealthy. So this is the secret.
Now I have to ask you something else.
You feel happy?
- Yes.
- You feel as happy as before 2000 or less happy? Now you are 40, when you were 30...
When did you marry?
- Two years ago.
- You have children?
- No.
- You don't want?
- Maybe next year.
It's a plan. First, we don't have children because she has a fear of having a child.
This is her case. In her case you will find out why we don't have children.
- Ok, that means you take precautions.
-Yes.
Her position is quite serious. This is also making me precautious.
When I was 30 I had financial problems, right now I don't have at all financial problems
but I have different problems.
- No drugs, no cigarettes, social drinker, had rubella, smallpox, father
and uncle has similar stomach problems. Your stomach is the worst,
the weak point in your organism. And because of ancestors,
as well... they have the same problem. Now I want to ask you something else.
If you are in a high place, and you look down, do you have a problem?
- Not much. Because for example she has a big problem.
I can sit in the balcony on the 6th floor and I won't have any problem.
- If you look down?
- If you look down... it looks high!
Not a fear, but I can think for example if there is an earthquake
this is too high I can't jump,
if there is an earthquake maybe it is advantage to be in the balcony,
everything is collapsed, you can walk out, this is what I was thinking
but I think also if these things are not strong in the balcony, the protectors,
therefore I'm not touching them too much, if I touch and break I can fall down.
This makes me nervous. If I had to make it from one to ten, my heroism is 2 or 3.
- Is it sometimes that you look and you imagine it would be terrible
if I would fall from this height...
- You die.
- In the meantime you live this falling?
-No. I have not this kind of fear.
- When you have to go through a bridge and there is water...
-No problem. Because I used to drive every day the Bosporus bridge Asia to Europe,
I don't recognize this is a bridge. It is your daily life.
But she got a fear, I don't have it. I know the differences.
- Are you able to speak to strangers?
- Yes.
- Very easily.
- Do you perspire at all?
- Not much, but we recognize because we were driving from Istanbul to here,
8 hours, driving 2 hours I recognized that that my back was sweated.
But I am too much a sweating person, I am not a water drinker.  I don't drink water.
- That means you don't like the water.
- Probably.
- You don't need it. But do you drink tea, or drink coffee?
- Every day in the morning I drink one or two teas between 9 and 10.
And around 11 I drink one café latte Arabia, not Turkish coffee, nescafe.
- But if you do homeopathy you stop coffee.
- Yes, I know. I can stop coffee. It is not a big thing. I can drink tea.
And I am drinking juice. Apple juice, orange juice, all juices I like.
I can't drink water, I can drink like one third of the glass...
- Why?
- No I don't like to drink water.
If I am thirsty for example I go open the refrigerator, take the apple juice,
mix with the soda and drink this glass non-stop.
Apple soda I can drink. Cold milk I can drink. But water; one third of the glass.
Then I have to push myself to drink a lot again.
- But, except in the morning, do you drink other drinks during the day?
- Not much.
- But how much? Can you tell me?
- Maybe a whole day from 9.00 to 21.00 I drink total 3-4 cups of tea but small glasses,
2 cups of coffee and one glass of water. Lately, the last 6 months
I am pushing myself to drink water.
For example I drink 1 liter of water one the table just to drink, I push myself,
I finish half of it. Because now I am drinking alkali water...
We have a special machine at home which produces alkali water.
I bring in the office but I still don't drink it.
- Did you have an acute like influenza or anything with fever?
- When I was 11 I had a meningitis. I stayed 21 days, 3 weeks in the hospital,
it was like 3 weeks long treatment, they took water from the spine to start treatment.
Every day I was having 3 needles, injections, I remember this
and after three weeks she said it was in a very early stage,
when we started the treatment, therefore I was lucky I survived
because if I was one week late probably  I would have to live with side effects.
- Since that time you never had a high fever again? While you were married?
-No.
- Never?
- No, for 2 years.
- 3-4 years ago?
- No.
- Fever?
Maybe I got really one influenza last 5 years, maybe once I got influenza.
One day I was really hot but I took some strong medicine I took Augmentin,
I started Augmentin like 1000, for one week time, I didn't let it to get up,
I felt I was going to get it and I started early and it stopped the fever.
- So the last thing, the skin reactions; The upper part of the body around chest,
area reddish, patchy areas after exhaustion.
- If I take a hot or warm shower after the shower it is here like patches and also exhaustion.
After the sex basically I get...
-Altogether with the patches comes the exhaustion?
- No, after the shower and after exertion. After the sex I am getting patches.
- And you have condylomata/ warts at the surface of the penis.
- Yes, maybe 25 years. I had it since 25 years, maybe 30 years.
- Maybe 30 years and you are 40...
- I don't know, I might had it after the first sex...  I might have it after the circumcision.
- At the age of nine you had the circumcision. And became a man...
- It's the culture. I don't know because I thought those small things,
I thought it was because of this cut.
Because they are cutting the skin goes up,
and at the side of the skin there are these small things.
I thought this is because of this. Because I remembered this... long time... I don't know.
Five or six are still there. They don't bother, no painful.
As a number they don't increase, they don't decrease. They don't go big, they don't go small.
They are always there. We are trying to think everything that is on the body.
- Yes, you gave a good case.
-Hopefully! Good but difficult.
- Your pathology is not easy. It appears to be difficulties. I want to ask something more.
When you were younger you would do dangerous things?
For instance, would you think what would happened
if you put a kind of a steel in the plug, in the electricity, try to put...
- Not this but I used to drive very fast cars.
I took like parachute jumping from the plane, diving like 40m, extreme sports...
I think I will not die. If I die it will be fast, I don't feel nothing,
therefore I don't bother this kind of risky things, I would not calculate the results,
I would just go and do it. I did bungee jumping in a Greek island.
- You were not afraid in the beginning?
- In the beginning I was thinking I was afraid but then I said let's do it.
- I want to overcome it...
- Not like this.
I just didn't think of the results. If you think the result you wouldn't do it.
I was so stupid not to think the result.
You don't think because you are like 18,16... everybody does it.
- Do you sleep well? That means from the moment you fall asleep you wake
or do you have problems...?
-No.
If I sleep like 11 o'clock in the night I might wake up like 2 or 3 o'clock.
- With pain in the stomach?
- No pain in the stomach.
Either two things; if it hurts on my neck or my mind is busy.
This wakes me up.
Let's say tomorrow is Monday, I have things to do in the job like A,B,C,D I think at night,
I should not forget this, in 3 o'clock in the morning I am getting up and I am checking,
if there are things in my mind like brain checking... I am doing this.
Work is still important therefore anything that happens to work makes me nervous.
- Do you have any fears?
- Like certain things, health conditions make me nervous. Not a fear but makes me nervous.
Also, losing a job makes me nervous.
These two things; health condition, it's in my life for 2 years,
I'm thinking of what will happen, when we solve it, when we solve it, it makes me nervous,
I am thinking of it, the second thing I am thinking about generally is the job.
If something happens to my parents then I am thinking of my parents.
My father has a stomach problem. I think about my mother also. These two things make me concern.
- Are you afraid of the dark?
-No I am not afraid.
- Thunderstorms?
-No.
- The ice cream you like it because it is cold or because it is sweet?
- Both. But generally because it is sweet. In winter I don't eat ice cream,
I eat ice cream in the summer.
- You want to say more? Something we didn't ask you about?
- Not really... I think this is all.
One thing... during the day I feel tired after the lunch between 14.00...
- Suddenly you feel tired?
- No suddenly, but the energy level goes down.
-What time?
- After lunch.
- 13.00, 14.00?
- Exactly and if I have half a night sleep, or like we say... a nap.
This between 13.00 or 14.00, after the lunch and it goes down.
It also happens after the dinner, if I have a dinner like 18.00 or 19.00,
after eating the energy goes down and I feel like sleepy.
But I can sleep 20minutes, half an hour, it's like recharging battery.
One more thing... I cannot sleep if there is a light in the room.
I close curtains, doors and windows and it is nearly 95% dark, then I can sleep.
If the windows have no curtains, if the daylight comes like 4.00 or 5.00 in the morning,
I wake up. If I am not drunk I cannot sleep during the daylight.
Or if I am very tired.
- You drink every day?
- I don't.
Previously, when I was a student I was drinking three times a week.
Mainly I was drinking vodka, this was 2 or 3 years of my life.
And generally I am just drinking in the weekend.
Last 2-3 years I am drinking maybe once in a month.
-Have studied anything? Or you went to business from...?
- I studied economics. I worked and studied economy in Vienna.
This was also a tough time because , this was a stressing time of my life
because in 1992 the Turkish lira had a devaluation
because the economy has gone bankrupt  then I was studying in Vienna in the age of 20,
I got a phone call from my father he said devaluation hit Turkey
and he was sending me money he was sending like 1000 dollars
but after this time I will not send you I cannot send you 1000 dollars
because Turkish lira has crushed down, you either come back to Turkey or you work and study.
And then I started looking for a job, I found a job
and the rest of the 4 years I was living in Vienna I worked and I studied.
And when I was working, most of the times I was working at night,
I started working at a bar, I was working from 17.00 in the night
till 5.00 in the morning in the bar. Whole night. Then I came back home in the daylight.
Therefore I had to close the curtains so that I could sleep.
This was like 2 years of my life working and studying. I was doing night shifts a lot.
-But still during that time no problem with the stomach, yet.
- Very little.
- Some burning?
- Some burning.
But I was not taking regularly medicine.
If I had a burn, I was just taking maybe once in a week, anti-acid, after the lunch.
But very little. Maybe once in two weeks.
- But the problem that appeared during 2004 was a serious problem for you?
- Yes. Because this time I could not eat.
The time I ate everything was burning and come out in my mouth.
- I mean the problem you had with the job...
- Yes I was in Australia there was a problem.
- How big?
- I could lose the job and I could have gone back to Turkey.
It was a serious the job and the economic problem all combined together.
This was a highly stressing time.
But as I am looking now, during all my life, in the university in Vienna,
I was really stressed, because I went to Vienna in the age of 18, my parents were in Turkey,
that 6 years I was alone in Vienna, 2 years were fine
but after 4 years the stress level was up
because if you lose the job you cannot finish the study,
if you cannot finish the study, you are going back to Turkey, it's a big stress,
I am the only son, it's not a good thing. Then I came to Turkey, 2 years it was ok.
Then I went to London, I took a job in London it was an international job
but I was the youngest in the team. There was too much stress as well.
I was the Turkish man in the U.K. company.
Therefore everybody was watching, 2 years of stress there, as well.
What I am thinking stomach thing is like developing. It's like the last drop in the glass.
It's started maybe from the age of 20 and it's developed...
And in between, two years in Turkey it was fine, then a got again abroad, it started again.
Some time after 10 years , in 2004 it reacted but I think it is in the backyard,
maybe it has not started in 2005 but in the year of 2000.
This I think back my life... this is what I am thinking. Because I left Trkey at the age of 17 1/2.
Quite young, going abroad to study 2 years later, your country bankrupt,
you need to work and study, small stresses but there are some stresses.
-Ok, we'll try to help you.
If you take a case properly, you will always learn from each of you cases.
And you will be amazed after some years if you follow strictly the idea
of trying to find the correct remedy.
You will surprised how much you know about the organism of the people
who are in front of you. So, is he a nice man? Yes. Pure heart. Open.
No secrets behind, no mental aberration.
But the whole force of the disease is in his physical body.
So maybe you do not agree that it is because of the suppression of the acidity of the stomach
that he has such serious problems which are hernia and also the tumor.
But for me is very clear. This is what has happened.
You will ask anybody who takes that medication
and he has heartburn is he going to develop such severe problems?
The answer is no. Not everybody. But what is the difference?
Why somebody will have burning in the stomach, a kind of gastritis and uses this medication
and will not have these severe side effects and why this man has this severe side effects?
Because... hereditacly. The heredity shows that his weak point, weak organ is the stomach.
This is the organ that will break down under stress.
How far can go? Maybe you don't know this disease; Barrett syndrome.
Who knows Barrett? Only 2,3... Very strange.
It is a kind of inflammation of the inner lining of the stomach
especially the upper part which is connected with the esophagus and creates ulcers
which they have the tendency to become malignant.
For this boy who is very nice physical body has a weakness in the stomach which is severe.
If he's left like this he will develop cancer in the stomach.
In how many years.. maybe 12 years, I don't know something like that.
But will develop cancer, eventually. So therefore we have to know what we treat.
Otherwise I believe every doctor who is trained in a medical school he will be confused
with all this picture. He will not know what's going on really.
One is looking only on the tumor, the other is looking in the stomach,
the other is looking on the ORL. See a piece of the picture.
And we look on the whole picture and also when we treat we treat the whole picture.
When you give a remedy, the remedy in order to be correct has to cover the whole picture.
I will show you something and I will explain afterwards.
I want to you to show them the Arsenicum... in the repertory...
You see, if you go to the repertory you see his symptom,
he says if I drink milk the pain is gone.
What are the remedies? Can you see the remedy? Ars, asar and graph.
And the second you are looking in the beginning...
Sweet milk. Pain with sweet milk amel. also yoghurt... yes kind of...
So you remember what he said when he took Ars?
When he took Ars the pains were gone for a certain period of time.
This is what we say it is a partial action of a remedy.
Because you take a portion of the case, you don't realize is he an Ars case? Not really.
The patient doesn't look like Ars at all. If you look in the repertory
and you prescribe this remedy this remedy will take away the symptom not the disease.
That's why the disease is the same, they checked it several times.
If the remedy was correct the stomach condition would be much better if not cured.
- Just to make sure, when he got Ars 200CH, 30CH, 30CH it was for rhinitis
or for the stomach pain? Maybe I didn't listen carefully but I thought it was for rhinitis.
-The pain in the stomach and the allergy. Both.
Not the rhinitis, a discharge from the nose,
what he was describing was a postnasal discharge that was coming he had to spit it out.
That discharge was cut off , stopped. Plus the pain for a period of time stopped.
That is partial action of the remedy. The fact that the discharge is gone is not a good idea.
If the rest of the symptoms remain. That means that the outlet the organism has, stops.
Therefore the remedy is acting partially because indicated partially.
- It's suppressive.
- You can say it, it's suppressive.
The origin of the problem is the stomach. This is what we have to see improving with the remedy.
If we improve certain peripheral symptoms and the basic problem remains
that means we have not done a good job. Austria, do you agree? Yes, ok.
Therefore the remedy is not Ars. The Ars has quite a lot of his symptoms.
What is the remedy?
First of all before we go to the remedy according to the theory of the levels of health,
in which level you will more or less place this man? That would be a good test.
Do you have a piece of paper and write for me the level which you think is this man.
Just a number 1-12. Has everybody written down his own idea?
It doesn't matter if I collect. I saw more or less.
Has everybody written down? You are checking yourself, I am not checking you.
The pathology is chronic pathology.
Quite severe, not very severe, not malignancy, not absolutely life or death. One.
The second is does his organism have the possibility of developing fever? No.
From 11 years old when he got the series of injections he never had fever again.
This fact should put him under level 6. Because in level 6 we have frequent acutes.
Level 6 are frequent. Level 5 are not so frequent.
Level 4 yes, Level 3 is a quite good state of health.
With one acute every year, every second year at the most.
But can you say this man is very healthy and therefore he has no acutes? No.
Therefore the level which is correct to place him is level 7.
Now I want to know who has written down 7. Excellent, very good.
The average is quite good, that means you have perceived the logic behind it.
Therefore your treatment, if it is successful has to give what...
the possibility of the organism to develop fever again.
He has stopped having fevers due to meningitis.
The question will be if you treat this case can the meningitis come back?
Because we say that old symptoms are coming back.
You are tired, eh...? But can talk up to 12.00.
How old are you?
-30.
- He's 35.
- No. 44...
You asked if the meningitis can come back. The answer is no.
- The answer is no. Why?
- Because the organism will protect the most important organ
and the head is the most important physical organ and will not allow an aggravation there.
- This is a problem. I'll tell you what is my problem.
That once the possibility of the organism was taken away for developing fever,
the immune system is suppressed quite a lot,
that means something will come back if the treatment goes as deep as that level.
Will the meningitis which is an infection actually come back? This is doubtful.
What may come back is some headaches which may develop in the course of the treatment
reminding the headaches of the meningitis in the end.
They accuse us for giving remedies and it's a placebo.
They don't know that we have signs which guide us
whether the remedy was a placebo was a placebo effect or the remedy did a job.
Because a placebo would never follow this course, first the aggravation
then the amelioration then the pain in the neck will go back
because the last pain in the neck will be one of the first to go away.
The organisms starts going back.
And by the time the organism reaches at the age when he was 2005
he may have a partial aggravation of the stomach problem
and eventually if the correct remedy correct potency then maybe by repeating the remedy,
we don't know yet, may reach the point where he was 11 years old. What that means?
It means that we can bring an organism back to the state of the organism
when the organism was 11 years old.
That means we nullified all the damage done to this organism all these years.
And we renew the organism.
And give him the possibility to live many more years, naturally and in a very natural way.
Not pumping the organism with chemicals and trying to control his mental state,
his stomach state and whatever and one organ breaking after another.
See the big difference between homeopathy and allopathic approach.
What is the remedy we did not say, eh?
You would like to write down the remedy that you thought.
Write it down don't cut the piece of paper.
Some of you, you may write I don't know. What is the remedy? Do you have a computer?
Who has a computer system? What is your remedy...? No success this time.
Show me the symptoms on which you based the prescription.
Because I wrote down the remedy and at a certain moment she came to see what is the remedy
and then I looked at the computer.
Nose, coryza, discharge, postnasal discharge, paroxysmal sneezing, throat itching,
burning in esophagus, acidity of the stomach, pain-milk-amel.,
pain-burning, thirstless, condylomata. I don't believe that condylomata is condylomata.
It's just some cheloid. It's a kind of cheloid, it's not really condylomata.
It's totally different evaluation. It doesn't matter. Put everything salt desire, sweets desire.
And if you ask to solve this. You see the remedy is Arg-n. You did not find the remedy.
Who found the remedy? Oh my god...
- You were asking the keynotes...
-You are clever. By inference, not by knowledge you got it. Because I was asking keynotes.
Now I will tell you something else but you have to realize.
I was asking keynotes mental keynotes of Arg-n. He denied them.
Just because he denied the mental symptoms it does not mean the remedy is not Arg-n
it means that on the mental level he is well, he is healthy.
Mental, emotional level has not been touched.
You see the difference between the a person
who has not been touched in the mental emotional level how open and full of love and energy is he.
We have become ah.
With all these kind of anxieties, depressions and all these kinds of things.
And you see he is so open. But also the openness we have described it in the Arg-n case.
Has anybody taken  the e-learning? Who is taking the e-learning?
Go back and see the description of the arg-n
and you will see how much it fits with the openness of this person.
Feels very open and very easy to communicate and even to ask a stranger about a matter
which concerns him.
So therefore the pathology is fitting on this remedy but he is quite healthy
on a mental emotional level and therefore you cannot get the keynotes I was searching.
Because if the keynotes where positive when I was asking I would come to the class
and everybody would say Arg-n. Fear from high place.
I brought into homeopathy the idea of essences.
And I gave a description of the picture of the mental emotional states of the remedies.
As a result before I was back in Greece the whole world was prescribing on essences
and prescribing only on essences. George said you prescribe only on essences.
That was a misunderstanding. I gave some information.
A little bit more information than what was in the book.
But I never said that you prescribe only on mental/emotional symptoms.
You prescribe on the totality of the symptoms always as much as possible.
But see here now something very strange.
The computer says and I say also before the computer Arg-n. Now I will show you something.
Out of 17 symptoms, Arg-n covers 7. Go to the next remedy.
It says that the next possibility is Phos. Out of 16 Phosphorus covers 13.
And yet I say no Phos. Arg-n.
And the systems follows of course my thinking because I have programmed it
to think the way it think.
Go further. Show something else. Next remedy, Nat-m.
See 10 symptoms even Nat-m has more symptoms than Arg-n. No way. Nat-m is totally out.
Go further, Med. 7 equal. Why? Because if you take out condylomata Med will disappear.
You see why it is difficult even for an expert even for somebody
who really knows quite good homeopathy it is difficult to come down to the right remedy
unless you have a global information. This is the main thing.
You have to know the Materia Medica, as well. It's not enough, this is a tool.
The best possible according to my understanding. But it's not everything.
That means if you don't know anything, you put the symptoms, sometimes you hit it
but you have to know really what are you doing.
So how much you learn... they gave a remedy already which fitted some partial symptoms
and the remedy acted by closing down the symptoms not the disease.
- In theory this is in C group level 7, so we need more than 1 remedy.
In that case by your teaching I understand you're seeing layers.
Do you see more than 1 layer now?
- Yes.
-That's a part I cannot understand yet.
The layers, the graphic, I understand everything but I don't understand in front of the patient...
-To see the next remedy.
- Yes.
- You're asking too much. Argentum nitricum will do quite a lot for his stomach.
You may not believe I will ask him not to take any anti-acids and within a week
he will be able to eat without anti-acids.
But still the organism will come back with a force because underneath there is another remedy.
Which is the remedy I am not able to perceive at this moment.
I have to see the reaction and judge. Sometimes I may see most probably this is coming next.
In this case I cannot say because I do not have information about the underlying layer.
But we will see. And in any case the proof that his health has improved
and jumped to the next level will be the manifestation of fever. An acute with fever.
The moment that you see the acute with the fever you are very sure that the remedy has acted
but you should not touch this fever with antibiotics.
With homeopathic yes, because he will have a big reaction.
I don't know if it will be like meningitis but will be a big reaction with high fever,
with severe pain in the head during the fever. This kind of thing.
Maybe Belladonna type, I cannot predict. I took your time.
- I don't understand well while you choose arg-n more than phos.
Because they are too open and... why did you choose arg-n?
- Because for Phos there were contraindicated symptoms.
Phos needs water and he has the opposite.
He does not need water. Phos also needs very cold water. He never said that.
Phos as a child at least should nose bleedings. He denied.
Phos should have some kind anxiety if there is total darkness. They don't like it.
So there are a lot of opposite symptoms for Phos though the openness yes it is correct.
Looks like Phos.
- He said after short sleep he is refreshed. That's Phos as well.
- Yes, but catnap sleep , not the main sleep. Phos is very refreshed after the main sleep.
In the catnap, not usual. But maybe, yes, you may see.
- I perceive this patient chilly, in general.
Interms of the history he has problems with wet weather and in the change of weather
he always used to find some problems. To me it's a chilly patient.
This supports again Phos..., along with the openness, along with the sweet and salt,
it is a combination of Phos.
- You don't to tell me. Here it says, how many Phos, Phos has 13 symptoms out of...
but it's wrong.
What can we do? First of all he is not chilly. He can tolerate heat and cold.
He said, if it is very cold, no problem if it is very hot no problem.
So you cannot consider him chilly. Ars especially or Phos is very chilly.
- He has a family history of stomach problems.
But in his lifestyle he didn't have much of alcohol or drug abuse.
Did you consider his anxiety levels during his younger age when he had to work as well as study,
as one of the possible direction why chose arg-n over the other symptoms of arg-n?
- No. The moment that he says I want total darkness, the moment he says I don't like water
already the mind should go away from Phos.
And the Phos anxiety if we take in sympathetic should be much more than he expresses.
I'm concerned about my wife, but about my job also.
So Phos is not a matter of just anxiety it's an anxiety about who is suffering.
That is his anxiety.
He suffers, he's my relative then I'm anxious. Not the job, forget the job.
He is considered therefore it's not a Phos. Who prescribed Phos for this case?
They don't confess, ok. The potency. What potency should we give?
Very low, low, high, very high, medium?
You can give up to 200CH without any problem.
You can give if you like 30CH every day, you can give even 12CH
but I think 200CH will be a good potency, only one dose, for starting.
-Shall he stop the anti-acids?
-Yes.
Stop the anti-acids. Ok see you tomorrow.