So this lady comes from the USA and she knows homeopathy, you're a homeopath yourself
and most probably you have taken a lot of remedies.
- And probably proved them. I'm very sensitive to the remedies.
-But I see in your reports not the remedies that you have taken.
-They were probably too many...
-I need to know.
-The first remedy that I took was sep and that was when my son was born about 20 years ago.
I had postpartum depression. And doctor Karim gave me that 1M.
-The Pakistani?
-Yes he is living now in Connecticut.
That's the first homeopath I saw. He gave me 1M and started laughing hysterically.
I was embarrassed.
- After the remedy?
-Yes and that went on for a while and then I moved to California
so I had to see another homeopath and she gave me different remedies...
- Who is she?
- She teaches...
- She gave mixtures of remedies?
- She gave me a few.
Gosh I can't remember what they were. Arg-n I think was one of them. It was a long time ago.
- Ok. Then?
- I have taken a lot myself and I know I am not supposed to. I can't figure it out.
So I've taken sulph and sep, puls, arg-n, ars...
- Phos?
- I haven't taken phos.
Puls I have taken seemed to stop the moodiness and weepiness that I have.
- Nat-m?
- Nat-m no... Maybe once or twice, that's hard to say. I've taken quite a few.
- Ign? You took several times?
- A couple of times, yes.
When my dad was real ill and go to see every time I leaved I cried. That was quite a few years ago.
- And calc?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
- Sil?
- No.
- We'll see. We'll find out.
So you write here in your report that you were depressed since 6 years old.
As far as you can remember yourself. Because your mother separated
and you were around 4 years old then. Your dad was an alcoholic.
Your dad had indian blood?
- Yes.
- He was pure Indian?
- No.
- He was a mixture.
- French and Indian.
- And used to beat your mother. Had anal fissures.
Who? You or the father?
- Me.
- And were hospitalized about 3 times. When you were 3 years old.
- Yes 3 years old or somewhere in there. And then I had tonsillitis and they removed my tonsils.
- Removed your tonsils at the age of 5.
- Somewhere there. As far as I can remember.
- What you would say it is your main problem now?
- Very aggressive, anger?
- You have kept anger inside. You have never taken staph?
- I have.
- And several times?
- Staph not several times, no.
I really hate rudeness. I will be rude sometimes but I don't tolerate people who are rude.
I'll let you know. And very argumentative, very aggressive, irritable a lot.
I will argue with you and you can't control me. You cannot tell me what to do.
- That is a problem in your life, I believe.
Socially you have problems by letting yourself, expressing what you think about the other person
or political situations? Politically are you an anarchist?
-  I don't care about politics.
- You don't care about politics like all Americans.
- As you know we get into and half of the time it doesn't work.  Just go with flow.
- But what I want to understand; if you are in an argument with somebody up to what extent...
- I'll rip your head off. When I get really angry I want to hit something.
I don't but that's what I say.
- You want to do it. But when you feel this you cannot control at the moment yourself?
- Well, I hold it in but with maybe my partner I won't hold it in. I'll just let it happen.
- You let it out? Totally?
- Yes but I don't do that with people in general unless it's one of those days...
- You still have your menses?
- No I got through menopause. This is the second year.
- When you had your menses before menses it was terrible?
- Horrible.
- Anger and irritability...
- And very sad and very depressed.
- When the flow was coming...
- Lach didn't work either.
Actually made me a paranoid. High potency. It made me feel people are following me.
So I had to take me off that one.
That's more of a left sided remedy and most of my symptoms are on the right. But we did try that one.
- But still I want to understand a little bit more your inner state.
Do you feel that you have such anger that with the least provocation you would kill that person?
- Not kill, just smack them.
- Why do I ask this question? For which remedy?
- I have to think about that for minute. I know kill is more...
- Ok forget it.
- I'll think about it later though.
- What about merc? Have you taken merc?
- No.
- You salivate during sleep?
There is any salivation.
- No.
- Bad mouth? Bad odor?
- Sure I have a little bad breath in the morning, yes.
- A bit.
- I haven't been told that, I don't think so.
- Have taken hyos?
- I have.
- Bell?
- I have not taken bell.
- Stram?
- Stram I have taken.
As a matter of fact my son took it one time when I was in the room and I felt it I start laughing.
I have taken stram before and I could feel it.
- Which is good for you or? What was the effect of the stram or hyos...
- Stram was more fear of dark.
- You have still fear of dark?
- I still sleep with the light on.
And I think more for my parents and my dad being violent, I mean experience of violence.
- You had been the victim of violence?
- I just watched my dad beat my mom.
- And do you consider yourself as a violent person? You hit really, you kick gets?
- I've striked somebody before, boyfriend, twice.
- You seem proud of it.
- I'm not, no! But I did it.
- But afterwards you feel remorse?
- Yes of course.
- A lot of remorse?
- Yes.
And that's not something I've practiced, it's just how I felt at the time.
I don't like to be reprimanded. And I don't like to be told what to do.
- Have you taken nux-v of course?
- Yes.
- Carc?
- Nope.
- No carc? You feel very easily offended.
- Yes usually if people speak down to me or when many of them are rude
or mean to me I feel offended then yes.
- And then you respond?
- Sometimes.
- Aggressively?
- Yes.
- Abusively.
- Not abusively, more of lashing.
Just with my tongue. Very quirk, very sarcastic. Quick whip.
If I know that's going on with you and I am angry I can bring it out.
- And if you know the weak points of the other person,
for instance a man who is not much of a man, will you tell him?
- Yes. If I am in a relationship with him I will.
I wouldn't say it to you or to you but maybe after I knew you... Maybe.
But no, it's more in my relationships, yes.
- I brought it as an example, what I want to know is if you know the persons' weak spots
will you mention them immediately in case of controversy with them?
- If they've irritated me.
- You will.
- If they have irritated me and I am in that mood yes.
- Sexually you are active?
- Used to be very highly sexual.
Not as much anymore. I don't if it's just the partner or whatever but used to be very highly sexual.
- And you have taken plat?
- Yes. Sorry, I have taken quite a few.
- And orig?
- No.
In a hurry.  Everything I do it quickly. Work, eat, walk fast, impatient, I cannot wait for you,
hurry up, I've got things to do.
- Are you a kind of religious person?
- Yes, I would say.
I joined Jehovah's witnesses for a long time. And then I stopped. And now I am not doing anything.
- But during the lifetime when you were Jehovah's witness did you have a moral problem
between your behavior/ sexuality and your religion?
- No.
- There was not conflict in you.
I just did what was responsible and what was right, and no. I was married to a husband for 17 years.
- The first husband?
- I only had one.
- And what happened to him?
- I kicked him to the curb.
That was joke. I just left him because I wasn't happy, depressed.
- You told him to go or you left?
- I left.
- Because he cheated on you?
- He cheated on my probably 3 times.
And then at the end I cheated on him. Just to get out of the relationship.
- And finally you divorced? Officially?
- Yes.
- And now you are with a second man? You only had 2 men in your life?
- Third.
- Only 3 men in your life?
- Not in my life! No!
I got married 17 years and then I was with another man 6 years. And a lot of each cheated.
They cheated a lot. And then I have a lot of jealousy.
- You could not forgive them?
- No.
Kick them to the curb. Just it's another way to get rid of them.
I've a lot of jealousy. I procrastinate a lot. And I'm very good in business.
I'm very good with my patients and homeopathy and then I run an employment agency,
emplace people to work in dental field.
I've been doing that 23 years and that part I did really well, in business,
I don't do very well in relationships probably not so much in personal life.
- Do you want a change again?
- I just don't want them to get too close. I keep them at a distance.
And probably do that with arguing with them more. The argumentative and irritable.
- You can keep a tight cloth around your neck?
- I don't like that no. And I've done lach before.
- I don't ask it for lach.
- I have a big fear of a head-on collision with the car.
I don't like to drive on roads that are just 2-lane roads.
- But why you say that?
- Because I have a big fear of that.
- Because you have been in an accident.
- Yes.
- On a head-on collision in which you survived without problems.
- 2 really close head-on collisions. And then I have a fear of flying.
I don't like to fly in airplanes. Usually the landing part.
- You have received tarent?
- No. I have not.
And I love to dance. And then fear of abandonment but I push people away.
So I have that fear but I push people away.
- Due to your good character or bad character?
- Bad character.
- Do you really mean it or just say it.
- No, just verbally.
- That means you hurt them?
-  I argue with them and I say things that...
It is more of an irritation, I'm just irritating, I get irritated and I don't want to deal with it.
When I am sick I hate to be questioned, I hate to be talked to and I hate to answer you.
In my emotional state if I am irritated I hate to be questioned.
Don't ask me cause I don't want to tell you.
- But how do you deal now with my questions?
- Fine now.
- You were a little bit anxious, I tell you, you will forget about it.
- But that is with someone in a relationship again that is always irritating me.
And I like to drink red wine, it makes me very argumentative. But that's what I prefer.
I can't stand the smell of cigarette smoke but I used to be a smoker many years ago.
- Heavy smoker?
- 2 packs a day.
- Hashish, marijuana?
- Yes.
- You tried a few times?
- Yes, quite a few drugs.
- Did you have extra-sensory perception?
Experiences of the beyond?
- No.
- You had bad experiences under drugs?
- Some, yes. Pot not so much.
I did cocaine and speed many years ago. Probably 25.
- LSD?
- Speed, it is amphetamine. 26 years ago.
- There was a time where you were in depression? You didn't want to work,
you didn't want to do anything...? When was that period?
- I still get like this sometimes.
- And how long it lasts?
- A long time and then I take a remedy...
Usually puls brings me out of that for some reason. Sexually abused at young age.
3 times just when I was younger. By babysitters, men.
- And you remember it?
- Yes I do.
I have gallstones, so I get the pain. It goes from here to my back.
I have a favorite word that I use a lot when I am aggravated, at somebody "you're exhausting".
I tell my daughter that, I tell them "you're exhausting", I feel exhausted by them.
- Your father is still alive?
- No, he died 3-4 years ago.
- Your mother?
- She's alive.
- How old is she?
- 72.
- Your father had problems with his liver?
- I am sure.
He had depression and he had anxiety attacks, had rheumatoid arthritis,
had some heart issues at the end. But mainly the depression and the anxiety and the arthritis for him.
- Do you see dreams? Do you remember your dreams?
- I do.
- What is the theme mostly?
- I don't know.
They're crazy dreams, they don't have a theme. They can just be the craziest things.
I have to think about it. And I usually have more than one a night. I have quite a few.
- But in your dreams you are still arguing and quarrelling
and fighting like in your day time?
- No.
- What is the theme?
- I don't know.
I can't think of it. I haven't had any dreams in a while...
- When this feeling of anger comes inside do you feel a flush of blood in your head?
- No. I get angry and then I get sad.
- No, when you attack? When you respond? It is something... how comes?
- I usually feel it probably in my stomach and then in my heart.
I don't have a blood rush to my head. Stomach probably.
- Do you have any fears?
- I do.
I have the fear of a head-on collision, fear of dark, fear of landing in the airplane,
fear of abandonment and the jealousy thing, I get really jealous if he looks at another pretty woman...
- Then you become really angry.
- Yes. I hold it in. I don't say it.
- For sometime.
- Yes.
Then I usually drink red wine, gets out. Sorry but it is true... Jealousy is really big for me.
And I've always had issues with my stomach. I always had stomachaches that's growing up.
- You have taken aur?
- No.
And I get stomachaches and lately heartburn when I get angry.
Or when I am irritated at the person I am with. And my eyes ache when I start to cry.
- Are you suspicious?
- I can be yes.
In the relationship... where you're  cheating... yes, sure.
- You said you had this amelioration with the flow?
When you had your menses, because you took lach.
- They gave me lach because of this talkativeness, used to be but not as much anymore
and the thing around the throat. Actually I believe doctor gave me that remedy.
He also gave me nat-m...
- Studying your case before we decide...
- I know.
- If you interfere with this you will give us wrong symptoms. Just give us real,
original symptoms without hiding. I see you can speak very freely actually.
You are not a simple case as you understand
and because you have taken all the remedies you have changed I little bit your profile.
I see you blushed now. Do you feel it?
- No I don't blush. I don't think so.
- I see the change.
- I'm blushing?
- You became reddish. You don't feel it.
- Genital herpes I got that when I was young.
- Is not that I have to find your remedy. I have to justify the remedy, why I give the remedy.
That's why we study.
- No of course.
That's why I had to pull out the big guns.
I had to come here because nobody could figure me out.
Not as of today. So the biggest thing for me, my mental symptoms is I hate to be controlled,
I hate to be told what to do. I hate to deal with rude people.
I think those are my biggest mental symptoms for me and then of course the jealousy.
- How's your memory?
- Good.
- When you come to the depressive state, can you describe to me how you feel?
- I don't want to do anything. I just feel sad.
- And the tendency for crying comes then or indifference and apathy?
- More indifference.
- And how do you get out of that?
- I usually take puls.
- You take some homeopathic remedies.
And then you become overactive because of the way that you describe your life. It's very active.
- It's not as active as you think it is.
I run my business out of my home, the employment agency and that serve me well for my depression
and then of course I treat people off and on for a lot of years so mainly it's been more friends
and colleagues so far and now starting to treat people on more of a professional level
with a few other doctors.
- Where did you study homeopathy?
- A lot of it on my own, a lot of it from the internet,
studying through reading a lot of things from you as well, a lot of it just in my books...
- The fear of the dark is very strong?
That means if there is total darkness you will wake up in terror?
- No. Not too long ago I woke up and felt like somebody was standing by my bed and I screamed out.
And I used to have that long time ago I don't have so much anymore.
More of ghost, demons in the room. Yes, I like to keep a light on. I usually have the TV on.
So really late I finally turn it off.
- Are you taking the course?
- I am not but I'm going to be.
- When?
- You are in your 2nd period so I would have to start...
- No...
- e-learning?
- Yes, the e-learning.
- Not yet.
- So you are not aware of the theory that we have.
- No.
- Your previous life, your medical history... had fibroids when pregnant,
had gallbladder attacks, high blood pressure, constipation
and urinary tract infections after intercourse... What age you had your first sexual contact?
- 15.
- Did you have immediately an infection after that?
- No.
- But later on when you had...
- Yes the last 10 years. They have to be a lot of intercourse not just one time...
- You have to repeat. Don't speak so fast. Can you speak a little bit slower?
Because most of the people are not Americans here. So you said...
- After a lot of sexual intercourse I get urinary tract infections.
- Always?
- A lot of the times, yes.
- Your partner had gonorrhea in the past?
- No, I don't know.
- You had...
- Herpes, genital.
- Not venereal?
- Genital, venereal herpes, yes.
- I mean venereal diseases like syphilis, gonorrhea...
- I don't have that. And I don't know if somebody else in my past has.
-  Did you have med yourself?
- Yes.
- There was any effect?
- I don't remember. That was a long time ago. I don't recall.
- What else? Do you still have symptoms you did not mention so far?
- I don't think so.
- Why you are so nice with me?
- Because I like you! If you give me grief I may not be nice that's yet to bee seen.
- The way you describe yourself, I was afraid a little bit.
- Well I am really a nice person, for most part.
- But people of your own, you have the tendency to protect them?
- My children? Yes.
- You have a tendency "I am the boss. I will protect you..."
- Absolutely. You mess with my kids we're going to have issues.
- You have the American accent and though I've lived in America...
- We are not so bad!
- You speak a little bit fast which is difficult for the students as well to understand...
- I am sorry. It's part of the personality. It comes with the territory I suppose.
- Can you give me an idea how many days you feel energetic and how many days in a year,
just give me a little idea, you feel depressed. Can you judge this?
- I would say more depressed and aggravated than up and energetic.
And when depressed I spend lot of time trying to sleep.
And now it's just more aggravated and irritated.
- But when you sleep you sleep right through the night? Or wake up.
- No. I wake up.
- And in the morning when you wake up you are refreshed or unrefreshed?
- Usually refreshed.
- What do you like to eat mostly? You have preferences?
- Cheese, I like cheese quite a bit. Warm drinks, not cold.
- You have taken phos?
- No.
- "I always want to be right and I cannot stand anyone to tell me what to do, argue with me"
- It's true!
- "When I drink too much I sob". I don't understand this.
- Cry.
- You mean alcohol?
- Yes.
- I thought water.
- No, alcohol. Usually red wine.
- Red wine makes you cry or makes you happy and out of happiness you cry?
- No, out of anger.
- So when you drink wine you become more angry?
- And aggressive and then sobbing. My skin itches when I'm in bed, everywhere.
- That's why you have taken sulph?
- Probably, one of the reasons yes.
- Did you say every in your list?
- Yes.
- You're checking your list now to see if you have said everything.
- Yes to see if I have missed anything.
I procrastinate on everything.
- You love to dance and you love thunderstorms.
- I love thunderstorms. Makes me excited.
- When did you take sep last time?
- The very first time I took a remedy.
- Again?
- Not after that.
- Never again?
- No.
- Why?
- I don't know. It was just never given to me again.
How about remedy for "talks too fast"?
- When you sleep you keep a position or you change?
- Right side. I prefer the right side when I'm sleeping but I toss and turn quite a bit.
I can't keep a position but right side preferably...
- Thank you.
The pathology for this case is mostly on the mental emotional level
and if we want to put a name in the diagnosis we could say this is a manic depressive case.
I don't like putting labels in diseases because I know that all diseases
they have a kind of degree of intensity. So if we have in a certain so called disease with a name,
several degrees of intensity in which degree we decide that now we can put this label,
this is the disease.
The diseases they have a starting point and then they develop and they go deeper and deeper.
And they become more and more severe. In her case actually if she is here can you ask her
when it was the last time she had a fever. Get her.
I want to ask you a question. Do you remember if you had a high fever? 39C?
- I am sure I had.
- When?
- ...With tonsillitis.
- With tonsillitis? Can you tell me the age?
- Well I had tonsillitis a lot, like every year. 2 or 3 times a year.
And I am sure I had high fever with that.
- You do not measure it.
- I don't remember.
- When did you have your first tonsillitis.
- 3 or 4.
- And then again you remember having tonsillitis and getting antibiotics every time?
- Every time, yes. And then I took them out.
- What age they took it out?
- 5.
- 5, so early. So you could not have any more tonsillitis.
- Not after they removed but before. Lots. My tonsils were really swollen.
- Could not swallow.
- Yes. Sorry you guys. Bye!
- You did a good job. Bye.
She has very difficult temperament. Nice woman to have for how can I say for ping pong.
You say one word she says two and then three and four...
I am in a difficult position because I don't think anybody could have thought the remedy.
It's difficult the remedy.
Neither I have it here exactly but I will read to you the very close just to give you an idea.
From the Materia Medica Viva. "Strong personality that likes to be in the fore front.
Is haughty and self-confident, feels important and is quite selfish.
They talk loudly indeed they talk a lot and many times will mumble and miss words."
Very interesting, mumble. Like Lach.
It's interesting if you hear a little bit more because once you grasp the idea you never forget.
This type of cases are belonging to a seldom indicated remedy.
But you once you have seen it live then you will recognize it when you have a patient coming.
"They are people who love life and live it to the outmost.
Enjoying it to the limit and sometimes they will be euphoric [...] and apparently almost ecstatic.
It's an interesting observation that the poisoning of this remedy creates a tremendous...
she does not have that but doesn't matter... This remedy gets involved in arguments and quarrels."
Crotalus... The remedy is Crotalus.
"They get involved in cultural discussions with great animation
and also express emotions in a spontaneous, direct and many times even aggressive way.
They are sentimental and temperamental. They will get what they want from life.
And if necessary fight for it." You get the idea behind.
They have also fears such as fear of death for themselves and also for others,
anxiety for those who they love but also fear of strangers, fear of people,
fear of narrow crowded places. The idea here is that they cannot tolerate restrictions.
Especially those in the pit of the stomach and the throat.
But the idea of not being able to tolerate any kind of imposition, restriction is there.
They are attached to their family members and will take care of them.
They suffer very much if those who are closed to them are in trouble or sick.
And then such people there is another phase in which they come to the opposite state
and when problems start going deeper irritability and sometimes instability arises.
Even a very slight external influence may cause a breakdown in the emotional equilibrium.
And then tremendous weakness all over as if some evil were apprehended. Said it in a way.
Excessive irritability, snappish temper; irritable, cross, infuriated by least annoyance.
Soon this instability passes and the patient goes into depression and indifference.
The patient becomes melancholic, apathetic and shuns people, throws people away.
With sudden weakness, headache, heartache and diarrhea.
Depression and indifference towards everything. Great ill-humor and prostration.
And this I'm reading it from my Materia Medica which the remedy is Crotalus horridus.
But when I saw the case I wrote down another remedy not crot-h
which is very close to this remedy.
I wrote down this and it's very interesting that as he was putting up the symptoms
the remedy came up quite highly and I want to show you this now.
Show them the symptoms which you have put. And you will see a very interesting thing...
Also I forgot to read to you that the cascavella... ok I said the remedy.
Ok horridus and cascavella they have right sided problems where lach is left sided.
It looks quite a lot like lach but it is not lach.
So you see this temperament, this aggressive, responsive, snappish...
The symptoms now become of different importance.
What is important now in this case is the description of the mental emotional picture.
Unless you have it in your mind it is going to be very difficult
but still if you put all the symptoms, you put how many symptoms,
14 symptoms and you ask...generalities wine, dancing, fear of dark of ghosts,
in a hurry, indifference, irritability, rudeness, sensitive to reprimands,
loves thunderstorm... he put every case.
See now something very interesting. I wrote down the remedy crotalus cascavela quite early
when I understood the picture. Now it is very interesting with 14 symptoms
crot-c comes in 2nd position.
How come? See the program and understand the difficulty we have with homeopathy
that if you ask this compass to explain to you why he chooses as a 2nd remedy crot-c
how many symptoms do you think crot-c will have out of 14? 5. Crot-c has only 5 out of 14.
Carc comes first which is an interesting idea but carc is not that aggressive,
is very sensitive to reprimands, actually you have to change it here to 3rd degree.
Reprimands should be of the 4th degree. I'm correcting this all the time.
Of course as you understand it never ends, it's a constant headache...
give me the next after crot, it's staph.
It's 6 symptoms. Ok, give me lach. 7 symptoms. Give me tarent. 6 symptoms.
Give me cenchrix. One symptom.
Give me crot-h. 4 symptoms. Give orig. 3 symptoms. Calc. 7 symptoms.
Lyc. 6 symptoms. 9 nine symptoms for lyc.
So this is something which shows you the difficulty we have in choosing the remedy
and it's not enough to have mechanical tools that can give us...
we have to know at the same time the M.M. to have studied the M.M. and understand M.M.
Who found the crot-c? I told you it's going to be difficult.
That's why you are here. Don't get disappointed.
Because if you get disappointed forget it you will never learn, you will never try really.
I was in the same despair when back in the 60s when I was meeting such case,
could not solve the case and I could read all M.M. right through for one case.
I remember one time I took the case of a nice girl, she was so nice and I liked her very much.
I wanted to help her. I could not find the remedy. I tried for 2-3 hours forget it,
I studied after that, forget it then I slept. And I woke up in the morning
and I said "Oh my God, this is an ign case".
As soon as I woke up, my subconscious mind was still working out the case.
I gave it of course and it was a beautiful cure. But nothing happened.
Because I know you like to know the full story.
She got out of the ign state and she was not anymore fascinating.
This just to tell you in order to cure somebody how much effort has to be.
When I see a case I feel exhausted afterwards.
Just to see 2 cases a day for me it's beyond my capacity.
Especially difficult cases, if it is an easy case I know you give staph and finish,
nat-m or ign and you finish.
But if it as realy difficult case and you want to help  then takes really effort
and you have to be really dedicated. I want to help this person.
And the idea of a good homeopath, when you have inside the desire to help, the knowledge will come.
It is unbelievable. For me I have seen this again and again because the click comes...
that's the remedy finally.
This remedy now is going to start... for the first time really
she is going to feel better and grounded. She is beyond control. Nobody can control her.
After crot-c she will become more manageable, more human, she will understand,
it's not that "I am" the selfish element which we see, it will come down, it will be grounded.
What potency? Who wants to give 30CH? 200CH? 1M? 10M? 50M? Nobody.
- What is the remedy?
- Crotalus cascavela.
I was reading from horridus which is very close to cascavela... I haven't written the cascavela
but it is very close to horridus. So I was reading from horridus.
Because if  started telling you what are the symptoms of this woman
you would think "He just saw the symptoms and he comes and tell us the symptoms".
I want to show you that there is a science that this type of person has been recorded
and it exists in our M.M. but I have omitted  it because I don't write it with every remedy I have omitted
crot-c and not crot-h but they are very similar. They are both right sided remedies.
They are both this kind of person that is so easily offended
that with the least thing they will attack you, with the least provocation they will attack,
they will say whatever they want without control,
without ever being able to think what's going to happen if I speak so badly to the other person.
I wanted to read it from a similar remedy which is crot-h to prove to you
that there is already recorded...
Thank you, you saved my life. You learn a new remedy. You were lucky.
- When I looked at your repertorization possible rubrics like abused being or after abused being.
My question is do you avoid to take a rubrics with a possible cause
and just go for just characteristic symptoms at the present?
- Yes. I understand you question.
The thing is this that if you have a picture of a remedy you do not go
and give a lot of importance to the causative factor.
If you don't have a clear picture of a remedy then you try different remedies
then you may try the causative factor remedy.
For instance somebody had a head injury and he is depressed.
Just because of that you may give nat-s.
but if you have a picture of calc you give calc forgetting the causative factor.
The causative factor will play a role when the rest of the case is not clear,
it does not give you really the answer.
Many times of course the cases they don't have enough symptoms but she was full of symptoms,
she gave all the picture without any restriction.
Before entering she said "I need a remedy for anxiety", I said "Don't worry".
But I understood the moment she would start taking she would forget everything.
She forgot about the class, the whole situation, because all this internal intensity,
it was there. So thank you very much. Potency? Give 10M.