This is a lady 40 years old. You did not have any conception so far?
Maybe you had an abortion when you were 20 or 21?
– Yes.
– It was not spontaneous.
– I didn’t want the baby.
– Who was the gynecologist?
– He was in Denmark. I live in Greece the last 5 years, in Alonissos.
But when I was 20 I took pills not to get pregnant after the abortion
and then I stopped them when I was 28,
I used spiral for 1 year but I didn’t like it,
I could feel it so I took it out when I was 29 and I haven’t protected myself for 10 years.
The first 4 years I didn’t have any special relationship so I was protecting myself a little
but the last 6 years I am married to a Greek man here and we didn’t succeed to have any babies.
– Was there any gynecologist who examined you?
– Yes. After 2 years marriage I went to one in Denmark
to check if my tubes were open and they were ok.
– Did he see any endometriosis?
- Not in Denmark but I went to a doctor in Volos in November
and she said that if I wouldn’t stay pregnant after checking the eggs to develop,
if nothing happens she said I should go and look because there was a small shade on the picture
maybe there was piece of meat that prevents the eggs come down.
But it was just an idea she had. My husband has been checked, he is ok.
– He’s 100% ok?
– Yes.
– I see. Do you have any complaints with your health?
– No. I have sinusitis.
– And do you have a lot of discharge from the nose?
– It irritates me in the throat, things coming down from behind.
– Post-nasal discharge.
What comes out is sticky?
– It’s sticky.
– Very sticky?
– Yes.
– In the morning especially do you have to hawk it?
– Your husband notices that or he is annoyed by that?
– No.
– It’s mostly in the morning?
– No. One week I may have nothing and then suddenly for 2-3 days I’m irritated again.
– But much bigger noise than now...
- Yes, to get it out.
– Seldom the last year I have some dizziness.
My own theory is that I had a much stressed life in Denmark before I came down here
and maybe I was very tired without taking care of it and I had it maybe twice a year.
In the beginning it was more, I was very dizzy. Now I have it maybe once a year.
– And when you have this what do you feel in your head?
– I feel that the whole room goes around.
– Vertigo. It’s not dizziness. Things outside are turning.
– For 24 hours I feel I am little sea-sick. I am walking a little strange.
But now it’s more and more seldom.
– Do you have anything else?
Your menses are regular?
– Yes.
– Every many days?
– It’s not 100% regular. Maybe 28 to 30 days.
– The blood is normal?
– Yes.
– How many days?
– 6-7 days. But a lot only for 1 day and a half.
– And in the first days do you have clots of blood as well or do you have just blood?
– Seldom I have clots.
– Otherwise it’s...
- Normal.
– Dark blood or light blood?
– It’s quite dark I think. Then it is brownish in the end.
– Before menses do you get upset easily, are you more prone to cry or to get angry?
– Sometimes I noticed it, but not every time.
– Otherwise your menses can come just like that without you understanding anything.
– Yes. I’m not feeling something special now. I am not feeling tense.
Seldom it happens but it’s not every month.
– Do you have any swelling of the breast before menses?
– Sometimes I have a little in the one breast?
– In the left?
– Yes.
– Always the left?
– Yes actually.
– Do you have any headaches?
– No.
– Do you have any stomach problems?
– I had before but not after my life became more quiet and easy.
It was a little complicated in Denmark.
– Would you say it was wild?
– I would say emotionally I was with a man who was a drug addict with cocaine
and things like that and made me ill.
And because of those problems I have pain here in my stomach.
–Did he hit you?
- Yes, in one case he hit me.
– Not every day.
– No it was one time he got mad from the drugs.
– At what age did you start having sex?
– 17 years old.
– It was a good experience or it was rather negative?
– It was not the first thing...
- Nothing special.
– No.
– Later on you had problems with your sexual life
or you enjoyed it with no problem?
– No.
– Actually you had a quite a lot of enjoyment?
– Yes.
– Did you ever get any infection?
– No. Only small like fungi. Not something serious.
– Do you remember what type of medicine they gave you for that?
– No because it’s many years ago. It was in my early 20s I had some problems with that.
I had one pill that I didn’t like.
I had to take 5 pills in one day and you get really terrible taste in the mouth and feeling strange.
– You took all 5 or 4?
– I don’t remember but it was just a lot of pills.
– Do you remember before the age of 20 that having any infection?
– I didn’t have any infection but I had problem with my period in the beginning.
I got it quite late, I was 16 and then it couldn’t really get started.
I started to bleed and then it wouldn’t stop so I had a hormone pill to regulate it
because I was bleeding for 1 month or so. Just a little every day. I wouldn’t stop.
- When you took the pill did it help you or didn’t it make any change in your menses?
– It made me bleed very much and then I was actually on holiday in Greece
and I got frightened and I threw the pills out because I had really a lot of blood.
– Did you ever have any epistaxis, nosebleeds? – No.
– Is there any time when you feel worse or better?
– Yes. I feel best during the daytime.
I don’t like to work late. I don’t like to read in the evening.
– When you wake up in the morning you feel refreshed from sleep?
– When I was younger I felt very fresh in the morning
but after the problems I had in Denmark with my boyfriend I have difficulty to wake up
but I still wake up early.
– What time?
– 6.30 a.m.
– Do you feel warm or cold?
– I feel cold very easily.
You see I am wearing this and people tell me you’re living in Greece,
you cannot wear things like that now but I am not feeling easily hot.
– Do you swim in the sea?
– Yes.
– You like it?
– Yes, I like it very much.
– Swimming in the sea makes you feel good?
– Yes.
– How much?
– I like to lie in the sea, relax in the sea.
I like the feeling of relaxing, floating.
– But would you say that you go to the sea and you’re tired and you have a bath
and you come out of the sea lie down and feel full of energy?
–No. I think I need to sleep after a bath. I feel sleepy, in a nice way of course.
–Do you sleep well?
– Yes.
– Right through without waking?
– Do you perspire during night?
– I actually wake up and I’m often thirsty at night, I always have a glass of water,
I don’t know if it’s because I’m sweating.
I am not feeling wet on my body but I feel thirsty. I drink every night.
– That means you wake up and drink water. Many times?
– No. One time and I’m not annoyed of it. I fall asleep at once again.
– Your nails are strong or brittle?
– I have one with problem, the others are strong.
– Your toes they enter the flesh and you have to cut the specially?
– A little. My big toes but not the other ones.
– Are you constipated at all? You don’t have regular stool, difficult stool?
Every day you go to the toilet to have evacuation of your bowel?
– Yes, every day in the morning.
– No problem, no difficulty?
– No. It’s a little watery actually. Not much but a little.
– Do you have stool every morning?
– Every morning, seldom in the afternoon.
– What is the worst time for you? Is it in the evening when you are tired
or in the night or in the morning when you wake up? When you feel tired and you don’t feel well.
– If I feel like that it’s in the evening but actually one thing that irritates me
it’s I am feeling often very tired without reason I feel, kind of exhausted.
– When is that? Do you notice if it is a time?
– Usually in the midday. I need to take a nap for 20 mins and then I feel ok again.
– At about what time?
– 2-3 p.m. Some people don’t need a nap but I need to relax for 20 mins in the afternoon.
– And you need to sleep or only lie down?
– I fall asleep very quickly so I sleep for 20 mins.
– How much salt do you take?
– Not too much.
– What about sweets?
– I like sweets but I am not eating them very much.
– There is any food which you really do not like? You would never eat this food.
– I don’t like kidney and things like that.
I like liver but I don’t like the other things from inside.
– What else?
– I don’t like to drink orange juice, I get pain my stomach.
And I don’t like to drink it, to have it in my mouth.
– Even fresh orange juice?
– I can drink fresh orange juice if the oranges are sweet.
– Do you keep a position in sleep?
Do you sleep only on the left/ right side or you can sleep in any position?
– I have only a little problem to sleep in my stomach now.
I have pain my back if I’m on my stomach.
– Would you say your sexual desire is normal or much more than normal or less than normal?
– I’d say it’s quite normal.
– Do you have any fears? Are you afraid of anything?
– No. Not something special but I had some crisis of fear in my life.
– What kind of fear?
– I don’t know how to explain it.
It’s like when you suddenly feel afraid of losing yourself.
I had when I was 13 and when I was 24 and then again 2-3 years ago.
And I have worked to find out for what reason I get it
and I think I have found out somehow why I have this sudden attack of fear.
– Why? Can you say why?
– I think it has to do with things when I was 2 years old
when I was in the hospital taken away from my parents and they were not allowed to see me
and I think I developed it there.
I was very helpless with those doctors doing whatever they wanted to me
and I think from that period of my life I get this feeling of fear.
– Do you have any fear for doctors now?
– No. I have fears if people want to decide things for me and lock into a room or something.
–Are you afraid of closed places?
– Yes.
– Would you enter a lift?
– Yes, I do that I think it is more like I am afraid somebody to lock me into a room so I can’t get out.
– Were you ever locked by your boyfriend?
Did your boyfriend lock you any time?
–No.
– Anybody else locked you?
– I don’t remember.
– Fear of high places?
– The last year I had a little problem with the high places but sometimes I don’t have it,
sometimes I get very dizzy.
– Do you tolerate the sun? You go out in the beach, are you lying in the sun?
– Only if it not too hot. If it is too hot I go in a shade.
I enjoy the sun but if it is too hot no.
– But will you have any problems with the sun? Headaches and things like that?
– No. It can irritate in my eyes if I am not wearing glasses.
– How much water do you drink?
– In the summer I drink 3-4 lit.
– Cold water?
– I don’t drink cold water.
– When you drink you drink a whole glass or sips?
– I drink a whole glass.
– Were you having any problems with your ears as a child?
– No. Like inflammations? No.
The problem I had when I was a child was having very high metabolism
so that’s why I went to the hospital when I was a child.
I fainted in the morning I had very low blood sugar.
– And what did they give you? Thyroid hormone?
– I don’t think they gave me anything.
They just said I had to eat before I went to sleep in the evening.
My parents had to give me something to eat before I go to school.
– How is your appetite now?
– It’s very good!
– As much you can eat there is no problem, you don’t put on weight?
– I have to take a little care now. Before I could eat whatever I wanted.
But I eat 3 times a day. But I still have it like if I am not eating I get kind of exhausted.
– Is this exhaustion that you mentioned before a sudden exhaustion because you have not eaten?
– No.
– Do you have any leucorrhea? This discharge from the vagina.
– No. I had it when I was younger.
– You took some medication to stop it?
– Only when it caused itching as well.
– Then you took something to stop the itching.
– Yes because together with the itching it was some fluid coming out.
– And then you were given a medicine that stopped the itching and the fluid.
– I think it’s some pills.
– Do you drink milk?
– No.
– Are you affected by drafts?
If you sit somewhere where there is a draft are affected by it?
– Yes it will affect my muscles if I am working and sometimes if I sit like that
there is pain in my face from the nerves from the draft.
– When you sleep in the night now, with this weather, do you cover yourself with one blanket or two?
– One but not very thin. Normal blanket.
– Are you afraid of dogs, cats?
– No.
– Thunderstorms?
– No. I don’t like heavy wind. That makes me nervous.
– What are you afraid of? The house will collapse?
– I don’t like the noise, the atmosphere it creates.
– Do you remember having warts in your fingers?
– I had when I was a kid on the foot and on the hand I think.
– Do you know how they went away?
– I think they were burned.
– By a doctor?
– Yes.
– Would you say that you are open in your emotions,
you can express your emotions, your feelings or you are reserved and careful.
– I think I am quite good in expressing.
I get easily angry and get it out and I can tell if I have something that bothers me.
In that case I think maybe I am trying to be stronger than I am
if something bad is happening around me I continue to work and do everything normally
and maybe suddenly I get very tired instead of saying I’m not able to continue
because I’m in a bad situation. I think I am too proud to do that, I try to keep up.
– We’ll see if we can do something.
What happened with this case? Why the first question I put is did you have an abortion?
– Yes. Was it voluntary? Yes. I did not want the child.
– You know why? Because I saw a healthy woman rather healthy cannot have a child.
For me I have seen this phenomenon again and again
after voluntary abortion when there are some adhesions after excision of the uterus.
You know the gynecologist they go and scrap the uterus to get out the fetus
and by scrapping and making a deeper scratch they make adhesions
and these adhesions they do not allow the fetus to develop anymore, find a place to develop.
It is one of the worst cases that we can have because I have seen in spite of battling with such cases,
I have not been able treat cases of that type.
When the damage is traumatic for the uterus after abortion.
She is not able to have children because the endometrium has been spoiled
and has been growing adhesions and that’s why she cannot have a child.
Otherwise her hormonal system is working alright, the fallopian tubes are open,
the ovaries are discharging but no conception.
That’s a case where we have to treat this kind of disease
and as you saw me I had a big problem in coming down to a remedy.
Very difficult because I did not have enough information.
In the beginning I asked her also how she cleans her sinuses.
Because usually Med., they raise postnasal discharge which is sticky
especially in the morning has to be cleared and is so sticky and annoying that the person has to...
I had a woman quite respectable and I asked the children how they feel,
it’s terrible, it’s nauseating to hear mother doing...
Because one child came with the idea of Med. and I said your father died of heart attack?
Yes. What age? About 52. Your mother is doing that? Yes!
And it’s so terrible! That means the husband had gonorrhea,
the woman was affected by gonorrhea of the husband,
she develops this postnasal discharge which is characteristic of Med. and the child now got Med.
But then Med. was not confirmed you saw
when I asked her the time where she would be better should be what? Afternoon, evening time.
She should have said in the evening I become alive.
The second thing she should have said is that I come here actually in Alonissos
and live here because of the sea because I feel so wonderful when I’m in the sea.
I could not get this information either.
There was a third keynote about oranges; it’s the food of Med.
If you ask them how many oranges they can take they say unlimited,
more than 10. 10,20 oranges.
She said oranges make me upset. Forget Med.
There was a possibility of Sil. I did not see any strong keynotes of it.
She did not have the constipation,
the nails... soft nails... the draft was not a big thing with her.
And then Calc. There is no perspiration, no desire for sweets.
Nat-m. she did not feel this type of Nat-m. been having a lot of grief and being closed.
She was not that closed. And she despair me and I did not what to do.
You had me not speaking for quite some time.
I don’t do it usually but I had to do some hard thinking and searching.
I was looking some things which are of no interest to you at this moment.
No reaction... The late reaction is no reaction.
And finally what I had is... there were no fears actually,
the bleeding was not Phosphorus bleeding, was neither a big disturbance there.
She claims that her sexual energy is quite normal.
Hormonally I could not see any problem. Everything was functioning.
The only thing I could confirm from the very beginning was adhesions in the endometrium
until I asked her and she said yes it was somewhat confirmed by a gynecologist.
Therefore I had to give a remedy.
I thought of Hyos. Nat-m., Calc., Thuja, Acon., Sil., Staph., Nit-ac... Calc-i.
Show me the symptoms that you have used.
The symptoms are;
fear of narrow places, fear of wind, vertigo high places,
vertigo as everything is turning, catarrh postnasal, posterior nares, mucus in the throat,
thirst for large quantity, thirst in the night...Thirst in the night is very interesting
because if you look at the repertory you will see Sil. quite strongly.
Stool watery, leucorrhea itching, menses dark, sterility,
menses swelling of mammae before menses, warts suppressed, general in the evening worse,
inflammation of sinuses, weakness afternoon.
This is somewhat a repertorization that you may be using
and then it says that the best remedy is Nat-m. and you say Nat-m... I don’t like.
The second is Calc. She feels cold but apart from that there is no other... and then comes Thuja.
Explain why Thuja. Because of fear of wind, it’s very interesting,
I have added this for Thuja myself. Postnasal catarrh, has thirst in the night,
watery stool, suppressed warts, of course. Evening weakness and what is more;
adhesions... you never put it.
Anyhow you know that the tendency of Thuja to produce adhesions, warts, growths.
Her gynecologist said that there is a growth that impedes.
I don’t believe this is the real problem.
The real problem is that the endometrium has been spoiled extensively.
This is the real reason for her having this sterility.
And it is going to be very difficult to correct that
but the remedy with which we must start at this moment is Thuja.
When I said Hyos. nobody objected.
You should shout! I play tricks.
When I was teaching in the beginning I was teaching the Greeks here back in 1970.
They would bring paper cases put them on the wall,
they wrote and I said you take this and this and that symptom and because of this the remedy is Calc.
Do you agree? This is wrong.
I take this and that symptom and the remedy is Sulph.
Do you agree? No, this is wrong.
I take this combination... it’s Carb-v. Now we understand.
Do you agree? Wrong!
I take this and that and the remedy is Thuja.
Nobody dares to say this is the right remedy.
That means in cases where we have complications
we have to choose the right combination of symptoms
and choose them in a realistic basis.
Sometimes you are based on the pathology quite a lot.
You don’t have in all cases general symptoms or mental emotional symptoms.
But here with Thuja it’s interesting.
She says I fear wind. That’s interesting.
I was thinking of Thuja and she said I fear wind.
Because Cham. known for it but Thuja is not. Bye bye!
So the remedy is Thuja. What is the potency?
Who would suggest 6X? 12C repeatedly?
1. 30C? 4. 200C? 19. 1M? 4. 10M? 7. 50M? 1. CM?
The woman is healthy is general? No problem.
You can go as high as you like in this case. It’s no problem.
You can try, if you want, a very high potency 50M or CM with her to see whether she will react.
If she reacts in a very high potency there is a possibility bringing out the warts again
and reducing the adhesions. Maybe there is a possibility.
If she does not react in this case I would still insist.
I would first give 50M. Then I would wait for 2 months to see whether there is any reaction.
If there is no reaction I will go to low potency like 6X or 12X and give three times a day
repeatedly before I give up on Thuja
but if I give up on Thuja I don’t know what to do next, to tell you the truth.
I don’t see the underlying [remedy].
Maybe Med. is true.
Maybe it will change after Thuja as complementary she may need Med. I am not sure.
Calc.? I don’t see it.
She eats whatever she likes without putting on weight.
Sweets; she said she is not interested.
Sweat; there is no sweat.
Where can you base a prescription of Calc.? Sil. of the thirst in the night... maybe Sil.
but where are the other symptoms except of soft nails.
You don’t have enough information.
– How about Med.?
– I rejected Med. As a second [remedy]?
May be a shot in the dark.
You don’t have the real symptoms, the keynotes of the remedy on which you can base your prescription.
But I believe there is another remedy which I don’t want to confuse you but anyhow...
- What about organ-specific remedies? Fraxinus. Dr. Benett wrote a little book about fertility.
– I don’t know. What is this?
– Fraxinus americanus.
– Is a herb?
– A tree.
– I don’t know this remedy.
– I did think it was Thuja, but I would worry about giving a high potency.
Because of all the suppression that she had in the past.
– If both come back discharge and the warts she will be cured.
This is what we expect; that the discharge will come back and the warts will come back.
If that happens we’ll have a baby.
– But if you give the potency very high that will make a strong reaction that would be uncomfortable.
– No. There is not real deep pathology.
What happens is a trauma on the endometrium which is superficial.
If she has endometriosis it would be different because in endometriosis we have a disease,
a quite serious condition.