Ruth, tell me, how you have been feeling?
– When I look back I remember how scared I was that I would never work again.
I thought that was the end because I tried Homeopathy I had faith in Homeopathy
but it wasn’t working for me. You prescribed Lac-c.
I started with 200C and in days I started to feel I could climb the mountain again.
And I didn’t go back carefully. I just threw myself back into my work.
And I was amazed, I was very strong
but then again I would start to feel myself dropped and I took another Lac-c. 200C.
I can’t remember what time it was. That was 2 years ago.
I took Lac-c. 200C a few times and then I took 1M and even up to 10M.
And then last year in June, July.
Before June, July there was an election and there was huge work.
I felt I was carrying that load again and it’s different
if you’re a member of the parliament in opposition and if you are a member of a deputy minister
or you are in the ruling party.
I would be more important if I was in the ruling party.
But I am in opposition. It’s a struggle.
But anyway we did very well in the election.
I helped to change my province, 3 people became 27 and afterwards it was like a plateau.
I just suddenly crushed again.
And I started to cough the green-brown mucus again. I became very weak.
I’ve got laryngitis, I lost my voice.
But I knew those with things going back, to my past settled well, maybe it is not so serious
but I remembered that I actually took antibiotics because I was into my daughter’s wedding.
And I was just fading. The Lac-c. wasn’t working so I took antibiotics.
I got over the cough. My throat got better but I still wasn’t well
and I remembered that you had said, Stan. is a possibility.
– As next remedy. So what happened with Stan.?
– I took Stan. 200C and back in 24 hours. I got better.
When I find the right remedy it is quite amazing how quickly it works on me.
When I don’t...it floats over my head.
And then again I went back into parliament.
I’ve only gone up to Stan. just before I came here again the work, the pressure...
many things mounting, having to arrange with my family...
I felt going down again so I took Stan 1M. And you can see I’m ok.
I’m quite positive and I feel I am talking strongly and working very hard.
I’ve had a big battle. I’ve achieved some things.
– I remember you were saying that’s the end, I cannot continue, I will give up...
- I thought I’d never work again.
– You are working even more than before.
– Yes. You took off this wholeness.
I feel as if I’m working with more calmness, more acceptance. It used to distress me.
I don’t get the migraines anymore. I can even think of snakes.
Remember I told you I couldn’t think of snakes without going into a sort of panic.
I can even try to make myself see snakes in TV, think about snakes. It’s part of nature.
I can cope with it and I don’t freak as that about my children. I never lose that.
My deepest concern still is my children’s health.
Within that world I know I am more susceptible. My worst problem is still my back.
If I sit in the plane for 10 hours the people next door want throw me out of the window.
– You are restless.
– Yes even sitting here...
- You become restless and what type of pain is it?
– It’s a deep ache. Sometimes a burning pain.
And the worst one is between my shoulder blades.
And it’s better when I move around. It’s hard for me to sit.
And even in parliament I hate it to sit down. I like to go out and work.
– Because a lot of people are thinking of a remedy at this moment, tell me,
you are on the cold side or warm?
– Very much the cold side. I can’t bear cold. I don’t like extremes of weather.
Severe heat makes me tired but I am coping with this. But I cannot bear the cold.
– Can you bear drafts?
– No, very sensitive to drafts.
I like air but I hate drafts.
– The night in bed you can sit in one place or you have to change frequently?
– I think I change quite a lot. But I lie on my back now.
I put a cushion under my legs and I’ve tried to train myself to lie on the back.
– Your legs in bed are quiet or restless?
– I think they are quiet.
– You eat eggs?
– Yes. I like eggs.
– Milk?
– I like milk.
– You take plain milk and drink?
– Cold milk. I don’t like hot milk but I like hot tea.
– How much milk you take?
– Not a lot.
I don’t drink a lot of cold milk because I know it’s not particularly healthy.
I like warm Milo.
– Your nails are strong?
– Not very strong. I’ve got ridges on my nails and I get that cracking on the edges of the fingers.
– Do you perspire at all during sleep?
– No.
– And you cover yourself?
– Very much.
Even in this weather I will have to be covered.
– The anxiety about your children is pathological or you say after all you say it’s normal?
– I think it’s more normal but I think I am more concerned about my children than most mothers.
There are out of the country and if I know they are not well it’s on my mind all the time.
I immediately need to do something about it.
But I am not as bad as I used to be.
Ok we go inside and tell you how to continue.
As I always say, in order to bring about cure we need correct remedies in correct sequence.
Those who remember this case when we discussed the different possibilities
and we came down to Lac-c. as the best prescription.
Now, Lac-c. exhausted its action.
But it’s very difficult I had suggested Ruth in case Lac-c. exhausts its action,
most probably she will need Stan.
Because any homeopath who was not very careful would prescribe Stan in the first place.
That would be wrong. Ruth said I cannot even talk.
Stan. is like this, they talk on the telephone and they make big effort to talk on the telephone.
Their voice is almost gone.
And when you hear that and when situation is so bad and dramatic as Ruth was describing,
in the end of career I can’t continue, I am totally exhausted, I’m depleted of energy.
Then you are tempted as first remedy to give Stan. That is wrong.
Stan. would work but for a very short time, would show some effect and back to nothing.
Now Lac-c. took first the first layer and she needed,
and this is important also, repeated doses like the Nat-m. of Ernest. Nat-m. higher and higher,
exhausts its action and then Sep.
This is the same idea as we have been talking before.
You have to be aware, you have to be very careful when you prescribe homeopathic remedies.
In the beginning Ruth was saying he gave me this and that,
helped me in this and that, the end result is that Ruth is breaking down finally
and that means little help here and there is not homeopathic prescription.
Good homeopathic prescription must bring you back to functional conditions.
To the best of your possibilities, of your potentials. This is Homeopathy.
The other is... we give remedies. Ruth has taken 20 remedies.
What for? Like every case that comes here of course.
That does not mean that I will never give a wrong remedy.
Of course I will, especially in complicated cases that have taken a lot of other remedies.
I may not be able to see clearly what is the first remedy that we have to start with.
But these examples show on the one hand what wrong Homeopathy will be doing
and what correct Homeopathy is doing and the possibilities of correct Homeopathy.
And here now Ruth says I have back pain.
And you are the practitioner and you have to decide what is the remedy that you’ll have to give.
The first possibility is wait. The second possibility is same remedy.
The third possibility is new remedy. The fourth possibility is same remedy higher potency.
These are the possibilities you have to choose. These are your chances.
You are supposed to take this case and you are going to tell me what you’ll do.
Who says I would wait? 4. Same remedy? 2. New remedy? 6.
Same remedy higher potency? 9. Majority loses.
Unfortunately, it doesn’t always work this way.
You don’t give Stan. when there is no this exhaustion.
The main picture of Stan. is total exhaustion.
I had described to you in the M.M., not to you, in the classes actually.
I have described the weakness and the tiredness of Stan. It’s unbelievable.
Now, she doesn’t have it. She is very active. You go and give Stan. now?
That means Stan. has at this moment exhausted its action or I don’t know if it has exhausted
but the problem is shall we wait?
Or shall we give the same remedy or a new remedy?
This is the problem. You don’t give the same remedy, definitely.
Here it is not indicated. At this moment Stan. is not indicated.
If you give she will has a proving, she says I prove the remedy and she will be weak.
You have to choose between waiting and a new remedy.
Here you have to judge 2 things; first, whether a new remedy picture is appearing.
If that is not there you better wait.
The second thing to judge is whether the patient at this moment is suffering to such an extent
that you have to do something about it.
So we have to judge whether Ruth is really suffering at this moment to the extent
that we have to prescribe something because the suffering is quite a lot.
If the remedy is clear, even if the suffering is not so much, you are entitled to give the remedy.
If the picture is not clear, even the suffering is quite strong, are you not entitled to give a remedy.
What will you do? Let her suffer? Yes, let her suffer.
You say wait until the picture becomes clearer.
Because in comparison to what she has been gone before now the suffering is 10%.
Not even 10%. I will ask Ruth to make an estimation on the present situation in comparison to the beginning.
– I think because the potential is still there always to go down.
I feel as if I am not back to where I was when I was really a fit person.
I’d say I still have 10%.
My back is such a problem when I am on the plane that I really struggle to get sit for 10 hours.
It’s quite intense. I endure it but for me it’s quite serious.
– Fair enough. As I said a cure takes place when the first layer is gone, the second layer is gone...
For Ruth we are this layer, third layer and what shall we give, what is the remedy?
What is the remedy is very simple. It’s very clear. Puls. is very hot.
Needs the air. She is very cold to the extent that with this weather she needs covers.
Puls. will never do that. Puls. will never cover herself in hot room in summer.
Therefore, Puls. is definitely not there. But you need a remedy which is very sensitive to cold.
Who cannot stay still because of the pain in the back. Who desires cold milk?
We have suffering while sitting and better walking. She has to get up and move to be better.
She is very cold, she does not like drafts and she likes cold milk. Very simple.
Everybody recognizes the remedy which is Rhus-t. Very good.
This is a signal from America that you are doing very bad work there! The CIA!
So we will suggest that Ruth can use one dose of Rhus-t. 30C only,
don’t go higher for the moment, and try not to exhaust yourself for a few days.
Ruth’s tox! What is good about our school is that the students can observe all cases.
We never hide any case. You see all the cases how they are doing.
I understand some of you are depressed but don’t bother.
In 40 years you will be experts! I completed my 41th year of practice!