We look at the case of a child of how old?
– 3 and three fourths.
– A report from the NHS by Dr. Mitchell...
Can you read the conclusion of the report?
– He concluded that Alex has mixed developmental disorder predominately involving her speech and language
but with some autistic features, an immature pattern of motor development and a disordered attention span.
She may later develop dyspraxia. Alex has not been immunized at all by parental choice.
– Did you take hormones in order to become pregnant?
– No, nothing.
– And pregnancy was easy or took long time?
– Pregnancy was fine.
I had to have a cesarean because she was in breech position and she came out early at about 38 weeks.
– You have to give a little bit of you medical history.
– The medical history for myself; as child lots tonsillitis’ and one series of NSU,
non-specific urethritis, acne rosacea and lots of... Lots of upper respiratory tract infections.
– With a lot of antibiotics?
– No. Maybe when I was younger maybe one course.
– Do you have other children?
– No, she’s our only one.
– When did you marry?
– 1978. We were married 19 years when Alex was conceived.
– Why?
– We don’t know!
– There are 2 things; either you have been taking precaution measures and you did not have a child...
- We did for 10 years but then...
- For 10 years you did not want a child and you took protection
and you did not have a voluntary abortion?
– No.
– And after 10 years you decided to have a child. And you had free sex.
Then you found out that there was no pregnancy and then you did something,
took some medicine, or homeopathic medicine?
– No. It just happened.
– You let it be.
– We thought it was fate. It’s not going to happen.
So we didn’t worry about it.
– We tried initially with an ovulation test but it’s not very romantic to sit there with a kit
so in the end we decided...
- If it’s not meant to be, it’s not meant to be
but miraculously it happened and this is her.
– Let me understand. You were married at what age? 21. We met when I was 19.
– Was it your first affair?
– I had a relationship before my husband.
– No pregnancy before?
Do you remember if you had precaution and you did not have pregnancy?
– We didn’t. We used the rhythm method with my first relationship.
– You were examined by a gynecologist?
– No, because I didn’t want drugs or offer me lots of other things.
– It became a kind of problem for you,
after a few years you saw that there was no child coming?
– Yes, as the clock ticks away for any woman you do,
you think I’m coming up to 40, Gosh this is it!
I kept thinking maybe should go to the doctors but I really didn’t want to
because I know they would suggest hormones.
I thought maybe I should get checked out. I just delayed it and became pregnant.
– So it came after 19 years of marriage.
– Here is my medical history...
- 15 months you had divergent squint.
– No this was the baby. She had a squint. It’s intermittent.
– I saw it in the beginning and then it disappeared.
– If she sits here it will happen because of the light.
The bright light will take one eye here on the other way.
– The medical history is only for you here?
Your father or mother died of Parkinson disease?
– My father 10 years ago primarily as a result of Parkinson’s disease.
– He had 2 heart attacks.
– He had 2 heart attacks before that.
– Your health in good health?
– I have to spit 3 times don’t I? I’m in good health!
– Grandmother; hernia, diverticulitis, polymyalgia and angina.
Maternal; malaria, twice pneumonia, cholera, ischemic attack, bladder cancer.
Your grandfather is still alive. And grandmother had heart problem.
But you feel good?
– I do.
– You do not visit ever any doctor?
– Until I got pregnant.
– In childhood you said you had pneumonia?
– No, tonsillitis.
– After that you never fell ill?
– No.
– Is that true?
– Yes.
– If Liz gets anything is always connected to throat.
– A little bit, no heavy stuff that needs medication?
– The only time where I had a really bad cough in me first relationship,
he was a medical student and he worked in a tuberculosis ward and he gave me this awful cough
and since then I‘ve since always had this mucus, cough.
– Did you get any medication because of that?
Were you tested for TB?
– No. No.
– The child had a cranial osteopathy.
– Yes.
They were going to suggest several operations, not yet but for a later date for the eyes.
– And normal dentition?
– Yes, teethed normally.
– Fontanels closed?
– It closed late...
- About 2 years old.
– She walks now? I see her she crawling.
– She can walk.
– Can she run or is it a kind of ataxia?
– She can run.
– It rolls a little bit, like a sailor.
This is what they are talking about when they are saying immature motor development.
– Are you connected with sailing?
– No! I just sit down on the beach!
– Speech slow. What can she do?
– She can just say a few words now. Mommy and juice.
But she cannot hold a conversation. She can understand.
For a long time I felt she couldn’t understand and I do a lot of things for her
but then she realized that mommy does everything for me,
I’ll let her do everything for me and she does understand
because now I realize I have to get her to talk to me more.
– From my point of view her comprehension is quite good.
She gets very frustrated because the speech that comes is babbled, it doesn’t make sense.
– But if you tell her bring me this, she will.
– Yes.
– All the time?
– If it suits her. She’s obstinate.
She can do it when she feels like.
– She has a cough?
– She started in nursery school last September and from then on it has been coughs and colds
and the cough was quite bad about a month ago.
She was coughing every time she had a cold drink.
– And she was vomiting?
– Yes.
– Every time she coughed she vomited?
– She vomited only after cold drinks or if she ran.
– Will she vomit or cough and vomit?
– Cough and vomit. Not all the ingested in the stomach. Just a bit.
– She also had these 2 febrile convulsions.
– The convulsion started when the fever was high?
– The second one 39C, passing 39C.
- I don’t know about the first one.
– The second one was a lot more serious.
– She was fitting for 3-4 hours even after she was at hospital.
– They gave benzodiazepine.
– They didn’t know the cause of the fever so they were always trying to find the cause of it.
They injected her with antibiotics.
– On May she received Nat-m., Phos. in June, October last year Carc.,
December Bell., February Agar., again February Nat-m., May Sil. and April Tub.
– Is she restless like she is now?
– Yes.
– She has to be busy.
– What does she like to eat?
– Everything. She loves salty things, crisps, chocolate, tomatoes, pasta.
But she’ll eat anything. All the Greek food, all the fruits.
– Did you breastfed her?
– Yes, for 7 months.
– Then you stopped because?
– She was hungry.
– She can get irritable if she doesn’t eat her food or sleep.
– If she eats she feels better?
– Yes. She loves chocolate but she’s not into sweets.
Only the chocolate. And she loves her milk.
– Does she drink milk?
– Yes, she drinks a lot, very heavily. Large amounts.
– Anything... Juice.
– But how much milk?
– She likes the milk but I give her chocolate milk cause she prefers that.
But she loves milk anyway. I don’t give her too much milk anyway.
– Why?
– I just give her twice a day because...
- This is absolute frustration.
– She does not like to be held?
– She does.
– She looked affectionate when she came to me.
She embraced me. Is she like this with strangers?
– Yes absolutely. Some people may think this familiarity is inappropriate for a child her age.
– Have you seen any sexual irritation? Playing with her genitals?
– No.
– The only time I’ve noticed it as if we are in the process to toilet train her,
when she is sitting on the potty because there is noise happening there, but nothing special.
– She likes to eat!
– Have you found out that you can put a lot of salt and still will eat it?
– We haven’t tried that.
– She has the preference in the morning on her toast, she will have a salty yeast.
– When she vomits she will vomit like rocket or not?
– I just comes.
– Normal vomiting but in the febrile convulsion yes she vomited like that.
– She was never a vomiting baby. It was only during the cough that she vomited.
– Have you noticed is she likes to eat something sour? Like lemon?
– No.
– She got a piece of lemon, we were in Skiathos for 2 weeks before we came here,
she put in her mouth and spit it.
– The outside of the lemon?
– The inside. And she threw that away pretty quickly.
– She likes her sleep.
– She sleeps a lot?
– She sleeps well at night.
– The other thing she has done is really grinding her teeth in her sleep.
– Does she eat fruits?
– Yes. She loves fruit.
– What kind of fruits?
– Anything. She doesn’t really like oranges because the pulp is too fussy.
– She sat with me on the beach yesterday and she ate a whole pear quite happily.
She eats plums, apricots, peaches, apples, bananas. She loves fruits.
What particularly annoyed us with the pediatrician,
at the conclusion his words to us was there is nothing more that we can do medically.
It’s educational problem go talk to the education people.
And his final sentence, you should hear this I’ve lived with you for 10 years I feel I know you,
was many people when they are told of this diagnosis go out and spend a lot of money on alternative ideas.
He said it’s a waste of money. That was his final word.
– I’ll see him in September again.
– Will you see him?
– Maybe.
– See him in 2 years and bring him the child and ask him...
I don’t really understand what has happened. And there is this misconception but...
– From a medical point of view?
– No, from homeopathic point of view, the way we look upon the cases.
Can I ask you some more private questions? How was sex between you?
Frequent, not frequent?
– In the first years frequent
but then my husband had a lot of travelling so it was like ships in the night.
– Not frequent.
– Do you know the day you had sex and she was born?
– Because it was not frequent we can say even the minute it was!
– Do you remember a special mood in which you were?
– Very romantic!
– Was it more need for real sexual contact?
– From you talk the other day can I remember when it was like when we conceived
and I really cannot. Do you remember?
– It was an afternoon; I was home from work and...
I seem to remember it was quite good!
– Do you remember if you were relaxed during the intercourse or tense because of any kind of anxiety?
– No.
– We had just discussed and accepted the children are not going to be part of our life.
So we were both concentrating about building our career.
We just accepted that children were not going to be our particular thing.
And then out of the miracle she arrives. It is 100% natural.
We took nothing, it just happened. It was fate.
Who knows? I don’t know.
There won’t be anymore, she is the only grandchild from either side of the family,
I’m 51 this year, my wife hides her age very well
and it is important that we give her the very best opportunity that we possibly can.
Because when she gets to be in her 18s maybe we won’t be around for her.
– What was the age that you became pregnant?
-41.
– We’ll see what we can actually. That’s enough.
– Thank you!
I just gave you an example of the research
to see how difficult it is to get the real facts in such a research.
Because this is usual, the memory is not so fresh and of course
and many people will not be able to spot the time exactly that was conceived.
Why we have this problem?
This problem is because I think of 2 reasons;
one is some hereditary predisposition and there is also another factor which plays a role
and which is well known in gynecology and pediatrics
that the later a woman bears a child the more possibilities we have for some kind of defects.
There are also a few things. The child is quite good-looking.
That means love was there but as said it is not the first year of love.
Analyzing this situation we come to the conclusion
that we have to treat something which comes as hereditary predisposition
which comes as a combination of the parents,
the ancestors and it is not going to be very easily and fast recovery.
But I do believe that if this child gets correct homeopathic treatment
can become a normal child by the age of 8-9.
But she will need good homeopathic treatment.
I would like to take this child 2-3 later to the pediatrician.
Today you did a very beautiful job!
I was surprised because I saw the remedy
and I said to him at the moment, let me see, and the remedy was absolutely there
but show them the symptoms on which this repertorization is based.
She is affectionate, curious, kissing, restless, desires to wonder,
strabismus, grinding teeth, vomiting on coughing, vomiting drinking cold water,
tottering gait, intense fever, eating after ameliorates, fruit desire,
milk desire, salt desire, gonorrhea suppressed? I didn’t hear that.
Learning to walk late. Who thought of this remedy?
– In the last semester of my pregnancy I could only have ice in my mouth
– During pregnancy she had a keynote of Verat. Look at this.
Desire for ice. Verat. people like to have ice cubes. She crunched them.
– My husband it was a cheap way to keep me happy because I it was only ice.
Because I didn’t crave anything else.
– Unbelievable! You see this very interesting story.
She was in a Verat. state and most probably the same remedy will do good to her.
I don’t take your case; you’re not in the list!
– I miss a little this late speaking of this child.
It’s tendency of Tub. or Agar. better by eating which is very strong for me.
4 years and not a sentence.
– But it is not just late speaking.
It is mental aberration, problem. She had Agar. and Tub.
– If the mother had become Verat. during pregnancy
what do you think would have happened if it was given to her because of the desire for ice?
– Then the child would have been born much healthier.
I may suggest because of that phenomenon that the child might have been born normal.
– I would have 2 questions; one is how many U/S had the mother during pregnancy?
– Mother, did you have any?
– I had a very early one in 9 weeks, the nuchal scan developed by a Greek professor.
– What’s his name?
–Nikolaides.
– He developed a test?
- Nuchal test. It’s a fold in the back of the neck.
– Explain to me what it is.
– To know if there is any problem with the child early on.
– Do they take some fluid?
– No, just visually they measure it.
– From the length of it they can decide whether you have a tendency to Down’s syndrome.
– It’s specifically for Down’s syndrome. What did they tell you?
– It was very good. I had the chance of a much younger woman having a normal child.
– Fortunately it’s not a Down’s syndrome case.
It’s a very interesting case that makes the prognosis even better
because it gives up the confirmation that our decision is really correct
and therefore makes the prognoses even better.
Take her with you to the doctor in September!
That is very important;
you don’t have to have aberrations and symptoms on the mental or the emotional level necessarily.
Symptoms can only be physical. The rest of the organism can be left intact.
It’s such a misunderstanding because all this came from misunderstanding of my teaching.
Where I first the essences some of my students thought George prescribes only on mental emotional picture.
This is not true. And then I had to undo all this.
And I said for God’s sake you always take the 3 levels
but sometimes the problem will be mental only, emotional only or physical only.
Or it may be spread in all 3 levels as well.
Don’t focus yourself to the idea that you will have to find a mental picture of Nux-v. or Lyc. or Phos.
You can get Phos. who will be not at all this social and who can be contacted easily.
The same way that you will get a Plat. who will not be interested in sexual act.
You may ask a Plat. how is your sexuality and she says it doesn’t exist or it’s normal.
It doesn’t have to have the picture to have all the symptoms of all levels
because if you try to find that you will be misled to phantasy.
You will leave facts and you are going to phantasy projecting;
he is afraid to give a lecture in public, why, but I have never given a lecture I don’t know.
No you are afraid to give a lecture
and you project some reason why he is afraid to give a lecture in public.
Because you want you want to make a mental picture of Lyc.
where they are afraid to give a public lecture.
Then you conjecture, you use your phantasy.
That’s not correct and you have to be very careful about that.
The greatest calamity for Homeopathy are this misunderstandings.
The way I have shown in all my classes I take into consideration the facts
and I put together the real information.
I remember here one of the time I had collected all the teachers.
You come and we discuss. Somebody presented a case, another presented a case.
There was a case of great claustrophobia. Different remedies were suggested.
One of the teacher gets up and says this is case of Arn.
Why Arn.? We don’t have any symptoms of it.
He says what I think has happened to this person is that
in his previous life he was a victim of an earthquake so the building fell
and hit her and bruised her and at the same time she was feeling claustrophobic.
In an earthquake, in a previous life she was claustrophobic and she was born and now we have to give Arn.
This is projection. Any remedy can be justified through these projections.
They tell me a patient was sitting there...
- He was clairvoyant. It was not a delusion.
– He did not claim to be clairvoyant
because we asked him some more questions to which he didn’t answer correctly.
Clairvoyance has no place in science.
Somebody was sitting there and he put a question and the patient goes like this.
You look? This is Staph.! Why Staph.? Because he closed up.
That kind of projection I mean.
You have to be very careful of people telling you such kind of things.
The result tells you. Do you have result and what kind of result?
Everybody in Homeopathy claims to have results.
Especially the Indians, some of my Indians friends claim they have 100% but what kind of result?
I said my God when my first got this idea 100% I said I’m in the wrong place!
Why do they call me to teach them? My results are much lower than 100%!