… Are you German?
– Yes, I’m German!
– I thought you were English.
–No, I am German.
– So, you are a medical doctor, you have been in Homeopathy for 19 years, so you have been treated by other homeopaths in Germany.
– Yes, one.
– Can you tell me what is your problem?
– My main problem is a very painful splenomegaly.
It’s 8 times as big as a normal.
– Why is that? Have they told you?
– They have done all the investigation, blood analysis but without result.
There’s no reason, they don’t know.
– Are you anemic?
– Yes.
– Severely anemic?
– Yes. I always was anemic but severely anemic I was when I had profuse menses and my hemoglobin was very low for years.
– The hemoglobin was very low?
– Very low.
– And did you ever had transfusions?
– Yes, I had about 10 years ago, for half a year I had every month a transfusion.
– So they don’t attribute this severe anemia to the fact that your spleen is large?
– Because they didn’t find any other reasons for this splenomegaly they said it’s the only reason, why the spleen is so enlarged.
– So you have pain as well?
– I have pain, not always.
It started 2 years before at night.
I had stitching pain all the time.
– Where?
– In the area of the spleen and especially when breathing in deeply.
It was very stitching and then I took China officinalis.
– What potency?
– 12 LM, every day for 2 weeks and after 2 weeks the pain stopped but I went on taking China. I took it for a year.
– Did it help?
– It helped perfectly.
– But you said this stitching pain started 2 years ago?
– Yes. Suddenly one night I woke and I had stitching pain when breathing deeply and I could not lie on the left side at that time during night.
– I see. So you said now your problem is splenomegaly with pain this means that pain continues?
– The pain is not always  but it comes and goes.
– And did raise the potency, did you take another potency of China?
– Yes, after one year I changed the potency and I took a 200C but it did not improve.
I waited for about 2 months and then I took 1M and it was a little better but not really as it was the first time.
– But you repeated 12 LM? How low potency?
– I took 12 LM about a year…
- Until it did not act anymore.
– Yes.
– So tell me your other problems.
I am always tired, exhausted and weak.
I have it because of the anemia but I’m very very weak especially in the morning , after sleep it
takes hours until I really have energy and it’s better in late afternoon about 16.00 or 17.00.
– After 16.00 and 17.00 or just between 16.00 or 17.00?
– Not between. It starts to be better at 16.00 or 17.00 and then it goes up.
The morning is always very bad.
The other problem I have; my menses have improved very much but still I am very weak when I have my menses.
I weep all the time but I don’t know why.
– Weeping during menses or before?
– During. And enormous weakness.
The moment it starts I am weak, I have to lie in bed and I cannot work.
– Next…
- 10 years ago I had this problem with the menses, then it got better but the last 2 months it’s a little worse.
It’s not as good as it was before.
Then I have cystitis very often.
I had it for the first time when I was 21, I remember.
Then I got for a long time antibiotics, then it was better and since about 3-4 years I have it after each coitus, I have cystitis the next day.
– The anemia started in very early age or it started later?
– I remember that I always was pale and weak and tired all my life.
I never had really a lot of energy but 10 years before when my menses were suddenly so profuse the anemia got much worse.
– Are you sleepy?
– Yes, I could always sleep.
– And you are very chilly?
– Very chilly, even in summer.
– What remedies have you taken except of China?
– Calc. 10 years ago...
– Ars.?
– No.
– 10 years ago Ign., Phos-ac., Lyc. and Lach. And 3 years before Phos. That’s all.
– Continue.
– My other problem is that 3 years ago that my friend left me, we went together 20 years and since then I never felt really happy again.
I am always very sad, I couldn’t overcome the relationship until now.
I weep easily when I talk about it, often I have dreams of our formal life.
I meditate why did I fail.
– Did you take Puls.?
– No.
– But you  are very chilly, still.
– Yes, I am very chilly.
It was even worse when anemia was worse, it’s a little better now but still I am chilly.
I forgot one thing.
Sometimes I have pain in my left kidney and doctor saw the CT and said that I have big spleen and it’s squeezing a little and so there’s congestion of the left kidney.
So it is suggested to operate the spleen but I don’t want to.
– Did you take after this separation Ign. or Nat-m.?
– I took Ign. but it did not help.
– Nat-m.?
– I did not take.
– Do you need extra salt in your food?
– No.
– Normal or even less than normal?
– Normal.
– But sweets?
– I like sweets, hot, spice food and wine. If I drink wine I feel better, I have more energy.
It refreshes me. I have to drink, not much because I’m tired, but I drink every day one glass of wine to feel good.
– Continue.
– No other problems. My main problem is the spleen.
– But you say also hay fever since…
- Oh! Yes, since I was a child I have it every year.
– And if you don’t eat regularly...
– I am very weak, I have to eat 3 times a day.
– Your nails?
– Break easily. Also, I cannot climb a mountain.
Even when I was 10 it was the same thing. I’m out of breath.
– You have aversion to milk.
– Yes, I have aversion.
– Very strong?
– Yes, I cannot drink.
– And meat?
– Not very strong but I don’t like it.
– Oysters?
– I hate. I could not eat.
– And fat?
– Also, very strong aversion. Not butter but fat.
– After this separation do you feel that you have closed up?
– Yes. I don’t speak to anybody, I don’t show my feelings.
– Also you didn’t want to cry here. You said that you wanted to cry here but you controlled it.
– Yes, I try.
- At the same time you tell me you are weeping a lot when you are alone.
Weeping during menses for instance…
- When I am alone I can weep.
– If I am familiar to somebody I can weep.
– Do you like to be consoled?
– Yes, I like it.
– How was your sexual desire?
– It was normal but when profuse menses started I was always weak and I had no desire due to lack of energy but normally it’s normal.
– The fact that you separated with your friend was due to your fault, he put it as if it was your fault or his fault?
– He put it to be my fault.
Nothing special happened.
But he had a strong desire for very young women.
He was 60 years old and he found a 20-year-old woman.
It was a sort of tick he had.
And he said I am too complicated for him because he was manager he had to travel a lot and I am very homesick always.
I did not want to travel with him and so we had a lot of problems together.
– You have always been homesick?
– Always. I remember when I was 15 I was homesick.
– And you have some fears?
– I have some very strong fears.
Fear of insects, beetles and spiders and fear of hospitals.
No other fears.
– Do you have dreams?
– Yes, always the same. I am living in a big house with a lot of windows and doors and it’s night and suddenly I feel that there’s somebody outside who wants to kill me.
I feel threatened and I try to close doors and windows but I cannot do it so quickly and he approaches and at this moment I wake up.
– Dreams of being pursued.
– Yes.
– This friend with whom you were 20 years together was the first man for you?
– No. But the cystitis started after him or before him?
– Before him. After my first relationship it started.
– The very first?
– Yes.
– The very first relationship of yours was he a womanizer?
– No. But the second who left me he was a man who was interested in other women all the time we were together.
But the first no.
– Do you know if the first had gonorrhea?
– No. But he (the second) had a gonorrhea.
– How do you feel near the sea?
– I feel very good and now I am in Alonissos for one week I am not tired.
Also I cannot sleep during night because it is so hot, I have fear of insects but I wake up in the morning and I am not tired.
It’s amazing.
– The climate is helping you.
– It’s good for me.
– You work as a homeopath or in a hospital?
– I work together with other 5 homeopaths, not in a hospital.
– Which area?
– In Munich.
– Can you describe your character?
– Yes. I never become really furious.
I am very soft, very mild, very compliant, I have desire for harmony.
It’s easy to live with me.
– But you think this is because you suppress your anger or your negative emotions or is it because your character is like this.
– No, it’s my character.
– And in spite of this you describe a case of Puls.
You describe your character as we describe it in the Materia Medica for Puls. Compliant, soft…
- I have a lot of Puls. elements.
– You said you are very chilly. But does draft affect you as well?
– It affects me but also when I am very chilly I have a lot of desire for fresh air, always.
And draft affects me.
– Very much?
– Not so much.
– Here you say you’re worse by change of weather. You feel it?
– Yes.
– And worse in the sun. In spite you’re chilly you are worse in the sun.
– Yes, I could never lie in the sun without an umbrella. I feel weak and exhausted.
– Full moon, cold and heat.
– Yes. I don’t sleep very well in full moon.
– You say I have a strong desire for protection and safety.
– It’s true.
For example, all my friends are 20-25 older than me because I am longing for protection.
– That’s why your man was also quite older.
– Yes.
– 20 years?
– Now he is 60… yes, 20 years.
– You like dogs?
– I love dogs.
– And you suffered very much when he died?
– Yes. I was really sick when he died.
– You had a kind of rape when you were 12?
– Yes. By a known person or unknown?
– A known person.
– This made you afraid of men? You cannot say… - I cannot say.
But it was a shock because at that time I was in monastery, in a boarding school and had no idea of what was going on.
So it was really a big shock what happened.
I was educated very strictly, very catholic.
– Also you have a desire for order and cleanliness and you feel easily disgusted.
– Yes.
– Former disease?
Tell us.
– At the age of 18 I had a tonsillectomy because when I was a child I had very often tonsillitis, very painful, every winter 2-3 times.
Then often cystitis, as I said.
At the age of 21 I had appendectomy.
When I was 8 adenoids were operated.
And between the age of 21 and 35 I had 4 times a miscarriage.
– You don’t have a child?
– No.
– 4 times you had a miscarriage?
– Yes, but involuntary.
And the profuse menses 10 years before.
In 1996 I had 2 times very severe inflammation of the lungs, 3 years ago.
– Your father died with Alzheimer disease at the age of 80.
– Yes, 2 years ago he died.
– Your mother suffers with headaches.
– Yes, since 40 years.
– You don’t suffer with headaches?
– Never.
– You have enough already!
–You eat meat?
– I ate because of my anemia but not because I like it.
I don’t like it.
– Not any kind of meat?
– I can eat chicken. No other kinds.
– Lamb?
– No.
– Pork?
– No. Not at all, I hate the taste.
– How much water do you need?
– I’m very thirsty, I drink about 2 lt a day.
– And it has to be cold or room temperature?
– It doesn’t have to be cold.
I like warm drinks.
But it depends on the season but it has not to be cold.
– At this period you are constipated?
– Yes.
Whenever I am travelling I am constipated.
Even if I am travelling 2 weeks.
I believe everybody knows the remedy.
Your nails are really brittle?
She said your nails are brittle. I want to know how much.
Do they really break?
– At the moment it’s ok but sometimes they break.
– They have white spots.
– No, it was a pressure.
– Her hands are very cold.
You did not tell us about your perspiration.
– When I am excited I perspire easily.
– Not when you sleep?
– Never in sleep.
– In this case you will have to differentiate between several remedies one of which is Puls., the second is Sil., the third is Med., the fourth is Nat-m.
These are the possibilities in this case.
Puls., Sil., Nat-m., Med. Whatelse?
Mang. is a possibility for this case.
Severe anemia, Mang. Somebody was asking.
Causes severe anemia and makes the person very tired and wants to lay down all the time.
By lying down Mang. feels better even in their anxiety, if they are depressed, they lie down and they feel better.
They have cough, they lie down and they feel better.
They have a pain, they lie down and they’re better.
Lying down is the essential feature of Mang.
Now, she wants to lie down all the time and sleepiness.
People without much hemoglobin they, easily become sleepy,
they want to sleep all the time.
The patient says I can sleep anytime.
The thing is which is remedy at this moment.
She has been through a kind of a grief, she does not show so much, but most probably she feels it quite a lot.
Correct?
– I want to ask a little bit more about the consolation.
She said she likes it but she’s a very closed person, eventually, if you are very closed you don’t like consolation.
So I’d like her to clarify that first.
– If I am very much familiar to somebody I like consolation but from people I don’t know never.
If somebody is very close to me…
- You will accept.
– The things that we have to consider is the remedies she took before.
Which of these remedies have acted?
China has acted, that means China was indicated and China did whatever it could.
After that there seems that all the other remedies used were not effective, left the case as it was with China, and even a bit worse.
After this we consider that China was the correct for the time she took it.
And now we have the next remedy to consider after China. China-related remedies;
China followed well by Ferr. is possibility, Calc-p. Complementary remedies to China is Ferr. Very good. Nat-m. is there as you can see.
Show the repertorization.
Now you will see the remedies that come up more prominent.
Is Nat-m., Ign., Puls., Ph-ac. Ph-ac. she received, there is no question about that.
So either you choose Nat-m., Ign. she took there was no real effect…
So you have actually to choose between Nat-m. and Puls.
Taken into consideration the great amelioration in the sea, Med. is possible because her husband had gonorrhea before.
So, we may consider.  Is the first remedy Med., Puls., or Sil.?
– What position do you sleep in?
– I sleep mostly on the back and my hands are upon my head.
– She is improved in the seaside.
– Alonissos has special vibrations which improve everybody!
I don’t think so.
I feel very tired here.
But in spite of that tell me your opinion.
Do you have another idea?
Do you want to give another remedy? Ferr.?
Let’s see who wants to speak for Puls. 21. Sil? Nobody. Nat-m.? 42. Med.? 2. Mang.?
No. Ferr.? 2. Plus one, me, 3…no.
In this repertorization I will put one more symptom and see what happens.
Which is this symptom I want to introduce?
Show the list of symptoms.
Weeping during menses, enlarged spleen three times, stitching pains on abdomen, copious menses, general;
afternoon amelioration , anemia. Anemia actually you have to introduce with 3 degrees, it’s a very severe anemia.
General weakness; three times, pain during urination, sleepiness, bladder pain after coition,
desires spicy food, alcoholic drinks, she actually said wine but anyhow.
You put it twice... ameliorates.
Extremities; nails, complaints; brittle nails, aversion fat, aversion milk,
homesickness underlined 3 times, fears of insects, fear going to the hospital,
dreams of being pursued, worse after coition, sea air ameliorates, mildness,
change of weather aggravates, exposal to the sun, mortification, tendency to abortion…
forget it, take it out. Rectum; constipation while travelling.
That’s it.
Show me now what is the result.
It’s Nat-m., Ign. and Puls.
Now we put one more symptom which she had.
– I’d like to put sleep; unrefreshing underlined 3 times.
Because she woke up very tired in the morning.
– She’s tired all the time.
But she is even worse then. Sleep; unrefreshing, in the morning.
Unrefreshing sleep or in the morning?
– More tired in the morning and then in the evening.
– So weakness in the morning .
– Morning, tired in the morning.
– Yes put this. How many times?
3 times. Tired in the morning. Mag-c. Put this 3 times.
– I’d like to ask a question about music, if it affects her and how.
– She likes music, she’s German!
– I like music very much, especially classical music.
– She’s not Tarent., she definitely.
She is the opposite of Tarent. Nat-m. again. Puls., Calc., Phos-ac…  Can you find it?
Sleeping with the hand over the head?
I want to put another symptom.
Which one?
She said about some kind of food she hates; pork.
– She said she hates oyster.
– Oysters and pork, so we can put both.
Aversion oysters and pork.
Put these two, twice.
Arms under the head or like this?
Over the head.
Can you find it?
2 times.
Put 4 times!
Forget it.
You have no chance!
Show me the result.
Still Nat-m. Useless!
So what is the problem now? Weeping?
She did not weep here.
She started but she controlled it.
This is more of Nat-m. tendency.
Nat-m. will hold it. Puls. will not be able to hold it so much.
So what is going to be the first remedy?
– I just have a question.
I asked if she had fever blisters and she does have that every year, once a year.
– Very good, put fever blisters.
Did you put worse from sun?
Good. Fever blisters; lips.
As you may see this repertorization is very fast but you have to balance in her case a few things which are in favor of Nat-m. and others which are in favor of Puls.
So the question is; is this a Nat-m. case on a deeper level?
You are asking this question.
All her symptoms are symptoms of Nat-m. as the repertorization is showing or maybe Nat-m. is on top at this moment and underneath is something else?
This is the problem which you have to solve.
And in favor of Nat-m. is what?
Tell me a keynote on which you will base your prescription on Nat-m.
Those who prescribed Nat-m. must speak now. Grief.
She has grief.
How she reacts to this grief?
Show me the grief remedies.
Let’s make a little bit of differential diagnosis. Aur., Caust., Ign., Nat-m., Puls., Staph. Capital.
– I would like to ask if she’s got any kind of hatred towards ex-husband.
What it has to do with hatred in general.
– Any woman who is with a man for 20 years and the husband left she would like to kill him. This is the natural.
You’ll see what she will say.
– No feelings of hate.
I feel no hate.
I feel sad.
– She mostly blames herself.
You have to be careful when your patient is giving you the history.
She said many times I weep alone or I stay and I meditate to see where I was wrong.
What did I do wrong.
Where is my responsibility. Grief. Ign. If she is meditating forget Ign.
She’s not for meditation, she’s for action.
Quick act, responses.
She will hate the bastard and she would like to take some revenge
and she will try different things for example appearing in front of him
with another boyfriend and then going home and hitting herself and going in to spasms
and reactions.
Then she will sob.
She’s not sobbing and she is not hysterical.
A similar but deeper reaction will be from Nat-m. Nat-m. takes life very seriously,
especially a relation which is ended is a very serious matter for Nat-m.
They will take it very seriously, they’re hurt.
They will go in bed and they cannot cry and the emotions stay here,
are choked there and some tears are coming out.
They try to cry, to relieve themselves but they cannot.
This is the typical Nat-m. reaction after breaking up. A Puls. reaction…
A Staph. reaction… you would like to hear?
Staph.; you have to take the consideration that Staph. in case we have exactly the same situation,
20 years living with a man and the man finally leaves, Staph. will be crying a lot,
we’ll be weeping all the time.
She will not be able to control herself, she doesn’t want to control herself.
And what is important, through this reaction she will not deadened her emotions
where Nat-m…. Let us say Nat-m. had 90% emotions.
In any case if you are a Nat-m. you have less than normal emotions.
The emotions have been reduced to 98% already.
But you have a relation which leaves you, then the emotions are reduced 50%
and sometime only 10% of the emotions stay.
All the rest is suppressed, swallowed and I am not going to show them again.
And then you see this hard emotional state in which you cannot penetrate
and if you manage to penetrate through talking and
communicating the characteristic is that…
Nat-m. you can open it and he can talk.
But afterwards we will go back home and he will have a terrible headache,
will be depleted from energy, will be terrible.
The fact that she has spoken is a great aggravation.
Because she spoke to you.
You think she will feel better now; no, it’s the opposite, she feels worse.
That is typical of Nat-m. Not with Staph. Staph. will be better and will feel easy
and the emotions remain.
Let us say if she had 95% emotions he will go up to 90% or 87%.
The emotions will be reduced very little.
The emotion together with the sexual desire are not easily affected.
They feel destroyed, they cry for long periods of time but the emotions are not dead.
This part of the human being is still alive and that is important where with Phos-ac…,
it’s one of the main remedies for grief, especially which comes after death,
loss of beloved persons. It’s paralyzed… it’s not the right word.
Exhausted in mind and body and emotions.
Primarily in the emotions.
The emotions just go dead.
With Nat-m. we have 45% emotions left.
With Ph-ac. we have 2%. Nothing.
So they reach that state of total indifference where they say I don’t care,
I don’t want to remember, they forget, the memory goes totally down.
They close up.
But they can tell you, they can communicate,
they can relate to you what was exactly the situation.
With Nat-m. it will be very difficult to accept that this man or woman left me.
You’ll see resistance in telling you.
If somebody comes and tells you this man left me, it’s either Staph. or Puls.
There is maybe some crying, or maybe not.
It’s so easy to say.
For Nat-m. and Ign. they are too humiliating for them,
for Ign. but especially for Nat-m. the humiliation element is tremendous.
They don’t want to be humiliated in front of you, in front of the class.
If somebody comes and tells you that my husband left after 20 years because ,
it’s almost a marriage, and she says I am a person that I need protection,
I’m soft, I’m easygoing. How do we describe Puls.?
She couldn’t have described better Puls.
What she described is a typical Puls. case.
What is the problem with Puls.?
The grief?
The grief of Puls. is there.
The sun?
The sun is there. The exhaustion?
The exhaustion is there.
She has all the symptoms.
And the pork she hates.
The way she sleeps is typical of Puls.
It is absolutely typical of Puls. sleeping with the hand over the head.
You don’t know that.
It doesn’t matter, I say it for those who doesn’t know.
Then the aversion to fat.
What else do we have for Puls.?
Better from fresh air.
In spite the fact that she is so chilly.
Let’s put chilly.
Show me chilly remedies.
What you may have been thinking is…
For a moment I thought this is a case where we first need to go to Sil. which is cold and then complement the Sil. action with Puls.
But the information as it was coming was overwhelming for Puls.
So the fact that she is on the cold side we have Puls. many times and especially in an acute situation, she chills but still wants to be fanned.
But she has chills. Puls. is not always a remedy which is very much aggravated by heat.
– But she likes to drink a lot. She is thirsty.
– Let’s see thirst. Warm drink.
This is a problem but thirst… see excessive thirst… extreme.
The problem is that she needs warm drink,
show me desires warm drinks. Ars., Bry. and Lac-c.
Here we really don’t have the Puls. Puls. has aversion.
– In the rubric desires warm drinks.
And hot is another rubric then Puls. is in the second degree.
– Spicy food.
This is not a problem.
Let us say the most prominent remedy for this lady is Puls.
There is no question.
My only question is before Puls. she needs a Med. or a Sil.?
This is the only question I’m asking.
Should we give before Puls., Sil. or Med. first?
Because of the amelioration.
We don’t have anything else except the amelioration from the sea.
We don’t have any other symptom to support Med.
Evening ameliorates perhaps.
– Did she get a splenomegaly after the transfusions?
– The splenomegaly was after the transfusion?
– The blood transfusion was in 1986 and the splenomegaly was 2 years before.
– The splenomegaly was 2 years before the transfusion but not even if it was after the transfusion.
If you go to the remedy, you can find remedies which affect the spleen especially.
Fer. is a possibility., Cean. is a possibility.
But when you have such a case where you have so strong symptoms for a remedy
you don’t go to such little remedies unless this  fails.
The problem is Puls. in what potency…
- Did you have any investigation on the red blood cells as sickle cell anemia?
– Blood analysis was made, everything was made and nothing was found.
– Like osmotic resistance and things like that?
-  The question we have in this case is can we reduce the spleen.
I believe yes, giving my prognosis for this case I say in spite of the fact
it looks quite serious the prognosis is not so bad and we will be able to reduce.
How long it may take?
I believe the time that she will need treatment is 3 years.
In 3 years you will have a considerable reduction of the spleen and of course a considerable amelioration of her usual case.
Now we go to the potency.
Always with the potency you ask yourself if the pathology
is going to be in the way of your potency.
That means the high potency will push the organism to go away
and start but if there is substantial physical pathology will stop this very soon
and will have a relapse.
Therefore, the fact that the spleen is not actually performing,
becomes bigger and bigger to comply with the demands of the body
and the spleen is not in a good condition.
Therefore the spleen will be an obstacle.
Therefore we have to go slowly into stimulating this organism.
The remedy is Puls. 12C.
It will be good enough given 3 times daily and try to raise the potency 12C like 13C after 10 days, every 10 days you raise one potency.
– I would like to speak against Puls.
– I spoke against but you can speak against also.
– Puls. is not in the rubric enlarged.
Her spleen is 8 times bigger than normal.
–Find anemia…
-  And then she’s very thirsty and I can’t see that this is a very clear Puls. case.
There’s a lot of Nat-m. there.
I want to speak for Cean.
Because in Phatak it says this remedy has a special affinity to the spleen,
which enlarges enormously.
Pain in left hypochondria.
Anaemic patients where liver and spleen are at fault.
Enlargement of liver.
And it is complementary to Nat-m. and related to Chin. which has acted.
So in this case I will consider Cean. strongly.
– Here anemia, if you look anemia, you see Puls.
One of the main symptoms which kent relates is anemic woman etc.
The fact that there is severe anemia the spleen is going to be affected so therefore
logically you can come to the conclusion that definitely Puls. will affect the spleen.
It doesn’t matter whether it has been recorded or not.
Somebody tell me has been recorded already…
So this is not against Puls.
Especially take notice of that; that if you have a picture of a remedy,
it doesn’t matter whether the remedy has produced the pathology.
You can give any remedy as long as it has the essential features
and in spite of the fact it has been recorded as having the pathology which you are treating.
Therefore this argument is not valid.
The second argument that Puls. is not thirsty, is not true.
It has been even recorded since in memorial that some times has extreme thirst.
So these are not arguments to take away from Puls.
– I have a reference. Enlarged spleen…
- In Hering.
Here you are!
So what do you say now?
Your argument is gone!
– Is it true that it doesn’t the remedy that covers the whole picture
doesn’t cover the full pathology if pathology isn’t far advanced?
I mean how far advanced is it?
It’s not destruction, is it?
And I wanted to ask to her reaction to her father’s death
because I still think possibly that there is a case you wouldn’t have given before Puls.
because the grief and her reaction to this is much stronger.
This may be a top layer. Puls. is maybe the next layer.
– I have not very good relationship to my father.
So his death was not a big problem for me.
– You cried?
– No. He was very strict and we had a bad relationship.
It was not a problem.
– That’s why she was attached to this man so much.
The dog to whom she had a relationship tell me how much you cried about your dog…
- I cried, I was really sick, I was really depressed, I needed Ign. and I cried for about 2 weeks.
It was terrible.
– Sometimes it happens with the very strict parents.
They’re too strict and the children severe the relationship.
Because the parents didn’t know the natural tenderness and affection
which is due to the children and therefore the children become rebellious and many times
they go to find other avenues of satisfaction which are today the drugs every youngster
is grabbing.
What is interesting in this case is the way she says she reacted to this particular stress.
She says she meditates to find out. Puls. is a mild individual.
Is not violent.
Even when Puls. becomes violent it is manipulative violence.
What do I mean?
I’ve described before.
Puls. wants attention and she doesn’t have the attention she needs and protection.
She feels neglected all the time and in order to create attention she may become violent
but what kind of violence?
They will take this and there is the man and she throws this there.
Not to hit me!
Will never throw it on the man!
Will just throw it next to him to show how upset I am.
This is what we call manipulation of Puls.
That means I am very angry, I want to attack you, you bloody bastard!
She could just do this and smash his head but she will not do it.
It’s not violent.
Is very sweet, easygoing, very easy to persuade etc. exactly as she describes.
With the aversion to pork you don’t need almost anything else!
Of course the fact that she says I am under grief the mind could go to Nat-m.
Then you say Nat-m. is not aggravated by sun?
Yes it is, Puls. also. But Nat-m. is a cold remedy?
No, it’s also a hot remedy.
But the desire for fresh air is characteristic more of Puls. than Nat-m.
The aversion to fat belongs to both.
But where is the desire for salt to support a Nat-m.?
I’ve changed and my change is that I need salty sardines.
If she had told me that I would say yes, Nat-m. Just because of the desire for salt.
Here we have this mild person.
But is this cold?
It is because she is anemic.
It’s symptom of her pathology to be cold. Anybody who is very anemic is cold.
But I didn’t hear anybody telling me that.
– You knew it!
– Yes, but are arguing. Puls. has to be hot and she’s not hot, she’s very cold etc.
But when you go to her pathology… find me an anemic person who is hot.
It’s not possible.
So it is pathognomonic to her pathology.
That’s why you don’t see the aggravation from heat but when it comes to the point
where the heat, the sun… forget it, I cannot stand one minute.
So you have to have an anemic remedy.
Which is it?
What is the problem?
Actually very little problem.
The only problem I accepted is the desire for warm (drinks) but even that has been recorded in Puls.
Therefore Puls. 12C 3 times daily.
Thank you!
He doesn’t like my prescription.
– I’ve a question. Do you think it would be likely she might need Med. later on?
How would you decide that?
– Maybe, maybe not.
Maybe she will not need the Med.
What is conducive for her at this moment is the temperature
which is the optimum for her blood.
Her blood has such a composition that this temperature suits better the organism
and that’s why she feels better.
Did you go to swim?
You felt good?
You liked it.
– What sign will you look for if she doesn’t move with the 12C?
And you either want to give a higher potency or change the medicine.
What will make you decide to push the potency higher or to alter maybe to Nat-m. or Med.?
– I will try a higher potency yes.
I will try first, if it doesn’t move at all, let us say within a month there is no change,
because with this low potency we expect later the results.
We expect the results to start after a month.
What will be the results?
The first thing she will feel is more energy.
That means if the blood starts being better the energy will rise.
So if she sees a rise in the energy cause this is what is lacking mostly
that means the production of the blood is of a better quality
and of a better quantity perhaps.
Therefore she will continue.
So, I believe within 3-4 months the energy level will be quite high.
If in 3-4 months there is no change then I will try the higher potency 200C,
in case there is no change then I will try a dose of Nat-m.
and if there is no change then I will try Med. And if there is no change I will try Ferr.
And if there is change from Puls., I believe she will finally go to Sil. So instead of Sil. -> Puls.
it will be Puls. -> Sil. Another secret I will tell you;
don’t be in a hurry to change the remedies.
Once you have studied a case so much and so thoroughly
and so deep you better stick to this remedy and don’t change…
There’s no effect, give another remedy, then you confuse the case.
– I just want to ask is it possible to change the potency of Chin., continue Chin.?
– There is a possibility that in case after Puls. there is an improvement
and at a certain period after a year there is a big bleeding
and this big bleeding cannot be controlled by Puls.
Most probably maybe go back to Chin. where she will need
a dose of Chin. 200C or 1M to counteract the bleeding and then go back again to Puls.
You see there are different possibilities which we cannot predict beforehand.
It’s not possible.
– What I wanted to say and I forgot; since about 10 years I’m taking chemical drugs Ferrum.
And Puls. is a remedy for abuse of taking Ferrum for long time.
– And since you are taking Ferrum you have to control your blood
and see if your blood count, the hemoglobin improves
then you can reduce he Ferrum until you almost take it out.
“Chlorotic girls”, was the old term.
It’s a wonder that nobody gave her Puls. because she was feeling cold.
That was the main reason.
Nobody thought that this is because of her pathology.
If it is pathognomonic of her pathology you can’t help it.
Let’s say you get somebody with diabetes mellitus and you have a very high degree of thirst.
Can’t you give a thirstless remedy?
Of course you can give a thirstless remedy because it’s the pathology
which creates the need for water.
Of course you can give Puls. in diabetes mellitus
in spite of the fact that there is a lot of thirst.
It’s as easy as that.
– I was wondering about the pathognomonic symptoms but there are other
pathognomonic symptoms that we took in the case like the weakness
which is an obvious symptom of anemia and other symptoms.
So, if you feel like talking about the differentiation when you take a symptom
that is pathognomonic obviously and you can’t or you don’t rely on it…
- We did not prescribe Puls. because of weakness.
If I have said I give Puls. because of her weakness or, in a different way,
I give Stan. because of her weakness.
That would be wrong. If I had prescribed Stan. or Ph-ac. because of her weakness
this is wrong because as you say this is pathognomonic,
you make take into consideration in your repertorization because these remedies…
You see all anemic remedies will produce weakness there is no question.
You can take it into repertorization but you cannot say because of weakness.
But you can say I give her because she is soft, mild, crying,
desire open air in spite of the fact she’s s cold and aversion pork and fat.
Because of these I give Puls. because all these are not pathognomonic,
they are the characteristics of her remedy.