Here again is something which I have said many times that the correct remedy has been given
but then it spoiled by several other remedies that are given wrongly.
This woman has been raped, she got a very big fright,
she almost lost her mind and she started Ign., a little bit
and then some other remedies with no much effect
and then she comes to the right remedy and she takes Stram.
After Stram. she will develop certain things.
Nobody can be 100% well after the remedy.
You have some things but you have to evaluate the amelioration
against the new things that are developing.
If the amelioration is good you just don’t touch the case.
So, all the other remedies after Stram. are mistakes.
It doesn’t mean because she comes to you
and as a homeopath that you have to give necessarily a remedy something
which is the practice of almost everybody.
Everybody thinks if I give a remedy now you will be much better.
No. You have to evaluate.
That’s why I am taking it so carefully what happened... I took this and that.
When did it happen? And then I see the gap 1993-1995 no remedies.
That means this woman was peaceful inside. There is a big turmoil.
Stram. is not a simple remedy, it has subconscious which is loaded with darkness.
And when it goes away this darkness and aggression and the person is peaceful you wait.
So even when she came here if you see the whole
and then you see the analysis I came to the class and said no remedy.
In spite of the fact she still says most of the time I don’t have these mood swings.
I said wait because she is still in a quite good condition.
Wait is the right prescription, not to give a remedy
because she comes to the big master and the big master gives another remedy, no.
It’s not like that.
You don’t have to prescribe a remedy if the organism is in a state of balance.
Can it be better balanced?
If you have a very clear picture you may try otherwise you must say wait.
So the analysis of the case into the class was wait because she says 98% of the time I am well.
2% of the time I may have this mood swings.
Still the effect of Stram. from 5 years ago is there
in spite of the fact its action has been reduced by several wrong remedies.
That was the evaluation during that time,
wait and we would like to see now what has happened after this waiting.
Waited for 1 year with no remedy. Unless she has taken a remedy herself.
Not necessarily if you take a remedy yourself is always wrong. It can be right.
Last time I saw you we said no remedy and what happened after this.
– I’d like to use a few notes.
– Try to tell me whatever you remember and after you can consult your notes.
– After I had no remedy I got quite an aggravation the same day.
Everything was amplified. It was very extreme.
First I found it very disappointing that I didn’t get a remedy.
– You got angry with me?
– Yes.
Because I honestly thought that there was something that could help me.
I understood the reasons why afterwards,
I realized it was probably a good prescription not giving me a remedy
but still felt there was something that could have helped.
Makes things a little easier for me. The aggravation that I had was...
I just came completely overwhelmed in the evening
and it was actually the evening of the party here and I got very emotional
and an outburst, really upset, crying and I felt like my world had just collapsed.
Everything had been taken away and I had a massive anxiety attack.
Things that we have been talking about have been right to me...
- Did you become violent?
– Yes and no. Nothing unusual.
I feel sorry for my partner at the time, I got a bit nasty and really stormed off, really erratic.
I just wanted to leave immediately. Unreasonable. I couldn’t reason my thoughts.
I felt calmer the next day and what was unusual had four dreams in a row, four nights, four dreams.
– Which were about?
– The first, it was the first night I’d gone home to Manchester and it was a most unusual dream.
I dreamed I was in Alonissos and I haven’t actually swam into the caves here in the bay
but I dreamed I was swimming into the cave and it was beautiful,
everything was beautiful and sunny,
I went in the cave then all of the sudden things changed and got dark
and I was aware that the tide is coming in,
a big tide and when I tried to get out of the cave I realized that I was trapped
and my arm was trapped between two rocks and the more I tried to struggle
the more I got worried I was going to drown, I couldn’t escape.
I paralyzed, the feeling I had, I couldn’t move and the tide was coming in.
And I started to scream. I woke myself up screaming.
Before I were caught I became well aware that my arm was trapped,
felt the water was coming over me and I realized my arm wasn’t trapped but I couldn’t move it.
It wasn’t trapped but I couldn’t move it but I felt it was too late.
I woke up then screaming. The next three nights I had a dream which was repetitive.
I was in a car and although I was driving the first night,
I was going very fast and there was traffic approaching...
I was definitely in the driver’s seat
but I wasn’t controlling the car and this car was in front of me
and I could see and I couldn’t do anything about it.
I was going to crash and I felt paralyzed, I couldn’t do anything about it
and I didn’t know I could do anything and then just before it happened I realized
I was in the driver’s seat and I could have stopped it but I didn’t.
And that was the time I woke up screaming.
I had the same dream for two more nights but it was different each time.
The second I was driving again, same road, same obstacle came in front
and this time I realized I was driving and I tried to lift my right leg to put it on the break
and I couldn’t lift it and I started panicking cause I couldn’t lift my leg, so still paralyzed.
And in the crash I woke up like it happens.
On the last third of the repeated dream it was different. I was driving.
This time I saw something approach, I knew I was driving,
I knew I had to lift my leg to put on the break and I couldn’t
and I was fighting to and I managed to lift my leg
and I felt that I actually moved my leg and managed to stop it before it happened.
That was the last time I had a dream. I haven’t had any dreams like that since.
– You did not have any more dreams like that?
– No. I went over what happened with these dreams.
I did think about them very deep because it was quite strong.
I was interested it was all about realizing I thought I was trapped
but I couldn't do something, I was paralyzed, I couldn’t move my arm and leg.
And in the end I did. That was quite strong actually.
Apart from that things have improved a lot and after that anxiety attack
which happened here I’ve not had anything so strong and things have seemed to be a lot better.
That was a strong feeling; paralyzed.
What I have noticed and perhaps I didn’t mention it last year
for a few years now I felt that my mind sometimes gets paralyzed as well.
I sometimes if I had to make a decision I feel overwhelmed, paralyzed
I won’t go with anything decision and I’ll just stay where I am knowing
that it might be something smaller or large, I have been doing that recently, I’ve improved
but now I realize in my thinking, at projects there are loads of things I wanted to do,
were piling up and don’t know where to start, so I wouldn’t start,
I just look for new things to think about doing I wouldn’t deal with the things I have.
– Then after July things were quite good?
– Yes. I had a lot going on, as well.
I think that helped me because I had so much I had to deal with.
I didn’t have so much time to focus on worrying about not doing things.
I did take a remedy myself.
– When?
– I took it in October, I took Verat. 10M.
– How did you feel after that?
– I felt it did me well in a sense that in the back of my mind
one of my biggest fears used to be I wanted to be strong mentally
and because of my mother I always had a fear.
And my mother was showing more and more signs of Verat.
and I just felt that underneath maybe there is a little root of that.
Some my behavior in the past and my thinking could have easily developed into that kind of way.
As I child I was a very big thinker.
– You used to think that  you may go crazy?
– Yes, that was very strong!
– And still it is a fear?
– No. That’s gone completely now. I feel very stable.
The last 6 months I don’t feel vulnerable and emotionally unbalanced as I have been in the past.
I feel I have got to another level.
– You feel you are much better than before.
– Yes.
– Did you take another remedy?
– No. I took it once.
I have taken just one of the remedy but it was for a proving so I took it once.
That was in February. It was an proving remedy that belongs to the lily family.
Plant. I had symptoms but they seemed to come and go
and I don’t think it was any detriment to taking...
- Did you write down the symptoms during that time?
– Yes. I have got some of the symptoms here.
Did you mean with the remedy or the proving?
– Proving.
– I felt very well on it, very relaxed.
I was very calm and I didn’t repeat it like people in the proving did.
I took it because I wanted to experience the atmosphere.
– You did not belong to a group where you were doing the same thing?
– Yes.
– Who was doing the proving?
– It was through the college so I just wanted to take part to it, taking the remedy.
But I don’t feel it was detrimental in any way.
In fact it was interesting that I didn’t real I made the connection with Verat.
and the remedy that belonged to the lily family.
The only remedy I had was when I was away and I was quite ill
when I was in Africa in February and that was Nux-v. 30C.
I think I got 2 30C but it was good.
It helped me physically and also in my state of mind.
– Do you have any salivation during night?
– No, I don’t now but I used to have.
I went through a time for about 2 years when I was every night.
But for the past 2 years I haven’t been having.
– And it was quite strong before?
– Yes. It’s funny because I had never had it before.
I noticed I had it for a 2-year period and never had it before then.
– Where you having any treatment for your teeth then?
You had amalgam?
– No.
– Are you grinding your teeth at all?
– I don’t think so.
– You still need warm drinks or this is gone?
– Yes. This is interesting, I still like warm drinks and I am still a chilly person
but I am not as cold as I used to be.
I used to be extremely cold, icy cold really, especially legs and arms.
– But what about warm drinks?
– I love warm drinks. Even here I like hot drinks.
I have occasionally water but I like coffees and teas.
– That means you cannot drink cold drinks?
– I drink both.
To be honest I can drink many drinks at the same time.
I usually have a tea, a coffee and water at the same time.
– You still drink coffee, tea?
– A lot.
– You do not know that if you drink coffee it antidotes?
– I mean coffee substitutes. I’m not on an official remedy for a long time!
– Are there official remedies?
– I wasn’t prescribed a remedy. I do drink coffee but I drink it very weak.
– How is your fear of the dark?
– It’s ok.
– You don’t have much fear of the dark?
– No.
– Fear of disaster?
– Fear of insanity, you said no. That’s gone.
– The desire to kill somebody? Are the impulses coming?
– I don’t think I have that anymore.
– It doesn’t come from time to time that you want just to throw things?
– No. What I do get is I do get intolerant sometimes,
I get annoyed of things that aren’t done properly.
– This fear that you had not to be looked at?
How is that fear? You did not want to be looked at.
– It’s funny I never thought it since last year.
I don’t think it’s there anymore.
– Sometimes getting malicious?
– I can be snappy.
What I have noticed, a big difference is that
if I feel something I will say it quicker now, if I am upset will say something.
And what I have been doing is that I do feel if something is bothering me I will talk about it.
I’ll probably get snappy first, say something to get the storm off
but I will come back and talk about it.
– Are you awkward handling things? Dropping things...
- I was for a while. I hadn’t noticed it recently but I did notice past 2 years.
Sometimes I felt a little bit disorientated. Uncoordinated sometimes.
– Did you have some things dropping out of your hands?
– It wasn’t that bad but I used to have a problem with picking something up.
My mind would race ahead and was holding something else.
My mind was too fast and I forget what I would do with something.
I know it’s very common but I used to do that a lot.
Had two thoughts at the same time.
– Can I ask you something a little bit embarrassing?
What am I going to ask you? Have you got any idea what I am going to ask you?
– No, I don’t know.
– Nothing comes to your mind?
– No.
– I want ask you why you have your hair cut covering your face?
Why do you think you have this hair style where your hair is covering your face?
– I didn’t think I had actually!
– It’s natural. It just falls by itself there?
You don’t comb your hair like this?
– It is habit. I used to have a very big hobby of doing this.
– But why are you doing that?
– I supposed to hide.
– How long have you been having this hairstyle? Since you were 18 or 19?
– It’s quite a long time. I used to put it up a lot and pull my hair back.
I didn’t use to have a fringe.
– When did you change to that?
– Probably it would be around then. 20sh maybe.
– But do you remember this came together with some sexual desire
which was increased during that time? You got more interested in boys?
– Yes, probably around that time. Could be.
– What are your notes?
– Basically it was just the remedies. I think I am much more focused on things.
I still have this feeling.
I can live with it but I believe it’s down, I can’t throw it off.
I have this feeling sometimes that there is still a shadow looking,
waiting sometimes for me to trip up,
grab me back and pull me back to these heavy, dark days I was in.
I don’t feel I have moods. I am not a moody person.
Things are very good for me now,
quite bright and happy but it’s like I allow sometimes thoughts of shadow.
Just overwhelm me but it tries to make me think about the past
and I don’t need I feel to think about the past...
I spoke last year a lot about having to get things right and the fear of getting things right.
I used to be frightened of not getting things perfectly right.
And that’s has gone a lot.
I feel a lot better but I still have this fear that any minute something could happen and be all finished.
It can creep up me sometimes. It’s nowhere near where it used to be. Much better.
But I was only thinking a month ago that it would be lovely to be rid of this feeling
because it’s not needed anymore. It’s gone away so it’s not interfering with my life.
But it just takes the edge of things sometimes.
Commits me see for the negative.
Worry that things are going to go wrong, unnecessarily sometimes.
But I am really a very positive person.
I am very happy with how things are going. I got a lot to do.
But I always believed it’s possible to be 100% good,
I don’t mean perfect but 100% right for yourself so you put your heart and soul to everything.
One trick I do, I’ve realized this,
when I have the feel that things are clouding up I try and clear them,
I want like a fresh start.
So in my mind every day I try polishing things
so every little incident may be creeping in from the past
or things aren’t quite right I try to look at them from a new perspective.
It’s something to start a new morning. I feel like I carry unnecessary things with me.
– Your father is still alive?
– Yes, he is.
– He was fond of you especially?
– He was. Like salt of the earth.
He is a proper, good, typical father figure but he never showed what he felt much.
– But he was protecting you, pampering you?
– I think he loves me very much but in fatherly way protective.
We never really used to talk about things.
He was very practical.  Never encouraged.
I don’t mean it in a negative way, he’s genuinely wonderful man
but he will look for the negative in some things.
Whatever I do he wouldn’t say that’s good, he’d say that wasn’t right.
So he would always look at the fault.
– When you work, are you working continuously or in jerks,
that means you have some energy, you do things and then you are exhausted?
– Jerks. My energy is in little packages. I need a break.
– If you’re very angry how will you react now?
Shout, throw things, throw a tantrum?
– There are 2 ways.
– Do you have tantrums? If you want something and you cannot get it?
– I have 2 reactions to things now.
I try and I say ok I won’t let this bother me and deal with it.
Sometimes can do that and then I am very pleased with myself.
Other times I just can’t help it.
Before I can even control it I storm off and then 5 minutes after I finished.
And then I can come back and talk about it.
I do have a habit taking things the wrong way.
It’s when I react over the top, unfairly.
I told about sabotaging things last time.
I feel sometimes I test people unfairly, I don’t mean to,
I torment them all, not every one I just mean people closer to me perhaps.
I deliberately do things trying to get a reaction I am waiting for reaction that I can react.
It’s like something so I can say “I’m bright.
It’s not as good as I thought it was” and back out.
I’m always looking for an escape. I always used to do that.
An escape route. It’s there underneath, I think.
If I am upset I won’t deal with something. I’m off.
It’s very childish. But I’ll come back and talk about it.
– Ok. Thank you.
Here we have one of those cases which you don’t have a clear picture.
You don’t get either because we don’t know enough about Homeopathy
or we don’t know much about the patient or the patient cannot really express how is feeling
and therefore there is a kind of confusion concerning this case.
From what she says in words we cannot really get anything tangible.
You can hardly get any symptom. What you can get it by observation.
We can use the observation of how she talks, how she feels without her saying that.
She uses a kind of speech which is jerky, jumpy and there is an inner excitement.
I feel this kind of behavior belongs to a person who has quite a lot of hysteria.
It’s a hysterical person, she go off in a hysterical reaction
in case she is pushed a little bit harder than usual.
From that point of view there is a remedy that may fit this case and with great reservation.
We could use this remedy to see if such a remedy could give what she wants.
What she needs is more balance, more grounding.
She feels that all these which are happening inside
and bring to her this excitement is not really good though she says I am quite good.
You feel something is lacking in order to be completely balanced.
She is still battling to bring balance in herself.
As you can see she tries to impose balance upon herself
because the organism is excited and working too fast.
So, we need a remedy that fits such a pathology.
Where can you find it? It doesn’t exist!
Has anybody an idea? You have an idea. I cannot treat my wife! He can!
– Cof.
– That is the delusion of the husbands.
Forget a husband can see his wife objectively. I have the best wife, always.
Cof. is a good prescription but not for this case.
Tarent.? Tarent. or Tarent-c.? Tarent.!
Are you sure? Wrong! It’s not Tarent. Tarent. is totally different.
Bell. Why? Desire to escape. She is too pale for Bell.
Too hysterical.Bell. are much more down-to-earth.
They know what they are talking about. There is a kind of awkward ness.
I want to read from M.M. a few phrases to tell me if you hear this case is fitting?
“Fits to hysterical women with sensitive nature.
Feeling of coldness. Shuddering, nervous laughter. Excitement. Suppression of menses”
I did not investigate that.
“Hurried tremolous and awkward. Best in activity, activity in jerks with weakness alternate.
Violent anger. Talks excitedly. Scolds.
Uncontrollable laughter. Desire for black coffee.
Chest oppression, hysterical spasms of the chest, anxious palpitations, fear of death.”
What is the remedy? Show them the repertorization. I did not get it myself.
I got it from the computer and this is a remedy that fits mostly, not exactly.
Mosch. has these frightful dreams, dreams of being drowned, nervous laughing,
gestures, involuntary motion of hands and the speech is hesitating, abrupt, hasty, with jerks,
all this makes one symptom and the malicious you just put it once, I am not sure.
Hyos. and Mosch. comes as a second prescription.
So if she had admitted that she wants to kill we go to Hyos.
If she does not admit that she wants to kill her husband then we go to Mosch.
She has to decide and resolve for us the dilemma right here!
The moment she will really change level, she has been affected by Stram. as we said,
you will see changing her hairstyle. The hair will go back.
She is hiding from herself, from others, she is too shy, too sensitive to be shown,
allow others to see her, she is afraid others will not like her.
She does this unconsciously. You don’t belong to this category.
She is much stronger. Mosch. or no Mosch.?
– You’re the boss!
– I’m the boss...
I feel there is quite a lot of hysteria and what impressed me is the laughter.
If we put the case and replay you will see how many times the laughter comes,
the tendency to come in a jerky way. Nervous laughing.
I cannot replay but you can put back the case and I can show you again and again.
Who remembers this? Who saw the nervous laughter?
There is a kind of consensus that her laughter was a little bit out of context.
This is the tendency of the person and this is what observation should do.
Your observation is there to see the way she speaks because you cannot get really tangible symptoms.
She is I am better in everything except of one thing.
– George, what about the destructiveness?
– Mosch. has that. My problem with Hyos. as completing the action of Stram.
was that in Hyos. first of all you need the real desire to kill.
They are not killing but the desire is there.
The desire to kill this, this and that person.
Also the impulse to kill comes with Merc. as well. Merc. most probably
was indicate in a stage 2 years ago with the excessive salivation
and most probably Merc. having different impulses she may been benefited by it.
Now, it’s not yet the time for Merc.
So if you we give Mosch. and after it we see that the salivation starts coming back,
most probably her organism is preparing for a Merc. state.
Hurried. Tremolous. Excitement. Talks excitedly is exactly what she does.
She is trembling all over.
Do you realize you tremble all over? No, you don’t.
You think you are calm now? You are not that excited.
What do you say Mr. husband?
– It’s impossible to treat your wife!
– But usually you can give some information.
You think it is a good remedy, you agree with that?
What do you think? She is calm now? Do you call it ‘calm’?
– Yes, before the storm! What shall we do?
– 30C.
– So high? You are so courageous. Ok. She doesn’t like this remedy, it is obvious.
I have something very important to say here.
She was here and she said she had an aggravation after we made an analysis,
no remedy, in the night she goes in tantrum.
She calls is ‘an aggravation’ and then an amelioration.
This is how things are misunderstood and misinterpreted.
When you expect a remedy and you don’t get a remedy you get angry and you have to get out of your anger.
Your anger finally comes out, it’s expressed,
she said by that time she could not control myself,
I did not know what I was thinking and doing all these kinds of things
and reactions and next day she was better.
This is NOT an aggravation.
Let’s say we had given a remedy and this reaction took place.
How would you explain it?
You would think that the remedy had acted, there was an aggravation and then an amelioration.
That’s one misunderstanding.
Second misunderstanding is that she says I saw 4 dreams with a pattern.
If we were doing a proving especially a dream proving
who would not believe that these dreams were because of the remedy?
This is how the misunderstanding comes
and how all these super nonsense are coming on the Repertory and the M.M.
You give one remedy to the whole class and you say tell me tomorrow all your dreams.
And one says he had a dream riding his bicycle and the other one had a dream with a goat
and someone had a dream with a tree with two branches.
Everyone is belonging to the same remedy because the dream means he is pursued by the devil
because devil has two and the motorbike has these 2 and the goat also has these 2.
Therefore the general theme is pursued by the devil.
That is what is going on now in proving of remedies.
Not only that but this section all has placebo and all this section has the real
and they see some dreams which fit with the dreams of this group
and they say that’s even better this group confirms
that this pursuing of the devil is really correct and belongs to the remedy.
Instead of saying if these people have the same dream with this group
that means this symptom must not be taken into account.
It belongs to placebo. It is accidental.
You cannot say it belongs to the remedy once it also appears in the placebo group.
But you cannot make a proving in one night and you don’t have to take the remedy, the powder,
you put it over the head or under your pillow,
you sleep on the pillow and if you see a dream that dream belongs to the remedy.
You have to be aware of this kind of proving and not take it seriously.
I criticize provings which are done in such a superficial way as to give a remedy
and sleep over and tell me tomorrow night what is your dream
and then they believe that the dreams you saw are because of the remedy.
It’s not because of the remedy. It’s because of a thousand of conditions.
I will talk a little bit about the provings and I will tell you what is my ideas
but Paul Herscu one of the good American homeopaths is writing a book
on proving on which I gave my views.
So, if you really want to see my views on proving this book will come out
and you can read but I will tell you a few things
because it is a very important issue that is confusing us for the moment
because a lot of people say let’s do a proving. It’s not so simple.