This is a case that comes from Denmark.
She is 33 years old, has 3 children, she says I am very sick
and I fell that I am not inside my body. This is the main complaint.
I am never happy, I am tired and I feel I want to fall down.
I have been sick for about 10 years.
You have been sick with this coming out of your body.
– Yes.
– You come out of your body and this makes you fearful?
You are afraid?
– Yes.
– What else?
– I feel like my body goes away from each other.
– Is pulling out.
– Yes and I feel that side wants to go this way, that side wants to go the other way.
And I feel my mind is not here. I have to concentrate very much to be there.
– One thing I have to tell you, if you tell me a lie, I’ll make a mistake.
– Of course I know that.
– Because I asked you in the beginning if you have taken homeopathic remedies and you said no.
Then we found out that you have already taken Thuja 1M.
3 times, Thuja 6X, Thuja 12C and you have also taken a complex of remedies.
– I didn’t mean to lie, I forgot it.
– Ok, you didn’t mean to lie but I am warning you
that if you give me a wrong information I’ll make a wrong prescription.
It will not be my fault. The first thing I want to ask,
you come from Denmark, have you taken cannabis?
Have you tried cannabis, hashish, marijuana?
– Yes and pot.
– It’s the same thing?
– Not the same but close.
– Which is the strongest?
– I think hash.
– And since what age you started taking hashish?
– 13.
– These symptoms you are suffering now from, for 9 years, you are 33,
you are actually suffering from the age of 24.
From the age of 24 your body comes out, correct?
– Yes. I have to tell you something.
It has not happened from one day to another.
– Gradually, more and more.
– Yes. I don’t remember how it happened because that went slowly.
There were other symptoms before I felt I am out of my body
but I cannot remember now how it is to be inside my body.
It’s normal for me now to be like that.
It is not normal but I don’t remember how it was before.
I don’t remember exactly because it was so long ago.
– When you started using hash, you did it every day or 3 times a day or 5 times a day?
In the beginning you got once and then slowly you took more?
– No, it is not like that. In the weekend if I want to have fun.
I don’t take it the other days because I need to control certain things.
I take it with my friends to have fun and we sit together
and we smoke hash, laughing and everything...
- What was your reaction when you smoked hash?
– I am laughing. But I stopped because one day I was not laughing any more.
– Did you see some illusions?
– No.
I don’t see anything but one day, somebody opened the window.
I wanted them to open it because I was very hot
but when they opened the window I started to become cold and I wanted to close it.
I was telling them all the time to open and close it.
Every time they opened it I started to feel very cold
and when they closed it I started to feel very hot.
– And that made you stop taking hashish?
– That and another time where I drank alcohol and used hash in the same time.
I remember I was in a disco and I walked and the door started to appear smaller, coming to me...
- You thought you would suffocate.
– Yes.
– Did you ever feel that you are getting crazy?
– When I smoked hash?
– Yes. Or later on in these 9 years.
– Yes.
– All the time you have this fear?
– Not when I smoke hash but sometimes I feel I’m getting crazy.
– You say here you went to many doctors, you spent all your money but still you are very sick.
I cannot live a normal life, I don’t like to be with people and I cannot have a job.
I try to be strong for my children and give them a normal and good life as possible.
I remember that time I was inside my body and I was not sick.
I was happy and I liked life. Now I just survive.
I long to be normal and have normal life like everybody.
I want to be a good mother and I hope to have a job so I can give myself and my children a good life.
I hope you will try to help me etc.
– I want to tell you something.
I help myself a little, I am better than before.
– How?
– I studied flower medicine, Bach flower.
– And you practice?
– Yes. And I help myself a little but not completely
because maybe is difficult for me to look after myself.
– You are divorced? You divorced with your husband or you were never married?
– I am married now for the first time.
– So the 3 children you have are with 3 different men?
– Yes.
– When this happens you feel that one hand is going out and another foot is going out
or from the solar plexus, from here it goes out?
– It’s not going out. I feel one side wants to go out.
I can’t relax. I fell tense always and sometimes it’s difficult to breathe.
– She feels tightness and tension.
– And sometimes I feel it difficult to breathe.
– For instance you go to bed to sleep and there you leave your body
and you go out and you roam around the room.
– No, not like that. I just feel my soul and my body are not complete.
They are not in harmony with each other.
– They are separated.
– Yes.
– But do you see sometimes while you are awake like this,
you see some pictures?
– No.
– Never? You hear voices?
– No. When I was a child I saw but not now.
When I was a child I heard voices. When I was a child I saw things in the room too.
And when I was a child I was very much afraid of many things.
Sometimes I was afraid that my mother would kill me.
– What else?
– I remember I slept in my bedroom, I was afraid
because I was seeing things in my room and was afraid.
I don’t know what it was but I was very afraid.
I went to my mother and I wanted to sleep beside her on the floor.
But I was afraid of my mother too.
I had in my mind she wanted to kill me.
– Do you remember if there was a thunderstorm?
– No.
– Thunderstorm is when the rain comes and then there are some noises.
– I am not afraid of thunderstorms.
– By that time as a child you remember if you were afraid of thunderstorms?
– No. I don’t remember that. I was afraid if there was peace and silence.
– And if the room was dark?
– Yes, very much afraid. Now I sleep with a light on.
I don’t sleep in the darkness. Sometimes I feel somebody is behind me.
I stand in my kitchen and I make food and I get shocked
because I feel somebody is next to me but here is nobody in the room.
But I feel someone is there and I am afraid.
– But do you have an idea of it is a priest or a bad man who wants to do harm to you?
– I think that there is something bad
because if I felt it was something good I wouldn’t be afraid.
I am very much afraid and I get a shock.
– When you feel this presence.
– Yes.
Sometimes I get a big a shock too when my children and husband are coming.
– The moment they come in.
– Yes.
Sometimes if I sit on a sofa or something I feel there is something underneath.
– That wants to pull you from underneath?
– Yes. My father did many stupid things to me.
If I was swimming in the water my father would take my legs and pulled me down.
He swam behind me. You understand what I mean?
When I was a child when I got to the water to swim in the swimming pool,
my father swam behind me and grabbed my legs and pulled me under the water.
I think I have shock from that too.
And sometimes he took his hand on my nose and my mouth so I could not breathe.
– Do you remember if as a child you were very angry and you expressed anger?
You hit your sister, brother? Do you have a brother?
– I have a sister.
– Do you remember hitting your sisters?
– No. When I was a child I was very nice, everybody had told me that.
I was too nice. I didn’t show my own feeling.
I was thinking very much about other people.
I always liked children and people.
If my father did something to me I didn’t tell to my mother, I wanted to hide my father’s mistake.
– What do you mean? Your father did something wrong?
– Yes, for example sometimes if my mother was out he hit me.
– And you didn’t tell.
– No.
And when my mother was coming home I would like to tell her
but I told myself it was a lie, that it was my mistake,
I lie, so I didn’t tell anything to my mother.
I have a tension today, sometimes if something happens I push it away.
– You forget it?
– Yes, I forget it in the same time.
– When it happens?
– Yes. Like I don’t want to see if something bad happens.
If it is something small sometimes I push it away.
– But do you remember good things?
– Yes, I remember good and bad.
I don’t mean I push it away completely but I like to look at the good things, not the bad things.
– When you sleep does saliva comes out of your mouth?
– Sometimes, not always.
– Once a week, once a month, once a year?
– Maybe once a week.
– What are these pictures?
– I’d like to show you the pictures of how I was
when I was inside my body and another picture, not inside my body.
I don’t know if that helps.
When I look at the picture I can see I am not inside my body.
- But it’s a dark picture.
What else from these drugs, except of hash and pot did you take?
Cocaine, heroin?
– One time I took cocaine.
– Only once? Sure?
– I am 100% sure.
– Heroin?
– No.
– So your sleep is good or you wake up? You see dreams?
– Sometimes I dream.
– What?
– It is very different.
Sometimes I dream about my feelings, what happened to me in the day,
about my feelings before in life, sometimes I dream something scary.
Like the most scary movie. I think I am very sensitive.
– Sensitive towards what?
– To everything.
For example if I try something in life which is hard
or if I see a scary movie it is very hard for me, I will remember that.
– It’s very hard to get it out of your system.
Do you sometimes see things or you see certain things and you see then happening as you thought?
– Yes. Sometimes yes.
One day I stood in a shop speaking with a man and I wanted to buy something
and I knew what will happen, what the man would say and in the 5 minutes everything I thought happened.
– And everything happened as you thought?
– Yes. But I don’t think about it like it’s something not normal.
For me it was normal. I was not afraid or anything.
– Do you have animals in your house? Dog?
– No. I had a cat before. I love cats.
– You also love animals in general?
– I love them but I can be afraid, I am afraid of dogs.
I love them but I am afraid of some of them.
– Are you afraid of dogs?
– Yes.
– Very much?
– Not very much.
– Do you swim in the sea? You like swimming?
– I like swimming.
– If you see the bottom with the goggles inside can you see?
– I don’t like to go underwater. I cannot breathe.
– Fear of suffocation.
– I am very much afraid to fly with an airplane. I am very very much afraid.
– Are you also afraid to be in a narrow place?
– Yes.
– If it’s narrow...
- I feel I cannot breathe.
– Do you take the lift if you have to go to the fifth floor or you go upstairs by the stairs?
– I am not so much afraid I take the lift.
But I am afraid of the airplane.
And I am afraid if I sit in high places.
One day I went to a concert, there were some mountains and I was placed up
but I went down again and crawled down from the mountains, I was so afraid of height.
– Now you are afraid if you are in a balcony?
– I am very much afraid.
– Afraid to look down?
– Yes.
– You have dizziness or you are just afraid?
– I feel that maybe I want to jump. Maybe I cannot control myself.
If I am in the balcony I feel I want to jump, I feel I cannot control myself.
Sometimes something inside me would like to jump.
– Impulse to jump from high places.
Do you feel fear of pain?
– Yes.
– Very much?
– Any of these men that you had ever hit you?
– Yes but not very much.
– Did you hit the man?
– Yes.
– One time or more?
– The first one with whom I had the first child I hit him 5-6 times.
– And you were out of yourself. You could not control.
– I felt he did something very bad to me.
So my feelings were very hurt so I got angry.
– And you hit him with something or took a vase and hit him or with your hands?
– With my hands.
– But do you have an impulse to kill somebody?
Do something violent?
– Yes. I don’t always control myself.
Now I live with my husband.
If I feel that he will do something very bad to me I like to take something
and throw it on the floor, I like to slam the door.
– You were always having high sexual desire or it was normal or less than normal?
– It has changed. The last 2 years I don’t have very much.
– When did you meet this man you are married now?
2-3 years ago?
– 4 years ago.
– You stayed 2 years without being married.
– No I was married at the same time.
– So you are married for 4 years.
- Yes.
– So you met him and after 3 months you married him.
– Yes.
– You felt that this was a good husband? Why did you marry him?
– Deep inside myself I don’t feel he is good for me.
Something tells me he’s not good for me.
And at that time I was alone in my life, I lost all my family,
I had a very difficult time concerning everything and something inside me loved him.
I have feelings for him and he has feelings for me
but I want to use my sense I know inside myself that it is not good for both of us to be together.
– Is your husband from Turkey?
– No he is from Jordan.
And he is Muslim and I am not Muslim, I like to be free.
I don’t have any religion, I don’t believe in hell.
I believe nobody goes to hell. I believe hell is on earth, not when you die.
I found a husband who pushed me down.
– All the other husbands you mean?
You want a husband that will suppress you?
– No, I don’t want it.
But that is what happened to me.
– Is this what happens every time?
– Yes. I want a husband I can be free.
I don’t want a husband to decide about me.
– So he was a good husband for you.
– No. In some ways he is good but I am not completely myself.
I feel I lose my identity.
If sometimes I am with people I try to look at them and then I become like them.
I try to be the best for the people around me.
– Become what others want you to be.
– Yes. And that is what makes me angry sometimes,
that’s why maybe I start to break things
because I try to do it but inside myself I don’t like it because I am not myself.
I am sorry, I am getting angry with myself
because I don’t like myself, I feel I lose my self-consciousness.
– Self-esteem.
– I feel I lose that.
– But do you have confidence in yourself? Or you have no confidence?
– When I want to do something I have.
Maybe I don’t have it completely but my mind is very strong.
– Are you thinking a lot?
– Yes. I think very much.
I think all the time, my head never stops thinking.
– And you think about philosophical problems,
why I am here, what is the world, why we are suffering?
– Yes, I think about that.
I think about why I did that to myself,
I hope I was stronger so that I could survive and be myself again,
I would not take people inside my life who are not good for me.
And I think very much about life.
Why people are here, why things are like that?
But sometimes I like it, sometimes I don’t.
In one way I like it because it’s important for me to think about it
because this gives me something, I know now very much about people and life and many things.
– When you look somebody you understand whether he is a good or a bad person immediately?
– Yes. I know it but I don’t listen to it always.
– But you perceive it.
– And when I don’t listen to it I lose myself again.
– If you don’t do according to what you feel then you are confused in your head.
– And I am starting to lose myself. Because I don’t trust that feeling.
– You go away from yourself.
– Always I go away from myself. If I trust or not trust... it is there.
– But you never felt like you left your body totally
and you were roaming about in your dream or anything like that?
– Yes, in my dreams I feel I leave my body.
When I was a child I left my body every evening.
I was very happy because I liked to go into that state.
I went to the mountains, like Himalaya mountain, I was alone, I would like to do like that.
Every evening.
– So, did you go to India eventually?
– No, I never went.
I see the picture of that time when I was a child and this is the place I went when I was a child.
And I went every evening, I put myself on the bed and I was very happy
because I knew now I will got to that place.
– Did you have a guru?
– No.
– You never went to a guru?
– At the age of 13 you started using pot sometimes.
– Yes.
– You had a strong character, you fought with your parents?
How did your parents allow you to do this without problem?
– My father left me, he went to another country when I was 13.
– So you felt free to do whatever you like.
– Yes, I was free but I was sad too.
I thought that maybe I started smoking hash because I started not to care about myself.
And my mother was not strict with me.
– When did you stop going out of your body and roaming about? What age?
– When I was 13 I didn’t go out of my body anymore.
I was missing that, I hope I could do that again but I couldn’t anymore.
– What age did you have sex for the time?
– When I was 13.
– With a man, how old?
– I think 20.
– And did you enjoy it or it was a bad experience?
– No, it was a bad experience.
– Did he force you?
– No.
– You wanted to experiment.
– Yes, but I don’t know why because at that time I had a boyfriend
and I loved that boyfriend and he wanted to sleep with me
but I did not wanted to, I was very angry at him if he wanted to sleep with.
I felt that he would do something bad for me if he wanted to.
After that I slept with somebody I didn’t like.
And I knew I would lose my boyfriend that I loved.
– But you did it.
– Yes.
I was surprised, I didn’t like to think about sex or anything.
– Your father had done something that made you a little bit...
- No, all my life when I started having problems
I was thinking that maybe my father has done something bad for me
because I feel it, but I don’t remember.
But I feel he did something.
And even now I can get angry if I think about sex or if my husband does something to me I can be angry.
– If your husband wants to have sex with you,
you become angry?
– Sometimes.
– Because you don’t want and you cannot tell him that you don’t want.
– I tell him that I don’t want.
– Now, you tell him.
– Sometimes maybe I can sleep with him, even if I don’t want,
because I don’t want to make any trouble.
But sometimes I like to sleep with him if he is nice to me and we are close to each other
but I don’t like to sleep with anybody I feel I am not close to.
But I can be very angry sometimes especially if somebody touches my ears.
I feel I want to kill them.
– If they touch your ear?
– Yes, inside my ears.
– I feel my father has done something to me I didn’t like, he did many things I didn’t like.
– Like kissing you in your ear?
– No, but I don’t remember exactly.
I remember many things but I don’t remember something about sex.
– He hit you many times?
– Yes.
– Was he a violent man? He is still alive?
– Is he in America?
– No, he is in Spain. He is from Spain.
I don’t think he is violent but my mother is not easy too.
She likes to dominate, to decide about people very much.
And she drives people crazy. I can understand my father now.
My father is a nice man. He is not a bad person.
He does some things stupid but I don’t think that he knows what he is doing.
– In your room, where you sleep, you leave all the lights on or you leave some light?
– Between a little and full.
When I was a child my mother was afraid of many things too.
And my mother was telling me things she still says that if you do this, that will happen to you.
If you go to the street maybe somebody will rape you or kill you.
And she shows me the newspapers saying that many bad things are happening in the world.
And I was not strong when I was a child but I’m stronger now
and I haven’t seen my mother for 4 years.
Because I want to get away from her.
I don’t want to hear every day, you get up every morning and hear all that.
I tried to help myself, I tried to get away from that and think positive about life
but that’s difficult if somebody speaks to you like this all the time.
I am not strong enough not to care, I am so sensitive.
– Tell me if you are alone in the house you feel better or worse?
Do you want somebody, especially in the night? You will feel good to be alone?
– No. I wait for my husband to come home before I sleep.
Sometimes I don’t even like to go to the toilet
and sometimes I need to go to the toilet but I stay in the room.
– How is your thirst? How much you drink? Normal, very much, very little?
– It’s hot here and it’s very much now but in Denmark it’s normal I think.
– In your country you drink cold water,
very cold water?
– Yes.
– From the fridge?
– No, I don’t put it in the fridge.
– Do you take a lot of salt in your food?
– No. Normal.
My mother used to give me very much salt as a child.
She got very much salt in the food. And she gave it to me when I was a child.
Because of it I used my mind I studied very much what is good for the body
and I know now salt is not good so I stopped.
– When did you stop?
– Maybe 6-7 years ago.
– By that time you used to like very salty things?
– I think I ate it because of my mother.
– So, when you stopped, when you put less you had no problem.
You still like the food.
– Yes.
– You have your menses now?
– How old are you now?
– 33.
– And you have your menses?
– Yes.
– A lot of blood, normal or...?
– I think there is a lot of blood the first 2-3 days.
– Clear blood or clots?
– Sometimes pieces. Not before but now there are some pieces.
– Do you remember as a child did you use to have nose bleeds?
– I think so, yes. I remember yes, but I don’t know if they were many.
– Sweets? Do you like sweets, chocolate?
– Sometimes it’s difficult for me to know what I like and what not
because I don’t listen to myself.
If like something sweet I don’t eat it because it’s not good for me.
I worked with myself for many years.
Before I liked sweets but I know what is good for me now and what is not.
So if my body says I want something my mind say no at the same time.
– Did you ever were infected with gonorrhea?
– No.
– Sure? You had no infection,
but you remember you took antibiotics for that?
– No.
– You never took antibiotics?
– Yes, but for infection here.
– At what age?
– When I was a child, I don’t remember when.
But from 10 years old I started getting very much.
– Until?
-- Until I was 22-23.
– You took antibiotics constantly?
– Not constantly but very much because I always had an infection here.
– But did you go to the doctor?
– Yes, my mother took me to the doctor.
– Did they say it was lupus this infection?
– I don’t understand that.
– What did they say it was?
– It was just an infection inside here.
And I have an infection sometimes too if I go to the toilet.
– You know when you go to the toilet and have pain.
I don’t know the word in English.
– Cystitis.
– Yes, I have infection in the urine and here.
These 2 problems I have very much.
– But lately did you have any of these problems?
What was the last time, at 22 when you were getting antibiotics?
– No, maybe when I was pregnant maybe 1.5 year ago.
That had to do with the urinary infection.
Sometimes I feel I have an infection again but I take very much water now.
If I feel it now I drink maybe 3 lt. of water and then it goes away.
Because I don’t like to take antibiotics.
Before my mother made me to take antibiotics every month.
Do you want to know what I wrote here?
– Tell me.
– It’s difficult for me to trust people sometimes.
– Do you trust me?
– Yes.
– Can you say no? Would you say no in case you couldn’t?
– Yes. It’s difficult for me to say no but...
- Are you suspicious about people?
– Yes.
If somebody does something to me and I feel is wrong,
for example I like somebody and that person makes a mistake,
just one mistake can make me go inside myself, like I’m not open.
– And detach.
- No, I’m not like that because I know myself now but that’s my first reaction.
But now I know myself and I know who I am so I tell myself don’t be like that
but that’s what happens to me.
I control myself very much too, I am not spontaneous.
Maybe sometimes I am spontaneous but that’s not very much.
Most of the time I control myself.
– Do you want to control everything?
– About what happens in life? About people?\
Yes, I like to control, sometimes and many times I like not to control.
– You like to be free.
– Yes. Sometimes I feel I miss something inside myself
and I need other people to make me happy sometimes.
I feel they have something I don’t have
but at the same time I feel they take something from me when I am with them.
I feel I want them to give me something but in the end I feel emptier sometimes when I am alone.
It’s best for me if I don’t go.
But at the same time I feel I need very much love from other people.
I need somebody to give me love. Sometimes I feel I just like to be a baby.
I don’t like people to tell me what to do.
If somebody I love is bad to me,
for example if they tell me to go away from them I’m getting very sad, not just a little.
I start not to care about myself and think about killing myself or take cocaine.
I am thinking of doing something bad to myself if somebody I love does something bad to me.
But that has just happened a little because I come back quickly.
That’s the first reaction. I have a difficult time if I am very busy in my life.
Not before but when I got sick,
sometimes I feel I have something to do in life that makes me nervous.
Sometimes I feel like just getting up in the morning is hard for me
because sometimes life is very busy and you cannot say stop, I don’t want to.
Life wants something from you all the time and sometimes it’s difficult for me to follow
because I need peace very much.
When my father left me and went to Spain,
when I started to think if my father did something to me when I was a child,
I spoke to my mother but she pushed me away like I am crazy.
She didn’t want to listen to me.
So I feel all my life people push me away,
nobody listens to me and they just leave me alone.
When I got far for 4 years ago they haven’t called me, not even one time.
They just left me and they know I am very sick and I have a very hard time.
If I open my mouth and speak about my feelings they are pushing it down again,
my father and my mother.
– Ok, thank you.
I allowed her to be here so in case you want to ask an extra question you can do it.
I asked her because Alice told me is she still smoking;
she says no smoke, no cigarettes, no pot, no hash, nothing of that type.
So I believe her, she is telling the truth.
I scared her so much in the beginning!
That she will not easily tell something not true.
It’s our responsibility now, she gave everything about herself.
And she gave it amazingly well.
I did not expect when I saw her that she would be able to describe
what is going on inside her.
Because the first thing I could see was that she was being using pot.
She has been using hashish and these drugs
that detach the etheric body from the physical one.
And this detachment, when it happens it can stay forever.
And it causes a state of great panic and fear.
Those who remember my lecture on Cann-i.,
how I described the fear that develops out of this detachment of the body.
Now she feels she has this state permanently.
Let’s understand what has happened to her.
She says very important things, for instance,
when I was a child I was leaving my body happily, going to nice places
and coming back and I was expecting the night time
when I would leave the body and roam about and I was very happy.
Now, she says, I am detached from my body but I am totally invalid.
I live constantly in fear, in that state
where I am paralyzed and you could not see the full force of her problem
because of something which I did and I will explain it.
I made her feel comfortable in spite of the fact I was very aggressive in the beginning.
I said don’t tell me a lie otherwise... But I made her feel comfortable.
I just listened with great attention to what she had to say.
That’s why she opened up eventually and was able to describe what is happening inside her mind.
Otherwise she would feel very confused,
full of fears and full of this state of detachment.
But how this state from pleasant detachment became unpleasant, sick detachment?
The yogis which practice meditation they practice in order to get out of their bodies
and go to these astral planes where the feelings are fantastic.
It’s the upper place of the astral world where
what is happening is quite spiritual and therefore pleasant.
So what this little yogi was doing, she was a little yogi,
6-8 years old who came out of her body,
left the body and could go and meet anybody she liked if she put in her mind
I want to meet my friends she could go and meet her friends in whatever country or whatever place.
This is the detachment which happens in every one of us during the night when we sleep.
Every one of us leaves the body and goes accordingly to some plane.
Now why we are not going to very pleasant places,
why our dreams are not very pleasant is because our conscience is not clean any more
like a child’s conscience.
That is what prevents us from coming to a dream world in the night
which will always be a pleasant situation. She was given a gift because this is a gift.
It is a kind of very refined regulation between the astral and the physical body.
If that regulation is absolutely correct then somebody can leave with his astral body
and come back with no problem.
And this is attained by people who have a clear conscience
and can leave their body without a problem.
Because if they don’t have a clear conscience the moment they leave their body
they come into contact with lower spiritual world where they can see aggressive situations.
She says now my dreams are grand guignol,
she did not understand what it is but this is what she meant
when she says her dreams are the most terrible dreams sometimes.
And this is very teaching for all of us to understand
because most of you I believe you are dealing with patient
and you have to have the correct knowledge to advise correctly the person
who comes to be treated by you.
So you have to know and understand all these working of the human body.
And when she was a child and was pure in her conscience without any fear
she could leave the body and go to the uppermost astral areas where there is no fear.
But what happened in her life?
Her father grabs her and pulls her in the water
and this is an experience of a child by the father, a terrific fear.
That my father almost drowned me. Certain other things are happened
and at the age of 10 she starts taking antibiotics.
Had some shocks one after another, I expect some other shocks as well,
as you may also understand from what she says and finally at the age of 13 she is a liberated woman,
she explores the world but which world? Not the uppermost classes.
She finds some friends and she describes very vividly how they sat around
and smoked pot and had a good time.
I believe 37% of you had some similar experience.
Once I put this question in California to my students, most of them were MDs,
I said who has smoked hashish and I saw all hands raising.
Then I asked who did not, no hand!
It’s something very strange to me
because at the time I was in India in 1960’s I had no idea of these things
and there I met some Americans that had already come
and they were trying to persuade me to join their company.
I said forget it, not for me! And you should not do it also!
It was a big debate and I don’t know if I won
but I never took any drugs because in India I was very happy,
why should I take any drugs if someone is happy... to become happier?
But you see her life, the father left etc.
What is clear is that she is born as a little yogi with a possibility to read minds.
She could read the future of the people,
she could go to the astral world and could advise by giving them fantastic information.
She went to communicate with people of her age that they were using pot etc.
and something which for me is also unbelievable,
at the age of 13 she also experienced sex in the way she wanted.
Many times in my classes I have said don’t do that
because it would bring you to a state of mental disorder
because the sexual thing is not a simple.
If you do it it means you have to separate your emotional body from your physical one.
So you let your physical body have some pleasure while the emotional body is looking.
Sometimes you may have the experience when you are having sex you are looking upon
and say what am I doing now.
This is the time when you have sex without love,
without connection, without intermingling with each other.
If you do that you separate your emotions because the pain is so much.
If you let your emotions inside your body you will feel so much the pain of this experience.
It’s a painful experience if you have sex with someone you don’t love.
If you only want to have the pleasure experience of the physical body
you have to separate and this is what she did.
First come the antibiotics that started breaking down the organism,
then at the age of 13 she is already damaged by quite a lot of antibiotics and then comes the pot.
It separates the astral from the physical body.
You take a lot of hash or marijuana,
and your body is separated and we know this very well
because we know the fear of insanity which is produced by Cann-i.
You will see our repertories. Fear of insanity Cann-i. is one for the main remedies.
Actually she was damaging herself first
because she did not know she was taking antibiotics then taking drugs,
separating the body even more but what happened to her?
I mean here you have a system, a human being which is regulated to come in and out quite easily.
You don’t need too much interference to block the regulation and leave it half-open.
Her astral body remained forever not in and not out.
She lost all her energy, power and feelings. All are gone.
When you have the impression of her, I wanted to show you the picture before,
she was a totally different person.
She herself looks at this and says who am I?
Am I this? Have I become this?
She has become the ghost of herself and she is dealing with a ghost world now.
A ghost coming and staying behind my back.
This fine regulation is damaged, very severely.
But in that state, I’ve told especially in my lecture of Sep.,
that Sep. are looking also like her, not exactly, but almost.
They have no feelings but they can perceive what you are thinking and what your feelings are
because they are detached.
It’s very interesting, the moment that you are detached,
that means I am not connected and I can see objectively,
if I love somebody there is no possibility I can objectively see my wife,
my girlfriend or child, I think it’s the nicest child, the cleverest,
I have a dog and it’s the cleverest dog.
My dog has been killed and for one day I was out of function,
totally and I had to take Nat-m., this is a confession to be able to functional again,
because I was attached to the dog.
Everyone who was coming to my house, I was like look what my dog is doing!
You don’t see objectively. You don’t see, you don’t take distance.
The moment that you become very detached then you can really see the truth,
what the others are thinking and their feeling.
She has that, she can see that.
But what is the problem? It’s a good thing.
Because she does not know how to close this. It’s permanently open.
It’s like having no skin to protect you from people touching you.
They touch a wound if you don’t have a skin.
This is what is happening with her.
Therefore, unless we understand this and we have this kind of analysis
how we can interfere with her body in order to bring back this regulation
within the physical body and the connection so we can bring her back to life.
If you ask her she says I am not living, I don’t know how I am living.
Don’t see her eyes when I spoke to her because she became more and more alive.
If I was detached and not showing love to her you would see a ghost talking.
But since I understand these things I am not needing this kind of observation
and when I need to do that sometimes I am totally detached but with her it would be the worst thing,
you have to really show that you are interested
and her story is interesting for everyone of you I believe.
Am I right? Listen the difference between connection and detachment.
I asked a question, I said do you think that I am right.
Do you think this case is interested?
I am absolutely sure 99.9% find the case interesting,
what I hear is mmmh and not from everybody, about 30%.
Who is this 30%? Those who are in contact with mequite a lot.
The others have a detachment saying what is he talking about.
I can see some of you intellectualize inside yourself whether I am right or not
but the case is interesting!
So you say yes the case is very interesting, that’s all.
Because in our society we are half mad. Crazy.
Our western ‘civilization’  has made us half-crazy.
That’s why 70% of the American people have a psychotherapist
and now it’s coming this fashion to Europe, even to Greece.
It’s unbelievable! Oh you have to see a psychologist!
Because they cannot communicate anymore, cannot give love to each other,
cannot do the natural thing that a human beings do in their relationships.
You detach too much and you pay the price. And not this price.
This is a big price because she broke all the laws.
A woman being 30, 40 or 50 and may not have sex and it is better if she had,
forced herself with somebody she does not love.
Say it my personal craziness what I have seen is that this is what happens.
When I see the stress when it comes I see that they have damaged themselves many times
by pushing themselves with a man who they don’t love
and therefore I have this syndrome which I call “Husband syndrome”.
Who knows the husband syndrome? Not too many, it doesn’t matter.
Now, she has a problem because she lives with a husband with whom she is not in love also.
Maybe she is not in love because she is not feeling well.
Is my body well so I can enjoy having sex with him?
After your remedy maybe she will enjoy more being with her husband, I don’t know,
but at this moment it’s still negative for us to live with somebody
she says she is not in love with but is a nice man. This is husband syndrome.
He is a nice man, I can tolerate him, I love him because he gives me security,
he is in the bank, the manager, he has social status,
he is intelligent but does not excite me emotionally and sexually.
Women are in trouble when they do that.
These are women which are faithful to their husbands!
They are not playing tricks. Ok, I don’t like my husband.
There are other cases that will have on the side somebody else who satisfies them on this level.
These particular women who develop husband syndrome become sick, permanently,
having from one syndrome to another.
You cure one set of symptoms and then they come with another set of symptoms.
That’s why it’s very difficult to cure a woman who lives with a man with whom she is not in love.
Now we come to the real problem because as you heard,
for those who understand a little bit of M.M.
When I see her I know she has taken drugs, marijuana. She is detached.
If you go and see Cann-i. my lecture is exactly that.
Further than that she is having fear of losing her mind, fear of insanity.
This is a case of Cann-i. but I want to know a little bit more and the story unfolds.
Fear of insanity; Calc., Cann-i., Manc. and Puls. are the capital remedies for this problem.
The worst is Manc. It’s the most crazy.
The second is Cann-i. and then comes Puls. and then Calc.
But other remedies have that.
The analysis of the computer after the first 6 symptoms said Cann-i. is the probable,
with Anac., Carb-v., Cic., Op., Nat-ar. Cann-i.
what I was thinking and also the computer was thinking exactly the same way.
She started giving other symptoms.
When alone ameliorates, frightful dreams and fear of suffocation.
If you put these then the computer changes its mind and it says...
No, it doesn’t change it completely but the other remedy you have to think about is Stram.
It gives you a very good idea.
Who has this program, VES? Very few.
I understand, that’s why you could not find the remedy.
The computer will give you some ideas, it’s not the highest authority is you and your knowledge
but the computer definitely will give you some good suggestions.
The computer says Stram. Do you agree that she has some symptoms of Stram.?
Yes, very good. You have step 3?
In the third step you have put 32 symptoms. Give me the analysis.
The analysis says Stram., Med., Staph., Arg-n., Anac.
All these interesting remedies for this case, each one for its own right.
It’s a miracle that she has not had a gonorrhea with the type of life she was living.
Correct? I am surprised because she has a typical symptom of Med.
What is it? The fear.
Show Med. Clairvoyance, prophesying, fear dark, fear someone is behind,
startled easily, frightened easily, fear of insanity, suspicious,
menses clotted, cold water take it out.
Med. has 20 symptoms out of 30. Staph.? Who says this case is Staph.?
Let me see. Who says may be? Who says this case is Stram.?
Who says maybe it is Stram.? Who says this case can be Anac.?
May be Anac.? Arg-n.? May be Arg-n.? No one in favor
Who says this case is Phos.? May be? Who says Cann-i.? May be Cann-i.?
– Why did you say Arg-n.?
- Did you put impulse to jump from high place?
She bruises easily, she says. Is this a case of Phos.?
Who says Phos.? 6. Margit said that she has all the symptoms of Cann-i.
If I ask you this woman when she was a child she needed Cann-i. yes or no?
We finally agree on something.
That means this woman needed some remedy, whatever it might be,
then maybe second and a third one and now she has reached a state where she needs X number of remedies.
Yesterday when we saw about Gels. and some woman was asking me,
whether this was a core remedy, I did not understand it
and perhaps I didn’t give the right answer.
The right answer is that Gels. is the uppermost layer of that case.
Later on, underneath will be a second remedy
but unless you try to lift the first layer,
second and third layer it’s not going to have a real effect.
Bring this woman back to life is a matter of great skill, understanding and knowledge.
So, we have to think very much in this way that means
what most probably was the remedy as a child maybe it was Phos., yes.
You see how it is. Most probably she was Phos.
Now she got some frightful experience.
Maybe she developed after that a state where she would need to go
and have her mother next to her, have the light on.
Maybe she was developing a layer of Stram. Now we are clearer.
Do we give now Stram., or the remedy that case most of her present symptomatology which is Cann-i.?
Now we have strategy, a way of going about
that means we will prescribe Cann-i. with the possibility that maybe now
she will need full light on in her room,
the fear maybe will be more when she comes to Stram.
and then you give it and then she may come into the first layer of Phos.
in which case she will have the possibility of coming back to connection with life.
She is disconnected from life now because life force goes throught the vital force.
This is the analysis of this case and we will start by giving her a few doses of Cann-i. 200C.
She can take for a week and then wait and see what happens.
Wait for 4-5 months and then she can communicate.
Next year, she will be willing to come and continue her treatment. You understand?
– Would you expect a strong aggravation from the underlying layers?
– Not in the stage. A strong aggravation will come most probably after Stram.
And things will be become physical and she will bring out this skin eruption.
She meant sinusitis? I perceived it as a skin eruption!
She will have back this sinusitis full force and urinary infection and she will be very happy!
– Should you give Penicillinum in potency?
– Forget it!
– Would it make a difference in the case if she had used LSD or other hallucinogenic drugs?
– The way she describes her symptoms? No. If she had described other symptoms, yes.