Can you tell us what the problem is?
– I read in your book you could heal lupus.
– I never wrote in my book I can heal lupus but...
- Ok, I wondered if you could help me.
– That’s different.
– You have good success rate.
– In some cases.
– I‘ve had serious illness in 1995. I had cancer of the bowel and needed a resection.
– Without having an opening.
– And I was left incontinent.
– Of stool and urine.
– Both. Before the operation they said I have fortnight to live.
– Can you tell us how old you are.
– 52.
– And you were told before the operation...
- I would need this bag, radiotherapy, chemotherapy.
– You did?
– And I had a fortnight to live if I didn’t have the operation.
So I went forward to the operation. Then later, in 1998 I had a triple bypass.
And the surgeon there said you have 3 months to live if you don’t have that done.
And he said you were born with heart disease.
That threw me a bit because I’ve seen many doctors in my life.
Obviously as you do and not one of them picked up on that.
Though I was breathless and had lots of problems that could have related to the heart.
– When was the bypass?
– In 1998.
– That means 3 years after the operation.
– Yes, that’s right.
– Now the heart started after the operation or was it already there?
- It was very weak before that because...
- You had your heart checked before and it was found to have a problem?
– It was the heart surgeon who told me I was born with a heart disease and no one else had picked up on this.
I think it’s quite lazy and it’s struggling along into 50 till all this goes.
It was a miracle I’ve lived this long without ever realizing I had a heart disease.
That’s what I think. And in 1986 they gave me a diagnosis of lupus.
10 years back somebody said you have lupus.
– Was there a biopsy done?
– It was a test done into a homeopathic hospital.
– Tests.
– Blood tests, yes.
And breathing tests done in the Royal London homeopathic hospital.
And they said you have lupus.
– Where was the lupus?
– In the face.
– So somebody saw that typical eruption and then they made a blood test?
Do you know the blood test?
– There is a recent test.
– SLE. Hashimoto thyroiditis, CA of the rectum, bladder instability,
ischemical disease with coronary artery bypass impossible and chronic fatigue.
Myalgic encephalomyelitis. Current treatment; thyroxin.
Atenol, Zocor, aspirin, co proxamol and includes hypromellose eye drops.
So we have a rather complicated case here.
You have been taking all these drugs?
– I take less of them now. I don’t take Zocor anymore.
I don’t take the painkillers anymore. I take the thyroxin and Atenol.
– What is the Atenol for?
– β- blocker.
– And you take aspirin?
– Yes.
– How many aspirins?
– One every day in the morning.
– And what is the problem with your eyes?
– They are very dry because of lupus, Sjogren syndrome.
Like sand is thrown to the face.
– Are you married?
– I was. Divorced.
– Do you have children?
– Yes, 2. One 25 and one 29. A boy and a girl.
– Were you married once?
– Once, 23 years.
– And then you divorced.
– Yes.
– Is the boy the oldest?
– Yes, 29.
– So you were married quite early.
– 21.
– Did you have affairs before?
– No.
– You were affected before with venereal disease?
– The only think I can think of is when I was abused by my stepfather.
– At the age of?
– 5 to 12.
My real father left when I was 18 months,
I never saw him after that day till the day he died.
And this other man arrived when I was about 3.
– When did you start having affairs? At what age?
– I did not have affairs.
– That means you married without having an affair before.
– No. I was abused from about the age of 5 till about the age of 12.
And I thought how do I stop this.
So I prayed and next time he came I said that if you touch me I would tell the man next door
because he was quite a friend with the man next door.
And he kind of respected that man and he said you wouldn’t dare and I said try me
so he didn’t try and I had that kind of protection until I left home at 16.
And my mother was ill with multiple sclerosis.
And when I discovered my father’s death certificate, he had heart disease and bladder cancer...
There is a quite chronic heredity.
So when I went to a homeopath in Britain they said oh, you are too difficult to deal with.
So I wanted, if you are a clever man, to help me.
I did see an homeopath last October and she gave me Syph. 1M, I think.
– Up to 1M or just 1M?
– 1M repeated 3 times.
– And this was in...?
– October last year.
She got a bit hesitant about taking on my case
because she said I might have to go through cancer and heart disease again to sort of get better.
She was afraid of theses flair ups.
– And you have heart problems at the moment.
– Yes, I do.
– What was the effect of this remedy? Was any effect? Did you feel anything?
– Not dramatically, but I feel kind of calmer.
I was really nervous and agitated. I feel a bit calmer.
– Since October you repeated the remedy?
– No, just once.
– Did you take another remedy?
– No. On the plane I did. Some travel remedy that helps with fear of flying.
– So you have fear of flying.
– Yes. Claustrophobic. I don’t like lifts.
– Do you have any other fears?
– I am alone but I don’t like being alone very much.
– You fear to be alone?
– I did but I got used to it.
– Fear of being alone only in the night or even in the day?
– Night time I think. And fear of death I had.
Because I have been through so much like nearly died of cancer, nearly died of heart disease.
Somehow I am here so it can’t be that bad. Someone up there is looking out for me.
So I feel more connected with the source now.
– After your divorce did you have a relationship?
– No.
– You stayed alone.
– Yes.
– And your children are not in the house.
– I am on my own in a flat.
When I first left home I lived with some hippies but then I found a flat.
– The hippies did not rape you...
- No, they were good, I felt very safe. I was in Wales.
They respected. They realized I had a lot of problems. They were kind.
I mean there were drugs going on but I didn’t want to get into it. It was a choice.
– You refused.
– No, it was just... I didn’t feel ready.
I felt very sort of abandoned and lost and depressed after the divorce in 1990
I went to these hippies and I needed to get with a group.
I was just full of depression after all that.
– I am confused now.
– You said you left home at the age of 16 and then you joined some hippies.
– No, 1990 I joined the hippies, after my marriage.
I was feeling depressed and someone said come and join us for holidays
and I went and the hippies were there and it was ok.
– You were already grown up.
How did you live after leaving home at the age of 16? Did you go to work?
– I worked a little bit to get some money and then a friend said come
and share a flat with us and I shared with 3 other girls in London.
– While you were working?
– Yes. It was very difficult, I did 2 jobs to sort of keep going.
And when I was about 17 I had a nervous breakdown.
– Because of too much stress?
– Yes. And I got married at 21 to a chap who was older than me.
– Much older?
– Yes 23 years older.
And like you say you marry for security and stuff you said yesterday... That’s true.
– But is it true that you never had a real love experience before?
– Not really. What happened to me put me off...
- Yes, because of the experience. The problems with the eyes is it myopia?
– Astigmatism and...
– Shortsightedness.
– Do you know if any of your ancestors were suffering with TB?
– A great uncle had TB.
– Did he die of it?
– No. He had an operation.
A lot of them had rheumatism,
one great aunt had cancer and my mother we don’t know much about her family her mum and dad
she was brought up by aunties because she was ill I was brought up by her great auntie,
so she brought both of us up.
My mother’s auntie brought me up as well as my mother.
– Did you have a period in your life in which you were happy?
– Beginning of the marriage when I had the 2 children. About 8 years.
– After that you found out that that something was going on which you didn’t like?
– I had very bad periods, endometriosis.
Which resulted in hysterectomy in 1998.
– My husband had a vasectomy in 1976 and he lost his interest so we started fall apart.
– You had normal sexual interest or was it too much and you suppressed it?
– It could have been. It was not as good as it could have been.
You talk about that Eros, I’ve never experienced it.
– So you answer like an English woman.
What I want to know actually is a more straight answer;
did you have sexual desire that was suppressed because of your husband situation?
– My situation was suppressed because of the situation in my childhood, the abuse, that made it worse.
– That’s one. But you got in marriage and you functioned.
– I tried.
– Did you function in the marriage?
That means if you had sexual intercourse...
- No proper orgasm.
– That means you were excited during the foreplay but no final orgasm.
– I never had.
– Never?
– No. I wanted but no.
– That means you had some desire. There was an excitement.
– Physically it was painful, it was too difficult. The endometriosis made it painful.
– But the endometriosis came after your marriage.
– I always had painful periods.
I got to doctors but they didn’t do nothing about it.
And then a friend of ours who was a gynecologist and he said come and see me privately,
so I went to see him, he said you have endometriosis 22 years.
I will take your uterus away. It’s too painful for you.
And I was about 40 then when he told me that.
– But with endometriosis you had 2 children.
– I know. It was a miracle! It was very painful.
– How did he know it was 22 years that you had that?
– He told after he took the uterus out. He did the examinations.
– By looking at the condition of the uterus.
– It was very painful.
– You started having painful periods. Premenstrually or during?
– Very premenstrual tension.
Migraines, I wanted to kill someone, I was really angry, threw things.
– You were angry because you were a woman because this happened to you?
– Sometimes because I was a woman, sometimes because I wanted to feel pain-free.
I wanted to enjoy.
But since the hysterectomy the migraines have gone, that pain has gone and it’s good.
– I wrote the remedy here and he pressed the button of the computer and showed the same remedy.
But we can continue for the sake of the class understanding the case.
You look very calm, very composed.
– I’m working at it! You have a calming influence!
– Thank you.
– I can sell myself as Calmol!
Your sleep was good?
– Yes.
– Did you have nightmares?
– I had in the past.
– Bad nightmares?
– Very bad. Screaming.
– Were you waking up with screaming?
– Yes.
– And then your husband would come and calm you.
– And it took you some time to calm down?
– There was dreams of knives, persecution running.
– Somebody was chasing you with a knife to kill.
Did you have dreams of you killing somebody? Hitting or killing.
– Yes, I wanted to kill the stepfather very much.
– Did you kill him?
–No, I should have.
– He is dead now so I’m relaxed.
– But still inside you you have not forgiven.
– I have tried to forgive but it’s not easy.
– It’s unbelievable. I don’t want to torture you more.
You are a good case. We’ll go to the class and analyze your case.
This as you can see is a very complicated case with very deep pathology.
It comes because of a predisposition as she explained
plus this genetic predisposition was brought out because of severe stress.
The way that she described the stress,\
everybody can understand how much this child has suffered and what terror she has been through.
How do we know the terror?
Because of the nightmares that were in the subconscious,
this kind of nightmares indicate the depth of the terror that she was going through.
This had a terrific effect upon the physical body and brought out all the pathology.
This is a typical case where it shows what we claim;
that the pathology is only the end-result of a process in the organism going into a imbalanced state.
So imbalance can go from one pathology to another
and if it is too much and the organism resists in one system
and the pathology spreads to the other system whether it is digestive, urinary, genetic, mental or emotional.
What is interesting for her case is that this woman with all this suffering
could have been really mentally affected a lot which is a miracle
that she is in such a good state with only the fears.
For those who know Homeopathy, the remedy is clear.
Everybody knows the remedy. You have a problem with the remedy.
I expected I would come to the class and everybody would know the remedy.
If you were in the school process I would make you write the remedy in a piece of paper,
give it to me, then afterwards I’d put the marks.
It’s a typical case and this is interesting.
Such case is not possible be effected homeopathically unless she starts with the right remedy.
And the remedy is clear. Maybe it’s clear for me.
But I believe you will also see it.
Here we have a case in which fright is one of the main problems.
She got terror, fright. Ailments from fright you can take it into your repertorization.
Without this causative factor the remedy was coming.
When I wrote the remedy he looked and he pushed the button,
the computer was giving the same answer without ailments from fright.
This is a case where fright as a main causative factor has started the process of pathology
which this woman presents.
And the remedy can be found only if we take into consideration the mental,
emotional sphere and not the pathology.
If you take SLE, cancer of the colon,
heart problems you will never come down with the right prescription.
Here we really have to deal on the first causative issue
because she gives us enough information on that level to be sure that this is the remedy
otherwise if you take the details of the heart,
you give a heart remedy, forget it.
If you take the details of the colon, you give a colon remedy, forget it.
If you get the details of SLE give Sep...
Sep. is a possibility yes or no? She has received Sep.?
You had Sep. Long time ago. I did not know.
She forgot to tell me I said you were having Sep.
Why I suggested so? I am not a psychic!
Because I know how the mind of homeopaths functions.
If she went to the homeopathic hospital and said about the orgasm they would give Sep.
So I said you had Sep. and she said yes.
Because of this typical saddle eruption combined with aversion sex.
She didn’t say aversion sex. That is different. She was terrified to have sex.
You saw me when I inquired, because I gave all the information, did you have some excitements,
yes she had excitement, she could not reach.
Why she could not reach? She could not trust.
The idea is this organism can no more trust to such an extent
as to have herself given up to the other person
as in a state of sexual intercourse when you really reach the climax,
your orgasm leads you, as I said the other day,
God has given us this tool so you cannot resist,
you have to give up your ego but she was conditioned so much because of fear
she could not give up her ego, her protection.
But was what inside of her? What was the main feeling?
Anger. Terror. She said several times I want to kill sometimes.
I wanted to kill him. Anger.
And then we see the subconscious fear and terror which comes through.
We will be lead eventually to the remedy.
Also it is interesting to understand this remedy.
She says I do not like flying.
It’s not aversion or fear of flying it’s fear of been enclosed,
being in a cage where you have no escape.
But all her life since childhood she was trying to find a way to escape
and she has found out that she cannot escape.
She has to have this type of...
I don’t know what word to use for such things happening.
Fear of narrow places it’s not a fear of narrow places it’s an understanding construction of the soul.
How it was constructed through that terror.
I have to escape, to leave, anger.
When menses were coming, anger,
she said this reminded her of being a woman that they could have done these things to her.
Just leave it as it was originally.
Let me show you the symptoms that he was putting as he was hearing the case.
Give the symptoms. After being abused,
after being abused sexually, fear of being alone, fear of being alone in the night,
fear of death, fear of narrow places, sadness, sighing, myopia, cancer lupus,
involuntary stool, urination involuntary, chest heart complaints, thyroid,
endometriosis, suppressed desire, coition painful, general menses.
Even this kind of repertorization which is irrelevant to what I am saying
and to the way I understand her case brought out the correct remedy.
Don’t show them! Is this a case of Caust.?
Because she is losing urine, she has fear of narrow places.
Is this a case of Tub.? Hyos.? Bell.? Stram.? Cocc.? Staph? Show them.
Flat repertorization. What is the first remedy?
Arg-n., Lyc., Sulph., Lach., Psor., Ars., Calc., Sep., Bell., Kali-c., Nat-m.
Go further, Puls. Is this a case of Puls.? No?
You will have a surprise? Graph.? Nit-ac.? Sil.? Ant-c.? Am-c.? Carb-v.? Nat-c.? Nux-v.?
She wants to kill. Caust.? Hyos.? Ign.? Phos.? Spong.? Staph.? Glon.?
Never mind, show me the VES.
Why you changed it? It was Stram. first.
Why didn’t you put nightmares?
Even second with this kind of repertorization you can immediately see that this is a Stram. case.
Put the causative factor. Ailments from fright. 3 times.
I want to ask one question. Which question will I ask now.
I did not ask it inside I wouldn’t make it very clear.
Are you afraid of the dark?
– Yes.
– Very much
- Very much.
I did not ask this question because I didn’t want to make it very clear for you.
I wanted to challenge you a little bit.
Before putting fear of the dark show me Stram. ailments from fright show me the effect.
– I already put fear of the dark!
– Oh, you put. Take it out. Fear of being alone in the night, if you put it 3 times, that’s it.
– I’ve got to combine with fear being alone?
– Don’t combine. Fear of being alone is different.
Just take it out fear of being alone in the night.
Without fear of the dark. When he put as causation fright Stram. comes up,
in spite of flat repertorization, VES says this is the remedy.
Put fear of the dark. Therefore, this is a clear case of Stram.
Who thought of Stram.? You need more education.
– You said something about Con.?
– Forget it.
– Here first things first.
We don’t have here a woman where her ailments come because she had a great erotic life,
sexual life and suddenly there is a divorce and she has to repress herself
and after that all the symptoms develop.
This is a case of Con. This is different here.
Here we have a woman who out of absolute terror symptoms have developed and what are the symptoms?
Except of the physical symptoms that do not indicate the remedy,
if you take only the physical symptoms forget the remedy.
You can never find it. It is interesting also that she does not go after she leaves home,
the terror is so much that she will not dare to make an affair.
She is terrified by this idea.
And only in the safety of a marriage then she accepts to have sexual intercourse again.
That means this is not a case of Sep. Sep. is not interested
and if she was a deep Sep. like her never had an orgasm that means she would never marry.
It would not be necessary for her to marry.
She would not feel inclination to get married at all.
This is unfortunate, I thought 99% of the class would say Stram. I do not see that.
Now the idea is what potency we shall give in such a case.
You’ll start with 6X, 12X, 12C, 30C, 200C, 1M, 10M, 50M.
Who will start very low? Nobody.
12X? Nobody.
12C? Nobody.
30C? 7. 200C? 81! 1M? 19. 10M? 7. 50M? He is right!
– But George she has quite a few organic defects and do you dare to give 50M is such a case?
– Certainly not!
– I said it just to see the reaction of the class!
You should know me better by now!
Sometimes I will say the wrong thing and I will see dead silence
but nobody dares to challenge and say what are you talking about?
Here as we say is the country of freedom. We go back to the challenge.
That means whatever you know, you know. You should not be gullible.
Because I can come as a teacher and tell you whatever I like.
And you are going to swallow that. You go to teachers who tell lies, myths, stories without having any effect.
And you believe them. No! You should challenge.
Here is a deep pathology how you give 50M?
You cannot give 50M because she may go into big reaction and what are you going to do?
Therefore when you have a deep pathology on the physical level,
here we have the combination,
why most of you made a mistake because the problem is on an emotional level
that means in order to touch the emotional level you have to go high
but you can go high and you must go high if the physical body is in a condition to withstand the reaction.
Here we have doubts whether the physical body is in a condition to withstand the reaction.
Therefore we have to be careful and therefore we have to go quite low.
Not here but here. We have to start carefully.
At the same time she takes other drugs.
These drugs are in the way that means to eventually counteract the homeopathic remedy.
Therefore you have to give it repeatedly in order to counteract the chemical drugs
which are used at the moment until the organism reaches such a condition that she will be able to dispense,
get away from the remedies she is taking.
So we have to go carefully and be patient and not expect from one day to another,
it will take longer but it’s a much safer way of treating.
Therefore, 12C. She can start 3 times a day.
But every 10 days you have to raise the potency and go to 13C, 14C, 15C, 16C.
Do you understand why this is a case of Stram.?
Still there are some doubts. Show me this rubric.
This is another rubric which is closer to ailments from fright.
Ailments from fright with anger. Put this rubric instead of ailments from fright.
Acon. also comes high in the repertorization because somebody might have thought,
I have though that this case needs Acon.
Why? Is this correct?
Who can give me the differentiation between Acon. and Stram.?
Why Stram. and not Acon.? I’ll tell you how this could be an Acon. case.
It could have been an Acon. case if she would have come here
and said that what is torturing her mostly at this moment is a fear of dying and dying quite soon.
That means after the shock, in order to have an Acon. case, the symptom of Acon. is I am going to die!
We didn’t hear it. Fear of dying also. Acon. will not say like that.
Acon. will say it in a stronger way, fear of dying of Acon. is really fear of dying
She has been near death.
She says they have predicted I will die after 3 months, I did not die.
This is not an Acon. Forget it. The moment a patient speaks this way concerning death...
Of course she has fear of death.
She said after I had all this pathology having fear of death is not the prominent symptom.
What is the prominent symptom? It’s the anger.
I want to kill. Acon. does not want to kill.
But it is interesting that whatever way you can repertorize Acon. should come,
except of course of flat repertorization.
Flat repertorization will very seldom give you the remedy.
It means that the remedies which have most of the symptoms are the best. No.
In Homeopathy we say totality of symptoms but actually we don’t have it.
We have totality of keynote symptoms. Which are the real keynote symptoms?
There are the ones that will give you the answer to the case.
Not the totality. The totality sometimes will give you but actually seldom.
– What about syphilitic aspect of this case?
With Stram. would you give after another remedy perhaps?
– The idea of the miasms is the same as the idea of layers on which we are unfolding a case.
Always you go according to the symptoms to find the remedy.
If you go according to a theory there are so many theories that you can produce
that you will be totally confused in the end.
You have to go pragmatically, realistically, according to the symptomatology of the case.
Get the symptomatology of the case, get the essence of the case and then you will find the remedy.
And whether it fits on the syphilitic or on the sycotic it doesn’t matter.
Syph. was given to her. For what reason?
There is no reason for giving Syph. for such a case.
If you go to idea of syphilis you give Merc. to the case.
You can make a case anything you like,
but the actual symptomatology of the case will lead you only the Stram.
No other remedy.
– What do you expect the remedy to do with her?
– Cure her?
– Cure!
– No.
– What do you expect?
– I expect gradual improvement to what extent, I don’t know.
I would expect for instance that the eruption will come out again in the nose,
the saddle, that will be a good sign, I will expect that the heart will be better functioning,
I will expect also that the retention will be better slowly.
– And in the emotional level?
– On the emotional level; much improvement.
– And what will be the last potency you would give her?
– I don’t know because I will see how she will react on these potencies
and if there is a relapse then we go higher.
It’s not an easy case to handle! Give Portugal the opportunity.
– Will there be any return of the headaches?
– Yes but no dramatic aggravation will take place. Thank you very much!