This is an 11 year-old child with an iridocyclitis which destroyed almost completely the left eye.
She still has maybe 5% of her vision and the problem is now to save the rest vision
and to protect the right eye.
–When was the last eye examination done?
– It was done a few months ago and they said that 95% of the nerve is destroyed.
– What about the right eye?
– The right eye is in order.
Nothing’s wrong with the right eye. Can I give her history?
When the child was 9 month old she had an otitis for the first time which was treated with antibiotics.
Then she had 5-6 times otitis which were treated 4 times with antibiotics.
Three quarters of each year she had eczema in the right wrist and on the elbow
which was treated with cortisone.
When she was 2 year and 3 months old arthritis of the left knee started.
First was treated with anti-inflammatory medicines and laser and when this didn’t help she had steroids,
she put them on the knee and the inflammation stopped.
– What year was that?
– When she 2 and 3 months old, she was born in 1990 so this was 1992.
Very shortly after this, 3 months later,
a certain skin disease started which is called morphea,
it’s a benign subgroup of scleroderma it started on the thorax and it was also treated with cortisone.
So since she was 5,5 years old the situation is stable on the skin,
it has not changed but it was also treated suppressively.
Then, shortly after the treatment of the knee...
- What age was the skin condition?
-2 years.
– We were not sure when it began because in the beginning it was very small.
– So they cannot say when it really started. But it was treated after the knee.
And then shortly after the knee treatment the difficulties with the eye started.
And when the child was 3 Quarters an iridocyclitis was diagnosed.
ANA was positive 1:160 and eyes were immediately treated locally with cortisone.
There were constantly some small inflammations of the eye and 2-3 times severe.
Constantly cortisone drops were used.
In February 1998 a severe damage of the vision was noticed, behind the retina.
She got 2 depos one in July and one in October of 1998
and she was treated 4 weeks with 60 mg of cortisone a day.
And under the treatment with cortisone the child develop migraines,
left side with pressing or stitching pain and woke up with pain in the morning,
sometimes with vomiting which ameliorated the pain.
She had checks 5 times a week and then her internal cortisone stopped and it has subsided.
In 1998 she developed warts on the soles of her feet and a neighbor treated her with Thuja
and the warts vanished and did not come back.
The child came to me for treatment in 1999 with the wish to stop this process in the body.
I did not succeed very well I must say. The child is self-developed quite well but...
- What remedies have you prescribed?
– Shall I say some of the symptoms she had?
– Beside the history of the disease the mother related the following things;
she never had acutes, if she ever caught a cold the symptoms vanished very fast.
Then she is a very warm child, sticks feet out of bed,
doesn’t want attraction, sleeps on abdomen, feels much better in the seaside,
likes to take pieces of ice into her mouth, has quite some fears of darkness,
being alone, war, nature catastrophes, high places, injections,
bites nails unintentionally, likes to eat smoked meat,
sausages and bacon but cuts away fat from meat, desires ice cream and noodles.
– Wait. Say it again so he can put some symptoms.
- Feels much better in the seaside, likes to take pieces of ice into her mouth,
fear of darkness 3 times, fear of being alone 3 times and the other fears were not so intense,
war and nature catastrophes 1 time, high places and injections.
Nail biting, desires smoked meat...
She had extremely red cheeks from birth and on.
It’s a pity we don’t have a photo, it was like a cherry.
– Why not now?
– Because of the treatment it’s gone. The whole child changed!
Then she is very sympathetic especially in the social sector,
nausea after chocolate, sensitive to bad smells, loves cats and dogs very much,
has tendency to develop blue marks on the skin when she hurts herself.
This is also gone.
– How are here platelets? Are they low?
– They were always normal.
– Liver no problem after cortisone?
– No.
– She’s a very easy going child, always happy, likes to eat,
takes a good breakfast, goes to school, comes to home, never tired.
Always does what is expected from her, never complains.
Because of the arthritis of her left knee and some of the symptoms I gave Med.
That was the first 30C.
– What was the reaction?
– She took it for 5 weeks. 2 times a week I gave it to her.
She developed an acute with 38C fever and during the time she took it she was very obstinate.
But the time without remedy this subsided and she was the old compromising self again.
And the eye remained stable which means the pressure was quite normal.
I think 17 or 16.
And there were no other changes so I did not think this remedy was very helpful
and since she had a very significant desire for smoked meat
and because of the great sympathy on the social sector and the early suppression of the eczema
I gave her Caust. in different potencies up to 1M.
And then the follow up 3 months later...
- What was the result of Caust.?
– 2 old symptoms came back for short time.
Pain in the left Achilles tendon on walking and stomach pain when the stomach was empty.
These were old symptoms and they came back.
– The pain in the knee?
– Nothing.
– Neither the skin?
– Neither the skin.
I did not know that she already had Thuja, I found out this later.
Then she developed a very strange sweat and then mother said
that she always had this sweat and the smell was like an old cellar.
After Caust. the girl had more desire for ice cream and chocolate and aversion to fat and vegetable,
more fear to be alone, to go to the dark cellar and for the relatives.
The fears got even worse after Caust. So, because of the strange smell I gave her Thuja 200C and it...
- Does Thuja have this smell?
– Yes, moldy.
– I always decided the treatment after the eye doctor who primarily prescribed cortisone
and eye drops for the pressure.
She gets 3 different drops;
against inflammation, to open the retina and to put down the pressure.
– She still takes this?
–Yes.
So, Thuja brought back the otitis and stopped the nail biting and stopped the desire for sweets.
The eye pressure was still high and the parents wanted a remedy
and because of she being like a grown-up,
very adjusted and very much compassionate with animals I gave her Carc.
The follow up 3 months later, girls seemed to develop more self-confidence,
was not so yielding anymore and since there was not effect on the eye
I repeated Carc. in higher potency 1M and this was probably wrong
because after this the eye pressure went up very much.
What is so difficult in this case is that I cannot check on the eye
because it is always treated with allopathic treatment so I really got afraid
because suddenly they said now there’s glaucoma,
the eye pressure was very high and the pain in the Achilles tendon much worse.
– The pressure of the eye is a latter finding? How was it before the treatment?
– The eye pressure started when she was treated with cortisone orally,
before it was normal and when the oral cortisone started then the pressure went up.
And the highest pressure was 42 I think.
But when I saw her the pressure was 17.
And then because she was very warm again and stick the feet out of bed I thought Carc. was probably wrong,
I started with Sulph. 1Q but I didn’t see any effect.
In the meantime she was operated on the eye with laser
so the pressure wouldn’t go higher because of the glaucoma.
Then after this operation, it was 16 and this was in September last year.
And the symptoms were now in the Achilles tendon.
– Did you put red cheeks as a symptom?
– In September her fears were really very much reduced.
Only fear in the dark when she is alone, no more nail biting,
more self-confidence and I did not see a remedy so I thought,
well this nerve is destructed in the eye and I gave her Phos. in low doses only because of the nerve.
Under Phos. she developed a severe cough.
I gave is 30C twice a week and then when they stopped the Phos. the cough also stopped
and now the last I did because I really don’t know any more what she really needs was Ferr-p.
After it the eye is stable and we don’t have any more troubles with the eye
but I know it’s not a deep prescription.
I don’t see the remedy she really needs. I hope you do!
– You said she was a warm child. Is she still?
– She still is.
– She likes open air?
– She likes swimming in cool water.
– She has a shower with cold water?
– Showers not but in the sea she enjoys cold water.
– Do you understand English?
– No.
– Can you describe her character for us?
– She is a very pleasant child, very easy to handle, very obedient.
– If you tell her something will she do it?
– Mostly she does.
– Is she going to the school?
– Yes.
– Is she a good/medium student?
– In Mathematics she is medium and in language she is good.
– She has a lot of friends?
– Yes.
– She is a social child?
– Yes, very social.
– Is it really that she doesn’t bite her nails anymore?
– Is it true?
– She stopped.
– With what remedy did she stop biting her nails?
– After Thuja.
– She still likes smoked meat?
– She like it but not very much.
– No craving.
– What about bread?
– Yes. But she doesn’t desire noodles anymore.
– Fat?
– No.
– Is she sleeping ok without nightmares?
– Yes. She sleeps very well.
– She still likes to put ice in her mouth?
– She likes.
– And she likes to have cold drinks?
– She would drink it from the refrigerator but she doesn’t get it.
– Can she eat warm and cold food as well? She prefers cold or warm food?
– It depends on the food.
– But she is fighting now with her sister.
Before she never fought with her.
She also doesn’t accept if somebody hurts her in school, she fights back.
– Do you know if she grinds her teeth during sleep?
– She doesn’t.
– Does she ever use to come to your bed when she was sleeping in her room?
– No. Just when she was a little girl but then no.
– How much water does she drink?
– Normal.
– She likes fruits?
–Yes, she likes.
- What she likes best?
– Strawberries, nectarines and peaches. They have to be ripe.
– Oranges?
– She likes.
– Does she sing?
– Yes.
– Does she dance?
– She loves dancing.
– Is she sensitive when you reprimand her? When you make a remark how will she react?
– If she did something she puts her hands down.
– Does she cry?
– Seldom.
– She has pain in the Achilles tendon when she’s walking.
Still has it sometimes when she’s running walking for a long time.
– Is she having chewing gum now?
– Yes.
– Do you know if there is saliva running in the pillow in sleep?
– Yes, sometimes.
– Does she have aversion eating from a place she thinks it’s not clean?
– If an apple has a brown piece, she says I must cut it out.
Doesn’t like drinking from a glass when another person has drunk.
– Let’s go inside.
Everybody say “kalimera”! The class is quite heavy.
What happened? You don’t see the remedy?
You cannot find the remedy. Depression of homeopaths!
We have to go fast I will not discuss so much with the class but you ask question of course.
I will make the analysis of the case and the first thing we have to understand is
why this girl is in that condition.
This girl is in the condition because genetically she brings along disease which is quite serious.
I don’t know how much treatable it is with Homeopathy.
Scleroderma we have some effect,
no cure of such cases but in this case due to the fact that cortisone has been given
and repeated doses of it we have a transference of the disease from the skin to the joints.
Because it was given repeatedly cortisone so the disease was not allowed to stay in that level,
the disease moved into much more important organ and destroyed it.
There are 2 questions for the homeopath? Can you cure such case?
If somebody comes to you and he has interest if my child will see again the answer is absolutely no.
We can do nothing about the eye. The eye is finished.
Can you do something else? What can we do?
Not to progress, that’s one.
Definitely the disease is going to progress and it’s going to progress on the eye level
because the organism seems to have a sensitivity,
a weakness on this level so the disease will stay there.
Most probably the prognosis of the case is quite bad especially for the other eye.
What can we do? A patient comes to you in that state and you will say what?
First of all you cannot do anything for the eye,
what you can do maybe we can try to stop the progress of the disease.
Maybe. Why maybe? Because of several factors.
We have here a quite deep disorder we don't know how to handle it
and we have to handle it as I said to you from the beginning absolutely correctly from the beginning
and in order to have a really curative effect not just patching up things.
You have to give the first correct remedy, the second correct, the third correct, the forth correct,
the child will need a series of remedies within a treatment 3 years to do what?
Here is what we argue; Homeopathy is not a placebo story.
The first that will show you whether the remedy has acted or not, the stoppage of the progress,
is to bring back the inflammation on the knee that will be at least as bad as it originally was.
That will show you that the treatment is correct and if you treat further correctly the child
then you have to bring back the original skin condition.
That is the only way that you can know that your treatment is successful,
everything else is placebo effect or similar to it.
Don’t delude yourself that you are doing Homeopathy when somebody comes and says I feel better...
We have a story and the story has to go backwards in the order in which it came.
We go back to the treatment. [doctor’s name] is a good prescriber
but we have to see critically upon the treatment.
Was the treatment successful? She herself said no.
But now you know what is the problem? Because there are some changes.
What we have to do now is start the treatment.
That means if we want to have an effect we have to give the first remedy that was indicated but never given.
And most probably, some of the remedies which she gave would be again indicated in a latter phase.
Why these case are difficult? Because we have here the uppermost remedy with the symptoms.
Which is whatever, Sep.
And then you have an underlying layer which from time to time brings out some of its symptoms.
The second layer which is Nat-m. And then you have another layer.
Even the third layer can give out when you take up the case new symptoms.
You take all these symptoms which belong not only to the uppermost
but even to the second or to the third layer.
That’s why the uppermost case will look confused.
And you as a homeopath have to be able to see what is the real uppermost layer to prescribe first.
Like in her case the first layer has to be this layer.
If wrong treatment is given it will suppress and sometimes it will disappear totally this
and you will be not able to find anymore the remedy.
The reason is that Homeopathy as she did took away the warts.
Thuja was giving up some symptoms. You gave Thuja and you took out the warts.
But taking out the warts means nothing.
Biting of nails disappeared but it did on the expense of the rest of the organism.
When you try suppress the organism it doesn’t stay unmovable.
It’s not something steady. It tries to rebalance.
That means in trying to rebalance itself it will create a new picture that will be more confusing.
There you cannot see the remedy anymore.
That’s why prescribing superficially is very dangerous, not to the patient as side effect,
it’s very dangerous because you are going to confuse the case more and more
and finally when it comes to the real homeopath he has a big problem.
I prefer to treat cases treated only allopathically with heavy medication
than with homeopathic remedies one on the top of the other. It’s very dangerous.
I’m warning you because you may be thinking Homeopathy is doesn’t do any harm.
Take this or that. Youla told me one of the goats hit her here.
She has goats. Do I give Arn.? Why should you give Arn.?
If it is a little pain it will go away by itself.
Giving Arn. is speeding up perhaps.
But at the same time you don’t know what it is doing on the organism.
That’s why you have to be very careful to what you prescribe.
Even the least acute remedy. Because there are things that don’t need to be prescribed upon.
Of course if here in our case we have another 4 remedy Med.,
even it can come up like this and is better in the sea. Has warts,
better in the sea, sleeps on abdomen. You make a Med. case.
You can make a Med. case. Is this a Med. case?
It is a Med. case after Sep., Nat-m. and Thuja.
That is the real knowledge and the real art of Homeopathy.
After this lecture, Mr. Vithoulkas has told us what is the first remedy.
Say to us how we should have started in this case?
Give me the symptoms that you put in the repertory.
Nails, fear of being alone, of the dark, disaster, obstinate,
sensitive to odors, sympathetic, glaucoma, inflammation...
She is not obstinate. Take it out. The knee, warts, perspiration...
Salivation in the night, refreshing things desire, juicy things desire combined,
cold drink, cold water desire, fat aversion. Sensation of heat, ice desire.
He has made what we can call a bad repertorization.
As you know I never interfere with repertorization except of one time saying put that symptom.
Otherwise I don’t interfere.
This is a bad repertorization because he has put all the symptoms that were originally there
and symptoms that developed after the remedies.
But looking at the case recapitulating the whole case...
We have a patient here and we try to find the remedy that fits best for that child.
And we have a child who has some fears; fear of being alone, fear of the dark etc.
and who is a very nice child according to the description, not headstrong,
nice, sweet, obedient child who is hot and who desires cold things.
For any homeopath who knows a little bit of M.M. this brings you to one remedy. Puls.
A sweet child, an easy going child, who is hot, desires fresh air, doesn’t like fat, has fears...
- I was naturally thinking of Puls. but she never cries!
– Very good!  Do all Puls. cry?
– I think so.
– I’ve told you so many times!
Puls. many times cry but I have said I gave you the example of this woman from India,
the minister of textiles, she was controlling all the exports of textiles of India.
A woman like a man. Did you ever cry, I asked her? Never in my life.
I say this example many times...
Now, you have all the picture of Puls. fortunately for the class
because if she was crying everybody would say Puls. I was hesitating to ask the question.
I asked it in the end. And when I got negative answer I said nobody would think of Puls.
But you have to understand that the remedy for this case should have been Puls.
Show me the result of the computer with all this bad repertorization.
Even a bad repertorization, putting everything inside, I can make Puls. without any doubt.
Just put aversion fat instead of one, three times. And put disgust 3 times.
raise the intensity of the disgust and the aversion to fat and see what happens.
Only Puls. Don’t even consider another possibility.
It doesn’t give you a second possibility at all. That means there is no other possibility.
– Puls. has this craving for bacon but she cuts away the fat.?
– I don’t know.
– I ask if you ever saw it.
– I don’t know but you have given Caust. Caust. may be the fifth remedy.
What I say is that the totality shows that Puls. should have been given as a first remedy.
Don’t take into consideration negative symptoms. You thought of Puls.
Every homeopath should have thought of Puls.
If you do think of Puls. go back and study, don’t practice!
– I think there is a very typical misunderstanding not to consider Puls. in such case.
You would have missed it too. On one point I got the idea of Puls. and then I said no it can’t be
because you think it’s a good remedy for gentle diseases and that’s a misunderstanding someone often has.
If a remedy is gentle you don’t think that it has the power to cure such a violent disease.
That is a misunderstanding we have in our brain.
– I was treating in Germany, in the hospital in Munich was there anyone present? You were.
You remember a case of lupus? Puls. It’s a serious condition!
A systemic disease which has quite serious consequences.
What was interesting in this particular case...
I said Puls. and did not specify the potency. So the doctor gave 200C. No effect.
He says if George said Puls., we better try 1M. No effect.
He said if George says Puls. we might have a high potency.
The third month he prescribed Puls. 10M. Beautiful reaction, he says. I have his report...
She shows me her original repertorization where the VES says Puls. is in the second place.
– You remember von Boenighausen got Puls. from dr. Weiern,
a scholar of Hahnemann himself, to get cured from tuberculosis.
– Sure! Any disease. There is no differentiation of remedies;
this remedy is for an acute and this for chronic.
This is total nonsense. The most severe case of cancer may be cured by Acon.
– Puls. has desire for smoked food! I thought of Med. because of the arthritis in the knee!
– You disregard the child’s character, worse heat and you went to Med. Med. is not incorrect.
Most probably it’s the second or the third remedy.
It’s not totally incorrect and that’s the problem because you prescribed well and you changed the symptoms!
Because if you had prescribed altogether Ars...
- I just wanted to ask a question about the early childhood of this kid
because why would have such a severe otitis and got antibiotics for 6-7 times.
What about the story from the mother, the heritage, the pregnancy, the birth of the child?
– The otitis is covered very well by Puls. because it’s one of the main remedies for otitis.
But I what I would expect with Puls. that the knee, the skin, otitis
will come back but in the way it originally was. Not just little pain in my knee.
This is a little effort of the organism. It’s not the curative effort.
The curative effort would make the knee develop an inflammation which is quite bad.
– What about the eye?
– Once the knee is back no problem with the eye.
The destroyed eye is finished.
– Yes but before the knee is coming any eye problem?
– I don’t believe that.
She says she doesn’t remember but even there you may say that the organism under the antibiotics for otitis
has already gone down and is preparing to bring out an inflammation in the eye and the knee.
If the inflammation in the knee is allowed to develop the eye will be spared.
But iridocyclitis is considered as a rheumatic problem. Why do they say so?
Because they saw it is connected with rheumatic situations.
That’s why they call it a rheumatic disease.
It was the connection between the joints the inflammation in the iris.
This is what happens to the child.
It goes finally to the eye but the organism definitely will try to protect it as much as possible.