What is the problem?
– I feel in a way I’ve come through circle with a lot of things in the past
and I feel I need to be brought together.
Issues I’ve worked things through and I’ve done things very well,
I made progress but occasionally I have manifestation of anxiety attacks.
Mental thoughts which are unjustified.
And I react in such a way that it’s draining my energy
and I realize after a while that it was unnecessary
and my main aim now is absolutely focus on my work.
I feel I’m very fortunate at the moment, I am very happy with my life,
everything seems to have come together
and part of this anxiety had to with because everything I wanted has come.
I’m frightened of losing everything resulting back to the state I used to be.
Most of the time I am very good but that 2% has that draining effect on me.
– What was the state to which you are afraid that you may go back?
– It’s like things are going very well I feel that it overwhelms some times
and I fear I am going to ruin things, deliberately.
– Destroy things outside or inside you?
– Outside.
I have no problem with the inside.
I feel strong. But on the other side I’ve always avoided outside things.
I’ve spent a lot of my life building the inside
and now it’s materializing and sometimes every step of the way I have to check to see
that I’m doing it for the right reason
and if I have the slightest doubt I am not I have to pull it down again.
This is the first time in my life I am actually building the outside and it feels good.
– Give me an example because I don’t really understand.
– It’s very important that everything I do is on every level is being true to myself
and if I feel any falseness is cracked into my thinking in my life I have to destroy it.
Anything that is not genuine I cannot tolerate.
– She has to be true to herself.
If she feels she is not true to herself,
she has to destroy anything that isn’t true to herself.
– Yes. And sometimes I find myself deliberately provoking situations to test...
- Can you give me an example because you are talking very theoretically
and I don’t understand what it exactly means.
Give me an example. Are you married?
– No.
– You never married?
– No. I was determined to sort myself out,
feel strong enough, have no children
but I am at the moment for the first time I am in a committed relationship
that hopefully will marry next year.
My work, what I do in Homeopathy, is my life in the sense that I couldn’t do other things.
I found out what I was meant to do and I have quite a history in the past of incidents
that have happened which I have overcome which have been very severe.
– Like?
– A brief little history of what has been in the past;
I was a very happy child, spontaneous, I was brought in quite strict, religious background.
At 16 I was attacked, raped and as a result of that I cut off from the outside world
and I had no relationships till I was 25 and during that time I started very much
to want to sort myself out on a deeper level.
– How did you do that? By the help of a psychiatrist or psychologist?
– Myself. I started to be interested in things.
– After this rape you did not consult any psychologist?
– No.
– No psychologist, no psychiatrist. You tried to heal yourself.
– Yes I did. It was quite difficult;
I went through a few stages of suicidal attempts and gained 5 stone weight.
– It’s 30 kilos.
– What I was trying to say is that in the past I’ve overcome these things.
It made me realize what’s important in life, not superficial things,
I’ve always had opportunities to do well on the material level.
– You studied something?
– Yes, I used to be a lawyer.
– Did you finish your studies?
– I did but I hated it.
Because the kind of work that I had to do was very...
- My question is, did you finish your studies or gave it up?
– I dropped right to end.
I did all my studies for 5-6 years and then packed it in when I was in the last stage.
Then I came across Homeopathy.
– And then you went to one of these schools of Homeopathy?
– At what age?
– 30.
– Until that time you did not have any treatment either allopathic or homeopathic?
– No. I refused allopathic treatment.
I was always forced to have allopathic treatment because my mood swings I had.
– Did you break things, did you hit somebody?
Why did they force you to have treatment?
– Because I cut myself off and I became aggressive.
I wanted to kill everything. I never killed anybody. It was all inside.
I used to pull my hair out and scratch my face and destroy myself.
– And when you attempted suicide through which means did you attempt?
– Pills overdose.
– What pills?
– It was rather the amount than...
- Were psychiatric pills?
– No, just ordinary like paracetamol, aspirin, anything...
- How many times you did that?
– I did that twice.
– How were you saved? Taken to hospital or vomited?
– First time vomited and second time taken to hospital. But I managed to get out.
They wanted to give me treatment there but I wanted to get out of that.
I lied basically. I never told people what was the matter.
I couldn’t talk to anybody and I wouldn’t.
– Is it easy for you to talk about these things now?
– Yes, but only after Homeopathy treatment.
I couldn’t discuss it till my 30s, now it feels I got passed all this and I only mention it
because maybe they are relevant to those state I get back to.
I feel 98% ok. That’s why.
– Can you tell me what remedies you took?
– Yes. Ign. 1M April 1990, Ign. May 1990, Carc. 1M September 1990,
Staph. 1M November 1990, Stram. 200C 1993, Anac. 1M I gave that myself,
Plat. 1M May 1996, Aur. 10M I gave that myself June 1996
because I was given Plat. and I know it’s very suicidal and I knew I needed Aur.
Then I had for emergency reasons Lach. for a complication in surgical procedure.
That worked very well.
– 1M?
– No. It was 30C repeated about 5 times. Nat-m. 1M in June 1997 and Zinc. May 1999.
Theozamine June 1999 and Zinc. September 2000. That’s all!
– What was the result of this treatment?
– The first remedy I had, Ign., the first 3 days I got an energy boost and then felt nothing.
The repeat, nothing. Carc. nothing. Staph. nothing except I got skin eruption
which lasted for a very long time.
Stram. very good. That was the best reaction I ever had.
Anac. I felt it on the edge of the aggression I was going through. Plat. nothing.
– Anac.?
– Medium reaction.
I was getting very extreme I was afraid I would kill somebody.
I was really that bad. I was getting aggressive. 1M.
– What year?
– 1995.
-  And Stram. was 1993.
– Why didn’t you repeat Stram. if it was so good? You repeated it?
– No. I only had it once.
– Between 1993 and 1995 I see a gap without.
– Because Stram. did very well, I was actually doing very well for about a year or more.
I actually went back to my homeopath who gave me Stram. about after a year
and he said it didn’t do anything.
So I felt it in an Anac. state because very suddenly he wasn’t available,
so I took it myself.
– And in 1996...
- He gave Plat. when I was in bad state and did nothing.
I took Aur. And that did take the edge of things because I was so frightened,
I would do it again and I knew it’s no point,
you can’t keep your through your life keep repeating...
I literally made the decision after the second suicide attempt,
I said to myself if you go and do it again there was no point.
And I made a promise to myself that no matter what happens I will never do that again.
So when I saw myself getting in such a state I took the Aur. myself.
And it took the edge of it. And then Nat-m. did nothing.
Zinc. actually did help a little.
I was surprised I needed it, I thought it was a funny prescription.
I was so all over the place. No energy, not focused and very mental and physical fidgety.
It helped building the outside.
Theozamine nothing and Zinc. 200C to the edge of the things again.
I don’t think I am in a bad way at the moment.
– What is that 2% that bothers you? A state of panic?
– I get paralyzed. I feel as though everything’s overwhelming and I can’t cope with things.
I feel like I’ve got the capability, I know what I want to do,
I’ve got a lot to do and I feel very confident a lot of the time.
But when I get this 2% it’s like I can’t even begin to try control it.
It’s so overwhelming, I feel paralyzed.
I can cope with this now, it’s so rare but is still there, getting less and less.
It’s very extreme when it happens and it takes me out for a week after.
I feel so drained, very tired afterwards.
– Exactly an example you are afraid of losing?
– It’s very difficult when I am not in the state to explain it
but I just think that anything I build I’ll sabotage it.
It’s like I build something too high, I like to trigger a reaction
that I can justify finishing with something before that I can say...
- If you will give us an example like I had a relationship and then this happened
and this is what I thought and this is how it ended up... Real example.
– In the past I had 2 abortions.
And there were circumstances where I was frightened of the circumstances.
I didn’t feel it was right for me on lots of levels and it was very difficult decisions.
Especially the first. Emotionally I was terrible.
It wasn’t an easy decision. But I had to.
I felt unless I am strong and got everything in perspective
it’s just not right to build anything and although looking back I think for me on a deeper level
it was the right choice apart from the fear of not being right
but in the present time I am very happy with my relationship and it’s very good I think.
But there is a part of me which is frightened if I’ll deliberately destroy it.
– You are afraid of your past, that the habits of your past may come back and you destroy something.
– I don’t think they will but every now and then it’s there.
When it comes on my I shake.
And if anyone says anything to me I take it the wrong way,
any comment I think it’s a personal attack and I overreact.
– Can you give me an example? Swearing? Shouting? Hitting?
– I get quite aggressive myself. Perhaps be sharp with people and I shouldn’t be.
I pick something which I think will hurt and say it to get them before they get me.
I do that, not very often, but I do that.
I’m also very suspicious  finding very difficult to trust people.
If you’re by yourself, you’re ok because none can get to you.
But I’m not like that. I want to be with people and I want to be in relationship
but I have this fear that one day the floor is going to be pulled under the feet
everything will scatter and I’, frightened because if I get in that case...
I know how I got before and I’m frightened...
- All these remedies you have taken did somebody else give it to you
or are the self-prescribed?
– I got 2 myself; Aur. 10M and Anac.
– All the others have been given by a homeopath.
The homeopath who has given them to you is inside the class?
– No. Just of the remedies, the Zinc.
Apart from that I’ve seen 3-4 homeopaths through.
I’ve got some generals, may be relevant.
What I tend to do is if I am upset emotionally I have this hobby of needing,
it’s not fear of loneliness, for comfort if it warm weather, not very hot weather,
I need a hot water bottle.
It doesn’t release anything any upset or if I feel shaky or worried.
I have to hold it like this.
– Because you feel inner coldness?
– I know thing.
When I have these attacks it’s interesting. I often feel it’s like coldness.
When it is very extreme and things are being really upsetting I feel like ice inside sometimes.
I love hot drinks, I drink gallons of very hot tea.
I feel better for eating all the time, I love food. My appetite is very good.
Physically I don’t think I have any problem on every level, in sleep or anything.
I think I am happy at the moment. I’ve purpose.
– Did always speak in this way, very fast?
– Yes.
Sometimes I’m alright, slower.
But if I feel a bit excited I can do a little bit too much.
One thing that might be relevant.
I have a situation a whole life with my mother.
She has always been very difficult and I was undermined a lot of my confidence.
– The first time that you said you were raped it was somebody from your relatives?
– I joined the police at 16, a cadet, and he was an instructor in charge.
I was very young. It was an authority figure.
And I do have a bit of resentment against the people who trigger me off,
people who are perhaps quite pompous and arrogant.
I take an instant despite to them.
Maybe they don’t mean to be but if I perceive them to be superior and thinking this superior,
I don’t get I want to kill them back again, I can recall that feeling.
– Aggression.
– Yes because when you trust somebody who is supposed to be looking after you
and they take advantage of that situation
and you get angry with yourself for allowing yourself to be so susceptible.
And yet you shouldn’t do that. I am struggling to be strong enough.
– This experience which seems to be quite important for your case
came as a surprise to you or it was expected because he was flirting?
– It was interesting because he was the kind of person who was much older,
a sergeant training cadets.
A lot of the girls 16 used to enjoy flirting with him
but I wasn’t like that. He was a little bit false.
He was the kind of person who would say the right things to the right people
to get a promotion and never got it.
In the people who were below he wouldn’t get any interest.
I wasn’t going out with anybody, even though I was 16.
I just spoke to him as I would always with his last name.
He liked the girls call him by his first name and be friendly,
I called him by his second name.
There was something about that I shouldn’t really like.
I don’t hate him or dislike him. He started by picking on me.
He said I did things which I hadn’t done.
We used to do training, running and swimming
and he said that I was laughing at him.
– How long you stayed there in the police?
– I carried on in the cadets for 2.5 years and then I did my 2.5 years as a constable.
I completed my probation. I left when I was 21.
– What I want to understand is he really raped you or he tried to?
– He did.
– And it was your first experience.
– Yes.
I thought I was going to die, that he wanted to kill.
He threatened me with a knife and I’ve still got a scar,
he broke a bottle and cut me a little bit.
I was so disappointed of myself because I wanted to fight
but I thought it would get very violent if I try to fight so I almost cut off emotionally,
I just switched off and couldn’t feel anything.
And I honestly thought I would get out alive, I thought I would die.
That fear stayed with me, till I had Stram. I was never of the fear till I had Stram.
– Now, this feeling comes back sometimes?
- That terrible feeling never got back as bad. It was like feeling half-dead.
Emotionally I couldn’t relate.
– You were paralyzed.
– Yes. No relationship. I couldn’t relate till I was 25 I never went out.
And I went to extremes. Between 16 and 25 I never went out with anybody.
Not even kissed. 25 just like that I started going out with lots of people.
Within one week I got out 6-7 people. From one extreme to another.
I was trying to feel something.
– At this time did you enjoy going out or it was bad experience again?
– It was different because I didn’t feel right.
I was like observing. It wasn’t really me.
– You were doing this out of curiosity and see how you will feel?
– I think it’s a bit right.
I don’t know why I spent 11 years not going socializing, not going out with people.
It’s just how I felt.
– But after you started going out...?
– It was better for me because to be able to communicate better with people.
– This incident was not reported to the police?
– No.
– And it was just one time and didn’t try again.
– Did you threat him?
– I got transferred.
There was an incident just after then he tried to threaten me,
accidents can happen and I turned around very aggressively
and said I could kill him but I didn’t.
Interestingly, there was an incident 2 years ago, where I feel better.
Almost a similar thing happened in my clinic where I work.
I was attacked, attempted this time I fought him off and I took the case to court,
it was a trial and it was very difficult.
I got him convicted and I felt that’s what I should have done years ago.
It gave me an opportunity in a field with than unresolved issue
because I felt much stronger then.
– How do you feel in the dark now?
– I’m fine now.
– Before?
– It was terrible.
In those I was absolute picture case of Stram. I had terrible nightmares for 6 years,
terrible dreams of being chased by black,
vicious dogs that ripped me to pieces, I could feel the pain.
When I had my Stram. I had a tremendous aggravation.
I went upstairs, I went to a corner and I was shaken,
so frightened to move out of the corner till the afternoon of the next morning.
– Stayed there the whole night?
– I couldn’t move. I stayed in the nighttime, that was interesting after Stram.
– And when did you start feeling better.
– 2 days after I walk up with without a dark,
heavy feeling that I have carried with me.
The heaviness was gone. It was the most amazing reaction to remedy I’ve ever had.
– And the fourth or fifth day you started feeling lighter?
– Yes. I felt like my old self again.
I used to be very light and I became very heavy, dark,
used to think about death all the time.
– Now you can sleep in the dark without any problem or you need still some light.
– I’m alright now. I usually, when I am by myself, I like to see the night light, the sky.
And funny enough, one thing I have noticed is,
my present partner wants to sleep in 100% dark and I am ok with it with him.
In the past I couldn’t be like that with anybody.
I couldn’t stand the dark. I’m alright now.
– What I asked before, at the age of 26 you started going out and having affairs,
were you able to function sexually?
– Yes, but not really. Mechanically. I didn’t get anything out of it.
It’s a bit of ego boost, I guess,
because I got a lot of attention and I found out a lot of people wanted to go out with me and nice people.
I guess on one level but for myself I felt out of it.
I realized after short time that I didn’t want to go out with many people
and so chose 1 person out of 7 that I decide I quite like
and I’ll go out with him as boyfriend and I stayed with him for 8 years.
I never really loved him and he knew that and he said I do and I will do.
I used to feel very bad that I knew and used to tell him.
We had good times and he was a very nice person
but a bit possessive and restrictive and I had problems when I decided I wanted to get away from him.
He was very clingy and saying he will kill himself if I do that.
But I had to get away and it was the second time when I got into a bad state,
suicidal, I had to decide, I felt so trapped.
I thought I can’t have the responsibility for someone else doing that.
I can’t live with him.
And what managed make me break away was I met someone who’s completely different,
much younger and that was a genuine relationship.
I’ve only had 2 genuine relationships.
– The one you have now?
– This is the second.
– How do you feel with the last relationship?
– When I met this younger person it was a very good healing relationship.
We used to talk about things, I discussed things that happened.
We were interested in so many different things and we helped each other.
Even though we knew it wouldn’t last forever, I knew that but it was right for me.
You need it now but I knew you will get out of it and he was a lot younger.
We finished at the right time.
But it was a good relationship and I did the right thing in finishing it.
The present relationship I think is very good.
– How old is he?
– He is 65 in 3 weeks!
– But you still feel comfortable.
– Can you function with him sexually?
– Yes very good. But on every level.
– With the younger one were you functioning sexually?
– Yes. These were the 2 relationships that were functioning.
– That means you were enjoying sex.
– Yes.
– You want to say something more?
– I do feel very good with the present relationship
because although the other relationship was very good as well
it felt more like I was still finding what I wanted to do myself
and now I feel on every level we can complement each other very well.
I’m not making excuses I feel genuinely challenged in the right way.
– If you had this original man in front of you would you still like to kill him?
– It’s a very interesting question! No. I went through that.
– How?
– I worked through it. Because of what I believe in. It is not a religion.
I truly believe that what comes around goes around and in a way he triggered things in my life
which I would have gone along a certain path.
I’ve got wonderful things happening now which I believe wouldn’t have happened.
I feel now it was worth working through things.
And if he is still alive, he had a lot of enemies actually,
he was the type of person who would remove people, male colleagues,
he’d get them lose their job. To live with himself must be very difficult.
Because ultimately I think peace of mind is the most important thing and he can’t possibly have it.
– So you feel he has been punished already?
– I don’t know but I think sooner or later it will happen.
The last comment I was going to make has to do with my current situation.
I do worry a little about my parents, my mother.
She is a bit mentally ill and she had a big effect on me in my lifetime.
As I get older I realize the I can’t be responsible for her.
– Is she in an asylum?
– No. She is very split personality now.
I’ve tried to relate to her and she’ll very aggressive with me.
Nasty things she will say and deny and that’s been very upsetting recently.
– Do you still have dreams of violence?
– No. Very rarely.
– Did you ever take drugs in any period of your life like marijuana?
– No. One thing I’ve always been, no matter how hard things got,
I would not accept allopathic medicine. I wouldn’t touch drugs.
I am not even drinking. I enjoy it but I am not really a drinker.
– Marijuana?
– Got once purely out of curiosity.
– Did it have any effect on you?
– Yes. I got the smallest amount.
But it wasn’t me. I’ve got always to be controlled. I didn’t need it.
– Where you infected by any veneral infection?
– No, I’ve never had.
– Do you perspire?
– I am at the moment but not usually.
– You feel cold or hot?
– I tend to be on the chilly side.
– Your feet are usually cold or normal?
– Everybody who touches them complains there are very cold.
They can get cold. Sometimes I’m very cold but I don’t feel cold.
People say oh you’re cold!
– When they touch you.
– Yes.
– Do you put on weight easily?
– Only if I deserve to.
I have to eat quite a lot to put on some weight.
If people ate what I eat would be much bigger!
I have quite a good appetite.
– Do you eat sweets as well? What do you like to eat?
– I don’t like shellfish. I love pasta, potatoes, chocolate.
I like it as well as other things.
I like puddings, not too sweet, sweetish.
I like things like chilly, onions...
- Thirst?
– I would say I am not thirsty but I drink lots of tea so I take a lot of liquid.
I drink 30 cups a day!
– Warm?
– Very hot! I love very hot temperature in food and drink.
– Are you fastidious at all?
– No. The opposite.
One of the things regarding that is I get very frustrated with the clutter.
I want to simplify things. I seem to attract it!
– Do you have any fears?
– I guess I’ve covered it in the sense that I have a fear about making a wrong decision.
I used to have terrible fear of insanity when I was a child.
I don’t have that anymore. I know I am not!
– Do you eat eggs?
– I like eggs, yes.
– Very much?
–Yes.
– Do you have fear from high places looking down?
– I wouldn’t say it’s a fear, I wouldn’t go to edge of places.
– Fear of death?
– Not anymore.
– I spent a lot of time thinking about these things.
When decided after my second suicide attempt that I will never do that again
I imagined myself doing that and thinking if I am dead then that’s it so what do I got to lose?
I imagined I’ve done it and everything else is a bonus!
I am not frightened of anything. I’m pretty fearless in some respect.
I would take any kind of challenge.
I don’t mean silly challenge, within reason.
Nothing really frightens me anymore.
I’d react to things.
– Dogs?
– It has to be a vicious, aggressive dog.
Even then I would think, I am really good in thinking in nervous situation, I keep calm.
Maybe now I am talking fast or seem nervous but in emergency I can think under pressure.
– At this moment do you consider yourself as being calm or trying to control yourself?
– I feel a little a little bit fluttery, shaky. I don’t know.
If there’s something apprehensive about something I can shake,
perhaps it’s not visible to someone else
but I know because I get a cup of tea
and I’ll be going like this have to pull myself and it will pass. Not very often.
– Can you speak easily in front of people?
– It depends.
If it is something I believe in, in informal situations I can talk forever.
But formal situations... I haven’t practiced on that.
I’m pretty open with people. I will openly talk about many subjects.
– You didn’t say anything about the father. Good relationship?
– My father is 81, he is Polish, and he is very strong constitution.
He’s a really good person.
I’ve realized as I got older my mother dominates this relationship
and unfortunately he doesn’t speak up for himself.
I get very angry with him.
Recently, this is an issue for me,
he doesn’t react and then he says to me why is this and why is that
and he doesn’t do anything about it and he is so capable.
I get angry for him sometimes. I get angry at my mother for him.
– Do you want to hit your mother when something like this happens?
– I have actually recently hit her twice and I’ve never done that before.
I’ve slapped her twice. I felt bad for myself.
After many many years I realized how in a way she undermines,
criticizes and dominated my father.
It was almost on behalf of both of us and I know it’s not the right thing to do.
– You were impulsive.
– Impulsive but I couldn’t also apologize for it after because it was a true what I felt.
Perhaps I shouldn’t. I know maybe it’s perhaps of her illness.
She can say some very hurtful things.
– Well, thank you!
Do you all agree that in the beginning the interview was jerky?
Who agrees with that? Let me see how many people agree.
How many people agree with what Margit was saying that in the beginning of the interview
she was quite in a state of not calmness, she was too excitable, jerky.
And eventually she calmed down.
It was a difficult interview
because there was a excitement which can easily go overboard
unless you know how to handle it so people can feel more confident and comfortable
so this excessive excitement will calm down and they will able to express more.
This was one these cases where in the beginning she was quite excited,
not able to put her thoughts into a very coherent route
but eventually she became much calmer and showed her real character.
There was a possibility of misunderstanding in the beginning concerning the mental state
and eventually things became calmer.
Concerning the remedy I have to say only a few things.
The remedy that was really the correct was Stram.
and should have been given in even a higher potency.
There is no question about that.
The next remedy which acted was Aur.
But it acted because she took 2 wrong remedies before
that brought her into the state of Aur. Anac. and Plat. were wrong prescriptions to the extent
that she was brought into that state.
Got Aur. herself and somebody gave her Plat. afterwards due to the fact,
most probably, that was relating this experience,
what she was doing sleeping with different people, changing partners.
But this is not a case of Plat.
Because a Plat. is not going out of curiosity
but out of real need for sexual intercourse.
When Plat. is stimulated on this level there is an absolute need
to have a kind of release on this level
and the release doesn’t come that means the orgasm is not deep enough,
it’s a superficial orgasm, which doesn’t satisfy deeply
and there is a constant need for a stimulation and again superficial orgasm etc.
They can 5-10 orgasms in a day without being happy and satisfied.
This was not the case.
She said I was going out to find out why others were doing this,
I also want to do it. But she said I felt nothing.
Forget Plat. in such a case.
A woman can go with 50 men in a few days and is not Plat.
if she goes out of curiosity or as an ego booster.
What shall we do in such case?
Let me see how many people say to give Stram. same potency. Stram. higher potency?
A new remedy? 6. Wait? 1. What new remedy would you give?
– Sep.
– Med.
– Hyos.
– Thuja.
– What is happening is like this;
after Stram. she had several wrong remedies and she had Aur. which balanced again the organism
because it was going suddenly to the wrong direction and Zinc. she said I feel something going on.
– I gave the Zinc. My observation is that it has helped as she says she is very fidgety, always moving.
And this has calmed down.
– You think it had an effect.
This is how a homeopath should analyze this case.
The patient reports that Stram. was very good. Never repeated.
And then she comes to the point as we said Aur. and then back again
but still in a fidgety state as Ernest is saying,
gives Zinc. 200C 1 year ago and there was some calming effect still you cannot say
that all these remedies after Stram. had done something substantial except of Aur.
that was after Plat. the case was aggravated without curative effect.
This is the case where we have aggravation without curative effect and Aur. brought her back.
If we do proper analysis we have to say this;
that this case having  Stram. very positive effect we have to repeat this
to see if can take further the case.
The problem is, what you have to ask yourself,
is whether the Stram. picture is coming back or it started coming back.
Are we sure that Stram. picture is coming back? It’s not clear at all.
I tried to investigate the issue of Stram.
with the darkness, aggression, the hatred, the violence.
Apart from this incident in which she slapped her mother which she feels it was an act of justice for her,
not of injustice because her mother is torturing her father
according to what she understood and somebody had to do something so she did it.
We are justified to repeat the remedy when we have a relapse
or quite a good picture of the remedy again.
Even if the pathology is not as deep as before.
But you have to have the keynotes of the remedy
before you can expect to have an effect on this case.
I tried to find out whether the keynotes are coming back.
A big keynote is the fear of the dark. Another keynote is nightmares.
You remember the previous case with the nightmares,
and these nightmares, Stram. nightmares?
She had similar nightmares with her. Similar stories and pictures.
The nightmares are not there, the fear of darkness is not there,
the violence is not there, she is quite happy
and what she says from time to time I get into the feeling that maybe I will do something,
I will make a wrong decision, fear of disaster, fear that I will bring a disaster in my life.
Give the repertorization which you did...
So the repertorization will again show Stram. 20 out 25 symptoms.
It has a lot of symptoms.
Most of you will give a higher potency of Stram., correct?
– Hyosc. is the only remedy with fear of being betrayed.
Knowing more about the situation with her mother,
she must have a feeling that her mother goes against her so much.
This is a strong consideration for Hyos.
Feeling of  being betrayed, self-betrayal.
– The problem is that when you prescribe a remedy
especially in a sensitive case of that type you have to base your prescription in something really solid.
So the most solid appears to be Stram.
but not solid enough and that should make you cautious.
The next question you have to ask do we have another remedy
which is quite solid and quite indicated in her case?
And if you put that question, what is the answer?
Excuse me eating but we are not going to have an interval and my energy is going down.
Tell me. No answer. The answer is no.
We don’t have an alternative at this case.
We don’t have Hyosc., Zinc., Puls., Calc.
We don’t have something solid to prescribe upon.
Therefore unfortunately in this case you have the right answer
(you can experiment with whatever you like)
is wait until you have more confirmation for Stram.,
most probably, or for another remedy.
In this situation where she says 90% of the time I am happy,
given the fact that she has been through hell, quite a lot,
being an Stram. for more than 10 years,
because this is one of the remedies that is not very pleasant being in that state of Stram.
And the fact she says everything that happens to me is on a mental/ emotional level,
not on the physical, so she has been suffering quite a lot in the mental/ emotional level,
given the fact that her mother has some problem on these levels,
we have to be very careful on how we prescribe on such a case.
You see Plat. took her off! It’s not a case on which you can experiment and give a remedy.
You can give a remedy and see what happens, you can do that of course
and then your best guess would be Stram.
but I am not sure that at this moment Stram. would not have an aggravation without an amelioration.
Then what happens is especially when you’re not experienced homeopath
you immediately jump into counteracting this by different other remedies
and as a result you find yourself in a bad situation
because it’s not producing a picture.
What would be the picture if after Stram. in 1996 and she come to us 5 years later
and says I want to be treated,
it’s my impression, now we would be able to find more easily the remedy,
either a new remedy or a Stram. to be as relapse case.
Now, it’s difficult because of the interference of the other remedies.
And therefore taking a chance to prescribe a remedy at this moment is really taking a chance!
– I would like to know when she gets in those states which she described,
which are very seldom does she then have any Stram. signs like fear of dark?
– No, I don’t get that but it’s more paralyzing.
I cannot think usually. That’s the overwhelming sensation.
But the dark is not a problem.
– She seems to have a paralysis of her will, that she cannot decide,
is afraid to make a decision or the decision may bring about a kind of disaster whatever it might be.
I was not able to make a decision and given the fact that she says 98% of the time
I feel good we have the luxury to say wait.
So the right answer was given by only 1 person...
This shows the real problem that we are facing each time with Homeopathy.
It shows really that things aren’t easy and you have to put a lot together
before you come to the right decision.
And the decision is always when you really benefit the patient.
All others are theory. And the theory is in order to support the patient.
It’s not like we like to have a theory.
The theoretical parts and the laws are in order to be able to make this kind of decisions.
Unless we have some rules to make these decision...
I could tell 2 or 3 rules... It’s not like that.
It’s a whole understanding of the theory, the M.M., the pathology,
the understanding how serious a case is, how deep it is, where it belongs to,
should you touch it, should you stimulate...
I understand your difficulties but these are the facts.