This case, a year ago received Puls. 10M and according to this report,
a big and deep change started the same day almost with Puls. 10M.
You can see in my first and second letter that a very deep healing process
started from that day and has continued until today.
The fax is on the 13th of March 2001.
"I have a feeling that my picture has changed so please do not stop prescribing, etc."
So, I would like to see what is the situation, where is it now?
- How it is today or shall I tell you what changes I had?
- Yes, you can give me the changes and then you tell me how it is today.
Straight away after Puls. the cramp in uterus, bladder and rectum was gone,
and after that also I had even more headache, I had a headache almost every day,
for I don't know how long. I was here in Alonnisos, I had headache all the time,
I couldn't sit in the class, I had to go out sometimes.
And also I took the Puls. here at the course, and here in Alonnisos...
- But you had an aggravation of the headache
- Yes
- It was worse these days
- Yes, it was worse
and also it was my feelings that I was talking about, from my childhood, about...
- Shall I read the report that you have sent me?
You say in your report, "on May 24th, the same day I got the remedy,
I had a much stronger headache, and gradually subsided during one week".
So for one week you had aggravation of the headache.
"I was swollen in my face, hands and feet. I felt sick and drained of energy.
My headache moved from the right side of my head to the left side.
The bleeding was reduced and on the 26th of May I started to get eczema
on my fingers and on the hollow of my knees. My headache were diminishing
and I had constipation which I had as a teenager".
- For a period of time you had it...
- Yes, through childhood and as a teenager
"On the 27th of May, still reduced bleeding, feeling of lack of confidence and worthlessness".
- Yes, that got worse here, in Alonnisos, much worse.
- "Feelings that I continuously had earlier in my life. And the headache eventually disappeared.
On the 3rd of June suddenly weeping and feeling worthless especially when comparing with other people.
The menstruation is small but does not stop completely, although the period should be over.
On the 5th of June, ultrasonic gynecological examination at the hospital
revealed a 2cm big submucosal myoma in my uterus. On the 13th of June, my menstruation came 6 days early.
On 15 of June, constantly depressed and despondent, which I was earlier in my whole life.
It went away during my education, I had psychosynthesis with Assagioli. August 99 to May 2000.
During the menstruation that began on the 13th of June, I had no cramps
in my urinary bladder, uterus or rectum. The blood was less clotted, the color was more bright red.
On the 3rd of July, still small bleeding, the menstruation does not stop completely,
eczema on forearms is much better, on finger it disappeared, no headache during this menstruation.
Since June 2000, my appetite has changed. I like meat, I need meat, I eat meat but not the fat parts.
Earlier I did not like meat except for shellfish, fish and chicken.
My dreams have changed before the 24th of May, weeping in dreams because of feelings
of being forsaken and outsider feelings. After taking Puls. my dreams have changed,
I have not had any such dreams. And the abdomen is not so bloated after eating."
- So, you can continue from there.
- Yes, right.
I still have this stiff neck, very much, and shoulders. I still cry very easily,
like I read the newspaper and start to cry, I easily cry. And I have still my dreams, but not in the same way.
It's a dream about a very-very deep sadness, only a sadness, I don't know what kind of sadness,
but I wake up crying. And I still very often wake up with dry eyes, I'm still pressing my teeth when sleeping.
- Pressing or grinding?
- No, pressing.
I have still very loose stool, and still my stomach swells when I'm eating, I want food
but it's very unpleasant when I have this. And I still swell everywhere,
my breasts, the whole body, my mind, everything is swelling up before menses.
But I've never had migraines, I'm so happy about that, and my eczema is gone. I still sleep with my hands over the head...
-You still sleep like that? Because there was a period where you did not sleep in that position.
-Yes that was a period, and it came back. Also I was eating meat suddenly. I don't want that now.
- Now you don't want meat?
- Not at all
- And you don't want fish?
- I can eat fish, but I prefer not.
What's new is that I have no sexual desire since... it started in August last year slowly,
with the depressions and so on, then this thing comes, and it still is very much so.
And it also is, that I have no desire for nothing. I'm still depressed, in a way.
I don't know if it's depression but I have a heavy mood all the time, I have existential crisis inside,
more or less all the time. And I have a feeling inside myself that I'm empty, I'm not alive,
not really alive, because nothing motivates me, I don't want any special food, any special drinks,
I don't want my sex life. Everything has changed, it's all going down on that level.
Other things is much better. And what's new also is that my hands are swelling up when I'm out walking,
and that is strange. And they go stiff.
- Do you like to walk?
- Yes, I love it.
- So there is one thing that you love.
- Yeah! That's true
- You walk fast or you like to walk slowly?
- I like to go slow.
And what's also new and is very strange is that, when I'm talking I have a lock, here in my right ear.
- As if the ear is blocked?
- Yes, I hear my voice inside the head all the time, when I am talking, but it doesn't bother me
when other people are talking, it's here on the right side. And that is new, I had it for a month,
I think. And what's new also is I have all the time feeling that my teeth are cracking,
when I'm eating I have to check if they are OK suddenly.
- As if cracking, as if breaking...
- Yes, suddenly I have a feeling like, oh, they are broken. So I'm a little bit scared when I'm eating.
And also what's a bit stronger now is my intuition, it's stronger than before.
- The blood has stopped?
- No, it's much better, but the pattern is I think the same,
because before I had 13-14 days of menstruation and it was very-very heavy about 7-8 days.
Now I still have 10-11 days of menstruation, but it starts normally, I have too much bleeding
for about 4 days, and then it's going down and it can't stop really.
- It can't stop till the next?
- No, not really. Yes, it will stop but it takes so long time.
- But the actual amount is less now, because before it was 6-7 days very heavy,
now it's 4 days heavy bleeding and another 7 days slight bleeding.
- Yes, and sometimes not really bleeding, but there is...
- Sometimes leucorrhoea?
- Something, there is red blood but it's not the menstruation really, it won't stop, that's the feeling.
- The color, what is the color? It's brownish or what? After the first 4 days?
- When it's trying to stop?
- Yes, before it stops.
- Then it's normal red.
- You have 4 days heavy bleeding, red. After the 4 days you have a little bit.
- Yes, but it's still menstruation, but in the end, it's turning to be something brownish.
- Is there any specific odor?
- No, nothing.
- After the bleeding, is there any kind of leucorrhoea, discharge?
- No.
Also what's new is that I have a kind of restlessness. That's not me, usually in that way,
I don't like it when the day goes on the same and the week goes the same.
Suddenly I want things to change, and that's very new for me.
- Very unusual you mean?
- Yes. And in a way I like it, but I also don't know how to handle it.
- Is this a feeling that you are bored and things must change, or is it a feeling of hurriedness?
- No, not hurriedness, I never feel in a hurry. I'm still this calm person. Yes, that's also new,
I don't have that temper like in the other interview in 2000, I was getting angry suddenly, and I don't now.
- Do you tolerate heat good or bad?
- No, I don't want heat, I can't breathe in the class.
- It's too stuffy for you
- Not stuffy, but it's bad air, it stands still, I want fresh air
- Anything else?
- What's gone also is today I feel my limits, before I didn't feel my limits,
I always did too much and then I go down, I feel my limits.
- And you can say, I don't want anymore?
- Yes, I can say Stop! and that is very good.
The eczema didn't go so bad as I thought it should. You told me last year that the eczema
with Puls. 10M would come back, it did, but I have never had eczema on the whole body.
I thought it would come back much more.
- It came but not enough, that is the impression.
- I don't know if it should be more, but I was thinking it should.
But now I'm very tired of feeling like this. I had enough for myself.
I don't want to feel this heavyness and emptiness. And it's terrible that my sexual drive is gone.
It used to be very good for the first time in my life.
- And why do you think this happened? Are there any external reasons for that according to you?
- I've been depressed so long, something to do with that, and the bleeding, I was very tired of it..
- When you took the psychotherapy? The Assagioli therapy?
- I'm making education, yes?
- What do you mean? You are educating yourself or you're educating others?
- I am going in the school...
- To educate yourself
- Yes.
- But Assagioli, as far as I know is psychosynthesis, that's what they call it. Are you still going now?
- Yes, I have one more year left.
- And during this period you are applying some of these principles to yourself?
- Yes, of course.
- Did it cross your mind that maybe what you had, this bleeding, and the myoma, it might be cancer?
- It is not cancer, I checked that. I did an operation, did I write that?
- No.
- In October 2000 they took away one polypous, about 1-2 cm, but I still have a myoma 1-2 cm and I don't want to do any...
- Did it cross your mind that it might be cancer?
- Yes
- And did this idea affect you? Did you say "Oh God, I cannot have a child,
and my uterus will be gone" and things like that.
- I was thinking about death, and the whole life from childhood up to about 1997,
I didn't want to live. But then it changed and I want to do that. When you asked these questions,
and I was thinking about cancer, then I thought "Am I going to die? I don't want to die now".
That's what I was thinking.
- During previous years, when you were depressed, you had attempted suicide?
- You asked me that before, and I had said no, but I've been thinking about it,
and when I was about 15 I tried to take my life in a very naive way.
It wasn't really serious, it was a shout for help. But I wouldn't do that now. Not at all.
- Do you take a nap in the afternoon, sometimes?
- No, not at home. I do here.
- How do you wake up after a nap? You wake up refreshed or unrefreshed?
- Refreshed. I wake up refreshed in the morning too. I sleep very good.
- Your sleep has changed after Puls. or it was always good?
- It was always good.
- And refreshed
- Yes, I like to go to sleep.
- How much water you drink now?
- That is strange, I don't drink as much as before.
- You drink less.
- Yes.
- Your desire for sweets is less?
- I have no desire for nothing. No sweets, nothing.
- But you still eat it.
- Yes, I eat it.
- You lost some weight?
- No, I would love to but it's difficult. I put on weight.
- This [.....] I would like to investigate this, why you took these injections?
- Yes, I forgot to tell you. Sorry about that.
- Since December, you write here
- Berberis D2, Ultrica Urens D3, that's a mixture of injections for the myoma. Anthroposophical injections.
- You still take them?
- No.
- How long did you take them?
- I wrote it somewhere, I only had the Puls. at least, I think 8 or 9 months, nothing else,
and then I started these injections, and then I stopped and then I started again, twice a week.
And what also I can mention, I can feel in here something pinched me sometimes. I've been sighing very much.
- Do you eat fruits? A lot?
- I eat every day. I like them. No special desire.
- You like smoked meat...
- I don't eat meat at all.
- Before, you used to like smoked meat?
- That period, when I was sending this fax to you, I ate meat, but no, I didn't take smoked meat.
- How long is now since you are sleeping again with the hands over your head?
- Since the end of the winter. February, I'm not sure
- You said that crying now is more easy.
- Yes, I think after Puls. that is more.
- You cry more easily and more times?
- Both.
- You have to repeat Puls.
- I knew you would say that.
- Take 1M and 10M. 1M the first day, 10M the second, and 10M the third. 2 times 10M,
unless there is a reaction within the first day. If you take 1M and there is a reaction,
you develop a headache, or an eczema, whatever reaction, you don't take any more.
But if there is nothing, no effect, the next day you take 10M, the other day, third day, another 10M.
- I hope my husband is writing this down.
- 1M the first day, the second day 10M and the third day 10M. Take it like this,
and forget about the rest. 1M, 10M, 10M. Three days.