Heavy menstruation. Very heavy.
– Heavy with a lot of blood?
– A lot of blood.
– What type of blood?
– There are 2 kinds.
It’s the normal blood and also this very thick clots and it is so much of it.
I have very rich for at least 5 days and totally the menses go on for 13 days.
So I got very tired.
– Most probably you have been examined by gynecologists.
What is your specialty? Are you a M.D.?
– No, I am a massage therapist.
– And you have been examined by gynecologist?
– No. This started... not so long ago. It started at least one year ago.
I protect myself from getting pregnant and then I had this spiral.
– When did you use this spiral? 1,5 year ago?
– The first time was is 1997.
– 3 years ago. But the bleeding is...
- It must be for about 1,5 year. Nearly 2 years.
– So it is not due to the spiral. You don’t think it is due to it.
– I think it is because it started then.
I had this first spiral in 1997 and this heavy bleeding started.
After 2 years I took it out and the bleeding went on. I didn’t get normal again.
– That means now you don’t have this spiral.
– No.
– And the bleeding continues but it started 3 years ago after the spiral.
– When I had the spiral. Then I took it out.
It got a little bit better after a time and then I tried another spiral and then it got worse at once.
And I got this problem with migraine my whole life. But it’s much better nowadays.
– How is that better?
– It’s better for about 3 years at least.
I took out my amalgam 3 years ago and everything got much better. Eczema also.
– But these headaches started at what age?
– I had it since I was 22 or something.
– Why did they start?
– I don’t know. So I took all the amalgam out.
– At what age?
– It was somewhere in the 80s I took it out. Perhaps 30 years.
- And the headaches continued...
- After that it started to go better.
– But really better it got 3 years ago.
– Yes. It was gone for quite a long time.
But it comes sometimes with these heavy menses,
before the menstruation and 3 days while the menstruation has started.
– So every time you have the menstruation the headache also comes before the menstruation?
– Sometimes it doesn’t come.
– Most of the times it comes.
And what is the form of these headaches?
– I got my menstruation now, when I am here and also had the headache,
I take some pills because otherwise I can’t be here but it starts feeling as if I have a helmet,
like cotton in my head all over and then it concentrates on the neck
and this time is on the right side and goes up in the head like a needle in the eye.
Sometimes on the left but mostly on the right I think.
– And it starts on the back?
– Yes I have very tense muscles here in me shoulder and my neck.
– And the headache is such that it can make you vomit?
– No, I don’t throw up. All my energy is totally gone and you can do like that I will fall.
– Exhaustion during the headache.
– Yes. I can hardly stand up and do things. I feel totally empty.
– And if you don’t take medicine you have to lie down?
– Yes.
– You have to take medicine every time?
– When it’s heavy I do.
Otherwise I just try like this. Aspirin, no stronger things.
– Anything else?
– I have these eczemas since I was a child.
– Where?
– Now or back in time?
- Back and now.
– As a child I had in my arms and back of the knees
and then in teenage I had very much on my hands and for some period I had it around my face, my lips,
but that was a short time.
And when I was 30 years old I had very much on my hands all the time
and it was very difficult with my children.
I also used very much cortisone.
– Do you remember at what age the eczema started? You don’t have to be very accurate.
– Perhaps from 10 to teenage.
– And the headaches started at about 23. 10 years later.
In the meantime when eczema was the worst? What age?
– In the 30s. When I was 30-32...
- 30 and onwards it was worse the most of it. The children were small.
– When did it become less? At what age?
– It started when I took out the amalgam then it got better... I don’t know. About 1982.
– So you were 32 by that time.
– And then years go and everything goes better, eczema and the migraine.
– And you use cortisone ointment?
–I had done that when I was a child and when I was growing up.
– When you were 30 and the eczema was bad did you use cortisone?
– No, I did not because I met the anthroposophical medicine when I was about 20.
So I tried not to use cortisone.
– But they gave you anthroposophical medicine.
– Yes, but didn’t help.
– So you think the amalgam helped you.
–Yes. I have that feeling because when I took that out things happened.
– No do you have any salivation during sleep?
–No. I wake up with dry eyes. Not every morning, but it is often.
And I like to drink water in the night. A little sip.
– What else you suffer from?
– Now when I have these heavy menses I also have cramps in my rectum,
uterus and bladder the 2-3 first days of the menses.
It’s so heavy that I have cramp. It’s quite new, I didn’t have that before.
– What was the last remedy that you took?
– I haven’t had any remedy. I’m totally clean!
I am excited to see what you can do!
I have taken twice some pills for this heavy bleeding,
otherwise I couldn’t be here.
Perhaps it is important to know; tranexamic acid.
That’s something that makes the bleeding less.
– The blood from menses is thin or there are clots?
– Very big clots.
– But at the same time the blood itself is like normal or thinner?
– Perhaps thinner.
– Do you have any leucorrhea after menses?
– No. The menses has difficulties to stop completely.
It seems to stop and then it comes a little bit more for a few days or week and then it’s completely stopped.
– Did you have an abortion in your life?
– Yes, I had. I had in 1986, 1987 induced abortion.
In December 1999 spontaneous abortion that was one week after I after expecting my menses.
– Can you describe this condition for me? What is the feeling of the cramp? Is there pain?
– Where I go on the toilet and the stool is coming it hurts.
– The rectum feels cramped.
– Yes, when the stool is coming the uterus cramps and I try to relax.
– And there is a pain or no pain?
– A little pain.
– But what about the cramps in the bladder?
You feel the uterus, the rectum and the bladder all cramped.
– I don’t know if it hurts. Of course, I feel it but it’s not painful.
I have to concentrate on relaxing. One week before menses I sweat a lot in the night.
I also get loose stool 1-2 days before menses so I know it is coming.
I like eat more food before menses.
I have more appetite and I don’t feel when it is enough.
This is just before menses the other days I don’t feel hungry so much.
– What would you like to eat?
– I don’t crave anything special. I don’t eat meat.
– What do you like best?
– Perhaps a little bit heavy food.
I love salad but I can’t live on it.
– You say you don’t eat meat but you like heavy food.
– Pasta and some nice vegetable sauce that’s heavy for me. Augbergine, tomato, garlic.
– Can you eat the fat of meat?
– No. I don’t like it.
– Not at all? You take it out?
– Yes, I take it out.
– Before menses I get irritated. I get easily angry and so.
I love to sleep on the back with my hand over the head. I love thunderstorms.
– What else can you say?
– When I am sleeping, I am grinding teeth.
– Did anybody tell you that?
– I feel it. I’m very tired in my teeth.
– Your husband who was sleeping with you he was telling you, you are grinding your teeth?
– No, he is snoring so he doesn’t know.
– Are you sure you grind your teeth.
– I feel it because I am tired in my teeth.
– You think you are grinding your teeth.
– Perhaps I am pressing more than grinding. I feel I have been pushing them in the night.
And I have difficulties to feel when my own strength is gone.
I work easily too hard till it’s too late.
– Next?
– I’m scared of heights. When I look over the edge it feels like needles in my legs.
– How do you feel emotionally?
– Good. I am happy.
– You have no specific problem.
– No, my life is good now.
– Are you worried about your children?
– I think I’m normal mother.
– In general you feel cold or hot?
– Sensitive to draft.
I get easily tense in my neck and it goes further with headache.
When there’s this migraine I’m very hot in my head.
It feels like fever and the hands can be cold and the feet feel cold.
I have cold hands now, I have a headache.
here’s another bog problem; always when I eat my stomach gets swollen.
Every day, all the time and I’m so fed up of it.
–After eating?
– Yes.
– If you eat breakfast it will happen?
– It’s ok but lunch I can be swollen up until late in the evening.
When I eat bread, garlic and cucumber and some vegetables... That’s worse.
– Which are your worst hours?
– About my stomach?
– No, in general. If that time comes I always feel tired, not well...
- From the afternoon and further. Perhaps until 18.00.
- Which is your best time?
– It’s in the morning and before lunch.
– When you wake up in the morning you feel good after sleep,
refreshed or you wake up unrefreshed, tired and after half an hour you feel good?
– I feel mostly good.
I feel best when I know I’m free but when I need to go to work I’m heavier in the morning.
But generally I think I am fresh in the morning.
One more thing about my menses; the breast is swollen before menses, 2 days before it is worse.
– The fear of height is very strong?
– Yes. I go out and look over the edge on a high balcony there’s like needles in my legs.
– But very high like tenth floor. What about third floor?
– No, that’s ok.
– You said you like thunderstorm but do you feel better in thunderstorm or you just like to watch?
Or you feel good as if the air is refreshing you?
– I don’t need to go out to the thunders but I like to be at home and it’s stormy outside.
– Why? Your organism feels good or you like it as a phenomenon?
– I feel good.
– Without affecting your organism? Are you happier?
– Perhaps. I don’t know.
– How is your sexual drive?
– It’s good.
– Very good or excessively good?
– It’s very good. I am happy now in life, really.
– Before menses you have more desire?
– No, less desire before menses.
– During menses?
– No.
– After menses?
– Yes. Shall I say something about my history,
I don’t know if it’s important but all my life until about 3 years I always had a feeling of forsaken
and I always felt outside but that’s not anymore.
–How did this feeling go away?
– Now I am studying in Stockholm Psychosynthesis.
– Assagioli?
– You know him!
– I know everything! Hahah...
The difficulty in your case which brings a state of paralysis...
- This is important because these studies with Assagioli have changed very much.
I am grounded in myself and I don’t have that feeling anymore and I am being educated to be therapist.
Another thing, as a child and up to 21 years old I was clairvoyant
and then it went away but I still have this very strong intuition, feel things before happening.
I can very easily listen to my patients and I listen behind, I don’t how to express...
I still have that.
– You listen and you understand.
– I understand and I know more than they are saying.
– You have any problem going into a lift?
– No.
–Going down or up.
– No. I am a bit worried about my eyes.
I see worse year by year. I have cataract and astigmatism.
– Do you like fruits?
– I like them but I don’t crave them. I prefer orange juice.
– From all fruits?
– If I have apples and oranges I take oranges.
– But from all fruits which would you like best?
– Orange. Strawberries. But they are not so good for my stomach.
– But you like oranges which are sour?
– A little bit sourer.
– Would you say you like unripe, green fruits?
– If you do physical exercise do you feel easily exhausted
or on the contrary physical exercise makes you feel better?
– It makes me feel better. I love long walks.
– And you walk fast or slowly?
– Medium. If I go very fast I get tired.
– But you like dancing?
– Yes, I like dancing.
– Do you feel good after dancing?
– Yes, I feel good. Do you know eurhythmy?
– Yeah, sure! I said I know everything but what is this question?
You have cramps on your bladder.
– It feels like cramps, it’s difficult to urinate.
When the urine comes there are cramps. But this is new for me I haven’t had it before.
– Just one time?
– No, I have it since a few months now.
– Without taking any medicine, any remedy?
– No. I don’t like medicines.
– Do you have a kind of fear of taking medicines or you just don’t like drugs etc.?
– I have a fear of chemical drugs, yes.
I have been taking anthroposophical medicine without problem
and this is very interesting for me to have some homeopathic medicines.
– But you have no problem taking a homeopathic remedy?
– I am a little bit wondering.
– Whether you are going to take the remedy?
– I will take the remedy!
– When you sleep, you said you sleep only on your back?
– When I have my menses I sleep on the side.
– Which side?
– It depends on the headache. Now it’s on the right.
Because I have to sleep on the side that hurts.
Push the pillow up here and then I sleep on the right and take the knee up.
Otherwise on the back with my hands over the head.
It’s lovely like this! I want my feet covered.
– Always?
– Yes.
– You never stick them out of covers?
– Never!
– Are you afraid of animals?
– I am afraid of one kind of dog because when I was a child one dog bit me on the leg.
– Ferocious dogs.
– Yes, shepherd dogs.
It was a police dog and it was a little bit mad. I drink a lot of water.
– You sip it?
– Yes.
– All the time you like to drink but not too much?
– It varies. I drink a lot of water because sometimes I really want it,
otherwise I drink because I think it’s healthy. But now I am thirsty.
– But when you drink, the natural tendency for you is to drink small quantities?
– Yes.
– And frequently?
– What about perspiration? Do you perspire in your sleep?
– Only before menses. Yes, I sweat all over.
– Before menses in sleep?
– Yes, but I wake up in the night.
When I am exercising I don’t feel good when I am sweating.
– Do you think you are a restless person? You like to be active?
You seem to be calm but this is out of training or natural.
– I think I am calm.
– Do you have acute conditions like bronchitis or influenzas?
– In general?
– Yes.
– No, very seldom. Except the migraine, no.
– Do you like fish?
– Yes.
– Salt?
– I take salt, normal.
– Sweets?
– I like them but I don’t crave them. Before menses I eat some.
– What about your nails? Are they strong?
– No, they are not strong?
– Soft?
– Yes.
– Brittle? They break easily?
– Do you bite them?
– Sometimes. And the panaritium is always broken like this.
– And you take them out like this?
– Yes, sometimes because they are broken.
– Are they inflamed?
– No. Just dry and broken.
And on my foot I easily get something like eczema between the toes. This one.
– Now at this moment you have no eczema?
– I have here and here. But this is getting better here in Greece.
In the summer and warmth.
– During this period when you had this psychosynthesis
and the feeling of being forsaken went away,
do you remember any other changes taking place in your organism?
– Physically? I don’t know... I feel more in harmony and I feel I am me.
– What were you feeling before?
- I was always feeling out ship, forsaken.
– Isolated, forsaken...
- I got sad easily and scared that people would leave me and so.
And that feeling I had all my life, since I was a little child.
And I think it comes from my mother,
she was living in stress and she was pregnant with me and didn’t really want me
and she was giving birth to me alone, my father went away, left us.
So, I think the feeling comes from when she was pregnant to me.
– But your father left during that time and never came back?
– Yes. Nowadays in my life it happens that I dream that I’m crying and I wake up.
I don’t know if this is important.
– You see that you are crying but you are not really crying?
– Yes, I cry in the dream and then I wake up and I am crying.
– And you don’t know why.
– The story in the dream is always about me sometimes desperately looking for my husband
and I can’t find him and sometimes it’s a story I don’t really remember,
it’s about something I think I am going to be... Forsaken perhaps.
– Do you work for somebody now or you work on your own?
– Me and my husband work together with patients. He is a doctor.
We have something like a small clinic with patients coming to us.
– So you are doing a kind of Assagioli teaching, psychosynthesis...
- Yes, I am being educated now, I am going to work with it.
I am going in the school now. We will work with that with our patients also later.
– Did you ever have any aphthae in the mouth?
Like white spots in the mouth which are painful.
– No.
– How do you feel in hot weather?
I like Alonissos now but when you have the courses in July it’s too hot for me.
I can’t think, I can’t do anything. I feel I am swelling in the heat.
– You retain water in your body.
– Yes, I think so.
–What about cold? You feel happier in cold?
– I like the Swedish winter when it’s a really nice, snowy, dry winter day
but I could easily start to cry if I stand in the shower and the water gets too cold.
Then I suddenly feel like crying. Then I need warm and nice water.
I am very sensitive at that moment.
– Do you have the need to be protected by your husband?
– Yes, that’s a need I have. It was more before, now it’s still but it’s less.
– Do you need to be consoled? If you want to have somebody to tell you don’t cry, to console you.
– I need someone that sees me. That I am something, yes. That’s a need.
– To have somebody giving you affection.
– Yes.
– Do you understand the word consolation?
– Yes. I think so.
– Do you need consolation when you are not feeling well?
– No. I rather feel I need to be confirmed.
I am happy with myself to be alone. I like to be alone.
But also because of my childhood I have the strong feeling that no one really saw me.
– Recognize.
– Yes.
– Did you ever have any warts except of this eczema?
– Do you remember how it went away?
– Burned.
– Were they many? Do you remember?
– When I was a child I had on my hands, I don’t know exactly where.
And I had about 2-3 years ago on my small toe.
– And you burned it?
– yes that one I burned.
– Was it bleeding?
– No.
– Anything else?
– No, I don’t think so.
– Alright, let’s go outside.
First question that we are asking in this case.
Is this a clear case? Who says yes? What is the remedy?
Calc. Anybody else who has a good idea? Who says it’s a clear case?
No one. Do you have any idea what remedy it might be? Puls. Thuja.
Another Sep. I will write down here your ideas.
Calc., Sep., Puls., Thuja., Med., Verat., Lyc. Another idea?
Cupr., Nat-m. Who will be for Calc. 3. Sep.? 7. Puls.? 9.
Thuja? 8. Med? 1. Verat.? 1 Lyc.? 2. Cupr.? 1, Nat-m.? 5. Cycl. 1.
What you are seeing from the number of people, actually I don’t know your expertise
but if this is a class of experts and these are the numbers, then we have a problem.
Either the case is totally confused or the practitioners are.
In this case what happens is both! Both the practitioners and the case are confused!
And in spite of the fact she says; and this is the first thing we talk about,
whether the case is clear or not and she says I have not taken homeopathic remedies,
she means she has not taken high potencies.
She has taken anthrposophic medicine in which they are using perhaps 50 remedies
and using them repeatedly which of course has an effect.
The case started with a quite severe skin eruption,
don’t forget that, which was treated with cortisone.
What we see now is no skin eruption what you saw very little here,
you cannot even consider it as skin eruption.
That means all the skin eruption is inside now.
The first thing we have to know is that if this case is doing well after 1, 2 or 3 remedies,
we have to see the skin eruption coming back.
This is really difficult but you have to tell your patient that if this happens
it is a successful treatment and you really hit the remedy!
It depends whether she would like to take the remedy or not.
The second is why this case is not clear. Do you know why?
– Perhaps it’s because she did psychosynthesis.
A lot of the symptoms went away with that and maybe we should start with that.
– Why do you say that? Do you have a reason to say...
- I think unless it’s a total deep cure to process,
if you take away some symptoms with whatever technique you still have to take them into account, maybe.
– Again it is the same idea as I told you on different levels, we have different action.
You can have upon your mind an action and you can change your mind.
If this changing of the mind is not due to a total curative stimulus
then you will only have a metathesis, a transformation.
Let’s say here you have fear of being forsaken.
She does psychosynthesis and this symptom goes away without changing the total picture.
That means on this level this symptom has gone somewhere here
and transformed itself into another symptom, another dimension. But within this level.
Therefore we cannot consider it as a cure though the symptom is not there.
In her particular case what we see?
That this symptom has been transferred into a subconscious level.
The symptom is not anymore in the awareness of the person, it is on the subconscious level.
The moment she goes to sleep the subconscious takes over and the fears which are there
they come through dreams and in her dream she has the same problem;
she is afraid she is going to be forgotten by others.
So actually this symptom is there but on a deeper level where she is not aware anymore.
The question that we have as practitioners who are treating the whole person is such a transfer happens,
do we have repercussions in other areas?
And especially in the area in which this fear is moving.
Has she lost something when she lost that symptom?
Has she lost the ability to be more sensitive, to feel the pain of others?
Here we don’t know. And it’s difficult to find out.
But my experience shows that where there is no deeper cure there is a symptom going on which disappears.
I will give you an example which is very common and you may have done it yourself.
There was a time when they said salt is very bad for health.
So a lot of Nat-m. cases who used to take a lot of salt because of their need of salt, they stopped eating salt.
Their mind ordered their body not to want salt anymore.
And you ask a case and they say I used to desire salt
but as soon as I heard salt is bad for me I stopped eating and now I don’t desire anymore.
That is not without consequences.
That means that the salt which the organism needs to feed the nervous system is not enough and therefore,
in order to cope with this lack of salt,
which is needed but the organism does not take it because salt just goes out or is not given,
then this nervous system will put another barrier on deeper level
and the person becomes depressed to the extent that he does not need any more that salt.
So desire for salt is transferred into depression in which case the person does not need any more salt so much.
Really, when she says I don’t care about salt, they don’t care anymore about salt.
In the meantime you see either irritability can be transferred or depression or anxiety,
it depends on the organism to what it will be transferred.
I had several cases but 2 dramatic cases I will tell you.
2 girls, the same story, they said as we were growing and developing breast...
At the age of 12 and 13 when the girls first develop breast
and the boys they start looking with sexual connotation
and if the person sensitive perceives that and does not like.
A little girl of 12, if they look at her and she feels that is bad I don’t like it
and I have seen 2 cases in which they stopped growing.
The breast did not develop anymore. In one case she lost her hair.
She developed the androgenous hormones which stopped the female characteristics.
She lost her breast and her hair. She became bold.
She came to be treated when she was 32, she was wearing a wig and no breast.
The mind has a very powerful hold of the organism. It can do things like that.
But if there is no total cure we always have a transference.
That fear which is bothering me is transferred to something else.
In psychiatry they know it very well.
They know the person loses one fear and eventually develops another.
This has happened in a way in that case but that is not all.
What has happened is that she took cortisone, anthroposophic medicines,
she had what we call an aggression in her body by using the spiral which her organism rejected it,
did not want it and started the bleeding.
But it is interesting if you notice that by the time she started having the bleeding actually
she was ameliorated in the headaches.
So the organism is one and acts as one.
You cannot separate one part and the other, the mental, the emotional or the physical.
It always makes a balance.
So due to these interventions and especially because of a tremendous fear,
this fear which she mentioned according to my understanding it was limiting her life.
Fear of being forsaken. It was a huge thing.
That’s why she is very happy now to have get rid of this fear.
She nods, she says yes you’re right. You cannot see that.
In our analysis, first question, shall we take into consideration this fear?
Yes or no? Why yes? Because she has said in my dreams I wake up crying. She does not cry now.
In her dreams she is crying that means all that issue goes on in a subconscious level,
she cries, she feels abandoned, there is no help.
She has helped herself so far in the waking state by using her logical mind and a methodology
which is Assagioli’s psychosynthesis and this is something which a lot of people say it helped them.
I don’t dispute that.
What I say is do we have perhaps a better system of medicine which can take away both;
the headaches, the bleeding and the fear of being forsaken and can we give a remedy and cure her as she is now.
What she is interested is stop her bleeding and her headaches and the bloatedness.
That’s all I want. Don’t touch anything else.
I don’t care if I cry in the evening. We cannot do that!
Actually we can if we want to stop the bloatedness.
What you are interested in more? The bloatedness is the worst!
Ok, I’ll give you 3 remedies, you take one after another and in 3 days you won’t have it.
How long will the cure last? I don’t know.
What I know is that after 3 days she will say I don’t have the bloatedness anymore.
If she asks me to cure the bleeding I can cure it and in the next period she won’t have it.
The idea is can we cure her and at the same time not going through the aggravation
which means not going through returning the fear of being forsaken and eventually returning of the skin eruption.
And can we do this with one remedy?
The answer to the first 2 questions is we cannot.
If we do correct work she will have back the fear of being forsaken for a period of time
and she eventually will have back the skin eruption.
Can we do it with one remedy? The answer is no, we cannot do it with one remedy.
The reason is because of this situation.
Can I see the repertorization?
Let us say you put in your repertory all the symptoms that you need.
Give me the symptoms. Feeling of being forsaken.
You reduced them to 10? There were 30 symptoms!
– There are still.
– Irritability before menses, mental amelioration during thunderstorm,
weeping while dreaming and weeping in sleep in one rubric.
Heat of head during headache, pain on menses before,
pain right side, cataract, dryness in the morning.
For instance here we may ask just as a matter of interrogation
how much the disappearance of the fear has to do with the cataract.
As a matter of inquiry.
Clenching teeth, appetite increased before menses, thirst in the night,
thirst for small quantities often, distention of abdomen after eating,
rectum constriction during menses, rectum diarrhea before menses,
menses clotted large clots, copious menses ,protracted, thin blood,
cramp in uterus during menses, chest swelling of mammae before menses,
dryness of fingernails, about fingernails...
Farinaceous desire, draft of air aggravation, skin warts suppressed,
skin eruptions eczema, lacerations of wounds, weakness during headache.
Is any symptom that you would like to add in this repertorization?
Almost everything we could find in the repertory.
– She used the term ‘cataract’ and sometimes people mix up words and mean something else.
– Have you been examined by an ophthalmologist? He is an ophthalmologist.
You mentioned ‘cataract’. Was after an examination by an ophthalmologist?
Yes. And did he tell you the degree? In the beginning?
Because you are very young to have cataract.
– I had that since I was a child.
- The cataract?
– I think so.
– Are you an ophthalmologist. Give us some information.
– It’s possible to have a cataract from birth.
– Wait a moment. This is different.
Real cataract yes, she is having the beginning of it.
– Probably she has things in her lens all her life already. It could be...
- Is it possible that she can have cataract since childhood and at the age of 40
and she will still have the same cataract? Is that possible?
– Yes, it’s possible. But what you call nowadays a cataract is...
- An opacity.
– It’s more an opacity nowadays. She has some opacities all her life.
– Without developing?
– Without developing.
– One of the characteristic of the cataract is that it is maturing, as far as I know.
That’s why they say wait it’s not mature yet and it always becomes mature and you have the operation.
In her case what she says is she has that cataract from the age...
I don’t know... to the age of 40 and stays. It’s not a cataract.
We are talking about something totally different situation.
If she was really examined and a cataract was found developing
that means she had this development lately. The last 3-5 years.
– Probably she had some opacities all her life.
Might increase now but would still talk about a cataract.
– Let’s not become ophthalmologist. Are you ophthalmologist?
– No. She said when she was talking about her forsaken feeling that she was not seen.
And there is a symptom in the repertory, mind delusion unseen.
– No. This is a delusion. She doesn’t talk about this.
She talks about her presence. Nobody takes notice of me, I’m here.
She was feeling that nobody was taking notice of her presence. Not a delusion.
– She said I have a sensation I was not seen.
– It’s not a delusion. A delusion is different.
– My cataract is slowly getting worse.
– Somebody told you from childhood.
– I had these since childhood.
– These glasses?
– Yes. But it’s getting worse. I will change the glasses more often nowadays.
– Let’s not go to this detail because we are not specialists and I am afraid that it will confuse.
We come to the point where we have to decide what is the remedy for this case.
What should be the first remedy.
Here, we have the possibility of Lyc. Sep. is coming as first remedy and Puls. is the second,
Psor. is the third remedy and Lyc. Sil., Aur., Chin. and Verat. Is this a Sep. case?
There is one symptom which she said which is characteristic of Sep. most probably and that symptoms was...
Take out this thunderstorm symptom... Puls., Sep., Psor., Sil., Chin.
Would you say she is crying easily?
– You asked if she is crying easily.
She’s not except with cold water in the bathtub or in the shower she cries easily!
She actually likes hot bath.
– Every evening I have a hot bath.
– Very hot?
– Yes, to relax.
– And you enjoy?
– And I rather cry by myself.
– You cry but not in front of others!
– No, I prefer not to disturb others. I cry by myself.
And I forgot to say when you were interviewing me that for few years I was very ill in my stomach,
I couldn’t work, I had this constant diarrhea every day and I could hardly eat anything.
– Chronic lumbar pain in association with this chronic diarrhea.
That was about 1989 or 1990.
– Would you say now that you have lack of self-confidence?
- Yes, a little bit but it’s better. I still have it.
– But at the same time I know no person who knows exactly how she wants to things to be.
If I ask you, how would you like this you will say maybe so or so.
Maybe she knows exactly, I want it this or that way.
You can hardly find a person who knows so well and at the same time she says she has bad self-confidence.
– Maybe in the house she feels confident and outside of the house she feels unconfident.
– Yes.
– Actually, what you are saying is that in the house she’s quite dictatorial!
– She is not dictatorial. But she is so pronounced.
She knows this I want, that I don’t want.
If you ask me what I want then I will say maybe this or that.
She never! She knows exactly she wants this and doesn’t want that! It’s so clear.
I haven’t met any person who knows so well from inside what she wants or not.
– I am more sensitive before menses and I easily cry and I get easily emotionally hurt.
– Aggravation cold bathing. Show me the remedies. Show me Sep.
Show me bloatedness in the abdomen, afternoon, after eating. Show me the remedies.
Carb-v., Nux-v., Puls., Sep. It’s very difficult decision.
What shall we do? After this analysis what would you prescribe?
Can I see your impression? You are the homeopath, you are prescribing.
Who prescribes Calc.? 2. Sep? 7. Puls.? Thuja? Med.? Verat.? Lyc.?
The only remedy that was actually raised was Puls.
The lady in the first row does not agree with Puls.! She said no.
This is not a Puls. Puls. should cry and cry. But it is not always crying.
As you remember I told about Puls. in India.
A minister of textiles actually she was looking like her.
For an Indian she was very tough. She came to me and I said Puls.
So she went back to her homeopaths in India. Puls. for you? You never cry!
I said yes, Puls. Her liver was not functioning.
She was retaining water and when menses came she would become bloated and she had another dress,
the whole body was retaining water for years after she was injected for rabies.
Puls. took away everything. The only thing I could perceive for Puls. was a slight fear of dark.
But from that time onwards I learned not all Puls. cry, not all Puls. are easily lead and persuaded.
They have quite strong personalities especially when they feel they’re inside their area of expertise.
My decision for her, the first remedy will be Puls. 10M.
I respect your opinion but I have to make the decision.
Puls. 10M, first remedy with a hope that she will come back with her forsaken feelings before are over.
What are the main things on which we prescribe Puls.?
Of course it is the forsaken feeling which we know in Puls. is so strong.
About the bleedings and the headaches it’s ok
but what is interesting is she sleeps like Puls. she stressed that.
She said I sleep in that position which is the latest symptom she is having at the moment.
I asked her about fat; she said no I don’t like and she cries.
Instead of crying in daytime she cries in sleep and she feels forsaken in her sleep.
So this is not a clear case of Puls.
but Puls. it is perhaps the best possibility we have.
– She is not a clear case, why 10M?
– Because I feel that the problem in order to be touched
since it is gone already in the subconscious level
has to be a powerful potency to touch the deeper emotional problem
which has been suppressed. That’s the first one I want to touch.
– Am I supposed to take this once?
– Only once and pray to God.
– And nothing between this year and next year I see you?
– It will depend. What I expect is that the next remedy will be most probably Lyc., much clearer,
and the third remedy must be Thuja.
The last remedy will be Thuja and after Thuja we will have the reappearance of skin eruption.
At any time you can drink coffee and stop the process!
– I should not drink coffee.
– You must not drink coffee. Absolutely forbidden!