Your case number is 347. What is the problem?
– I’ve got 3 main problems. The first is ME; myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue.
The other is migraine and the third one is a chronically tense, painful back.
– When did these symptoms arise? Especially the ME.
– After I have been in parliament for 2,5 years, in my first term, I had pneumonia,
I had treatment with IV antibiotics, I went on working really hard
and I never really recovered and about 6 months after that many things happened,
I had a great deal of pressure because I chose it, I didn’t have to do it but I did.
It just started then and it just got worse and worse until I was almost bedridden.
For 9 months I struggled to talk, to work, to concentrate and I have a homeopath in South Africa,
he helped me with many remedies and we hit on one; Nat-c. which helped me.
The back problem I’ve had since I was about 25, on and off. It’s getting very bad now.
– What kind of back problem? Is it on sacral or lumbar region?
– That’s one of my symptoms. It varies.
It can be on the left, on the right, in the thoracic vertebrae, in the lumbar region, sciatic...
It varies. I’ve got chronic arthritis all the way down my back.
As a child I slipped down a haystack and I landed on my bottom, not on my feet.
And I think it’s the damage of that.
– And migraines?
– I didn’t have them for a long time.
They’re coming back now. I get them about once a month.
I get a premonition of the migraine.
My vision goes away on the right side and sometimes I get,
like television screen, right in the right corner. And then...
- The migraine starts...
- Yes. I usually want to on working so I take Sandomigran.
I will try yoga, deep breathing, meditation.
If that doesn’t help then I take Sandomigran
and then I am left with the headache for about 2 days.
And the headache is usually worse on the left side.
– What other remedies have you taken except of Nat-c.?
Can you give me a list?
– Many. What I can remember I’ve taken Sulph, Thuja, Med., Lyc.
Before I took Puls., Ferr. and Nat-c.
-That’s all?
–Sep.?
– A bit. On and off over the years I’ve tried little bits of the others
but the one’s I’ve found, I thought they made some difference, I’ve carried them.
I’ve taken a bit of Sep. but not a lot.
When I take a homeopathic remedy I usually prove it.
If I take Puls. 10M I get shooting pains down my leg and bladder symptoms.
If I take Nux-v. I get very severe aggravation of my flu symptoms.
If I take Lyc. everything gets worse on the right.
I once took Lyc. and I had cutting pains in my abdomen for about 6 months.
I also have indigestion.
– I can mention something about ME, it’s quite important, I think.
Like I said I have a premonition with the migraine.
As I am sitting talking to you now, I am putting a lot of energy into it,
otherwise I would be just mumbling. My speech becomes very mumbling.
I just don’t want to talk. Talking makes me worse.
Especially talking on the phone.
I get impatient and that impatience makes me much worse.
Also I get the premonition of getting back.
I get almost like an electric current through my face and around my mouth and a bit in my right ear,
in my right hand and in my right foot.
And then I know when that starts to come then I know I am going down again.
I have a lot of hawking of mucus. I got a lot of postnasal drip.
I don’t cough it out. And when my homeopath gave me Nat-c.
I had a lot of brownish-greenish mucus that I was coughing at that time.
– With the migraines do you have to vomit?
– No.
– And where exactly are they situated?
– The picture goes patchy on the right,
the light starts to flicker around the extreme arch on the right
and then I get a pain in the back of my head and in my neck too.
– On the left side or the whole back?
– Mainly on the left.
– Which extends towards the eye or stays there?
– Worse on the back of my head, very bad.
– On the left occipital protuberance. What else you had as history?
– In my history I have a tonsillectomy as a child,
I had a hysterectomy at about 35 or 37, now I am 57 so that was 20 years ago.
– Why did you have the hysterectomy?
– I had a prolapsed uterus and I was starting to have bladder problems with it.
The doctor said either a repair or a hysterectomy and didn’t know Homeopathy then.
I had a hysterectomy.
– Anything else?
– I couldn’t eat for about 3 years because I had such severe burning pains
if I ate anything I used to get very severe pains.
Everything in me is extreme.
If I work, it’s extreme, if I get ill, it’s really sick,
if I get flu my body aches, I think I am going to die.
I do things with a passion, it’s very hard to just...
I try very hard, I’ve tried to change my nature, to be calm,
to talk slowly, to meditate, when I am anxious, I get very anxious.
– You are anxious?
– I am a Jewish mother in extreme.
I am chronically anxious about my children.
– Another anxiety?
– Your husband is...
- A doctor, a surgeon, he’s in South Africa.
– And you have any other fear or depression? You talked about depression.
What kind of depression?
– Not depression. I’ve never been depressed.
– Anxious and fears?
– I fear thinking about snakes. I don’t like the thought of snakes.
Even more than the idea of meeting an idea on the ground.
I don’t like to think about snakes.
I think it could be from when I was a child my parents left to go to the seas,
I think I was about 10, I was a very sensitive child.
Somebody stayed in the house and told us many stories about snakes.
And then I remember having the most terrible dreams about snakes.
I don’t know if that’s the reason.
– You cannot see it in even in a picture?
– If I see a picture of a snake...no.
Sometimes if I close my eyes and I am in a bad state mentally or emotionally
and I see snakes I can go crazy.
But I haven’t for quite a while.
I just know that I don’t like the thought of snakes.
– Any other fear?
– No. When I am in a high place, the impulse, I wonder how many people don’t jump.
I don’t want to jump. But the thought... It’s so easy; just jump!
– What about food? Do you have any particular desire?
– I like sweet food like sweets fruits and sweets, I love ice cream.
I say why didn’t I take Phos.? Hot drinks, always and a lot of them.
It must be hot. I really don’t like warm food.
I must have hot soup, hot drinks.
–Salt?
– I don’t like salt. I like potatoes.
And I don’t like onions or the smell of onions, especially raw onions.
I cannot take acids; tomatoes, vinegar.
– Your mood changes?
– Not so much.
– This happens in case you are sick or in case you are well?
– I’d say about my mood when I do feel something it is very intense.
If I see a beautiful scene, like I would walk around here I am on a high.
– You are excitable.
– If I am dancing I get very uplifted.
If I hear music I get very moved by it.
If start to talk about politics I get worked up.
The same tune can play over and over in my head, I hear and...
- You cannot get it out.
– Yes. And I get pins and needles easily.
If I sit on the ground, if I sleep on my hands, I get pins and needles.
I used to like to sleep on my tummy with my hands under the cushion,
but now because of my back I made myself lying on my back
and I also like to put my hands up above my head or just like this.
I often get chilblains in my left fourth toe. I’ve got very dry skin.
I can tell you my generals.
I can’t bear to be sitting in a closed room for a long time.
I have to get up and move and have air. All my life.
In parliament I’d get the worst marks for the one who sits in the afternoon
because I just have to get up.
The artificial ventilation, closed rooms, warm rooms...terrible.
I can’t stand it.
Even when I am really bad with the ME and I don’t want to do anything
it frustrates me not to do something.
I want to try and do something.
I’m better when I move and physical movement.
- Dance?
- I like dancing. I feel good. Or if I walk.
– Now that you are in such weak state if you walk you walk slowly?
– Yes.
I am doing everything now slowly because hurry makes me much worse.
If I wake up and I know I am late and I have to hurry I just...
But I normally do like to do everything quickly, my nature is to talk quickly,
I hate being in queues, if I talk on the phone and they have this machine... I can go mad.
And I’m not good with workers. I am quite nasty.
– Impatient.
– Yes because if my staff is slow and they don’t do what I want them to do
I get quite ratty, I’m not very nice. Quite strict.
I’m more concerned to get the job done than to be nice to the person.
I am guilty afterwards. That’s my nature.
– Would you find some cutting remarks to do to somebody who is...
Something that you know it is his sensitive point.
– I don’t try to hurt him. I just say what I think.
I am very anti-political correctness. If I don’t want to do what is fashionable.
I prefer to do what is right and honest. It’s very important to me.
Joining my party was always a very strange thing to do.
White and Jewish and middle class in the black Zulu party...
people thought I was crazy. Doing Homeopathy 12 years ago in South Africa...
My own medical colleagues thought I was crazy.
– But you didn’t care.
– I almost enjoyed it.
– You do whatever you like... Do these headaches ever change place?
Or are always on the left side?
– No, sometimes are on the right. I come to remember now.
I think sometimes after my migraines I use to have pains on the right. I am remembering now.
Recently I had it on my left, also my backache was most on the left.
But sometimes I think my pain used to be on the right.
– Not that one can be on the right, the left time on the right?
– Yes and changeable. I have ridges on my nails. I have hangnails.
When I am very anxious I pull out my hair.
My classmates from the medical school even remember it when I was anxious.
And now when I’m feeling stressed and there are problems I’m on the telephone
and I want to get rid of the telephone I pull out my hair.
I get a lot of tension in my body.
– You actually pull out?
– Yes. Very bad habit especially for a politician.
I’m talkative. I like to talk.
I’m like very much opposites go together in me.
The more I learn the less I think I know.
If you have a seminar like yesterday, in the end of it I will think that’s the one possibility
but that’s the other possibility.
In my work I know that I am very opposed to the government I have total conviction about what I am doing
but sometimes if I think deeply through it I think well perhaps at this stage the civilization is in,
everything they are doing that is bad, that is populist, that I think is dishonest
but I am totally committed to fighting and maybe they’re up!
I always see two sides. In my life it’s very important to have balance.
– Can I ask you a question? How is your sexual drive?
– Normal.
– Was never totally lost?
– No.
– You didn’t tell me whether you feel cold or hot.
– I’m very cold and I’ve always got cold feet and often cold hands. Not here.
– The desire for sweet is very great?
– No. I just like sweet things. I don’t like sugar in my tea.
– But hot drinks definitely you like?
– Very much.
If I have cold drink it gives me headache. I got bad teeth.
Should I tell you about my dreams?
Sometimes I have amazing dreams, as if I had discovered paradise in my head. Vivid colors.
I was seeing the sea and the lagoon and mountains and it’s like the colors here.
Blue and magenta and turquoise and pink. It’s quite beautiful!
And then sometimes a scene of nature and I’ll be there and there are animals and water and plants.
Almost what we would like to create a paradise.
But other times my dreams are full of trouble.
I’d move to a place, a house and then there will be vagrants coming in
and I would be not able to find my children and my family would be all around.
Just problems, things that I have to deal with. There’s two conflicting dreams.
I often dream that I’ve lost my children, I can’t find them.
I have a very sensitive sense of smell.
Very acute sense of smell and sense of color and I don’t like noise.
I love music but I hate noisy music or grating sounds like chalk on the board.
– When you do something you do it in hurry always?
– Yes. If I write I make mistakes because I will say one thing, I will say ‘bad’
and I will come back and I will see I didn’t ‘there’ that I wrote ‘bad’.
And if you have me in a quiz show and you ask me my husband’s name I’ll probably forget it.
When I have anticipatory anxiety even after all these years of being on the stage and being in politics
I still feel anxiety before I talk or I perform in public.
Anticipatory anxiety before performance. If I take Lyc. high it gets worse.
– Did you ever try Gels.?
– For acutes. When my ME started I took Gels.
It helped a little, not a lot.
– Anything else?
– When I am like this will suddenly come out perspiration sometimes in my face and my neck and my chest mainly,
top part of my body.
I think that’s all. My memory is really bad.
– Can you tell me exactly where are the weak points of memory?
– If somebody would tell me the Greek word for ‘hello’ or which way we walked
I feel like I forget it immediately and they have to tell me again and again.
That’s when I’m ill. My memory just goes.
And I will write something in my diary and then I look and think ‘when did I write that’?
I have no recollection. I feel like somebody else took my diary.
– What about words? Can you find words easily?
– No. Especially again when I am performing.
If I write, I do a lot of articles, beautiful... it just comes,
flows but if I am talking I just can’t find the word that I am looking for
and the harder I try the more it goes away.
– And you forget names of course very much.
– Very badly.
– And you forget what you want to do from one moment to the other?
– Yes.
– When did you have the pneumonia?
– 1996.
– Since 1996 your health took a downward trend.
– Yes.
And I’d make an admission; on 1997 I got the ME, on 1998 I had vaccination for flu because I was scared.
I just thought I’ve got such a busy year and I was better
and they had given me some time off from parliament and I had to work and I couldn’t be sick.
– Ok.
– As I was sitting here now there was a current in my hands.
We are living now in this world in which we will have to face problems of that type
and you heard the problem of Ruth and you know how big is the problem of
what they call it benign myalgic encephalomyelitis ME
or they call it fatigue syndrome or post viral syndrome.
It has different names this disease but what is this disease?
Is nothing else but the aftereffects of antibiotics in an organism who has a weak immune system.
It breaks down the immune system for good and forever.
They call it post viral syndrome. They found out that it comes after an infection.
They never said what about what did we do to deplete the organism
by antibiotics or by chemical drugs.
Can you realize how simple facts are missed or they don’t want to see?
The responsible authorities they don’t want to see simple facts
and then there are associations of benign myalgic encephalomyelitis or Epstein-Barr.
This disease has 4 names. This disease was practically unknown 50 years ago.
And today there are associations with the patients.
As the other case we will be discussing afterwards, he belongs to this association.
The victims are so many that there are associations of course.
When I say there was no such thing before 50 years I don’t mean it didn’t exist,
I mean that there was no such an epidemic as we see today.
All diseases, what we see today, according to my understanding
they have existed from time immemorial.
AIDS also was existing.
If you deplete the immune system you get several syndromes
depending on the change that you have depleted.
Of the immune system. And you get the benign myalgic encephalomyelitis
or you may get AIDS or you may get a totally different disease.
That means even in time immemorial if somebody was mistreated,
ate badly etc. and his immune system was low,
you may have found some clinical picture looking alike.
But this is an epidemic. I will ask if he has any numbers in England.
You most probably have numbers in England of registered people suffering of it.
– The number of people belonging to the ME association I think is about 3.000.
The estimates I ‘ve heard about the disease depends on who has done the study,
but it’s about 1.5 to 4 per 100.000 of the population.
–Which means for England in actual numbers?
- I think the estimates are too high.
The highest estimate I’ve heard is maybe 100.000 people in England.
– I will take half of it, 50.000 in England and in West,
will be by millions perhaps 2 million people
because you have to take into consideration people like Ruth are not registered.
Thousands of them are not registered.
Yet we have a disease which is in the West, it doesn’t exist in India.
They hardly know this disease.
In South America they hardly know this disease. In Africa too.
Now they will start knowing it.
For the last 10 years where the antibiotics have been exploding there,
they will start knowing all these diseases, as well.
But not before 20 years ago, unknown in Arab world, in Asia, in Africa, in South America.
Yet in the western world using all this excessive medication...
Hundreds of thousands and it’s a severe depletion of the immune system
and it needs very careful prescribing.
In this case if you don’t prescribe correctly and start giving a remedy after another
you deplete the organism more and more.
And you have to take that into consideration very much
that you do not give remedy after remedy in such cases.
They will end up in total depletion of energy.
You have to be very careful how you start and how you proceed.
With Ruth now, take this depletion of energy
especially when she says that she cannot talk on the telephone,
the remedy that comes to the mind, Stan.
And you have to think of another remedy maybe Gels.
As she was progressing giving her case, better dancing, better with motion,
the idea of Sep. came especially with the fact that she had a prolapsed uterus.
So there is an idea of Sep. there as well. Cocc.
We could have Cocc. in case she would complain with vertigo.
She complained of migraines and this is different.
Sep. has the headache which is preceded by visional disturbances.
Visional disturbances preceding the headache is Iris. Show me these remedies.
Because she has clearly that symptom; visional disturbances before the headache.
She describes it very clearly.
– So, you want to see the whole list of the repertorization?
Or the rubric?
- Just the rubric.
– Which one is the rubric, sorry?
– Vision, blurred before headache.
Gels., Hyos., Iris is strong, Kali-b., Sep., Sulph., Lac-d., Pod., Psor. and Tub.
– Cycl. has blurring during headache.
– This is preceding the headache.
The possibility of Tub. is there also.
I don’t know if she had any tubercular predisposition in her family.
No. But the fear of snakes is so strong that we thought of Lac-c.
And Lac-c. has another symptom; desire for hot drinks.
– And another thing she has is her inner state to cover alternating sides.
– She said I pulled out that symptom. But I am not quite certain.
– My symptoms do vary a lot.
Like my back is being sore mostly on the left but some days on the right.
I’ve had a lot of sore throats. I’ve forgot to mention that.
Sometimes left, sometimes, right. I think I was a right sided person.
But lately I’ve had problems on the left.
But sometimes it goes back to the right. It does fluctuate.
– Let us say you have 4 headaches in a year or a month.
The first headache is on the right, the second headache on the left,
the third headache on the right, the fourth headache on the left.
This is Lac-c. Is that the case? Definitely not.
I pulled out this and she left it in the air.
– But in her very inner state she has alternating opinions...
- Not alternating. She can see 2 different aspects, 2 opposing aspects.
– But perhaps I should also add I am terribly tenacious.
Badly, so. If I want something to happen I just have to go on until it happens.
If I do one thing and it needs two I will do two
and if these do needs another one I will do three.
If all three to succeed need four and five I have to do them.
One of my children said if you want to break someone’s head just ask Ruth to do it.
I can’t stop. Although I know I am making myself ill, I don’t want to, I have to.
– Can you find the compulsion? Another possibility?
Somebody will speak about Ph-ac.? No.
In spite of the fact you see the memory is affected quite strongly still the emotions are there.
They are not flattened.
– What about Puls.?
Changeable symptoms, desire hot drinks. Puls. is there.
– But it’s not really... What about Puls.?
She is very chilly. Stuffy rooms.
The problem is with the stuffiness in a closed room and she is cold.
Are you crying easily?
– No. I cry for ideas.
If I will hear a very great speech or I will see a film, at the end of the film,
the idea moves me I will cry.
– You are excited about the idea.
– Are you very tidy?
– She is not tidy.
– Just the idea of Tarent. Everything done in a hurry and nervous affinity.
– She likes dancing, yes. I would be surprised to see a Tarent. in so low energy. She is very low.
She said when I come to that state, it is like a disease like MS; it comes in waves.
A wave comes, they go very low and during that time she can even not be able to articulate.
So difficult and tired she is.
– I considered also the combination of weakness and excitability.
Perhaps points to Arg-n. or Arg-m. Electric shocks blains, impulsiveness, hurriedness.
– She is not impulsive in the way... I didn’t get it. The way Arg-n. is impulsive.
Arg-m. Find me the repertorization for Arg-m. Repetition of thoughts, song.
This is not the right rubric.
The right rubric, repetition of thoughts, a sound which she heard, this is a Puls. symptom.
Does anybody have this right symptom? She hears a song and the song is repeating itself.
No, it’s another rubric with 6 remedies.
Can this keep you awake? No.
Anyhow let’s see the remedies. Which is the remedy to start with?
– Still think it’s Arg-n. because of the symptoms;
the stage fright, the weakness, the occiput side left,
the delusion of snakes, talking aggravates, lack of vital heat.
And she said when she is standing in a high place she thinks about how easy it is to jump down.
This is the impulse of Arg-n.
– Alum-sil.
– Pourquois?
– The pains that wander she has, the various areas of the pain shift,
coldness that she has in her body, then she has these effects of the nervous system in the spine.
The Alum-sil. has these effects upon them.
– Why not Phos.? No fear of thunderstorm, ice cream desire.
Who does not desire ice cream? Who would like to have an ice cream now, at this moment?
Take Phos. instead. The remedies that have a possibility are 2;
Stan. and Lac-c. Between these 2 remedies we have to choose the first remedy
and because there is a strong keynote this desire for hot drinks
which she stressed so much and the fear of snake being so strong.
These 2 keynotes of Lac-c. stressed so much by her.
It leads us to the fact that we have to start with Lac-c.
Not only that, but we see in her repertorization, it also stands first.
So Lac-c. is the remedy of first choice with a possibility of Stan.
and a third possibility for Gels. And under Lac-c. I believe that Sep. will arise.
So this is a case of Lac-c. and Sep. most probably. She will start with Lac-c 200C.
In such cases you don’t go higher than 200C because the organism is weak.
Also in such cases there is no way that you can find a clearer picture.
The picture is not clear as you see. It’s Stan., Gels., Sep... But we choose Lac-c.
You don’t go higher.
But you have to repeat several doses before she can start having a reaction.
She will start taking Lac-c. 200C for at least a weak; 7 doses.
And after that she will decide whether she needs some more doses or wait.
The general rule is once you have a reaction from the remedy you stop.
If you wake up tomorrow and no reaction, take a second dose.
Third day no reaction, fourth dose. You go like this and see how things are going.