This is the case of Daniel 32 years old.
I had seen Daniel 4 years ago in private, not in video,
he persuaded me and I prescribed for him Nat-m.
50M and Daniel was complaining primarily for severe allergic reaction.
– Urticaria, angioedema since 1993.
– With Nat-m. 50M it appears
that Daniel was better for a period of 9 months
and after that it started coming back more and more and now he is quite bad.
– I’m not sure about the period I was better but I think for that period it did some work.
– He was better.
– Let’s see what happened afterwards, after giving you the remedy.
Did you do something to counteract the treatment?
– I cannot remember. Nothing specific.
– Do you remember if you kept on drinking coffee.
– Probably I did. I am not a big coffee drinker
but I have drunk coffee very infrequently for my work,
I’m a lawyer I need that to keep me awake sometimes.
– Now, how much coffee do you drink?
– I’ve actually eliminated coffee...
I’ve got a slight swell in my right eye, my left hand you can’t see
but it got welts and a slight one in my right arm there but when it gets bad it can get worse.
– Show this picture.
– A picture only a mother could love!
And that’s quite a while back, it hasn’t been that bad for quite a long time.
– It’s been worse where his whole face gets swollen.
– If I should go back to the beginning, in 1993 I was about to go abroad,
I had my wisdom teeth taken out, had a general anesthetic,
I think antibiotics as well at the time and a week later I had my first attack,
not quite as bad as that
but similar and at the same time I pricked myself with a palm tree and my entire left hand swelled up.
Another coincidence I was bitten by an insect,
I just mention it because I week later I felt a fluid running out of my ear.
That started then, I have been having these recurrent attacks sometimes it is bad.
I’ve had this kind of attacks about 5-6 times during the years
and other than I get a swollen eye, swollen lip, swollen soft tissue and pressure definitely makes it worse.
The soles of my feet definitely get worse when I’m short of sleep and stressed.
-I live a stressful life.
– You say stress is a factor.
– I’m not sure. I think definitely lack of sleep is.
It tends to trigger it and pressure, when I’m sitting on a chair.
It tends to start and goes away within about a day or two.
– Food?
– I have not been able to identify any food that triggers it.
Two foods I know I am allergic to sulphur dioxide in drinks,
it’s preservative and these color fruit drinks.
Wine is fine. It’s a food preservative. It’s a concentrated drink that has water juice.
They often use sulphur dioxide.
I start the wheeze, my chest closes up, I definitely have a response to honey,
my throat gets very irritated, I start to clear the back of my throat.
Other than that I don’t have any food allergies that I’m aware of.
– We’ve tried many diets and he hates to diet.
I tried to cut out salicylic acids, wheat and sugar.
– Have you ever taken aspirin?
– Yes and actually I had a bad reaction. My throat...
- Was it inside the throat?
– I couldn’t speak actually, it was inside the mouth,
it was the one time I was nervous that my breathing is trapped but it hasn’t ever happen again.
– Has he ever taken cortisone before homeopathic treatment?
– Yes, I took cortisone after the aspirin.
But before my original allergic reaction in 1993, no.
– I am in South Africa, he is in London.
He weren’t going to a doctor, sometimes he will listen to me I treat him, it’s very bad,
but this is how it works.
– With homeopathic remedies?
– Yes, on the e-mail.
– So what remedies have you prescribed for him?
– I’ll tell you what I’ve prescribed for him.
Another doctor in South Africa when he comes home has prescribed for him.
As a child when he got exertional asthma I used to give him Ars. which did well.
I used to give him low potency Nat-m. for hay fever.
He had quite a good response but it didn’t last very long.
He used to get conjunctivitis quite a lot and I gave him Puls.
and even now I tell him to take it makes him better.
The doctor I saw in Pretoria said that Kali-i. would do him good
because he was getting exhausted from work and he as a very high achiever he always succeeded very well
and wanted to do in work very well and he has this inner conflict
between doing the right thing in work and for his bosses,
I don’t know if the father has an influence himself and wanting to be himself.
He is a very romantic person. He wants to study...
- Archeology, astronomy, history, literature.
– There is much conflict inside  him.
– Keep going, you’ve summarized pretty well!
– I can try and give you the case. As a baby he nearly died of salmonella.
I was working, someone else was looking after him,
he got giant urticaria when he was very young from a high dose of a fever mixture
and I think it might have had salicylic in it.
He often had a post nasal drip and itchy nose, even now he gets it.
He got in-growing toe nails often and had to have an operation for that.
And then the main complaint, he completed his Master’s in Law in N.Y.,
he came home, he had the prick on his hand,
he had his wisdom teeth removed and he swelled very badly,
it started in his scrotum and then it was spread to his legs and we took him to urologists
and the doctor said he had septic fasciitis,
put him into hospital IV drip and his hands swelled up with the drip.
After he left to go overseas he told us that he kept with the swelling all over.
The swellings are indurated, they are quite hard, it gets itchy,
it develops like a raised plaque and sometimes you see it’s surrounded by red spots.
They affect everywhere, all sides, soles of his feet, hands, eyes, arms, leg, torso
and there’s no pattern, I’ve tried to see if it starts left or right but...
- I mentioned that sometimes there is a left and a right symmetry.
Lot of it starts as a severe pressure, my watches here, my hands swells,
sometimes it starts with the one eye and then it’s spread to the other eye but that’s less often.
– And I think a strong symptom; same time as he swells he develops different stool.
– Quite often. I get an upset stomach.
– Every time he has an allergic crisis then he has different stool.
That means softer?
– More fibrous, more flaky. Like bran flakes.
– And he thinks that he’s better from exercise.
– I think it produces adrenalin which sort of brings down the swelling
but when I go and I exercise perhaps I take my mind off of this.
– Better from exercise, mental, physical or both?
– I think a bit of both. Definitely mentally, I feel much better when I exercise.
In terms of the allergic reaction I sometimes feel it has a good effect.
I can sit here and wanting to scratch forever
but when I go and exercise I feel the itching has subsided.
– He always had a sensitive skin.
If he scratches it, it goes red, if he squeezes a spot it gets inflamed.
His back was prone to acne, not bad acne.
– He had a bad acne as young?
– No. His back in prone to acne.
– When I was a child rolling on grass I got hives.
Grass produces a sort of allergic reaction.
– For the gastrointestinal history he loves sweet things, pastries,
sweet fruit juice, wants to drink juice with all his food, ice cream, cold drinks.
And he’s a cold person.
–In what sense?
– Not cold to people, you’re warm to people but physically cold.
– You feel easily the cold?
– No, no I wouldn’t be so sure about that.
I think I can survive in a t-shirt.
This is warm weather but in cold weather I don’t always feel the need to be well dressed.
I enjoy the cold. I disagree with that.
– Do you like to stay under the sun?
– Yes but I don’t mind cold environment.
I’m in England now and I can wear a t-shirt in cold weather. It’s not so bad.
– Mother always sees he takes a jersey or a shirt.
Now you took a shirt, you put it on,
in your flat in the evening sitting by the window you put something warm.
– I can handle the cold better.
– He dislikes fish. And he struggles to put on weight.
– I can’t, even if I try. If I do a lot of gym and physical exercise,
then I put on weight but other than that I can eat as much as I want I just don't put on weight.
– And he hates to be frail, he wants to be strong and big.
He hates when he’s like me!
– I feel better if I exercise.
– What about salt?
– I don’t use a lot of salt in my food.
– You dislike it if it is too salty.
– Yes.
– Very strong sense of smell and his spine, he is very prone to stoop.
Then his emotions and his personality; very full of tensions.
If you talk about the child of love, he was my first child,
the child of love and a lovely child!
He was a very easy child, a good child at school.
Everybody loved him. He was just kind and warm, affectionate.
He cries easily now but he used to hold it in.
Used to not to want to be weak, wanted to be strong.
He gets pleasure from pleasing others and even impressing others
but he wants to do what he believes in. That’s a conflict.
– What he believes is correct or is fitting him more?
– I wouldn’t do something to advance my career
if I thought it was compromising my values and what is important,
so I am not cutthroat in that sense.
I’ve done things that I thought would be good for my career
and to impress people that I work will so I will do that,
I do go that road to impress people
but if I had to kill somebody or tell a lie or do something bad I wouldn’t do that.
I wouldn’t be happy for my success.
My sense of values of right and wrong are very strong.
– He dislikes confrontation but he doesn’t avoid it.
Even in university he would never be politically correct,
he did things that made trouble for him because he believed in being open.
But still it upsets him because he doesn’t like the confrontation that comes.
– I don’t go looking for confrontation but sometimes I enjoy debate.
When it comes I’m there. I get this from my father I guess.
I’m not an aggressive person
but when I get a sense of a threat or conflict I don’t mind facing it.
– He won’t be walked over yet one has the feeling that he is a yielding person.
He will fit to the girlfriend for example and the things that they like,
he will go with them, he doesn’t like to upset me so he will try to do the Homeopathy if I say so
but if he doesn’t want to do it he will go his own way.
As I say there’s much conflict.
He’s very rational, analytical and he finds it difficult to have a faith in spiritual things.
– I tend to approach things rationally.
I can be inspired by beauty in the world and music and nature.
I’m not a religious person and I tend to be more rational.
– I tried to make him meditate but it’s not easy.
He can’t do it. And he has song sense of righttitude.
– I also have an awareness life’s not fair sometimes
and I don’t expect people to treat me fairly,
if they take advantage it’s my fault I didn’t protect myself.
Here’s the way I approach it.
– He doesn’t like to talk about his diet, his treatment and his problems.
He likes to talk about the world, archeology, astronomy, music, art and literature.
And he hates to be humiliated.
He thinks that recognition from others is more important than self-satisfaction.
– Maybe yes.
– But he does not forget criticism although he is very forgiving to those who love him.
He has a lack of inner peace.
He’s always on the move, wants to go places, see countries.
– Do you feel you are in a hurry?
– I need to do things, yes. I never just sit back and do nothing for a long time.
I need to be reading, I need to be learning, improving myself.
– His house is in a mess, he needs to sort out his affairs but he doesn’t.
He wants a girl and he likes company. Insatiable appetite for life.
– You like company all the time or there are some times that you want to be alone as well?
– I sometimes like to be alone as well
but lately I spend less time on my own reading and thinking about things.
Maybe leaving home, living abroad you tend to be more involved ina community.
I’ve spent a lot of time developing myself as a person.
I think I may have spent a lot of time reading, studying.
Now I think I like to meet people, spend more time being social.
I have always been fairly social.
– If you are in your flat and you’re upset about something
and somebody comes and says you don’t look well, what is the problem,
you like this kind of interference?
– Not really. I’d rather say I’m fine, I’ll be ok, let’s talk about something else.
– His friendships are not friendships, they’re just formal.
He has just a few personal friends that he can confine.
– My closest relationships are the people I’m involved with,
a girlfriend I don’t confide a lot of people. I confide my mother!
– He has a conflict in work and with his girlfriend and I think the way he explains it.
The conflict between his feelings and his mind.
– Are you able to express your emotions, feelings of affection to your girlfriends?
– Absolutely. Completely. What about your girl consoling you for something?
You like it?
– Yes, I do.
I think I am open in that sense.
If I have big conflicts, I have big career and personal decisions to make now
it’s not like it has been around for the past 7 years that I’ve had my allergic condition,
basically I’ve been involved in a relationship for a long time and we are on the stage
we have to decide if it’s going to go on and be together for the rest,
we get married or we are not going to.
That’s the big issue to deal with and I am dealing with it right now.
And it is my job.
I have to decide whether I am content with my current job or move elsewhere, move countries.
So a lot of dilemmas I am dealing with. I am not a very decisive person.
I struggle to make choices.
I have been thinking about these things for quite a while now.
And sometimes I tend to take decisions when the circumstances force me to.
When I do I do very well. At work I’m not very good at planning long term.
If there is a crisis or something going on I deal with it very well
but I am not very good at being proactive, I tend to wait for situations.
– Rather than creating a situation for the future yourself.
– But the conflict I see is between his emotions, because he loves the person,
and his mind which says if this is an arranged marriage it will be wrong.
And also in the work, between staying in the job and making a lot of money
and becoming important and thinking oh! That’s not what I want.
That’s not really what is meaningful to me.
And the conflict is the same conflict he has always had.
And he is being much worse lately.
And when I come to London and he talks about it
and he things he is sorting something out and he wakes up the next morning...
The body is just full of red blotches, very bad.
It’s worse because he talk.
– I tend not to confront such things.
It’s quite good to talk about it openly as we do,
but on the other hand I tend to put them aside, I tend to ignore.
My whole condition, I pretend it doesn’t have any effect on me.
I haven’t been very aggressive about eating, doing elimination diets or anything like that.
I just tend to say it will go away and I have been able to live with that until now.
But I think I am reaching the stage now, it’s just enough!
– And just a few generals I can add, it might help.
He dislikes animals messing on his clothes but he loves cats.
– Dogs slobbering over me, I can’t stand it!
– Dogs, no...
- I love cats.
– Can a cat jump on you?
– Yes. Because cats are clean.
Dogs are messy. He doesn’t like dogs. He used to be fastidious.
He didn’t like to share glasses or eat from somebody, now he is changed.
– That was long ago, not now, before I started dating people.
– Like he is totally changed. He hurries when he is walking always, you’re far behind.
He goes ahead always. He hates to be weak, like I told you,
therefore he denies his illness.
He works hard to build his muscles and change his small frame,
he has a tendency to be skeptical and suspicious and to doubt people and their motives.
He is careful with money but he is learned to be generous with gifts.
He like to be careful with his money.
He loves to talk about things that interest him.
He bites or picks his nails all the time, he picks his lips,
picks his toenails all the time.
All his life. And he grinds his teeth.
– When I sleep.
– And Dr. Luke said he must always think of delusions.
He has this feeling of dissolution sometimes that it’s all meaningless.
He has worked so hard, he’s put so much into the relationship...
- I am very optimistic about life and everything, I really am,
but it’s slight cynicism, you know you don’t think that just by being applied
or practical or focused in a particular area,
everything I going to work out for you.
In a way I see it as a transient thing, maybe that I will find the path.
Either in terms of relationships or work and I will get it on and it will be fine.
The purpose of putting an effort to get something,
there is a slight cynicism about the world in general.
– Looks like you are a little bit futile.
– Yes. Hard energy and hard effort which I have put for a lot of things in my life,
may not necessarily be the answer.
– As a child they said he was like 60 years old.
He was so mature. But as a person now he is full of child-like things.
He can play games, he likes to laugh, he loves to go and play games even with children.
– I joke with people.
– He desires air, I think you are definitely a cold person.
And the treatment, now I can tell you the last few treatments I have given him and how he responded.
Like I said he had Ars. as a child, Nat-m., Puls., Euphr.
– Tell me the treatment after I gave him...
- I went back to Kali-i. because it helped him before.
And I told him, because I was away and doesn’t like it when I ask him the questions,
I just gave him a formula, I know that’s bad,
but I said take Kali-i. 200C, take Tub. 200C
– So, you have given Kali-i. and Tub. repeatedly.
- Alternating. I think he got Tub. 3 times, 200C, 200C and 1M.
And then I thought he was getting much worse.
So I just stopped giving him anything,
but after the Tub. I spoke with him one day and he had his asthma
and he got the conjunctivitis, like he used to have.
So I thought that’s fine, I am very happy. Just leave it.
But then the swellings started to get much worse.
And the one day, because he was starting to feel weepy I told him to take Puls. 1M.
And he took it and then I am never sure if he was getting worse from an aggravation
and would get better or the meds have just passed over him.
So I left him after that.
– So Kali-i., Tub. and Puls.
You have given these 3 remedies after Nat-m.
– And I think a little bit of Sulph.
but low, 12X he had for 2 weeks, every day and Sulph. 200C.
I think Sulph. has helped him but I wasn’t sure.
– Your feet in bed are warm or normal?
Do you have to stick them out of covers, do you have to wear socks?
– They are normal.
– When you sleep you cover them?
– Yes. Last night I noticed they’re a bit cold so I put a sheet on me.
But generally I am not that sensitive.
– Do you have any salivation during sleep?
– Not often, very seldom. Just when I wake up but nothing major.
– He has a healthy libido.
– What?
– Healthy sex life.
– Healthy or too much?
– I think it’s healthy. It’s active and it’s healthy.
It’s not obsessive, it’s not too little.
Right now I am trying to focus on everything else.
Because I’ve got another things in my life to worry.
– Do you take fruits?
– Yes, quite a lot.
Bananas I love, I like peaches, apples, mango I love.
Lots of apple juice.
– What about fruits which our sour?
– No. Lemons, grapefruits I don’t like.
– Do you have nightly emissions, an orgasm during sleep?
– No. One thing I do have when I urinate,
there is a slightly release after I urinate.
– Drops of urine after urination.
– Yes, in the last 4 months I think.
– How much water do you need?
– I don’t drink an enormous amount of water.
- You drink cold drinks instead?
– Yes, a lot.
During the day I don’t drink a lot, I need to remind myself sometimes to drink.
– What kind of cold drinks you drink?
– A lot of apple juice, sparkling water
and just recently I have stopped a lot of fruit juices.
– I told him to stop drinking them.
– If I had my way I would drink a lot of fruit juices, diluted with water.
I don’t drink a lot of Coke or things like that.
They are bad. I used to like Sprite and Fanta.
– Have you ever used cannabis indica?
– Twice in my life when I was much younger.
– Was any dramatic effect?
– Not that dramatic, very pleasant but not initially.
It was not as dramatic as maybe I thought it should be.
And that was on 2 occasions, when I was 23 years old. I haven’t since.
It definitely had a very pleasant effect but maybe I expected more.
My mother mentioned my sense of smell is very acute.
Music has a very good mood enhancing effect on me.
I listen to a nice piece of music and I will love it. I love dancing.
– What kind of dancing? Latin American dancing, salsa, merengue.
– What about rhythmic and strong music?
– I like it, yes. I enjoy it. Heavy African rhythms.
I enjoy it but I am not into head banging music,
not heavy metal and that sort of things.
I like more melodic, more harmonious.
– And when he was a child I gave him Kali-c. once and he got ulcers on his palate.
– You like the fat of the meat or you take it out?
– I take it off.
– No way you eat it?
– I wouldn’t just eat plain fat.
If there is a bit of fat in the meat I would have it but I don’t like fat.
– Eggs? You like them normally or a lot?
– I like eggs. I don’t take a lot of them because of my problem.
I tend to have cereal in the morning when I am going to work,
but I like eggs, I like to put tomato sauce to them.
I like spices and seasoning.
– He doesn’t like to eat eggs without them.
– But what type of eggs you like?
– Fried eggs I like the most.
– Would you like to have every day 2 fried eggs?
– No, that would be too much. I like to alternate, to have cereal.
It’s bad for the cholesterol.
– If it was good to have an egg every day...
- Probably I wouldn’t have eggs the whole time.
It’s funny because sometimes I think eggs also irritate my mouth lining slightly if I have too much eggs.
I’ve never been sure about it but sometimes I get that sense.
– Do you have any problem tying your clothes here?
– With my shirts yes.
– Can you put a tie? If you are just intolerable.
– No, I prefer not to wear a tie, but I have to for work. So I am used to it.
– He is focused now but if he talks about himself these days he just drifts off.
– While we are talking now I am being quite focused
because I am trying to give you all the information I can to get better
but I have been drifting a little. I really have.
– Because you don’t find the conversation interesting enough or engaging enough?
– Partly.
– When he is thinking he wants to explain his thoughts he starts to talk and then he just...
What was I saying? Like too much is happening.
– He doesn’t remember what he is saying?
– He just loses his focus and he doesn’t want to focus in his life and make a choice.
– How is your memory?
– Pretty good.
– Do you forget sometimes what you are saying or what you have to do?
– No. I don’t have bad memory like going senile.
I tend to remember things. Lately maybe it hasn’t been that good as it was.
I am feeling a lack of direction lately to a certain extent in my life.
It’s true. Direction career-wise.
Personal-wise, the country I am going to live in.
I think everything has been drifting.
I haven’t been as focused as I could be.
– What about South Africa? You are not thinking of going back?
– I don’t think so.
– When I fix the country he will come back.
– When you become a prime minister you can come back!
– After I gave him Nat-m. 50M, did you repeat it?
– No, it was just once.
– I was scared.
– He has been vaccinated of course?
– Yes.
– And also when he was a child they did routine tuberculous test on the children
to see if they needed BCG and he was positive.
They said he needed BCG but I didn’t let them give it to him.
Then I was so angry because he had had the tuberculous test.
I thought it shouldn’t be necessary.
– Are you afraid of the dark?
Can you sleep in the dark without problem?
– Yes.
I think water sometimes might be uncomfortable, I scuba-dived, I didn’t feel entirely comfortable.
– As a child he was more scared to go to the deep waters.
– I think I had a bad experience once.
I was pushed into a swimming pool by a kid. I didn’t like that.
– That’s a keynote; he doesn’t like to be criticized. He doesn’t like to fail.
– I don’t like failure. I don’t like to take the risk of failure I suppose.
I take risks but I calculate them.
– That’s another contradiction, he wants to travel and adventure but he wants to stay.
– You never ate fish in your life?
– I’ve eaten fish, I just don’t like it as much as meat. I love red meat.
– But not fat in the meat?
– Pure fat, absolutely not, meat with a bit of fat in it I can live with it.
Slightly fatty meat tastes fine to me and maybe sometimes a bit of fat can taste good
but if it recognizably fat, pure fat, absolutely not.
When I used to eat pork, I used to eat the crackling,
the fat on the edge of bacon, I like that.
It tasted quite nice but otherwise not.
Because burned sometimes it doesn’t even taste like fat.
– You say in-growing toe nails but I see you don’t have a problem,
do you cut them especially?
– No, I had them operated.
Sometimes they get a bit irritated but I still have slightly in-growing toe nails.
One thing to mention; I burp quite a bit, I don’t know where it comes from but I do.
– I think definitely when he is nervous.
– He always had a gland here.
– Not lately though.
– Little discreet gland.
– Does he have problem with his teeth?
– Not very good teeth but I gave him fluoride as a child
but his teeth are the worst of my children.
– Perspiration during sleep?
– Sometimes when I am stressed or anxious I notice I do perspire
but otherwise no. If I sleep and I wake up I’m fine, if it’s hot I perspire.
But definitely I have noticed when I am very anxious about something I perspire.
– Ok. Let’s go!
The first that we notice is that we struggle to have a clear case.
Why is it not clear? Maybe the interference of several remedies after Nat-m.
which has brought about a period of amelioration has interfered
in order to give this sense of confusion.
The question is whether still Nat-m. is indicated or whether another remedy makes an appearance.
I was not really able to point down either the one or the other.
I was not able to see whether a clear case of Nat-m. is still there
or whether another remedy is better than Nat-m.
In the process as we were looking there were a few other possibilities
but none of them was clear.
So given the facts that Nat-m. was the one remedy that actually kept him
for a period of time on a better situation,
given also the fact that he never stopped drinking coffee
because as he said he’s careless about his diet
and he did not most probably pay attention to the idea of not drinking coffee at all.
You take homeopathic remedy, especially Nat-m. is sensitive to coffee
and it’s one of the main remedies that has this type of reaction.
You will see this allergic reaction.
So taking one coffee in 9 months maybe has no effect but taking coffee regularly,
once or twice a week definitely will have an antidotal effect eventually.
Do not get the idea that if I drink only one or two coffees a week that will not antidote the remedy.
Therefore on the one hand we have the fact that Nat-m. had given an amelioration for a period of time,
in spite of the fact he kept on taking coffee,
given also the fact that we do not see at this moment another remedy appearing,
given the fact that he put 33 symptoms... Can you just show?
Still Nat-m. is the first remedy. What are the symptoms?
He’s taken all kinds of symptoms. Desire for company, consolation....
Sensitive to odors... Eye swelling... Flaky stool.
Show me, this is a peculiar symptom. Verat. is quite strong there.
But I could not confirm it. Phos. also is a possibility and therefore
because Nat-m. and Phos. were a possibility,
for a moment I was thinking,
when I was talking about fried eggs
and all that of Nat-p. Nat-p. is a more open person than Nat-m.
More communicative, social and somebody who does not like to speak about himself
but he cares about others.
He is interested in conversations. I was not able to confirm.
There are 2 keynotes; one is night emissions in their sleep.
A typical Nat-p. in men usually has orgasm during sleep.
Of course he has a normal sexual life and does not have the extra energy
but it doesn’t matter.
Still it happens in spite of the fact the person may have normal sex life during the day.
Desire for eggs. And therefore my suggestion will be stop the coffee entirely,
stop also the mint from the toothpaste.
Eliminate and use toothpaste with another flavor like strawberry or something
because I found out that Nat-m. can be antidote by mint.
Therefore he has to stop coffee and mint.
That’s all he can do anything else he likes.
And go back to 50M and take 3 doses.
You have to give him 3 doses, one every day of Nat-m. 50M and have in mind Nat-p.
If we have a kind of reaction then we wait,
even after the first remedy if he has a reaction, you stop.
Second dose, he has a reaction, you stop.
Third time 50M then wait in any case.
– There are a few symptoms missing from Nat-p. one was the night emissions and...
- The desire for fried eggs. Real desire. They can have 10 eggs a day.
There was but not strong enough for me to go straight to that.
I investigated that and he said not every day. Any questions? No, thank you.
Yesterday, I wanted to ask about the Nat-m. case.
You originally said that if you give a remedy that is close
but it’s not the right remedy it will have an effect
but after a time the effect will go.
Maybe isn’t this the case with the Nat-m. where the man had an effect for a while
and then the effect went away.
– Which case of Nat-m. are you talking?
– Yesterday it was the last case of Ruth’s son. Daniel.
Angioedema. Is it not possible? Is it not an idea?
– I don’t understand your question, repeat your question.
– They question is it possible that Nat-m. was very close to the right remedy
but was the wrong remedy and thus had an effect for a while and the effect went away?
– Yes, it’s possible though if it is close in this way he would report
rather an amelioration on the emotional level only, not really on his condition.
Usually if it is close and especially Nat-m. will report an amelioration in this condition.
The second is his mother told for 9 months he did not complain.
After that he started complaining.
He cannot remember very well for how long.
But what made me think of Nat-m. again was the fact that he never stopped drinking coffee.
And we know that if somebody keeps on drinking coffee it will be sometime
when he will definitely antidote his treatment, especially Nat-m.
So the first thing we have to do is to repeat and see whether Nat-m. will still work.
When I saw him it was much closer than he appeared here.
But still I feel that Nat-m. will do again the job
and most probably better than the first time if he stops drinking coffee.
- One of the students said your shoe laces are open.
– Don’t worry! My shoe laces are always open!
I’ve never fallen! Let them be!
– Is it possible to treat a relative, Daniel was treated by his mother?
– Difficult! It’s very difficult!
For instance, I have been treating my wife for 30 years unsuccessfully!
I don’t know what happened. You cannot see. You’re blind.
Most probably the woman has this ability blinding us so we cannot see the truth!
– Is there a wife syndrome too?
– There is no such syndrome and you know why. I like the way that you stop and ponder!