This is a case of a child of a medical doctor from Portugal
who is not an experienced homeopath and has prescribed for his child and I will read his report.
- She has been treated by [doctor’s name].
She has been treated by her, who is a teacher of mine.
Because there are no schools of Homeopathy in Portugal, unfortunately.
– Sophia was born 25 weeks premature. We have to go a little bit fast.
Due to an obvious delay of her neurological evolution she was seen in a rehabilitation center
when she was 11 months old and neurological consultant moderate diagnosed cerebral palsy.
She began homeopathic treatment with Nat-m., due to chronic constipation and irritability and she improved much.
She had in the meanwhile impetigo and several bouts of bronchiolitis treat with Ant-t.
But in February 1998 she had a left tonsillitis that progressed right and then asthma that didn’t respond to Ant-t., Sulph. or Tub.
She had to be admitted to hospital where she was treated with steroids because she responded to nothing else.
After discharge from hospital she began to cough during sleep, waking from sleep and had aversion to drinking water.
She improved much with Lach. 3LM and then some older symptoms reappeared like sour belching after eating, constipation and pica.(paper)
I should have waited longer but not believing Lach. to be her similimum, I gave her Lyc. and then Calc. but didn’t help her very much.
Since she is restless and obstinate child, fears animals, specifically dogs, had frequent bouts of lower respiratory infections,
tuberculic eyelashes and likes very much to tear paper I decided to try Tub. again, 30C.
The very next day around midnight, during sleep, she initiated sudden for the first time in her life, focal convulsions.
Left arm and leg. Since the pupils were dilated I gave her a single dose of Bell. 30C,
according to her doctor and there was an aggravation of the convulsions with opisthotonus and jerking of the head to the right side.
In hospital after the convulsions stopped, there was an aggravation of another formal symptom,
startling easily from the fright, noise at 4 a.m.
These symptoms I am reading now, does she still have them now?
-The easily startling yes. She gets frightened very easily.
-She wakes up at 4 a.m.?
You write here that startling easily from fright, noise and at 4 a.m. she had a high fever that was suppressed by antipyretic.
That was only one time. She does not have fever in the morning.
- No, it was just that time.
- She began treatment with carbamazepine,
1 month later she had another bout of partial convulsions and according to her doctor
I gave her a single dose of Stram. 9C, 30C, 200C but 2 hours later she was still having them,
so I had to treat the convulsions with diazepam.
Next morning she was very frightened, like she was seeing monsters and was unable to recognize her mother for a while.
She likes bathing very much. Craves bread, fruit and fat.
She is happy and a lovely child and like company, to be the focus of attention and to be carried.
Consolation improves her symptoms much. She chokes frequently on swallowing.
She had fear of machine noises, animals and is startled easily from fright and loud noises.
She used to bite her own arms when contradicted. Is this symptom still there?
- – I think not anymore.
- – Sometimes diarrhea, alternated with constipation.
– That’s not recently also. She used to be constipated, now she is not.
– She is frightened easily. I gave her Lach. 3LM for 2 weeks but there was no positive response.
Constipation did not improve. In the meanwhile she had the third bout of seizures, even under carbamazepine.
Her doctor advised me to initiate Nat-m. again;
there was frank amelioration on constipation, fears, easily startled and resolution of a tonsillitis, she had a few days after initiating Nat-m.
However, this winter the lower respiratory infection showed up again with much rattling of transparent mucus,
wheezing and persistent coughing with 1 a.m. to 5 a.m. aggravation, getting better after expectorating and worse from crying and eating.
After 6 weeks therapy with Nat-m. she was still having these symptoms so I changed to Kali-c. 1 LM, after 3 doses did not improve,
she had to be given Ventolin because she was exhausted from coughing and not sleeping.
My last trial was with Phos. LM but on the third night of therapy during sleep, even medicated with carbamazepine she had convulsions again.
This time very dramatically she bites her tongue, begins to vomit, food got stuck on the throat and she became cyanotic and breathless.
Thanks to God we were able to remove the food and reanimate her.
This is the report from her father and as you see the child is not able to walk.
The child is now...
- She will be next month 4 years old.
– She is under antiepileptic drugs.
– She is still under carbamazepine.
– And during the epileptic attack can you describe how she looks like? It is only on one side still?
– Normally she has convulsions during sleep or immediately after sleep.
And the convulsions always begin on the left side. First she becomes unconscious.
– Without trembling?
– Then the left arm begins to tremble, then the left leg and then it becomes generalized.
– Trembling or convulsions?
– Convulsions. But it begins with a slight tremble on the left.
– Slight tremor. Show her mother. Do it. Was anyone epileptic in your family or hers?
– Not at all.
– Was anything like tuberculosis in your family or hers?
– My mother had tuberculosis. And her sister also had tuberculosis.
– Is she behaving the way she behaves here? That means the moment her mother put her down she started crying.
– Sometimes she has these violent tantrums.
– She likes to be in that position like this or this is best for her?
– She normally crawls. She is very restless and likes to crawl.
– How about her teething?
– Just irritability.
– The teeth are not out at all?
– They’re all out but she had no ailments concerning her teeth.
No fever, no convulsions, no diarrhea. Teeth came later than usual.
– She was vaccinated?
– She was vaccinated twice against poliomyelitis.
The first time she got fever and the second time she got a bout of lower respiratory infection.
– The triple vaccine?
– She has done it once but then we had to abolish completely the vaccination because when she had this vaccination,
the triple vaccination, she had some sort of spasms.
– After the vaccination, she had the first spasm? For how long?
– They were not complete convulsions. They were spasms. Like tetanic spasms on the left side.
Her doctor gave her Sulph. and with Sulph. they disappeared completely.
So we stopped completely to vaccinate her.
– With her eyes? She has some strabismus?
– It looks like strabismus, according to her eye doctor, it looks like strabismus but it’s not real strabismus.
– What is it? The right eye goes inside.
– The lesion is not on the nerves it’s on the brain cortex.
It’s not a real strabismus. The eye doesn’t move to the right side.
– But the right eye is convergent to the left.
Except of these remedies have you given any other remedies?
You don’t mention Sulph. here. You gave Sulph. in the beginning, you say, but you don’t mention it.
She was given Sulph. when she had the spasms after vaccinations.
Probably I forgot to write.
– On her previous history we have, due to respiratory depressions she was under mechanical ventilation for 17 days.
On the 11th day of her life she had STA. What is STA?
– Staphylococcus epidermidis, sepsis.
– And a great right ventricular hemorrhage was detected echographically.
The last TF echography was performed in October 1995, showing a slight bilateral ventricular dilatation.
She was discharged from the hospital on the 113th day of life, almost 4 months, her weight was 1.860 grams.
– I think there is another symptom that I forgot to tell you.
She shows very often grinding of teeth. Sometimes during sleep. And she has hiccup very often.
– When it was the last time she had fever?
– April this year, we went to Barcelona for vacations and I got a cold and she got a bronchiolitis and viral pneumonia.
I saw the X-ray, it didn’t show infiltrates, I think it was just a bronchiolitis but the doctors in the hospital told us
that it was a viral pneumonia.
– And she took antibiotics?
– Yes.
– Do you know what is the condition if you don’t give the antiepileptic drug?
Have you left her without the antiepileptic drug to see what is the real condition?
That means every how many days she may have the convulsion.
– Well, if we don’t give her antiepileptic drugs the convulsions don’t stop at all.
And it’s very dangerous.
– Has she ever been in a status epilepticus? Because you mention here, 2 hours she was...
- The first time we tried to control the convulsion with homeopathic remedies and we waited about one hour
and a half and she was still having convulsions.
– And then she ended up in the hospital?
– Yes.
– And then what did they give during that time? Valium?
– Yes. But now we have to solve this problem with a different drug because Valium was not working very well.
In one of these bouts of convulsions she received 25mg of diazepam and she was still having convulsions.
So we changed to another drug that they use in England the pediatricians, which is midazolam.
A very small dose in the nose and 5 minutes later the convulsion stopped.
– You give it during the convulsion.
– Yes.
– So, you control actually the convulsions and don’t give before the convulsions, regularly.
– The preventive medicine is carbamazepine. She takes it regularly to prevent the convulsions.
– But if the convulsions still come, then you use the other drug.
– Yes.
– Which actually controls.
– But I have to tell you another thing that is not written on the paper.
Once, she was vomiting very much during the convulsions and I gave her Hyosc. and the convulsion stopped for 5 minutes
and then restarted and I tried to give her another dose but it was useless.
Concerning her character; she is very restless, she likes movement very much and she is very jealous.
– How do you know she is very jealous?
– She has no brothers, she is my first child.
She is in a special school and the professors and school teachers say she is very jealous.
She wants all the attention for herself.
Sometimes when I am caressing her mother she tries to show some temper.
– She is too hot. Is she very hot?
– She is normal.
– How much water she drinks?
– When it’s very hot she drinks often water but she prefers juices.
When it’s very hot she drinks water but normally she doesn’t like it so much, she prefers juices.
– If you make a noise she will get startled?
– Yes, sometimes she does.
When we are travelling, if a motorbike passes by, she startles and when she hears dogs barking she gets frightened very much.
– Is she afraid of dogs?
– Yes.
– Very much or isn’t it obvious?
– I think the main problem is that she startles very much when she hears the dogs barking.
– What about during convulsions, do you observe in her face making grimaces or distortion?
– No, definitely not. The eyes turn to the left but this is normal when people have convulsions.
– Do you know if there is itching in the nose, does she scratch her nose at all?
– Yes, very much. Sometimes the eyes also.
– Do you know if she has any pinworms? Have you noticed pinworms in the stool?
– We have her stool analyzed and it showed no parasites, no worms.
– Itching in the anus?
– No. She is also very obstinate child.
– If she wants something you have to give it to her.
– We can put her glasses 30 times, 30 times she removes the glasses.
You can put her the shoes and she removes her shoes. She also likes to strike and to pinch.
And we say please don’t do it and she goes on doing it as often as she wants.
When we tell her don’t do it she does it.
– She makes sure she will do it. Sophia! Attention!
How is it in your language? Aten??o!
If you tell her bring me this, will she try to do it? She will understand first of all?
– She understands a lot of things but she normally doesn’t fulfill orders.
Her mother says she fulfills sometimes orders.
– Is there any excessive perspiration?
– No excessive perspiration, no perspiration at night, during sleep.
– What food does she like most?
– Fruits and bread.
– And milk products.
– She likes cold milk and yoghurt also. Cheese.
– You mention somewhere here that she used to like paper.
– She eats paper, sand.
– She likes these very much? I mean whenever she finds a paper she will start biting it?
– Yes.
– Have you tried to see if she likes chalk?
– No, we didn’t try.
– Can we give her a piece of chalk see if she likes? If she will put it in her mouth, we’ll see.
In her hands. She bites? I mean she can bite or she doesn’t have much strength in her jaws?
– She doesn’t have normal strength.
– But she can chew for instance meat?
– We don’t give her meat. She never ate it.
– You are vegetarians?
– Not completely vegetarians but sometimes we eat fish.
She eats fish almost every day. We both eat fish, 2-3 times in a week.
– So you are vegetarians.
– Not completely. But she likes vegetables very much. She likes vegetarian food.
– Take the chalk from her now. No specific liking.
– But she likes to tear paper very much. When she has a magazine or a newspaper she tears the paper and tries to eat it.
– Show me!
– That’s very typical of her.
– Now the constipation is not there.
– No. When she began taking carbamazepine her bowels were not functioning very well
but now I think she is used to the drug and the bowels are functioning daily.
I think at that time the constipation was more related to the drug than to her constitution.
– How frequently will she have a convulsion now? Once a day, once a week?
– She used to have convulsions every month, once a month, but she had the last convulsion 2 months ago.
– Does she show affection?
– Yes.
– Do you know if she likes sour things like lemon or vinegar?
– Lemon, she likes.
– Sweets?
– Sweets, she likes. Lemon she likes but vinegar and sour food, we don’t eat them.
– How much food will she eat?
– She has a good appetite. And she likes to eat very much.
– Can you describe to me for instance you give her to eat and after half an hour she wants again to eat something?
– No.
– How many times she eats?
– 4 times a day.
– In between she does not ask?
– Not in between because we usually don’t give food between the meals because we think it’s not right.
– Before convulsions does she make any noise?
– No noises. Sometimes she makes this with the throat ...
- What about talking at all? There is no word she can pronounce?
– She can say hello but her speech is very much delayed due to this cerebral palsy.
– She cannot say any word actually, mama, father...
- No. We are really treating her with a special formal physical therapy and she improved very much, but her speech is still very retarded.
– Call her!
– Sophia! Normally she is much more active than she is now, because she didn’t sleep very well. There is this time difference.
– Sweets? She likes?
– Yes, she does.
– What does she mostly eat, fish? Fish is her main food and what else?
– Fish, soya, tofu, cheese, eggs, lots of vegetables ...
- Mostly out of what you say, what do you think she likes the most?
– What she likes most is fruits and bread.
– Can she eat only bread if you give her?
– Yes.
– Is there any salivation from her mouth?
– Yes, she salivates very much but normally these children with cerebral palsy have this problem. She has a lot of saliva.
– But I don’t see saliva running now, since she is here. In the night in sleep?
– I think she salivates more during the day, not especially in the night.
– You said she likes to be carried.
– She likes very much to be carried.
– That means if she is excited or nervous or restless you have to carry her otherwise she will keep on shouting and screaming?
– Yes, that’s right.
– She pushes you. If you touch her she will push?
– No, she likes very much to be touched.
– To be caressed?
– Yes.
– By anybody or by her mother and yourself? If I try to touch her she won’t react?
– That depends on the person. She likes especially to be caressed by her parents,
but she accepts to be caressed by other persons, but that depends on the persons.
– If we are present, nobody...
- Nobody will touch her.
– She cries.
– When she is crying she likes to be caressed by her parents and nobody else.
But just when she is crying. When she is normal, people can caress.
– Do you think she likes salt more than usual?
– She doesn’t like food without salt.
– She behaves now normally or she is quieter, or less quiet than normal?
– She is usually more active than she is now.
– Now you think she is exhausted because she didn’t sleep.
– She didn’t sleep well and there is this jetlag, this time difference...
She is more active usually but normally she goes around the room and...
- Ok. Thank you.
– Thank you very much.
This is one of the cases that we are going to be discussing theoretically how we handle cases that are under allopathic treatment.
This is an example case of what we mean, we have not spoken yet, but we will see how we handle such a case.
What do you think about this treatment so far? Homeopathic treatment.
There is a problem, right? With this homeopathic treatment so far there is a problem,
because we can say that the homeopathic treatment has not stopped the progress of the disease.
The disease has progressed and quite fast I would say, towards a deeper level.
We have a case where we have severe retardation complicated with epilepsy.
And the epileptic fits being constant is not a good sign at all.
It means that of course we don’t ask for the encephalograms, which we believe they have done.
When was the last EEG?
– It was 6 months ago. She had the first when she was 6 months old and then 6 months ago she got another one.
But the EEG’s didn’t show any focus on the epilepsy.
– They didn’t show any focal point?
– Not at all.
– It was generalized.
– They didn’t show any changes. And she had a brain CT then.
We could just see a marked dilatation and deformation of the right ventricle.
– As we have been discussing before, in order to have a real effect upon a case you have to start the case with the right remedy.
Unfortunately nothing else will work.
And then you have to follow it up with, again, the right remedy and then the third remedy has to be correct as well,
before we have real effects.
Otherwise we see a superficial kind of amelioration of certain symptoms but the actual focal point of the disease is progressing,
is going deeper and deeper and sometimes is helped by the wrong homeopathic treatment to develop much faster.
So, from that point of view we can say that Homeopathy is not so innocent, as we like to present it.
It cannot have side effects like the allopathic drugs but it can push the disease deeper, faster than normally will go.
Once it does not stop the progress and it does not improve, then, if there are changes, these changes are negative.
The changes are going towards the mental emotional sphere and also the central nervous system.
So we have to be very careful when we prescribe especially in such sensitive cases.
We have to think very much before we decide on a remedy.
– The convulsions they are from the very beginning, from birth or they developed after treatment?
– The convulsions started 1 year ago but she began to be treated homeopathically probably 2 and a half years ago.
She was having Nat-m. – Lach., Nat-m., Tub.
– Yes, Tub. also before the convulsions.
The first bout of convulsions was 24 hours after we gave her 1 single dose of Tub.
– They remembered this.
And you will understand in the analysis what I mean when I say that once you prescribe prematurely a remedy,
which may be indicated later on, this remedy is going to bring about disturbance, not cure.
You understand what I say? You have to take into consideration always as much as possible,
the totality and because the totality is never covered by one remedy, you find the best possible remedy.
And then you are within the rules. But if on the beginning of a case,
let us say you cannot see clearly the remedy and then you say since the father or the mother had tuberculosis
and she is grinding her teeth why not giving to this child Tub.?
This was the thinking and it is a good thinking because it could have been given a mixture of 25 remedies, which would be much worse.
Now you will have a complete masking of the case.
Still this particular case is masked because of the antiepileptic drugs.
But even if on the top of this you have given 20 remedies to take every day, you cannot find anything.
– I would like to know from the mother the complete state of mind, her emotional aspect during the 9 months of the pregnancy.
What did affect her, what emotions were very strong in her,
what happened to her personal life and was her basic feeling during those 9 months.
Because I feel that it has a lot to do with the child,
which has been born with cerebral palsy with so many recurrent infections within her first year of life.
– We planned this child, wished her very much.
During the 6 months of pregnancy my wife was very anxious, we had some financial problems, she had problems at work and was extremely anxious.
She was being treated with Lyc. during her pregnancy by an homeopath.
I think she suffered a lot during her pregnancy and she showed some craving of sardines which is a very typical fat fish in Portugal.
– She craved for sardines?
– Yes.
– And you never gave Nat-m.?
– No, she was just taking Lyc.
– This is why in the course that we give, we give the essential parts of Materia Medica because I have found out that what happens is;
students are given a lot of information about different remedies, they cram this information and in the end all remedies look alike.
What is the use of that? Somebody has to tell them these are basic things you have to take into consideration.
If you have a mother who has been suffering a lot, that means she is under stress and she desires sardines,
that means salty fish, the remedy most probably is Nat-m., not Lyc.
Because if that was Lyc. the symptomatology would be different and the character of the mother would be different.
– But there is a special rubric that says sardines desire Cycl. and Verat. not Nat-m.
– Yes, but it’s very simple what I think.
Desires fish and desires salt. Which is the remedy that desires fish and salt?
It’s one remedy. Nat-m. Salty fish Nat-s. also. Nit-ac. Is also salty fish.
So the repertory is not everything but here you use common sense.
He says she developed very important thing.
When under stress you develop a special desire that means I don’t get elements of that food which I cannot absorb.
Of that food which I crave, therefore I take it and I put it out.
I am not able to correct all the repertory of course.
But it is interesting that the first remedy the child gets is Nat-m. and the father says under Nat-m. the child did well.
Where it did not do well? Afterwards, where Lach. and Tub. were given.
That means the time for Tub. is not there but there are indications for Tub.
Then you better wait until the full picture of Tub. is prominent.
Because grinding of the teeth, we have several remedies.
We have Bell. very strongly, we have Cina very strongly, Stram. very strongly.
Grinding teeth during sleep Apis, Bell., Cina, Tub., Ars.
How do we know the grinding of the teeth is Tub. and not Cina? It’s not enough.
She doesn’t have worms. Just because she does not have worms it doesn’t mean anything.
Let’s go to the analysis because we have to go a little bit faster to catch up with some cases we have.
In the analysis what we see in the child.
We see a child who has epileptic fits, so we have to find a remedy which has epilepsy.
The second thing we see is the character of the child.
The character of the child is a child which is difficult.
Crying as the father described the child, you give her something and she throws it, you give again, she throws it...
A child which is obstinate, a child which is crying, shouts for no reason.
So your mind should go primarily to 2 remedies.
Which are these 2 remedies which you have to think because of this behavior of the child?
You have to think Lyc? No, you have to think primarily of 2 remedies;
Cina and Cham with a third possibility which is Calc-p.
The behavior the child exhibits is a behavior between Cham., Cina and Calc-p.
What are the differential points among them?
– The differential among Cham., Cina and Calc-p. is the desire to be carried and the amelioration from being carried.
But I want to say that we spent some time with Sophia and her parents at the beach for a few hours and the picture was quite different.
She did not cry at all for 2 hours that we were together.
She was very affectionate, she was making eye contact, she was coming to me even though she didn’t know me
and was very nice and fondling and laughing in a very good mood.
It was a different picture that what we saw here on the video.
– Don’t make the mistake.
Usually when a case is taken from the class somebody has a roommate that means somebody is also observing and also brings some feedback.
And the patient says one thing and then she comes and says, in a particular case I am talking really,
she behaved like this according to me, this is confidential information about the woman,
she behaves like this because I saw her with a Greek man and something was going on
and she implied most probably that they had an affair and this affair did not go very well
and therefore she burst out crying and she had a tantrum.
This was confidential information coming to me.
I asked her roommate, I said this information comes to me, what do you think? She said it is nonsense.
She was 10 minutes with this man in a coffee shop, they were talking and then she came to the room and we were together all the time.
But the imagination of the other woman who saw them for 2 minutes, presented a whole picture which had nothing to do with reality.
So, you have to be careful about your momentary contact with the patient and how he deals.
We ask the parents to describe in general the behavior so the parents they gave us the description
and that is the description which by the way fits with what we see.
Therefore we cannot say the child is very nice because the parents describe the child as such.
This is very simple logic that you have to follow.
And sometimes of course it happens that the child sat down there quite exhausted,
the parent explained this is unusual to see the child so calm, usually is much more restless because she has not slept.
You take your observation because you were together for 2 hours.
You cannot rely on this observation prescribing a remedy.
We need a remedy that has in its pathology the possibility of giving out epileptic fits,
convulsions which is a remedy which is quite difficult in their characters.
Show me the repertorization and see how many symptoms you have used.
You see the 2 remedies which are prominent immediately come to the mind are Cham. and Cina because Cina grinds her teeth .
Cina is obstinate, is difficult in her character, contradictory.
She wants something and then she throws it out.
All this description is like Cina but let us see how many symptoms Cina has altogether.
– 23 out of 34.
– Cina covers 23 of the symptoms that he has put. I did not tell him to put.
As you know whoever sits next to me has to put whatever he likes.
I correct a little bit. Is it true?
- Did I tell you any of the symptoms to put in?
- No.
– I corrected perhaps only one symptom.
– Changed degree.
– Changed degree of one symptom. So whoever does the repertorization the effect should be this.
Not me. The facts. So let me see which remedies cover. Explain. Cina. Desire to be carried;
you know that to be a characteristic of Cham.
Do you know this to be a characteristic of Calc-p.? No. Calc-p. does not matter what you do.
She will continue. Ant-c. also. The other is different, Cina. Contrary. Obstinate, headstrong. Restlessness.
Very restless, Cina. Shrieking. Startled from fright. Striking.
You remember the father says she strikes, she pinches, she hits. This is characteristic.
You can put this in the third degree. Bell., Cina., Hyos. and Nux-v. Cina comes within the most aggressive remedies.
The child exhibits the aggressiveness, this attack.
Show me again the Cina, explain Cina. Striking, rolling...
Strabismus convergent with right turned in. The right eye turned in. Teeth grinding.
And teeth grinding during sleep. Stomach hiccough. Constipation... is not now.
Take it out. You had to have a piece of paper for those who did not have the computer and do this by hand.
It is not possible that you understand so well the remedies that you immediately perceive.
It’s even difficult for myself. And I completed 40 years in Homeopathy day and night.
20 hours a day and night, Homeopathy. Still I cannot be sure between Cham. or Cina. How can you?
You have to open the Repertory to find it. Dentition, grinding.
Respiration difficult, night, midnight, after 1h. She said that?
Respiration difficult in the night? – Between 1-4 a.m.
– Sometimes she has real difficulties in breathing.
– It’s still now?
– Yes, I thought it was because of her tonsils were greater, the adenoids,
glands were dilated and sometimes she has difficulty in breathing. And I thought maybe it was the reason.
– Did you operate?
– No. We were waiting to see you.
– But if it was because of the tonsils the difficulty in breathing would be constant it wouldn’t be within a particular hour in the night.
So therefore, we can leave it.
Respiration wheezing, waking midnight after 4, generals night midnight, generals convulsions.
Convulsions on the left side of the body. Cina has convulsions on the left side of the body.
Also has convulsions from left to right. Convulsions in the night.
Lime, slate pencils, earth, chalk, clay desire.
Cina therefore covers the most – if not all- the symptoms of that child.
So the remedy with which we should start this case is Cina.
Now what is going to happen after Cina and how we shall handle it and how much we shall repeat
and whether we will be able to ameliorate that child while taking the antiepileptic drugs
it is a question mark which we will discuss in the general theory lessons where I’ll give you an overview of how to handle such cases.
Because it is not only epileptic cases, it’s asthma cases, a lot of other cases which we have to talk in detail.
For the time being in order to start treatment for this child, Cina is the best remedy.
Also I have to say that if the antiepileptic drugs were taken out
we would see another picture and the other picture would be much worse than what we observe here.
Sitting and being quite... there is no being quite.
There is a tremendous pathological activity in the brain, generalized which will make you terrified,
you would see a terrifying picture really.
The real picture is terrifying and the aggression may be much bigger than what you see now.
You see the aggression and the convulsions under sedation.
The whole child is sedated. So we don’t see the real picture and that is a problem.
Now definitely Cina is not going to be the remedy which is going to finish or cure the case.
The child will eventually need other remedies.
And the other remedies we cannot at this moment see what might be.
Even Ign. which was coming can be a possibility.
Tub. definitely will come a time when it will be indicated and then you will see the real effect from it.
Calc. also may be of the remedies, or Calc-p. one of the remedies that will be needed later on.
But definitely the right remedy will start ameliorating the case to what extent... I don’t know.
– What do you think about the vaccination?
If I remember well it was after the vaccination of polio, not the convulsion but the cramps began.
And if you think that the cramps are lower level of convulsion, you can think there is a development in this way.
So there are some special nosodes of polio.
– That is true. He said that the whole thing actually started after vaccination.
The vaccination affected this child very much negatively and started the left sided cramps.
But the child started convulsion at the age of 3.
So there was an effect of the vaccination pointing to the danger this child was running if went under severe stress.
What was the severe stress?
She took antibiotics and then eventually Homeopathy and then developed this kind of convulsions.
Definitely there was a predisposition in the child and the predisposition manifested itself immediately after the first polio vaccination.
The idea he was discussing is it possible that we use Polio 200C.
This you do only in cases you are totally lost because you have given all the best indicated remedies and you had no effect.
In such case only you are justified to take the causative factor, as we call it.
Give Polio in post-traumatic epilepsy.
For instance, in a post-traumatic epilepsy if you have a picture of Sulph. you give it.
But if Sulph. which seems to be indicated does not act and then the next best remedy is Apis and you give it
and does not act and the next best is Nat-m. and does not act, then you are entitled to give Arn. as a causative factor.
But many times you will give Arn. in the beginning and in post-traumatic epilepsy and nothing will happen.
That means he needs Sulph. Not always Sulph.
– How many steps you have to take before coming to this point of giving the...
- The Tub.?
– Yes or Arn.
– As long as you have a picture of a remedy.
Here we have the picture of Cina but we have of a picture of Cham.
In case Cina does not have any effect then we have to try Cham.
And if there are some changes or new symptoms we take into consideration we may see that the child needs again Nat-m. or Ign.
– I just wanted to ask about the curability of this case.
- What is your prognosis?
- The prognosis is not good because we don’t know the depth of the problem at this moment.
I don’t want to say outright this is an incurable case but I will say most probably is an incurable case.
In any case if we manage to stop the epileptic fir the child will never become normal in her behavior and in her mind.
She will be lacking always, she will be behind always, but as long as she can exist without chemical drugs this is a tremendous improvement.
If you can take this child out of these drugs, because this child is convicted under this regime to live the rest of her life,
how long she is going to live, in a very difficult condition.
With Homeopathy maybe we have a possibility to improve this condition.
To what extent... I don’t know. What I foresee is not a good prognosis.
– You spoke of the danger of giving Tub. too early
and I don’t know if anybody has repertorized the number of times Tub. appears in the case.
But some of the teachers say until you give the deep-acting, chronic like Tub. nosode you won’t clear the case.
– This is a problem.
– You have to find the right moment. But how do you know the right moment sometimes?
– How do you know the right teacher also?
– I am asking the right teacher!
– That’s why you are a member of the parliament!
The problem is that each one who pretends to be a teacher including me,
because we pretend to be teachers, we call it “åëÝù Èåïý” in Greek.
There is an expression that means I am a teacher because God had told me to be a teacher.
This way anyone can be a teacher.
The problem is that these people have small experience and in their little experience they found out
that when they gave Sulph. or Calc. and did not act and they gave a dose of Tub. the case was solved or opened.
But this cannot be generalized.
Once they see one or two cases like this, they come and say unless you give the deeper remedy... this is totally wrong.
What they thought to be the deeper remedy was the uppermost layer.
Unless you go layer by layer you can never benefit the case because all the cases today as I said have different layers.
This is a symptomatology of Tub. and under Tub. there is a symptomatology of Sulph.
and under Sulph. there is a symptomatology of Nat-m.
Because Sulhp. brings up a symptom to the surface which is desire sweets
and another symptom which is vertigo high places together with a few other of these symptoms, they think this is a Sulph. case.
They give Sulph. nothing happens.
Then, they see also the desire of salt, they give Nat-m. because desire for salt is popping up in the original case.
And they ignore the essential features of Tub. which were there.
Eventually they give it and they say now, unless you give the deeper remedy...
But the deeper remedy is the uppermost.
If you have here a deeper remedy, let us say Psor. is here and you have to give 3 remedies before Psor. and you give Psor.
The most probable is the organism will not move at all. Nothing will happen.
But if you give Sulph. which is the immediate underlying
then the organism will move and will change the symptomatology without progressing the case.
Will upset the case. A headache which is on the right will go to the left.
A vertigo which is while rising from bed will be while lying in bed.
This kind of changes and the person will report some changes which are unfortunate.
Because it means that the case has not progressed. It has been disturbed.
Not because the remedy is not indicated but because it’s indicated as a second remedy, not as a first one.
And you have to take into concideration...
here you see the computer immediately will show the uppermost remedies are Cina and Cham.;
there is no question about that.
If you give Ign... You see the mother had been suffering and maybe she was Ign. or she needed Ign. why don’t give the child Ign.
There are different theories that we hear from different teachers.
Then, you upset the case again with certain changes but not really curing the case.
The problem with Homeopathy is that it is difficult in each application.
But if you see the end results, they are phenomenal, they are unbelievable if you do it properly.
If you do it haphazardly, superficially then you will be in a state of Calc-p. all the time.
Dissatisfaction. You saw it with the cancer case.
You saw the improvement. One remedy, second remedy, there is improvement.
30 other remedies could have been given, no effect.
I could even say if Calc. was given as the first remedy, most probably you would see only a disturbance.
But giving it in the correct order then you saw the result.
– Which potency?
– Here, in these cases you don’t go high, you go low. That’s the first rule.
The second rule is because there are chemical drugs, you have to repeat quite frequently.
That means, quite low, repeated 3 times a day at least for quite some time.
And the problem will be how to reduce and when to start reducing the allopathic drug.
You have to start with Cina 30C, 3 times a day.
I will not go to 12C here because I need a little more strength to overcome the drugs which are very powerful.
And after observation of 20 days the parents they realize the child is getting quieter
and some indications are there that the remedy is acting curatively.
They have to start reducing the antiepileptic medication by a fraction every day.
By a very small fraction.
I don’t know how you can do it technically, but he is a medical doctor, the father, he most probably will find a way to do it.
You continue to give the remedy and if possible after...
What it may happen is that in the process may reduce the chemical drug as it gets better and better.
If at the certain moment they will notice a kind of a relapse they have to change the potency a little bit;
like instead of 30C they have to go to 31C, 32C, 33C and as they reduce they raise the potency
and the moment that the child is kept
and the child at a certain moment when the reduction will be quite substantial will have some epileptic fits.
These epileptic fits, if they can be controlled by the extra remedy which they use in the nose that will be very encouraging.
Because not every day again the organism will take the chemical drug.
In this way they can continue reducing the chemicals and raising the potency of the remedy.
There is going to be a time where most probably will have a change in symptomatology.
They have to take care in every change that the child will have to see whether this change will fit with another remedy.
And what will be the next remedy.
It’s a case, unfortunately, that needs somebody quite experienced to take care of and to advise.
Because you can imagine the moment he will take out the drug she will go into status and then the damage will be permanent.
Here we have the problem that we have the whole hemisphere is distorted and affected;
it is not just focal epilepsy. We have epilepsy because of the whole hemisphere being damaged.
And we have to build that hemisphere slowly again.
It is not an easy job. We attempt to do something next to a miracle.
and then we have to do it very carefully so we don’t damage.
- Will be Cina modifying the severity of the case?
– Cina, if it is the correct remedy, will reduce the aggression of the fits.
And will reduce the aggression of the child.
So the child herself will be less aggressive, less disturbed internally and will have...
I don’t know if it’s less severe or less in number as well, maybe both.
– Would you think of plusing the remedy?
Giving perhaps a liquid and succussing it each time before you give a dose
rather than just keep giving the bottle with the same potency?
– This you can also do it.
But I would increase the potency the moment I see this potency does not hold any more.
So that I have the possibility to increase the potency and then change the vibration 1, 2 or 3 degrees even.
You understand this? You just increase in case during the reduction of the antiepileptic
you will see more fits coming and then you will have to raise the potency.
– When the fits do return, why wouldn’t you use an homeopathic remedy for that acute?
– Yes, if they give me enough information.
If the fits give me information that I know now the fit is like Buffo, or Artem. or whatever.
Unfortunately here, in this school you will not see an easy case.
The cases we will see here are all very difficult cases,
attempted to be treated by both Homeopathy and Allopathy and end up coming here.
And you hear these people are coming from Portugal,
sometimes people are coming from Canada or even Australia, which is even further.
So if they do come that means there is nothing else left as a hope.