This is a case of a young man 42 years old sent to us from an American homeopath
who has been treating him for..
- 5-6 years but not in the states.
I started in Israel with 2 homeopaths and then when I moved to the states I went to see [doctor’s name].
– For how long have you been treated?
– 6 years ago.
– And the remedies that you have taken so far?
– I have written down.
– The remedies he has taken so far is Pod., Sulph., Onos.,
Sil., Staph, Lyc., Nux-v., Nat-m. most probably, Agn., Sil. again,
Bell., Calc., Lyc. and Nat-ar., Ars., Op., Sil., Lyc., Sel.
From the remedies you have taken I can see your problem also.
So what is your problem you better say it to yourself?
– The main problem I have is when I am going to the bath I am not getting empty,
never succeed to finish it at once so I have to go up to 10 times to the bathroom...
- To empty your bowel.
– Right.
– And you get a feeling that it is not emptied?
– Right. I get the feeling, I get urge and I have to go again.
– After how long?
– Sometimes it’s up to 2 mins sometimes it’s up to 2 hours.
There is not a pattern.
- Originally you have been treated by 2 homeopaths in Israel and by one homeopath in the States.
– One of the remedies helped but...
- Which one?
– The Pod.
– The homeopath gave it to me and after 4-5 days it started to influence
and for like a week I went once a day.
– And why didn’t he give it to you again?
– I think he gave it again to me but I don’t know why it is not listed.
It didn’t make any change. If I am not wrong he changed also the potency.
– You got different potencies. Nothing.
– But the first one worked for one week perfectly.
– Do you have another problem?
– I’ve a running nose.
It started 6 years before the stomach problem. It’s still running.
It doesn’t bother me so much. It’s there.
– Running nose...Water or mucus?
– Water, transparent.
– And every time you blow your nose?
– Yes.
– Every time?
– Every time.
But now it is not bothering me so much.
Maybe because I have a bigger problem.
– What is the bigger problem?
– The stomach, the bowel problem. Sorry...
When I have the bowel problem it also influences the urination,
when I have to pee it also doesn’t empty.
But when I have a good day with the bowel everything is also ok when I go to pee.
– So, the urination stops and then starts again...
- I can also to pee an enormous amount of time but again when the bowel is kind of empty it is normal.
– But otherwise you have to go very frequently.
–Yes.
– Every few minutes?
– No. There is no pattern.
Sometimes I have to one after another or 2-3 hours after.
– What else?
– Problems? Nothing.
– How is your energy?
– The energy is low.
When the bowel is not really good I’m tired.
– Your whole body is tired?
– When my bowel is good my body is ok.
– What is your work?
– I am working with the internet for 1,5 year.
– You’re a hacker?
– No! I’m from the good guys!
– Are you very good in this
– No. I’m more for the marketing.
– Selling?
– Yes.
– You’re good in selling?
– I believe so.
– What else? How is your health?
– Like 6 years ago I had a blood test in the States for allergies
and they’ve found many allergies; milk, sugar, wheat...
Like 15 different things and I stopped eating them for 5-6 months completely.
No wheat, no pasta, no bread, nothing.
And then it became very different. I went for once or twice a day.
Of course I lost a lot of weight, I still haven’t recovered and for 5-6 months it was much better.
– By this diet?
– By this diet.
Today the only thing I don’t eat is milk which I know it caused me terrible diarrheas.
– Immediately?
– Few hours after and honey.
When I used to have honey made my bowel like that.
Before this diet I also headache which started from here. It was terrible.
It was too often like once every 1-2 weeks.
Ever since I started with the diet for a few months I didn’t have almost any headache
and now I have only once o month. After the diet improved...
- And now you have it every...
- Once a month or so; normal. Maybe this is important.
When my nose started running for the first time it was after 2 days that suddenly out of the blue I had terrible pain,
for 2 days I simply lied down because I couldn’t even sit and ever since it is like 16 years my nose is running.
Before this it never ran. 2 days there was terrible headache...after this my nose started running.
16 years now.
– But I don’t see it running.
–It’s not so bad.
– Before it was worse?
– Not really, but it’s wet. I know it’s wet.
– Do you like the taste of milk?
– No, but the white cheese yes.
– But milk?
– Milk itself not so.
– You never liked pure milk.
– But coffee with milk yes. Pure milk, never.
– How do you react in weather? If it is very warm or cold?
– No problem.
– You can sit under the sun, sunbathing?
– Yes, no problem.
Once I had hernia on the right and it came back again. I made a surgery...
- And it came back.
– Yes.
– Do you have any fears?
– When I was young I had fear of heights.
– Now?
– Much less but it’s still there.
I wouldn’t voluntarily go to look from a tall building.
In the army I was a paratrooper and I never stood by the door.
I always was like third because I was afraid of the height.
– In the army you were a...
- Paratrooper but I never stood at the door.
There is always someone standing at the door, wait for the green light,
I never stood there, I was always like second, I didn’t want to look down.
– You closed your eyes and jumped.
– They pushed me! They pushed everybody.
– I see the redness around your eyelids. What is this?
Is it usual or because you didn’t sleep last night?
– No, it’s usual.
– Do you know if you grind your teeth in the night?
– I don’t think so. Nobody told me. Sometimes it happens but not so frequently.
– How do you know sometimes?
– But girl. She wakes me up saying to stop it.
– When was it the last time she did that?
– I don’t remember. A few months ago but usually she falls asleep before me.
So, she doesn’t know. She’s already sleeping.
– How is your relation with animals? You feel allergic to animals?
– No. A little bit fear of dogs, I don’t know why. For dogs...
- Cats?
– No, no problem.
– You can pet them?
– No problem.
– Are you going to take them in your lap?
– No problem. Dogs...I don’t know.
– In your family was anybody who had tuberculosis?
– I don’t think so.
– You know tuberculosis?
– I am not sure.
– In the lungs..
- No.
– They make a skin test...
- No. I know there is no lung problem.
– Do you get colds easily?
–No.
– Do you get any closure of your nose or is it always open and running?
– It is always open, running.
– Your sleep is good?
– Yes.
– You sleep right through the night?
– And you wake up refreshed or unrefreshed?
– Usually refreshed.
– You drink a lot of water?
– Yes.
- You’re a thirsty guy?
– No, I wouldn’t say I am a thirsty guy
but sometimes I drink in the heat because I know I have to drink...
- Do you need cold or hot drinks or anything is ok? Anything is ok.
– Yes.
- Concerning the temperature you say you have no problem that means you feel good in heat...
- Heat and cold.
– You can tolerate the cold.
– No problem.
– Do you salivate during sleep? Is there any saliva running through sleep?
Do you understand “saliva”?
-No. Ah, spit!
It was a period that I had a little bit but there was a period that I had it during the sleep.
Now, no. For that last I don’t know how many years.
– He grinds his teeth. He does not know it. You grind your teeth.
It’s only you don’t know it.
Your dentist has said anything or you go don’t go to the dentist?
- I go. Never said anything.
– You eat all kinds of food?
– Yes.
– You eat meat?
– When the meat has some fat in it you like it?
– The fat by itself no but when it’s combined...
The fat by itself no but when it’s mixed I have no problem.
– How much salt you like?
– Very little.
– You’re careful because of your health?
– Yes, I’m careful. Not only for the salt.
– You don’t like it really or you used to like salt and you stopped it when you heard that salt is not good?
– I stopped it when I started the diet a few years ago, with the milk etc.
They recommended not to have salt and I took less than I used to eat,
like sugar, now I don’t drink sugar.
I got used to it but before I used to have sugar...
- A lot of sugar?
– Not a lot.
– Do you know if you have been infected by a venereal disease;
gonorrhea, or trichomonas or anything?
– No and I made many tests.
– You have antibiotics before?
– Not as far as I can remember. Maybe with the hernia I had some but I don’t remember.
– But you had no infections like bronchitis or pneumonia or you had no influenza.
– Not that I remember.
– Maybe when the nose started I took some stuff, that thing that you put in the nose,
but that was 5 years before the bowel stuff...
- And why did you put this in your nose?
– For the running nose because the doctors didn’t know why it was running.
– Sexually how you feel?
– It depends on the bowel.
If it’s a good day it’s good and in a bad day it’s bad. If it is bad I avoid it.
– So actually your life depends on your bowel motion...
- Pretty much.
– Would you say that you are anxious about this? Maybe you think you have cancer?
– Sometimes I think it but after 12 years if nothing happened by now...
- But in the beginning you were thinking?
– Yes, I thought of it.
– What I am asking is whether in the past you were very anxious.
“Oh, I have cancer...My bowels are not working.
Most probably I have some cancer that’s why it cannot come out”.
– I was more excited about bowel movement rather than cancer.
Of course it comes to my mind, all the things that can happen,
but I was more worried about the bowel.
I did some many tests and they never found anything including cancer for which they obviously looked for.
During the years I did all the tests that could be done by the doctors.
– Do you have special dream, that means a dream that repeats itself?
– Usually the come with periods like for a few months a have constant dreaming about something but then it goes.
Something interesting about the dreaming;
sometimes I dream something,
I wake up and months or years after I stand in some place and I say I was here my dream
and I can’t explain it but I know for sure I was there.
It’s not accurate, but it’s accurate enough to say I was here, I dreamed about it.
– Do you have any dreams of falling.
– No. Sometimes I feel that I can fly but not very high
like 50m in the air. As if I am able to take off.
– Being able to doing it actually?
– Doing it!
–When you have stool your nose runs more than usual?
– No, I cannot say.
When I eat spicy my nose is running terribly.
– You said that you feel tightness in the rectum?
– Also, yes. All the system.
– How can you describe this tightness?
– It’s like everything is trying to pull back.
– Not to let it go.
– Yes. In bad day of the bowel it’s also with the urine.
– Did you have any bad experience in your life?
– I had a very bad experience when my brother died
but it was years after this problem started.
– No, before the problem...
- Before the problem not really.
– When did you have your first sexual experience?
– Somewhere between 16 and 17.
– It was with an older woman?
– My age.
– When did you have your last vaccination?
When they give you something to protect you from smallpox, diphtheria...
What year did you go to America?
– 3 years ago.
– Where you vaccinated?
– No. I don’t remember when it was the last time I had any.
– It was in the childhood?
– I think so. In the army we received a few.
– What age you went to the army?
-18.
Just when you go to the army straightaway you get them.
– And when this bowel started?
– In the end of the army after 3.5 years.
I think it’s in the end or right after.
It was somewhere there put I cannot put a finger like I can put with the nose.
– The nose what age it was?
-16.
– And what happened, tell me again because I could not hear while I was writing?
– Suddenly for 2 days I had a terrible headache that was focused here
and I had to lie down for 2 days because I couldn’t even sit.
– But were you exposed to some draft or cold before this?
– Not really, it was summer, it was August.
I week before this I believe it was the summer camp, kibbutz, in a small city.
– You lived with your parents, not in the kibbutz?
– No the kibbutz was just for 2 weeks, it’s a camp, with my parents.
– And you had how many children?
– I have one sister and one brother.
– What did your brother die of?
– Car accident.
– You run fast with the cars?
- I’m a careful driver.
– This running nose is becoming worse if you get exposed to cold?
– Yes, a little bit. It’s getting worse.
But maybe because of the sun it’s dried a little bit.
– If you described your character what would you say about your self?
– I believe I’m honest. I think I am smart. I like to laugh a lot. Joke.
I think I’m friendly. My girlfriend claims that I am stubborn.
But she says it’s about all Israelis so I cannot differ my self from the population.
But I think she is right a little bit, I’m a little bit stubborn.
- If I see the way you insisted coming here...
- If I think I need to do something I’ll do it.
Even if it is to come to Alonissos for 2 hours,
I came a few days in advance so I will not miss anything, I had to plan.
And I am going to stay a few more days so if there is going to be help I’m not going to be exposed to...
- You’re going to stay here?
– For 4 days for sure.
– Here in the report I get it says you never get excited for anything. Is that true?
– Pretty much. There are very few things. It happens rarely but it happens.
– How is your concentration?
– Not so good but the memory is very good. The concentration depends.
If something is interesting I will be concentrated,
if something doesn’t interest me although I know I have to focus...
When I was young the concentration was good. I don’t know why now it isn’t.
– You never have any vertigo, dizziness?
– Not really. I had a few times.
– Only if you look from a very high place you get some dizziness or fear?
– It’s a fear but it’s also something like...
- Turning, vertigo?
– Yes. A little bit.
– You have a fear you may jump or the height may pull you?
– No. I know I’m not gonna jump!
- But drawn down?
– Yes.
– Do you ever think something that will happen and you promote your thinking and your imagination
for instance you go downstairs in a very high building and you run down and at a certain moment
you think what will happen if I just fall down and go down the stairs until I’m crashed?
– No. Never had these fears.
– You never have an impulse to do some dangerous things;
putting your hand in the socket testing?
– No.
– None of these remedies except of Pod. helped you.
– Just the bowel and just for the bowel not for the nose.
– If you eat honey will you have diarrhea?
– It’s the bowel is like tightened and pushed.
It’s a little bit different from milk. The milk is more diarrhea.
– Do you have a lot of gas?
– Yes.
– Very offensive or not?
– Yes, a little bit offensive odor.
– Find feeling of tightness in the rectum or in the abdomen.
Do you think you have said everything?
Tell me the desire to urinate is frequent but not really like you urinate,
you wait there, it stops, you wait there,
it starts again and you wait for a while and it starts again and... interrupted urination.
– It’s more like I urinate I’m moving with something...
- And then it starts again.
– How much sleep do you need? A lot?
– 6-7 hours. When I started the diet I used to sleep 4-5 hours.
When I started the diet I was very energetic.
When I started the diet avoiding milk, honey, bread
I was very energetic I could sleep only 4-5 hours,
lot of sex, made up for previous years and next years!
– Do you know if your parents have any disease?
– They don’t tell. My father has one kidney taken out.
He also has to go twice a day in the bathroom.
He is going twice a day and he’s happy.
– Your mother?
– She has cholesterol and she is going to the bathroom once every 2-3 days.
– If you are in a room where it is stuffy, they smoke does it affect you?
– I don’t like the smoke. It bothers me a little bit. I don’t like when people smoke next to me.
– But you will be the first one to go open the window? Or it’s not so bad?
– If I can and it won’t be a rude thing in someone else’s place I will probably do that.
– Do you cry easily?
– No. Not at all.
– Never?
-When my brother died I cried.
Every year when we go to the annual I can’t help it. It’s like once a year.
And when I remember him I feel like tears are coming.
– The stool sometimes tries to go out and then backs again?
– No.
– Once it’s out, a little piece is out and then it stops.
– When it’s out, it’s out it doesn’t go back.
– And when it’s out the rectum closes and no more urge or there is urge but it doesn’t come out?
– The second. I feel that I still have and it doesn’t go out.
– No power to expel it.
– I feel it’s inside but I t doesn’t go out.
– Alright. I want to give you some more information that was sent with his case from America
about this nice man that we saw and in the report it says that he is a good guy.
Feels bad if he hurts someone. He never has criminal thoughts.
It seems this is a standard question in America now.
I never thought of asking this question so far!
But it becomes a popular question for America and continues and he says it’s hard for him to shout
and also not very aggressive. Also has many friends but deep feelings keeps to himself.
Can lose his concentration as he said, never gets excited for anything, it’s underlined here 3 times.
We did not really get this impression from him.
Good childhood, good parents.
These were things we did not discuss and the case is very difficult.
I can tell you that though the pathology is not important, is not serious,
yet affects his life quite dramatically and he is not a happy man.
He could have been much happier. Why his case is not clear, I am not sure.
It was unclear from the beginning.
Either there is a very small remedy which we don’t perceive
or maybe we have not hit the remedy because he took a lot of remedies as you saw already.
Or maybe because he took so many remedies the case is not very clear.
So we can discuss his case.
I would like first to show you a repertorization with all the information that Phil was feeding the computer
which I did not like and I read it.
He put; constant discharge, watery discharge, diarrhea after milk, fear of dogs,
inflammation of the margin of lids, copious dripping, pain on the rooth of nose,
abdominal hernia inguinal, insufficient stool, constriction of rectum, frequent urging,
stool after urging, bladder urination incomplete and unsatisfactory,
bladder urination interrupted, dreams clairvoyant, dreams of flying,
internal constriction, spices aggaravate, tobacco aversion, smell of tobacco.
If you put all that the computer shows this. I did not like the result.
Show me the result. Phos. and Nat-ar.
Which have come up as you see both these remedies were given to him.
Sulph., Bell., Nux-v.,  was given. Staph. I think was given.
No? Yes. Nit-ac. No.
Anyhow most of these remedies were given and in the beginning I had written down a remedy
which I thought it would be and when I looked in the computer I did not see at all this remedy.
So I ask him to do a different repertorization.
What I want to say is that in repertorization
in order to get some ideas you have to put what are the most clear symptoms if you have such and look through.
You put 4-5 symptoms, you look, you put 1 more, you look, you put another, you look.
To see where is the best remedy. Where comes in each step the best remedy.
Has anybody any idea? No idea.
The whole class is stunned by his case!
– I was thinking about Thuja. Mainly because of the vaccination.
He is not sure how it was his causative agent.
– The only problem with Thuja is that it creates it a dryness of the mucus membranes which is very aggravating.
They cannot sleep because of dryness. He has the opposite.
This cannot exclude but ok, Thuja is a possibility.
We would like to find a remedy that must have both this problem in the abdomen,
the insufficient stool that doesn’t come out and the constant catarrh.
These are 2 main things which we have to couple with certain keynotes and with his character.
So the best remedy will be a remedy that will have his pathology plus some keynotes plus his character.
– Nat-c. because much diarrhea, aggravation and the type of the insufficient stool,
he has to go very frequently and urination is incomplete he has to go very frequently to empty down his bladder.
These are 3 strong symptoms I find of Nat-c.
– Very good.
– I thought maybe Mag-m.
– Also Mag-m. is a good prescription because of the sensitivity to milk.
But which is the remedy which both sensitivity to milk and sensitivity to honey.
Nat-c. So therefore I ask him, put the second repertorization, show me the symptoms.
I stayed for a while and I told him to the constant discharge, the watery discharge,
the diarrhea from milk, the grinding of the teeth during sleep, red lips edges,
constipation insufficient, aversion milk, constriction of rectum, pain root of nose extending to forehead.
That’s it. So, we have a possibility that the remedy is Nat-c.
We have to investigate whether this remedy fits his personality. What is Nat-c. personality?
You did not hear the Materia Medica, you don’t know the personality.
Nat-c. personalities are low-key people who like to help others.
They can even sacrifice their own pleasure for other’s.
They are people who will be sensitive and considerate of others but Nat-c. has a peculiar...
I did not put the aggravation from honey, just put it.
If you put it will become even stronger but it has in its character I didn’t to ask him inside,
Nat-c. has something I will ask you now.
He has aversion to certain persons. You don’t like certain persons.
For one reason or another you don’t like some persons.
If this person appears, you leave. Do you have such thing in your life?
– It’s kind of jealous? Yes.
– Don’t say yes because I ask! This is very bad what I am doing now!
Maybe because we want some more confirmation.
What I am asking is whether you have certain strong aversion to certain people you don’t know why.
You don’t know why but if my mother-in-law comes I don’t like.
This happens often, don’t take this example. When the friend of my cousin comes I don’t like him.
So you don’t like him so much that you have to leave the room.
– No that much that I have to leave the room
but I can see there are people who I don’t like but not like you say.
It’s not I cannot say why I don’t like them.
Usually I see someone and from the look I will say I don’t like him.
But I know why I don’t like him.
- This is not confirmed.
Another question that I would like to ask is if this is a longstanding case of Nat-c.
we could have a sensitivity to the sun and he could relate one case at least where he had a sunstroke.
Did you ever have a sunstroke? You stayed in the sun and you had headache?
Was this case of headache because you were lying in the beach for 2 hours in the sun?
– I don’t think so.
– Never had any problems with the sun.
– Not really.
– You didn’t eat pork.
– I try to avoid pork because of tradition.
– Otherwise you like it.
– I tried.
– There is no sensitivity to the sun and there is no aversion to certain people.
Show me. Kali-c. is an idea. Show me why.
Because he has diarrhea from milk, grinding teeth, red lids,
constipation insufficient, aversion milk and constriction in the rectum.
Kali-c. And show me the next remedy. Which was, forget the Calc... Mag-m.
Discharge constant, watery, diarrhea, constipation... Aversion to milk.\
His character fits mostly with the description of Nat-c. and Mag-c., Mag-m.
The magnesias are peaceful people are peaceful people they are not aggressive, they are seeking peace.
Are you like this? If somebody fights you try to make peace?
– Yes. Unless I want him to be beaten.
– In some cases is which there is an Arab…?
– No. It’s not nationalistic. But if he deserves it yes, absolutely.
Even I punch him too.
– He’s healthy!
In these levels why we cannot get symptomatology... They’re quite healthy.
Apart from the fear of heights and a little fear of dogs we cannot get symptomatology on mental and emotional.
– I would like to ask a question to the patient
because he said that his bowel problems started at the end of the army.
And as far as I know the army in Israel is 2 or 3 years and it’s very tough I imagine,
How did that influence him? What did that do to you to be in the army for 3 years.
- First, I had to stay 4 years in the army,
one more year and the last year was the easiest for me because I had the hernia surgery
and then I had to leave the paratrooper because it was in a base not far from home.
This was the quite time in the army.
And the bowel problem started after so I can’t say it’s because of the army.
This was the easy part, the last year.
I think the main pathology depends on his allergic complaints
because the problems with the stooling are totally allergic complaints.
If he changes his food the symptom diminish and you can imagine
that if he had complete test of the food and would change the food totally
he wouldn’t have complaints with his rectum and stooling.
These complaints he had even before he went to the army but it increased...
- No, the complaints started a year after the army.
– No. The allergic complaints he had even when he was 16, and the military...
- Wait. You call allergic complaint the running of nose?
– Yes.
– The running of nose, most probably,
was an inflammation of the frontal sinuses which created the severe pain here
and when they were opened and then there is a catarrh of the frontal sinuses most probably...
But you can take is as allergic. Continue.
– In my opinion, I have many patients with these problems.
It depends on the allergic reaction of the intestines.
This makes at least also the chronic sinusitis and these problems.
So if you diminish the food he will not stand then the complaints will diminish
and then you are in a position to find the correct remedy much easier.
– I am not sure because how is that?
An Ars. case who is aggravated by cold, you put him in a warm room and feels comfortable.
Do you think you will find it easier? No.
Therefore actually you have to allow the food that stimulates aggressively to be there
so the organism will give a full range of symptoms.
Exactly when he avoids certain type of food there is pause of the symptoms.
You will find no symptoms at all because it is a matter of digestion.
The digestive system is very affected.
Both Nat-c. and Mag-m. are affecting the digestive system.
Nat-c. affects the digestive system from the stomach downwards.
Mag-m. affects it from the liver downwards.
So this case of this nice man is a case where definitely there is a problem in digestive system.
And the moment you reduce his allergens he has no problems.
But the problem to make his able to eat this kind of foods without problems
and even if you apply now this diet strictly you will get rid of symptoms?
- Maybe it will be better because of fewer carbohydrates.
– Better but now completely eliminated.
–Even when I stopped it right away it was more symptomatic things.
I was relieved a little bit but I felt it’s not like when I had the Pod.
The Pod. made me keep on and keep on trying.
– I would like to ask the patient I have not understood what is going on when you are having stool.
Can you start having stool and then it stops and you get the constriction or what?
What is happening?
– It simply doesn’t leave me completely. I am not empty I cannot get empty.
– So you can have some stool?
– Yes. I have 6-7 times min.
– And then you have a constriction? Tightness?
– I got tightness all the time.
– George I would like to ask you about a rubric if you can use it.
It’s rectum; constriction, preventing stool.
– This is too dramatic for him but you can use it.
Constriction, rectum, closure. Show preventing stool.
Berb. Nit-ac. Again Nit-ac. Put this twice. Nit-ac.
There is a possibility but his character is not like this.
He doesn’t have any fissures. He will not show great anxiety.
Maybe he hides his anxiety but I tried to find out how much his anxiety was
and his anxiety about health is not very high.
Your anxiety about your health?
You consider it as very high, high, medium or low?
– As far as the bowel movement it’s very high.
It drives me crazy for the last 12 years.
– When you wake up in the morning you said you feel refreshed?
– Yes.
– The fat in the meat you can eat a little bit.
– Not but itself. I don’t like it by itself.
– The real Nit-ac. takes the fat from the others and eats it. Contradictory symptoms.
– He said that he had cramps from honey and he is planning his things in advance and his fear of height and falling.
So, I thought of Arg-n.
– Possibility of Arg-n. The stool is formed or unformed?
– Unformed. It’s small pieces actually.
– And soft?
– Yes.
– Always soft?
– So it’s not well digested. Have you put stool small and soft?
And underline it thrice. Show me Nat-c. why. 9 out of 13.
Take out honey aggravation.
My problem with Nat-c. is that his complaints are not in the stomach.
They’re after the stomach. Otherwise his character looks quite a lot like Nat-c. from what he says.
We can put frequent urination because it is not interrupted urination.
He doesn’t stay and goes, stops...
He goes out around and after 10 minutes he goes back. That’s the idea.
Interrupted urination. Frequent urination too much.
Do we have any ‘nervous bladder’?
Thuja. Who said Thuja? He said he found it.
Anybody has any better idea?
– I can’t understand why you rejected Phos. Phos. is very outstanding in repertorization.
He has Phos. fears, Phos.-like personality, Phos. aversions.
Why have you rejected Phos.?
– This is not Phos. personality.
It’s an Israeli personality.
All the Israelis when you bring them in they will give straightforward answers and they will tell you everything.
They have good communication.
Because they have not been especially people of Israel themselves,
not the American Jews or the other Jews who have a good life,
they have lived difficult periods of life.
The survival instinct is still there, they have not overcome it totally.
Emotionally, they enjoy quite a lot. And their spiritual [sphere] is further away.
That’s why you see they’re balanced in their mental emotional level.
The Israelis are quite balanced, quite like him.
So, don’t be misled to think he is over-communicative.
Actually when he was asked he said he has a lot of friends but my deeper feelings, I keep them for myself.
Also there is no anxiety, there are no the typical fears of Phos.,
there isn’t the anxiety about others,
which is very strong and other keynotes like desire for ice cream, salt are missing.
– I have the symptoms you asked about the nervous bladder.
There’s one urination, frequent, nervous origin and there is one only Cub.
And there is another one, I’m not sure if it’s nervous...
- Find Cub. In M.M.
– Urination, busily occupied, must run and pass little urine.
3 remedies; Calc., Kali-c. and Calc-iod.
– Is that possible to be Kali-c.? We just missed the issue altogether.
Mucous membranes generally, but especially that of the urinary tract, are chiefly affected by this remedy.
Frequent urination of a nervous origin. Urethritis.
Cattarh of nose, throat with fetid odor and expectoration. Mucus increased.
From posterior nares. Rawness of throat and hoarseness.
Cucurbita; Copaiva; Piper meth; Sandal. Cub. from which author is this? Boericke.
Beasty extravagances... It’s terrible remedy!
Diarrhea with borborigmus, flatulence and involuntary stool, like yellow diarrhea,
constipation often lasting over 8 days.
Scanty but frequent dysenteric stools with colic and tenesmus.
My God! This remedy fits his physical symptomatology.
The fact that it doesn’t fit his mental symptomatology it doesn’t mean anything
because as I said he is normal mentally and emotionally.
You don’t find much disturbance. Cub. seems to fit his irritable bladder and irritable colon.
And the catarrh of the nose.
Discharge from the nose of crusty, green and yellow matter with discharge of mucus sometimes thin, sometimes thick.
Burning in the throat. Stuffed up. Obstinate stoppage of nose...
Very unpleasant dryness. Fullness and pulsation.
Coryza with discharge of mucus.
– There is one more symptom, when he said during the history that he doesn’t like fat in general.
If it is only fat he doesn’t take it.
And there is one more rubric in the repertory rectum, feces, remain in, as if.
It has only Nat-c. Rectum, feces, remain in, as if.
Because that why he keeps on going frequently to the toilet to pass.
Because of this sensation that something is remaining.
Because you asked him in the history if he likes fat.
And he said simply, plain fat I don’t like.
But if it is with something then I don’t mind. But plain fat he has an aversion and also has Nat-c.
– This is as if feces remain. Ask him about that.
If this is the case. The symptom is like this;
You have stool and you feel the stool has remained in the rectum.
– Yes in the colon.
– Show me this rubric.
– I’ve got a question. How is it if he is lying back?
Is it possible to pass the stool? I am thinking of Med.
– If you lie back the stool passes more easily?
– I don’t know.
– So we have Cub., Thuja, Nat-c. Mag-m., Pod.
Do you remember how many times they gave you Pod. in the beginning, after this week?
– They gave me the first time Pod.,
then 3 weeks after I took another remedy and then another remedy and then again Pod. Twice.
–The second did nothing.
– Nothing.
– This is a question because if he says the only remedy that touched my case was Pod.
there is in your considerations sure be Pod.
But is Pod. a correct prescription at this moment?
And what might be the right sequence of remedies that he has to take in order to solve this case?
Is starting first with Nat-c., Mag-m., Cub., Thuja, Nit-ac.
How’s Agar.?
Sometimes the anxiety hidden and I don’t know how much is really his anxiety about this whole issue.
What is the first remedy? That’s the problem.
If we just hit the first remedy then the second will almost cure him.
Cub. You never drank milk in your life.
– I didn’t like plain milk, never.
– The stool is always soft is a matter of bad digestion there is no question of that,
the liver is not functioning properly.
Soft, is not diarrhea, is unformed stool which means the digestion has not been completed.
There is no undigested food. Real pieces of undigested food in the stool.
– Sometimes corn, I can see it but not anything else.
– If you eat corn, you may see piece of corn.
–Tomatoes?
– No. Sesame, I can see also sometimes.
– You can see some undigested pieces.
– Do we have any time modalities, better or worse during a period of time in the day?
– Usually in the morning it’s more severe.
– But in the morning you feel ok?
– Yes.
– You wake up and you are refreshed and you can work.
– I work, I can do anything. I just have to put in mind this.
– Show me Kali-m. Allen in stool.
After fatty food pastry...
Stool dry, constipation... Sluggish liver.
Constant pains in rectum, dysentery... Urinary organs?
See Kal-m. has a particular preoccupation with bowels.
Even if they have a good bowel motion they feel this is not satisfactory, this is not good enough.
The same I have found out with Agar. and Merc. Merc.
Also has this preoccupation with bowel motion.
I did not have a bowel motion today. I did not full stool.
And this is a very big preoccupation. But in him it’s exaggerated.
It’s quite strong the symptom because he does not empty the colon and he has to go several times.
– Was there any anxious movement just because the complaints started after you left the army,
you felt the army may call you back.
– No. I left the army happily, if I can say so.
And as far as the first question it started gradually that’s why I cannot say in a certain day.
It was gradually and I didn’t pay attention in the beginning.
–This is a good question which I also had. The answer is this, what he says.
This is something which is connected with some kind of fear or anxiety or both
that affected the nervous system on this level and not affected the mental emotional.
– I would like to ask one question because he says he is full of energy
and isn’t that a main symptom that you got diarrhea without any weakness?
– As far as my energy is concerned, it’s kind flow.
When I started the day from one day to another and I quit the milk and wheat I was full of energy.
– But now his energy is low, with this condition. Head pain with coryza.
What happened with his was that he got an inflammation most probably on the frontal sinuses,
very severe inflammation because the pain was unbearable,
he was lying down there without being able to move
and suddenly the canals opened and the discharge started and he was relieved with the headache,
only occasionally now you have it and the discharge continued from that time.
So the correct remedy will bring back this headache.
The bowel motion started after operation?
– Yes, Ι believe a few months after.
I believe even 1 year after.
– What may have happened?
– He had an inguinal repair the first one and then he had a second re-repair after that within a year.
He’s got fibrous tissue formed and he got retention in urine coming through.
Difficulty passing, the same symptom again, the mechanism is affected.
So he had an inflammation along his pelvic plexus leading to the base of the spine
which will show nothing on the scan but that’s where it started...
The problem probably arises from the surgery.
– This is the idea of this tissues forming after the operation, scar tissue.
Adhesions. The creation of adhesion after the operation.
You had twice this operation?
– No.
– The second time the hernia started coming back and you still had it.
But the bowel problems came one year after the hernia operation.
Is that correct?
– Yes.
– So most probably it is connected, what he says is correct,
some adhesions were formed that most probably affected or cramped some nerves that nerve the colon.
– In the inguinal canal he would still have either part of the large intestine,
part of the small intestine going down and each time it goes down
it will cause him to have retention of the bowel and the stool won’t work correctly
and he pushes it back up and he has a good day...
But if he’s still got an inguinal hernia he is still going to keep influencing him.
– That’s correct.
– And he cannot press as strong as he could without the hernia.
– Can you press to have a stool without problem of the hernia? You can. He can press.
But still the hernia comes out quite strongly?
– It’s not so severe. I can see it, I can feel it sometimes but it’s not so severe.
That’s why I don’t do the second surgery. But I can push.
– Does the hernia being out or being inside have anything to do with the condition of the bowels?
–No. I doesn’t really bother me.
– I would rather think of the adhesions affecting the nervous system by pressure.
– If it was related to the hernia operation why was he quite normal 1 week after Pod.?
For 1 week it was working quite well and when he had this diet for half a year it worked normally.
– The second thing you said is more valid. When he had the diet.
This is also correct what you are saying.
Why when he had the diet he had much better stool, actually.
– Cause anytime you have a herniated part you get a build-up of abnormal bacteria
in a short space of time so you get abnormal gas.
You change the diet, you modify the entire flora of the gut and so he has a reasonably good time.
You stick something that is an allergen it will trigger the fermentation process
in the circulated part, whichever is circulating. And he’s got a problem!
– Is it possible that we may have some structural changes that could not be seen?
Do you have a CAT scan?
– No, but I had most of the conventional medicine tests.
– You did all the examinations? And they did not find anything?
– They didn’t find anything wrong...
- Except of the allergy?
– They didn’t find allergy either.
– No they found allergies.
They found that you are allergic to milk.
– That’s what I found, not them.
– You noticed?
– Yes.
- They did not tell you?
– I had many blood tests.
– You noticed! They did not tell you to stop eating bread, milk.
– That was a special laboratory in the states. They told me about this.
– That’s what I say. They said you have a lot of allergies.
– But then when I stopped taking them, few months after it gradually returned.
In spite of the fact I did not all of them.
– In spite of the fact you did not eat the symptoms started coming back?
– Yes.
– In pathology the big remedies they have quite a lot of symptoms.
Thousands of symptoms within them you can find similar symptoms.
And unless you find something which is a keynote or an essential feature is his character,
you say he’s very closed, I see he’s very much suffering because of grief...
You cannot and give Nat-m. and expect to have an effect.
Nat-c. Yes. Because it has this aversion to milk and diarrhea from milk, diarrhea from honey.
These things are keynotes of Nat-c. and you can yes.
Nat-c. is a strong possibility but he has not the sensitivity to the sun.
I have never seen so far a Nat-c. without sensitivity to the sun.
He may be altogether different in this level,
he may be just normal because temperature-wise his organism is working quite well.
– Excuse from my notes he’s already given Nat-m.
– The only remedy which has keynotes is Nat-c.
The thing is that most probably underneath this is Thuja condition.
Now is Thuja underneath or on top?
Definitely with the aversion to onions which he says Thuja must have been as a young man
the remedy mostly indicated and that’s why it comes up.
And the other thing that takes me away from Nat-c. is the fact that except from the sensitivity,
since the digestive is involved how is that the stomach is not involved in this case
where Nat-c. primarily is a person who cannot digest,
eats and has pain, no digestion and suffering in the stomach area.
He suffers from there onwards.
I have similar cases but together with mental or emotional disturbances which I had tried for years to calm down.
An irritable bowel for years with careful prescribing.
And it still goes very slowly. Don’t think this is an easy case.
Now, what is the first remedy? Thuja.
Who says Thuja? Who says Nat-c.? Who says Mag-m.? Who says Nit-ac.?
Who says Cub.? The most logical will be to give Nat-c.
Show me the last repertorization.
How do you react with eating vegetables? Good?
It doesn’t depend on the type of food you eat, at all. Your bowel motion.
– No. I didn’t notice. Besides the milk and the honey that I have noticed strongly, nothing else.
– Bread?
– Yes, I am eating bread.
– After stool do you have to lie down and make some exercises to specially relax your bowels?
– No, not really. Sometimes when I am really tired and if I lie down,
it’s a little bit good for me. But it’s very rare.
I don’t have time to rest after every time.
– We’ll give him a dose of Nat-c. 200C.
It was the first remedy I wrote, the only remedy I wrote as soon as I heard
but then I doubt it very much.
Now I am thinking it’s not possible that the remedy could not have been given.
In case he has received , then we go to Mag-m.
He will try Mag-m. and then as a third remedy Thuja.
Why Thuja?
- What is the justification?
– I think there was an effect of vaccination on him beforehand.
Then again he was vaccinated in the army and I believe the second vaccination had an effect
and the effect ended up to that condition.
I don’t know if this is absolutely direct or not, involving other factors as well.
Thuja gave us a keynote quite close and gave another keynote which was...
You found 2 keynotes actually in this case.
– Bladder incomplete, obliged to urinate 5 or 6 times. Onions.
- Yes. Onions, he used to have it in the past.
We have some symptoms and we have the vaccination and that’s why we are thinking of Thuja.
– Also is the catarrhs in Thuja that blocks the urethra...
- Also it’s interesting as I ask him the question Thuja has a catarrh of this type
but when they go for stool they moment they have defecation the nose is running constantly.
It’s like opening a valve and the nose runs during stool.
But he did not confirm.
If he had said yes to that we would not be discussing all this time but he said no.
– I have a question about the timing how you decide when to give for example Mag-m. followed by Thuja?
– What are the deciding factors.
– Yes, how do you determine that.
– Well, if he has been given already Nat-c. and did not act we don’t lose the time just repeating Nat-c.
The second possibility is Mag-m. from repertorization and the third possibility is Thuja
because of the combination of vaccination with certain of his symptoms, characteristics.
And then of course the possibility of Cub. may be there.
By tomorrow morning we’ll have the answer definitely. And then we decide.
Who wants to give Nat-c.? Less people now. Who wants to give Mag-m.? Less people.
Who wants to give Thuja? Thuja is a good prescription for him as a starting at least case.
We will decide tomorrow whether it will be.
We got the information from the homeopath from Israel. The information is that he even had Nat-c.
We are very sorry about it! I will start the case with Thuja 50M.
I remember one of my first cases I had to solve was a very nice young woman who I liked very much
also she was a pianist and she came to take her case,
one of my first cases and of course I took very detailed information and I repertorized for 3 days.
3 days, 3 nights, repertorized the case because it wouldn’t come.
And the third night I went to bed and I woke up in the morning.
As soon as I woke up, I don’t remember the dream, I said Ign.!
Ign. acted beautifully but it was working in my subconscious mind or whatever
and then I thought she is romantic, hysterical, a pianist, an artist,
I put all these together, I’m talking 1960.
I put these together and the remedy came.
So this is something also that we see in Thuja cases.
In Thuja case we don’t have a clear case and we battle.
We don’t get a straightforward symptom and then you have some keynotes of Thuja
and the fact that we have the vaccination and the fact that the nose is running and I know this running nose of Thuja.
It seems to me finally after all this turmoil that maybe we have to start with Thuja
though I don’t think that his condition will be solved totally through this remedy.
But we will see how far it may go and maybe the next remedy will develop
will be much clearer and then it will give much better results. 50M.