You can tell what happens.
- Thank you for seeing me. I’ve got shingles.
– Where?
– On my back. Running from the back under my breast.
– How long ago it started?
- It started 2 weeks ago and the eruption has dried mostly,
it is just marked, but it is the pain...
- The pain is severe.
– Yes. They pain is worse in the night and in the morning.
– You mean in the night when you wake up or when you go to bed?
- I go to sleep ok, especially here because it is more relaxing
and I wake up after about 1-2 hours with the pain
and then I go to sleep again and I wake up again in an hour or 2... About 3-4 times.
– With pain... And in the morning when you wake up...
- I have difficulty getting out of bed because I feel stiff. I have to be helped to sit up.
– You are stiff all over the body?
– The back.
– And you have to be helped to get up.
– Yes. I can get up on my own by rolling on the side but to sit up...
- And you feel stiff on your whole back.
– Yes.
– Did you take some medication so far?
– What did you take?
– I took Rhus-t. 30C at the beginning.
The next remedy was Ran-b. 30C.
- You use the Latin pronunciation in your land.
– Yes. Bry. 30C which was recommended to me by a homeopath.
She wanted to have 200C but I didn’t have it on me at the time
and she recommended me to get 200C next day
but I called her back and told her I was cold and she suggested Ars. 200C.
There’s been no change from remedies just a natural progression of the disease.
– The pain was continuous?
– The pain comes and goes.
– This stiffness that you are talking about it was from the beginning
or it became worse and worse as the days went by?
– The pain and stiffness is mostly when I am getting up.
– But that was from the beginning?
– No.
– The stiffness started how many days ago?
– The last few days. I was in too much pain to really take notice.
– You took painkillers?
– No.
– And the pain has become worse and worse or is it more or less in the same level?
– The pain is less severe now.
– The stiffness is more?
– No. Only in the morning.
– But you told me there was stiffness only in the morning. There was stiffness during the day as well?
– Not a lot. The worst thing is jarring, from the beginning
and the touch of anything.
Even my hair hurts.
– Even touching the hair made you feel worse?
– One hair fell out on my breast and that hurt.
– Even touching your hair you felt pain?
– No, it fell and the touch of the hair was painful.
– What about if the touch was really strong?
– At the beginning, no touch at all.
– You could not tolerate any touch.
– I wouldn’t let anybody near me but now it is not so severe.
– Now still jarring is aggravating.
– Every step I make with the right foot, as the heel touches the ground, is painful.
– Did you take Bell.?
– No, only the remedies I mentioned.
– Did you have any other remedies ...
before for homeopathic treatment?
– Not for a long time.
– Was any remedy that helped you in the past?
– The only remedy that ever made any difference to me and I felt different was Carc. many years ago.
And in an acute situation Sep. and Nat-m. 30Cs.
– Do you like salt?
– No, I never take salt.
– You dislike salt? Or it is normal? If the food is a little bit salty...
- I don’t like it. I am not used to it. I don’t use salt at all.
– You’re health-conscious.
– Yes.
– In your family you don’t use salt.
–No. Only to pick up wine stains on the carpet as a cleaning agent.
– What is your blood pressure?
– Normal, maybe a little bit low. But I don’t test it, I don’t bother.
– In general you would say you are bothered by heat or cold?
- I am very chilly. The wind on my back from the open windows behind me down the stairs is painful.
– That means you are sensitive to drafts.
– The skin is sensitive.
– Now that you have shingles or before?
– Now it’s the pain on the skin but normally I don’t like cold wind anyway.
– Are you married?
– Yes.
– Do you have children?
– This dress that you have now seems to be very light.
– But it is warm in Greece. I can get very hot quickly and very cold quickly.
– And then you would suffer from being very warm or you tolerate it?
– I love the heat but when I am active physically I get hot quickly and don’t like it then.
But I would rather have heat than cold anytime.
I am not going back home!
– Do you like milk?
– No, I never drink milk. Not from an animal.
– Do you have certain preferences for food? Some real desire?
– I love vegetables, fruits, salads.
– You’re vegetarian?
– No. Fish.
– What about sweets?
– Not specially.
– Do you like eggs?
– I very rarely eat them but I don’t dislike them.
– Your nails are strong?
– They used to be but in the last few weeks or couples of months I noticed they started breaking
and my hair is falling very badly.
– The last 2 months?
– The nails the last 2 months. The hair at least 3 years but worse now with the shingles.
– Do you have any fears?
– I don’t think so.
I have 2 very strong aversions; one is the pig, I will not eat anything from the pig...
- Are you Jewish?
– No.
– It is not a matter of religion.
– No, because it is dirty.
- So you developed this aversion after you saw the animals...?
– No, when I found out what the pig was about.
But I didn’t like it as a child either.
And tobacco.
– You don’t like somebody smoking near you?
– Yes very strongly. I don’t like bad smells. But I like good smells very much.
– And tobacco is a bad smell for you.
– Very bad.
– Some like it!
– No, it’s very bad. It makes me smell bad.
– Do you have a special sensitivity to odors?
– Very keen sense of smell.
– Can give me the type you are? Are you duty-bound? Easily irritated?
Very easily going into depression or anxiety? Anxious about your children?
– They say I am a workaholic but I can also be very easy going and very laid back.
At the moment I am very slow because of the movement.
– Would you say you are lazy?
– Nobody would think I am lazy, they say I am workaholic
but I think I can be lazy if I have the opportunity.
I don’t know... on the beach.
– Before the shingles your sleep was good or it was interrupted?
– Very good what there was of it. I never get much sleep because I am always working.
– Because you want to work?
– Not so much want to, I have to. There’s so much to do.
– So you don’t allow yourself to sleep enough.
– That’s right.
– And how you manage with your energy?
– My energy is good. But I have been so tired, I have been almost asleep during the day,
I am working at the same time, if that makes sense.
– How can you do that?
– I found I was asleep but I was still writing.
– In your sleep?
– In the day.
– Keep on writing in your sleep?
– I noticed I couldn’t read what I have written and I was asleep as I was writing.
– You have been asleep and still continue to write?
Correct?
– Yes.
– And talked in your sleep?
– I don’t talk in my sleep. This was during the day when I am working. I was so tired.
– And you could not remember what you wrote and you could not read...
- ... what I have written because I have written it and I’ve gone into sleep as I was writing.
I was dreaming and then came back and realized what was happening.
Only a few seconds perhaps, I don’t know.
– Just because you felt very tired.
– Exhausted.
– Your appetite is good?
– Always has been but through this illness it wasn’t so good.
– Can you tell me if you can wear something around your neck which is tight?
– I’d rather not. But if I was cold I probably would.
– Do you know this zhivago, turtle neck?
– I keep the room where I am working always warm so I don’t have to wear many clothes.
I don’t like to wear a lot of clothes.
– But can you stand wearing a bra?
– No, I can’t stand it.
– What about in the waist? Wearing a belt?
– That’s ok.
– If you had to wear a tie, could you or you would rather not?
– I would probably do that, but if I was cold, I would put anything on.
– How old are you?
– 45.
– 35?
– Thank you! 45.
– Your menses are still there? You have your menses?
– Yes.
– How is it?
– No problem.
– Do you have pain before menses?
– No, I don’t have any problems.
– And your sexual desire is normal
– Not at the moment.
– You are not interested at all.
– Well, it’s the pain.
– Can you tell me if you keep a special position for sleep?
You sleep on the right side, on your left side?
– It’s difficult because sleeping on the right side is sleeping on the pain,
sleeping on the back, where I would like to sleep is painful and sleeping on the healthy side is worse.
It drags everything down.
– Before this happened, in what position did you sleep?
– Always on the left or on my back.
– Do you always speak like this with low voice? Or sometimes you get animated and you speak loud?
– I’m usually quiet spoken but with my family, if I have to get them in order, I can raise my voice.
– And then your children are afraid of you?
– No, I find actually, if I really want to make a point, I’ll actually go quiet.
It’s more effective. It works on my patients.
– But all English people speak with this voice? Is it the culture?
– No, I think I am considered to be quiet spoken.
– But you are trained. I understand you trained yourself to speak on low voice.
– No, this is natural for me.
But at home I am a little bit different.
– With your friends are you loquacious?
– I am a Gemini.
– So you want to speak all the time. What means a Gemini? I don’t understand.
– If I know people then I am the soul of the party. If I don’t know people I am quiet.
– Now, you don’t know me, you’re quiet.
– I know you a little bit. I‘ve been here before.
– Is there any problem with constipation or diarrhea?
– Since my first marriage break up, I’ve been a bit erratic. I go too much.
– You go 2-3 times?
– Maybe. I got used to it.
– The stool is formed or unformed?
– Unformed usually. Better with this illness.
– During this time, these 2 weeks, has anything changed in your desire to eat?
– I have no appetite.
– No appetite for anything. Maybe you have appetite for something,
like ice cream or sweets or oranges or...
Has anything changed or you just lost your appetite?
– Before the eruption came up I had a gall bladder attack.
The pain was underneath here, going like that.
And so I was very careful with what I was eating, but I had no other symptoms, no vomiting, nothing.
So I decided to have a pizza to find out if it was the gall bladder or not and I felt better afterwards.
– After pizza?
– Yes, I don’t eat like that normally, but I felt better.
– So you eat pizza everyday now?
– No, just that once.
– If you want to make a point, you will make your point or you’d rather keep quiet?
– It depends on where I am and whether I am in charge of the situation.
If it’s with my patients, I will make the point very clear.
– You said you have been divorced for the first time and then you re-married?
– Yes.
– Do you think that the first divorce was your fault or his?
– There are always 2 sides of a story. He’d say it was my fault, I’d say it was his fault.
We were not right for each other.
– What was your complain concerning him mostly?
– I think the biggest thing was that he didn’t regard me as a woman. I was just a friend.
– He just ignored you or...?
– When the children were born I wasn’t important any more.
– So you felt...
- Neglected I suppose. I was just a useful friend.
– During that time if you said something, would he listen?
– No, he never listened to anything. He had a big newspaper in front of him and that was it.
– Never mind what you were saying.
– I could be changing in front of him and he would not notice I was there.
I was too young to put up with that. My husband now is very different.
– You have a good relationship with your husband now?
– Yes, he is also a Gemini.
– You know astrology?
– Only where it seems to be right...
- You are supposed to be compatible if you are both Gemini?
– They say that Gemini are in 2 places, doing 2 thing at the same time
when now in our house it’s 4 things,
and my son is a Gemini and the cat is Gemini, so it’s pretty crazy.
– The problem is how to treat your shingles now.
No matter whether you are a Gemini or not, it’s not important.
– I am afraid that the eruption will go away but I will be left with pain for a long time
because it can happen with shingles.
– Your father was mistreating you or he was ok?
– I knew you would ask about my father eventually!
He was strict... I didn’t love him very much.
He was a workaholic. I didn’t see him a lot and I was glad when he wasn’t there.
– Were you afraid of him?
– Yes. He always made me work whenever he saw me.
He always wanted to make sure that I was working. It didn’t work out.
– You didn’t get much affection from him.
– No. I got a hiding or two. Not a lot of love.
Well, we have a general rule how to look upon such acute cases.
The rule is that if the acute condition gives you a clear picture, you give this remedy for the acute.
If the acute condition does not give you a clear picture,
then you will most probably have to investigate deeper to find out what is the deeper indicated remedy
which most probably will act.
So, if we go in this case, my question is again the same,
is this a clear cut acute case of shingles?
Several remedies have been prescribed, quite carefully I would say, so no effect.
Are we missing the acute or do we have to go deeper?
This is the first question.
We cannot answer it on a theoretical basis. We can only answer it according to facts.
Which are the facts? The facts are the symptoms.
What the symptoms are telling us and always base your prescription on the real symptomatology.
Don’t project your imagination, your fears, and your anxieties into the patient.
You ask a patient something and he answers. That answer you have to take it as correct.
If the answer is ambiguous, you are entitled to ask more questions to make it clear.
Otherwise don’t make imaginary symptomatology.
Because the moment you see this person you can project anything you like to her.
She has suffered, she has not suffered, she is this and that, she has fears but she is not aware...
You can make anything you like. The facts are only what she gave.
She gave certain symptoms on which you have to work and only then you may have an effect.
Ask some questions to see if you have found any remedy which is indicated in this case.
Have you found any remedy which fit the acute condition? Who has found?
– Initially I was thinking of Bell. but very much worse by jar in the case. Or Mez.
– Why Mez.?
– The sensitiveness to touch, falling hair and neuralgia.
– Mez. is sensitive to touch on the hair, it’s different.
What she says is, if the hair touches the place.
That is different. That is worse with the least touch. This is the symptom.
Mez. has a great sensitivity on the scalp and even if you touch the hair the pain is felt in the scalp.
Bell. is a possibility because of worse touch and worse jar,
but there is another remedy which is worse touch and worse jar, which is Lach.
– Mag-c.? Worse cold, worse hot and there is kind of neuralgic pains, worse touch...
- It’s a little bit far out your suggestion. You will see here the real facts.
That means you have to repertorize the information which you are given.
Either with computer or by hand you have to repertorize and see what is the remedy
which covers mostly this symptomatology.
So, skin eruptions, pain, sleep on waking, put some more symptoms.
Generals jar on stepping, underlined 3 times, stiffness in the morning on rising
and touch aggravates and general drafts aggravates.
And if you repertorize this with these symptoms,
which is the remedy which will come up? Can anybody tell me?
– Lach.
– Lach. Let’s see if it is Lach.
Lach. is quite prominent in this case.
This was the reason why I was investigating the aggravation from clothing.
Lach. women cannot tolerate wearing something tight around their breast and around their neck.
The only problem is that Lach. is a warm remedy. It’s aggravated by warmth, not by cold.
She insisted that she is cold and Kali-c. as a second possibility is an interesting possibility
because it is a cold remedy.
Let’s see why; because Kali-c. has pain on waking,
has the stiffness, has the jar, the touch and the draft.
And she is a workaholic.
Kali-c. are people who like to work, who actually work because of their sense of duty.
They have too much sense of duty and they work because of that.
When we added some symptoms in the repertorization, hair falling, complaints of brittle nails,
aversion pork, sensitive to odors, mania for work, general side right, aggravates right side.
Actually take it out because this is now worse on the left side, even worse she said on the left side.
Don’t be afraid of these wasps! These big ones they don’t sting!
And always we have remedies against the wasps. Show me this step!
This step shows that Lach. still is the first remedy, Ars., Sep., Merc., Ign., Caust., Bell.,
Coff., Kali-c., Chin., Staph., Nat-m. etc.
Vario. also stands in the medium remedies, it’s a possibility.
Explain why. Because of herpetic eruptions and sensitive to odors.
So, what is your decision so far?
Lach. stands very much ahead of other remedies but the problem is the heat and cold.
– I think we don’t know so much of the time before it starts.
She didn’t say anything of what happened before.
Was there any trouble or something like this?
– She is here she can tell.
Can you tell us if something extraordinary, a stress happened before these shingles?
Did you get very tired? Did you get a cold?
Did you have a fight with your husband? Did you get jealous?
– No. There has been no fight but in the last 3 years I have been working really very hard
because apart from my clinic,
which has always been full time, I took on a school of Herbalism and Homeopathy
which was going bankrupt because there was nobody else to do it and I worked all hours,
day and night, sometimes all night, several nights a week.
I tried to save the organization, which I have almost single-handed.
I’ve got a good team but they don’t have the time,
so if something needs to be done it’s always me and I am just exhausted.
This is a sufficient reason to have shingles.
– She was exhausted, her energy dropped and then she developed the symptoms.
– I found another strange thing. She is a woman who works very hard and has a lot of energy for her work
but what struck me was this voice. This muffled voice.
– Low?
– Yes. And when you look at this symptom there is Lach., not Kali-c.
– What symptom did you look?
– Voice muffled.
– What does muffled exactly mean? Who is English? It means low?
– Indistinct.
– So is this muffled?
– No.
– What you are looking is a symptom of Lach. where it says mumbled.
This type is the Lach. It’s not the low voice.
If she speaks clearly but very low, this is not Lach. Lach. is a mumble.
I make it a little bit exaggerated but there is the type of voice
that you feel is going to have a brain stroke very soon.
Most probably you found that symptom.
The Lach. symptomatology is strong apart from 2 things;
one is the cold and the heat which does not fit and the other which does not fit with Lach. is what?
– She is not loquacious.
– Maybe. Another one? She said she sleeps on her left side.
Lach. usually would sleep on their right side because
if they sleep on the left they have heart problems;
palpitation, dyspnea, dysphoria and immediately they turn to the right side.
So Lach. does not sleep usually on the left side.
She says I prefer to sleep on the left side.
At this moment she says even on the left, or on the right is worse because it seems the pain is worse.
This symptom is in between. What shall we do? We are stuck now.
Let’s see the next step. Mind speech, soft voice, stool soft.
This is the last. Show me! Lach. is still strong.
How much have you underlined this symptom?
Tight clothes aggravate. Put that symptom. Underline it once.
– I think it’s very important that the pain gets worse, when she sleeps on the painless side.
– Yes, sleeping on the painless side.
Put this! The symptom is lying on the painless side aggravates in generals.
Let’s ask her a question since I did not want to put this question inside to guide or misguide you.
Ask her whether she considers herself jealous.
What is the answer? Write down the answer, what she is going to say.
I ask, are you jealous?
What she is going to answer? Write it down.
Everybody must write. Ok, tell now. I have absolutely no reason to be jealous.
I wouldn’t permit a situation where I would have to be jealous. I’m too sure of myself.
– You would not permit, what do you mean?
– I would not permit a situation where I would have to be jealous.
– But she said that when her children were born, she wasn’t any more important to her husband.
– No, this was the first husband. She is talking about the second husband.
– Yes, but I say she was jealous with her first husband.
– I don’t know if she was jealous. She was ignored.
– No, I wasn’t jealous. Just neglected. I don’t think I was aware of it at the time.
– Who wrote she was going to say she was jealous?
Who wrote she is not jealous? Who wrote nothing?
You see the problem? We have a strong case of Lach. Quite strong.
With characteristics of Lach. yet, we are missing the loquacity, the jealousy,
we thought we were also missing the sleeping on the left side.
Now she said no, I used to sleep on my right side, which is Lach.
The shingles also, we would prefer to be on the left side, not on the right side.
You have to mix 3 remedies before you can make all the symptoms.
So what you do? You search your mind and your repertory.
So, here we have strong indication for Lach.
Apart from the fact she is aggravated by cold, there is no problem with PMS.
It is very seldom that you will find a Lach. that will not have a PMS.
That means in the sexual sphere she is functioning quite normally.
– What about her perspiration? – She has lots of perspiration?
– No, it’s normal and I don’t use any deodorants. I think it’s a bad thing to do.
– So, you are stuck, you don’t know what to do. Give Lach. and see what happens!
Because of these counter indications you have to search other remedies
to see how many of her symptoms other remedies have.
– Perhaps I should say that I do have one fear although is not present at the moment.
I fear that I may have a stroke because it runs in the family.
My mother had a stroke at 76, my grandmother had a stroke at 76
and I was relieved in a way that I had shingles and I feel relieved it
and perhaps that’s how I sort my problems out.
– Another issue that did not fit with Lach. was the fact that she has low blood pressure.
Usually when this Lach. situation is in the organism,
there is an internal pressure which rises the blood pressure.
She says I have low blood pressure.
Again a symptom which is against Lach. Show me the columns!
Let’s investigate some other remedies before we decide to see how many of her symptoms
are covered by different other remedies.
Let’s say Ign. Ign. covers 13, covers industrious, mania for work.
I don’t know if this really is a symptom.
She had to work all this time but this is not something I would consider as a symptom.
You have to take it out actually.
Sensitive to odors, low soft voice, hair falling, soft stool,
stiffness on the back in the morning on rising.
Take out stiffness on back let alone stiffness in the morning on rising.
Extremities nails, brittle nails, pain on waking, herpetic zoster, draft of air aggravates,
intolerance of clothing, pressure of clothing.
Just put neck only, underline it once.
Aversion pork, stepping aggravates, 3 times that’s good.
Lying on painless side aggravates. Show me now the general repertorization.
The expert system. With the corrections.
Caust. Let’s see, it covers 10 of her symptoms... Dreams.
- About dreaming of snakes or something?
– She has nothing in particular.
– Nothing special.
– Show me the columns! Investigate the next remedy.
Nat-m. Show me the next remedy.
Bell. Show me the next remedy.
Ign. Show me the next remedy.
Staph. Show me the next remedy.
Lach. But she has no other symptoms of Merc. Show me Merc.
How many symptoms does it cover?
– Sep. She mentioned it helped her in the past and it has 10 symptoms.
– Sep. She didn’t say she has aversion to sex.
She says I am feeling very painful and that’s why I try to avoid it.
– Instead of taking so many symptoms why we do not take 4-5 very important ones
that are very close towards the patient and may only give us a few remedies.
– Which are these?
– I would give importance to the aversion to pork,
the since childhood is a very strong feeling in her...
- Ok, first of all this is not a real aversion.
It is after she had seen what all pork is about.
That is not a real aversion to pork, as we know it with Puls.
The aversion became out of seeing this condition,
but you can still take it but not as a strong and important symptom. The second?
– Tobacco. When somebody is smoking a cigarette she does not like it.
– Not even that. Because she said, not only tobacco, it is any smell which is not nice.
Tobacco included. That means smells I don’t like
because I have an acute smell and you can take it as acute smell.
But aversion tobacco is not a special aversion.
Aversion to all smells which do not have a nice smell.
Therefore you can take tobacco but not give special importance.
– I’m not. Also the neglected feeling.
– Neglected feeling is something which existed in the past and does not have it now.
Now, ask her, she has a good relation.
She says my relation now is quite good and compatible.
She explained compatibility by Gemini or something,
which I don’t understand but anyhow she said at this moment
I am happy with the second marriage which was totally different than the first one.
In this marriage I don’t feel neglected.
On the contrary I feel I am being taking care of, perhaps too much.
Is this correct? Yes.
She says very good analysis. So, next.
– The fear of apoplexy, the fear of getting paralyzed.
– The fear of getting apoplexy.
Again, this is not a main symptom,
because she said my mother had an apoplexy at young age
and I have the fear because of that event that I may also have.
Still there is a kind of symptom there but not a strong symptom to base a prescription.
The symptoms which are really strong are worse jar.
This is something which you have to have it in the worse stepping;
with every step she has a pain. This is something very strong.
Then, the next thing is the worse touch.
From a pathology point of view these symptoms are important.
Now, from a psychological point of view she says I don’t have any fears
except of that fear that I may get a stroke.
But touch aggravates has to be 3 times.
So what is the remedy?
– Can I ask how is the expression of her emotions,
I don’t know whether you’ve had a loss in the family and you were able to express your grief
or any other strong even and do you express your feelings easily or you tend to be closed?
– I lost my mother about 10 years ago and I miss her a lot but I think I coped well.
The biggest grief was 3 years ago with this college
that I took and all these that took place at the time. I was grieving a lot then.
– Do you like fruits?
– Yes, but only when the weather is warm.
I don’t like cold food when it’s cold.
– When the weather is warm she likes fruits.
– I eat seasonally if possible, so in the winter I eat hot vegetables
and in the summer I eat salads.
– You have fruits in your house?
– Yes, in the summer.
– And you will peel an apple and eat it or an orange?
– I don’t eat citrus fruits.
– Why? Because they are sour?
– Because they are not indigenous in Britain, they don’t grow there, we should not be eating them.
I try to eat what is right. I eat what grows in England.
– Out of philosophical belief or out of taste?
– It just makes sense to me.
– Philosophy.
– Yes.
– Your philosophy is that it’s better to eat season fruits and local fruits than anything else.
– I wouldn’t fancy a glass of orange juice in the middle of the winter.
– Bring the columns. Explain why! Staph.
Has the touch aggravates 3 times, right side, stepping, jarring, herpetic eruptions,
pain with waking, stiffness in the morning on rising, hair falling soft stool, low, soft voice,
sensitive to odors and if you had done your repertorization properly,
you would have come to this remedy,
which is not only indicated at the moment, but the story she says, I was left alone to finish the job.
This already is a kind of suppression but what is interesting,
is the story she tells about the first husband.
She could not talk to him.
We have said that in the pathology of Staph. are very nice, sensitive people, full of emotions,
they don’t lose their emotions but they cannot find their right.
They cannot speak out, they cannot tell to hell with you, you are a bastard...
They just cannot reach that point where they could say that.
Unless they are even beaten by the husbands, suppressed by the parents. You remember?
She gave the story, I didn’t want to make it very clear for you,
that’s why in the investigation I did not give enough indications
so you can battle with finding the correct remedy.
So the correct remedy which fits actually the local symptom, which is worse cold also,
which also fits some of her pathology coming from the past,
that means we have here a remedy which not only will take care of the shingles
but will take care of her psychological state as well.
She will feel much better psychologically as well.
If we had found a remedy let us say Bell. or Lach., or Kali-c.,
that would take the pain slowly away but would not touch the emotional sphere.
With Staph. we don’t have counter indications.
On the contrary we have confirmatory symptomatology.
Who thought of Staph.? Only the computer! We communicate too well.
But you see we reached at this conclusion after a thorough analysis of each remedy
of each symptom to see which the weight of each symptom is.
What would you have given her if she had come 10 years ago when she was married to the first husband
and she would relate to you that story and then you would ask what about your father
and she would relate a similar story with her father?
You would immediately have thought of Staph. Most probably the Staph. elements are left.
There are tendencies, she said I raise my voice wherever I can.
Do you remember this answer?
You overcame this answer, you bypass the right answers to put together the case
and make it a real case. And in this case you can give Vario., Thuja, Lach., Kali-c. etc.
and there is not going to be a real improvement on the case.
In which case we hope to be an improvement.
What we are interested in is that we make a prescription based upon the facts
and we don’t twist the facts.
We don’t project, we don’t put thing into the repertorization that do not exist.
So you want to see again? Show me the Staph.
Show them what Staph. is covering in this case.
Sensitive to odors, speaks with soft voice, hair falling, soft stool,
stiffness on the back on rising in the morning,
waking from pain, herpetic eruption, jar stepping, right side, touch aggravates.
That’s all. And ailments from grief.
If you put ailments from mortification, if you put suppressed then it will come much stronger,
but you don’t need that.
You think, you have the idea from the repertorization, you see the Staph.
and you say maybe this is a Staph. case.
How she behaves. And you don’t see the Lach. Because I was not happy with Lach.
Is this a Lach. case? But Staph.? You say yes!
So she needs a very high potency of Staph. 50M? She needs 50M.
– I thought for a physical thing like this might be better to be lower because if it aggravates...?
– No aggravation.
Is Staph. her constitutional remedy?
There is not such a thing but the basic remedy. This is a question mark.
Most probably Staph. covers a layer that was created upon her basic pathology since childhood.
Because of the treatment of her first husband, of her father maybe,
a layer of Staph. remained on the top.
And then this layer instead of being treated with Staph. it was treated
with Ign., Nat-m., Sep. and it’s going.
And then you give Staph. and a certain symptomatology that will come up from the younger age,
will pop up and will remain and then they will be the guiding symptoms for treating this case further.
Because in Homeopathy it’s very seldom, especially with the people of the West,
that you give one remedy and the person remains well for another 20 years.
The people of the West we are too sick, we have several layers, especially because of vaccination,
of antibiotics, because of the way of life, because of pollution, physical pollution in which we live,
because of culture in which we suppress children,
we suppress emotionally the children so much that we create problems with the children.
Don’t cry, crying is forbidden. You know Germans never cry.
English also, don’t laugh! And Norwegians!
You go towards the south and children are crying and the mother doesn’t pay any attention,
lets the child cry, she says what is the problem, she says maybe she is angry. Let her cry.
That is why in the East in general, health is not damaged on these deep levels,
mental / emotional so much, it is mostly physical symptomatology.
So in India, in Pakistan, in South America, in Africa the pathology which we mostly see
is not mental emotional, is mostly physical.
The reason is pollution, culture, antibiotics, which they don’t have and vaccination.
All these countries did not have the type of treatment that we had in the West
and we created the problems that we have today,
concerning our emotions and our mentalities.
The idea of what happened in the war, it was planned by some sick minds.
There was a war, nobody knew why.
Planned by sick minds that they could have easily stopped the whole thing,
they could easily have arranged, but they preferred to have a war.
The problem is that this is a society in which misinformation has become like the Goddess of today.
Misinformation that means the media will present to the people whatever they like
and people will believe. Half of you believed that the war was justified.
If not half, perhaps one third. If not one third, one quarter at least believe the war was justified.
The war was not justified. They could have found a way... What did they do?
They created 800.000 refugees, they created thousands of deaths
and they create 200.000 refugees on the Serbian side that means 1.000.000 refugees
with thousands killed in the name of humanity.
Wait a moment! If you think how this mind was twisted
and you try to find the depth of the sickness you will find in vaccinations,
in antibiotics, in the way we live, in the pollution.
Because if you get people that don’t have a natural life, emotional and mental life which is natural...
How many women today cannot bear a child? Millions.
In the West they cannot.
And they have found artificial dissemination, artificial this and that...
Lie down for 9 months to bear a child etc.
Even in Greece we have severe problem by this.
How nature has now come back and kicks back.
Because of sickness. It is sickness which breeds hatred.
And all these people who play like marionettes with us,
they play on the fact that we have hatred, that we hate each other.
That’s all. Greeks hate Turks, Turks hate Greeks, Kosovars hate Serbians,
Pakistani hates Indians etc.
These people collect information and then they erupt the wars.
But these minds which conceive this are in a deep state of sickness.
That’s why when we treat people of the western world,
we will need a series of remedies before we can bring them back to real health.
And real health means I have feelings again!
I haven’t killed my feelings. Most of us we have killed our feelings.
It’s not allowed to do that, it’s not allowed to do this.
And most of us we have reached that state of Alzheimer.
You know Alzheimer? It’s an epidemic. I am losing my memory, of course.
If you are bombarded by radio waves, TV waves, satellite waves...
these walkies-talkies, mobile phones have these transmitters.
This is a transmitter which transmits radio waves, electromagnetic waves.
I put it here and the electromagnetic waves go through my brain and I boil my brain.
And it’s a big discovery! This is the end!
You see the antennas all over and how many microwaves go through our brains
and then you find out I don’t have any more sexual desire,
I am not interested, I don’t have a relationship any more.
Why don’t you have a relationship?
Because I have been hurt so many times and because you have been hurt so many, what happened?
I’m out of this, forget it!
Get Nat-m. or Ign. not so much Staph. because in Staph. the emotions are not killed.
But get a Ph-ac. I am not interested. Get a Carb-v. I am not interested.
I have no interest. Get Nat-m. the emotions are there
but they are so hurt that there is a kind of block.
Get an Aur. She says I am so depressed,
I don’t have time for anybody else, I just have to deal with myself.
If an Aur. case has a responsible position in the making of the war what is he going to do?
Inside him there is death. The idea of death is connected with Aur.
Death is the best way out. That’s how they think!
But these people are not only bank managers, they are managers of wars and think tanks.
We pay you, you find the best way that Kosovars and Serbians will have war.
Their minds work, they don’t know what they are doing.
And they say this is the best way;
you send an agent and tell this, and tells the other side that
and then an eruption comes and they start fighting.
And after that this is going to happen and then...
You are a painter. You paint?
I jumped from one subject to another like Lach.
Now enough of this differential diagnosis.
The main thing is to remember this is a layer which we try to take out to lift.
Maybe she needs 2-3 repetitions of Staph. before this layer is lifted out
and then the next layer will come where she may show some fears, anxieties more prominent.
And then this will make her case much clearer
and then you prescribe and then you will see the real difference.