You are going to give me some advice on this case. I’m confused.
You can tell this story.
You started having homeopathic treatment, how many years ago?
– 12 or 13 years.
–And for what reason?
–I started with a lot of pain in my bones, like my father did, when he was on the same age like me.
It started with a bad lumbago when I was in holidays in Greece,
in Crete and did a lot of windsurfing and then suddenly I woke up in the night like today
and I couldn’t walk and I had a lot of pain in my back, I could only move on my knees and my arms.
Yesterday I drove a lot of time with a motorbike and I think my suitcase was too heavy
when I came here 3 days before.
I took Rhus-t. 3 days before, also for my bad inflammation of my chronic polyarthritis
and a day later I got a new inflammation here on the point of my small fingers I never had before.
And 2 days I could not take anything with my fingers and all my bones also my knees were very bad.
Also my feet, I couldn’t go on my feet and now since this morning my pains on all the bones stopped
but suddenly this old pain that I had years before came back very fast
and it’s going worse every half an hour.
I cannot move my right leg and I am very painful.
I took a lot of remedies all over the years.
I started with Rhus-t. later maybe I got Arn., Puls., Lyc., Nat-m.
Of course I had a lot of problems in my life.
Later I got again Lyc. and then Med. And all things came back, also pain.
– Just a moment. Let me clarify a little bit because it was very confusing.
When she took Rhus-t. for this condition, it give no results and then she took Arn. most probably,
and then Lyc. Lyc. seemed to help?
– Yes.
– She repeated Lyc. Lyc. helped her several times and then it stopped helping and she went into Puls.
Puls. did not give much effect.
– And then Sil. It was going better but nothing really helped.
All the inflammations went on and the pain in my fingers suddenly stopped ...
- How many years now are these pains going on?
– Maybe 8 years. Suddenly we went so bad that I couldn’t stand up in the morning.
– So, most probably here we have a case of rheumatoid arthritis which is not a simple arthritis.
It’s much more aggressive as a condition and more obstinate. Not easily curable.
The fact that she is having for 8 years already the condition
and that she has not a lot of deformities that shows that
Homeopathy has helped her quite a lot so far.
You said Med. gave you a negative reaction?
– Yes. All the inflammations were worse.
Also my knee, I had an accident about 25 years ago,
I was operated and suddenly it started again I got operated for 5 years.
For 5 years I had such a knee but I had not time to be operated
and then they opened it when my oldest son had a big accident,
I had the time to lie beside him in the hospital
and then they opened it and all the cartilage was gone.
It was like that all over the bone.
After this was getting on all the other bones and before I only had a lot of pain on my left knee.
Also, when I took Med. all accidents, I was a horse rider before when I was young
and I was falling a lot of times all over my back side and I had one time a bad accident
when horse was standing on his feet and making like that on my right feet
and they wanted to put my foot off but I took a new remedy there and then they could leave my foot on.
This pain is also there now. Sometimes I cannot put the foot on the floor.
All the old accidents are coming back I think. It’s very painful.
– You said after Puls. you took Nat-m.?
– Of course.
– It helped you?
– It helped my mind.
I was feeling much better and it cleared up my mind and my feelings.
I was feeling much better and couldn’t feel so much the pain,
the bones were all the time the same like before but I couldn’t feel the pain so much.
But then I stopped I was feeling better mentally.
– Did you go back to Lyc. or took Lach.?
– I took Lach. Lach. helped of course.
I had a lot of problems with my thyroid and then it was gone.
Also my menstruation was going on, but suddenly when I was 38 I got menopause
and I was feeling very bad and Puls. helped at this time also.
My period came back a lot of times every time when I took it.
About 5-6 months later I took another one it came back and then nothing happened anymore.
It’s gone since 3 years.
– Altogether in these 14 years how many remedies have you taken? 30, 40, 50, 60?
– 15 remedies. I have a good homeopath but nothing would really act on me.
Between I took Nux-v. but it didn’t clear the case.
– You also took Sil. And now you have this pain in the right sacroiliac junction.
Severe pain, which comes every half an hour?
– No. I am feeling that every half hour it is getting worse.
When I turn a little bit around and I want to move my knees it’s getting more.
When I am sitting still and I am walking it’s ok. When I am walking slowly.
But when I want to move a little bit then I have a lot of pain.
Also when I move to the back...
- What would you do in such a case?
After Puls. she says she had all her fears out.
– Puls. and Nat-m.
– When you took Puls. you took it for psychological reasons or for the pains?
– For psychological reasons and also for the pain in the fingers and my knee.
– And you had a lot of grief?
– Yes, I had a lot of grief.
– You separated from your husband?
– Yes, he was a drinker and I had a lot of bad time with him.
– And your children stayed with you?
– The children stayed with me and we moved away when they were 2 and 4
and I only had the feeling that I can do something to change my life.
I only had a few marks in my pocket and I started with a good feeling
and I got very good practice for Homeopathy and other things also Chiropractice
and the people came and I got a good new home and good job and all were going well.
But suddenly I had problems with my new boyfriend and he didn’t want to move to us of course,
the children were growing up and they needed a father, 2 boys, and suddenly I went off him,
met another man and I married him 3 years ago but we had a lot of problems.
He is very sick. He is depressed and I wouldn’t know it before.
And a lot of times I would get off him but I can’t, of course,
I changed my practice and my home and my children love him and I cannot go back.
Now it’s ok, it’s working but it’s like a normal marriage, I think.
– Out of the remedies which you took, which is the one you think it helped you most?
– Lyc., I think. It was also the remedy of my mother and my biggest child.
He always takes Lyc., I don’t know why.
– She wants to ask a question.
– Just a question; in what potency you took your remedies?
– First, 200C or 200D and then 18LM.
– And Lyc. helped you most first? 200C?
– Yes.
– And then LM?
– LM. When it worked well we waited and then doctor gave me 18LM.
– And the others the same?
– The same, yes.
– Thank you.
– Sometimes I like to swim in cold water and I have fear about cold air
but sometimes I need it to go out in the cold air and to breathe cold air.
– You have fear of cold air?
– When it’s too cold and sometimes I need to go out, I open the window, I need fresh air.
I think it was Puls. all the time. But I want to have fresh air all the time.
I cannot sleep when there is no window open in the night.
– Is there anything that affects the joint pains?
– They are better in warm or very hot water or very cold, with ice.
I love to swim in very hot water. The stiffness is gone when I spend a lot of time in hot water.
And the stiffness every morning is very bad
when I wake up I can’t move along from my bed and I have to put on...of course of my knees also.
– Let me give you my thought, so far about the case.
Here from a homeopathic point of view we don’t have any kind of real information.
Of course we know this is a woman she has been through a lot of stresses, grief, at the same time,
at a certain point she develops rheumatoid arthritis she has taken several remedies,
some have helped, some have not, some have more, some less.
This so far, as far as we are concerned at this historic moment in her case
we don’t know anything about the case. We don’t have any information on which we can prescribe.
Either we have to try to do what? Can anybody tell me?
What do we have to try to do at this moment? We are facing this problem.
Lyc. has helped, let’s try it again or whatever.
She wanted to take another dose of Rhus-t.
What will you do in such a situation?
I must say this is the worst situation that you can be in.
Because the case appears like that I will you give some information concerning
what we have been talking this moment. It’s interesting what she’s telling.
She says 15 days ago I started with Rhus-t.
– 4 days ago.
– When did you start?
– 14 or 15 years ago.
– What remedy?
– Rhus-t. Because of the lumbago.
– Was this the same thing or different?
– I think it was the same.
– Started with Rhus-t. And then it did not help. And then Arn., did not help.
The pain kept rising and then Lyc., it went down and then it started coming again,
Lyc. again most probably and then Lyc. again and again. Something like that happened.
And then at a certain moment she says I took Nat-m.
It’s not possible to reconstruct exactly the situation.
But more or less this is what I understand.
If she takes Nat-m. here that means that she took it because she had some grief.
How many years ago?
– 10 years.
– So, he is 15 years ago, here is 10 years ago, there is grief.
She takes Nat-m. and helps her with her psychological state.
You repeated Nat-m.?
– I think so.
- And then...
- Suddenly the pains started with my old operated knee, it was the first pain,
and every month there was another bone was getting more like that, on the feet and everywhere.
– When did you take Puls.?
– Maybe at this time. And then bones went better.
– With Puls.?
– Yes, I think so, it was better.
– And the pains? –
They were much better.
– And the knee? – Also,
it was getting better.
–Why did you have to have the knee operated?
– It was too bad.
The meniscus was broken again, there was a little piece in the knee and the tried to take that off.
Of course, I couldn’t move my knee anymore.
And I also had a bit the fear of my son...
- During this time you developed fear of what?
– Fear that my son would die.
He had a big accident and also I had a lot of fear
that I would move to the new place where I live now.
I thought this is not the right place to stay for me.
I gave up all my life before;
where I lived, I had enough money, I could do want I wanted.
Now my hands were bounded and so I think this was because I couldn’t step away.
The symbol was that also my feet got swollen
and me knee was getting swollen, of course, because of the grief.
When you feel you can’t do anything I think this happened to the rheumatism,
and it was coming more and more.
The doctor told me if you would not take methotrexate, in a few months you will sit in a wheelchair.
– You took methotrexate?
– No. I didn’t, never.
– Did you take cortisone?
– No.
– Aspirins?
– Yes.
– How many aspirins?
– Not many but sometimes when there was pain.
– Lach. helped you with the thyroid? Was it swollen?
– I had pain and I couldn’t handle anything on my throat
and also I think the doctor gave it because of the inflammation.
It was red and swollen. It helped a lot.
– Do you remember other remedies that helped you?
You too Nux-v.; no effect. Med. had negative effect.
Between I had a bad migraine and he gave me Nux-v.
Only because of the migraine.
– The problem in this case is that we don’t know the theory well.
And that’s why we arrive at a stage where wrongly
or may directly may arrive by accident to the right state.
Because you prescribe remedies one after another according to the symptomatology a person has.
You prescribe a remedy and then you give another one and then another
and then the right one and then the wrong one and then the right and then the wrong...
you go ahead like this.
The fact remains that at every time you have to make an evaluation of the situation of the patient.
And unless you know the theory you cannot make this evaluation.
Your evaluation is going to be wrong.
The moment that your evaluation is going to be wrong you don’t know what to do next.
Will you give a remedy or not? Here you have an immediate problem.
She’s suffering a lot. Are you going to give a remedy or not?
At any moment you are facing this. Where did she have the grief?
She took Nat-m. The grief was better. She took Puls. for the grief and she developed some fears.
The fears was a positive or a negative reaction after Puls.?
Puls. helped her swelling and brought out some fears.
Is this right or wrong reaction? Who says it is wrong? 17.
Who says it was right? 4.
Puls. helped her psychologically but brought out some fears.
And my question is you hear this from your patient,
are you going to say I have made a mistake I gave a remedy
which made better the swelling but brought out some fears?
Or are you going to say nice, good it’s correct?
– Would it depend in balance the fears are more but the pains are less, in general?
She got some fears how serious are they and how good is the pain relieved?
– But if the fears were hidden deep inside of her as you said in another example
and now they are coming out it would be good, it would be a progress.
– But you have to know; is it good or bad?
And you have to have some rules according to which you evaluate.
If you don’t know the rules, if you don’t understand the rules then you cannot evaluate.
You can say Puls. is wrong, antidote Puls. Or Puls. is correct and...
- So fears instead of swelling is wrong? It’s going to the emotional sphere, deeper.
It cannot be the right remedy.
– That’s correct. The fears are not good when the swelling is better.
But is that all that you are evaluating?
– In the beginning there was depression in Nat-m.
And I think it’s good that brought out fear.
– That is correct. What she says is the correct evaluation.
If there was a depression and swelling.
Because she lost her husband and lost her children. She has depression.
She takes Nat-m. and the depression is better,
then she takes Puls. some fears are developing but the swelling is better
and the depression is better but now she has the fears.
The evaluation is that the remedy is correct.
But in order to do that you have really to know exactly what is happening.
How much depression? What kind of depression? How deep?
To be able to really evaluate what the remedy is doing and always the idea is that from this 3 levels
(mental, emotional and physical) you try to see this direction;
from the mental to emotional, from emotional to physical.
And from the upper emotional going down to emotional.
And this is how you can really evaluate the case.
Now, in her particular case she says 3 days ago she took Rhus-t.
and when she took it in the past several times it never worked.
– No. Only the first time when I had lumbago by the windsurfing.
– Now, 3 days before, you took Rhus-t. Did it have any effect?
– I think new swellings came up that I never had before,
much pain and suddenly, until this night,
I couldn’t use my fingers anymore without pain.
For 3 days I had much pain now the pain is gone.
My knee is ok and now I have this pain.
What is your evaluation?
What are you going to do? Are you going to repeat Rhus-t.?
– I think it was the effect of Rhus-t. that I am sitting here like that.
– With Homeopathy you have to know certain things;
diseases don’t go just like this without any problem.
You just give the remedy and the disease disappears. No.
You have a process and you have to know whether the process is the correct one
in order not to interfere in the wrong way and the wrong time,
in order to let the remedy do whatever it can and then evaluate
and decide whether if you should enter with another remedy.
I will reveal to you something that I have never said before.
I spoke about energy complexes which are mental, emotional and physical.
Also you must know and you must have the experience that you give a remedy
and the person comes back and says I am feeling better
emotionally, mentally, physically I am the same.
The main problem may be the same but the person comes back and says I feel better in my emotions.
What I am going to reveal you that this energy complexes here which are disturbed
when you give a remedy that fits only a partial part of the human being
which is either the mental or the emotional or physical,
it can happen a rearrangement on this level
that takes place a balance in this level and yet the whole organism is not touched.
Do you understand now why some of your patients they come back after you give Nat-m.
and they will usually say I feel better but my ulcer, my knees, my pains, my headaches, no change.
Because what you have done is you choose a remedy which fits this energy complex which we call mental
or the emotional or the physical.
In the same way you give somebody a remedy for his knee, for his pain in the knee.
It touches the knee pain, it cures the new pain but affects nothing on the whole organism.
That means you choose a remedy which fits only the physical complex, not the whole organism.
When you choose a remedy which fits really fits, is the similimum for the whole organism,
then you have a different type of reaction.
That’s why we don’t like to hear after we give a remedy “I am better”.
What we like to hear is that your remedy made me very sick. The sicker the better.
That means you have really touched the energy complex,
which is behind these complexes which are partial.
You really touch the similimum.
And then the organism is shaken and tries to rearrange itself in all levels.
But in so doing then what you will see is this kind of direction.
Not I am better here, I am better there...
You will see an initial aggravation which can be bigger or smaller,
depending on the complexity of the case.
How deep is the chronic case.
In such case you may need to have to wait and see the effect of such prescription.
You may have to wait for a month or two or six to see the effect of your prescription
before you can even think of giving another remedy.
Is it possible that in every case we’ll have this big reaction?
No, it’s not possible, unfortunately.
Those who know more about the theory that we teach here about the 12 levels of health, the groups etc.
depending which group the patient belongs,
depending on that group that he will have this or that reaction.
Here we have this case which gives us this feedback.
3 days ago she took Rhus-t. 200C and she said all these years I never had it.
I took Rhus-t. not any effect. Now you had an effect.
– I think so.
- What are we going to do? She is in pain.
Are we going to repeat Rhus-t. because it has an effect?
What you have to ask in order to investigate a case is
how Rhus-t. has affected her mentally and emotionally.
Is any type of effect on these levels? What can you say?
– I don’t know, maybe it’s because of the pain that I am feeling worse or confused.
Every time, every year when I come here to find a little bit power
and to relax a bit I know every time when I go home, it’s going better.
On another point my best girlfriend is with me here on the island
and she is in the same situation like I was when I was here for the first time,
cause she wants to get a divorce and she has no power,
she is very depressed and a lot of time we are talking
and I think all my inner things will go out because of her.
– Because of her situation.
– Because I have been in the same situation 10 years before, maybe.
– You understand her situation and you are affected by it.
– Yes, maybe. I am the only friend that can help her. She has no friends anymore.
Her husband was so bad to everybody that she has no friends anymore.
And all these come together so my suitcase is too heavy.
I think all the things are coming together now.
– You have to ask these questions,
what I am asking is something you have to think and you have to ask.
She says after Rhus-t. all my pains which I had here
which were severe disappeared and now I have this pain.
You have to ask whether this pain here is a better
or a worse situation than having the pains in the extremities.
Is this pain a deeper or a more peripheral pain?
If it is a deeper side that means from the peripheral joints it goes into a deeper joint,
is this a good sign? No, it’s not a good sign. What did Rhus-t. do?
It suppressed from here to there.
– If this woman’s joints are another kind of problem
then the backache which is caused by external wind I think it is more superficial plane.
– That is correct. You have to ask that.
You have to ask whether what she is having here is because of riding a bike and she got a draft.
She says I was riding a bike and I got a draft.
So the question is, is this a continuation of the rheumatoid arthritis situation
where from here it goes there, no good, or is this something else,
an acute situation which came either because she lifted some weight
or because she was exposed to a draft or because she made a wrong move on the bike.
If it is a continuation it’s not good.
That means Rhus-t. has suppressed and it can do that.
But is this really suppression or might be that this is a next situation not so deep?
– What you said, the susceptibility to get a draft causing such a deep pain wasn’t there before
and it’s a part of the progression of the arthritis condition.
– There is one more question here. She said I started with this pain.
Do we really have a suppression or we have a return of an old symptom?
Because she says I started with this pain.
– I think 2 days ago.
Sometimes you have a feeling that there is something that disturbs you,
I was feeling there was a little bit but I forgot it and now suddenly
since this morning when I stood up it was starting so much.
When I remember I think it was since that time when I took Rhus-t.
A little bit only a shine I think it was there. But now it’s acute.
I think it’s not only about the motorbike and the wind. I had something here that could be.
Maybe a little bit but I think it’s not the only reason.
– If this pain, which she has now, is a return of her old symptoms due to Rhus-t.
you should wait, you should not touch the case.
If this is a super imposition upon her organism of a new situation because of draft
or because or wrong moves you can give a remedy.
All these are the thoughts which are going on in my mind concerning the case.
– In the beginning didn’t she say it was exactly the same way as it was 15 years before?
She said first the joints and after that the back.
– First it was the back and then the joints. Is this correct?
– Yes.
– This is what is going on in my mind,
all these questions which I put forward when I am examining the case.
– One question;
do we have to observe the conventional medicine you’ve got during the operation at the knee?
– What medicine she took?
– Yes and can this change the effect of the homeopathic remedies?
– What remedies did you take after the operation?
– Nothing. I only took Arn. by myself.
– No painkillers, no chemical drugs, only Arn.
– During the operation she must have taken narcotics for example or perhaps antibiotics.
– But don’t forget the operation was several years ago.
– And this doesn’t change the effect of homeopathic remedies?
– After the operation she took several remedies, she took Lyc. again, Puls.
– The second operation was 3 years ago.
The first time was when I was 20, more than 24 years ago,
the second was 3 years ago and they told me in 3 weeks you can walk
and you will never feel pain and after 5 months I could only walk in steps.
Such a pain I had in my knee, I was not better.
– So you took remedies?
– Only Arn. and then nothing.
– And then you could not walk.
– No, but I took ice or heat sometimes but no normal remedies not aspirin, nothing.
– But homeopathic remedies?
– Arn. I remember, I think first I took Nux-v. after the narcotics and then Arn.
and then nothing. Sil. one time I think.
Of course inflammation was not going off.
I had such a knee over a month.
– How are you going to think about this case?
Because these are the cases that you are going to face in your practice.
We clear up in our mind and we say either it is a suppression or maybe it is a curative action.
Then can we do anything else?
– I think up to this time she has taken all that remedies just for the symptoms, nothing else.
But this time it’s better to take the whole case from the beginning to do the right nemesis,
to think of all the symptoms because we are always talking about these local symptoms.
That’s not enough to find the right remedy.
For half an hour we are talking only for local symptoms.
So we have to go to what you are telling mental and emotional, everything,
the totality of the symptoms, what actually are these. It might be the only solution.
We have to forget about all these remedies I don’t mind now if I retake the case.
I have to think about what happened exactly; that might be important for me.
– That’s correct. What he says is correct.
We reached that point where we have all these symptoms and the history
and the remedies and the effects of the remedies but actually we don’t know the present situation,
so the question is, if we take a full case at the moment we ask mental, emotional, physical symptoms
can we then prescribe a remedy yes or no? Who says no? Who says yes?
My answer is yes and no. Yes if we really see a clear picture now.
If we have a clear picture of a remedy now we are allowed actually to prescribe.
If we don’t see a clear picture we better wait. So this is the right answer.
You ask the question, give to make the interrogation that you would like to know about her.
– It’s not to make the right question.
Is to restart and find out what is the purpose of her visit.
– The purpose of the visit is the pain which is in the sacroiliac junction on the right side.
We have several remedies like Aesc., Nat-p., Thuja.
We have remedies of this or that type for sacroiliac junction but this is not good enough.
– You have to think of all the remedies to see what remedy could be after these physical pains.
– So you are going to ask, this is your patient and you are going to put the first question to her.
– I believe she is stressed to talk only about these things, the physical problems,
I maybe start with some modalities how it happened and how she is getting worse or something.
And to come back slowly to the mental state.
– Modalities of the pain. She can give us the modalities of the pain. She gave already.
When she is moving a little bit from the sitting position... there is motion aggravates.
One modality but if she walks she is better.
Another modality she gave is that warm ameliorates but local cold also ameliorates.
Very cold and very warm both ameliorates.
– These are strange symptoms that should be collected.
– You ask her what else you want to know.
– For example she told that first motion is aggravating, when she walks, the later motion is ameliorating.
It might be right to note down and after we have to listen how she says.
– She already said it. Say it again, how you feel the pain. The modality.
– When I am beginning to move it is very painful, I cannot sit very still,
I have to move a little bit but when I move in the beginning it’s very painful
and when I am walking slowly it’s ok and when I am walking all is ok.
When I stop and I start again the pains starts again.
– The first motions aggravating and later she is ameliorating.
– Next question.
– How is the modality when you feel cold air or something?
She told about the draft of the air, but how it happens can you explain?
– With the motorbike!
– How do you explain how you feel better with cold or warm.
– I am feeling very hot in my face I think.
– Flashes of heat you have?
– Cold hands and hot face.
– So it is very important thing to know that the face is very hot and the feet are cold.
– My feet are also cold. But I never had it since months.
– What do you want to do when you want to relax your pain?
– I go for swimming and I don’t know if I want to lie down on a bed.
I think I prefer to walk more.
– So it is reconfirming that the motion is ameliorating.
– So, what else?
– What is your internal situation when you are in the house?
– Here on the island?
– No, in your house, inside, how do you feel? Your pains.
– I cannot tell.
– Another question.
– If she goes out of the house does she feel better?
– I feel better when I am in the nature. Every time I am feeling better.
– So this modality I think it is clearer that she wants open air, open air is ameliorating as she confirmed it.
– I think fresh air coming is better.
– I think there are other doctors that maybe want to go on.
– Can you describe your very inner state?
– When I am in pain I cannot think of mental things now.
– How do you feel beside of the pain? Emotional?
– Calm not aggressive or something. I only feel the pain now.
– How did you feel before it started?
– I think lucky to see the nature around and to have no problems. I thought all was going well.
– You were happy.
– Yes, really. Every time I am here I feel happy.
– You were happy and talking with the girlfriend?
– Yes.
– You described something else before.
– This girlfriend has the same problems like I had when I came here to the island 10 years before.
– And you were happy to hear this again?
– No. I know her story for about 1 year. There is nothing that changed.
And for me every time I have a lot of people I should help them, also mentally.
It touches me but not so much, of course I’m a homeopath,
every time I have people with problems
and so it’s a normal problem like other peoples’ who are sitting there.
Maybe it is going a little bit deeper but I think I am standing more over this.
I think I have enough to do with myself and not only with the problems of my girlfriend.
– I would like to mention 2 things outside of the interview;
The one is the state of the class,
it’s like confusing and the other point is she told us none of the remedies really helped her.
– No she said that Lyc. helped her quite a lot.
– But not totally. And Puls. helped her quite a lot
but one sentence was no remedy helped really deeply. Isn’t it?
– Lyc. did very well and I had no pain and my bones were better,
they got normal I think but suddenly I had new problems with my new husband,
again the same things, I wanted to get off. But I couldn’t of course.
I think this was also a point in December but I couldn’t because of the money
because of the situation with my children.
I knew that I had to stay there for now on for 5 years maybe until they are grown enough
and I will find another solution to all the things.
Maybe I’ll stay there. I don’t know. But now it’s going normally I think at home.
I think there is no family without problems.
– Which aspect of your life you are not very happy with?
– Who is happy? If you ask 95% of the cases will not answer positively
because we always have an ideal of what might be the best position for us to be and we are not there.
You ask her if she is happy.
Unless she says I am depressed or I am anxious, suffers, otherwise... are you happy?
– I would like to know at which areas she is having so much unhappiness.
– What you can ask is; are you depressed?
What is important for us is the changes that the patient himself notices concerning his own state.
That means I was not feeling my iliac junction and now I have pain.
This is a change definitely. I had no anxiety, now I have anxiety. That is a change.
But if you ask a person are you anxious, no.
Do you have fears? No.
Are you depressed? No.
You can keep on asking questions like that and the patient does not realize
that there is such a change.
You cannot force the patient to tell you really that maybe I am this or that.
Because if you force at one moment you may get some positive answer
on which you cannot base your prescription any more.
Because it is not something which is given...
- Is there any food that you strongly crave?
– Sea food.
– Like?
– Lobsters or something like that. No oysters.
– Sea food you mean fish?
– Yes. Fish and shrimps and all that.
– Octopus?
– Yes, also.
– And also sepias (cuttlefish)?
- Sep. I had also in between; I forgot it!
– Any strong aversion for particular food; what do you strongly dislike?
– Oysters!
– Which remedy has aversion to oysters?
– Lyc. No! You don’t know your repertories! Aversion oysters, Kent gives only one remedy.
Not Lach. Lach. has desire. It’s Phos. Phos. has aversion to oysters, strong
and Lach. has desire for oysters, strong.
– Any food aggravations?
– No, I can only tell...
- These are good questions.
We can go ahead and ask her specific like do you take onions?
– Much. And garlic I prefer.
– You like onions?
– Yes.
– And no side effect. It doesn’t give you bloatedness or...
- No. But I prefer garlic. I eat much garlic.
If I can I eat 5-6 pieces a day, when I don’t have to work.
Here in Greece it’s possible.
– Sweets?
– Sometimes. More when I was younger.
– Salt?
– No.
– What about fatty food?
– When I was younger I took fat meat and pork also but now
I don’t like any more fat on the meat or the pork.
Of course when I eat pork I get more pain in my bones, every time.
I prefer salads and fresh food.
– What is your reaction to weather in general? Are you a cold person?
– When the weather is changing to storm or to cold I feel it 1 or 2 days before.
I have a lot of pain in my bones. I am very stiff, I feel it in the morning when it’s raining.
– That’s a good modality. Underline it 3 times.
– Also when it gets hot. I feel it also the day before.
– Somebody is asking are you weeping easily?
– Yes. Music also yes.
When there are some memories and there is a lot of music that has been in my life
and when I listen to special music...
- Which is the remedy that weeps with music?
Nat-m. Graph. weeps with music. Nat-c., Aur.. They are affected by music.
But when they say I weep with music the first remedy has to be Graph. Nat-c. is sensitive to music.
Aur. is sensitive to music and Aur. is better with music.
Depression, they put music... What kind of music?
Classical music mostly, soft music. And their mood becomes lighter.
But they may have a depression or anxiety
or they may have a hurried feeling which is all the time inside
and they put music and they eventually calm down.
Which is the remedy? Everybody knows... Tarent.
Very good! These are the modifications concerning music.
– I remember the Tarent. case from the year before, not the last year, but the year before.
I like spiders, yes! Much.
– So what can you do more than that? We try to take the case.
Kent says if any remedy benefit a patient in one potency,
all the other potencies of that remedy will help the patient further on.
He doesn’t say that exactly. What he says is this;
when a remedy has helped, a potency has helped, you can try other potencies as well.
Do not give up the remedy. But this doesn’t mean that if you try it will always help.
He didn’t say that and it does not happen also.
You may have a remedy helping in 200C and no other potency will help.
But when you have a remedy which has helped and helped in general
then you don’t give up this remedy before you have tried a higher potency or a lower potency.
– Why not do that in this case?
– Well we are thinking of that. We will see in the end what we will decide.
Whether we should give another Rhus-t. higher.
How is your sleep in general?
– Bad. I am dreaming a lot.
– You talk in your sleep?
– Maybe. I don’t know.
– Do you grind your teeth?
– No. But I am snoring bad since a few weeks.
I had problems with the nose.
I think maybe I have a little hay fever but I don’t take a remedy for this.
In Germany the last weeks was very hot. We had more than 30°C for 2 weeks and it was not normal.
– Do you have any headaches now, during this period of time?
– Yes, I had.
Suddenly I had when I drank one beer and on the next morning I had as if I had drunk a lot of beer.
– Only one time?
– Yes. But I remember the last year when I drank beer, I’ve had headache.
I never had headache before. I can drink good wine and then I have no problems.
I can drink a lot of wine but if I drink beer I have a headache.
– Are you thirsty?
– Yes. The years before I wasn’t and since 2-3 weeks I am very thirsty.
– For cold water or it doesn’t matter?
– Not very cold.
– You are thirsty and you are drinking.
– I am drinking water if I get some.
But sometimes I forget to drink. I am not drinking enough all over the day like necessary.
– Do you feel frozen or sweaty?
– When I am tired I am very frozen.
– But in general you are cold?
– When I was younger I was colder but now the last 2-3 years I need to open the window
and sometimes I am feeling very hot. Sometimes I have little feelings like fever.
– You never took Calc.?
– Maybe but it was long ago. Maybe 10 years ago. But I don’t prefer eggs.
I like them but they’re not necessary. Sometimes I like to drink a lot of cold milk. Sometimes.
– Lately do you like milk?
– Cold milk, yes.
– Are you sweating on special parts on your body?
– Yes, in the night. I had times when the bones are very bad.
I was sweating all over my body; under the feet and mostly here, on the head and the shoulders.
All was wet when I was waking up in the morning. I had it for months.
Also in the winter when it was very cold outside and I was sweating.
I was getting very hot,
then I was throwing away the covers and suddenly I was frozen
and shivering and it was changing all night long.
– Your feet are normally outside of the blanket?
– Good question. I don’t know. Sometimes, yes.
When I am sweating and I am hot I put the feet off the blanket.
– Are your feet smelling of the sweat?
– No.
– Are you sweating every night now for months?
– I had about 1-2 years, I was sweating and couldn’t sleep all night.
I also had problems to sleep;
at 3 a.m. I used to wake but I am very sensitive to electricity
and I know from the town where I live that at 3 a.m. they change the electric
and about that time when they change it I wake up suddenly and I can’t sleep till they pull it down.
I sleep again when it’s 6 a.m. It was a big problem for a long time.
And now we put off every electric device in the bed
but the problem is now we have a new mobile phone on top of the roof
and there are 3 mobile antennas that are coming over my head.
– Have you ever taken Tub.?
– Yes. The first time before I got Lyc. I had it long time ago.
– And no effect?
– I think I was better.
But the bad thing with my bones came out when the mental things happened.
– Do you like cats, dogs?
- I like cats much. They come to me and every time I feed them.
Dogs I like but I am a little bit afraid of dogs because I was bitten when I was a child.
I accept them but I don’t like them.
– Was there any time that you had a pre-tuberculous condition as a child?
– I think my grandmother died of lung affection and in her family there was TB.
And my mother got scabies when she was young, in the war.
Psor. I think it was the remedy. Psor. was also the remedy for my second son.
– Any dreams? Do you see persistent dreams?
– A lot of times I am dreaming that I am looking for a street and I am missing a train that is waiting.
I can see it but I can’t get it, I am too late and I get the wrong way to get there.
This is what I dream a lot of times over years.
– Once again please, very slowly.
– There is a train and I want to get this train on the railway station
and I want to get there and I am asking somebody for the way but it’s always the wrong way
and I never get this train and the train is going and I have to wait or find another way.
This I dreamt a lot of times, also the last months.
And if I am talking about something over the day with somebody I am dreaming it again in the night very often.
And I can also feel or see that some things will happen. I feel it before.
– You said the main symptom you have is pain currently. How does the pain make you feel?
You have the pain, it has been worse the last 3 days.
How do you feel when you have pain?
– Bad.
– Can you just enlarge a little bit?
– Most probably you are English.
– That’s right. How did you guess?
– That’s why we have problems understanding!
– I am feeling sad, my energy is gone then, when the pain is coming I have no energy.
It is very painful and also in the morning when I get up and I have pain.
It needs a few hours until the pain goes and you can laugh or something like that.
Also, I don’t like noises in the morning. I need a lot of time in the morning.
– Are you ever bleeding without any reason? From the nose or somewhere?
– When I was a child yes. A lot of times.
– Nose bleed?
– Yes, very fast when I was 5-6 years old.
– Bleeding while you are brushing teeth?
– Sometimes, but when I put off the amalgam it stops.
– How do you feel about travelling? Are you worse when travelling or better?
– I am feeling much better. I think it’s Tub. I like to travel any time.
I could travel all the time. Although there is pain.
– Do you ever dream of doing work?
– Yes, I am working very hard in my dreams and sometimes I feel that I have done it really when I wake up.
I am so tired that I can wake up and feel as if I was working all night.
– You didn’t get paid for it either!
– You are working hard in your dreams; how about in real life? Are you a hard worker?
– Yes, the last 10 years I have to work hard.
– I have another question which is completely disconnected.
Have you ever been anemic in your life? Feeling weak?
– No.
– In former times, when you were without pain were you sometimes
in the center of attention of your friends?
Were you laughing very often?
– Yes.
– Not only listening but... - I am laughing a lot.
When I am in group I like to laugh and not to discuss problems.
– In former times before your period stopped, how was the period?
– Very fast, very painful,
a lot of blood and 3 times I had to go to the hospital to stop it.
I got an operation, I was bleeding a lot when I was young.
– Painful where? In abdomen or back?
– Uterus. It was like when you get a child.
– Before the period or during the period?
– Before 1-2 days and during also.
– You had this pain in the back 10 years ago?
– Maybe a little bit earlier yes.
– And you took Rhus-t. then?
– Yes.
– And nothing happened?
– It was getting better.
– You had an amelioration from the pain on the back from Rhus.-t?
– The back was ok then but the problem with the fingers and the other bones started much later.
– So Rhus.-t was curative originally?
– The first time yes.
– And your mental emotional state?
Were you in a bad mental emotional state at that time originally when you got the back pain?
– Now?
– No, before. When it was there originally.
– 15 years ago or now?
– When the Rhus.t worked originally with the pain, your mental emotional state was...
- It was ok. At this time I had no problems.
– Also you have to remember, because we are looking for mental emotional
that when somebody has this type of disease when it is strongly on the joints.
Especially there’s rheumatoid arthritis will very seldom have mental emotional symptoms.
The disease is on the physical body now.
And it is not easy to find really strong mental or emotional symptoms.
If we take the intensity of the pain, that fact that she is red in the face,
hot in the face and cold in the extremities we can be thinking of Bell.
But if we take that she is desiring cold milk
and the predisposition we can be thinking of Tub.
If we take the modalities
which she has and the desire for cold milk we are thinking of Rhus-t.
Also with Tub. is the extreme perspiration that she has during the night.
So with the extreme perspiration and the coldness of the extremities we may be thinking of Calc.
Because the thirst is increased quite strongly the last time
we may be thinking of Bry. as a complimentary to Rhus-t.
We know that Bry. compliments the action of Rhus-t.
Actually through taking her case we come down to these remedies mostly
and we may decide which one is the correct.
For Phos. I would need at least to have the thirst with cold.
At this moment there are no Phos. symptoms
unless the thirst was really for very cold water which she did not confirm.
- Calc-p... - There is a possibility especially because we heard her sigh a few times.
She sighs from pain, of course.
– Kali-c. because of the sweat during the night and the lumbago.
– Kali-c. is not one of the remedies that perspire during the night so much to take it as a keynote.
And this is not lumbago. This is really concentrating on right sacroiliac junction.
An inflammation on sacroiliac junction.
– Does the sweat she gets ameliorate the pains?
– She cannot say because she just had the pain today.
– I am not sweating now.
– Before?
– Maybe when I am very wet in the morning the pains get better.
– Anyone who will give one of these remedies is a good homeopath.
Not good enough!
The reason that because we are thinking of all these remedies as we analyzed before
we said if the case becomes clear after we take the whole case then we can prescribe.
The case according to this analysis is not clear.
If we have all these possibilities that means the case is not clear.
Therefore because we see between the remedies that they have a great possibility
because of the desire for cold milk and the modalities Rhus-t. still is a possibility,
the correct remedy to give at this moment is this;
Placebo.
If you want to give something to your patient, 3 days ago you had given Rhus-t. right or wrongly,
then we have to wait to really see what is happening.
Has Rhus-t. really suppressed the case or is going to promote the case?
If it is the correct remedy
she will within a few more days start feeling better in that junction as well.
The problem is that the case is not clear
therefore if we don’t want to confuse the case further we should wait.
3 days ago you gave a remedy, there is a reaction,
there is a possibility that an old symptom has come back
and we don’t have a clear remedy, we have to wait.
But where she points out the pain, the intensity of the pain also,
shows definitely that there is an inflammation in the sacroiliac junction.
But you can do a physical examination as well.
Unfortunately from a purely homeopathic point of view you cannot give a remedy.
What you can do to relieve the pain is use some aspirin.
But this type of pain especially if it’s a return of the old symptom
that means if the organism comes back to the beginning of the rheumatoid arthritis
this type of pain is quite severe, quite obstinate, it’s not easily gone away
and if you expect by a remedy to take out this pain within 24 hours
you are going to make a mistake even if the case is quite clear.
This type of pain with this type of disease is not going away easily.
And if you want to reduce the pain, I can reduce the pain, by tomorrow she will feel 60% better.
I’ll give all of them.
If you just give 5 remedies by tomorrow, about 24 hours,
a day after tomorrow she will feel 60% better but...
Now there is a possibility that her state of health will become better.
If you are careful, if you know what you are doing, what you expect,
if you want to reduce the pain of course it is very easy, you just add Thuja to that,
6 remedies and perhaps Aesc. also. 7.
Homeopathy is like the people who are pure.
The people who are pure don’t do anything wrong.
But sometimes they are tempted to do some sins. You know what I mean.
After that it does not matter whether 1,2,5,25 sins, then it goes like this.
As long as you keep your purity you are on the right path.
As long as you tempted to do this,
to reduce the pain with 7 drugs then there is a kind of downward process
The bottom is where all remedies lie. 780 is the M.M. of Boericke.
which will take you right to the bottom. You can use all of them. That’s the bottom.
If you reach that point, you will need all the remedies to relieve your patients.
It’s the other way around.
If you start with giving a lot of remedies and you start reducing the remedies
the you may reach the point where really you understand what you are doing,
you give a remedy, you observe, you evaluate, you wait and then you are satisfied with your case.
I can tell you that. My experience shows it again and again; to make sin does not pay.
Polypharmacy, poly-relationships...
‘Poly’ means ‘much’ Greek.
That’s why Greeks used to say stick always to the golden means,
never too much.
Homeopathy is exactly this.
I feel that this case was very difficult for all of us.
Me included. So nobody is happy, I can see in your eyes.
There is a difference between a simple inflammation of the sacroiliac junction
and a collagen disease which we call rheumatoid arthritis.
Actually it is a whole syndrome which is has this junction involved which is very painful,
very obstinate and not manageable with (manual) manipulation.
Therefore in this particular case I will be very careful if somebody suggests
that I can promise  you she will be better...I would doubt it very much.
I would also ask her if she wants to take aspirin.
She can take aspirin to reduce the pain than giving 7 remedies to be able to bring about the least pain.
I have found out that many times through the aggravation period
which I consider 3 days is within the aggravation period I have found out if I explain to the patient
this aggravation is because of the remedy
then I see this aggression of the patient
“you gave me this remedy and I am much worse”, I let them talk and then I say ok.
This is what happens in Homeopathy; we have an initial aggravation, this is very good.
They calm down immediately and they give you the time to observe because otherwise you lose your mind.
Now she is not shouting but much more difficult cases they shout.
– Especially being homeopath she is advising herself...
- We have to have the time for observation. Now what shall we do?
I don’t know. Because it’s too early after the remedy and the remedy has brought back an old symptom.
Let’s see. Another remedy is not clear.
That remedy also still has some indications.
Maybe we have to go later on to go higher if we see that the pain continues.
Maybe something will change. The most probable of these remedies are Rhus-t. and Tub.
These are the 2 most probable remedies which may still be indicated or may still have to be repeated.
– I think you are right but...
she has severe pain.
In Brazil there are colleagues who are very enthusiastic
about associating acupuncture to relieve the pain.
Which is your opinion about it?
– This kind of pain is difficult to be relieved with acupuncture.
And my experience is that acupuncture can also have a suppressive effect like Homeopathy.
I just relate to you a case of high blood pressure with sleeplessness.
I prescribed Calc. She came a month later I can’t remember, with a severe lumbago.
The blood pressure was normal. She was sleeping well but now she had that lumbago.
I took the case and I could see no clear remedy.
I said I’m sorry I cannot give you a remedy you have to stay with your lumbago come again after a few days.
he went to an acupuncturist; the lumbago was gone.
In one week after the lumbago was gone the blood pressure shot up and she had a brain stroke.
When she came back after the hospital, she told me the story, I said I am very sorry.
You should have asked whether you should go to an acupuncturist
but she decided herself because somebody said you do this.
So we have to know quite well our pathology as homeopaths.
We have to know the pathology and what the real prognosis of our case is.
Her prognosis, according to my experience,
is that she has to go through this inflammation for several weeks perhaps
if this is a return of an old symptom where rheumatoid arthritis started with this place.
But after that she can remain quite well.
If we start interfering with this reaction of the organism either by homeopathic remedy
or manual manipulation or acupuncture, in her case I will say...
I don’t want to do that.
I don’t want to touch this case.
A simple severe sciatica, I prescribe a remedy and I see no effect.
She will say can I go to acupuncturist I would say of course go to an acupuncturist.  She can try.
But when we have a severe case where she has not sleep at night,
she has high blood pressure and the anxiety was very high,
I prescribed the remedy and I see all this calms down and the organism takes it on that level.
I said thank God, that’s very good.
I didn’t say to her it’s very good because the patient is suffering now.
If you tell her it’s very good she will tell you thank you very much!
You say now wait, come after a week and we’ll see if there is a clear picture
but before you have a clear picture after such a good reaction it’s not good to give another remedy.
This is my experience and I have several examples that show that
because lots of cases have been spoiled with the homeopathic remedy afterwards.
There is a correct reaction and then different remedies are given
and they spoil the reaction finally and then you say why.
But as you said it is severe but you have to know this RA case where the sacroiliac junction is involved
you are going to have a very severe case and you have to treat it very carefully if you want a cure.
To give LM potency in this case? You can try that.
That is the most innocent thing you can do.
– May I ask you one question? Deep inside of you do you really think that this case is a Rhus-t. case?
With all your experience?
– I will tell you something my experience says.
When I have seen a very clear case and I have given the remedy and did not work.
Sometimes it looks very clear and it’s not really clear, it’s something else.
And when I have seen such cases in which there is an effect after the remedy
I cannot dispute that effect because I see the effect so... hands up.
Maybe it’s not a clear case but what I also know is that most probably this case
after Rhus-t. will go either to Bry. or to Calc.
Most probable is Calc. for her.
So I expect a certain moment to see the picture of Calc. more.
Feeling the cold more and perhaps sweets are going to come up
and maybe the desire for eggs will appear but these changes will be on a long period of time.
Not like that, not quickly.
If it was clear, what potency we could have given this moment?
– 10M.
Is the case clear for you?
But do you understand the way I am explaining?
Do you understand this way of thinking or you think I’m in the clouds?
There was a man many years ago when I was talking and were some French homeopaths,
I’m talking about 20 years ago, they never gave one remedy,
they said that’s nonsense
and when I spoke for the first time in America about one remedy one the French said
George is such a nice guy but he’s on the clouds. He is believing in utopias.
Now many more people believe in utopias.
We will wait and see.
Maybe tomorrow you will be 20% better.
– Wonderful! Nice holidays!
– You see she would like to have the pain gone of course but if we try she will come tomorrow
and she will say I’m worse and that is something you don’t like to hear.
Let’s see tomorrow. Tomorrow we will see the case and re-evaluate and I will tell you.
Our friend there can examine her.
– Shall she take aspirin?
– Yes, why not. She can take aspirin to reduce the pain.
There’s no problem with aspirin, I have found out.
Interferes very little or not at all with the homeopathic remedy.
Our remedies are much more powerful and they can interfere quite a lot and can change quite a lot.
My pain is gone I think completely and in the afternoon one of us gave me a little bit of craniosacral therapy
and he wanted only to look if there is no effect that I have lumbago prolapse.
My leg was out of feelings and it was getting colder
and after this therapy I could stand up more and the pain was 50% gone.
I went home and I could walk slowly. If I wasn’t moving a lot the pain was ok.
I went to bed, I drank a lot of water and then in the morning I woke up and the pain was completely gone.
Only when I move on my motorbike I could feel it a little bit
but the problem is my hands were swollen in the morning and my old sinusitis was coming back.
I had a bad cough in the morning and I had something like a stone here but now it’s gone.
That’s also an old symptom I had it a lot of years.
Now I am feeling well, I think it was Rhus-t. that is working out now.
–Until she went to bed she still had a lot of pain, she just woke up in the morning feeling better,
feeling the pain was gone.
Now the fact remains that we should not be in a hurry to give a remedy when we see some phenomena
which follow a certain rule of action.
And the rule is wait and don’t interfere because if you interfere you don’t know,
you will say what about giving another dose of Rhus-t.
Was it going to do some harm? I don’t know if another dose of Rhus-t. will aggravate or help the case.
The fact remains that once you see the action if the remedy that follows certain rules
that these rules are according to the order of things, to the order of healing, you don’t interfere.
You let this happen and proceed. I believe what he did has nothing to do with what she feels today.
Nothing at all! The healing was happening already and followed this path.
Here you have really the healing process which happens.
You don’t go and interfere when this healing process is happening.
This is the idea. And this is what we have to learn because it is difficult.
The moment she comes in so much pain, you feel very sorry you say I have to do something.
The best is not to do anything.
– May I have a question? If we are giving a wrong remedy how long we should wait to go on?
– It depends. The wrong remedy may do nothing.
But if the wrong remedy is close to the case that’s a problem and you may have to wait some time.
Unless you know the right remedy straightaway.
Sometimes you have 2 possibilities and you choose one.
The second is equally strong and the one gives some effect
but no correct effect then you can immediately go to the second possibility.
But if the second possibility is not clear you better wait.
Tell me how you are today.
– My bones were a little more painful in the morning and went to the swimming pool
and swam a little bit and it was going better I think.
– Cold water?
– Yes.
– Yesterday I saw her also drinking some coffee and drank it happily!
You have to be aware of such things because you don’t know what’s happening after she drank some coffee
and you don’t know whether it is really a relapse or whether it is antidote by coffee.
So there is some confusion you have to try to avoid as much as possible
but what I wanted to say here because somebody,
I can’t remember, asked the other day concerning Sil,
if Sil. was given before would it have acted, I said no.
This is the same case here. She took several times before Rhus-t. without any effect.
There was a time when Rhus-t. appeared in the layers.
She had to take first Lyc. or Nat-m. or whatever now in this case we cannot know exactly
because she took several remedies some of which acted, some did not act.
We cannot know exactly the sequence of remedies and how they acted.
But unless we can evaluate every time what is happening in the end it will be confusion again.
In this case in particular let us say we decided the other day to give whatever remedy
and then there are some more symptoms and we will give another remedy and another remedy;
will spoil the case because now the case is doing well.
Usually when a teacher takes a case he never says this is good.
Always the teacher wants to give a better remedy.
This is universal egotism of all teachers.
I’ll give you a better remedy. You never do that.
When a remedy is correct whether it was given by herself
or by the worst possible homeopath still the signs are that the remedy is correct.
I had this problem a lot of times in America where I would give a remedy
and next year I would know another 5-6 remedies were given in the meantime.
Where the originally remedy acted beautifully and eventually they have spoiled the case.
Invariably this was happening. George gave you a remedy, it’s no good, I will give you a better remedy.
Eventually they spoil the case.
That is why it is very important that we know the theory
and we know the theory as Ruth was saying yesterday by heart.
By the time you have the problem you cannot go to your notes and see what fits that case.
The theory has to be learned by heart.
M.M., repertory it’s no problem you can go look, study the case.
What you cannot study is the theory. Should I give a remedy or not?
There are absolute defined detailed rules for that.
So if you have a case which is doing like that you say... hands up.
Wait and we’ll see what happens and what happened was the right course of action.
Now, the question is in her case her RA is going to finish?
This is the last remedy that she will need in order to cure or to complete the cure of RA?
I doubt it. That means after Rhus-t.
if you wait long enough you will see another picture which might be Bry.
which is complementary to Rhus-t. which might be Calc. complementary to Rhus-t.
But you have to wait until such time that you see the picture of Calc.
If you now think she is going to be Calc. let’s give her Calc. and see what happens, you spoil the case!
Because you don’t know whether this organism
will need a repetition of Rhus-t. 3 or 4 times before it goes to Calc.
How many times you have to repeat? I don’t know at this moment.
If the Rhus-t. symptoms come back you have to repeat it until they change into Calc. symptoms.
Also she said yesterday after examination by this nice fellow he says I felt better
which may have confused the issue but he himself I did not do anything I just examined
because he thought it might be a hernia.
So he wanted to see whether it is a hernia in the vertebrae.
And he said it’s not a hernia, of course, it was an inflammation of the sacroiliac junction.
Alright? What I wanted to make sure is that you have to be objective especially when you teach.
This is supposed to be an advanced seminar.
Some young students they have come from Israel they want to see Mr. Vithoulkas.
But this is supposed to be a seminar where most of the people are teaching, not students.
And that’s why what we say here is quite advanced. We don’t go into details and explain everything.
Talking on teachers it is important that we are always objective in our evaluation.
We must not say something which is outside of the rules just to make ourselves important.
I could have given a remedy to her. Take Bell.
And she would come today and say I am better.
And you get the impression that she is better from Bell.
Because I know this is going to happen. She is going to be well without any other remedy.
So I give Bell. and I make a theory.
And you believe that better is because of Bell., because 2 days ago I gave her Bell.
Where the actual truth is that what I explained to you here things are going towards particular order.
Wait. How many of you resisted this idea and you said she is so much in pain you have to do something?
Just examine yourself. Thank you.