This is a gentleman from Denmark who suffers of something very peculiar and unusual.
He has been treated by several homeopaths and himself and the remedies you have taken so far are...
- Nat-m., Nat-c., Kali-ph., Calc., Lyc., Sil., Nux-v., Phos., Spig., Tub., Arn. and Hyper.
– Your problem is...
- That the left side of my face registers electromagnetic fields from ordinary devices
like lights, computers, radios, all electric motors...
I get burning pains around the eye in different places.
That’s how it starts. For example if we turn on a fan here will start a burning pain.
If I sit in front of that computer after 5 minutes I get this burning pain here.
And then it gets more and more intense as if somebody is holding a cigarette.
– So much?
– Yes.
And if I sit long enough as if someone is pulling the cigarette out right here.
Before that happens I move.
If I can’t move then I have a problem,
like in a long distance airplane when they have many TV screens above the head.
Then I get extremely restless.
After a while the brain shuts down I get into a coma.
If you ask me a question I can hear it but I can’t answer you.
This happens when I am near any device.
And it started from working with computers.
I was assistant’s analyst for 8 years
and before that I had a translation firm for a couple of years
and I worked in the translation with a computer.
That was 1983. Before 1983, no computers. Good health.
– No problems?
– Except for a migraine every 3 months.
Would come out of the blue.
– Your job had to do with coming in contact with electrical devices?
– All day in front of the screen.
– You mean you started in 1983 with the computers.
– Yes, then there was no problem.
– And the problem appeared how many years later?
– In 1983... it appeared 2 years later
because I was working there for a translation firm
and the PC screens at that time were more magnetic.
And then I translated books and I got my own little PC which was extremely magnetic.
I’ve measure it.
– You have such a device? You made your own device?
– No, I bought one. Many people have this problem.
– You can give me the address, I want to buy to check the devices here.
– I have one at home. I can bring it tomorrow.
– I can pay you for this, you can leave it here and buy a new one.
– It started where I worked very hard for a book.
I worked very hard anyway.
Then I moved to Denmark where I thought I would get this job
because I have been working as an engineer at the oil business before.
But I didn’t get it.
– Do you usually have this problem with the throat?
- This has been for a long time. Mucus in the throat all the time since probably 15 years ago.
– After 1985... It’s not coincidental with the sensitivity.
- No! The sensitivity came from one day to the next.
The total breakthrough. But there was a build-up.
Came from one day to the next in my job...
- What year?
– November 1993.
In 1985 I started to notice maybe a headache, feeling lack of energy.
– But 1985 at the same time coincides with your throat starting to collect mucus.
– I don’t think so because I was smoking.
Then I quit smoking in 1987.
And I think after that it was more pronounced.
In 1993 it was when this allergy started.
Which means I cannot work anywhere
because I can’t be in an office and I cannot do manual work
because then they use motors and if I deliver newspapers
there are the neon lights of the streets.
– The can affect you?
– Yes. I get sick.
– In 1993 it started from one day to the next my face was burning
I went on the bars and there was like people sticking cigarettes in my head
from the neon lights on the bars.
Get dizzy, then I got to the train, the same.
For several months I could only be for 2 minutes in the supermarket
because of the neon lights.
Then it would burn and I would have to run home.
That’s the condition since 1993.
Then I’ve been very limited in what I can do.
So many square meters I can be at home because of it.
– Have you been near a converter?
– No.
– Have you checked this?
– Yes.
- Whether it is really bad?
– No.
– You have not checked?
– I have not been. I have checked, yes.
– And it’s very bad?
– Yes.
It’s quite bad but it has started with the PCs definitely.
No transform stations, no high wires. Nothing like that.
– But I noticed 2 years after working every day
that I would start getting a little bit headache and feeling unwell.
So I changed from that kind of screen to a plasma/LCD screen.
That was better for some years.
Then in this system analyst job I got the plasma screen
because there are many electrical fields so I removed the magnetic fields
because already in 1985 I was sensitive.
Then with the electric fields I worked for 5 years then... boom.
– Then the big change started.
– Then I gradually got a red face and from the one day to the next
there was a quantum jump in the health to sensitivity.
Way up to anything electrical.
Even the pocket calculator will burn.
– Mostly is burning, no other symptoms?
– No. It starts burning.
– And then eventually effects the mind.
– And then I get extremely restless and lose concentration.
Then I have to get out of there otherwise it gets very painful.
– And it can lead you up to almost coma?
– Yes. It can put me in coma because the last 2,5 I had to study anatomy.
And there the first year it was with neon lights and it was very painful.
Then I got to come to home and there we had an overhead projector with a fan
and the fan became very painful.
Then I bought another overhead projector without a fan
but then the lights became very painful.
– But the worst is the neon lights?
– It’s not the neon light.
It’s because there is a spool, a coil that makes alternating magnetic fields.
If they took away the spool the neon would be like any other light.
But there is a long coil they call the ballast that keeps the current running
and that sends out thousand nanotesla in half a meter.
I can feel these things in long distance. Through the walls.
There’s a couple of strange symptoms that I noted down because my memory is going really bad.
I had to learn some memory techniques to pass these courses.
But when there is electrical sensitivity thirst is increased. I get very thirsty.
I can watch TV but if I read and the TV is on there’s 10 times more pain.
If I concentrate on something else then it gets more painful.
There is some more but... But those are associated with electrical disturbance.
- Any other?
– Better from reading. Just generally.
But when I have electrical sensitivity I’m worse from reading.
If I sit the near the thing there...
and lately in the middle of the night I wake up
with where the dark field of vision has this net floating across.
- Fine net in the vision.
– Those kinds of disturbances.
And in the morning sometimes I wake up
with a burning pain on the right side of the tongue the last few years.
And I have lots of urinary symptoms
because I run all the time.Mild prostatitis probably kind of symptoms.
I think it gets worse when there is electricity and I have to drink and run.
– Do you have frequent urination?
– Yes. Especially in the morning from 5-7 a.m.
And if I go and take a walk, every half an hour I have to urinate a lot.
And the stool has been loose in 1986 I was getting sick, cold,
just a fly comes by and I got sick.
I went to this biopath treatment where they gave me medicines for clean up.
For 1 year I had diarrhea and since then the stool has been loose and frequent.
- They damaged the flora.
– Yes. And then there was the clean up and then I got better.
– In theory, yes.
– Before there was no problem.
– Do you have any effect when there are electrical changes in the weather,
like before a thunderstorm?
– I noticed a little bit but it does not bother me.
I hate cold, wet weather. I really hate it with passion!
Living in Denmark is a little bit strange though. I still have kids there.
– How do you feel here?
– I love the warmth!
I like the Amazon, my wife is from Brazil and we go to the middle of Amazon and I feel great.
– You mean in the jungle?
– Yes. When I was a child living in Norway for a couple of years I had colds all the time.
Then we moved to South America and it was gone.
– South America, where?
– North of Venezuela, a little Dutch place.
The Dutch where hanging around some islands.
– In the seaside?
– Yes, it was a little bit like Alonissos. Same size.
– Your father is still alive?
– Yes, he is 84 but he is just about to take the jump.
My mother is also alive. They are very healthy.
My grandfather... they all lived to 84.
– It’s the limit! So they know when and where to go.
– And my health was always very good.
– Did you have any acutes?
– Yes, when I was 31 I had chickenpox
because I didn’t get sleep one night, I was near a kindergarten.
– At 31?
– Yes.
– Was it heavy?
– Yes, it was all over. I was covered with spots.
– Anything else?
– Yes, in 1986 I got mumps. I never take any medicine.
– Since when you are married? Since what age?
– I have been married thrice. 3 times.
– When was the third time?
– 4 years ago.
– The second time?
– That was in 1983.
– And how long you lived together?
– 6 years or so.
– From 1983 to 1990. Then she threw me out.
– She threw you out?
– Yes.
– Why? Because you were a bad guy?
- No, she found another guy.
– But what about you? Going out sometimes?
Having affairs?
– No, no.
– All men are good.
– One at a time!
– That doesn’t fit my thinking...
If you go swim, after swimming you feel rejuvenated, good?
– I love swimming. I feel good, yes.
– Really good?
– Yes, really good.
– Do you know the remedy which is better (in the sea)?
– Med.
– Did you take Med.?
– I was thinking of it but then I took Tub.
because my mother was afraid of animals all the time
and I didn’t feel good after I got tuberculous vaccine.
And I love to travel. I thought maybe there is a nosode blocking so I took.
But then I couldn’t lift my arm, my right arm.
– After Tub.?
– Yes,
then it got to the deltoid muscle and I had a big pain here.
So for 3 months I couldn’t lift my right arm. Still a little bit.
Then it went to the left one, a little bit.
– Did you ever had any gonorrhea?
– I had once a chancre on the penis when I was 22.
– It means syphilis?
– No, kind of ulcer. And I went to the doctor.
– And she gave you penicillin?
– No, he didn’t give me anything, he said it wasn’t anything.
– Was any discharge from the urethra ever?
– No.
– Sure? Around 1983-1984?
– No, when I had that one I was 23, in 1968.
– When you were around 40-43?
– No problem.
– No infection from any woman and you had to take antibiotics?
– No, never. I took antibiotics when I was 9 months old.
But it wasn’t my decision.
I had pneumonia and it was in Chicago, there was a great new invention, penicillin.
My father was very proud because he had used this modern medicine.
Otherwise I have stayed away from all medicines.
– Since the age of? When did you become aware that the antibiotics are bad?
– I just knew it. Internal knowledge.
– And you avoid them all your life?
– Yes.
– And you were able to avoid it?
– Yes, if I got headache I don’t take anything.
– What position do you keep in bed?
– There is a thing there.
I had a back problem in 1989.
Suddenly I was carrying so many things and then boom!
And I was flat on my back for 3 weeks,
being carried back and forth to the chiropractor, which I didn’t like very much.
I had to use a ladder to move around to get to the toilet
because I just couldn’t stand up.
This was probably because of the overload,
I was a sailor once and I lifted many things.
But then it took me several years, I did yoga exercise.
– To strengthen the muscles.
– Yes, then I was ok.
Then I go once a year or twice to chiropractor and after taking homeopathic medicine
then there is no problem.
– Which remedies of the ones that you mentioned acted on you, you remember?
– I have them written down here. I sleep on the left side.
The sleep on the right side is painful.
– Because of this incident?
- Probably.
– Calc. helped you?
– No, then I got very depressed.
Then I got more dry skin on the fingers because I have problem here with the fingers too.
– You still have dry skin.
– Yes. I just got depressed.
Nat-m. 1M was the first remedy; then I became open for a couple of hours. I am fairly open
but so opened that people would come and sit on the bench next to me and talk.
I thought this was really amazing.
– You attracted.
– Yes.
I was magnetizing people come sit down and talk to me.
Then I took Nat-c. LM to 20LM for 2 years.
The homeopath said you must be Nat-c. Then I thought probably I am.
So I took slowly LM to 20LM and then I started to really prove it at 20LM,
I hated people, I couldn’t stand anybody getting near me.
At the bus stop I would stand far away from the people.
I couldn’t stand Danish people anymore.
– That’s not because of Nat-c. most probably.
– This isn’t it because I found that with any homeopathic remedy
I would be a little bit better with electricity.
But nothing cured. With Kali-p. I got paralysis of the arms.
Weakness and dullness in the brain LM and 2LM.
– That’s very good.
– Lyc. no reaction. Sil. tired and depressed.
Nux-v. the electricity sensitivity went way very bad with LM. I call it e-llergy.
But with Nux-v. I became very sensitive. With Phos. I had a big cough.
Spig. I met (doctor name) in Oslo and I gave him 2 symptoms
from when I was on the plane and I was in a certain seat of the plane
and when it lands it was like somebody sticks a big needle into my eye.
It was like that while it was landing.
And he just heard that and said it’s Spig. But that didn’t do anything.
Arn. I took because these bicycles they have these chains
and I locked it and it recoiled and hit my right testicle,
which was very painful and then I took Arn. 200C and it got better.
I have a spermatocele there which is painful the day after intercourse.
Otherwise when I get very bad I get Hyper.
If I am in a plane and there are 50 TVs and I have to be there for 8 hours
and I am really in torture then I take Hyper. To sort of put a little wall up.
I took some last night because there was a motor running in the house
and I had to go out in the street because it was too much pain.
– In the house?
– Where I am staying.
– In the next room?
– Yes or upstairs or somewhere.
There was a fan or something running and that gives a strong pain
and then it goes in the nervous system and I get like this and I have to go out.
– So you feel best in a forest?
– Not in a forest but in the warm climate, like here.
This is a sensible climate. But up in the north it’s dark and grey.
And people get like that too. I like more the bright people.
– Class is enjoying your description. Your symptomatology.
– That’s good.
But it’s a very disabling thing because all my education, all my experience is out of the window.
I have a trouble to find an office for Homeopathy
because in the business section you always have some motors running; air-condition, PC...
- We are encircled totally by electricity. We cannot escape.
But I want to ask you a few more questions. Do you take fruits?
– I like fruits.
– Sour or sweetish?
– I don’t like sour fruits so much.
– Oranges?
– Yes. Especially I like peaches, bananas and cherries.
– What about fatty food?
– I don’t like fat food and I don’t eat meat.
Not because I don’t like it but in 1986 I would get very sleepy after eating beef.
And then I heard they put all the hormones so my mind just dropped it.
But I eat chicken and fish.
– You like very much chicken and fish?
– Ok.
– Sweets?
– No, I don’t like so much.
Ice cream?
– It’s ok.
– Your nails are strong?
– Usually but now they got brittle and I have a lot of in-growing toe nails.
– After Sil. this happened?
– No. It has been like that for many years.
All toes. I have to watch it.
– You have salivation during sleep?
– No.
– You have strong teeth or problems?
– Ok. I had a lot of mercury fillings which were removed in 1987.
– They thought maybe that was the problem.
– Yes, the migraines. Then I was suffering from these migraines,
very peculiar migraines, they were just coming once every 3 months.
– Now they don’t come?
– No. They come in a very mild form once a year.
– These headaches were removed after the fillings were taken out?
– Yes. Mostly gone.
– There is any metallic taste in the mouth?
– No. But previously before the fillings.
He said there was a lot of voltage in some of them.
– You never took Merc. as a homeopathic remedy?
– No. I’ve thought about it but I never...
- Did you take any Caust.?
– No, I thought about that too but I just stayed away from anything.
I thought of Caust., Sulph.,Zinc. and Merc. But I leave it up to you.
I like salt too. I buy sticks with salt on them.
– You like salt very much?
– I would give it a 2.
– What about salty fish?
– Not so much.
– The fat of the meat... definitely not. Always.
Do you remember any fears in childhood? You have any fears now?
– No. I fear heights.
– Strong fear of heights?
– Not so strong that if I see on TV there is a problem if somebody else falls down and not me.
If I go high up somewhere and I look down I don’t like that.
– Another fear? Fear of dark? Fear of being alone? Fear of people?
– Fear of sharks maybe. But that’s not in the repertory.
But only when I am swimming.
–Snakes, no?
– A little bit. I don’t like them.
A little bit black dogs. Big ones.
– The big shepherd?
– Not the shepherd but the black one.
– Doberman?
– That’s the one! Rottweiler!
– We go into the class so the class can ask you some questions.
Do you have question that you want to put to this very interesting case?
– Can you tell me if you perspire easily?
– Yes, if it’s warm. When it’s warm and there’s exertion otherwise no.
– Is offensive?
– Not.
It can be really warm and I still don’t perspire nor do I get thirsty.
– Your thirst is normal?
– I drink a lot.
– Cold water? Very cold?
– No. I don’t like cold.
– Are you very fastidious?
– Not at all. My wife is more that way.
- You don’t need any more questions. The remedy is very clear?
Good luck. Carc., Caust., Med... but he refuses.
Let’s see the repertorization. Cold and wet.
When you hear this your mind should go to Dulc., Calc., Rhus-t., Calc-p.
and your mind could also go to Nat-s.
Which is the best of these remedies?
Calc. So, it’s a very easy case.
But he said he took Calc. and nothing happened.
On the contrary he felt depressed.
Therefore Bell. is the best next possibility.
We give Bell. because of the headaches. Because of the cold feet.
Your feet are cold?
– Yes.
– I can make a Bell. case for him! I can push the questions.
What about your head? Is it hot? No.
He feels hot after the electricity. Bell.
Desire for travelling and all that.
But would you give Bell. in this case?
It’s very doubtful. I would not give Bell.
Because I am not happy with Bell.
Even the headaches that would be supporting are gone.
And the headaches had to be Bell. headaches. They were not.
And then next remedy is Con.
In Con. you need to have at least the dizziness or the vertigo.
He doesn’t complain of that.
We go to Med. Med. is a possibility because he is quite open,
communicative but in the history he denies. You know how precise I was.
If he had got gonorrhea in 1983 by 1986 he could have developed this throat problem
and then we would be sure.
Also except from better in the sea he does not have any other keynotes of Med.
Do your feet burn and stick them out of covers?
– No.
– They’re rather cold.
So, therefore Med. which appears to be a good prescription is not there.
Let’s ask for Caust.
Because of the paralysis which happened several times and the throat one thinks of.
But... there is a big but.
Caust. is better with cold wet. Maybe in this case is not so.
But we don’t have the sweets, he likes sweets, there is no aversion to sweets.
Where shall we base our prescription on Caust.?
What symptomatology? What about injustice? Tell us.
– I don’t jump up and down.
– He has some very strong symptoms of Calc-p.
That is mind, sensitivity, electricity to.
The second is wet cold weather aggravates, Travelling, desire for.
Larynx, trachea, scraping sensation, tries to clear the larynx.
Desire salt and fear of high places.
And he has also the general physique of Calc-p.
Obese type and round one.
– Calc-p. is one of the remedies that should come to mind and I believe Calc-p...
- There is one thing I would like to mention that I don’t like people walking behind me.
It’s uncomfortable. Even if it is 5 meters or more.
– Put that into repertorization. Fear of people behind.
– You say you don’t like sharks
but I think most of us here don’t like sharks either.
But is it when you are swimming can you swim out of your depth comfortably?
– Yes, but I am worried about sharks when I’m swim out in deep.
It doesn’t have to be so deep because they can come in quite shallow.
– Even when you were a child did you have fears
what was in the room, what was hidden, shadows?
– No.
– Med. Has come up. Show me Calc-p.
– Scraping throat, disposition to hawk, weakness of the memory,
mental exertion aggravates, desire travelling, weather cold, wet,
salt desire, high places... very good.
– What I thought was quite exceptional that he children diseases at the age of 31 and 41...
- So what you make out of that?
– Well, I think there must be a deep pathology lying underneath this problem.
– Why? Because of these acutes?
– No because his system wasn’t able to have those diseases when he was a child.
When he should have had them.
Therefore he got it later and that means that his system is not responding correctly.
– We have a different opinion here.
I consider those who get children diseases lucky people who have good constitution.
Unfortunately today we cannot get any more children diseases
unless you go to places like S. America or India, Africa etc.
then you will get children diseases but here you don’t get them.
According to the theory that we have been teaching here
that shows a very low level of general health.
The fact that he got shows rather a good constitution.
The fact that he did not get it in early age and he got it later is not so important.
Important is that he got it.
And according to the levels of health there are only certain levels of health
on the upper side that can get children’s epidemic diseases.
If they don’t get epidemic diseases, this is a bad sign.
Show me any autistic child who got epidemic disease,
show me any schizophrenic child, show me any epileptic child,
show me any diabetic child, show me any severely ill with systemic diseases.
Like SLE, Still disease... And cancer.
Put all these children inside an incubator with all these viruses and bacteria.
They don’t get. The same with schizophrenics while in asylum they sleep in terrible conditions.
Sometimes it was found out that in an asylum
people were sleeping in mud and not getting anything.
The organism becomes so strong, so violent, it kills all the bacteria...
These are points which I brought out in the teaching of Homeopathy.
There are all things that have to be investigated.
They have to be listened and to be investigated
so the whole attitude toward Medicine should eventually change.
Medicine has not taken the right way of thinking.
It’s a wrong way of thinking for Conventional Medicine
and the time will come when they will take into consideration all these ideas
and then they will find out the beginning.
– One more symptom I found of Calc-p.
In the rubric skin, electric sparks, sensation, as from electric, 2 marks.
– This is something different from what he says. It is an electric spark.
For instance you sit there and there is a kind of discharge of electricity.
It’s like a hit by electricity. This is true. Calc-p. is a good prescription.
There is no question but I still would like another remedy.
Which is this remedy?
I will show you because it’s difficult to find this remedy.
I will show you this M.M. from Clark.
– I don’t know if it’s important but I worked with a lot of chemicals for a couple of years.
Mainly Caust.
– Caust. is a chemical which doesn’t exist.
– Caustic soda.
– Caustic soda is not Caust.
– In petroleum industry.
– What year?
– 1977 to 1979.
– What bloody did they inject in my organism?
It was blue here. I don’t feel anything here. Just numb.
The dentist told me for 5 weeks you will not feel anything here.
First time I hear that. What was this? For 5 weeks I will be numb here.
Cannot feel anything. Don’t anybody kiss me here, I will not understand anything.
As you know there are several remedies prescribed in this case
but this is a case in which I will prescribe a remedy which I never prescribed before.
This is the first time I am going to prescribe this remedy for this nice gentleman.
The reason is because he has been given certain remedies which had an effect, especially Nat-m.
He said he opened etc.
There was definitely some effect upon his character, he was closed, now he is not closed at all.
I can be closed but not him.
The remedies had an effect but we did not have the effect of the last effect upon his organism.
We do not touch this. And maybe we have to take the first layer out.
And then go to the next remedy. Which is this layer out?
Anybody has an idea? Show the M.M., don’t show the remedy.
You showed it! The remedy is Electricitas.
This is a case in which we can say that the remedy has created the problem.
So it is isopathy but still may be the solution to the problem.
And on the occasion of that I have to say a few things.
Mostly that in order to have a remedy we have the possibility this remedy can create symptoms.
Because in our M.M. there are remedies like the Luna or the Sun
or such nonsense which cannot be used as remedies.
And then some people ask me what about electricity.
Electricity can produce symptomatology and therefore it can cure it.
Unless you have the possibility of that substance
which you are proving can create symptom it cannot cure them.
You know the idea of potentizing a song.
You put your gramophone in front of this and you have the national anthem of Danish people.
And then you give it. Such crazy things are circulated within the homeopathic profession.
This is unfortunate. Potentize an Indian song and then give it.
Headache, hysteria, paralysis, rheumatism, we go further.
Caspari is the authority for the symptom... Go down.
Nervous tremors, anxiety, fear, restlessness.
Violent headaches, palpitations, swelling of parts, are among the most prominent symptoms.
Has related a umber of cases in which the injudicious use of electric baths brought on phthisis.
In another case the chest and arms became stiff and paralyzed.
This is very interesting.
A young married woman who had general and local (uterine) electric treatment,
complained after it of feeling very heavy, as if she weighed a ton.
One patient after a bath said his chest and shoulders “felt like marble”.
The action of the remedy upon the points which he complained.
He became phthisical and died.
The paralysis caused by electricity was in several cases quickly relieved
but Morphine, both in the solution and in the potencies.
Antidoted by Morphine. I have found Phos. the best antidote.
Electricity antidotes Merc. Go to symptoms. Mind.
Let see which are the symptoms. M.M. Tears, sometimes with timidity.
Sighs, sometimes with tears; the patient cries a lot.
Restlessness, anxiety, anguish, sometimes more particularly in the chest;
internal anguish, violent agitation, timidity, fear of the approach of a storm.
Ill-humour. Involuntary laughter.
Loss of consciousness, insensibility, foolish action, errors in the appreciation of time.
Loss of memory, confusion of head... Vertigo, cephalalgia, pains in the head, sometimes drawing.
Bruise-like, pains in occiput. Crushing pressure in the forehead as from stone.
Shooting in right side of head... Painful cramps.
Disagreeable shaking. Show me the tongue.
He said he wakes up with a painful spot in the tongue. Mouth.
Sensitiveness of the tongue, esp. at the point, which is also red.
This is exactly what he had said. We don’t know if it’s red. Throat.
Constant tickling in the throat. Face. Color, bright red.
Increase of sweat on the face.
– When I am affected by electricity then I get a cold sweat in the forehead.
Urinary. He complained about frequent urination.
Sensation as though the bladder were going to burst.
Very frequent emission of urine. Involuntary emission of urine.
Urine in the morning... All this effect shows an effect on the prostate gland.
So here we are justified to start with this remedy actually
and after the antidoting of the electrical influence upon his organism
most probably some symptoms will stay.
May be the coughing, the choking, the hawking, maybe the headaches will come back. I don’t know.
But I believe that this sensitivity to electricity will be reduced by taking Electricitas.
If you find it in 30C or even 200C...
You will have to take once every day for about a period of 15-20 days
and if you feel better you can stop and as soon as you have a relapse you start and take it for 30 days.
But if you little better and little better you continue taking it for 1-1,5 month.
The problem is to find a pharmacy that will give you a correct remedy.
I think you had a case. Can you relate the case you had?
– It was a case I had.
I got a phone call from this guy I on the day I was being assessed for registration
for my society of homeopaths, that was in 1992.
I had seen him maybe 1 week before and he had the worst skin eruption I had ever seen.
For those of you who are English and old enough you remember the Singing Detective
where this guy had a very blistering and severe eczema.
My patient’s skin was purple...
- Slowly please, I don’t understand.
– Tell the essentials. Say how sensitive he was to electricity.
– He had worked in an electricity power station.
He had this horrible skin eruption and also had very severe anxiety as well.
He said if they put a shed in the middle of that field I would go and sit there.
Very anxious and terrible skin eruption.
And I was working on this case and his mother has been in the hospital,
his wife has been sick, there were other things going on and there was one thing I kept going back to,
he said his problem had started when his shift pattern changed in the electricity substation.
This is where huge voltages came through, transformed to small voltages.
So he was spending much more time exposed to this enormous voltage.
And I phoned him up. And I said are you sure this is true
because I have been in Homeopathy 4 years and I thought this remedy is absurd.
How can you potentize electricity? It’s impossible.
He said I’m sure it’s true and that seemed to be true.
I had a potency of Electricity 200C which maybe I would be hesitant to prescribe that high
but it seemed right. So I gave it to him and 1 week later he phoned up
and he said the skin eruption is worse and this was the day I was being assessed
and I said how it can be worse, it’s the worst skin eruption I’ve ever seen?
I was being assessed and I was in the phone and I was trying to speak quietly
so this woman would not hear that I was such a terrible homeopath!
I said this may be a good sign. Crossed my finger and my legs and my toes.
And I said is it anything else that’s happening.
He said the fine thing is I do feel better myself. I said ok, it’s good.
And I saw him after 1 month and the place where I was working was in a shop,
sold herbs and the therapists were back and this guy was early for his appointment
and as he got passed the shop he was waving at me and smiling.
And his skin was more than 50% better after one month.
He was much better himself and his skin went on 100% better within a few months. One dose.