Jenny first came to see on the 13th February this year.
Jenny had M.E., myalgic encephalomyelitis and she previously for 10 years had antibiotics almost every day.
– So many years? And you’re still alive?
– Sort of.
– Then Jenny realized this wasn’t good and went to see a homeopath in Liverpool
and after 2 years Jenny was given a lot of remedies.
– Let me ask her first. Why were you given antibiotics constantly?
– The symptom I presented to my doctor was just acne.
– Therefore you were given antibiotics; for acne.
– Low dose antibiotics. It was about 8 years.
– I understand now. She received a lot of remedies. What remedies can you give us the list?
– Thuja 12C, aqua pura, Carc. 200C, Gels. 200C, Ph-ac. 30C., Sep. 30C.
Then when the skin aggravated she was given Sulph. 30C., Sil. 30C.,
Hepar 200C., Ph-ac. 30C., Merc. 30C. but no results and then in March last year Jenny received Carc. 1M
and a combination of remedy of Sulph. Sil., Car-v. 9X together for 5 days.
Then she had Puls. 30C., Pod. 200C., Sulph., Carc. 1M again
and she also had some time in the last 2 years Ign. 200C
and for acute episodes Hep. And Hyper., Pyrog. and Sil. Also Ph-ac. and Gels.
– I think that’s it!
- I took her case and I took her symptoms.
I’ll tell you the remedies. Nat-m. 1LM. There was an improvement and then a relapse.
First of all she had very severe headaches which were very bad and I gave Bry. 30C.
– After Nat-m. 1LM there was severe headache and you gave Bry.
– The headaches disappeared with Bry. immediately and then I waited and needed to give Nat-m. 5LM.
– I had 2LM, then 3LM and then 5LM.
– I waited until there was a relapse cause there was improvement
and then when it began to go I gave the next LM. So we got to 5LM and again an improvement
and then the picture changed, Jenny was telling me that any kind of mental exertion was impossible
and the mental exertion really made her ill. Do you want to describe?
– I’d always been troubled by mental exertion, I’ve always been a bother but by it really did become very severe.
Just even thinking caused great pain in my brain.
I can’t remember what the pain was I seem to remember there was a pressing on my brain.
– Any effort?
– Any effort whatsoever.
– Just give me an idea. Reading a story would be an effort?
– Just a sentence, just to look at a book with words was painful.
– That was an effort?
– Yes.
– Causing headache?
– Now? Still?
– I still have but it’s a different sensation in my head.
For some periods of time I can read, other times I’m quite aversed to it.
– I prescribed for that condition.
– What did you prescribe?
– I gave Pic-ac. and that was beneficial. That made a difference.
And I kept with the Pic-ac. until the improvement leveled off and then I went back to Nat-m. 30C.
We had 30C every time with a relapse.
– I’ve written down exactly what’s been happening cause I can’t remember.
– So your memory is very bad?
– It’s not that my memory is bad,
it’s just that things changed so much from day to day.
When I take remedies I don’t know what’s happening. I just have to make notes.
My short-term memory can be quite bad though I find it quite hard to retain information being told me
and then I might hear it but it doesn’t register. After I took the first Nat-m. I started to deteriorate,
I think it was about 2 weeks afterwards. I was told to get a second one
and when I did I started having a lot of discharge.
– From the vagina?
– Yes and the rectum.
– Discharge of liquid?
– Like egg-white.
– From rectum also?
– Yes.
– And it was very offensive from the vagina?
– No smell.
– Neither?
– No smell at all. No discomfort.
– Were you examined by the doctor to see
what happens in rectum whether you had a kind of a tumor or?
- I have been about 2 years ago.
– Was it painful when they examined you?
– Not at all.
– What did they say this discharge was?
– At that time I didn’t have discharge. I never had discharge.
I’ve only had discharge since I’ve been taking the remedies.
In fact when I first took the 1LM I had discharge as well. And with the Pic-ac.
and when I got the Nat-m. 30C.
– The discharge continued.
– For about 4 days.
– Not now?
– Not now. Just when I first took the remedy.
When the discharge began I started feeling a lot better again.
– Now she is taking Nat-m.?
– Well, I repeated when the improvement started to go down.
When the improvement stopped and symptoms came back I gave one more.
– What potency?
– 30C.
– The last time that you took Nat-m. there was a discharge?
– There was the second time I took it but since then it has been away.
I relapsed again and I was told to then start plussing to shake the 30C in water
and I was told to do that until I started feeling better which I did until yesterday afternoon.
– And the discharge started again yesterday afternoon?
– No it was Sunday, Saturday evening until yesterday afternoon. The 30C in water plusing.
– And no discharge appeared?
– Not that time.
– From the beginning the gums started to discharge.
– Discharging what?
– It was a white liquid.
– Like milk?
– Milky-white.
– You know that if you are treated homeopathically,
do you realize that you are going to get back all the acne?
– Last year when I was given a couple of remedies my skin was horrendous, the acne was excruciating.
– What remedies had you taken by that time?
– When the acne flared up I was given Carc. Sorry I was given Carc.1M
and a combination remedy and then my skin...
- And then what happened after that? You let it alone or you took another remedy?
– That was when I was given Sulph., Sil., Merc., Ph-ac. after the eruption.
– And then this combination took it back again?
– No it just kept coming. Nothing happened to the skin, it kept coming and coming.
– And how it became better?
– It just on its own over time.
It’s a lot better now from what it was. I could barely talk when it first came up
because it felt like I had acid felt on my face it would burn, it was violent.
– During the time of this flair up you felt better in general?
– When my skin was extremely bad I felt very ill.
And that would go on for about 10 days,
2 weeks and then for another 10 days my skin would clear and I would feel virtually normal
and then I go down and then I was up and down like that,
from March last year up until December and then in December I just went slowly down and down
but the severity of the acne was better.
– With what symptoms you went down? Lack of energy, lack of concentration?
– The fatigue definitely and the energy was awful. Sleeping 12-13 hours and no refreshing.
Sleeping in the afternoon heaviness of the head, dullness, lethargy, apathy,
listlessness, depressed, no sense of humor, headaches.
– All these symptoms were there before the flair up?
– Yes.
– So all of them came back?
– But worse.
And every time they came they were severe as the last time.
– What happened with Sep.? You remember when you took Sep.? Was there any reaction?
– Sep. my homeopath told me at the time was just to tackle period pains.
– But do you remember anything happening with Sep.?
– No.
She said when I had pains take the Sep. I really felt no difference at all.
And there was so many other remedies at the same time, I wouldn’t know what was doing what.
I really couldn’t give an accurate feedback.
– You don’t have to report anything I see very huge package of symptoms.
Do you discover any peculiar symptoms of hers?
– Just now?
– During the time of the treatment.
– I found the case very simple. I’ll tell you the rubrics I took.
Ailments from love disappointment, very strong, mind weeping when only alone,
sympathetic, fastidious, salt desire very strong.
– You still have salt desire?
– I like salt. I don’t crave it. But I do like salt.
– You put extra salt in your food? You put.
– Yes definitely.
– Desire for open air and aggravation from the sun and dreams visionary.
– You mean you see the future?
– No.
I can’t really remember any incidents but there have been times in my waking
while an image comes into my head and the event happens,
I’ll think of a person or a thing and that person or that thing will appear quite often,
when I haven’t seen for a while.
And sometimes I’ll have written some thing, or drawn some thing
or perhaps mentioned something to somebody and that will happen.
It happened today actually. 2 days before we flew up here I was doing some drawing.
It was a paper bag which had some pattern on,
the crisscross patterns and I just liked the colors in it
and I did myself and there was a big mix with our apartment room
when we arrived last night and we had to move to a different room this morning
and there on the table there was this tartan and all the same colors,
the same pattern and that happened a lot to me.
– You take milk or you don’t like it?
– I don’t eat dairy in general.
– What about milk in specific?
– I wouldn’t choose to drink milk as milk.
I would eat it in porridge or cereal.
– Are you married?
–No.
– You’re 25 now.
– Yes.
– How is your sexual desire?
– I really don’t have any. I usually am very sexual person but...
- At the moment, no interest.
– Very very little.
Very odd occasions but... very little.
– As a child you remember having leucorrhea?
– No that I can remember or know of. I may have done but I can’t really remember.
– Jenny’s mother is here so she can confirm.
– You say you sleep 13 hours and you wake up in between or you can sleep straightaway 12 hours?
– At this very moment I’m not sleeping that length of time.
I’m actually  sleeping 8-9 hours. And I haven’t slept that long for quite a few weeks now.
But yes I do wake up through the night sometimes. Not every night.
– But you wake up always unrefreshed?
– Always.
Some days are better than others but I’m never bright and awake.
– Most of the time you feel depressed?
– Yes.
– And what do you want to do? Want to stay alone?
– Yes. I want to be on my own.
– That’s definite.
– Yes. And even coming out here to a new country, different environment, I’m not happy with that.
I want to be in familiar surroundings that I know, that I feel safe in.
– And better alone.
– Definitely.
– The last week or month the desire for salt is less, the same or more?
– About the same.
– The desire for sweets?
– I have moments where I want very sickly sweets while normally I don’t like to eat sweet things.
Normally a little piece of chocolate is fine but there are moments where I really want the sugar.
And quite often there’s another desire for sugar but that’s a different feeling,
is when I am extremely fatigued and I feel I am looking for energy
and I always crave carbohydrates.
– Your nails are brittle?
– My nails break easily but are not brittle.
They feel very thin and scratchy. And they always crack at the sides, the angle.
– Premenstrually you feel depressed, angry?
– I am not different premenstrually.
I get tenderness in my breast but other than that no.
– No swelling?
– Yes swelling and tenderness. It’s quite painful but no mood change really.
But my last period, premenstrually there was less tenderness than I’ve had
and I’m actually premenstrual now, there is a lot less than it usually is.
My period wasn’t as heavy either.
– Which are the worst symptoms for you at this moment? What makes you feel worse?
– I couldn’t distinguish between a couple of them.
I’d say the fatigue and the general malaise, heaviness, dullness through my body and my mind.
– Do you sometimes attend a discussion
and you feel that you don’t understand what they are talking about?
– If I’m very tired at the time I find it very hard to focus then and follow what they say.
I can only watch, a simple film on the TV, anything complex I just don’t get it at all.
I wouldn’t say it’s lack of intelligence.
– Have you studied something?
– I did a 4-year teacher training degree.
– Have you worked as a teacher?
– I do a little bit of piano teaching, not for what I trained.
No, I haven’t done any work. Never. I left university and then I was really sick.
I gave up. I think I kept willing myself on to get the degree and then I just collapsed.
I don’t know how I made it through.
– Do you perspire a lot or not all?
– I have been since the remedy, I had a lot of perspiration.
– When? In the night in the bed or during the day?
– As soon as I wake up in the morning right through the day.
– Early in the morning? From the bed?
– Yes. When I get out of bed.
– You start perspiring?
– Yes. But not every day.
– But do you perspire with the least exertion or under certain conditions, when anxious?
– It probably gets worse when I become anxious.
But I can perspire just sitting on my own in my bedroom for no reason.
– Do you perspire during sleep?
– No that I know of.
– So you perspire mostly after you wake up in the morning.
– Yes. From when I get up in the morning.
– Do you have any fears?
– Only of the sea.
– Be drowned?
– No I just wouldn’t like to come in it.
I used to as a child but I as I got older...
- But are you afraid of the sea to swim?
– Yes. I can watch it.
I could probably paddle in it. But I wouldn’t swim in it.
– You don’t go further.
– No.
– Why, you had an experience?
– Anything else you are afraid of?  Animals?
– No, I love animals.
– Snakes?
– I wouldn’t choose to have one on my neck
but I don’t dislike them. And I hate cruelty to animals more than I do to humans.
– At this state that you are now, do you have feelings or your feelings are also gone?
– At this very moment I am anxious. Because of this situation.
– I’m talking about the last 2 months.
The feelings are there or you feel you are not really interested actually in anything,
nothing can excite you?
– Very little does excite me now.
I can’t be very simulated by anything, even the things I used to love.
I suppose my most predominant feel is despondency and hopelessness because I feel so ill all the time.
I’m beginning to think maybe it’s too late to get better.
But then there’s always something inside me that thinks;
you’ve survived this and to survive what I have put into my body
there must be a will to live somewhere, there must be some soul vitality to pull me through.
And I desperately want to because I think there is a lot of work in the world I want to do.
– Who has diagnosed your M.E.?
– I can’t remember. I’ve seen so many doctors.
It was actually a consultant who was specialized in M.E.
He doesn’t do anything for the people he just specializes in it. That was last March.
- March 2000.
– Eating makes you feel better actually? Can you say?
Or only in the evening?
– I don’t know whether it is in the evening or because the meal’s warm.
But I think definitely in the evening but I think in the day
if I eat lunch I will feel slightly better.
– There are any other symptoms that you want to add?
– Bowels.
– My stool is generally very loose, mushy and quite a strain to go. I have to push.
– In spite of being soft?
– Yes. Not always but sometimes.
But last week for a few days after taking the second Nat-m.,
I was going to the toilet 2-3 times a day. More easily.
And since then it has been easy, it’s still very loose but it has been easier.
– This love disappointment that he mentioned was a big shock for you or you were expecting it?
– It wasn’t a shock because I ended it. But I regretted it afterwards.
It took me so long. I was only 15, 16.
– And you were so much involved with it?
– Yes.
– Why did you end it? Can you tell?
– I can’t remember. I think I felt stifle, it was pushing me down,
pressed, I wanted to be free and do my own thing and I felt quite pushed out.
But I regretted it. And since taking the remedy I just keep dreaming about him every week.
And I never dreamed about him before but I do now.
And I wake up and it’s like all happened again. I feel sick to my stomach.
–Ok.
– George can I ask Jenny one more thing? Might be helpful.
When you said you that after you see George you’d work or give up.
Do you feel like you’ve something to say?
– I feel this is my last hope.
I feel after this there’s no other avenue I can try because I have tried so many.
– With the problem that you have there is no other solution!
– From the little I know Homeopathy I believe this is the only solution if there’s one at all.
Either that or I need a miracle. But I feel almost peace.
If you told me I can’t help you I would walk away with a peace knowing that I’ve tried,
I fall long and hard.
– Was she inside the class?
– No. I can just give up and resign myself to it.
– This is not such a hopeless case. It’s not.
– She also had feelings of anger.
– Against the guy or against everybody?
– Not towards him at all. Against doctors.
– Rightly so!
– Doctors with small ‘d’.
– Because they were not able to do anything for you.
– No, because I think that I am here because of what they’ve done.
– It’s not the fault of the doctors, it’s the fault of the system. It’s much broader.
If somebody gives antibiotics for 10 years,
it is because the system allows him and tells him that’s what you have to do.
– But having said that I kept coming back to my doctors with more symptoms
and say I am concerned about taking all these tablets. Are they safe?
Are they causing any problems? They said no it’s fine, you’re ok.
Just take some more and take this and take that. And at the end I had enough.
But I also know that I made the decision to take them as well.
But I dared with the best of the knowledge that I had at the time
and I put my face on those doctors and I put my life in their hands.
I have let go of the anger now, because there was no point, it was eating me up.
– Also your feeling about being unfair?
– Feeling of being unfair?
– I feel as though, I know am a good person and I know I have talents and I know I have strengths.
I feel as though I could do a lot for the world.
I want to do so much for others, for myself,
and I get so frustrated I can’t and at times it does feel very unfair.
– What are you interested at the moment mostly?
– Getting better.
– What religion you are?
– I don’t practice a religion.
But I believe in the power of the universe.
– Did you try to find some solution in spiritual movements?
– Yes.
I’ve tried spiritual healing, going to church, talking to God, praying,
non-stop praying, I still pray but most to the world.
– Were you connected at a certain moment with spiritual people?
– I wouldn’t say I was connected I had a contact with
but I never became part of a religious practice.
– Did you ever thought of committing suicide?
– I’ve thought of it but I really don’t think I could.
Not because I think it’s coward’s way out. I know people would say that it is.
But unless you’ve been through something extremely bad and you’re not getting better,
I don’t think it’s a coward’s way out. Because this is torture.
– After this affair you never had another?
– Yes.
– At the moment you have an affair?
- No.
– You’re not interested either.
– No. I have nothing to give.
That was with my last relationship. I ended it.
It was 5 years ago because I was getting so ill. I just had nothing to give anymore.
I couldn’t do anything. I couldn’t go out, enjoy myself. So, it’s pointless.
– Thank you! We’ll analyze your case.
Here we have a difficult case.
A lot of remedies have been given and we have come to the point
where it is difficult to decide what to do further.
What is the right thing to do with the case?
– I say perhaps just to give Nux-v. and Sulph. to clear the case.
If she’s had a lot of homeopathic treatment and start again.
– You don’t say things like that in the class!
There is not such a thing as giving something to clear up.
The only thing is when you have enough symptoms to prescribe on a remedy,
you prescribe that remedy and then this remedy will clear up the situation
and will give you a better picture.
If you mechanically decide that in order to clear up a case you give this or that,
or even worse combination remedies what you are going to do is to further confuse the case.
So the case is already confused. Because we don’t have much time I will analyze the case myself
and I will have to say this that the case has been given several remedies
as you hear without giving the correct remedy.
And as you know in order to cure such cases like this one which has been created
of course due to the long time taking of antibiotics
and as you know the M.E. has several names being given.
Chronic fatigue syndrome, also post viral syndrome
because they noticed that after some virus for which they had given antibiotics this syndrome appears.
That is a syndrome which has come as an epidemic in our societies
because of excess use of chemical drugs. But we shout, nobody hears.
Nobody wants to take notice and these are the results. We have the cases of that type.
Then this case comes to Homeopathy and the homeopath gives several remedies;
Carc., Sep., Sulph... And there is a time when there is a reaction.
And after the reaction whatever brought the reaction,
several remedies were given to stop the reaction.
After the reaction combination of remedies was given. She said nothing happened.
According to me what happened was that this combination of remedies stopped the reaction
and brought back the situation, the result, the condition.
Of course she stopped it after a month or so.
But it is important when she says when I had this flair up I felt normal.
I will tell you the exact situation. She said immediately during the flair up I felt
because of this condition I felt bad. Of course.
She was discharging. But after a period, 10 days, I felt as if I was normal.
Is it correct? Is it in your notes? This is what I am talking about.
During the aggravation period of course they will say they don’t feel good.
But after the aggravation period is down she feels normal.
Felt normal because she had this aggravation.
Therefore because a constant prescription of drugs was given
we are not in the position to know what brought about that reaction.
This reaction in any case was a  curative reaction. And should not have been stopped.
Should have been left alone to continue 1-3 months and prescribe only if you could find the next remedy.
This case is a typical example what happens when you mix remedies.
You don’t know which remedy has done what and you don’t know what to do further.
So this is the situation you will be all the time in cases you don’t know the theory.
You don’t understand what’s going on.
This is the best possible reaction and you stop it.
You give 5 remedies and you stop it. She said nothing happened.
But such a reaction cannot be stopped in 1 or 2 days.
It will stopped in 10-15 days. That’s why she feels nothing happened.
Of course something happened and something very severe happened.
The combination remedies that were given afterwards they stopped this reaction.
Therefore I consider this an unfortunate period and then she comes to Ernest.
Now prescribed correctly on the idea of love disappointment together with the salt,
aversion to sun, the symptoms that he has referred. What is his mistake?
– Bry. for the headache. – No.
His mistake is that in this case, since he was prescribing on the emotional level
the health of this woman was good enough to prescribe a high potency.
He did not prescribe a high potency.
He prescribed 1LM or 2LM these are slow acting remedies and he chooses the right remedy
but he gives it in a very low potency and that’s why you saw this reaction up and down.
But what it is interesting is that the case starts now coming to a more clear situation.
Because he says after Nat-m. a discharge started from the vagina ,from the rectum,
which is milky discharge. That immediately should bring to the mind what remedy?
Carc.? Ign.? Phos.? Ph-ac.? Forget it! Med.? Forget it!
You have given Nat-m. to a case, after Nat-m. you have as a reaction milky discharge from the vagina.
What is the first remedy you are thinking? Chin.? You need re-training!
Sep. The first remedy you have to think is Sep. for God’s sake!
Nat-m. and Sep. are complementary. And after your Nat-m. the organism shows you
that this is the next line of thinking.
Sep. has to be given! But this is very simple.
I am sorry that you do not follow but this is simple. Not only that.
There you investigate that can be a Sep. case. Of course it can be!
She says I have no interest in sex at all. But this is not all.
She says in the evening I feel better. She says when I wake up I perspire.
All these are symptoms of Sep. Not only that, she says I have no feelings.
Nothing to give. This indifference, this lack of stimulation from anything.
Not really stimulated by anything. This is a state of Sep.
- Wants to be alone. – She says it so clearly I just want to be alone.
Then I feel better only when alone.
So if you open your repertories better when alone you will see Sep. is the only capital remedy there.
What else do you need in order to understand this is a Sep. case?
We don’t need anything else. What will you prescribe? Sep. what potency?
You are afraid? 7 o’clock is the party. Don’t be late!
At 10 o’clock I am going to leave! But you can continue.
What are you going to prescribe? Tell me! Raise your hand.
Ernest, be careful!
– 1M.
– Who else? Tell me.
– 10M.
– Somebody 50M? Let’s start from 30C.
Who will prescribe 30C? Nobody. 200C?
1M? 10M? I just want to see. 5. 50M? 2. CM? Nobody. What would you prescribe? 1M.
It’s wrong. Nothing of that is correct.
I persuaded you that this is a case of Sep. and you believed it!
Milky discharge, better in the evening, better alone, no desire for sex.
It’s a typical case of Sep. Yet, it’s not the time to give Sep.
Why? Because Nat-m. has not exhausted its action.
– She has slowly improved.
– Nat-m. has not exhausted its action. Why do we say that?
Because she was given a low potency of Nat-m. with the result
that the discharge was brought out to characterize, define, confirm that this needed Sep.
Now what she says is that she took 30C, no discharge.
That means still is on Nat-m., what she needs is Nat-m.
and when the discharge comes and stays that is the time you enter with Sep.
– I thought she said that the discharge was egg-white...?
– No, she said milky. Are you English?
– No.
– You are not English.
– She said milky from the gums.
– She said milky. Show me what this bloody computer is saying. Show me.
Why you changed it? You changed something again.
Inside it was different. What are you doing?
I told you to leave it like that, how it was inside.
– Ok. Inside was Nat-m. first, Sep. second.
– Thank you. Nat-m. was first and Sep. second.
Close it because I get angry when I see this.
I looked at this and said ok. Let’s go inside.
And then... Ok. But it doesn’t really matter, here we are basing our prescription on facts.
We are expecting from Nat-m. to do certain work. It’s not going to cure the case.
It’s going to open up the case toward Sep.
When the discharge comes and confirms all the other picture.
And  then there is beauty and then you see the results.
And then you see the effect of homeopathic treatment.
Otherwise forget it you just throw remedies here and there without really any effect.
Nat-m. therefore first 50M, then discharge then Sep. 10M easily.
Something that I want to tell you is concerning the repertory. This repertory information.
What happens is that they have taken all kinds of information that comes and put them in the repertory.
So we have lost the original programming and the results are not as they should be.
Because of too much input of information, of crazy information as well.
Those who use the RADAR they have to separate and they have the possibility to say
I would like to have repertorization with these authors only.
And you use the old authors. Kent basically and some other authors.
But if you use all the authors,
whoever has inserted information in the repertory it’s not reliable and you are going to get wrong symptoms.