You come from Israel, you have been born in Israel and what is the problem?
– There are 2 problems that I am coming for.
First is that since I was a child I was a constant desire to die which is very much increased this last year.
– You say this laughingly!
– I try not to feel it.
– But if you feel it, you still laugh?
– No, I’m crying.
– And when you feel it is it painful?
– Very painful.
– You took Aur.?
–No.
– You didn’t take any remedies?
– I took a lot of remedies.
– What remedies have you taken?
– I’ve taken Phos., Nux-v., Plat., Lach. and Anac. and Nat-c. and Mag-c.
and Carc., Lyc., Puls., Naja., Ph-ac. and Caust.
– You have a good memory!
– No, I wrote it down.
– It’s impressive how well you remember!
– So, you say since childhood. Do you know why?
Was there a reason, you were living in kibbutz?
– This is a good reason, but not mine!
I think it’s because I wasn’t very happy at home.
– Due to your problems or due to the problems in the family?
– In the family. I was a very happy child with a very miserable childhood.
My father died of cancer when I was 7,5. And he died after very great suffering.
And my mother who was even before a very tough woman became even tougher.
She beat us very much.
– You have another sister?
– Yes, I have. A younger brother and a younger sister.
– And she was beating you more than the others?
– Less. I was the beloved child.
– Your depression started immediately after your father’s death
or has it no connection with your father death?
– I don’t know but if you wanted me to tell
what is my first memory is the memory has my mother is telling me that my father is dying.
– She was very abrupt.
– Yes, very violent and aggressive with no sympathy at all.
– No sympathy for you or for your father?
– Both. I was alone at home and she came and I was very happy that day
because I had a very great mark in a test that none got such a mark and I went to her
and said mum see I got 100, none got 100 and she said your father died and you deal with marks, go away!
I don’t want to see you, you creep! And I didn’t cry.
I was just amazed. Oh, that happened!
– And later on did you cry?
– Yes.
– Because of that event or for another reasons?
– Because of that event when I am telling it to close people.
But because of other events but not in front of her.
Never in front of her. I never show her that I’m weak.
When she left me to sleep outside the house because she was angry I didn’t even say anything.
I went and slept outside.
My younger brother and sister used to cry and shout and say mummy, mummy and she took them back.
But I never.
– You are very proud.
– My father told the story that when I was less than 3 he punished me.
He was a very gentle man and he said you go to the toilet and you think about what you did
because you did something very wrong, you sit there and then I’ll come to call you
but because he was gentle he left the door open and he sat very close that I could see him.
And even though after one moment he couldn’t stand it and he came and said come out and I said no.
You said sit , I will sit. And I sat there 4 hours. Stubborn.
– Do you have problem with the thyroid? Can you swallow?
– When I was 12 they thought I had
because it was bigger and they checked it and said it’s on the border.
But when I was pregnant I was regularly checked and it is ok.
But this began when I was 10, I think it was because I grew up very fast.
This last year it became much stronger because I had a baby,
she is 11,5 months old and her beginning was very difficult for her and for me also.
And since then I have a terrible anxiety.
I feel that I cannot reach her, I am not good enough to do that,
I don’t know how to do the right thing.
And it doesn’t leave me even for one moment the anxiety about her.
And I don’t sleep, I feel I don’t sleep even one night.
My mind is always thinking. It began in the first months always about her.
What to do if she cried, if she feels wrong.
Now it’s not only about her but I am thinking all the time, I can’t stop thinking.
Even when I am sleeping and I am dreaming it’s not really a dream it’s like thoughts.
So I have no rest. All things are getting worse and worse.
– Do you have enough energy to go along?
– I have a lot of energy. I do everything at home and I work. I go to bed.
– But you cannot sleep?
– I sleep but I sleep bad. I’m thinking during sleep.
– If there is a little noise will you wake up?
– Yes, immediately.
I’m hearing when she is turning from one side to other
and I wake up and I see what happens with her.
So my husband sent me to sleep in my clinic jus to have some sleep!
I go upstairs and sleep there.
And it’s a little bit better but I am still with my ear all the time.
So I’m really very tired.
– That is one problem. The other problem?
– The anxiety which I never had before. I was not an anxious person at all.
– When was it started?
– When the baby was born. She screamed all the first months.
– After your labor?
– Yes.
– You labor was natural or were you given some medication?
– Just painkiller, Epidural. That’s how we call it in Israel.
– Is it a painkiller or hormones?
– No, I didn’t need it. It was very speedy and painful.
I asked for it. I couldn’t stand it.
I had a contraction one after another from the beginning,
it was very passionate. Like a storm!
– You have one child?
– Yes this is my first baby.
– And your husband is supportive?
– Very supportive.
– Are you a homeopathic practitioner?
– Just a beginner.
– You are living away from your mother now?
– No. Very close.
– But not in the same house?
– No! I left house when I was 18
and lived very far away and then I felt stronger to be close to her
and she is very good with my baby and I want my baby have a grandmother
and so I am dealing with it, it’s very difficult, she is still very violent.
– Have you ever been violent in your reactions towards her?
– Never even not in talking. I wanted to, very much, but never.
My brother and sister they beat her when she beat my sister when she was 17 she beat her back.
I didn’t do that.
- But you would like to do it?
– Yes very much! She deserves it!
– But have you ever expressed your anger verbally or in action to other people?
– Just with my husband.
– What are you tending to do, are you violent with him,
you are just verbally violent or you want to take something and throw it to him?
– No I never wanted to throw something
because I can talk so the anger doesn’t grow inside me I can say you did this,
it’s not ok and I feel terrible, I can even shout so the anger is going out but it’s only with him.
With other people I just go I don’t want to be near that.
– Are you sure you did not take Nat-m.?
– Never.
– Ign.?
– Are you sure these remedies are the only ones or you can’t remember?
– It has been 13 years since the first remedy which was not for this at all.
– Not for the anxiety?
– No, never. Just the last ones the Lyc.
and the Caust. were for the anxiety.
– And the anxiety is for a specific reason? Anxiety about the future?
Financial anxiety? About the health of the husband? Health of the daughter? Or is it anxiety which has no reason.
– There is a baby and I have to take care of her and I cannot.
This is my feeling. So she’s helpless.
This is my feeling I have to be very anxious about what happens with her
because I feel like I don’t have the natural instinct how to take care of her.
– You feel all the time you may make a mistake and this mistake can be fatal?
– Yes, exactly because at the beginning she suffered a lot and it is my fault.
– Why?
– Because she couldn’t nurse and didn’t want to take a bottle
and she was hungry and she screamed 24 hours a day.
– And you did not know what to do?
- I knew what to do, I put her in a sack and I jumped all the time for 3 months.
That relaxed her. After 5 weeks she started to eat from the bottle
and it took it another 3 months and then she became better.
It isn’t the right thing to do, jump with the baby, she has to be better
but I took her to a homeopath and to doctors and none could help her.
That was what I had to do.
– About your other activities are you confident?
That means the only lack of self-confidence is towards the child or for other matters as well?
– The opposite. I am very sure. Even too much. I am sure that I am right!
– Now this feeling or thoughts that you would like to die, what prevents you from doing that?
You think about the child, the pain that you are going to cause?
– Yes pain to my husband and my daughter. It’s my duty to take care of both of them.
I cannot leave them with that pain, it’s a terrible thing to do.
– But inside of you there is a kind of constant battle;
I want to die but I must not. Is this a constant thing?
– It’s not a constant thing because the desire to die is not all the time; it comes in attacks.
– Have you ever thought of how you would do it?
– I want to shoot myself. I have a constant desire just to do it and finish all this nonsense.
– Do you take afternoon sleep?
– Never, cannot, even if I am very tired because I am active.
I want to do things. So I can rest some time if I am very tired but never afternoon sleep.
Some physical problems; my nails and eczema here. Also this one.
And eczema here and here. Usually I have problems with my skin.
They come and go without anything.
In this I put some cortisone ointment when I couldn’t even move my hands and I couldn’t do anything.
It was very bad. Oozing and bleeding and I couldn’t even move.
But usually I put nothing and the skin problems are coming and going.
– Your menses are normal?
– No.
– Before menses you are more anxious?
– Yes.
These days between ovulation and menses all the things are getting worse till the menses comes.
I am getting very depressed and anxious and I eat quite a lot this year.
Eating all the time. It’s not an appetite.
I just have to do something with my mouth. I don’t care what it is, whatever.
I don’t feel hunger at all. I just have to chew something.
I also thought of starting smoking because I want to do something with my mouth.
I didn’t want to do that because I hate cigarettes but I thought about it.
Because chewing gum is not very polite so I cannot do it all the time. So, I am eating.
– Do you like something to eat? Sweets?
– Usually I don’t eat sweets at all. I don’t like sweets.
But nowadays, this year I don’t care if it’s sweet or not. Anything.
It’s terrible and I put on a lot of weight. Not from pregnancy; after pregnancy. 15 kilos.
– What about thirst?
– I am thirsty.
I became thirsty from pregnancy and I drink a lot. I was not thirsty before?
– For cold?
– If it is hot outside I want it to be very cold, if it is not I don’t care.
– And you drink one glass of water or 2-3 glasses at the same time?
– I drink a lot. I don’t know how many glasses though. I don’t take little water.
– Are you an ambitious person?
– This is the big question.
I think I am an ambitious person with no healthy ambition. This is the big problem.
I don’t know how to define it but yes, I am ambitious person.
– You want to be the first, the best?
– Yes. I must be!
– Concerning your temperature...
- I am cold. As the years pass I am getting warmer but as a person I am cold.
– And you are aggravated by cold or not?
– I don’t think I am aggravated but I don’t like cold weather.
If I am stepping on the floor and the weather is not very warm I cannot warm my feet.
– Your feet are cold?
– If I am stepping on cold floor it will never be warm.
– Otherwise?
– It’s ok.
– You don’t stick them out of covers.
– No.
– In what position do you sleep? Any position.
And how many hours of sleep do you sleep?
– Between 6-8.
In the summer less and in the winter more. This is usually.
Now I can sleep all day.
– Do you have normal bowel normal.
– A tendency to constipation which absolutely disappeared after pregnancy.
– What time you...
- Every morning, before breakfast.
I have to take time for this. It’s not coming very easily.
I have to have time to walk and to think with no interruption and then it comes.
– The anxiety is all the time?
– It doesn’t leave me even for one moment since she was born.
The most terrible time is noon when she goes to sleep and I am alone with her.
Being alone with her is very difficult for me.
I want someone to be there if something happens.
I sit on the sofa when she is sleeping like this and I don’t move
because I do not want anything to happen, that she will cry or something...
- What is the best time for you?
– Usually in the morning when I am waking up.
Now it’s the evening when she is going to sleep and my husband is at home.
It’s not because of the time. Anytime that he is with me is ok.
– You need only your husband or just anybody?
– I prefer my husband but sometimes I go to my mother to be with.
– You drink milk? You like?
– Sometimes.
– Eggs?
– Sometimes. No fish.
Nothing from the sea and also not the sea. I hate the sea. I don’t like it.
– The sea makes you feel bad?
– Sad. I don’t like it.
– Do you know why? Was there an experience.
– I don’t the smell, the look of it. I don’t like it.
I like to be a place where are woods very very much. Not the sea.
Here it is ok because it doesn’t smell so strong.
In Israel it has a very strong smell and I don’t like it.
– If you sleep in the afternoon how you wake up?
– Not good.
– Very bad?
– Not very bad.
– You feel like dead. – I will never wake up like this.
I will come with a little headache and heaviness and sadness but will disappear very quickly.
– How is your sexual desire? – Absolutely normal. Good.
– Do you have any leucorrhea?
– Never.
– Is there any dryness in the vagina?
– Salt? You take it normally?
– Normal.
Maybe a little less than other people. Thank you very much.
For her case we have to differentiate between several remedies. Which are these remedies?
For her case there is a possibility for Aur., Nat-s. and Staph.
You want some more? You have another idea?
For all 3 remedies we have quite good substantiation.
The way that she described her depression and the battle inside,
that she tries to resist committing suicide
because she things about the relatives
and the pain that will cause them is characteristic of Nat-s. That is true.
The fact that she says she has been so much suppressing her anger leads us to the idea of Staph.
We also know that Staph. has suicidal depression
and also prefers to shoot herself instead of jumping from a high place.
At the same time she says I am thinking so much of suicide that our mind goes straightaway to Aur.
and she confirms by saying that I am really an ambitious person, I am active, I do everything.
What is the first rubric that you want to look?
Something she clearly said.
Suicidal depression; Aur., Nat-s., Psor., Aur-m. are the main remedies.
The next you want to look is commit suicide by shooting;
Staph. is there, Aur. and Nat-s. Staph. has been raised.
Does anybody have the original Kent Repertory?
Can you tell me if Staph. is there? Suicidal depression, shooting.
Nat-s. and Aur. These 2 remedies.
And then what other symptom you look? Distorted nails.
What she is actually having in her nails is not distortion it is either a fungus
or it can be a prodromal state of psoriasis.
– I had it when I was 17 and it was fungus then.
– Ok. We have eruption, then we look eruption on, around or under nails...
Smiling when speaking. Let’s see this which is quite strong.
She will say everything with a smile. Show me this rubric. It’s interesting.
Aur. has this suicidal depression and at the same time has this smiling while talking.
– She laughs when she was talking seriously about suicide.
She laughs at serious matters.
– I don’t think.
When you have a symptoms it’s a mental symptom.
What she has is more a kind of saying things but not smiling over serious matters.
I will explain it to you. Show me smiling over serious matters.
Anac., Plat., Nat-m. Nat-m. would be a nervous laugh. Plat. would be a mental case
where she would talk seriously and then she would laugh.
It is something that worries you to see. It’s not what she had.
She is totally in control of what she says. Here is a function which is uncontrollable.
– There is also a rubric laughing alternating with desire for death.
There is only remedy.
– Which?
– Aur.
– But she does not have that.
That is not a symptom you can take for her
because what it says there is a pathological condition.
Laughing and then I want to kill myself. It is a kind of craziness.
You are so inexperienced, I can see it from your remarks, I’m sorry!
When I first started treating people, after a few months,
they brought me a boy who was crazy.
They said this boy is not feeling well, can you see him? I said yes, why not.
The boy came and I thought I could talk with him
and he started talking and talking without me asking any other question
and he spoke about what he had done and spoke and spoke at a moment I felt totally inadequate.
What is this in front of me? I cannot communicate!
There was somebody who was totally out of mind.
He was crazy, in a state of acute insanity.
You will see in my first years I could not understand what this is.
I got such a fright myself looking at this phenomenon in front of me that I could not communicate with!
He was just talking and the opposite can happen with a novice.
Because you read in books and you don’t have the real experience
you feel somebody is laughing maybe he is crazy!
Just because he is laughing you think maybe he is crazy. No, it’s not like that.
There are some symptoms where somebody is really crazy or half-crazy or whatever.
I have seen this with homeopaths over and over again,
they mistake either taking something too seriously
or somebody has cancer and they treat it for common cold.
That’s why it is important to know medicine.
You have to study clinical medicine before you can really evaluate what is happening with the case.
Otherwise it will be like the doctors who just come out of the university,
they have no experience, they send them in different villages.
Here in Greece they have to go on a village for one year to learn medicine by themselves.
What happens is that all the doctors they are sending to the big hospital
in big cities hundreds of people that had nothing.
They were not ill, they had nothing serious.
But their inexperience made them so afraid that they sent them.
On the other hand, I could hear for instance in a case of diabetic coma
where the doctor gives IV saline with sugar to bring back the patient.
Patient never came back. This can happen even with medical doctors.
As homeopaths we have to have 3 times more education than the medical doctors
to be able to evaluate a situation correctly,
otherwise both the patient and the doctor will go cuckoo.
I have seen total inadequacy. We go back to her.
Therefore Nat-s. is a remedy which can be indicated for her and Aur. is another remedy
which can be indicated for her and Staph. is another remedy that can be indicated.
All 3 remedies have good indications.
Let’s see what VES says. Aur., Aur-s., Sep., Nat-s. Why Nat-s.?
The seaside air aggravation is very interesting.
Let me see Aur. Show me Sep. Nat-m. Show me Psor. Puls.
Ambition is not is Staph.? Aur-s.? Add one; ailments sudden bad news.
3. Aur., Nat-m. as second possibility. Aversion salt.
Not aversion but... normal. Aversion fish, definitely?
– Not definitely but other things from the sea never ever.
Fish, if I have to, if there is nothing else maybe. But I don’t like it.
– Fat of meat?
– Ok, sometimes.
– Eggs?
– Sometimes.
- Soft/ hard boiled?
– Sometimes. Anything.
– If the egg is not boiled well?
– Very soft?
– Slimy.
– No!
– Worse in the sea.
- Fruits?
– While I was pregnant I had to have a lot of fruits.
But usually just occasionally.
– What was the best?
– Fruits, peaches while I was pregnant.
I was craving for peaches but just during pregnancy.
– Show me the rubric ailments from hearing sudden news.
Gels. and Calc. Calc-p. is not there.
– Is it justified to take the rubric sea air,
aggravates because she has aversion to the smell of the sea.
There is no aggravation, there is strong aversion that what she keeps on telling all the time.
That is why she dislikes the sea and everything that comes from the sea.
Is it justifies to use the rubric sea air aggravates?
– You can take it but not base your prescription on that.
You cannot say because she has that then I give this remedy.
But you can take it because she says definitely forget the sea for me,
I want to go to the woods.
You can take it but cannot base your prescription upon it.
It is not very clear. She said she wants to kill herself by shooting.
That is something you have to have.
– So she had aversion to sweets but actually now she eats the sweets.
– Yes. Also you can take it out. No problem.
– Is also there is that rubric anxiety, conscience of.
What is the reason of that rubric?
- Because she has bad conscience about the way she handles her child. This is what she said.
– And also afternoon sleep aggravation is not a very severe aggravation.
– Sure. I asked her and he has put it afternoon aggravates.
– 2 marks.
– You can even take it out.
– Thank you.
– I don’t tell them what to put! I don’t even look.
– Can you think Pall.
– Show her Pall. In Aur. is there no ambition?
There is no ambition. Incomplete repertory!
I have said many times this is characteristic of especially of Aur. children.
– I would like to know about the effect music has upon you.
– I like music very much, I am very sensitive to music,
I can cry and be happy from music and if you will put the wrong music I can be very angry.
– What is the wrong music for you?
– Very strong, disco music. I hate it.
I love music, I sing a lot and I play the piano.
I like arts, not only music. Any kind of art.
– I don’t see Ign. Do you know what my problem is here?
My problem is that these remedies and perhaps one more is in series.
Which one to start with is the question.
There is no question that there is an Aur. substratum
because she said at the age of 7 look mother I am the first!
What happened during that time, the Aur. predisposition became stronger
or another layer was imposed upon because of that silent grief.
Put ailments of silent grief.
Do we have to start with Nat-m. or Staph. before we go to Aur. or can we go straightaway to Aur.
because she has definitely the main points of Aur.
which is suicidal depression but she does not want to jump from high place.
That would make me immediately say that Aur. is the uppermost remedy at the moment.
When she says shooting, though Aur. has shooting as well,
when I ask her what is her best time I expect to hear to hear
that the best time is in the evening when Aur. eases in evening
but she says morning time is my best time and in the evening
because my husband is there.
Another thing Aur. by itself can manage, does not need the help of others,
does not need to have support from somebody.
They are self-determined and self-efficient people.
She says I am self-sufficient very much but except of this area.
Do you we have to treat this area?
Do we have to take away this before Aur. picture becomes clear?
And if then if what I am thinking is correct what is the uppermost remedy
that will be best for her, Nat-m., Staph. or Nat-s.?
The type of battle she has is very characteristic of Nat-s.
but I am not sure if this is so because I put these words into her mind.
I said, do you feel that and she said yes exactly.
But I still doubt when I ask a question
because a little one here was asking why do you ask direct questions,
when you put a direct question and you get an answer it will depend on the type of the answer you get.
Oh yes! This is an answer you can rely on.
Yes, yes... Uh-oh. Yes... uh-oh. Yes. Forget it!
It depends on how strong the answer you get is.
The time you touch the real symptom the idea of the patient is how did he know?
I am a magician! If you spot the remedy and then you ask a keynote and he says yes,
my God that is the time you can rely on that symptom.
But if you get yes or there is little bit of hesitation...
She gave me an answer which is Nat-s. quite strongly but still...
I also know another thing about Nat-s; Nat-s. people are otherwise quite balanced.
Except of this particular time when they get tired of life and they don’t want to live.
Forget for me there is no place.
But at the same time they think if they do
it they are going to give such big problems to their relatives and they won’t do it.
And then the next moment they go again and think they cannot stand it.
– I didn’t have it before I had a family. It’s only because I am a mother.
Before when I thought about committing suicide it wasn’t
because of my husband or my mother that I didn’t do that.
It is only because now I have a baby. It changed.
– There is another thing about her in the point of view of psychoanalysis which is very interesting.
She is not certain that she is a good mother, doing well.
Because her mother has put into her mind the doubt into her mind through her behavior.
That the mother can misbehave and don’t understand what is doing, killing the child.
You are killing me and you don’t understand!
This is why she was crying all the time.
Now what has happened is the doubt whatever I do
maybe I am killing my child and I don’t realize it!
She has the same problem. She says yes.
– What about her anger that she was having against the mother
when she was not treating well.
She was still keeping it, she didn’t show that to the mother. That’s suppressed.
– That’s why we said the possibility of Staph. is a big one. We’ll see.
– There are some good symptoms which I gathered for Staph.
Number one anger suppressed, anger with silent grief,
and anger with mortification and indignation because when she wanted to speak to her mother
about the good marks she was immediately mortified with the statement and the behavior of the mother
and there is a rubric fear bringing up his family.
Your family as a child could be part of the family, Staph. is a remedy in that rubric then,
grief silent laughing involuntary, sleep disturbed due to thoughts and sleeplessness
due to activity of thought, suicide by shooting, suicide disposition and desire for death.
All these symptoms are covered by Staph.
– That’s what we have been thinking. Correct.
– Show me silent grief. I have a problem.
Let us say the uppermost layer is Nat-m.
For a person to be Nat-m. has to have some closeness which she doesn’t appear to have
though she says she kept anger inside.
She is not a close person, she spoke easily about her emotions,
about what is happening inside her with great presence.
I have this problem for Nat-m.
- Nat-m. has no ambition.
– Who said that? That is not true. Don’t believe that.
Ailments from mortification. Yes, you can say so.
For Staph. what is the problem? Staph. has a problem showing anger
and during the anger if it is so much she cannot retain it she has the tendency to throw things and hit.
She expresses her anger in her relationship but with her mother... forget it.
Why she expresses her anger to her husband?
Because he loves you, you released me from saying that.
So you know it very well and you know you can do that and no consequences.
He will forgive you, he will say it is her character.
– I don’t do it so often.
– But if the occasion arises you have to do it.
It’s not pure Staph., Nat-m., Aur., Ign. Other remedies? Sep.
I don’t believe. The Aur. is the strongest.
But is Aur. the uppermost or we give Aur.,
nothing happens and then we have to change?
Show me also the rubric mortification.
You said this eruption you have it since childhood.
– In my nails I had it first when I was 17
and then I took pills and it passed away and then it came back again after I took Puls.
And the eczema is something I have since I was very young
and it changes places all the time and all my family has this kind of problems.
– When you didn’t show your anger to your mother were you afraid of being reproached?
– Not reproached. Beaten! I slept outside.
– Staph.
– I would like to ask 2 questions.
Do you like perform before an audience?
– I feel very good.
– Now, you messed up the whole thing! I used to be an actress and a singer.
– That means you can be trained to overcome certain sensitivities or shyness.
– I never had shyness.
Since I was a child I used to sit on the table and sing for everybody and dance and make jokes
and be the center of every place I have been at.
– Do you get offended easily?
– I think very easily by people that are important to me. Yes.
– You see how difficult it really is to make a decision.
When I saw her she said spoke 2 words and I asked have you not taken Aur.?
It’s very strange.
But if you dig you may find out that you may be right or wrong maybe first this and then that.
Classical Homeopathy is not easy
because it’s such the precision you need to have the effect otherwise forget it!
– In spite of being in a suicidal depression she has this fungal infection.
I think this is a sign of good health.
Is she not showing a clear picture of a remedy
because even in a suicidal depression her organism is having this fungal infection...?
- I feel he is right.
Because when I am not ill I feel like I am the healthiest person in the world
and when I’m sick I’m totally depressed.
– I’d like to ask 2 questions.
When you are angry before you start shouting?
Do you have any physical signs of anger?
– No. If I feel it is a person that I can show my anger,
I just show it and if not I’m leaving and maybe crying.
– But is it true that you show anger only to your husband?
– Only to my husband.
– I had 2 husbands. This is my second.
And also to my first one.
Also to my husbands because I feel very safe there and very loved.
I know I can be myself. I can show everything not only anger.
I wouldn’t also cry in front of my mother. Never.
– The second question I have is
do you have any problems with infections of your eyes?
– No.
– I believe that as a girl she did not have the depression of Aur.
but she had the possibility of being an Aur. case.
Now this blow came and I believe due to the thyroid effect that she became a Nat-m. case.
The responsibility of the child is the last thing that we have to deal with.
We have to find the remedy that has this anxiety with dealing with a responsibility.
Which is like Bar-c. Bar-c. doesn’t want the responsibility.
In that case we have a very good reason why she behaves like that.
The mother embedded in her psyche that you can inflict so much pain to the child unknowingly
and this is what she is going through.
Therefore I consider that the remedy we have to give as uppermost is neither Aur.,
nor Nat-m. is a remedy that will have a kind of lack of self-confidence
or lack of undertaking the responsibility.
From a very ambitious and sufficient person she has become insufficient in this respect at least.
Out of the 3-4 remedies which is the remedy that is the weakest in this respect.
Staph. So the treatment must start with Staph.
and then most probably Nat-m. as a second possibility or Nat-s. Nat-m. and Nat-s. can be exchangeable.
And finally we can reach the layer of Aur.
So Staph., very high, hoping that she will start shouting to her husband as well and be completely suppressed.
- I want to say 2 things. I think of Pall.
And if you can see now in the list it’s coming up.
I want to check the remedy with you and I want to ask her one more question.
You say that you love to be in company, you love company very much.
Does it exhaust you after a while?
– Usually the opposite happens.
– Show me Ign. Show me Staph.
The thing is as you can see really if you study the case,
that the symptoms may be so similar from one remedy to the other.
The point is what kind of analysis,
what kind of evaluation we are doing in these particular symptoms.
You have to take some symptoms which you can base a prescription upon.
Here there was a very difficult differentiation point
but I feel that as she says shooting is so strongly
and experience shows that Staph. really wants to shoot herself
and also the fact that she admits she has suppressed her anger for years,
there is no question about that.
That means if you give Staph. will she be released totally? No.
To a certain extent and then comes Nat-m. which will help her a little bit more
and finally will come Aur. So Staph. 50M for a start.
You can ask some questions actually.
– I wanted to say that I saw her a few days ago sitting and singing
and she was the center of us, not like Staph. Absolutely not.
– But I’ll tell you something.
Her character, her personality is very extrovert.
Such extrovert personality as she has to be kept inside such anger,
that fact points to the possibility of Staph.
because she is not a sensitive and very closed person.
She is extrovert, strong yet and she has this kind of indignation.
I don’t want your sympathy.
You go to hell I will stay here in the bathroom till my next life.
This is a behavior which can be Nat-m., Staph. and Aur. also.
But the fact that she keeps the anger, she says I want to kill my mother very gladly.
I hate. And she cannot express any of this anger,
after Staph. she most probably will go and tell her mother what she thinks about her.
You don’t believe? Let’s see what you will say next time.
She will say I could not believe I went to my mother and said you’re a bitch!
Ok, don’t do that! I don’t advise you because your mother will come to me!
When we give a description of a remedy in the M.M. we actually describe what we call the constitutional type,
the full type of Ign., Nat-m., Staph.
But as I have explained many times, the full type is somebody who is quite healthy,
needs one remedy and that one remedy will take away everything.
This happens seldom. The most usual is to have layers.
As you describe here your thought why not Ign.?
It is true, in a case of constitutional Aur. some grief comes upon and that changes into an Ign. pattern.
And this Ign. pattern may stay for years.
And if this person goes into a state of let’s say pneumonia, mistreated,
it may after the pneumonia develop a picture of Kali-c.
And this picture of Kali-c. will stay there so when you start the treatment
you have to give Kali-c. then Ign. then Aur.
That means the two layers that were corrected, they came after.
The Aur. or Sulph. underneath here or Calc.
Let us say you have this person with these 3 remedies.
He doesn’t take homeopathic treatment and then grief comes
and upon the grief is imprinted a state of Ign.
Another example that you’ll understand easier.
Let’s say you have a case where a person got a concussion,
felt down and hit and had a big trauma for which he needed Arn.
But never got Arn.
He comes to you 10 years after the trauma and underneath may be a Sulph. or Calc.
but unless you give Arn. first, you give Arn. 50M then the case opens up.
Then the Arn. level that was imprinted after the trauma must come out first and then go deep.
Unless you give the Arn. you are not going to help this particular case.
And you know that very well, right? That same with Nat-s.
Somebody has an injury and then he gets depressed and then he goes into a state of Nat-s.
It is after the trauma, after the concussion.
Then you give Nat-s. and then underneath is Sep. or whatever.
So we have cases in which a layer is imprinted and stays.