You were the strange case of Electricitas (Elec.)
– Yes, that’s me!
– What happened?
– I took Elec. 30C last July every day for one month.
First I stopped drinking coffee and then I got some headaches
which I usually get when I have a remedy.
During the first week there were aching pains in lower extremities, worse sitting.
The sensitivity to PC and TV was maybe little bit better. Happens with other remedies.
Then I had the pain between the shoulder blades which I had before in the back condition.
It went away. Then some cervical, lumber pain which I also have had before.
One strange thing; urination pattern changed. Many times in the night I would go back and forth,
now only in the morning 6-7 a.m. And this has sort of remained since then.
Then swollen gums which I had before. One day I woke with the right arm partially numb
which I have had before. There were some peculiar spot pains, one here and then one right here,
then in the liver area. This I’ve had before too.
Then my step son at the time bought one of these ghetto blasters. This boom boom music boxes.
And that one had some kind of frequency that would go into the midbrain
and I could not stay in the house. So, I had to go away.
– I don’t understand this.
– Ghetto blaster is a big radio you can carry it around and makes lots of noise.
And people like that. They can carry it around or keep it in the house. Plays CD, radio.
Music machine. This was a big one, for kids.
– It’s called ghetto blaster?
– Yes, poor district in America. Blaster means boom boom. Guys go around with this on the shoulders.
– It’s a kind of terroristic device.
– So I was driven out of the house
and who would have known that this little thing would cause that
my poor stepson had to suffer from this. Then I had very much dreams.
Like a TV series dreams at night. Very bright like watching TV. Nothing special.
Then after 30 days by nervous system was bzzzz like this from the Elec. The nerves were buzzing.
Then I stopped taking it and my electric sensitivity was the same.
It wasn’t anything special affected. Then I wrote you an email and we took Elec. 200C.
– From which pharmacy?
– This was from Ainsworth in London.
I got them to send me a whole number of potencies.
So 200C, then of course the first day I could work 50% better on the PC which I work sometimes,
I do some translation. And then after that to same.
I started taking it on 20 th September and then 10 days later, 30 th September,
I would get these pains spontaneous without being able to see any source.
And it was very painful so I took some Hyper. which maybe I shouldn’t have done
but I couldn’t go outside because of the lights out in the street,
I had to stay inside because it was very painful. And I didn’t want to go to the woods where is dark.
Not that I am so afraid of the dark but it’s no fun sitting under a tree.
Anyway, the urination pattern was permanently changed. Sleep at night and at 6-7 a.m. I have to go.
I wake up and go to urinate. That was Elec. and I waited till November.
I sent an email and said my picture was back to what it usually is except for his urination thing
and then I was going to go to Brazil in December.  I didn’t want to start taking anything.
You said to take Verb. 30C every other day for 12 times. Because going on the plane,
it was much pain from TV and much exposure down there.
Then my father died I come back and I had to go to Norway.
So I started to take 1 st January Verb.
There was not much reaction. Meanwhile I went to Denmark and then I had to come back,
my mother was alone, so I had to care her of her.
And then my wife decided she doesn’t like me anymore, so I stayed there in Norway.
She said not to come back to Denmark. I was having a little clinic in Denmark.
– Where do you mostly live?
– I was living mostly in Copenhagen for 15 years.
Now I am living in Norway, in a little town.
– Not in Brazil?
– You have nothing to do with Brazil?
– Not anymore! My ex-wife is from Brazil. But at the moment I’m staying in Norway.
At the end January  I was getting sensitive to some mobile antennas that there are in this town.
I had taken Verb. and I couldn’t know if could sleep at night.
So I took Hyper. and sent the email and we dropped Verb.
Then in February I got a message to take Chin-s. for 12 days.
I thought it was very interesting because my father is born in China but also had malaria!
– That’s more interesting!
– That’s just a joke.
0He also has had Indian sprue. He suffered of it all his life. I took it.
In day two there was a dream, violent sea and a beach, old ships of old time
and some amorous type business going on too
and then after a few days burning pain in the face and the forehead, burning pain in vertex,
I am getting more and more sensitive to yellow light.
My mother she was staying in the house then I took down to 25 watts
and then she found her place where she can be and so and now I am alone in the house
and so I turn off the lights in the evening because burns. Street lights burn.
Any ray burns. So yellow light is like sensitive.
Otherwise no big changes except of these kind of symptoms that I mentioned last year.
– All other is the same?
– Yes.
It’s the same basic picture except I was a bit depressed from losing the marriage
but I get used to this. It’s the third time that happens,
so… And that was February, finishing 18 th April. It’s the last day I have here.
But I am sensitive to the cellular towers, otherwise the house is ok. Beside the yellow light.
– You feel these cellular antennas!
–They have next to the hospital in the city where I live. 200m away.
But I don’t feel very much. It’s mainly when I am in one place all night sleeping
and in the morning is burning.
– And the burning is in the face or the whole skin?
You always show the face and the face seems very red. Have you ever taken Bell. before?
– Yes, sure for small colds. 12C.
But the funny thing is that I had twitching on the left side,
now I have a little bit more on the right side. A little burning pain on the right side.
But it’s 99% on the left.
– On the left side is burning and the twitching or only the twitching?
– Both. There is not much twitching.
Very little but it’s here around the eyebrow and also on the right side it’s on the eyebrow.
And the burning is like you scrap your elbow on the street.
– So strong?
– Yes.
It can get so strong like putting a cigarette there if I hang around very long.
For example on the plane if someone sits behind me with a laptop
or next to me it will start to burning in a spot like somebody holding a cigarette.
Then I move, I go to the toilet and stay there in the back of the plane.
– For the whole flight?
– Yes.
So there’s the symptoms when I get exposed to electricity is there’s burning
and then loss of concentration and lots of thirst.
If I start getting thirsty then I look around where’s the device? I am not usually thirsty.
– The water must be cold or anything?
– Could be anything but I like in the middle.
Can be cold, it’s ok but I prefer a little warm.
– And you will drink the whole glass?
– If I drink, I drink a lot.
– 2 glasses?
– I can drink a whole liter if I want in one go. But I seldom drink, even when it’s hot.
But after continued exposure the concentration goes
and eventually I will go to coma which had happened in my anatomy classes.
Then I get very restless legs, general restlessness
and then I have to go away because then it will get start getting into the midbrain. Nausea.
In Brazil I was near these cellular antennas in somebody’s house for 1 hour
and I started developing nausea and dizziness from that. Otherwise I am in pretty good health.
– Do you feel better in cold weather?
– I hate cold and wet weather.
That’s why I don’t like so much to live in Scandinavia. Cold, humid. That’s very bad.
The worst. I want to buy an airplane ticket and go to some warm place. It’s really strong.
– Do you have any fear?
– Not so much.
As I said last summer I don’t like if someone is walking behind me. But it’s not a fear.
I don’t really register any strong fears.
– High places?
– That I don’t like.
I feel very uncomfortable. That’s always been there.
– From last year you are still the same weight or you put one some weight?
– Maybe 1 kilo more since I went to Norway because there they eat a lot.
– Can you see in TV if there are wars and cut legs?
– No problem.
– You can see that. Also you can help in case an accident happens and there is some blood?
– That’s ok.
– No problem.
You were in the army some time?
– I’ve moved so much in my life but then I was in Norway
and they said now you have to be in the weekend soldiers. I liked that very much.
They made a sergeant and I used to win the war games every year, get the medal.
I like that! Also startling in sleep. This has happened, before more. It can happen.
- There is any salivation?
– Not really.
– You tolerate onions?
– Yes I like onions.
– Where you vaccinated?
– I’ve been vaccinated standardly I think.
I had TB vaccine and I’m sure I’ve had smallpox as a child.
– When you traveled to Brazil you have to be vaccinated?
– I didn’t take vaccination but one time I had to work down in Libya in the oil business.
I think I got a vaccination there in 1978… But I had no reaction.
Never had any reactions to vaccinations.
– Warts?
– Yes.
I have some that appeared here, occasionally, and then it falls off.
I’ve had some on the fingers.
– Fell off by themselves?
– Yes.
Somebody told me to put morning spit. You know when you wake up in the morning.
– You did it?
– Yes.
– And then they left.
– Yes. But I never took any medicine.
– I see, yes. I see some light. Let me see says the blind man!
– Let’s see if this is the correct light or the bad light which affects you!
– When I was a child I had lots of colds and then we moved to a warm climate.
When I was 7 or 8 I had many colds in Norway and we moved to South America and then I got well.
– When did you move to S. America?
– When I was 7.
– Up to that time you had lots of colds and then you moved and then no colds anymore.
– Nothing! Since then my health was very good!
– And how many years now you have these problems now with the electricity?
– 7 years.
– I was hoping it will go away by itself after 7 years but…
- Were you bothered by the electricity of thunderstorms?
– No. I like them very much but after having taken Elec. 300C for a month,
there came a thunderstorm and then a big headache came and then the thunderstorm went away
and then headache went away.
– That happened one time?
– One time, after having finished taking Elec. 30C for a month.
Otherwise I like thunderstorms.
– In bed you cover your feet?
– Yes. I do.
I am a little bit chilly in bed. And I snore, I’m told.
– Is it possible that your feet are cold and sweaty at the same time?
– No. I don’t really get sweaty feet at all.
– Do you get sweat in the night when you sleep?
– I can.
– Which area?
– The chest and the back and also can be the head.
If I drink some alcohol sometimes during the night come out like that. But not all the time.
– Going upstairs is easy for you or you go out of breath easily?
– No. I walked up the Washington monument in Washington.
I was very tired when I went up but it’s a very tall building. There’s one peculiar thing;
My ex-wife was studying some acupuncture and told that there was this point here which ameliorate.
So , when I was on the plane and going to Brazil for 14 long hours
and they lowered down the TVs from the ceiling and a terrible pain started,
then I was lying in a corner pressing here and it would ameliorate 30-40%.
Pressing this point here. So I used that when I had to sit on a course and it starts to hurt.
It helps 30%. But I am sure it is not on repertortories.
– When did he say restlessness to legs?
– Only when exposed.
I have 2 symptom pictures; when there is no stimulus and one when there is stimulus.
– And when there is stimulus you have
- Extreme restlessness of legs.
– Ok, we go analyze!
It’s the first time I prescribed Elec. It was a very big stimulus.
It’s so clear the symptom that is aggravated by electricity that we have to try Elec. first.
Has Elec. acted in this case? This is the case where even if you have old symptoms,
he mentions he had an old symptom in the back etc. No change.
Essentially there was no change because in order to say
that an old symptom has come back you have to have at the same time the amelioration in energy,
emotionally etc. So the fact of the change of urination is no good because it changed a symptom.
The frequent urination in the night most probably is due a little swelling of the prostate gland.
Now with this it can be less by different other factors except of Elec. Verb. did nothing
and also Chin-s. did absolutely nothing. Here we are facing the same problem, exactly.
No effect. And we have to take a new decision. That is his chance.
What is the decision? Does anybody have an idea?
Show me the symptoms that you have taken and I will give you my idea.
I think fear of high places you have to put it twice at least. Or vertigo high place?
– I don’t get vertigo just fear.
– Pain burning in the left side, thirst for large quantities,
frequent urination in the night, falling asleep jerking of the extremities on falling asleep,
restlessness of legs, perspiration in the night. Artificial light aggravation.
It’s interesting that we have this symptom and we look upon that. Show me the symptom.
Which are the remedies that have been recorded as having strong aggravation?
Phos., Puls., Merc., Lyc., Con., Dros., Calc., Glon.
Now you know the remedy I am going to give. Glon. Why? Show me Glon.
Fifth… Perspiration in the night. Put it in cervical region. Show me why Glon.
Do you like Glon.? He comes from Sweden where Glon. was discovered? Norway? It’s close!
– I just wanted to say that my health when it went bad it started with terrible migraines.
– I was joking about Glon., don’t make it serious now!
So I was thinking uh-oh he is going to give me Glon.!
Probably I will be getting these terrible headaches back!
– I was joking because Glon. is much worse with heat! Cannot stand at all heat.
Of course we know the sensitivity to sunlight but this is not your case.
You are a chilly person and hate cold weather, especially cold, wet weather.
– I love the sunlight.
– So how I can give you Glon.?
I told you I play games because I make you think!
Once we forget about electricity we have to go back to basics.
What are the basics here? He is chilly, fear of high places,
worse cold and wet, he is also sensitive to light which paradoxically we see Calc.
It’s capital. And when I ask him do you perspire in the night he said yes.
This is the area of perspiration of Calcareas, esp. for Calc.
So we have a lot of symptom of Calc. And we cannot go away from it and give Glon. now.
If we give him Calc. and develops eventually the old symptoms of headaches
and especially if he gets warm
and has sensitivity towards weather then we may be thinking of giving him even Glon.
But at the moment his symptoms do not indicate Glon.
in spite of the fact that it may be appearing there.
Terrible headaches may be not Glon. after Calc. but Bell.
As a complementary to Calc. if he develops strong headaches we may be thinking of Bell.
and Bell. He also has red cheeks and looks like Bell.
but at this time we don’t want to give Bell. We want to give Calc.
And please be better! You are so nice and people and people have a placebo effect.
If you see one of my cases… I mistreated according to the class.
The patient was crying for 3 hours and many people of the class got up
and said you have mistreated this case! Because interrupted her.
I said calm down… I wanted to make a decision! I wasn’t playing.
I wanted to cure her so I was quite cutting. .The whole class wanted to kill me.
I said ok. In spite of the knowledge of everybody I have been so nasty to that case,
I will prescribe this remedy 50M. Very difficult case, complicated.
She had taken half of the M.M. I said 50M of that remedy and see what happens.
You will see on video because all this is recorded.
Next time she said I am much better. She was a different person.
So it was not a placebo effect. And here is the proof,
she would like to come back and say the whole class I’m worse
and the whole class would kill me.
Because it’s natural if you can find a better remedy the teacher…
Look what I am! I am a great prescriber!
So, all this students wanted to be better than the teacher.
This is classic, not Classical Homeopathy!
It’s a classic symptom of homeopaths! Wanted to be better than the teacher.
Here he comes he likes me very much and he has seen all these cases that are cured...
by me, I stayed like this with no effect...
Because the remedy is wrong. Let’s see now with Calc…
- He talks about 3 divorces and I cannot see emotions.
If I had lost 3 wives I should cry I think!
– It depends if he wanted to lose them all or not!
– I didn’t see any emotion and there is a possibility for Ph-ac. when if you look in the M.M.;
face, burning spots Ph-ac. is the only remedy.
– This is not a keynote on which you can ignore all other symptoms
and prescribe on that. But the fact that he lost his wives…
I have lost my wives, I am exhausted, I don’t want to live,
I am totally indifferent to life… It’s a different picture.
Here I can see a man who has practically faced life after losing 3 wives.
Maybe he wanted to lose 2 of them. Maybe the third one he didn’t want to lose.
But the 2 maybe he didn’t mind losing. It’s another way of having a girlfriend.
You are married, in the meantime you make a girlfriend and lose your wife.
But whose fault is it?
– Can you give us some reason why you didn’t consider Calc-p.
– On the first place?
– Yes, anyway. Or did you consider it at all?
– One difference is that Calc-p. doesn’t have the problem from high places.
We haven’t seen this. Either very seldom or not at all.
In Calc-p. we also don’t see the perspiration during night
and especially around this area. Also in Calc-p. we have some different desire
and aversions.
– There which I was thinking is Con.
Because fear of high places, snoring, the artificial light aggravates,
urination frequent night, and cold weather aggravates.
If you want I’ll repeat. He is better in sunlight,
worse cold wet weather, artificial light aggravates, urination frequent night,
respiration snoring and fear of high places
and also while interviewed there was a constant scraping condition in the larynx.
This is also of Con. While he was talking to you he was constantly clearing his throat.
– What is the position of Con.? So you would give Con. I’ll tell you something.
Though Con. is worse in cold wet weather, he stresses this point
and we really have to have a remedy which worse cold and wet.
He stressed that point quite a lot.
– It’s the worst modality.
– And Con. is not there.
Another point which is very important also it’s the perspiration in the night around that area
which we don’t have in Con.
And the third point that in a case of Con. you would have some kind of vertigo lying in bed,
getting up from bed, turning in bed etc. In such a case we expect to see this.
So, don’t forget that all these remedies which are there have his symptoms!
Arg-n. has a lot of his symptoms. Show me how many. Cold, wet weather also…
Why not Arg-n.? Because the remedy has to catch the highlights of the case.
Clearing the mucus of the throat is Calc. but also Med.
Actually the last time, when we repertorized, Med. was coming as the first remedy.
But it was so strong that I really wanted to see whether such a remedy
which needs someone to be very careful to produce because you have to put the sugar very close
to a very great transformer of the electricity
where you know really there is electric currents going on through.
If you leave somebody sleep there for a few days I believe
he will become sick under an electric transformer.
A powder there maybe will have some effect in the molecules
and then you can potentize from there.
It is still a question mark for me unless Philip he has related to me a case
that was really impressive and that’s why I tried Elec. for this case.
– I wonder about frequent urination at night he didn’t have the last year.
– Now I have frequent urination at night. I am staying at this camping place
and it’s very inconvenient to get out of this little tent, I have to go many times at night.
– As I said in his case we have to find a remedy which is sensitive to cold and wet,
that has fear of high places, sweat around this area during sleep
and we have to find a remedy which has artificial light aggravation.
Even if we didn’t see Calc. in that rubric or if we did not have that symptom,
still most indicated remedy must be Calc.
– But may I tell you something; Calc-p. has also the fear of high places
and it has something else Calc. doesn’t have. Hawking during speaking is only Calc-p.,
which is also for wet and cold weather.
– It’s not only Calc-p. Where did you find it? Hawking.
There are quite a lot of remedies and a lot of remedies scraping throat.
Med., Caust. also has this. A lot of remedies have this mucus. What did you say about sweets?
– Scandinavians? I prefer Latin type! I like chocolate! That’s another kind.
Sweets, they’re ok. I eat now and then chocolate bar but it’s not a big craving.
– What about Scandinavian sweets? Greek sweets?
– I tried some chocolate with ice cream. Quite good.
– What about fat?
– I don’t like it,
I would throw it far away to the cat.
– What about smoked meat?
– I don’t eat so much meat but I used to like smoked meat.
– What about meat?
– I don’t eat meat. Chicken
– Eggs?
– I like eggs.
– Fish?
– Quite alright.
– Now you are a vegetarian?
– Semi because it’s too inconvenient being full.
– So you can eat some chicken.
– And fish, turkey. Smoked turkey is fine. Or lamb.
If I am very hungry I eat everything.
– Ok. Calc. 200C. Take it immediately, now and see if there is any reaction.