What I want from Andrew is to give me a general impression of what happened
and then we can go to details and find out...
- 3 of July she was given Verat. 200 and next day Verat. 1M.
She slept for 1 hour and immediately developed this constipation, very hard and large stool.
Very difficult and painful. And that remained the same since.
Then she had an aggravation, slept for 13 hours, vomited and had a fit.
– Didn’t go to the hospital.
– It wasn't severe as usual.
When she came through this I think she started to show signs of genupectoral position, knee-chest.
– I would find her on the floor in this position in the house.
The main thing was she slept longer than normal.
Even in the day, she would sleep for an hour and a half.
– When she developed the knee-chest position, how long after Verat. was it?
– First week. After the aggravation. Then I think in August, not so many changes.
– The only thing that I can see here after 20 days developing very offensive diarrhea,
vomited bile and for a few days she had diarrhea and the stool became not so big.
On the end of August she was irritable, clingy, bearing head, tantrums.
On the 22 of September cold, dry cough started.
Then she started having an acute. Temperature raised up to 38C.
– Convulsion.
– A really bad convulsion. It lasted an hour.
– And when she had bad convulsion, in October?
– Beginning of October, then contacted you and you said Verat. 200C.
– You did not give 1M here. Only 200C.
– 8th of October.
– Then fever continued and reached up to 41,8C.
– 2 fits and vomit.
– And she had convulsions with vomiting and Bell. was given, 30C, only one dose?
– Yes, only one dose.
– And she kept on the knee-elbow position
and on the 30th of November was given Med. 200C.
– Yes, we contacted you again.
– In the analysis I have said most probably the next remedy will be Med.
After that she developed strabismus.
– It became worse.
– Stool frequent already on the 3rd of December, 4 stools a day.
Stools extremely large and painful.
Can only pass the stool standing because sometimes it was like a tennis ball.
– I think we had a follow up appointment...
- And what happened with the ear infection?
– Her first perception was that she was much better.
– Yes, she was talking more, she was like in awakening.
She responded better and understood what you wanted her to do more.
And in January everybody, even the teachers in her nursery said that she was communicating better.
– Then she developed acute.
– Cough, fever but no fits after Med.
– And she had quite a few fevers before the ear.
– Before the otitis developed, in January.
– In January 2002.
– Very painful, crying and clinging at night,
it went on until we spoke again with you.
– She had fever with very strong thirst for cold drinks, I suggested Phos. and nothing happened.
I think you tried Puls. We contacted you and you said to take Puls. 200C.
– I see Verat. is never repeated in 1M, where in the beginning we gave 200C and 1M, you repeated only 200C.
If you repeat a lower than the first, it will not be acting.
But anyhow, nothing happened with the otitis?
Otitis developed more and more severe, discharging a lot of pus.
– After Verat. the pain went and then the discharge started.
– So we said wait.
– For how long?
– 3 weeks.
– For 3 weeks the ear was discharging and then what happened?
– I think another acute with vomiting and then the ear became painful again.
– We gave her Verat. in the evening because the vomiting wouldn’t stop
and the vomiting happened every hour for 6 hours throughout the night.
– So you gave Verat. 200C again on the 1st of February, and then what happened? Nothing.
– She got worse with the vomiting.
– What about the ear discharge?
– It got worse.
It turned a nasty dark green and the ear started to swell and protrude out of her head.
– Was it smelling badly?
– No.
– And then you couldn’t wait anymore.
– No, because she hadn’t been eating, we had been waiting for 3 weeks and she hadn’t been eating properly
and she lost 3 kilos in weight and it was just a miserable little girl.
– Did you take her to the hospital?
– No, the doctor came and prescribed amoxicillin liquid.
The next day it was cleared up, she was eating immediately.
– After the antibiotics she started again having convulsions?
– Yes.
– And how many times from January until today she had convulsions?
– She has had 1, only 5 minutes. She was awful.
She changed, she was very irritable, wouldn’t comply, was doing a lot of sparing of the head,
crawling backwards on the floor. Peculiar thing.
She was coming to our bedroom crawling backwards and usually with the head on the floor.
– And was very disobedient. Still is?
– She is now, she is very disputed now.
– For the last 6-8 weeks she has been impossible. Absolutely uncontrollable.
– Hitting, banging her head on the floor.
She throws herself on the floor when you say no to her.
– If you say no to her, if you are close enough....
– You get a hit.
– If she is not close enough to hit you she will hit herself.
With the flat of her hands on the head like this and then if she still doesn’t get a response,
she will throw herself on the floor and either she is faced down banging her head on the floor
or she is lying on her back she will hit the heels on the floor.
– Thank you sweetie! Go to your mother. Forget it!
– Her attention span is very short.
She loves a tape or a book or whatever but she will lose her interest within 30 seconds and wants to go on.
As you saw she is still going to strangers,
the camera was a source of great fascination to her and she remembered you.
Toileting, I think she has almost come backwards because she was almost straining
but the last 6-8 weeks it’s like she is rebelling.
She asks for the potty or the toilet continuously, so you never know when she is serious.
– Change places with Andrew. On the 11th of April she received Med. 1M.
but you see up to now no real change, as I understand.
– We had a change. She was more compliant, easier to...
- No, I mean lately.
– She has gone backwards.
– She needs another “centralization”.
– She is disobedient, worse from contradiction,
if you deny something to her she will become aggressive against herself or against others.
– Against us if we are close enough or against herself.
Not particularly to strangers.
– It’s the person saying no to her.
– I can prove it now!
– Go to your mother otherwise I will....!
– Alexander come here please!
– Is she making a lot of grimaces?
– One think I’ve noticed she very much talks to one side like this.
Talks with her mouth sideways and she quite often holds that position,
but she still holds her mouth like this and when she talks it’s with this expression.
– Does she grind her teeth during sleep?
– Yes, a lot.
– So you can actually hear it?
– She doesn’t do it anymore since last year.
– She does it now lately?
– No.
– There are not so much to grind if you look it’s only one way, one side.
– A year ago she used to very badly in the sleep.
– Was there any TB in your family?
– I think so, yes. I think in my family.
– Not in mine.
– Go there stay! Can you tell me if you give her some meat with fat will she eat the fat?
– Yes. We don’t give her much fat.
– Fruits?
– She loves fruits.
– Which fruits she likes the most.
– Strawberries, kiwi.
– She chooses oranges but she gets the juice from them and she leaves the pulp.
– Bananas?
– Yes. It’s not her favorite.
– Lately she has no more vomiting?
– No.
– And she’s coughing?
– She still got this cough from 6 weeks ago.
– The ear never discharged again after the antibiotics.
– No.
– How many days you gave antibiotics?
– 3 days.
– But with the first antibiotic the discharged stopped. Correct?
–Yes.
– Tell me if you remember as a baby she had ear infection?
– Only a mild one once.
– You don’t remember her having discharge from the ear?
– Never.
– It’s difficult because babies cry and it was red.
– You don’t remember something dramatic.
– She only had upper respiratory infections.
Always coughing at nights, it always starts and is worse at nights.
– Does she perspire in the night?
– Terribly. She is very sweaty. She’s very warm.
– Sweetie, Alex! Let me see your teeth! She is shy?
Her teeth are worn out. How old is she now?
- 4,5.
– You remember you said she was kissing everybody during that time,
she is not doing it anymore?
– Not as much.
– The restlessness that was quite strong during that time is still the same or less?
– A bit less. She asks to go to bed when she is tired.
– She used to have a tottering gait.
– A little bit.
– Still there?
– A little bit but we've started taking her to trambolining and she’s quite good.
– But the tottering is still there, the same, less?
– It’s a little less.
– The desire for fruit is as strong as it used to be?
– Not quite.
– How much salt she likes?
– Not as much.
– We spoke last year about something we have called mamait which she could live on this.
Now she is not keen.
– During heat she had convulsions.
Now here in this environment, it’s quite hot, did you have anything?
– No.
– Thank you!
What happened with this case? What do you think?
It was improving until the ear was discharging.
And you see full amelioration in a case where we have a retarded child,
beautiful reaction with the ear
but we were not able to stop the discharge and the inflammation that was going on.
I could not have details so I just said to repeat the remedy.
They repeated lower potency than the one they should have repeated.
1M was given in the beginning, 200C was repeated
and the whole thing ended up in taking antibiotics which is the most unfortunate thing to happen.
Because after that we very seldom get a clear picture.
Because you cannot say repeat again Verat.
There is no restlessness anymore so strong as it was in the beginning.
Then you give Verat. and immediately develops the picture of Med.; knee-elbow position.
You give Med. and then you have an acute
and you will see if you take the whole course the importance of having strong acutes
after and the importance of treating the acute correctly with Homeopathy.
Because even treating the acutes wrongly with Homeopathy you may have relapses.
If we were able to treat this girl correctly you would see a totally different child.
You will see a child in her age which would be a miracle.
I didn’t want to say it in the beginning
but we have seen such cases developing so well that it’s unbelievable.
It’s a pity that such progress has to be stopped
by interfering with antibiotics and now what is the picture?
Is this a picture of Med.? Where is the knee-elbow position?
It’s not there which is the main symptom.
The oranges... she takes a little bit and spits them.
There are no symptoms of Med. There are no symptoms of Verat.
Restlessness mostly. What is the picture now?
What can you give now? You have very little to go by.
A picture of what I see is a child which is disobedient, aggressive, hitting herself, does not listen,
hits the others and at the same time some infections of the respiratory tract are going on.
Can you give me the symptoms without showing the remedy?
If you have put this in your repertorization the remedy would be... what?
Tub. is the remedy. Why?
You can argue and say she is not grinding her teeth which is a keynote for Tub.
Why Mr. George you are giving Tub.?
The reason is we don’t have to have all the keynotes, we have the excessive perspiration,
she perspires a lot now, respiratory symptoms are prominent and constant.
Not only that but we see Tub. has 13 out of 16 symptoms.
Actually the knocking her head against the wall is there, striking is there,
convulsions is there, large stool is there, vomiting,
strabismus so we have a picture of Tub. which is confirmed by the fact that the mother family had Tub.
– One symptoms missing.
– Which?
– Intolerance of contradiction in children.
– Find this. Mind-contradiction intolerance in children. Tarent. also a possibility.
The possibility for Tarent. might have been
but the excessive perspiration in the night plus the hereditary disposition
plus the fact that before she was grinding her teeth.
All these brings to the uppermost layer now the remedy Tub.
Advance seminar I told you I am sorry. Tarent. doesn’t perspire as much.
Tarent. is much more restless.
But the fact that the child was grinding her teeth so much
points out that there was time where she needed Tub. when she was born.
I don’t know. Maybe after Tub. she will go to Calc.
I don’t know. But at this moment, with these symptoms you have to give Tub. 1M.
– Can I ask why you didn’t take the medical case of the father and you only took the case of the mother?
– The father’s here? Later on you will see that he had gonorrhea I think.
NSU, non-specific-urethritis. Both!
That’s why in the analysis it was first Verat. and Med. is coming.
The moment Med. symptoms came up we just jumped to Med.
Now as you all agree we give Tub.