You were in a panic state this morning only or this happens regularly in your life?
– It doesn’t happen regularly. But it has happened before.
– How many times?
-Twice.
– For a reason?
-That I don’t know.
I’ll tell you the first time; when I was around the 15 there was a stress for the exams.
I feel like I’m close to losing my mind. That’s what’s been going on.
And I’ve lost myself. I am analyzing myself all the time.
I have to bring it down at the moment to really simple things.
I feel like I am making a fool of myself.
Deep down there’s something that’s really ugly.
Still I’m confused about that.
There is always people around me, I met some lovely people here and people that I know a little bit
and maybe I’ve just revealed too much for myself
and I am confusing my boundaries with my friends and Homeopathy.
I’m scarred of losing everything.
If I go down any further and I lose my identity then what do I have?
It all comes to surface when I’m here and I expect to come here and enjoy the week
because I love Homeopathy but I think I haven’t realized the power of it until now.
– This is the first time you come?
– Yes and I felt before I came here I felt together and I can be a good homeopath...
I want to heal people but I have to heal myself first
before I can go any further now that all this stuff has come up.
When I bury it then things keep surfacing.
And it’s got to come out. I’ve been telling everybody.
I know I am making a lot of people very irritated with me.
– Irritated or very anxious about you?
– Both. Some people that don’t know me feel irritated...
- Was there any event that happened here with colleagues?
You had some kind of very close contact and after that you felt hurt,
you opened up yourself too much.
– I’ve opened up myself too much to people that didn’t need it at the time.
– Didn’t need to hear what you say.
-Yes.
– Did you feel immediately hurt after that or you went back home,
you thought about it and then the panic and the anxiety started?
– The anxiety has been worse at night, definitely. Because it’s inward.
And I feel that I have to deal with what’s inside and bring it out
and I haven’t been doing that properly.
– Are you married?
-Yes.
– Do you have children?
- Yes, 2 children.
– Do you worry about them or at the moment you are concentrated
on what is happening inside of you?
– Honest answer is I’m not really worried about them. Ι’m totally self-absorbed.
Except last night when I felt I was going through a lot of different states.
The worst point; last night I felt I couldn’t work with how reality was for a while.
I heard dogs barking.
I couldn’t work whether there was a delusion of dogs barking or if there really was barking.
I was very scarred. When I was at my lowest point then that was
when I prayed and tried to make a connection with my husband and the children.
The more connections I am trying to make the more I feel I will push people away.
Ask me some questions because I’m confused.
– Did ever have this kind of experience, maybe not so intense but less,
frequently or there are periods where you have no problem at all and suddenly it comes?
– There are periods where I have no problems.
– And suddenly this states comes out of always
more or less the same reason or for different reasons?
– It’s the same reason; lack of connection to other people. That’s how I conceive it.
– Do you consider yourself an open person that can easily open up to others?
– Yes, I can do but I am not really showing my real self.
So I’m not really opening up myself.
The duality between having done Homeopathy course...
perhaps it made me even more self-absorbed
because I’m analyzing myself all the time.
– You can forget about homeopathic rubrics and symptoms
and you try to describe exactly how you feel in your own words,
as if you don’t know anything about Homeopathy.
When you talk now to me are you certain you are present or... do you understand?
– I understand.
– But it’s difficult to answer
– Yes.
– Does it happen during this time?
I can make it more clear you may be talking and you think somebody else is talking, not you.
That you are observing.
– I felt last night that people were talking about me.
I’ve been feeling that a lot and that’s part of the picture that comes from time to time.
I get a bit paranoid. It’s obvious that I’m in a state because I’ve been so confused,
I can only deal with really simple things and I feel completely lost.
– What is your desire at this state?
– Just to find myself.
– Except of that, you cannot find yourself but your desire is to be with people,
people to whom to feel close, be with your children, husband, friend who you trust, be protected...?
– Any of these things. Do you mean right now? I want to be healed.
– Do you like people being around seeing you or you like to stay by yourself?
You like that some people will come and console you?
I don’t mean really only console you,
I mean maybe you need some protection, some people may protect you.
You feel unprotected?
– Yes.
– I cannot imagine so I would like you to describe for me. The real thing.
It may be difficult but you have to describe.
– It’s difficult for me to describe.
– Why is it difficult?
Do you know why or not?
– I don’t know why.
- For example if someone I feel is warm and I feel safe with comes over
then it’s ok for a while and I feel the connection.
This happened with some of the other people I’ve met here.
I opened up myself so much and they put their arms around me and that’s wonderful time,
when they’re gone then I slip back again
and I can’t keep on doing that to people because it is selfish.
That’s what is.
– Do you feel you are critical to yourself?
– Yes.
– In the night do you have any salivation when you sleep?
– Usually there is. But now my mouth is very dry.
– At this moment. And you would like to drink something?
– Actually I would now.
– Bring some water.
Can you swallow or you have difficulty if you try to eat?
– No, there is no physical difficulties swallowing.
But I have not really been hungry. And I think that’s part of it as well.
– Would you say that you are a person who feels more the cold or the heat?
– I don’t think I’m strongly either way, actually.
I don’t strongly feel the heat or cold but I can feel both at times.
Last night, for example, when I was in this restaurant there were times
when I didn’t feel the cold at all and people were saying oh you don’t feel the cold?
And then I would go the other way shivering and someone gave me her own jacket
because I’ve forgotten mine.
– You felt cold?
– Yes, shivering.
– Do you have any taste in your mouth?
– No taste.
– Do you have any bleeding of gums when you brush your teeth?
– Sometimes but not frequently.
– Do you have a lot of problems with your teeth?
– No.
– As a child you had problems with ears? Frequent otitis?
– No, I don’t think so.
– Do you perspire easily?
– Yes, usually when I’m nervous, I had a problem with that particularly in armpits.
– Why do you say it is a problem? Because you don’t like it?
– Yes, because it has a bad smell.
– So if you perspire you feel uncomfortable?
– Only if it’s something...
- You are trying to say something and you lose the thread of...
-Yes.
– Forget it. Do you a have a fear that others may see how you feel?
Even by looking at you?
Even if a stranger looks at you I think that he may know why I feel so bad?
– I’m confused whether you mean right this minute or generally?
– When you are in that state.
– Yes. I can have both.
I tried to go away and deal it by myself this morning
and left in order others no to worry and I met them up here.
When I went down into the town for start I got lost which is stupid
and I just wandered around and tried to do these simple things that would help ground me and...
I forgot the question.
– Another question;
do you have regular bowel motion or are you constipated or have you diarrhea?
– At the moment I’ve been going less frequently since I got here.
Normally I go regularly every day. Sometimes more than once a day actually.
– And here you don’t go once a day? You go once every second day?
– No, I haven’t been going so often. I don’t know exactly.
I don’t pay much attention to that.
But definitely there have been changes in my bowel movement.
It’s less often.
- You noticed that.
– You don’t drink much water.
– I think I am waiting for you to press the button!
I think probably need a good slap around my face...
- Do you have craving for ice cream, sweet, anything?
– Not now. I don’t have craving for anything really.
– Usually do you take sweets?
– Yes.
– A lot?
– I like something sweet every day.
– What about salt?
– Not so much.
– In spite of eating sweets you still are quite thin. You don’t put on weight.
Or are you careful and you don’t put on weight?
If you are not eating carefully you put on weight?
– No. It hasn’t been so. I don’t know now.
Probably I would put on a little bit weight if I overindulge now but I go to the gym.
I’m lucky in that way.
– Do you like rice?
– It’s ok.
– Milk?
– I wouldn’t drink a glass of milk.
– Fish? Not so much.
– You had any fears not only now but fear of dark, of animals, thunderstorms, death...
- Fear of losing things.
– That is the main fear.
– Fear of madness has come up.
Fear that I will go insane has come up for me these last few days.
Fear that people will not like me, that’s strong.
– The special people who you like or in general?
– I want to be loved by everyone actually and that’s not possible. I want the impossible.
– Can you describe a little bit your character?
Are you very irritable or calm, you are easily offended or very easily hurt?
– I’m very easily hurt actually. I’m sensitive to criticism.
– You express anger?
– Not easily.
– Can you give me an idea, if you are angry how will you feel inside?
– Not this moment.
– If you are angry have you ever wanted to throw something,
do you have the impulse to hit or do some violence?
– No, never.
– You never had this impulse? Not that you do it but is there the impulse?
– No, only to myself.
– Do what to yourself? Hit?
– I’ve already told. Kill myself.
And that’s why I’m scared going back to my black state I was in before
where I did try and kill myself.
– How?
– I cut my wrists.
– Because of that state you did not like yourself.
– That was after I had Adam, my son, in America.
I went through a very bad postnatal depression.
That’s the worst state I’ve ever been in.
I was totally out... rejecting love actually.
– You rejecting or others rejecting your love?
– Both.
– I couldn’t sort this one out. It’s a desperate need for love this inside.
When it is given to me I keep on pushing it away.
– What remedies have you been given so far?
– I took a remedy myself which was a big mistake. Phos.
– When did you take it?
– Yesterday, here.
– Did you take another remedy before?
– I’ve had Ph-ac. which I didn’t feel it was me but maybe it is at the moment.
I’ve had Phos. from my friend.
If sometimes I phoned her she said go away and take some Phos.
It was not often, maybe twice.
– Calc.?
– No.
– Merc.?
– No. I’ve been scared to take remedies
because maybe that’s the thing I’ve really opened up.
What needs to come out.
– Your nails are strong?
– Yes, they’re ok.
– Ok.
– Finished?
– Yes.
Do you want to ask any question?
She will be prepared to answer, she said.
America! Always forward!
– What is making you feel better?
– Attention. That’s what I want. That’s the uppermost thing. Thank you.
– You are friends?
– Do you have a time where you feel better?
In the night you said you feel worse definitely.
Is there another time when you feel better?
– Yes. Now. When I am getting the attention which is a horrible thing because that’s it.
I’m sure now you’ve pushed the button that’s it.
I am ready to reveal it now.
– You need attention.
– That’s the core of the problem.
– So if you have consolation you feel good.
– Yes. I like consolation but I do reject it sometimes.
– Can you feel worse when somebody tries to console you?
– Yes, I can when I’m depressed certainly because everyone keeps on trying to help me.
Now I’m sick of myself.
– Anybody else who wants to ask? Any psychiatrist?
Would like to ask some question?
– What do you mean when you say I’ve lost myself?
– I am afraid I am afraid to lose my identity, she says.
– Do you feel better when you feel accepted by a group?
Is it difficult coming into a new group at first?
Especially like this, a big one, for the first time.
– Yes.
– You feel better being accepted in a group.
– Ehm... I feel...
- Two little questions. Do you have suicide intention?
– No.
– She is afraid she may come to that state.
– Yes, I am afraid of coming to that state.
– What’s your relation to music? Can it help you?
– Yes. Dancing. I love to dance and I like singing.
– So the cure is disco!
– Let me ask a question myself.
Did you feel comfortable in the consultation room or uncomfortable?
– I felt confused. I didn’t want to speak.
I want someone who can really understand.
That’s what I feel; I’m talking but none really understands me and I am not making sense.
You feel nobody understands you. Are you sure?
Merc., Alum., Phos., Calc., Stram. Alum. and Merc.
are the 2 remedies you should have been thinking in this case.
She says the worst period is in the night where she feels she will lose her mind.
Show me fear of insanity during night. Calc., Merc. and Phys.
You see Merc. is practically one of the very few remedies that especially in the night,
they become fearful of losing their minds.
Alum. the way she talks, the difficulty in expressing...
Show me the remedies for fear of insanity in general. You don’t have it.
We see Calc., Manc., Puls. and Cann-i. Merc. is in italics and Alum. too.
Suicidal disposition; Merc. and Alum. again are on the second degree.
Here we have a problem. We have to choose a remedy between Alum. and Merc.
Which of the 2 is the strongest?
If you have heard the M.M. of these 2 remedies maybe you would be able to differentiate.
If you see the way she speaks, taking so long to say something...
that means the mind is not clear and it looks like an Alum. mind.
This kind of difficulty.
– Looking specifically on Merc. and Alum. and she says very pronounced she tries to find herself;
that’s more Alum. Merc. is more in great danger from the environment.
That’s not her problem. There is no danger from the environment but to find her own self.
– The saliva has become less but the constipation has become more.
– No, she didn’t say saliva has become less,
I asked every night and she said not every night.
– Oh, I thought she said it.
– It’s reduced now.
– Now she is more constipated.
– I want to ask if Hell. is to be considered.
– No. Hell. is much more dramatic.
– I do often lose my way in known places.
– Merc. wants to do things quickly and Alum. wants to do things slowly,
so you can ask her about it.
– Can you answer; you do things quickly or slowly?
– At the moment I’ve slowed down but I am often agitated and quick.
But right now, since I’ve been here, as I have been feeling worse,
I’ve lost this sort of hurriedness.
I am usually hurried in the things I do and I’ve got too much to do.
But I feel I am shut down at the moment and slowed.
– Could you tell us about the menstruation?
– I don’t have problems with menstruation.
– Do you have any changes in your body before the time of bleeding?
– Like PMS? Not much. I don’t have swollen breasts or pain with my periods, they are fairly regular.
– Did you have any operations on your female system?
– No.
– Can you give us some information if you like about your...
What was I going to ask you?
– To give some more information about myself.
– No. About your sexual drive. Can you say anything about it?
– My sexual desire is suppressed I think.
– Less than normal. Appears to be less than normal but actually is more than normal.
– It’s absent except when there is a situation. Then everything is fine. Spontaneously.
– Is there any change in your coordination?
Are you clumsy or everything is normal?
– No change in coordination.
– Ok, I think it’s enough. I want to continue what I said.
The way she spoke is characteristic of Alum. if this way comes because of a mental confusion.
Alum. does not know the answer and cannot make clear in her mind what she wants to say.
Here, it’s a very interesting observation
because we may have this kind of reaction as somebody said in Merc.,
where Merc. need others to be attentive otherwise they don’t speak.
You remember I told about the case of a singer who came to see me
and I asked her what is the problem with you and she stayed like that.
I waited for about a minute. I said what is the problem...
Minutes is a long time waiting to get a response!
I asked her 3-4 times, no response.
She has come to consult me and a psychiatrist was sitting next to me and it was one of my first cases.
I did not know at that time how Merc. could behave like this.
Suddenly it comes to my mind that in order to make her speak I have to ask her about India.
I told her have you been to India? She said yes.
3 minutes without any communication and suddenly I asked about India etc. and she started talking.
But in the beginning I never want to give the impression to the patient
that I am sympathetic, that I am listening very much...
I am very cool, I am just an observer. I put the question and then I observe.
She felt that there is no connection. She could not talk.
The moment I asked a familiar thing to her,
she thought this man must have been in India...
she felt the connection and she started talking.
And then I realized why Merc. has this type of stammering.
They stammer in this way, very sympathetic way.
They need sympathy, they need attention. And that’s why they cannot express.
Unless they have this connection and the sympathy they cannot communicate.
So she was in between, she was acting like Alum.
but I could not realize whether it was because of total confusion,
losing identity, somebody else is talking because in Alum. the confusion is such
that sometimes they talk and they hear the voice and they think somebody else is talking.
There is so much confusion.
In Merc. the fear comes in the night, that they are going to disintegrate
and then I started putting questions like are you constipated, to confirm Alum.
She said yes, lately I am constipated but not to the extent that you will have a confirmation.
On the other hand do you have a salivation? Yes, I have a salivation but not so much etc.
Do you have a bad taste? No metallic taste, no real problems with the teeth,
no otitis, no impulses where we have to confirm Merc.
And at the same time she could not confirm Alum. either.
All the key symptoms of Alum. I put except of some constipation.
When she entered the class and said I need attention.
That takes the case finally towards Merc. I need the attention in order to speak.
That with the night fear, though there are no impulses,
we can say that the case goes towards Merc. but show me how many symptoms Merc. covers.
It has almost all her symptoms,
even the repertorization will bring out Merc. as the remedy for her
but not Phos. Phos. can aggravate that state and make you much more crazy.
We will give Merc. What potency?
Who says 50M? 10M? 1M? 200C? 30C? 12C?
Of course you have to have a high potency for this case.
200C is enough I think. Get her 200C. I would like to have a follow up at 14:30.
I will just give you a report. A few things which I tested.
She would look and not speak but she seemed to understand every question.
I asked her what was the time, she looked her watch, it was 10:00 English time.
She looked and said 10:00 in London and in Greece 12:00.
She calculated the 2 hours difference and she gave me the information
that is 12:00 Greek time while her watch was showing 10:00 English time.
That was quite encouraging in the view of the fact that she was talking about demons and all that.
This has stopped, she didn’t talk.
I asked her several other questions, who she is,
what is the name of her father, of her husband etc. and she would answer correctly.
She wanted to hold my hand and to be with her.
I tried to stay as much as possible with her.
Also, another point which was encouraging was that she was shouting quite strongly,
shrieking actually, which she has not done after the high dose of Merc. I gave her.
And also she slept for about a minute or two.
For 3 days as we said she has not been able to sleep at all.
The moment I tried to leave she most probably felt deserted
and she got up and the men could not hold her, she wanted to come to me.
When they called me and I came back,
she grabbed me and didn’t want to leave me and she kneeled down holding my legs...
I don’t quite understand because she would not tell what she felt.
Either she is not able to speak or to describe or she does not want because she is afraid.
I received some information concerning her past and this happened after birth. After each birth.
For me is not an aggressive behavior at least in my presence I haven’t seen any aggressiveness
except of some thoughts which were coming some times, which shake her sometimes.
Now the fact that she does not shriek because the shrieking is to get out what threatens inside.
So if the shriek is not there and if she answers correctly the questions,
that means she is getting better.
Of course in such cases you cannot say that within a few hours the whole thing is over
especially when we don’t know the depth of the problem and what causes it.
I have been told that her mother has been mistreating her quite a lot,
she was quite promiscuous and she was unloading on her behavior.
God knows what’s inside the soul of that child!
She seemed to need affection,
she seemed to have some sexuality which is quite obvious but we will see.
The problem here is that we don’t have a hospital yet here
and so I have to meet everyone, everything that happens without hospital.
This woman hasn’t slept at all for 3 nights. Last night also did not sleep.
She was completely out and she would shriek, shout, trying to escape.
They tried to contain her very powerful men would hold her.
This is a really difficult situation that we had to deal with.
We telephoned her husband of course who is coming.
He knows the problem, this seems to be happening regularly
but we don’t have enough information about the case.
Concerning the remedy which we gave yesterday, I think that it did nothing.
So the question is was it the right remedy or the wrong potency or not a potentized remedy?
I went there, people will tell you what happened,
she was in a terrible state and I said I feel was probably that the Merc. 200C
which we gave here was a spoiled remedy.
That means a remedy has stopped acting.
Otherwise it should have some action which we didn’t see.
– The girl last night, where you were interviewing and we were watching the video,
she stood up as if the interview had something to do with her case.
Was that an aggravation from Merc.?
– No. This is one of the Merc. keynotes.
Mental disturbances in Merc. make them shriek.
The person feels like going out in the street and shriek.
I gave her a higher potency of Merc. from my house and we will see what happens.
Because in this case we should have had more information.
Andrew who telephoned her husband says the husband seems to know the situation and he is coming over
because who is going to accompany her, how is going to go back etc.
Most probably the reason she came here was exactly that
because she was quite sick and needed some treatment.
And what she actually needed was my attention and all that. Anyhow we will see.
– May I ask you a question? The patient is actually in an acute psychotic state.
I would like to ask you if you have experienced in the past patients
in these acute psychotic states with Homeopathy.
– Yes, I have. Acute insanity especially if it’s not long continued.
Acute insanity can be managed by Homeopathy within 2-3 days.
You will see this crisis subsiding. I had this experience.
Anyhow with the right remedy. You give the wrong remedy it will continue.
The other problem that we have, because we open the bottles and give a dose,
we open again and give another dose and at a certain moment this bottle is inactive.
What has happened is because of opening and closing the remedy has been neutralized.
I had this experience many times.
In Seattle [patient name], one the students was collapsing,
he was sitting there in the first row, we were in the hotel having the seminar,
he was collapsing with constant diarrheas, I saw him in that state I said to go upstairs,
we took him upstairs to the room and I looked a few things
and I asked the students who has Carb-v. 1M.
Somebody gave it to me, we went upstairs,
I gave him and I came down to continue the teaching.
After 1,5 hour I went upstairs I saw him and he said he was worse.
And because he was a homeopath himself, you remember [name] the naturopath,
tall, bald guy, he said I think I am Ars.
because I am afraid I am going to die and I am totally exhausted and it’s worse and worse.
He almost persuaded me.
But I said if he is a homeopath and he knows the symptoms
that means he overstates the fear of death in order to sound as if he is Ars.
So I said ok. I won’t give you Ars. I will give you again the remedy
and if in 2 minutes you don’t feel better I will give you Ars.
So I went down and I asked if anybody else had Carb-v. the same potency.
Somebody came and said yes. I went upstairs, gave him the remedy and I wait.
Less than 2 minutes he said I feel better.
In 1,5 hour he was driving his car back home.
But if I had listened to him, remedy wrong,
no the remedy was not wrong I was sure how Carb-v. would not act when the picture was Carb-v.?
Many times being having not that experience you think the remedy is wrong
and then you go ahead and give another remedy and another remedy.
But actually the remedy was not properly potentized or the remedy has been spoiled.
And I have seen that with the pharmacy in Athens.
I remember I prescribed Phos., Rhus-t.... Phos. 10M; nothing.
Where did you buy it from? This pharmacy.
Ok, go to that pharmacy and buy Phos. 10M and take it and tell me.
Fantastic! I phoned them and told your Phos. 10M is finished, change it.
With Rhus-t., Sulph., the same.
I have seen this again and again
but you have to know very well what you are doing before you can do that of course.
Because the first thing you think is I have given the wrong remedy, of course.
And that’s one of the problems we have.