Paragraph, aphorism 4. Who has the Organon? Very good.
Who has read the Organon right through?
Who has read the sub-notes in the Organon? Good. So you don't need me.
That is Ok. I just give you some ideas, some perspective in some aspects.
"He is likewise a preserver of health if he knows the things that derange health
and cause disease and how to remove them from persons in health".
There is wrong translation. "[..] and know to remove them from persons in health"
so the persons can become healthy, this is what it means of course.
"[...]if he knows the things that derange health".
By the time he was writing the Organon, they knew very few things that one could
say "deranges health". They did not know about the microbes, about bacteria,
about the different things which we know today. So what does he mean?
Can anybody tell me?
He says "[..]a preserver of health if he knows the things that derange health".
It's a big statement. He must have had something in his mind when he wrote this.
Things that derange health. We know that for instance bad food can derange health.
This kind of things. And exposing someone to the cold. Is that what he means?
Or he means something more? He means most probably, he is a pre-runner of his
ideas concerning the miasms.
He goes further and says "Useful to the physician in assisting him to cure are the
particulars of the most probable exciting cause of the acute disease, as also the
most significant points and the whole history of the chronic disease, to enable him
to discover its fundamental cause, which is generally due to a chronic miasm.
In these investigations, the ascertainable physical constitution of the patient
(especially when the disease is chronic), his moral and intellectual character,
his occupation, mode of living and habits, his social and domestic relations,
his age, sexual function etc. are to be taken into consideration".
In one paragraph he gives all the factors that we discussed already that could
derange the health of the person.
And the first thing he says is the general constitution of the patient.
That means he has noticed that if a person had a good constitution,
his treatment would be easy.
If his constitution was weak, his treatment would be much more difficult.
"[...]especially when the disease is chronic".
Constitution is connected with chronic condition. But one of the first things he makes
is his moral and intellectual character.
What could derange health is the moral and intellectual character.
What could be the cause of his disease is the moral and intellectual character.
You see how clear he is in his mind. He has perceived in depth what was happening
in the human organism in 1810. Not today, after all we know.
I can tell you that this paragraph is so important to understand, for a physician
who is treating cases, to understand why a case would be very difficult to cure.
Moral character bad. It means you get a patient.
He comes to your office with recommendations, this is an important person,
very rich person. Pay special attention to him.
And he comes and he has the air of the boss. He is the boss of everybody.
He pays money to everybody. So he has learned to be like this.
What he wants from you is just quickly fix this little problem which I have...
So I cannot lose my time with you. You realize the life of such a person.
What it really is. Lots of money, lots of women, a lot of corruption.
He has corrupted others. And he thinks everything is easy.
Everything is his own birth right.
So such people will be very difficult to treat, unfortunately.
Never mind how much you may want to help them. This is going to be very difficult.
Why? Because the corruption of their soul is so deep that it is not a kind of morality,
his moral character, it's a case of reality.
This person who is this and that and so strong, so rich... he has stepped on other
humans, he has pushed them down. Perhaps he has committed crimes.
He appears as if everything is Ok. "Just give me the remedy so I can go".
But you realize that this person has a life which is not clean at all.
And you can see in his face, you can see in the mode of the expression, in his
intellectual capacity...
Most probably Hahnemann had similar experiences.
That's why he says the moral character. Be careful! Examine his moral character.
You cannot examine the moral character because everybody will say "I'm the best,
I give money, I support people, I do this and that". What they will say about
themselves is what they think they are. It's not what the other self which is deep,
which is watching all the time says to him even in a subconscious level, but it's not
even in a conscious level but on subconscious level tells him
"Wait. You are a bastard. You are a criminal". Such people will be difficult to cure.
I can tell you. They are very clever people because they have been successful in the
society. They have attained position, politicians with great power.
And high judges and whatever. If these people come to you, you are an unlucky
homeopath. I can tell you, though it may appear that you have the best clients
and the most powerful. Because they are dangerous at the same time.
Because the moment you will not deliver what they think they should get... Because
they will not give you the ordinary money. So they expect that they will get the
equivalent of what they paid. The more I paid the more I will be better.
It's not like this. It's the opposite.
It's unbelievable in real practice how you realize what Hahnemann has written.
The genius he was. He says "intellectual character, his occupation".
What are you doing? There are people who are doing nothing today.
They just sit in their office and they have a computer and the millions come.
They realize this is not something moral for the world.
It's an expression. They don't really realize but on a deeper level they know this is a
very immoral thing what I am doing. Because I am stealing the people of the country.
This is the idea. This is what he says, the occupation.
And there comes a man, a carpenter who build these chairs.
I never expected such heavy chairs, such a nice office. You see here how nice it is?
He worked for three months. How much it costs? So much. Logical price you pay.
And he is an artist. A very honest working man who produced this creation and he just
asked for some money to live his family.
"[...]mode of living and habits, his social and domestic relations".
Another very important area in which conflict arises quite easily.
You cannot live forever. You become old and die.
You cannot...an old man comes and says "make me feel 16 year old. I'm sorry sir,
I cannot do it". "[...] sexual function etc.". This sexuality is also a big issue
because the preservation instinct and the instinct of procreation are very powerful,
both. So if somebody feels secure and good about these two issues, I have enough
money to support my family and my sexual needs are covered.
That person is a balanced person. Anxiety about money and how to support
my family and also insecurities concerning the acceptance as a human being
by others are very powerful issues.
"The unprejudiced observer". There are two other things that he tells here.
The exciting cause and fundamental cause. Exciting cause is what triggers acute
diseases. The microbes, the bacteria, the poisonous food, the pollution of the air.
That is the exciting cause. But he said except of the exciting cause there is something
which is underneath which is the fundamental cause or the maintaining cause.
Which actually he predicted the whole idea, genetic idea, which has come the last
30-40 years concerning the genetic predisposition.
This is exactly what he found out by simply observing his patients.
Here he says there is an exciting cause, there is something which excites a condition,
but also there is a fundamental cause which is behind this and to which he will
attribute the different miasms. The miasmatic theory is nothing else than the theory
of genetic predisposition, which we all know today.
And in paragraph 6 he says "The unprejudiced observer - well aware of the futility
of transcendental speculations which can receive no confirmation from experience..."
He had also a problem with people who are just bringing up theories, ideas
which have nothing to do with the practical issue of curing people.
"The unprejudiced observer". He who has no prejudice.
The homeopathic physician should not have any prejudice.
The diet is an important factor in paying attention for better health.
You have to examine it and if it is correct you have to accept it.
There's nobody today who argues with this, the kind of food we eat is very important.
There is another system of therapy which is called acupuncture. Do I have evidence?
Yes, Ok. There is another thing which is called osteopathy, chiropractors
manipulating the spine. Do I have evidence? Yes. Accept it.
If you are prejudiced, nothing works except of Homeopathy...
"[...]  be his powers of penetration ever so great, takes note of nothing in every
individual disease except the changes in the health of the body and of the mind".
For a homeopath he says, if you are unprejudiced, you look upon in an open mind
and you take into consideration the changes in body and mind.
This is the pathology you are interested in. Sometimes we say which symptoms should
be taken into consideration?
You should take into consideration the changes that have happened in a certain period
in the life of the person. I'm a happy person and because of an incident I lost my lover,
my child and I've become another person. This is the change.
This you should take into consideration.
I was digesting everything, now I cannot eat cheese, I cannot eat onions, I cannot eat
tomatoes, I cannot eat sweets, my stomach is upset. These are changes you have to
take into consideration. This specifies what are the symptoms you have to take into
consideration.
What is the problem with us today when we see chronic cases and of quite deep
character? What is the problem? Who can tell me?
-We have symptoms from different levels and we cannot have a clear picture which
symptom we have to choose.
-Very good! That's correct. I will say the same thing in a different way.
From the moment somebody is born and they start giving vaccinations, antibiotics
etc. changes start. Later on he has an acute. Later on more changes happen because
of some effects, of some incidents in the life of the person.
He gets acutes, he gets some frights, he gets some problems, the problems are
changing his mood, changing his character and then more problems, more changes
and when they arrive to us, there is not one set of changes that you can be aware of
and be clear. That would be easy.
If a person has lived a normal, healthy life and he is a villager in the mountains, strong,
was eating good, natural products but one day he was tired, he had to milk the cows
and it was raining and he got wet, he comes with a lumbago.
This man comes with a lumbago, I can tell you the case will be so clear.
One remedy and the next day he will back to his village working.
No changes and after changes... we have in the cities. In the city of London,
in the city of Athens, in the city of Paris and all these terrible cities.
"[...]except the changes in the health of the body and of the mind [...]which can
be perceived externally by means of the senses; that is to say, he notices only the
deviations from the former healthy state of the now diseased individual, which are felt
by the patient himself". These changes, he says, can be felt by the patient himself
remarked by those around him. This is information that you need.
What the patient will tell you, you ask the wife also because you will ask the patient
"Are you irritable?" because you suspect this is a case of Nux-vomica.
"Are you irritable? -No." and the wife makes like this and says "Ok...".
I told you a professor of surgery, another of his surgeons was sitting next to me in the
chair and I was taking his case and I asked him this question.
I perceived this was a Nux-v. case. He can be irritable. So his student had seen him in
operation and how he behaved and then I say "Are you irritable? -No, I'm very calm".
George kicks me under the chair and says be careful.
"And finally observed by the physician". There are 3 sources of information.
The patient himself, the people around him and what the physician observes.
All of them are important information that we should have in every case if possible.
It's not possible every time. Because people when they see you they want to speak
without anybody around. They want to be only themselves. Why?
Because they don't want anybody else to know what's going on inside them.
They will ask "Go out". If they say "go out" the case will be difficult.
If the person says "No, I don't mind, my wife can stay" the case is going to be easier
but if they know what you are going to ask...because if they do it in their ignorance of
what kind of information we need, that's a different story.
Because by the time they realize that you are asking difficult questions, the wife herself
opens the door and goes out says "it's better you stay and tell the story yourself".
"[..]All these perceptible signs represent the disease in its whole extent".
Hahnemann actually says if you have all this information, you know everything about
that character, about that constitution, you don't need anything more, this is the whole
extent of his disease. What about laboratory tests? Do we need?
Yes, we need laboratory tests. Mostly to know the depth of the pathology and also not
to make a mistake and misunderstand what's going on with an organism who is quite
undermined with pathology and you don't realize it and you give a very high potency,
there is a big reaction and all kinds of other things can happen.
Actually today we are using all possible diagnostic tools that exist with conventional
medicine and we have to know what possibilities there are. We must ask also if we are
not very sure about the pathology. Of course the homeopath learns to diagnose a case
through the symptomatology.
"[... ]that is, together they form the true and only conceivable portrait of the disease".
Do you want to ask any question so far, paragraph 6? So we can go to paragraph 7.
More complicated paragraphs.
"Now, as in a disease, from which no manifest exciting or maintaining cause
(causa occasionalis) has to be removed, we can perceive nothing but the morbid
symptoms, it must be the symptoms alone by which the disease demands and points to
the remedy suited to relieve it".
If actually there is no an external cause or a cause that maybe it is the exciting cause,
you have a woman who wants to be looking better, they press themselves with
different things and due to pressure they can have a swollen feet. You just tell them
to release the thing... When there is a bandage and there is a swelling you just release
the bandage to relieve the swelling. This is what he means.
He says unless you have found such a cause which is obvious and you have
to remove it, then the only thing that constitutes disease are the totality of
the symptoms. That is the disease of the person. Mental and physical.
It was me that I proposed the idea of mental, emotional and physical. The 3 levels.
I did this in order to separate and to define the depth of the problem.
This is in hierarchy, the mental, my mental level is clear, my emotional level is not clear,
I have some grief, I have some pains and I have my physical body.
I have noticed that if drugs were given for a person in depression, on emotional level,
he was having a clear mental level, he says "Now, I feel my mind is not clear anymore".
I realize that problems from emotional level they can go deeper into the mental level.
Also I noticed another way. When a mental problem was there, quite deep and
it was treated correctly the problem would go through the emotional. How?
By the person complaining after that "I have become irritable, I have become more
dissatisfied" and then you keep on treating him and then the whole problem goes to
the physical body and there is a problem with his stomach.
On the opposite, there is, as I have said in the Science of Homeopathy,
each level has different organs. That means mental level has functions,
it's like physical organs in a hierarchical importance.
Which is the most deep organ which keeps a person intact, the person feels
"I am George and I am not lost, I don't know who I am".
If I lost this, if I don't feel anymore my existence, my awareness, I don't have
my consciousness fully, then I go to the doctor and he gives me a remedy.
This focus of the high disturbance on the mental level goes lower into memory.
I lose my memory I forget more easily than before certain things.
In the same way with the emotional level. I am very depressed. Take a remedy.
After a month I'm very irritable. So the irritation is on a lower level than
the depression. Suicidal depression is the deepest. The person wants to kill himself.
It's the deepest on the emotional level from suicidal depression goes to depression.
The persons says "I don't think of committing suicide anymore. It was in my mind
all the time, not anymore, much less". He is doing well.
Otherwise how would you know what the remedy has done if you don't know
these things?
You have to read the Science of Homeopathy, if the chapter is not conceivable.
"[...]demands and points to the remedy suited to relieve it - and moreover,
the totality of these symptoms, of this outwardly reflected picture of the internal
essence of the disease, that is, of the affection of the vital force, must be the principal
or the sole means, whereby the disease can make known what remedy it requires".
"[...] The totality of these symptoms" which are reflected in the organism,
" [...]of the internal essence of the disease", which is the disturbance of the vital force
"[...]must be the principal, or the sole means, whereby the disease can make known
what remedy it requires". Actually what he says is what we always say that
in order to find your disease, it is not enough to tell me that you have a pneumonia,
it's not enough to tell me a conventional medicine diagnosis.
We cannot give you a remedy. This is something that was ignored for many years.
When I first came to Homeopathy, I came in Homeopathy by meeting somebody
who was giving mixtures of remedies for a specific problem.
You have headaches, he has a headache bottle, he gives you the bottle for headache.
What contained the bottle of remedies? Different remedies for headaches. All of them.
20 - 30 remedies inside. I have hay fever, I had also hay fever, I came for that,
he gave me a remedy I still remember "Rhinopalsan". And this remedy contained...
I can't remember how many remedies. I took all this mixture and my nose was better
but my energy went down. Actually it was suppressing me because it was low potency,
20 remedies every day... I suddenly felt heavy, tired...
Then actually I had rejected Homeopathy in the way I had rejected conventional
Medicine when I was 16. I went to the doctor and they said we can fuse your spine
and maybe you'll be paralyzed.
"No thank you very much, goodbye, I don't want to be paralyzed".
Unless I had an accident with my car and I did not know what to do, I wanted to read
a book about Homeopathy after all. They gave me this book,
Boericke's Materia Medica. "What is this book you read there on the bedside...?"
There was a friend of mine, he says "Boericke's Materia Medica".
Where can I buy it? [Address] Johannesburg. I took the bus because I didn't have
a car anymore, it was smashed totally but I was not hurt.
And I got this book which I read right through in 2-3 days, I can't remember but I did
not stop until I had finished all the remedies. Can you imagine this?
I still can remember some of the very small remedies I was reading 51 years ago.
Then I understood and I said to my friend who had introduced me to this guy
and I said your friend who is doing this is not doing the correct Homeopathy.
He said why? After that I bought Kent and I read and next time when we met
I explained to him why this man selling medicines for this kind of things
was not correct. But very soon I found out, all of Europe, America... they used it
in this way. That means they have never read what this man was writing.
They were just medical doctors who knew the diagnosis, migraine, hay fever,
duodenal ulcer, bronchitis and would give you the bronchitis remedies.
But what he was saying, it was totally different. He says the totality of the symptoms
will indicate the proper remedy. "[...] the totality of the symptoms must be the
principal, indeed the only thing that the physician has to take note of in every case
of disease and to remove by means of his art, in order that it shall be cured
and transformed into health". Very clear.
Paragraph 8 says "It is not conceivable, nor can it be proved by any experience
in the world, that after removal of all the symptoms of the disease and of the entire
collection of the perceptible phenomena, there should or could remain anything else
besides health..."
Here Hahnemann is quite definite, quite sure that after the removal of all the
symptoms nothing remains but health.
That paragraph has to be understood again in the spirit of the old times of Hahnemann.
Today it's not valid. Why? Because the phenomena today are such that you may have
no symptoms and yet there can be some underlying problem which will be manifesting
later on.
For instance, in cases of high blood pressure the person may feel in very good health
without any symptoms, yet his blood pressure can be quite high.
Actually, when the blood pressure is quite high many people feel excellent.
But that is dangerous. That means in our time when our constitutions have been
undermined by all kinds of pollutions etc., we may have an underlying condition
which may be preparing the organism for a severe problem.
Therefore this paragraph should be read in two ways. One way is that
when a person comes and is a good constitution and has a totality of symptoms
and you find a remedy that the symptoms are gone, really remains in good health.
This is one way that should be read.
The other way is that if a person has a weak constitution which has the possibility
potentially to develop a severe disease may not be apparent because there were
no symptoms to indicate it.
In another way, you may be giving a remedy and you have the alleviation of certain
symptoms but underneath there may be a quiet pathology which can be developing.
We know it today that this can be so. And this quiet pathology will manifest the
moment that there is a stress from the environment or from his own self.
That means there is somebody who says "I am well now", you don't need to continue
treatment but at a certain time and under stress suddenly breaks out in a quite serious
condition.
So this idea of Hahnemann, the way he says it..."It is not conceivable, nor can it be
proved by any experience in the world", this is quite a strong statement
"[...]that after removal of all the symptoms of the disease [...]  there should or could
remain anything else but health". So it could under certain condition
depending on the level of health an individual is in.
Don't be surprised if you have treated somebody and has done very well
and after 3,4,5 years under a stress either because of antibiotics, chemical drugs,
emotional stress or whatever other reason a predisposition which is engrafted
in his genes may just flare up suddenly, you may see a quite serious condition
developing. The matter of predisposition, we will discuss later on also.
"In the healthy condition of men, the spiritual vital force (autocracy), the dynamis
that animates the material body (organism), rules with unbounded sway..."
This paragraph has been misunderstood by a lot of people in the clergy.
Because it says "the spiritual vital force".
The meaning "spiritual" here I don't know the exact German word. It's the same.
Means something else as well? Spiritual, Stephan...Similar to spirit.
We have to take into consideration that Hahnemann was living in 1800
and he has to describe the energy, the biological energy of the body and has to find
a word to describe it.
And "spirit" during this time means something which is beyond material.
It is not something material, something immaterial, which today we know that it is
the bioenergy of the body. We know that the heart works with electric energy.
We move our hands, we speak with the energy which is produced in our body.
So therefore what he means is this energy which everyone has and everyone
understands about that energy. What is simpler than this?
How you move your hands? By some energy. This energy is meant here. That's all.
It's not something spiritual or something magical or anything like that.
Hahnemann here means only the energy of the body. We can say that we have
an energy body which is behind all the cells of our body, every cell of our body contains
this kind of energy. It's behind every cell, every tissue, every organ, every system
of our body, there is this energy. Therefore there is not misunderstanding.
"[...]   rules with unbounded sway". This kind of energy, he says, rules the organism
without any interference. Unbounded. Without any boundaries.
"[...]and retains all the parts of the organism in admirable, harmonious, vital operation,
as regards both sensations and functions".
It is this energy which controls our emotions and our actions, functions. "[...]  so that
our indwelling, reason-gifted mind can freely employ this living, healthy instrument
for the higher purposes of our existence".
What he says in a healthy body, most probably you will have a healthy mind.
Very simple. The ancient Greeks they used to say exactly the same thing.
So a healthy energy body will maintain a healthy mind and a healthy body.
And if that is so, that means, if you are healthy in your body and mind
then only perhaps, I say only, you can use this instrument for the higher
purposes of life. Which are the higher purposes of life?
Each one has different higher purposes of life. But which is the highest?
To make money! This is the highest! In dollar they say "In God we trust".
In dollar we trust. The highest purpose in life. There are people who believe.
What nonsense are you talking about... Reality is that money speaks.
You have money, you can do anything. You want a University? Ok.
You have enough money? Buy the university! For the higher purposes of life.
So use what was given to you in healthy condition for the higher purposes of life.
This is the idea. If you want to use it for attaining money, you can use it.
If you want to use it for having good time in life, you can use it.
But Hahnemann says you better use it for the higher purposes of your life.
Exactly he says "[...]so that our indwelling, reason-gifted mind can freely employ
this living, healthy instrument for the higher purposes of our existence".
You see why you suffer. Because there is no purpose. Take somebody who is rich,
who has everything... no purpose in life.
This person will be a raged individual, going from doctor to doctor, trying to find
something to stimulate...Why?
Because there is no purpose or the purpose was turned to the wrong direction.
Not higher, but lower purposes of life.
Once your purpose is turned downwards, you can forget about being healthy
and why are we not really healthy? Because we have this element,
this dark, negative element, it's ingrained in our nature. It's within ourselves.
We cannot get rid entirely of the negative part of ourselves.
Always we will have something that's dragging you down.
That's why if you read the life of people who have devoted themselves
to spiritual practices, the struggle against their own self is so great and so powerful,
somebody pulling them down and them pulling by sheer will, pulling themselves up
in order to come in contact with the higher purpose...
which for them, for the monks, for the spiritual people is the realization of the
unification with God. Feel that feeling. Full feeling that you are really united with God.
Can you feel that if you are pulled down with your desires, little things...?
Yes, you want to say something.
- I want to say something concerning the spirit-like. It's a wrong translation because
in Germany we have the same word for spirit and ghost.
And I think in this paragraph, this is meant as ghost-like because we cannot see the
vital force. It's ghost-like. It's similar to a ghost. And not spirit-like...
This is mistaken in translation.
- Some other Germans do not agree. Stephan?
- It's the same for ghost and the spirit but I think it's the spirit in the spiritual way.
- Anyhow I translate this so therefore there is no question about that! [LAUGHTER]
I enter the idea of Hahnemann, I understand he tried to explain something he could
feel but not touch. How can I say this force, this energy, how can this be described?
Spirit-like, vital force.
-[not audible]
- We use the idea of soul, who has touched soul and put it under microscope? Nobody.
But everybody has accepted it that soul is psyche, we have psychotherapists.
That means therapists who are dealing exclusively with the soul.
And they don't say "Who can tell us what the soul is? Has anybody seen the soul?"
They don't say anymore. They used to say it for the psychotherapists also.
But now the accept it. Soul-therapists, psychotherapists.
- Can you please go a little bit back to paragraph 8? You said if somebody has a weak
constitution then there is a risk that his predisposition will come up, as a big shock.
But surely with right homeopathic treatment can we keep this predisposition at bay,
can't we help it stay in the background and not rise despite the shock?
- In paragraph 8 you are talking?
- Yes because you said if people are healthy, then the symptom will disappear
with the right treatment. If they are weak, we cannot bring them back to health.
- Normally if they have a weak constitution, the symptomatology will go,"I'm good.
You can forget about treating yourself anymore". You release the patient you say
"Now you feel good in all respect. Continue". But in a weak constitution there is
the possibility that under a stress a flare up of a serious condition may arise.
That is why we cannot say, we cannot be so absolute with the expression once
the symptoms are gone, there is nobody in the world that can tell you that any kind
of disease exists anymore in your body.
- Correct but if somebody has a psychotic predisposition in the family, can you not say
with the right treatment you could avoid that they die at 45 of a heart attack?
If they have not developed yet the symptomatology but you think there's a risk
but with the right treatment, they may die in 75 or 80 of something else.
Or maybe weak heat but not young. We keep it at bay, that predisposition with the right
with the right treatment, so they are healthy.
- Whether you can eliminate a predisposition that can kill somebody at 45? Yes.
We can do, as long as, there are some symptoms to guide us.
This person comes to us. He is going to die with a heart attack at 48.
He comes to us at the age of 40. And we start treating him.
Then most probably, he'll avoid having heart attack at 48.
But let us say he does not come to us and he feels quite good.
And suddenly in 48 he gets an attack and dies. That is the question now.
This somebody who did not have symptoms, was he absolutely healthy?
And the answer is no. He was not absolutely healthy in the way Hahnemann stresses
it so strongly. That if there are no symptoms there is not any possibility,
anybody in the world can say that this person is not healthy. That is clear.
This is what we can say about paragraph 8.