I just want to say a few things concerning paragraph 9 which we have been discussing
yesterday and I gave you my idea of what is a higher purpose in life.
Perhaps this is a misunderstanding.
The highest purpose in life in some people is the spiritual enlightment,
the spiritual progress.
That does not mean that this is the only purpose of the higher self.
There are a lot of other noble purposes which each one of us has and tries to attain.
But I said from the higher purpose of attaining of becoming rich,
which is the opposite,
to this other higher purpose, which is the highest spiritual attainment,
there are a lot of other noble, higher purposes in life.
Each one chooses to do. For a woman may be to raise her children properly,
devotes all her life into that. That is a higher purpose in life.
For some other people to work on society and social matters.
Even some politicians, very few, they come to politics with the idea
that they will help forming a better society.
I didn't want to give the impression that higher purposes of life,
as far as we understand it now today, I do not know what Hahnemann meant
but what I mean today that a healthy person should use his abilities
for a higher purpose, to do something beyond himself.
You remember perhaps my definition of health and the measure of health.
Who is healthier than another. And I said, measuring health through creativity.
A person who is creative, who is producing, which bringing in life, new ideas,
new things in life, is a creative person.
The only difference is between somebody who is selfish and somebody
who is healthy is that what he does for himself should be also in,
half actually, in favor of society as well. What I do if I do it with the purpose
of helping society, as much as I'm helping myself, I am in a very correct,
good health condition.
If I go one way like discarding myself and don't care about myself, only society...
this is not healthy.
In the same way, if I go, everything for myself...
whatever I do, the purpose is to gain myself, forget the society.
They can die. I can sell my country, if I am a politician in order to make
some billions in my account, that is a very unhealthy condition.
You may say "But these people, they live long". It doesn't matter.
It's not a matter of how long someone lives but what is the quality of life they have.
So the quality of life counts very much. In order to have a good quality of life,
you have to have a balance. And also you have to have as little as possible
dark areas in your deep subconscious.
You understand what it means.
So in paragraph 10, Hahnemann says "The material organism,
without the vital force, is capable of no sensation, no function, no self-preservation,
it derives all sensation and performs all the functions of life solely by means
of the immaterial being (the vital principle) which animates
the material organism in health and in disease".
So this is his main argument. He says, what is the difference between a corpse,
a person who has just died, what is the difference of that condition and
the condition 3 minutes before? What is missing?
1,2,3 seconds before the death and after the death... What is the difference?
That the organism or one organ gave in or something like that? Not really.
The difference is that this vital principle, this energy body which keeps the life
of a person and gives the possibility of a human being to function,
it is this energy body, he's talking about a new concept in Medicine,
which was going to be realized and to be understood a few centuries later.
That when we want to cure somebody we have to take into consideration
the functioning of this energy body.
So it is his biggest argument actually. "[...]The material organism without the
vital force, is capable of no sensation, no function, no self-preservation",
what keeps the organism rejuvenating all the time. It is this energy body.
In paragraph 11 says "When a person falls ill, it is only this spiritual,
self acting (automatic) vital force..." You see he struggles with different words
to define what this vital principle is, vital energy, energy body etc.
"[...]everywhere present in his organism, that is primarily deranged by
the dynamic influence upon it of a morbific agent inimical to life"
and he is really a forerunner.
Cellier much later said that the stress of life, he had written a whole book about
The stress... What is the stress in life? Is it something material, some stone
that hits you on the head? No, we don't call this a stress. We call it an accident.
A stress is an immaterial attack upon what? Since it is an immaterial attack,
it is going to attack something immaterial in the body.
It is not going to attack something material.
When somebody gives you an information, which is really valid for you
and it is very important, you listen somebody on the phone and says
"Your son..." immediately you are aware.
"Your son, he was in the football game...", you start trembling "...
and unfortunately they stepped down and he's in the hospital".
What is this shock? Is it a material shock? Where has an effect? Upon what?
What is the substratum upon which this stress has an effect?
You may say emotions. Yes, but emotions are becoming alive,
sensations are becoming alive because of the vital principle, because of the energy.
So behind the emotions and the thinking and the moving and the function
is a substratum, which Hahnemann called "vital force".
And then it was a whole movement "the vitalism" and then they rejected
the vitalism and became the materialism.
They said vitalism is nothing, we have to see everything.
What do we have to see? Do you see the stress? Do you see anything?
Is there any possibility for anyone to observe a stress on a human being?
So he says this material body is "[...] primarily deranged by the dynamic
influence upon it of a morbific agent inimical to life".
So the whole idea of the stress and how it is transferred into the organism
and through the vital principle or the energy, always remember there is
a substratum, an energy body, which is affected primarily and then
this shock is distributed to the 3 levels. Mental, emotional, physical.
Depending this stress, depending where it will have the worst damage
in the person, depending on the genetic predisposition of his organism.
If genetically he is mentally weak, it will derange his mind,
will make the mother or the woman out of her mind. I lost my child.
If there is a predisposition towards mental derangement.
If the predisposition is in the heart, she will have a heart attack.
If the predisposition is in the alimentary canal, will have a colitis,
next day she starts with pains in the abdomen and eventually
an ulcerative colitis develops.
We accept that the shock is totally an immaterial thing,
which receives the organism and we do not accept that the shock is perceived
by an equally immaterial agent.
This is a way of describing the energy body which keeps up alive.
"[...]it is only the vital principle, deranged to such an abnormal state
that can furnish the organism with its disagreeable sensations
and incline it to the irregular processes which we call disease".
So therefore he says most of the diseases are immaterial attacks
upon the human organism and the receiver is the vital principle.
"[...]for as a power invisible in itself and only cognizable by its effects on the organism,
its morbid derangement only makes itself known by the manifestation of disease
in the sensation and functions of those parts of the organism
exposed to the senses of the observer and physician, that is by morbid symptoms
and in no other way can it make itself known".
Hahnemann makes very long sentences. Maybe you will have a problem reading
but what he says is that this stress makes itself known only through symptoms.
If you receive a stress and for a time-being you have a shock but you overcome it,
there's no problem.
If they tell you whatever but you are in a position to resist or to handle that shock,
nothing happens. There's no problem.
He says if this shock creates problems in sensations and functions,
in feelings and in the function of the organs, then it produces symptoms.
These symptoms are the problem, are the disease. Very simple.
He repeats perhaps too much in order to make his point clear.
He repeats the same idea again and again.
In parag.12 "It is the morbidly affected vital energy alone that produces disease".
So he says, the beginning of all diseases starts in the energy body.
"[...]so that the morbid phenomena perceptible to our senses express
at the same time all the internal change, that is to say, the whole
morbid derangement of the internal dynamis".
"[...]so that the morbid phenomena", the symptoms which are expressed
and we perceive them, indicate all the internal changes that have happened
in the organism.
"[...]in a word, they reveal the whole disease..."
His mode of thinking, his strategy is to tell us that what is the manifestation
of the disease, which starts from a shock, from an effect on the vital force,
it is only the symptoms perceptible to the person, to his people around
and to the observer. This is all.
Because he wants to bring up the idea of similars eventually
He prepares you to perceive and tries again and again to tell you that
the derangement of the organism means automatically expression in signs
and symptoms. Later on we will say how this can be alleviated.
"[...]also, the disappearance under treatment of all the morbid phenomena
and all the morbid alterations that differ from the healthy vital operations,
certainly affects and necessarily implies the restoration of the integrity
of the vital force..."
If you take away the symptoms, you have certainly brought back health.
This is his idea. "[...]therefore, the recovered health of the whole body".
The organism has recovered.
And in 13 "Therefore disease (that does not come within the province of
manual surgery) considered, as it is by the allopathists, as a thing separate from
the living whole, from the organism and its animating vital force,
hidden in the interior, be it ever so subtle a character, is an absurdity,
that could only be imagined by minds of a materialistic stamp, and has
for thousands of years given to the prevailing system of Medicine
all those pernicious impulses that have made it a truly mischievous
(non-healing) art".
He expresses the idea of his time, of what they thought to be a disease.
In those times the idea was that a disease is something separate from the organism.
A disease has entered my organism, so I can take it out.
This was the idea of the time.
So, we have a healthy organism, suddenly a disease, an entity, has entered
my organism and now we have to find a way to take it out.
And how to take it out, most probably, the blood is the best way to take it out.
So draw blood to take out the entity of the disease.
He says, all this is absolutely nonsense.
Because the disease and the organism is now one and the same, of course.
It is the organism that has become diseased through the morbific,
inimical influence from the environment.
In paragraph 14 "There is, in the interior of man, nothing morbid that is curable
and no visible morbid alteration that is curable which does not make itself
known to the accurately observing physicians by means of morbid signs
and symptoms - an arrangement in perfect conformity with the infinite goodness
of all-wise Preserver of human life".
Here he says, there is nothing inside the organism which is separate
and the disease will make itself manifested with signs and symptoms
and arrangement.
You have to realize also something else about Hahnemann.
He's a man of vision, a man of perception who discovers things and
discovery is fantastic. It's tremendous what he finds out.
He finds out that all these nonsense they tell people, the disease as an entity
which has entered and I have to take it out... all this is nonsence.
What I realize is that there is an impact upon the organism, the organism reacts
with signs and symptoms and this is one thing, the organism and the disease now.
There is no separation. He realizes that all this is an arrangement that has been
done by the higher spirit, the "all-wise Preserver of human life".
This is a deep belief in God. He realizes like all people who discover
something essential in life... they come to believe that this complicated world
in which we live is not possible to be accidental.
Something is creating it and there is some power, some spirit
which is beyond our comprehension and that we will never understand
exactly what's going on. There is a power beyond which arranges all this,
there is a kind of harmony which cannot be accidental.
It is arranged by an all-wise Preserver of life. He gives in a way his understanding.
He says "I've discovered this. But I cannot explain it.
There is some higher power which is arranging that. I don't know what it is".
I'm sorry. Some of you may be materialists and you may disagree.
I'm trying to give you the spirit of Hahnemann, the understanding of Hahneman,
the knowledge of Hahnaman. I'm not going to teach you about God...
Allah is better than this or that... Cabala is better than the Bible etc.
I know you are from different beliefs. I'm trying to give you the understanding
of Hahnemann and what he writes here.
Whether we like it or not, this is what he says.
He says in paragraph 15, "The affection of the morbidly deranged,
spirit-like dynamis (vital force) that animates our body in the invisible interior
and the totality of the outwardly cognizable symptoms produced by it
in the organism and representing the existing malady, constitute a whole and
they are one and the same."
The same idea, all the symptoms which are produced in a morbidly
deranged organism, they are not separate from the organism.
The organism and the malady, the disease are together.
"[...]The organism is indeed the material instrument of the life, but it is not
conceivable without the animation imparted to it by the instinctively perceiving
and regulating dynamis (just as the vital force is not conceivable without the
organism), consequently the two together constitute a unity, although in thought
our mind separates this unity into two distinct conceptions
for the sake of easing the comprehension of it".
The disease and the organism are together. What we do is separate the one
from the other for the sake of understanding better. Disease is now this.
What he means is the totality of symptoms.
He's very accurate in his expression and he is meticulous and he wants to make
his point very clear. "That is why".
He repeats again and again the whole idea, so it can be understood very well
because it is a new idea that brings to the world.
How could he pass it into the consciousness of the people?
He feels he needs to give all the arguments.
If you have a question about anything, you can ask me.
Par. 16, "Our vital force, as a spirit-like dynamis, cannot be attacked
and affected by injurious influences on the healthy organism caused
by the external inimical forces that disturb the harmonious play of life,
otherwise than in a spirit-like (dynamic) way". It's the same idea.
You cannot affect this dynamic body which is inside us, the energy body,
but with equally dynamic influence.
If you want to affect a stone, can you affect it with air?
You have to have another stone to affect it. So he drives to the idea of similarities.
Then eventually he will say how can you affect this dynamic plane,
you have to have a dynamic instrument to affect it.
This is where he is driving to.
"[...]and in like manner, all such morbid derangements (diseases) cannot
be removed from it by the physician in any other way than by a dynamic
alternative power of the serviceable medicines, acting upon our spirit-like vital force"
You cannot remove this problem that was caused by a dynamic influence
upon the organism but only through another dynamic means.
"[...]which perceives them through the medium of the sentient faculty
of the nerves everywhere present in the organism, so that it is only by their
dynamic action on the vital force that remedies are able to re-establish
and do actually re-establish health and vital harmony
after the changes in the health of the patient cognizable by our senses
(the totality of the symptoms) have revealed the disease to the carefully
observing and investigating physician as fully as was requisite in order to enable
him to cure it". It's very long process. It's very simple.
He says this vital derangement of the organism can be cured only through
another vital effect upon the organism.
Par.17, "Now, as in the cure effected by the removal of the whole of
the perceptible signs and symptoms of the disease, the internal alteration
of the vital principle to which the disease is due - consequently the whole
of the disease - is at the same time removed, it follows that the physician
has only to remove the whole of the symptoms in order, at the same time,
to abrogate and annihilate the internal change, that is to say,
the morbid derangement of the vital force - consequently the totality of
the disease, the disease itself".
He hammers the same point again and again.
He says that now the only thing you have to do is through a dynamic influence
to bring back the harmony of the already deranged vital force.
"[...]But when the disease is annihilated, health is restored and this is the highest,
the sole aim of the physician who knows the true object of his mission,
which consists not in learned - sounding prating but in giving aid to the sick".
Hahnemann always had strict morality in his teachings.
He was a very conservative man with a brain that would open up to new ideas
and he realizes that if a physician has to understand really what he says and
apply it must also have an open mind and clean character.
He says "the highest, the sole aim of the physician".
That means in order to understand and to cure, your soul must be pure.
"[...] who knows the true object of his mission" you see again and again
he considers the work of the physician as a mission.
And this is not just prating and words.
Parag.18, "From this indubitable truth, that besides the totality of the symptoms
with consideration of the accompanying modalities (par. 5), nothing can by any means
be discovered in disease wherewith they could express their need of aid,
it follows undeniably that the sum of all the symptoms and conditions in such
individual case of disease, must be the sole indication, the sole guide to direct us
in the choice of a remedy".
Nothing but the totality of the symptoms should guide you to find the remedy.
It's very simple.
- Also in the first paragraphs he says if you deal with the symptoms, then you deal
with the disease. So here I struggle with the concept of latent disease,
latent psora, latent sycosis. You can't see it but it's there.
So what are the symptoms there? What do we do when we know there is a disease
and we can't see it?
-When there is a disease and we cannot see it?
- If Hahnemann says when there is disease, it makes itself known through symptoms.
So I struggle with the concept of latent disease.
-This is something which was not prevalent during these times.
This time human organisms were much more healthy belonging to the uppermost
level, as we said, and therefore feeling healthy.
If somebody was not healthy, an epidemic came and killed him.
And there was, what we call, a natural selection.
We, as human beings, managed to bypass this natural selection by doing what?
By interfering into the immune system of the organism and rearrange it
in such a way that you feel or you are in a condition where you don't feel
symptoms but actually your basic constitution has been undermined.
That concept that we have today was not prevalent during that time.
A latent condition today means that the hereditary predisposition of the person
is of a precarious state.
And with any shock, it could flare up and kill the person.
We have undermined our constitution so much that we have created this idea
of latent conditions that can flare up at any time,
under some kind of stress to which we are sensitive to.
Now you will say, why not? We did quite well as a society using the attainments,
using the discoveries of Medicine. What is the problem?
And why do we say today that there are Levels of Health and these kind of things?
The problem that we have created for ourselves is
that by interfering on the immune system, what we say to the immune system
"don't be affected by this agent, by streptococcus, scarlet fever, epidemics..."
And we have found a way to manipulate the immune system,
so it cannot be affected by this.
You have to remember that for every change that we manage to obtain
on the immune system, there is a change of the whole constitution,
which cannot be obvious like you took a vaccination and immediately
after the 4th, 5th day you paralyzes.
You took vaccination and then after a week you had a kidney damage.
You took this vaccination and you had a kind of mental derangement.
Autistic or psychotic problems etc.
The idea that there is such a side effect on the human organism
because of the interference with the vaccination.
The fact that there is obviously certain people even reach death after the vaccination.
We have these statistics, we know how many are reaching death,
how many had side effects. Nobody denies that.
What we don't realize is that everyone who takes a vaccination has a change
either bigger or lesser. Everyone. What is that change?
That change cannot be always attributed to a certain organ.
If you take this vaccination, your liver will be affected. No.
But the interference brings about a change of the whole organism.
That change of the whole organism is distributed on the whole organism.
And it can produce mild or subtle changes that are not obvious.
So they say "I took the vaccination and I had no side effects". This is not so.
The side effects were there. What was the side effect? The side effect could have been
even that you wake up in the morning and you were very happy seeing the sun,
now you are not so happy. This little thing which took away a little bit of joy of life.
This little thing is very important for the organism, it's very vital.
If you lose this, you start entering the world of diseases.
But now you say, "I have no problem, Ok, I lost a little bit of joy or I lost this or that...
I don't have symptoms". In reality you have started with an undermining
of the organ which has a predisposition due to your hereditary.
When it's your brain, it will be your brain. When it is liver, it will be the liver.
When there is the kidneys, it will be the kidneys or the lungs.
But it has undermined your hereditary weakness and has progressed it
towards breaking down.
If there is a hereditary mental problem, you will have an autistic child.
If there is a predisposition for the heart, you will have a heart problem at
10,15,20 years but it has started since the time you introduced this vaccination.
The idea of "I am healthy" today is a very relative concept.
When you examine a patient, you say "How many hours in your life you are happy?"
He answers "Who is happy?"
Compare the state of your patients with the state of the children.
Very happy all the time.
Now, these children have been vaccinated and eventually this happiness
will not remain, will be taken away slowly. No symptoms. We call it no symptoms.
But there are symptoms and there are indications for us to understand that
there is a possibility of a breaking down of some organ in the organism.
Why is the child always happy?
And why this happiness is almost totally gone, as you grow up?
Another example.
We have in the earth primitive tribes, who never had any vaccination,
they are living in the Amazon, they used to live in Africa.
If you have seen these people, perhaps you have seen documentaries,
how happy they are and how easily are happy with little things.
They dance, they laugh, they enjoy.
Why are we in such a bad mood and we can't enjoy as much as they do?
They don't enjoy through sex because our enjoyment is mostly sex and drinks.
I become drunk and I am happy. They don't. What's the difference?
If we vaccinate all these people, they will lose eventually their joy of life.
That losing of joy of life is the result of our generations having what we call
a latent state of disease. The disease is lurking under and is ready to flare up.
During this time of Hahnemann I expect most of the people were in a kind
of a primitive state. They were quite happy in spite of the fact they were poorer,
they had less automobiles... much less possibilities than we have.
Happiness is not depending on how much we are having, it's an inner state.
So interfere with your inner state with chemical drugs and
you will destroy the harmony.
And then you produce more and more organisms which have a predisposition
to be affected by any kind of stress.
We are living today in a constant state of stress. How can we enjoy?
Why have we arrived in this state? What is the real reason?
The reason is that we have treated the organism wrongly, not with Homeopathy.
You may say "Ok, what do you suggest? We don't vaccinate."
It is too late. Either you vaccinate or you don't vaccinate you ancestors have given
you a constitution which is not really healthy.
On top of that you are vaccinated, so how many hours of your life you are happy?
Very few. This lack of joy, we do not consider it as a symptom because
we don't perceive it as such. We attribute it to mode of life, to the social condition,
I don't have money, I'm in a bad mood, I don't have a car,
I need a car and I don't have one... This is not true.
People could be happy without anything.
I lived in India and I have seen the poorest people on Earth
according to my understanding in the 1960s
and you would see the children and the people so happy!
I was amazed to see that happiness in their eyes!
I was thinking "How can I go back to Europe and see these sad faces?"
You look around and you see sad faces all the time. You are living in happy people.
Very happy! I gave him a rupee. But he is happy whether I give him the rupee or not.
Before he was happy, after that he expressed his happiness.
All the time he is playful.
Last time I was in India it was 2000, about 40 years later.
It was a different situation.
A lot of vaccination of course and a lot of treatment with chemical drugs.
I saw the same degenerative signs that I had observed in Europe.
These are facts that I don't know how to change but these are facts.
"Now, as diseases are nothing more than alterations in the state of health
of the healthy individual which express themselves by morbid signs
and the cure is also only possible by a change to the healthy condition of the state
of health of the diseased individual,
it is very evident that medicines could never cure diseases,
if they did not possess the power of altering man's state of health,
which depends on sensations and functions.
Indeed, their curative power must be owing solely to this power they possess
of altering man's state of health".
Since diseases are changes in the state of health, if we want to cure diseases
we should find a tool that can change the state of the health of the people.
Indeed in reality the curative power of the remedies must depend exclusively
to this power that possess of altering man's state of health.
He introduces the idea of provings. He says disease changes the state of health.
Remedies change the state of health.
That means the remedy that could alleviate the symptoms must have the possibility
to change the state of health, like a disease.
Disease has the power to change. Remedies must have the power to change
the state of health.
He introduces the idea of proving.
"[...]This spirit-like power to alter man's state of health (and hence to cure diseases)
which lies hidden in the inner nature of medicines, can in itself never be discovered
by us by a mere effort of reason; it is only by experience of the phenomena,
it displays when acting on the state of health of man that we can become
clearly cognizant of it."
Here he says that the power of the medicines to change the health
cannot be recognized by mere reason.
That means we cannot say that if you take a medicine which has a bitter taste
will help your liver. Because the liver needs more bitter things.
He says that in order to say later on that we have to try the different remedies
upon the human organisms in order to see what changes can produce.
The idea is that he wants us to understand that the tool we are going to use
it has to be tested first in the human organism.
Not imagining, not reasoning, not anything of that type with the mind
with the imagination. Are facts.
"Now, as it is undeniable that the curative principle in medicines is not
in itself perceptible..."
The real power of the drug is not the fact that the remedy is green or the remedy
has this or that consistency or anything like that.
He brings a totally new idea that the remedies have a power which is hidden
in the remedy. Nobody can see it.
He has understood that the effect of the remedies are not depending
on their chemical substance.
Depend on their inner power to change the health of the humans.
"[...]and as in pure experiments with medicines conducted by the most accurate
observers, nothing can be observed that can constitute them medicines or remedies
except that power of causing distinct alterations in the state of health
of the human body and particularly in that of the healthy individual..."
Only a pure experiment upon the healthy can reveal the power of the remedies.
"[...]and of exciting in him various definite morbid symptoms; so it follows that
when medicines act as remedies, they can only bring their curative property
into play by means of this, their power of altering man's state of health
by the production of peculiar symptoms..."
So the remedies can cure because they have the power to produce peculiar
symptoms to themselves. "[...]and therefore, we have only to rely on the morbid
phenomena which the medicines produce in the healthy body, as the sole possible
revelation of their in-dwelling curative power."
So we have to rely exclusively on the possibility of the remedies that have
to produce morbid symptoms, which are beyond health.
"[...]and at the same time what disease-curing power, each individual medicine
possesses."
He brings the idea here to two things; first that the remedies have an inner power
to change the state of health and the second is that the symptoms they can alter
and produce in the human organism are the ones that will guide you to the selection
of the remedy.
"But as nothing is to be observed in diseases that must be removed in order
to change them into health besides the totality of their signs and symptoms,
and likewise medicines can show nothing curative besides their tendency to produce
morbid symptoms in healthy persons and to remove them in diseased persons".
He says, in the same way that in a disease we can only see the totality of symptoms,
in medicines also we have to use the totality of the symptoms the remedy can
produce in order to alleviate these symptoms. Here is the law of similars.
The phrases are too long and sometimes you have to epitomize.
"[...]it follows, on the one hand, that medicines only become remedies and capable
of annihilating disease because the medicinal substance, by exciting certain effects
and symptoms, that is to say, by producing a certain artificial morbid state, removes
and abrogates the symptoms already present, to wit, the natural morbid state
we wish to cure."
What he says is that the remedy which has similar symptoms with the disease
will take away the symptoms of the disease.
The similarity of the symptoms produced by the remedy will take away the totality
of the symptoms.
"[...] On the other hand, it follows that, for the totality of the symptoms of the disease
to be cured, that medicine must be sought which have the greatest tendency
to produce similar or opposite symptoms."
He says that we must try to find the remedy which has produced similar symptoms
in order to prescribe it to the patient. "(according as experience shall prove whether
the morbid symptoms are most readily, certainly, and permanently removed and
changed into health by similar or opposite medicinal symptoms)"
"The other possible mode of employing medicines for diseases besides these two
is the allopathic method in which medicines are given, whose symptoms have
no direct pathological relation to the morbid state, neither similar nor opposite,
but quite heterogeneous to the symptoms of the disease".
In order to make us understand what he wants to say, he says
if you give a remedy that has produced similar symptoms this will alleviate
the totality of the symptoms of the case.
There is another way that you can prescribe an opposite.
That means you want to stop diarrhea. You will give a remedy that produces
constipation. These are the 2 ways.
Besides that there are other allopathic methods where they give any remedy
for any reason.
But the 2 most acceptable ways of prescribing remedies is the similar and the opposite.
He accepts that by giving an opposite, a remedy that produces the opposite symptoms
than the one the patient has, is a way of prescribing remedies.
He realizes it like Hippocrates also.
He says that remedies could be prescribed by having opposite effect on the problem
of the patient. If the patient has diarrhea, you give a remedy that can produce
constipation. And you give it in big doses and you cure it.
This was a way existing since the time of Hippocrates.
It was Hippocrates who brought this idea of the opposites first
and Hahnemann knew all that and he refers to this.
He said this is logical. But it is not logical if you give a remedy which has nothing
to do with the symptomatology of the person.
That means you give a remedy that has no opposite or similar effects then...
this cannot have an effect at all.
"All pure experience, however, and all accurate research convince us that
persistent symptoms of disease are far from being removed and annihilated
by opposite symptoms of medicines."
He explains and says there is that but he says that "all accurate research convince us
that persistent symptoms of disease are far from being removed" by the opposites.
He says you can give an opposite, you can give a laxative to a case
where there is constipation. You give a drug which produces diarrhea.
But this fact is far from being removed and annihilated, but these symptoms are really
not removed and annihilated by opposite symptoms of medicines.
"[...]that, on the contrary, after transient, apparent alleviation, they break forth again"
You take the remedy for constipation, you have this diarrhea but on the contrary
next time you may have stronger diarrhea.
"[...] only with increased intensity and become manifestly aggravated".
He relates his experience because they used to give several drugs on material doses
to have an effect and he has noticed that later on after the patient has used frequently
heavy doses of remedies on the idea of the opposites,
eventually they had an aggravation. And he concludes, therefore
"There is only one way of employing medicines in diseases that promises to be of
service besides the homoeopathic, there is no other, by means of which we seek,
for the totality of the symptoms of the case of disease, a medicine which among
all medicines has the power and the tendency to produce an artificial morbid state
most similar to that of the case of disease in question."
Therefore you seek to find the most close remedy that has produced
similar symptoms.
All this concept is targeting towards the idea of one remedy.
You have to find a remedy which has a similar totality of symptoms.
That is why we cannot accept to practice Homeopathy with mixtures of remedies.
This is what I realized when I read the Organon.
I have taken these mixtures of remedies, they had some effect but at the same time
they had side effect. Therefore then when I read this, I understood how wrong it was
to practice Medicine with mixopathy, mixtures of remedies.
And then when I tried to find out what was going on in the world at this time
I found out that actually the 95% of the Homeopaths of the time in the 60s
prescribed mixtures of remedies, because they did not want to sit down with
the patient and discover his totality of the symptoms.
And then they had not studied enough the M.M. to realize that this concept
fits with this concept.
Paragraph 25, "Now, however, in all careful trials, pure experience,
the sole and infallible oracle of the healing art, teaches us that actually
that medicine which, in its action on the healthy human body, has demonstrated
its power of producing the greatest number of symptoms similar to those observable
in the patient, does also, in doses of suitable potency and attenuation, rapidly,
radically and permanently remove the totality of the symptoms of this morbid state."
Observation is the only way to perceive the real truth of what is happening.
"[...] the sole and infallible oracle of the healing art"
Observation and pure experience teaches that this is the only way
that you can cure cases.