The idea of this seminar will be to discuss the main book
which is the Organon of Hahnemann and to really exchange ideas.
What I have in my mind is to read you the paragraph, then talk to you
concerning the meaning of what I understand to be the meaning
underline the paragraph and then I would like you to give me your aspect
or your understanding concerning this paragraph.
I will start, of course, with the first paragraph of the Organon
which says "The physician's high and only mission is to restore the sick to health,
to cure, as it is termed".
This is a paragraph that Hahnemann decided to put as an epitome of his experience
so far. He intended when he was writing this... he had done all the experiments,
he had cured a lot of people, he had organized his team for provings etc.
and he'd being a physician all his life and having been disappointed from what he was
practicing before, he was totally disappointed as you know from the conventional way
of treating and he wrote this paragraph.
Actually this paragraph contains for me all his aspirations and all his experience
in medicine. He was full of different ideas, theories of his time etc.
And suddenly he found a system which is effective, which can cure without side effects.
He was so excited with his new discovery and he says
just to hell with all these theories and aspects, ways of practicing medicine.
He says "The physician's high...", "highest", actually should be the correct expression
"... and only mission". Here the emphasis is "only mission".
You can understand his mentality and his way of thinking when he says
the physician has a mission, not a profession and the physician's highest and only
calling is to cure the sick.
For him the idea is that unless somebody is concentrated upon the idea of curing
the people cannot fulfill his mission as a doctor, as a physician.
This is the physician's only calling, highest and only calling.
If we go to compare with what is going on today in conventional medicine
we'll see what a distance there is between the concept of Hahnemann and the concept
of contemporary doctors.
The contemporary physician is well-versed in reading some medical tests
he has ordered, he will then decide that this is the best medicine for your problem.
He will give the recipee and send you to what we all know to be a state of health
which is worse than the previous state in which the patient came.
This paragraph is very applicable and should be taught to all medical schools.
You see today medicine has arrived to a state in which they say we believe only
in evidence-based medicine. Everybody now is repeating like a parrot
"evidence-based medicine". The same thing Hahnemann says.
Do you know what is the difference? The difference is the understanding of what
is evidence-based medicine today than what it was evidence-based medicine in
Hahnemann's time.
Evidence-based medicine in Hahnemann's time was to cure, simply.
Just cure your patient. Can you cure? Yes. You have fulfilled your mission.
Forget about the money, the prestige, all the other things that go together with that.
And I can assure you that if you learn to do this everything else will come, naturally.
You will have enough money to live, you will have enough prestige, you will have the
love of your patients, of the society, everything will come with this ability
to cure the sick.
Today evidence-based medicine... they understand... they say their own words.
Do you know what they think evidence-based medicine is?
Evidence-based medicine they understand or they want to interpret that whatever
you do, you have to be able to prove it. Why this person is cured?
Because we gave antibiotics which cure the specific bacteria and therefore we have
the evidence that this medicine kills the microbes. This is evidence-based medicine.
In a Congress in America somebody, I have inside information...
There was a congress in America with professors and discussing evidence-based
medicine...
One of the professors got up and said "Do you really realize what you are saying?"
Everybody was amazed. Homeopaths will come and according to this dictum
they will say that we can only have evidence-based medicine, that means we can only
prove that we cure people.
So there was actually a big realization and after this international Congress
the evidence-based medicine idea was much reduced and became a low profile idea.
Otherwise they would have promoted aggressively all over the world.
You want to say that you cure this patient, first you prove that what you prescribe is
affecting in this and that way the organism.
They thought through this idea they will kill all alternative medicine.
You are a psychiatrist and you do psychotherapy. How can you prove?
What did you do? Nothing. And you prove not, out! Which is the idea?
That only the medicine that we produce as a pharmaceutical industry is the only
medicine that has a proof that it can cure and we have the evidence.
It was a big mistake for them.
Because as this professor said...
By chance inside this Congress there was a professor who was my patient.
So he says "George, I must tell you I was participating in this Congress
and somebody, not myself, somebody else a very famous, very hard conventional
professor got up and said "Be careful, the homeopaths will use these dictum in their
favor". And that is true.
So underneath this phrase of Hahnemann you start to understand his spiritual and
his logical mind that was really caring about the sick.
A man who had tried to apply medicine in his time, he saw it did not work,
gave up medicine and said "I cannot continue to destroy the people with this kind
of medicine. I am going to start translating, make my living with these translations".
You see how honest he was? How spiritually powerful he was?
He gave it up, he had seven children, he says "I will start translating".
He knew seven languages, he had studied everything.
He was translating and earning his living and suddenly came across with the idea
"My God, if I give China and I have a replication that produces a similarity to malaria
that means China is curing because of the similarity to malaria. Let me see.
Producing similar symptoms to malaria and China, quinine was given for malaria.
There was explanation because it was bitter, for different other reasons.
His reason was this medicine actually is useful because it can produce in the healthy
similar symptoms. So he tried again and again with different remedies
and he saw the replication of different pathological states.
He said "Oh my God, that is a huge discovery".
And then he reads Hippocrates and finds there the idea. The idea was there.
Hippocrates had said that with similars we cure similars. And then he found the idea in
some other doctors that had noticed the same idea.
And that discovery brings him finally to experiment and to apply what he found from
the experiments and finally he writes this paragraph.
Underneath this paragraph is therefore all his life, all his beliefs, his faith, whatever...
They have said Hahnemann was a mason, he was this and that, he was whatever.
It has nothing to do with religion. It is the belief, the faith in the goodness of a mind
which is healthy, which is powerful and which is spiritually sound.
"I want to cure people". And the physician who is really a physician must want to do
the same thing. This is the paragraph, what it says in a few words.
I have not prepared anything, you may think I have prepared, you make a mistake.
I am just thinking together with you. The idea is whether you read the Organon
and you understand it. Because when I read the Organon for the first time in 1960,
I was reading the Organon and I said "Oh my God, it's so correct! "
I was reading and my mind was going along with his way of thinking.
This book was very easy for me to read and to understand.
Later on, I found out from homeopaths that Organon was so difficult to read, so difficult
to understand. Hahnemann writes in such a language...
Even the Germans would come and tell me that Organon is very difficult to understand.
I said how is this possible? And then I had decided one day to make comments on
the Organon and this is the beginning of these comments.
I would like to hear your ideas concerning the first paragraph, your questions,
another aspect that you may have.
Especially for Homeopathy today which, as I said, we have a lot of people
practicing Homeopathy but curing because of placebo effect...So if you don't learn,
you are basing your practice as a homeopath in the placebo effect.
You cannot say I practice Homeopathy, you should say I practice placebo effect.
Placebo effect is so common. Because somebody cannot sleep and what he does?
He makes a prayer because a prayer is believing that it is going to calm him down
and he can sleep. Placebo effect.
Another one, he takes passiflora, just a drop of passiflora , he believes that
passiflora will make him sleep.
Another one will read a paragraph, whatever...
But everything we will do to cure or to stop a symptom will be only according
to the faith we have to what we are doing.
And if this is mild, if it is something which is mild, whatever auto-suggestion we decide
to use, it will work.
This is what we call auto-suggestion. This is a very well-known phenomenon
of course, nobody denies. But to cure a condition which is really going on for years,
a chronic condition, is totally a different story.
- When I read the first paragraph of Organon, I was suddenly infected by an idea
and I found that finally somebody says it with clear words.
The doctor, he has to cure, it is easy. How can people make it so complicated
when the main idea is so easy?
Something else concerning the placebo effect which has been discussed also before.
I'm a medical doctor, when I treat patients with Homeopathy, they often ask me
"But now I have to believe and I have to suggest myself that it will be like that".
And I say "No, you don't have to believe anything. What you should do is to observe
precisely what is going on and obey to the rules..."
- What changes happen after the remedy...
- Yes, in detail and take care of the rules; no camphor, no coffee also... And then we will
see and just keep open-minded and I have the impression that makes the people more
free from this kind of...
- Yes. Anybody?
- I believe that of course the idea is very easy but I have many problems with the simple
word "to cure" because men cannot cure. It is the vital force, the nature itself
which cures. What we can do is to take off any obstacles to cure
or to see what is preventing the disease from healing itself.
This is really one thing which I don't like about this first paragraph that is to claim
to cure. Because to cure is something that men cannot do. They are not healers.
-Stephan, I understand. The second part you say.. the obstacles to cure, we will discuss
it later in the paragraph.
You bring up a philosophical aspect into this paragraph, which is the idea of cure.
What do we mean when we say "we cure".
Hahnemann is more practical than a philosophical explanation of the word "cure".
Because, as you know there's no cure in its absolute sense.
In the absolute sense, I am cured... there is not such an idea.
Because the process of life is such that will lead you definitely to a deterioration,
to disease and to death. This is the natural process of life.
So therefore, the idea of cure takes a relative importance and this relative importance
also can be debated, what exactly do we mean.
But if we analyze in that kind of depth the idea of cure, we will be entangled in
discussions that could be useful philosophically but not useful as practical application
of a system of medicine.
Hahnemann, don't forget, was a doctor who thought "I will cure people" when he went
to the school he thought "I will learn how to cure people".
So, his idea was to relieve the pain, later on he will define what is a cure for him,
in the paragraph, he will define it very exactly.
But in this paragraph the word "cure" for him it is the alleviation of all the symptoms
of an organism.
Later on, he will say it, if I have a system which alleviates all the symptoms of the
organism, I have accomplished a cure.
But if that was true and we could at all times alleviate the system, alleviate the
symptoms, then we have to arrive at the idea of immortality.
Because why should I die? If I have system that every time alleviates disease...
next month I'm 80 and I have been using Homeopathy exclusively for 52 years,
I use exclusively Homeopathy without ever having used allopathic drugs and I manage
to alleviate the symptoms every time but my condition today is the same as it was
50 years ago? Of course not.
What underneath has taken place, a deterioration of the tissues of the organism,
of the cells which they become weaker and weaker...
So therefore there is an end.
And therefore underneath there is always the possibility of disease.
So always the possibility of disease is lurking over there. Never mind the best
Homeopathy you can apply. You cannot say "cure" in its absolute sense.
So I believe Stephan who is very philosophical he meant exactly that.
What we mean by "cure". Is that, Stephan?
So I want to proceed to the second paragraph.
"The highest ideal of cure is rapid, gentle and permanent restoration of the health,
or removal and annihilation of the disease in its whole extent, in the shortest, most
reliable and most harmless way, on easily comprehensible principles".
Here again we have the experience of Hahnemann in his time with his patients
and his fellow beings who were around him during his time of life and he was writing
that, look at this, "The highest ideal of cure is rapid", immediately.
Many times people come and say "Well, your medicine is slow. I'm in a hurry.
I want to get rid of my pain very fast.
And we say "Well, it's slow but maybe it's better, a better way".
But Hahnemann says "rapid". Rapid in comparison with what?
What he knew at that time as a possibility for a cure.
"Gentle". Because he was so disgusted with all these kind of practices especially
with blood letting, with leeches, draining blood, so the disease will go out
with the blood, until people died of anemia etc.
"Gentle and permanent restoration of the health".
Now we have to bring these ideas to our contemporary reality.
What is our contemporary reality?
Is the cure of diseases that we treat rapid?
I'm afraid that here Hahnemann has mostly in his mind, he has the acute diseases.
He has seen the amazing effect of the homeopathic remedy in acute diseases.
He is so amazed that he will see a common cold, give a remedy and the next day is
better. He's in a shock, in a fright and you give an Aconite and the next day the effect
of fright, anxiety and panic is gone from the one day to the other.
There is a pneumonia and the pneumonia instead of the person goes on for 3, 5
weeks left by himself actually by that time, it takes 3-4 weeks for him to recover from
a pneumonia state at these days, he sees that he is cured within 4 days.
So for him it's very rapid and very gentle. And also permanent.
Here it is something that Hahnemann could see with the organism he was dealing
during that time. The organisms of the German people at the time were strong
constitutions. There were so clear pictured, you give a remedy and the effect was
amazing. Do we have the same kind of organisms today? This is the problem.
Do we deal with the same strong constitutions today? Or today we deal with
degenerated organisms? That you will have to battle sometimes for years before
you can bring about a balance in such organisms.
So therefore this rapid, gentle, permanent is for this time and as far as I am concerned
it applies today to strong constitutions, which come to be treated for acute conditions.
Chronic conditions, especially if they belong to lower levels of health, as we have
explained... So according to the level of health the uppermost levels of health
to which very few people belong, this is applicable.
But it has to be the uppermost levels of health of people.
Then you will see amazing reactions, never mind what is the pathology.
The reactions will be amazing. You may see this but only for the uppermost levels
of health. And what is the biggest problem today in our civilizations especially
Europe and America? The people of Western civilization, as we call it, they have
been undermined so deeply in their health that the focus of the disease has gone
deeper and deeper to the mental and emotional side.
That is the biggest problem we have. People are so confused mentally and emotionally.
They are so confused because they tried a lot of experiments. A lot of experimentation.
When I was, back in '71, in America teaching there and all kinds of crazy things were
going on and my students, the doctors would say "do you know about that?"
I said "please, tell me." They were relating to me all these crazy things which
I could not understand why they do it.
They would say, we have schools in which people go and what they do?
They touch each other. They touch. They're in a line and you have to do all this in order
to get the idea of being in touch with each other and you have to do all this in order to be
able to communicate and of course from the touch to the shoulder, goes to the touch
to the other etc... In order to do what? To excite themselves sexually.
Why? Because they cannot be excited. Sexual excitement in an environment which is
supposed to be a specialist who will tell you how to do it, how to make love to the
person whom you love. This is a totally crazy idea. This is automatic.
Anybody knows what to do when he is in love with somebody else.
Automatically, instinctively. If you lose this basic instinct, then you may need
treatment of course. And the treatment you do, if the problem has gone so deep
as not to be able to touch these basic human instinct, that means you have lost the
possibility to be aroused sexually. You lost it totally because of the interference of the
mental level, which is making a lot of thinking.
Critical about the other person, thinking all kind of things etc... Self-awareness.
What is self-awareness? Self-awareness means that you are looking for yourself
and you don't like yourself. This is self-awareness.
What could I do? The human beings have such a possibility naturally that if you meet
a person of the other sex, your natural tendency will be, if you like the person,
the natural tendency is to give and take in a state of non-selfishness.
If you are aware of yourself, how I speak, how I do, how I move...
If you were little children and you like a girl, you feel uncomfortable.
How I speak, what I do, etc. But this is a natural protection.
It has to be like that because if you lose this natural protection, when you are 12
you start having sex. This is terrible.
The natural protection is to be embarrassed.
You feel embarrassed when you are in a very young age 12,13,14,15 you feel
embarrassed with the other girls/ boys, you feel embarrassed and closed.
And this is a natural protection. Now in our society because we have been deeply
affected by disease, once you grow you cannot let yourself to the idea of unification
with the other. You remain self-aware.
You make sex and at the same time your mind goes away to whatever.
What am I doing now... Once this happens, then you separate.
You cannot continue actually. That kind of deep disturbance in order to be cured
needs a lot of homeopathic remedies and also a kind of very careful prescribing for
long time. Because the problem is deep.
Why do we say that people who are coming from villages, who are more primitive
and instinctive and they act... they give you a case which is very clear.
The more intellectual is a person, the worse is the case. You cannot make out.
It can be this or it can be that. I may feel cold but this may be because... an explanation.
I like onions but I have heard that onions they are good for me.
I take salt/ I do not take salt because I have heard that salt... And you cannot find.
You are totally confused what this organism wants. I don't know.
You are trying to find the basic instincts of the organism.
The basic reactions of the organism and you cannot. Is it possible to cure such people?
If you think Ok, I have aversion to sex, woman that needs Sepia.
They take Sepia and sex desire comes back. What is this?
This is not due to degeneration, it is due to physical imbalances.
Physical imbalance can be affected by Homeopathy a lot and quite easily.
But mental disturbance, the undermining of the mental or the emotional level,
it will take very long time to cure.
Many times you will see in your practice that a person with all these problems,
all these psychotic problems one day due to your treatment or due to whatever
reasons he comes to face his own problems, his own truth.
Once he comes, he realizes "I'm living in a darkness, in a confusion" and then there is
a relief in that person. There is a big relief, an enlightment.
If what he was having was quite serious mental/ emotional disturbance, which is
now gone in such an abrupt way to the extent that this was very serious,
to the same extent you will see this happening in his physical body.
That's why you may start having stomach problems, you may have colitis, you may
have all kinds of physical problems etc. which can extend up to malignancy.
A person who is so deeply diseased on mental/ emotional level, if I see a big change,
I will expect severe problems on the physical level.
Orthodox/ conventional medicine they know it, they call it somatization of the disease.
They have seen it happening. Because we are living with guilt, suppressed emotions,
suppressed grief etc. we can live years after years but these suppressed emotions,
this deep guilt, which comes because the mother said something, created a condition
to the child, "Don't do that, it's very bad! Don't go with a man! Man is very bad..."
The mother does not know how to handle the situation and makes an impact to the
child and the child becomes totally impossible to have connection with the other side.
Instead of saying wait, it's very beautiful to be in love but not now because you are 12
and your menses just started, that means you are woman...
But when you suppress, the emotions will be there but will appear how?
In the form of hysterical reactions, all kinds of strange reactions, shouting, in a
very unnatural way. You say Ok, I didn't say anything.
You insulted me... You go to an American woman and you say one word a little bit
more... and you're finished. They will take you to the court.
You say, for God's sake I wanted to make a compliment...
Of course the emotions are distorted, are not pure anymore. They are not emotions
of love, they are emotions which have been poisoned by the societal, environmental,
family conditions.
This is the most in our societies. So Hahnemann in his second paragraph talks about
that time and also says further "annihilation of the disease in its whole extent".
If you read this, you think you give a remedy and everything is finished, I cure
everything. But Hahnemann himself realizes few years later that when you treat
chronic diseases, it's not that simple and as he thinks more and more, he sees more
and more cases, he realizes that there are underlying problems which he calls
the miasms. The syphilitic, the sycotic and the psoric.
He establishes these 3 miasms as a reason for not being cured diseases easily.
When he says later on "I realize that the disease was deep and needed a miasmatic
treatment", it means that you cannot see in the shortest way and the annihilation
of all the symptoms.
Our generations they are not only affected by the 3 miasms, most of us, but we are
affected by more miasms that we know today.
And we have to unravel this and we have to learn all the process, what to do and how
to do it. And this is the difficulty in Homeopathy. You have to realize what it is now
underneath what I treated. I treat a level and a new symptomatology comes up
as a new level.
Paragraph 3, aphorism 3. Hahnemann who has a very systematic way of seeing things
and thinking..
Look at this paragraph how he says a lot of things.
"If the physician clearly perceives what is to be cured in diseases, that is to say,
in every individual case of disease (knowledge of disease, indication)".
You see what he says here "If the physician clearly perceives..."
He doesn't say "clearly sees". It is a difference between "see" and "perceive"
because the disease is not what only we see but what we perceive, as a patient
perceives about himself and also the doctor perceives about the patient.
So therefore what has been reduced today is clinical examination from established
medicine. They say, you don't have to speak. I press you. You feel pain here.
It's a stomach pain or it's a gallbladder pain. And I press you there and there is another
one and I hear your lungs there are some rattles in bronchi and then I see your heart,
there are some missing beats etc... Ok, have a cardiogram, have this, have an
examination in your lungs and come back and I give you the prescription.
He has not spoken to the person, the patient goes out many times and he says
"Well, he did not examine me. He did not ask me anything.
He did not ask me to tell him what's going on with me". This is most of the time.
Hahnemann perceives this is going to happen and that's why he says not just what
you see but he goes further to explain what he means.
He says "in every individual case of disease".
First says "If he perceives what is to be cured in diseases..."
This would be an indication that Hahnemann believed in diseases.
Believed that there are diseases that have to be cured which is not true.
That is why he completes the phrase by saying "If he perceives what is to be cured
in every individual case", not in a disease, Ok... In duodenal ulcer you have to close
the ulcer. That is not enough. You have to know what is curable in every
individual case. What that means...
He realizes that in an individual case, you may understand what can be cured.
You have to be able to have the knowledge in quotation.
It says "knowledge of the disease and indications". You have the knowledge of
diseases but you have to perceive what can be cured in this individual case.
Which is something that we do of course because we know we cannot do otherwise.
In a particular case we can say we can cure so far or so much...
And what is more interesting is that many times the homeopaths confuse individual
characteristics of a personality, take them as symptoms and want to treat them.
Every one of us has individual personality characteristics. It's a different personality.
The fact there is here a sign that each one is different. That difference is in
characteristics of personality. Everyone has his own characteristics.
If you take all together the characteristics, the total characteristics of the personality
of that person, it's different from the total characteristics of another person.
Therefore each one of us has personality characteristics, which cannot be changed.
If you seek to change such characteristics, you will be giving remedies for ever and
you will not be able to do it.
Her characteristic is to be sympathetic. She's suffering...
That kind of characteristic is in her personality. If that characteristic goes beyond
the usual, everyday characteristic, as she knew herself and she will come and tell you
"I am extremely sympathetic to someone who is suffering and my life has become a
hell because I cannot see anybody suffering and I suffer". That characteristic that was
there has gone to pathology. That characteristic you can bring back to normal but not
eliminate it all together.
Some other personality is very hard and he's not bothered whether somebody is
suffering or not suffering and this is a characteristic of his.
But he says "I have become so hard that I need to inflict pain to others in order to feel
that I'm alive, that I have some feelings".
When the original hardness goes so far, that is pathology.
For instance people who enjoy are the people who work in the police departments or
in the army departments, which are the ones who inflict the punishment, who torture,
the torturers.
These people they have from their own characteristic, they are choosing because
they are hard in their character. When such people that are choosing to inflict torture
on the prisoners, they enjoy this in order to be able to feel some joy... that is a problem.
That is pathology. You can take into consideration this, the exaggeration of his particular
quality and treat it.
Hahnemann says you must perceive what can be treated, don't go as far as trying to
change the personality of the person. When you perceive what can be treated, then...
that is a knowledge which is beyond the knowledge of a clinician, of a medical doctor
who knows clinical medicine. Hahnemann wants you to understand, to perceive
with your whole being what is to be cured there.
Where this organism has gone astray. You perceive it. You don't say it to the patient,
you don't need to explain to the patient a lot of things but you realize when you give
the remedy, then you know whether he's coming back.
When he comes back in the follow up, he gives you... ok, he's going good.
That knowledge is not enough. You have understood the diseases and you have
understood also what is to be cured in each individual case.
That means the peculiarities of each one. But now he says "if he clearly perceives what is curative in medicine".
So you perceive what can be cured in a disease but also you have to know what a
remedy can cure.
"[...] that is to say, in each individual medicine (knowledge of medicinal powers)",
knowledge of what we know to be the Materia Medica.
So you know what can be cured but also you have to know the Materia Medica.
Not imagination, provings.
"[...]and if he knows how to adapt, according to clearly defined principles"..
Later on he will give the principles on which you can apply the medicine.
"[...]what is curative in medicines to what he has discovered to be undoubtedly morbid
in the patient".
Then you learn your M.M. and then you understand that this is pathology in the patient.
And this is very important that you have a good education in conventional medicine,
not all the details, you don't need it.
But understanding that this is a case of cancer, it's not a case of simple influenza or
something like that. It's a case of cancer.
This is a case of rectal cancer and not hemorrhoids.
This is a case of cancer on the colon, it's not simple colitis.
You have to know that, otherwise you will be in trouble one day or another.
"[...]so that the recovery must ensue - to adapt it, as well in respect to the suitability
of the medicine most appropriate according to its mode of action to the case before
him (choice of the remedy, the medicine indicated), as also in respect to the exact
mode of preparation and quantity of it required".
The doctor has to know how the remedy was prepared, if it was prepared properly,
first of all, and then he has to define the potency, the dose.
Dose here means potency and repetition. I think he mentions repetition.
"[...]and the proper period of repeating the dose; - if, finally, he knows the obstacles
to recovery in each case and is aware how to remove them, so that the restoration
may be permanent, then he understands how to treat judiciously and rationally,
and he is a true practitioner of the healing art".
That means you know the disease, you know the medicine, you know how to apply
the one to the other, you know the dose, you know the potency...
But one more you have to know; the obstacles that prevent this patient from
being cured. And when he says "obstacles" by that time he describes, if you have
a little stone in your eye and you have to take the stone out, or a little piece of
metal that is bothering you and things like that... this is not all.
We have obstacles which can be physical obstacles and most of what we face today
are obstacles on a mental/ emotional level. These are the worst obstacles.
Because the society in which we live creates for us such big stresses.
As far as profession is concerned, as far as emotional life is concerned and as far as
social life is concerned, it creates such problems, such stresses that can be so huge
that even the homeopathic remedy will take away a whole lot of symptoms
because of this grief that you have, but the grief is not over.
You have lost your son, the beloved son, your beloved mother, father
and the remedy will be given and will take away...
but if the obstacle is there, you have to take into consideration which is the obstacle.
You have a child which is autistic and you feel this is a big load on your life.
You have decided that is your mission to look after that child in the family and you
become the victim of that family situation.
So the doctor comes and he discusses and sees the child in his sees the mother,
what she is suffering from and why she's suffering and all that.
She asks about the child, she says, well this is my mission in life, to look after this child.
But this mission in life is not taken lightly. It's a mission you carry on your shoulders.
This is different from a mother who is very happy looking after the child.
Because maybe this is a positive thing. But the stress, the obstacle to cure, the stress
will become an obstacle.
An obstacle to cure can be all the things we hide and we consider them as illegal.
I have stolen money from somebody, I have killed somebody, I have an illegal affair
and nobody knows and I keep it inside. That will become an obstacle to cure.
Because it's not confessed. Has not come out to light.
The person cannot see his own truth.
If they cannot see their own truth, they remain in a dark area.
There are dark areas inside. These dark areas, between light and dark,
between life and death...
Do you connect life with dark? No. Life is connected with light.
The idea of death is connected with darkness.
So therefore you keep these dark spots, you keep death inside.
It will affect your lungs, it will affect your heart, it will affect your guts, it will affect
your stomach, whatever... it will affect your body.
And that dark spot will keep your stomach not working with a cancer and finally
it reaches the stage of cancer.
Therefore you give a remedy, it goes better for a while, back, repeat the remedy,
back again, change the remedy, back again...
These are the dark areas, what is preventing the homeopathic remedy to act.
When this can be alleviated? When the person realizes "I am a criminal.
I have done this and that... I'm so bad...".
Why in religions they have found that if a person wants to free himself from his own
guilt, he has to confess and to repent.
The monks they live without having sexual contact.
The sexual instinct is a very powerful instinct. It has to be controlled, so there are a lot
of fantasies... Could the monk live in a monastery with these fantasies?
So they have found a way to get rid of the effect of the fantasies. What is it?
For every monk there is a person, his spiritual mentor where he goes every day and
says "I have thought, I did this, I thought very badly about other monk, I had fantasies
about sex...". You cry, he says "Ok, you go". Next day you go again.
Otherwise nobody can live in the monastery. If in the monastery they don't do that,
they don't have this strategy what's going to happen? A monastery of orgies.
Orgies take place in the monastery. Because everyone gets loose and the dark elements
which are kept secret, inside, they take hold of the person and you try to cure such a
person. Forget it. You will fail.
All are connected. In the societies they have found such ways in order to exist
the society in a kind of a peaceful way, so we do not kill each other.
Otherwise we will eat up each other. We are the worst animals in the planet.
Lions are nothing in comparison with us. We can kill by words, by actions...
Hahnemann is so perceptive, he says you have to understand what prevents your
treatment from being successful and you have to realize and you have to advise
your patient accordingly.
You see how contemporary is the Organon?
Why Homeopathy, when it is given to a person who has not such deep problems
still it can create a situation inside the patient that he will start telling the doctor
next time about his life much more I have done this, I have done that,
I was in love with this man, he did this to me and that... and then it's like a confession
and then you give the next remedy and what do you see? The organism confesses,
that means what is pathology inside, it brings it outside on the skin, on the light.
Bringing out a skin eruption is like a confession of the organism.
I have spoken about this idea and they accused me for interfering with the church.
This is absolutely stupid because we know it as a law.
When the remedy will act, will take the internal problem outside and will present it
as a skin eruption or an inflammation on the mucus membranes.
This is the best processing cure. I will tell you something. Don't get depressed.
Because I say that and it appears that I am outside of all that and you are inside...
We are all inside it these ideas. We all have shortcomings. We all have dark areas.
Don't be "Oh my God, I have done this sin!" Don't think this way.
Take the information and process it in a healthy way.