I come back to paragraph 33 with sub-note 17, which I was asked by Tania
to comment on this footnote 17.
Hahnemann in order to prove that the remedy is stronger than the disease
has given in footnote 17 an example, which we will analyze and you will see
what exactly is there.
"A striking fact in corroboration of this is that, whilst previously to the year 1801,
when the smooth scarlatina of Sydenham still occasionally prevailed epidemically
among children, it attacked without exception all children who had escaped it
in a former epidemic.
In a similar epidemic, which I witnessed in Konigslutter, on the contrary,
all the children who took in time a very small dose of Belladonna remained
unaffected by this highly infectious infantile disease."
Based on this paragraph there has been a lot of misunderstanding
and a lot of damage was done to Homeopathy. Why?
Because certain people thought that Homeopathy could act as a prophylactic
and they took this idea and carried it to such an extreme that the whole idea
was ridiculed in the press especially in England and everywhere else
and I have spoken about this and explained what actually had happened.
Hahnemann is a human, he observes and he thinks and he brings out conclusions
but that does not mean that what he writes should be kept as a kind of Holy Book
that we should try to fit all of our experience within this idea.
First of all he says, in an epidemic which he witnessed all children
who took Belladonna were escaped.
In an epidemic some of the people were affected. Not every child is affected.
So he comes to the epidemic he saw.
Out of the children to whom he distributed Belladonna, let us say 1000 or 2000,
whatever number, he doesn't say, but one can imagine how many people could
have been given Belladonna with the possibilities of distribution of his time.
So out of these children a big number would not be affected in any case.
Because in all epidemics it's like this.
If we believe that all children were protected, which I will accept, what actually
happened is that, he says he distributed the remedy during the epidemic
and most probably he gave Belladonna 30CH or 15CH, he doesn't say.
He gave the Belladonna as a protection, so the scarlatina of Sydenham has
a perfect picture of Belladonna.
So what actually has happened most probably is that the children
who were starting getting the epidemic, out of the 2000, the 100 children started,
they took Belladonna which acted curatively and it cured them before
they had developed a full blown of a scarlatina case.
Because we know the genius of an epidemic, if we realize that we have a genius
in action and we realize this epidemic has definitely the characteristic of
Eupatorium perfoliatum, we can in prevention give to our patient
Eupatorium perfoliatum, most probably to prevent, but it's not preventing,
to cure them in case they start having the problem.
Hahnemann's idea was that Belladonna was a strong medicine that
fought the disease, suppressed and did not allow the disease to come.
But actually it was a curative action of Belladonna in a typical case of Belladonna.
When an acute starts and you give Aconitum, the cases that respond to Aconitum,
next day will be Ok.
Because this is the remedy which is needed.
In the same way Hahnemann had observed this and
I'm sure that not all children were protected. There were 2 or 3 children who needed
Eupatorium perfoliatum or Aconitum or some other remedy that would continue
to be affected. But the general impression is that the remedy prevented
the children from getting scarlatina.
Otherwise, if you think that Homeopathy can act as an preventive outside of
an epidemic, that means you think I will distribute Thuja in case smallpox comes,
people are covered by Thuja and people will be protected by Thuja.
Because Thuja is the genius for smallpox.
If you do this and the epidemic really comes, then you are going to be in a big trouble.
Because you have given this year Thuja and you say take Thuja you are protected
and the epidemic comes 6 months later, 1, 2, 3 years later... you are not protected.
Thuja may protect you when the epidemic is on and act as a curative action.
Not as preventive. Because a remedy which has similar symptoms will act only
in the case the organism develops symptoms similar to the remedy.
It's very simple.
Unless you have the symptoms in the organism, you cannot imagine that
this potency given 1, 2, 3 or, as many as you like, will do anything
because in an organism in which Thuja is not indicated at this moment,
there is no epidemic, it's not indicated.
And I give Thuja to protect you from next year's epidemic, this is stupid, this is crazy.
This is a misunderstanding of the whole Theory of Homeopathy.
A remedy will act only if there are its symptoms in the patient.
Otherwise it will not act.
This idea was totally misunderstood and I was bypassing it because
I didn't want to make the point but since Tania brought this point
I had to explain to you that there are certain points which Hahnemann
is not the absolute, the all-wise God that knows everything.
Neither me, nor any human living on the earth.
But we have some things which are logical and which we consider them as correct
because we have seen them working in practice.
Further than the time of Hahnemann that he was facing different problems,
today we face quite different problems.
Today we face much more difficult problems than what Hahnemann
was facing himself.
Hahnemann himself realized that giving a remedy in a chronic case did not always - though it fitted - cure the case.
So he said why? It must be the miasm behind, the levels. What kind of miasm? Then he investigated.
Syphilis, gonorrhea etc. Then he started thinking this, what I have said, that the remedy
is more powerful... maybe it's not so, maybe something else is happening.
Today Dimitri from Siberia brought me something from Chronic Diseases.
This is written 20 years later after the Organon.
I would like to know the page also. Because I do not remember this.
But if that is true and Dimitri says he has just photocopied the book,
so there is no question about that.
See what Hahnemann had said 20 years later concerning this matter.
He tries to excuse himself for what he had said and he writes:
"Of itself this vital principle [...] opposes only a weak resistance to the invading
morbific enemy; as the disease grows and increases it opposes a greater resistance,
but at best it is only an equal resistance;
with weakly patients it is not even equal, but weaker.
This force is neither capable, nor destined, nor created for
an overpowering resistance, which will do no harm to itself.
But if we physicians are able to present and oppose to this instinctive vital force,
its morbific enemy, as it were magnified through the action of homoeopathic
medicines, if in this way the image of the morbific foe be magnified to the
apprehension of the vital principle through homoeopathic medicines, which,
in a delusive manner, simulates the original disease, we gradually cause and compel
this instinctive vital force..." To do what by the remedy?
"to increase its energies by degrees". I did not remember this,
it's first time I've seen it, that's why I doubted but it's exactly
what I have explained later in all my books.
We compel the vital force - when we say the vital force we mean
the defense mechanism-, we give extra energy to the vital force to face the problem.
"[...]to increase its energies by degrees and to increase them more and more..."
by repeating the remedy.
"[...] and at last to such a degree that it becomes far more powerful than
the original disease."
He comes exactly to what I have said. He tries to excuse himself for what
he had published in 1910, 20 years later.
"[...] The consequence of this is that the vital force again becomes sovereign
in its domain, can again hold and direct the reins of sanitary progress,
while the apparent increase of the disease caused by homoeopathic medicines
disappears of itself".
Here he wants to excuse the initial aggravation because he could see that
by giving continuously remedies produced also some extra symptoms in the patient.
And he said these extra symptoms which are produced by the remedy
will disappear eventually by themselves. Thank you.
But we will eventually discuss the idea of aggravation of Hahnemann
and the idea of aggravation as we know it today.
It's very interesting because I could not remember this.
Most probably I just passed it 50 years ago when I was reading.
-My understanding from this scarlatina example is that the children who were
really helped with Belladonna, they already were in a Belladonna state, but in initial
stages, that's why the remedy worked. Is that correct?
So could you please explain to us the genius epidemicus?
-The genius epidemicus is that many organisms when stimulated by a specific agent,
morbific agent produce a reaction which is similar with one another.
It looks like one of our remedies. In influenza, most probably a lot of cases
will look like Gelsemium.
But in another influenza many times the epidemic will look like
Eupatorium perfoliatum. Another time will look like Rhus tox.
Another time may look like Arsenicum.
At this specific time when the epidemic is hitting the children,
a lot of parameters are taken into consideration from the organism and
the organism decides to make a specific reaction, which gives you the impression
that a lot of these people are having a picture of Gelsemium
or a picture of Eupatorium perfoliatum. A lot, never all.
If you do it as a routine practice and you give a remedy in an epidemic, you give it
to everyone, not everyone will be cured.
Sometimes also the genius epidemicus, that means the remedy that covers most
of the cases is only less than 50% of the cases.
Therefore this idea of Hahnemann was an observation and he writes it down
in a footnote.
Otherwise Hahnemann would have said here we have a preventing medicine
for every epidemic and you give this and that...
If he was sure about a preventive medicine, he would have said it somewhere.
He says nowhere that there is a preventing medicine, that we can give in every
epidemic. Not only that, but he talks about during the specific epidemic
where Belladonna was indicated specifically in the majority of the cases.
Paragraph 38, "Or the new dissimilar disease is the stronger of the two.
In this case the disease under which the patient originally labored, being the weaker,
will be kept back and suspended by the accession of the stronger one".
This is exactly what happened later on in our times.
We gave antibiotics and we gave actually a disease, a disturbance on the vital force,
which was more powerful than the disease that we were trying to cure.
And in this way they suppress it, they suspend. The stronger suspends the other one
that goes to the background.
"[...] until the latter shall have run its course or been cured, and then the old one
reappears uncured."
The same exactly that happens when you give antibiotics in a chronic cystitis case,
this cystitis goes away suppressed, then you say "Ok, this case is cured" but
after a month or two cystitis is back.
Back in the paragraph 38, he gives some examples.
"[...]  Two children affected with a kind of epilepsy, remained free from epileptic
attacks after infection with ringworm (tinea) but as soon as the eruption on the head
was gone the epilepsy returned just as before, as Tulpius observed".
Can anybody comment on this example of Hahnemann? Is this a correct example or
is it the wrong example? Yes Dimitri. Dimitri is following.
-I think this is a wrong example because it is an example of law of Herring.
-It is the wrong example because most probably the child was given some kind
of medicine for epilepsy and eventually his organism went to a state where he could
be affected by a ringworm.
An organism in order to be affected by a ringworm, has to be in a certain state
of health. So when his state of health from a deeper disorder went to a better state
of health, was vulnerable after that to a certain outside influences.
Ringworm was one of these influences. When this developed and the inner problem,
you will be surprised to see the difference between somebody who has been
suppressed by ringworm and his mental/ emotional state...
Ringworm is very strong infection of the skin and has to be very carefully treated
and respected. This is my experience.
And people who can be affected by a ringworm are in a quite good state of health.
If you don't understand something, you must tell me.
Ringworm or wringworm?. It is an infection that starts with a point
which becomes very itchy, red and a little bit higher than the skin.
Then it starts expanding in a circular manner and can cover huge areas.
Latin name? Tinea capitis. I am not sure the tinea capitis which he mentions here
is the same as ringworm. Anybody who is a skin specialist here?
Herpes circinatus.
But in any case real ringworm it is, as I described to you, very itchy and
as the ring forms by little pimples which are extremely itchy and the color
of the skin changes... It's a very annoying itching and very difficult
to cure with Homeopathy.
The cause? It's not a fungus. A little insect.
The other example he gives again is wrong.
The itch most probably means psora, scabies, which eat up the skin and creates itch
"[...] scabies as Schopf saw, disappeared on the occurrence of the scurvy,
but after the cure of the latter it again broke out".
So the person with the psora, was suppressed, scurvy developed, an inner condition
most probably were given some remedies and the psora reappeared.
"[...]So, also the pulmonary phthisis remained stationary when the patient was
attacked by a violent typhus, but went on again after the latter had run its course.
If mania occurs in a consumptive patient, the phthisis with all its symptoms
is removed by the former..."
The manic depression in a tuberculous patient, as soon as the manic depression is
manifested, the tuberculosis disappears. That means it went inside.
The tuberculosis is a better state than manic depression. But if tuberculosis is treated
wrongly, suppressively, we will have a consequence and the consequence may be
as bad as a mental derangement.
"[...] but if that goes off, the phthisis returns immediately and proves fatal"
When the tuberculosis is very strong and is going to lead the patient to death
and we manage through strong drugs to suppress this we create schizophrenia.
If we treat the schizophrenia and it goes away then all the phthisis comes back
so strong that nothing can help anymore and the patient dies.
You see how clearly everything was said.
"[...]When measles and smallpox are prevalent at the same time and both attack
the same child, the measles that had already broken out is generally checked
by the smallpox that came somewhat later; nor does the measles resume its course
until after the cure of the smallpox.
But it not infrequently happens that the inoculated smallpox is suspended for
four days by the supervention of the measles, as observed by Manget..."
"but it not infrequently happens that the inoculated smallpox..." I don't understand
what he means here. They did not have vaccination by that time.
In any case the example is an example we don't exactly understand.
He brings several example that give his idea. The examples are good enough.
"[...]In an epidemic of measles, that disease attacked many individuals on the fourth
or fifth day after the inoculation of smallpox and prevented the development of
the smallpox [...] The true, smooth, erysipelatous-looking scarlatina of Sydenham,
with sore throat, was checked on the fourth day by the eruption of cow-pox,
which ran its regular course, and not till it was ended did the scarlatina again
establish itself."
So these are examples which on the whole they give the idea that disease can
be suppressed by a stronger disease, by a stronger medicine that we have today.
This is the idea. It's not suppressed only by one disease suppressing the other.
Today what is happening is that diseases are suppressed with strong chemical drugs.
Strong chemical drugs establish their own reign and do not allow the original disease
to appear.
If the organism manages to get rid of the effect of the chemical drug, then the original
disease reappears. What we know today to be the usual practice when they get
a strong conventional medicine and the patient remains without symptoms for a period
of time and after some time there is a relapse.
Take again the conventional medicine and the third relapse doesn't manifest anymore.
What has happened? The problem has gone deeper. Then they come to the
homeopath who has to unravel all this and to bring back the original problem.
But the original problem could also be in the ancestors.
It's not in the person himself.
In the person who was born healthy, yes we can do a lot.
But the person who was born with a hereditary predisposition due to the parents,
we cannot reach him but up to a certain extent. Only if the person was born healthy,
then we can make him healthy again even if certain of his diseases were suppressed
all along.
But the persons whose parents were unhealthy and they gave birth to a child
with strong and dangerous predispositions is not possible to alleviate totally.
We can relieve them up to a certain extent.
They can live comfortably but will never attain this joy of the healthy people,
which I was talking about.
So do you want me to answer this? Ok, there is a question here.
He says yesterday you explained how your view about your homeopathic process is,
it differs from Hahnemann's. For Hahnemann the remedies overwhelms the disease,
for you the remedy stimulates the vital force so that symptoms are increased
and overwhelm the disease. No, this is not what I said.
You have to understand the logic, otherwise you will be confused.
The logic is that the organism always in all diseases wants to cure itself, how?
By symptoms. Symptoms are manifested in order to counteract the invasion,
the disease. But why in chronic condition the disease is not cured?
You have chronic headaches and with the least stress you have a migraine
and you take some painkillers and the migraine is tolerable but next week
you have a little bit of stress, or without stress, the symptoms reappear.
Take again the painkillers. Every 15 or 20 days symptoms disappear.
These symptoms are an effort of the organism to overcome the disease.
And the chemical organism in its multiplicity decides that the best thing for me
at the moment is to relax an artery in the brain, therefore you have the pain or
to constrict an artery in the brain. I'm talking grossly.
This constriction of the artery is to prevent further damage of the organism.
This is the best thing the organism can do. Because there is a chemical imbalance
in the whole organism and the best thing that the organism can do is to have a stricture
of an artery and as a result you feel the pain.
But why does the migraine come again and again? It is an effort.
You say that Ok this is an effort of the organism to cure itself through this migraine.
But why the organism makes an effort again and again for 10 years?
Every 15 days I have migraines for 10 years.
Hahnemann will say that in chronic diseases, the organism by itself cannot be cured.
I say that this is the best way the organism is trying to cure the imbalance, not only
the migraine but the general imbalance that exists in the body.
So if this is true, what happens is that the organism does not have the means,
though he tries, to make a final effort and finally get rid of the disturbance.
Cannot make a super effort. So here we come and we give a remedy
which gives the extra energy that the organism is needing in order to overcome
the problem. We give, therefore we stimulate, so next day the migraine becomes
excessive. First time in my life I had such a big migraine.
But after that the migraines are cured.
How this was done? It is simple.
The organism gives out as a reaction a totality of symptoms.
You get a remedy to which the organism is very sensitive because that remedy
you choose, can produce similar symptoms. That means the symptoms that
are there increase. If you don't perceive this idea you will never understand
what's going on. You have to be very careful.
If you don't perceive it, forget it. The organism gives a push.
The defense mechanism is trying to cure itself through the symptoms and cannot.
Here we come with a remedy, we give the extra energy he needs in order
to overcome. That's why there is an initial aggravation.
Somebody may say "I don't understand". Please say it because otherwise
it will be useless to continue. You have to understand this process.
The organism when it is stimulated by the similar process like the disease,
increases the symptoms.
So Hahnemann later on will say, then when I gave the remedy in very small doses
I saw that there were a lot of aggravations, so I had to reduce the dose.
Is anybody who does not understand this concept? You do not?
It's very different. You say "and overwhelms the disease".
It pushes the disease to become more. Not overwhelm.
Overwhelm means to cover the disease. This is a wrong concept.
It is increasing the disease, not overwhelm. Overwhelm means suppresses.
This is the difference. Increases the disease.
Gives an extra energy to the defense mechanism so the defense mechanism makes
the final effort and the disease is over. Why the disease is over?
Because already the effort of the organism through symptoms was an effort of
trying to cure itself. That is why he does not have enough energy to overcome
and there is repetition. We give the extra energy and we increase, not overwhelm,
not suppress. Otherwise Hahnemann says overwhelms the disease.
The remedy is stronger and overwhelms the disease and the disease is finished.
But later on he comes to my idea. He says the same thing. Give energies more
and more "[...] we gradually cause and compel the vital force to increase its energies"
To increase, not to overwhelm. The remedy that we give increases the reaction,
the energy of the vital force. You still have a problem?
Who has a problem? Did you write down?
-The remedy creates symptoms. The primary reaction is the reaction of the remedy.
And the secondary reaction is the reaction of the vital force...
-Don't confuse yet the primary and the secondary reaction because it's different...
-I have a question. How the remedy increases the vital force?
-I just explained. You have an organism who has decided to cure itself
through 10 symptoms. That means he has brought out 10 symptoms that
bother the patient.
The remedy you choose to cure produces similar symptoms. What is going to happen?
If you have diarrhea and you have a remedy that produces diarrhea and you take it.
If you have diarrhea and you take a remedy, not high potency, low potency,
Arsenicum. If you take Arsenicum by the time you have diarrhea and the diarrhea
is of an Arsenicum type and you take a little bit of Arsenicum what is going to happen?
The diarrhea will increase, most probably the person will die because the diarrhea
will be increased. If I have a symptom and the remedy I take creates the same
symptom, that means this symptom will become more.
-But it's a little more.
-Later on he will say how to reduce the dose so it not be dangerous for the patient.
Before we go to LM potencies we have to understand so far...
We'll talk about LM potencies but not now, otherwise we'll get confused...
Later on, I don't know when... Most probably I will do this again a few times
until I cover the whole thing and most probably the whole thing will be given
to the students who will take the E-learning for students who are serious and
really want to study.
But at this moment we have the facts so far.
Later on Hahnemann will speak about the dose, how to reduce the dose,
how he felt that the patient was getting too many aggravations because
of the dose etc. Hahnemann himself supports my idea.
Because later on he will say if you give a remedy that produces the same symptoms
of course there is aggravation and then to reduce the dose and reduces not only
the dose but the potency and how he came to the idea of the potency.
The genius of Hahnemann was that he came to the idea of potentizing the remedy
to the extent that there was no chemical substance left anymore.
This is a discovery worth 10 at least Nobel prizes.
-I think that the confusion comes from us saying that the remedy produces symptoms.
From what you say it's not a remedy which produces symptoms,
the remedy acts on the vital force. And the vital force is the only one that reacts.
So we say that the remedy produces symptoms, but it's the vital force which
produces symptoms under the effect of the remedy.
-Exactly. The vital force is reacting to disease producing symptoms.
The vital force is reacting to medicines producing symptoms.
Which is the remedy that will help this case?
I thought you are a ghost at the moment I saw you there... Stop this. I'm afraid.
This is correct what you say, after this clarification is it understandable what I say?
Ok. Who has not understood yet?
These ideas were written in my "Science of Homeopathy" back in 1976
when I was writing the book published in 1978 for the first and this was one of
the basic ideas. When later I was teaching "Levels of Health"...
By that time I mentioned the Levels of Health in the original book.
Later on I say more about the Levels of Health in the
"New Model of Health and Disease", in my book which I think it's a very
instructive book for anyone who wants to understand what is happening
with the human body.
Then in 1995 I decided to give a series of lectures in a 4-year course, the original
course... who was in the original course?
I decided to give the original course in which I explained everything
that I had experienced so far.
What I do now concerning the "Organon", I try to clarify what Hahnemann
was writing and also the different aspects of my understanding from the ideas
of Hahnemann. That does not mean in any way that Hahnemann was not correct
or I am greater than Hahnemann, I hope you understand that.
I'm trying to give you my experience based on the ideas of Hahnemann.
After that I do not know what else I should do.
Some students many times have said "when I have a case and I try to find the remedy
and I cannot find the remedy I think you will come and tell me the remedy".
I cannot do that. You have a question? I will give you.
-About predisposition. Children that are treated with right homeopathic treatment,
what are the chances for their children to change the predisposition in a positive way?
And in how long time?
-I must say that there is a chance, if the parents were treated correctly
and they had children, that their children will be in better state of health.
The problem is that a child who is born does not depend only on the
genetic predisposition of the 2 people.
It depends on other factors; environmental and mostly according to my experience
on the state of health at the moment of conception.
Our state of health goes up and down and if the conception takes place in the best
possible moment of the 2 organisms, the child born can be much greater in health
than the parents. The parent give to the child the best possible, out of the 2.
And the child is born which is really complete. You know my theory on children?
No, better read the whole theory how children could be born healthy.
I gave this lecture during this course also and there is in my books.
Definitely there is an improvement but very important is the moment of conception.
In a family somebody is really a complete person, not a genius because genius
is different, but complete person, mentally, emotionally, physically, balanced and
you see his brothers and sisters in a terrible state.
That means the two parents were in love, they came and the first child was born
beautiful, complete etc. Then they hated each other after 3 years and they start
fighting, they had all kinds of conflicts and the second child is not anymore
as complete as the first one, depending on the health of the moment.
You get a conception the time when the man is drunk, they have sex and the child
will be born with a lot of problems.
-You said several times before the birth of children from diseased parents, teratogenic
factors, whatever who became more or less monsters can kill people, can accept the
killing of people without remorse, without heart, it's clear...
My question is, in the history of the mankind many situations where there were wars
and a ruler gave an order everybody in this town to be killed in that period we expect
them to be healthier people, how is this possible? This is my question.
-Particular leaders of these countries like Caligula or Neron were unhealthy,
sick individuals. I cannot investigate their health history.
But definitely they were very sick. Same kind of sickness.
I cannot say what was exactly the sickness they had and how it was treated but
usually such people are coming with diseases which are in relations
to their sexual behavior.