We have seen the line of thinking of Hahnemann, who tries to persuade everybody
that here we have found something of very great value that nobody can doubt
that it is so. That a disease is cured by a remedy that has similar symptoms
in its proving with a disease.
From this paragraph on we have a problem.
We disagree with Hahnemann. I disagree with what he writes and I will explain
that to you. This process of the similar remedy curing the similar disease
"depends on the following homeopathic law of nature which was sometimes
indeed, vaguely surmised but not hitherto fully recognized."
It was mentioned by others. But not fully recognized.
"[...] and to which is due every real cure that has ever taken place"
And now he states the law
"[...] A weaker dynamic affection is permanently extinguished in the living organism
by a stronger one, if the latter is very similar to the former in its manifestations".
His idea is that an affection in the human body, the disease, is extinguished
by a dynamic intervention through the remedy if the latter (if this dynamic affection
by the remedy) is very similar to the former in its manifestation."
He has a logic and he wants to support this logic.
I will commend later on after I have shown you paragraph after paragraph.
"The curative power of medicines depends on their symptoms, similar to the disease
but superior to it in strength".
The curative power of the remedies is due to the fact that this dynamic form
of remedies is superior in strength than the disease.
"[...]so that each individual case of disease is most surely, radically, rapidly and
permanently annihilated and removed only by a medicine capable of producing
(in the human system) in the most similar and complete manner the totality of
its symptoms, which at the same time are stronger than the disease."
He insists that the fact that the remedy cures the disease is because the power
of the remedy is stronger than the power of the disease.
I will read some more.
"As this natural law of cure manifests itself in every pure experiment and every true
observation in the world, the fact is consequently established; it matters little what
may be the scientific explanation of how it takes place..."
For the first time Hahnemann has a doubt of what he states.
Until this time Hahnemann has said there is no experience in the world who can say
this is not so. This is first and the only time where he mentions
"[...] it matters little what may be the scientific explanation of how it takes place..."
It's not important for me but I will tell you my idea.
"[...] and I do not attach much importance to the attempts made to explain it.
But the following view seems to commend itself as the most probable explanation,
as it is founded on premises derived from experience".
"As every disease consists only in a special, morbid, dynamic alteration of our
vital energy manifested in sensation and motion, so in every homeopathic cure
this principle of life dynamically altered by natural disease is seized through the
administration of medicinal potency..." etc.
Do you understand what he says?
The remedy is more powerful than the disease therefore what it does, he will explain
later on, it takes hold of the disease, suppresses the disease and whatever left over
is out of this powerful intervention with the remedy, then with time also goes away.
That means he understands that there are some symptoms that they may be left over,
belonging to the remedy after the cure but these remaining symptoms will just go away
with time. This is his explanation and he maintains that the cure takes place
because the remedy is more powerful than the disease.
When there's a weaker dynamic affection it's overwhelmed by a stronger one
and this goes away.
I was reading this by that time I remember and also I remember I was trying
when people asked me how this happens. And I could not persuade them
with this explanation.
So I said to myself, something else is happening.
Also I did not understand myself. How is that possible that this is not a suppression?
If this is stronger it suppresses.
Eventually I came to the realization of what really happens.
I will give you my explanation so you can judge which of the 2 explanations
is the most probable.
The symptomatology develops after the defense mechanism has been triggered
by a morbific influence. Something attacks the organism whether physical or psychic,
the organisms reacts with the totality of symptoms.
Why does the organism do this reaction?
Hahnemann gave his logic and I will give you my logic.
What do the symptoms represent? We say it's a reaction of the vital force.
A reaction for what? The reason there is a reaction and the specific symptoms
that the organism develops is in order to cure itself.
That's way the organism brings out symptoms. It's in order to reestablish the balance.
An example.
Your organism is attacked by bacteria or a microbe.
The first thing we see is the raising of the temperature of the body, fever, high fever.
And after 3 days whether he takes medicine or not the whole thing subsides.
The organism comes back to normal. He was attacked, reacted and because he reacted,
why has he developed the fever? Because the organism realizes that these microbes
that entered my body are so violent, virulent that I have to do something.
Otherwise I will die. What can I do?
I can raise the temperature so I know that these microbes can only live in an
environment which is less than 40.2 C.
If I raise my temperature in 40.3 C they die.
This is the idea of the process of an acute disease which has a prodromal period,
(the multiplication of the microbes) then it comes the main period, where we have
the reaction of the organism, once the organism realizes then the bacteria are
overwhelming me starts the reaction.
The reaction raises the temperature and eventually comes the resolution of the acute
which is either cure or death.
If the microbes need a temperature of 40.3 C and the organism can raise up to 40 C
the microbes keep on multiplying and then the organism tries more and more and
finally gets very tired and succumbs and dies.
The ending of every acute condition is either a cure by the reaction of the organism
or death if the organism is not able to bring up a strong enough reaction.
They understood this. This is the reason why we have symptoms.
But if that is true that symptoms are useful for the organism which is manifesting them,
if they are useful, then they should not be suppressed.
Because if you suppress them, then you will have side effects.
Somewhere else the organism will find a way to diffuse the problem.
With antibiotics we know what happens. We have found ways to suffocate
the microbes through antibiotics and in this way we attack the microbes.
How we treat successfully in acute conditions with Homeopathy?
By the similar remedy. What is the similar remedy?
You must remember we have given a remedy that produced in healthy organisms
a totality of symptoms.
We take this remedy which produces similar symptoms with the organism
under observation and we take this remedy and give it to this organism.
But if this remedy had produced similar symptoms with those of the organism
and you give this remedy, this remedy instead of going over and suppress
the manifestation, what will do?
The mechanics is that the organism in order to save himself it produces
symptomatology. Then you take a remedy that produces similar symptomatology
and you give it to the organism. For God's sake, what's going to happen?
You will kill the organism because the remedy you give, will make symptoms worse.
Because it is the same mechanism.
When the organism receives that particular substance reacts in a similar way like
it's reacting during disease. So you give on top of the reaction that has produced
the organism, you give a remedy to increase the reaction of the organism.
To increase the symptoms, not to decrease them. Is it clear?
Therefore the idea of Hahnemann most probably was wrong.
He understood that... it's not important what it happens but I will tell you.
The remedy is stronger and suppresses the weaker dynamic disturbance.
In reality it increases the reaction of the organism. By that time what it does?
As I said before, the organism needs in a pneumonia to reach for streptococcal
infection in order for the microbes to die 40.2 C.
It cannot reach that and makes an effort, 40, 40.1, in the morning the organism is tired
38 C, in the evening it comes again 40.1 C to burn out the microbes.
And the third day in the pneumonia the organism is struggling and is starting
to collapse. It's going to die.
There you come with your knowledge and you give this little push to the defense
mechanism, the vital force and you stimulate it. 40.2 C and the next day... no fever.
You see the logic behind?
- I think on one hand, you're right. For instance the phenomenon, if you give in
childhood fever 39.5 C a Belladonna, it can be that the fever rises even more but
then it goes down and I always explain to the parents that fever has its own sense,
in times it works better, the homeopathic remedy doesn't suppress immediately but
it helps to go over the peak of the mountain and then it can go into the healing.
So the period when the fever raises as a first reaction is in your sense the reaction of
the organism will be stimulated even more but then it starts what Hahnemann says
the wiping out and the fever goes down by itself.
And the organism knows itself when this is the time.
So you are right and Hahnemann is also right.
-There is a proverb in Greece. We say, you cannot have a full pie and at the same
the dog is fed quite well. This is not possible.
What you say is not correct, it contradicts itself.
Hahnemann says that the dynamic reaction - and he will further support this idea-
is stronger... He will say actually later on that the remedies can affect all organisms.
That means if I increase the amount of the substance,
there us going to be an effect in everyone.
If I give you - not poison, a simple substance, the mother tincture of Gelsemium-
100 mg, 3 times a day. The second or the third day there will be some of you
who will say I have some dizziness.
If I increase this, 500 mg and then I continue to 1 gr of mother tincture, 2, 3, 5, 10,
20 gr, everyone will have eventually symptoms.
So Hahnemann will say later the medicine can be increasing in amount and can
affect everybody while the disease cannot affect everybody.
It may be an epidemic and out of us only 20% will be affected.
The epidemic does not affect all people. You must have a predisposition.
But with medication you don't have to have a predisposition.
If I give you enough substance will create what today is understood as side effects
of chemical drugs.
If I give you one week of antibiotics, some of you will be destroyed within a week.
Some will not feel very much. But if I continue and increase the dose and instead
of 500 mg, I give you 1 gr 3 times a day, in 10 days everybody will be in bed.
His idea is the medicine, the substance can affect, therefore it's stronger than
the disease who can affect only certain individuals.
This is where he went wrong and thought the explanation.
But as I said, he himself doubts what he writes.
"[...]I do not attach much importance...".
"As every disease (not entirely surgical)..." why he says "not entirely surgical"?
He has also seen that when a tumor has been formed, most probably by that time
he would see some malignant tumors and he would see that the organism
had reached a stage beyond which the remedy could not affect
and he calls it non-surgical. That means if there is a big tumor,
I don't know when the surgery has started coming, but it appears in his time
they had started some good surgery, he says if it is not a surgical disease,
then we could do something.
"[...]consists only in a special, morbid, dynamic alteration of vital energy...
manifested in sensation and motion, so in every homeopathic cure
this principle of life dynamically altered by natural disease is seized through
the administration of medicinal potency selected exactly according to symptom
similarity by a somewhat stronger, similar artificial disease manifestation".
The idea of a stronger medicinal affection still continues.
"[...] By this the feeling of the natural (weaker) dynamic disease manifestation
ceases and disappears.
This disease manifestation no longer exists for the principle of life which is now
occupied and governed merely by the stronger, artificial disease manifestation".
His idea is that the disease is weaker, the medicinal power is stronger
and the medicinal power takes over and defeats the weaker manifestation and
now the stronger is ruling the organism.
"[...] This artificial disease manifestation has soon spent its force and leaves
the patient free from disease and cured".
This stronger artificial disease takes hold and leaves the organism free.
"[...] The dynamis, thus freed, can now continue to carry life on in health.
This most highly probable process..." You see Hahnemann who never doubts, says
"This most highly probable process rests upon the following propositions."
So I will explain to you this it's probable.
"The human body appears to admit of being much more powerfully affected
in its health by medicines than by natural morbid stimuli - for natural diseases
are cured and overcome by suitable medicines".
What I said before. For him natural diseases are weaker because they are cured
by medicines, so medicines are stronger than diseases.
He has not perceived the mechanism underlying his discovery.
The real mechanism is different.
"The human body appears to admit of being much more powerfully affected in
its health by medicines than by natural diseases - for natural diseases are cured and overcome by suitable medicines".
Paragraph 31, "The inimical forces, partly psychical, partly physical,
to which our terrestrial existence is exposed, which are termed morbific noxious
agents, do not possess the power of morbidly deranging the health of man
unconditionally". This is what we said.
The stresses whatever psychical or physical do not have the power to affect all
the organisms unconditionally.
"[...] but we are made ill by them only when our organism is sufficiently disposed
and susceptible to the attack..."
Hahnemann had realized everything was happening.
The fact that we disagree for this little explanation, it means nothing to take away
from his genius. He says in order for somebody to get sick, he must be predisposed
to it, he must have a susceptibility, a predisposition, otherwise he will not be affected.
You see how this predisposition is manifested in an organism.
I'll give you a very practical example which everybody will understand.
At the age of 16 you had a lover and he behaved very badly and he said something
insulting to you.
At the age of 18 you had another lover and he behaved in a similar way.
The 3rd lover that you will have, you will expect that he will be behaving in a similar
way and you already have created in you a susceptibility for this particular stress.
"If he tells me I don't like you anymore and I must leave you because I am
out of love with you" that can be so stressful because this susceptibility has been
building up in you and the 3rd time you hear this stress...
the first time you overcome, the 2nd time it was a bit more difficult, the 3rd
but the 4th time you're destroyed because the psychical impact found ground
that was preparing to be affected very much by such a stress.
The same organism, the same human being has a shock because lost his job.
He lost it first, second, third time... He doesn't care. He tries for another job.
There is a stress again but this organism is susceptible to that particular information.
That particular information is going to create a problem as disease in the body.
Hahnemann says exactly this "[...]but we are made ill by them only when our organism
is sufficiently disposed and susceptible to attack of the morbific cause that may be present,
and to be altered in its health, deranged and made us to undergo abnormal
sensations and functions - hence they do not produce disease in every one
nor at all times".
So stresses, disease have to find a susceptible ground. He makes that clear.
- I just wanted to understand the nature of stress. Can the stress be turned into a
disposition if it happens over and over or some people will not be affected even
if it happens over and over?
- A stress if it happens over and over again, it will definitely create a predisposition
but in the same individual different kind of stresses will take different number
of times that the organism should be attacked.
A woman likes her children. But there are women who can leave the daughters,
the son. They run away with a lover and they leave the child.
That woman does not have a susceptibility on this area.
Another woman for all her life it's her daughter. You can imagine with the first attack
on the daughter, that means the daughter becomes sick. It's a big thing!
The daughter becomes so sick that she may die. The woman will be destroyed.
That area for that woman is a sensitive one.
The next time if the daughter continues to become sick more and more, the stress on
the mother will be so great that she will becomes ill, she will definitely develop some
kind of chronic condition. But there must be a susceptibility.
And then he will continue...
"But it is quite otherwise with the artificial morbific agents which we term medicines.
Every real medicine, namely, acts at all times, under all circumstances, on every living
human being, and produces in him its peculiar symptoms (distinctly perceptible, if...)"
There is this "if" which many times we do not take into consideration.
The big "if" is this "[...]if the dose be large enough"
All medicines act on all human at all times as long as the dose is large enough.
That means when we want to try a new proving on a remedy,
what do we have to do in order to affect and to produce symptoms?
We have to give large enough doses in the provings.
That means if you want to prove chocolate. You cannot prove chocolate by giving
a little piece of chocolate to everyone.
Today we have to eat 100 gr of chocolate each one, Ok maybe 200 gr.
Out of us there will be 2 or 3 who will come and say I have my stomach this and that...
I will say "out of the experiment". The rest? Nothing happened.
400 gr chocolate today. Another 10 people will have this, headache etc.
You observe, you write down your symptoms. Do you want to continue? Yes.
Half a kilo chocolate. This is the way.
If the dose is large enough, everyone, even those who are very resistant to chocolate
if you keep on giving kilos of chocolate, they will become sick.
How do we prove the remedies?
Those first people who got out of the experiment because with a piece of chocolate
they became sick, they are the most sensitive.
Later on we will find in proving, Hahnemann says, when you have found these people
on these people you can try a high potency. And then you have a real proving.
If the dose is large enough.
"[...] so that evidently every living human organism is liable to be affected..."
By a kilo of chocolate every day the 3rd day you may go to the hospital
"[...] and, as it were, inoculated with the medicinal disease at all times
and absolutely (unconditionally), which, as before said, is by no means the case
with the natural diseases".
He says the natural disease does not have the power of increasing the dose.
The moment that I am attacked by a group of microbes...
By mistake I ate something with a group of microbes.
Then the organism, if it realizes that this is dangerous for my life, will create a reaction
to kill the bacteria. What is the reaction? If you took the bacteria from the alimentary
canal you will start vomiting, diarrhea and purging so that all the possible microbes
that they were created within the organism, eventually will be killed through
this reaction. That's why in a food poisoning you always have diarrhea and vomiting.
There are some organisms who are sensitive to this. So a poisoning in one organism
by some microbes ingested will be much milder than another one who very fast will be
going into a state of severe acute gastroenteritis with high fever and at the same time
blood in the stool or blood in the vomiting. That is a serious condition.
That means the organism was susceptible to that particular.
But the disease does not have the possibility, as I am sick, to increase the dose,
to take some more.
The disease has not the possibility to give me more of the microbes.
I took the microbes, in whatever conditions, because I breathed in or I ingested
but that's finished. After that the reaction starts and the natural disease
does not have the possibility to increase the dose, so I can die.
Because you will always die, if diseases had that possibility.
You would never survive.
I will read, just to show you his ideas. "In accordance with this fact..."
that the medicinal powers affect every human "[...]it is undeniably shown by
all experiences that the living human organism is much more disposed and
has a greater liability to be acted on and to have its health arranged by
medicinal powers..."
He has understood this and he says again "it is undeniably shown by all experience"
nobody can deny. He did not say this for the way he explained how the remedy works.
This is the only time he doubts. Hahnemann knows very well that when he says
there is no doubt, you can bring the whole experience, the whole world,
things are like this.
The only time he doubted was when he was explaining the way that the remedy acts.
Paragraph 33, "In accordance with this fact, it is undeniably shown by all experiences
that the living human organism is much more disposed and has a greater liability
to be acted on and to have its health deranged by medicinal powers than
by morbific noxious agents and infectious miasms.
Or in other words that the morbific noxious agents posess a power of morbidly
deranging man's health, that is subordinate and conditional, often very conditional
whilst medicinal agents have an absolute unconditional power, greatly superior
to the former."
Hahnemann was just saying as if he was a prophet that the medications that
you are going to give after 200 years are going to suppress and to cause problem
because there is no organism who can resist the effect of chemical substances,
medicinal powers. There is no organism who can resist, especially if the dose
is large enough and is repeated, that's exactly what happens today with
conventional, chemical drugs.
The moment they give a drug, what happens is what Hahnemann thought
it was happening with the homeopathic remedy.
It's very interesting that by mistake he predicts the way that a powerful medical
drug can suppress by its power the disease agents.
He thought this was happening on the homeopathic remedies, which was not true.
It is happening when the organism receives large doses of chemical drugs.
In paragraph 34, "The greater strength of the artificial diseases producible
by medicines is however not the sole cause of their power to cure natural diseases.
In order that they may effect a cure, it is before all things requisite that
they should be capable of producing in the human body an artificial disease
as similar as possible to the disease to be cured".
So he says the fact that they're more powerful, it doesn't mean that you
just give any remedy and because it's more powerful than the disease,
it will cure the disease.
You have to give a remedy that has the most similarity with the disease.
"[...] which, with somewhat increased power, transforms to a very similar
morbid state, the instinctive life principle,
which in itself is incapable of any reflection or act of memory.
It not only obscures but extinguishes and thereby annihilates the derangement
caused by the natural disease".
He tries to explain and he uses words.
That means the medicines you are giving not only obscures
but extinguishes and thereby annihilates the derangement caused by
the natural disease.
"[...] This is so true that no previously existing disease can be cured,
even by Nature herself, by the accession of a new dissimilar disease,
be it ever so strong, and just as little can it be cured by medical treatment
with drugs which are incapable of producing a similar morbid condition
in the healthy body."
He says the cure can take place if the medicine can produce a similar disease
in the human organism.
But this cure cannot happen even by nature.
The nature does not have the possibility to introduce into your organism
a similar disease that can cure the previous one.
Later on he will bring some examples on that.
"[...] no previously existing disease can be cured, even by Nature herself,
by the accession, the incoming of a new dissimilar disease, be it ever so strong."
If the new disease is dissimilar, the disease which you are having already,
will remain there.
And even less can be cured by medical treatment which is dissimilar
to the problems of the patient.
"In order to illustrate this, we shall consider in three different cases,
as well what happens in nature when two dissimilar natural diseases meet together
in one person, as also the result of the ordinary medical treatment of diseases
with unsuitable allopathic drugs, which are incapable of producing
an artificial morbid condition, similar to the disease to be cured,
whereby it will appear that even Nature herself is unable to remove
a dissimilar disease already present by one that is unhomoeopathic,
even though it be stronger, and just as little is the unhomoeopathic employment
of even the strongest medicine ever capable of curing any disease whatsoever."
He says, that if you give a dissimilar substance, it will never cure.
And the same thing will happen in nature.
If you have a disease and another dissimilar disease is coming,
it cannot be cured. And he will say later on that each one
will take its place in the organism, several disease may exist together
in the same organism.
When the one which is stronger will manifest mostly, the other which is the disease
which is dissimilar but weaker will be subdued.
And as soon as the stronger one is cured, the weaker one will come up again.
Exactly the same thing that happens with allopathic drugs.
Allopathic drugs are curing by dissimilar action.
They are very powerful and they subdue, they suppress whatever is there,
as disease manifestation, they do not see it anymore
and they establish their own reign.
What we know is that if we treat correctly a case, that has been suppressed
by allopathic medicine, slowly the effect of this suppression will go away
and there will come back the manifestation of the old disease that was there.
" If the two dissimilar diseases meeting together in the human organism be of equal
strength, or still more if the older one be the stronger, the new disease
will be repelled by the old one from the body and not allowed to affect it.
A patient suffering from a severe chronic disease will not be infected by a
moderate autumnal dysentery..."
This is what later on we discovered in the Levels of Health, where we say that
if a person is chronically ill with a severe chronic disturbance, such a person
cannot be affected by an acute, which is weaker than the already existing disease
in the body.
Hahnemann had very accurately observed that if a person was really chronically
ill, with a strong disease, a weaker disease, influenza, enteritis, common cold
or tonsillitis, all these acute conditions cannot affect an organism
who is already sick in a chronic, serious condition.
This is something that Medicine has not realized.
It has not realized that when they say, we give you these chemical drugs
and repeat it again and again and there is a time when there are no more acutes,
they feel they have done their duties.
They have cured the person from chronic cystitis which was coming again and again,
from chronic influenzas etc.
Now we cured you. You don't get any more cystitis with fever
but actually what happens is that the organism has become quite sick
and therefore a stronger disease does not allow a milder disease to affect you.
"So, also under ordinary medical treatment, an old chronic disease remains uncured
and unaltered, if it is treated according to the common allopathic method.
This is daily witnessed in practice, it is therefore unnecessary to give any
illustrative examples."
It's the same thing we say today that chemical drugs will not really cure
any chronic condition.
Chemical drugs will suppress but will not cure any chronic condition.
You have asthma and you take bronchodilators, cortisone and you breathe better
but this is only a temporary suppression of the symptomatology,
it's a temporary alleviation of symptoms.
But now the organism who is pushed every time with a chemical drug,
what happens, at a certain moment it gives up and says I can't cope with this stress
that drug is giving me anymore. Therefore I will put another level of defense
which is on a deeper level and what is this deeper level of defense?
It is a huge neurotic state, a serious depression, even a mental derangement
and when he comes to you to be treated he is not suffering anymore with asthma.
It comes with the neurotic symptoms, illusions, delusions, psychological problems,
you give the remedy and then asthma comes back.
-Do you feel the same way about vitamins, herbs...? Can they suppress?
-No, it's not the same in any way.
And it's not always that allopathic drugs will suppress. Not always.
Perhaps we can say most of the time but not always.
Giving some support to the organism to deal with a problem like vitamins, herbs,
better sleep, better diet, all these supporting things that you can be giving
to the organism, you may help him to overcome the problem.
In the same way sometimes, a supplement, even cortisone can affect a real cure.
Giving cortisone which is due to the disturbance of the super renal glands
which they don't produce the exact amount and you supply this amount
and the person feels good and can breathe again and suddenly
after a few months of treatment with cortisone, there is a big eruption arriving
which was the initial cause of the asthma because it was suppressed.
This can happen with allopathic drugs as well.
The problem is that the doctors don't realize that this now is a good process
and we have to be careful not to suppress again the skin eruption, the eczema.
But what do they do? When the eczema comes
"I have the eczema now, I have side effects from the cortisone".
The doctor does not know to ask "Did you have such an eczema when
you were a child? - Oh yes. - That's a very good process in your health."
That means this is not a side effect from the drug. It is a process of cure.
They don't know it and they send it to the dermatologist and the dermatologist
does a good job and in one week the eczema is disappearing
and the asthma reappears and then the asthma comes back to you
and you treat and you tell them it's very good that you have the eczema.
So I give you a remedy and if the eczema comes back, it's a very good thing.
Keep it and pray the eczema will come back.
Sometimes people cannot tolerate these reactions.
They come to you and they complain, I have this itching and I cannot sleep
and you are trembling and you are trying to cure the asthma quickly.
And then you make mistakes because you give one remedy after another and
then back again the asthma instead of waiting.
I remember a case with a boy and Roger Morrison was studying with me in Athens
and he had the case. He brought me the case and says
"George the parents say that they have not slept for 10 days because all night
the boy is scratching and the parents are awake trying to relieve him, please
don't scratch, because we have told them not to do anything.
And he comes to me desperate and says, I cannot see the remedy
and I said, I'm sorry I cannot see the remedy and then after a week they come back
and they say the boy has these symptoms.
I said that's Arsenicum, give Arsenicum tonight. The same night the boy slept.
After a few days the eczema disappeared, the asthma also.
So the boy was cured from asthma was cured and for the rest of his life did not
suffer of it. Can you imagine all this?
That this is possible, that there is a way to treat logically and he has given
all the information possible, as long as long you have understood this.
It's so important for a homeopath to have understood the Organon.
And I'm really sad to see homeopaths who never read the Organon.
They say, what is the Organon? I don't understand what the Organon is.
Do you want to ask a question? You have a lot of questions? This is good.
-What you have just said, does it mean that if you have a patient with cancer
having chemotherapy and you have the side effect of a very itchy skin eruption
that would be a good effect?
-Good effect.
-And then you would stop the chemotherapy at this point, shouldn't you?
-Today we have ways of knowing and we have possibilities to see
whether there is a retraction by the markers, by the MRI, laboratory examinations,
we know whether this is only an allergic reaction, because it can be.
That means the chemotherapy contains something to which the person is allergic
and it can have an allergic reaction. This is different.
But if the person says I feel better and the pains have been reduced
and the tumor also starts reducing, the markers are better and
there is a severe skin eruption, yes you can say it is a curative process.
-I was going to ask if one can differentiate when the cortisone or any other
allopathic remedy has a curative effect or if it is just a reaction?
So you said, you need to ask if the person is feeling better.
If the person feels better and has a skin eruption is not an allergic reaction.
Is there any other signs that we can...?
-There are some other signs which you can be certain that the cortisone
or the chemotherapy has acted.
I said you have the markers, you are checking, you have the pain,
which has been reduced, you have the general condition of the patient,
you have the MRI that you will see the reduction of the tumor...
You calculate all these together to make a decision
whether this was a curative reaction.
-When Hahnemann was presenting how he understands the homeopathic process,
he was saying the remedy was doing the action, it's overwhelming the disease
but the way you present how you understand it, you say actually
the vital force is doing the work...
-Exactly. We stimulate the vital force which does the reaction.
Not that the homeopathic remedy comes from the outside and gets hold
of the weaker and throws it out, not in this way.
We stimulate the vital force and the vital force takes extra force
to fight the disease and that is the explanation why we see initial aggravations.
Otherwise you cannot explain the initial aggravation.
In chronic headaches, the persons says you gave me a remedy and this time
my headache was the worst ever. You say, very good the remedy was correct, wait.
You know what you are doing. Once you know the Theory,
you know what you are doing and until you know the Theory,
then you cannot really cure.
You may give correct remedies and then spoil the case later on.
Because you don't know how to proceed.
-There is a mechanical analog to what you are saying. So if this is a straight line
of health and there is a deviation from health towards one direction,
let's say to the right, then if you want to bring back to the straight,
you have to pull that so it gets back...
-I didn't understand your mechanic model. Repeat.
-If you put the force, it has a force to come back again to the straight...
-The force of the disease is pulling one direction...
-This is the straight line of health. But in disease there is a deviation to one side
let's say. If you want to bring it back to the straight line, you have to pull it a bit more
so it gets the force to get come back...
-And the organism brings it back. You can say that, as long as you understand,
that the homeopathic remedy is not suppressing but on the contrary
is triggering the reaction and pushes more.
I'm hot now and my organism has to react. It has to bring balance.
It says you are very hot. What does it do? Some reaction, it makes me perspire
so I can cool off eventually through the perspiration.
He has to do that otherwise, I will have thermoplexia.
If the organism cannot do that, that means it cannot bring out symptoms
to relieve the heat, what happens...
I have a sunstroke, then I fall off and I faint in the seaside and the people
are bringing the person here.
The organism did not have forces to react and to perspire and to bring
all the other chemical reactions that are needed to counteract the heat.
The organism did not have that, therefore it has sunstroke and the person is out.
You give the remedy and then there is a perspiration and the person comes back.
It helps him to bring out the peculiar symptoms that are needed in order to cure itself.
That means you are pushing the organism towards the right direction.
Who was here, I think it was the Italian group?
They brought somebody with sunstroke, he was almost collapsing.
In sunstroke we have remedies like Natrum carbonicum, Glonoinum, Belladona,
Natrum muriaticum etc. The class gets very excited, the person is like this.
I go there and I touch him a little bit and I see has a mild cold perspiration
and I say, give him Carbo vegetabilis 200CH.
In 5 minutes the person was sitting there attending the class.
What you do is you help the organism to reestablish itself through symptoms
which are good for the organism.
Not every organism develops the same symptoms in all conditions.
Some organism will develop a severe headache.
He may be out of order completely under the sun because of a severe headache.
For that you do not give Carbo vegetabilis, you have to give Glonoinum.
Glonoinum will make his headache a little bit stronger for a moment and then is over.
-If the right remedy pushes the vital force, what does the wrong remedy do?
-That's a good question.
You have 800 remedies, if you put them on a vibrational rate,
you will see the remedy that the person needs is here, on that rate.
Left and right of this vibrational rate are close vibrational remedies.
If you give a very close one, you will push the organism and then a second one
and the third may bring the organism back into order.
The more distance you are giving a remedy from the correct one,
the less is going to be the effect.
If the remedy is totally out, no effect. The worse is the remedy to be not very close
but to be close enough as to bring about some changes. These changes are not good.
But if the remedy is quite close, it will push the organism towards a more correct
picture.
-Can we suppress with a remedy?
-Yes, you can suppress with the wrong remedy, if it is near.
-The first time, or do you have to have several remedies?
-You can suppress the first time, the second time...
You can suppress with a remedy that it is near, which means that it will be changing
the symptoms of the person without the person feeling better.
And you just change. A headache from right goes to the left.
Then you have to wait. The organism will bring it back by itself if you wait.
But in this way you can suppress but not suppress in the way that a chemical drug
will suppress. A chemical drug will suppress forever and will keep you
under its effect for 20 years.
-I didn't understand how cortisone or chemotherapy can have a cure.
Is it like a homeopathic medicine? Does cortisone act like a homeopathic remedy?
-Can you speak little bit louder?
-I don't understand how cortisone or chemotherapy can have a curative action.
Does it act as an homeopathic remedy?
-Yes. The possibility is that in these chemicals, there is one chemical structure
which is needed by the organism and takes a mother tincture of that remedy.
It's like treating with mother tinctures.
But being a similar within these different elements of the allopathic drug
which contains a lot of different elements, one element it may happen
to be indicated as a similar remedy or maybe there are some other functions
we do not understand yet.
I do not say that I know everything and know how this can happen.
What I know are facts. People have come and said I have taken a little bit
of cortisone and I feel great.
And I examine them and in all respect mental, emotional, physical, very good state.
Keep on this remedy. So the replacing of this very little cortisone brings
the organism into a perfect condition. You keep it. I don't change it.
I don't say stop this and I will give you a remedy.
In the same way, I have seen cases with deep psychological problems,
even with schizophrenia that have been given remedies which have produced
severe skin eruptions.
And during these eruptions the person feels his mind is clear
and the correct doctor should say this is a curative action
and this remedy is good for you.
It doesn't matter because I'm a homeopath and he has been given
an allopathic drug...
These are only ideas, it's not reality.
The reality is that this medication has tremendously helped this severely ill person.
Keep it. This is good for you.
-What about a person who is helped by cortisone to take potentized cortisone?
Have you tried it?
-No. I will not stop the cortisone of a person who feels very good
under a little bit of cortisone, I am talking 3-4 mg.
I have seen cases that they are doing well with this very little cortisone.
I will not stop it and give it potentized cortisone. I've never done it.