The last paragraph "[...] But purgatives for
itch, and issues for epilepsy, cannot be
more heterogeneous, more dissimilar
deranging agents - cannot be more
allopathic, more exhausting modes of
treatment - than are the customary
prescriptions, composed of unknown
ingredients, used in ordinary practice for
the other nameless, innumerable
forms of disease..."
He criticizes the kind of treatment
of his time and he says "purgatives",
remedies that cause diarrheas were
used for psora and also epilepsy.
They used to cure epilepsy by giving
purgatives, exhausting the organism
through constant diarrheas and in psora
if you are exhausted the psora will be
suppressed and as soon as you start
eating again the psora will manifest.
The same with epilepsy. They used to
exhaust the people make them crazy...
"[...] These likewise do nothing..." This
kind of treatments who do not belong to
either Homeopathy or Allopathy, which are
irrelevant, why cause diarrhea for psora?
"These do nothing but debilitate, and
only suppress or suspend the malady for
a short time without being able to cure it,
and when used for a long time always add
a new morbid state
to the old disease".
And if they are used for long time you
will get a new, more severe disease.
This leads us to paragraph 40 "Or the
new disease, after having long acted
on the organism, at length joins the old one
that is dissimilar to it, and forms with it
a complex disease..."
So the new disease after a long time
complicates with the previous one and the two
together, they form a
new nosological entity.
We see this everyday today, we see what
happens when conventional medicine starts
treating chronic conditions and in the
process there are side effects which means
new problems arising and while you
are treating a chronic condition
of the kidneys after some period, the
heart gets involved and the two together
they form a kind of a new pathology which
has both heart and kidney problems.
I transferred the idea of diseases, as
he says, to the idea of diseases treated
with conventional medicine.
Because this is more important for
us what he brings as an example...
It's a rare situation where two dissimilar
diseases meet in the same place but
actually his observation is true
concerning what is done today by
conventional medicine.
This we may not see, very rarely, we
will see that a new disease suppresses
an old one. But we see very frequently
that a disease is transformed into
some other complications
and side effects,
if treated constantly
with allopathic drugs.
"[...] Thus a syphilitic patient may
become psoric, and vice versa.
As two diseases dissimilar to each other,
they cannot remove, cannot cure one
another..." This is the idea that has
started to bring up the idea of miasms.
And he will conclude in the end that in
an organism you may have a psoric patient
who in the process he gets syphilis,
who in the process of his life,
he also gets gonorrhea.
And he says out of these 3 miasms
whatever is the most powerful influence
upon the body is and
will manifest first.
If you treat this uppermost miasmatic
disease, then the next one will come up
and manifest itself.
"[...]As two diseases dissimilar to each
other, they cannot remove, cannot cure one
another. At first the venereal symptoms
are kept in abeyance and suspended
when the psoric eruption begins to
appear; in course of time, however
(as the syphilis is at least as strong as the
psora), the two join together,1 that is,
each involves those parts of the organism
only which are most adapted for it,
and the patient is thereby rendered more
diseased and more difficult to cure."
His idea is that each of the 3 miasms
occupies a different place in the organism.
You treat always according
to the symptoms.
Which is the most prominent and the
most powerful will come up first.
An organism has a
predisposition for sycosis.
The sycotic Medorrhinum will be first.
The sycotic miasm will be uppermost
because father/ mother had
sycosis, it comes first.
And then after you treat with sycotic
remedies and this layer goes away
then it starts Mercury coming up and
you suspect there was some syphilis
in the family as well.
"[...] When two dissimilar acute infectious
diseases meet, as for example,
smallpox and measles, the one
usually suspends the other."
These observations we don't see today.
"[...]as it has been before observed;
yet there have also been severe epidemics
of this kind, where, in rare cases,
two dissimilar acute diseases occurred
simultaneously in one and the same body,
and for a short time combined,
as it were, with each other..."
Sometimes you have two different
epidemics combined forming a new entity.
I do not have the experience.
It's interesting to know.
"[...]During an epidemic, in which
smallpox and measles were prevalent
at the same time, among three hundred
cases (in which these diseases avoided
or suspended one another, and measles
attacked patients twenty days after
the smallpox broke out, the smallpox,
however, from seventeen to eighteen days
after the appearance of the measles, so
that the first disease had previously
completed its regular course)"
Two epidemics, one comes runs its
course and then the other one can come.
Sometimes both are occupying
place in the organism.
"[...]Rainey witnessed the simultaneous
occurrence of smallpox and measles
in two girls. J. Maurice, in his whole
practice, only observed two such cases.
Similar cases are to be found in
Ettmuller's works, and in the writings
of a few others.
Zencker saw cow-pox run its regular
course along with measles and along
with purpura." These ideas are
observations of doctors of old cases,
today we don't see such cases.
Paragraph 41. "Much more frequent than
the natural diseases associating with
and complicating one another in the
same body, are the morbid complication
resulting from the art of the ordinary
practitioner, which the inappropriate
medical treatment (the allopathic method)
is apt to produce by the long-continued
employment of unsuitable drugs."
50 years ago I've read this and
I'm reading it again today.
He says actually what I am saying. More
frequent than the diseases suppressing
each other, what suppresses the
diseases is the inappropriate treatment
which is employed.
And if their treatment was inappropriate
suppressing diseases you can understand
today how much more
powerful drugs we have.
Because by these times they had herbs and
leeches, simple things could not really
suppress as quick as we do today
with conventional medicine.
It's very interesting that he says that
because most probably what was happening
during this time, the type of treatment
it was so aggressive in severe cases that
the patient actually died so they had
much more deaths during that time.
Today people do not die, they
just remain deeply diseased
and deeper in any case
than before the treatment.
Today they can survive. We found ways to
suppress and let the organism stay alive.
And if it happens that somebody wants
to die, they do not allow him to die.
You say the heart is collapsing, Ok put
another heart, the liver is collapsing,
Ok put out the liver, put another liver,
the lungs are not functioning anymore,
put him in a machine
and make him breathe.
This is considered the topmost scientific
application of medicine today.
"[...]To the natural disease, which it is
proposed to cure, there are then added,
by the constant repetition of the
unsuitable medicinal agent, the new,
often very tedious, morbid conditions
corresponding to the nature of this agent..."
Due to the repetition of the medication,
you will have a new disease
which is of the nature of the
medicine you have been using.
So you have been using hormonal
treatment, the problem will appear mostly
on your hormonal area.
You are using medication of the urinary
tract the problem most probably
from a simple cystitis that starts,
will end up into kidney failure.
This was what he was saying.
"[...]adding to the old disease a new, dissimilar,
artificial malady of a chronic nature,
and thus give the patient a double
in place of a single disease,
that is to say, render him much
worse and more difficult to cure,
often quite incurable..."
When we take the cases sometimes we see
they have taken a lot of medications
we declare this case incurable. Not
possible to cure, unfortunately.
It's amazing that this man at this time he
could have noticed, observed and written
down such details of what was going to
happen all along the medical history
in 200 years since
he wrote this book.
"[...] Many of the cases for which advice
is asked in medical journals, as also
the records of other cases in medical
writings, attest the truth of this..."
He says, I read the cases in the medical
journals of the time and I came to
this conclusion. "[...]Of a similar
character are the frequent cases in which
the venereal chancrous disease..."
This parlance is a little bit
out of our comprehension.
Venereal chancre. I have never seen
this but if sycosis remained untreated...
Of a similar character are the frequent cases
in which the venereal chancrous disease
[...] complicated especially with psora or
with dyscrasia of condylomatous gonorrhea..."
This is less frequent when syphilis is
untreated there is a chancre. Ulcer.
There is an ulcer in the beginning but if
it is left untreated, this goes away and
the syphilis enters the system going
into the secondary syphilis and then
tertiary syphilis which the
nervous system is paralyzed.
But with sycosis, gonorrhea, the second
stage of condylomata is the one that
will stay for many years and they
will appear there and stay there.
Today sometimes we ask whether a person
got gonorrhea in his young life.
He says no. But actually if you
want to know if he got it or not
you have to ask about
condylomata as well. Why?
Because the secondary stage of
gonorrhea are the condylomata.
These condylomata are infectious, can
be infecting the partner with whom
you have sex. Therefore you are supposed
to have the gonorrheal, the sycotic miasm.
"[...] And all this complication he says "[...]is
not cured by long-continued or frequently
repeated treatment with large doses
of unsuitable mercurial preparations,
but assumes its place in the organism
beside the chronic mercurial affection
that has been in the meantime gradually
developed, and thus along with it often forms
a hideous monster of complicated disease
(under the general name of masked venereal
disease), which then, when not quite
incurable, can only be transformed into health
with the greatest difficulty."
Even in his time, once you had a
person having syphilis and gonorrhea
then you have a difficult case.
Now the perfect example of the suppression
of this venereal diseases today
is the AIDS cases.
In the AIDS cases what has happened?
It is syphilis and gonorrhea treated
repeatedly by antibiotics. So you
have the miasms plus antibiotics that
have suppressed these two miasms, with
the end result being an immune system
that is totally compromised.
I was so amazed to hear the definition of
AIDS, a totally compromised immune system.
Is this the definition of a disease? It's
the result of the treatment of syphilis and
gonorrhea through antibiotics.
And it was very interesting that in 1970,
when I was lecturing a group of doctors
in Athens I have said that some years
later, if they continue giving antibiotics
to such diseases they will create new
diseases that will be incurable.
And it was logical to say this because by
this time in Greece everyone was using
lots of antibiotics. You have gonorrhea, it's
nothing, common cold just take 3, 5 days
of antibiotics and it's gone.
Syphilis also, penicillin.
But penicillin in the first years in order
to treat syphilis you need 500 units.
After a few years 1000 units.
After 2 more years 3000 units...
So the organisms were resisting the
suppression and they needed more and more
by the time of Hahnemann, Mercury
was a very powerful agent and
anybody who gave Mercury was
suppressing all kind of diseases.
And that's why we see today
a lot of mercurial cases.
It's coming from ancestors who were
taking a lot of Mercury to cure this kind
of diseases whether syphilis or gonorrhea
and then it comes today where syphilis
appears on a totally
different picture.
It's not anymore the primary or the
secondary or even the tertiary syphilis.
Syphilis appears today mostly
in mental aberrations.
One thing which is very characteristic of
syphilis as a symptom is when a person
has a tremendous fear of dirt. Anything
they touch they feel it's dirty
and they have to wash
their hands immediately.
They can wash 100 times a day. I have
cases that when their clothes touched
somebody in the bus and they go to
the house they take the clothes and
they put them in fire. And
they are not rich people.
And they will throw them. It was impossible
to put again the clothes if it touched
somebody else. This is the one. The
second characteristic of syphilis is
- not in all cases but in many
cases- of severe alcoholism.
Severe alcoholism from young age
indicates the possibility of syphilitic
predisposition from the fathers...
par 42, "Nature herself permits,
as has been stated, in some cases,
the simultaneous occurrence of two (indeed,
of three) natural disease in one and
the same body. This complication, however,
it must be remarked, happens only
in the case of two dissimilar diseases, which
according to the eternal laws of nature
do not remove, do not annihilate and
cannot cure one another, but, as it seems,
both (or all three) remain, as it were,
separate in the organism, and each takes
possession of the parts and systems particularly
appropriate to it, which, on account
of the want of resemblance of these maladies
to each other, can very well happen
without disparagement
to the unity of life."
Two dissimilar diseases cannot cure, cannot
annihilate each other and can co-occupy
a different place in the organism in
such a way as to allow life to continue.
This is something not known to us. In my
memory I cannot bring a case of that type
but anyhow this is
his observation.
Aphorism 43, "Totally different, however,
is the result when two similar diseases
meet together in the organism, that is to
say, when to the disease already present
a stronger similar one is added.
In such cases we see how a cure can be
effected by the operations of nature,
and we get a lesson as to
how man ought to cure."
From this two similar diseases meeting
and curing each other we get the idea
how nature heals and we should
follow the same laws of nature.
Paragraph 44, "Two similar diseases
can neither repel one another,
nor suspend on another, so that the old one
shall return after the new one has run
its course; and just as little can two
similar diseases exist beside each other in
the same organism, or together
form a double complex disease."
So two similar diseases cannot expel
each other, cannot suppress each other
and cannot remain both
in different places.
-What do we mean by "disease"?
-Measles.
-But we know that disease is the totality
of the symptoms. So is it right to say that
we can have two diseases in one
organism, it's still one disease.
-No, his experience is that we
have different epidemic diseases.
We cannot say we do not
have different diseases.
In epidemic diseases, he says, there are
some who are similar in their expression.
So if these 2 meet, they cure each other.
Which is an example I do not know...
I don't have an example now. I don't
know if he gives any example.
Does he give any example?
After 2 paragraphs, Ok.
After 2 paragraphs he
will give an example...
So 2 similar diseases do not repel one
another, do not suspend and do not occupy
a different place, they
simply cure each other.
45, "No! Two diseases, differing, it is true,
in kind 1 but very similar in their phenomena
and effects and in the sufferings and
symptoms they severally produce,
invariably annihilate one another whenever
they meet together in the organism;
the stronger disease namely, annihilates the
weaker, and that for this simple reason,
because the stronger morbific
power when it invades the system,
by reason of its similarity of action involves
precisely the same part of the organism
that were previously affected by
the weaker morbid irritation,
which, consequently, can no longer act
on these parts, but is extinguished 2,
or (in other words), the new similar
but stronger morbific potency controls
the feelings of the patient and hence the
life principle on account of its peculiarity,
can no longer feel the weaker similar which
becomes extinguished -exists no longer-
for it was never anything material, but a
dynamic -spirit like- (conceptual) affection.
The life principle henceforth is affected
only and this but temporarily by the new,
similar but stronger
morbific potency."
In other words if the 2 similar diseases
meet, they extinguish each other.
I just remember something
from my experience.
I had a patient and examining him
he said in the past I had malaria
that was coming back again and again.
How it was cured?
He said I took different medication
quinine... nothing helped.
So how it was cured? He says one time I got
the fit of the trembling and rigor and
fever while I was near the sea.
So I felt an impulse to fall into the
cold water. He went there and fell into
the cold water and when I came
out, since then, no more malaria.
You can say whatever but
this is what he told me.
Can you say that it was a similar... a cold
creates rigor, he goes into the cold water,
that means that raises the
rigor, makes the rigor stronger.
It was like natural
homeopathic remedy.
A remedy from nature and perhaps such
similar occurrences may have happened.
Hahnemann repeats a lot of times in
order to establish in the consciousness
of people the ideas. That's why
he repeats it again and again.
Paragraph 46, "Many examples might be
adduced of diseases which, in the course
of nature, have been homeopathically
cured by other diseases presenting
similar symptoms, were it not necessary,
as our object is to speak about something
determinate and indubitable, to confine our
attention solely to those (few) diseases
which are invariably the same, arise
from a fixed miasm, and hence merit
a distinct name. Among these the smallpox,
so dreaded on account of the great
number of its serious symptoms, occupies
a prominent position, and it has removed
and cured a number of maladies
with similar symptoms.
How frequently does smallpox produce
violent ophthalmia, sometimes
even causing blindness! And see! By its
inoculation Dezoteux cured a chronic
ophthalmia permanently,
and Leroy another.
An amaurosis of two years' duration,
consequent on suppressed scald head,
was perfectly cured by
it, according to Klein."
I don't know what amaurosis
is... Kind of blindness.
-No apparent damage to the eye, still
blindness, it is named amaurosis.
-"[...] An amaurosis of two years' duration,
consequent on suppressed scald head..."
I don't understand, there is
probably a skin eruption on the head
"[...] was perfectly cured
by it, according to Klein.
How often does smallpox
cause deafness and dyspnea!
And both these chronic diseases it removed
on reaching its acme, as J. Fr. Closs
observed. Swelling of the testicle, even
of a very severe character, is a frequent
symptom of small-pox, and on this account
it was enabled, as Klein observed,
to cure, by virtue of similarity, a large hard
swelling of the left testicle, consequently
on a bruise. And another observer saw a
similar swelling of the testicle cured by it.
Among the troublesome symptoms of small-pox
is a dysenteric state of the bowels;
and it subdued, as Fr. Wendt observed,
a case of dysentery, as a similar
morbific agent.
Small-pox coming on after vaccination, as
well on account of its greater strength,
as its great similarity, at once removes
entirely the cow-pox homeopathically, and
does not permit it to come to maturity;
but, on the other hand, the cow-pox when
near maturity does, on account of its great
similarity, homeopathically diminish
very much the supervening small-pox
and make it much milder, as Muhry and
many others testify."
His examples are examples which we don't
have today and are the observations
of different doctors
of his time.
The fact remains that what he wants
to say is the law of nature.
That heals by similars. There is actually
a dictum in one of the spiritual books
of Jewish Bible that says "men heal
by opposites, God heals by similar".
I think I have written
it in one of my books.
Nature has shown us the way to heal really
in a natural way by using similar agents.
"[...]The cow-pox, a peculiar symptom of
which is to cause tumefaction of the arm,
cured, after it broke out, a
swollen half-paralyzed arm..."
It is interesting what he says here. I
remember a case, I had a gynecologist
who had given up his profession because
of a fungal infection that had made
his arm almost double in size
and was painful and weak
and cured it with one
dose of Thuja 200 CH.
It's strange. Perhaps this man who
must be now around 100 years old
and we spoke 3 years ago. I
called him on the occasion.
I wanted to find out if he still
used distilled water for drinking.
He had this fixed idea that
distilled water is the best.
So he had a machine to
produce distilled water.
So I called him 3 years
ago, he must have been 97.
"Hi, I'm George Vithoulkas. He said,
no I don't recognize your voice.
No, I'm George Vithoulkas, you have
come to me when your hand was swollen.
He says, that is true. But your voice I cannot
recall. So you are not George Vithoulkas.
Ok, whether I am or I am not
I want to ask a question.
I knew you were having a machine
that produced distilled water.
Can you tell me of what
type this machine is?
No, I will not give you... because I don't
recognize you're George Vithoulkas.
For God's sake! You don't remember...
I brought some other facts.
Yes that is true. But I can't
believe you are George Vithoulkas...
He was 20 years older than me.
It was a very interesting case because
this man went back to work and he was not
shy to say that I was cured with
Homeopathy. He was an honest person.
Now I see small-pox has produced this
and Thuja is the main remedy for
curing small-pox.
He brings examples about the measles. "[...]
The measles bear a strong resemblance
in the character of its fever and cough to
the whooping-cough, and hence it was that
Bosquillon noticed, in an epidemic where
both these affections prevailed, that many
children who then took measles
remained free from whooping-cough..."
What's interesting is that when you read
these examples you get the information
that by that time the children epidemic
was a very frequent affair of what
was happening. Today we have managed to
eliminate the possibility of a child
to contract an epidemic. There is no
possibility because of the inoculations.
We consider this to be good. Actually according
to the homeopathic Theory this is bad.
That means the deeper chronic condition
does not allow the child to get infected
with an epidemic anymore.
And the last paragraph 47 that says, "Nothing
could teach the physician in a plainer
and more convincing manner than the above
what kind of artificial morbific agent
(medicine) he ought to choose in order to
cure in a sure, rapid and permanent manner,
conformably with the process
that takes place in nature."
So the epitome of all these examples is to
tell us this is the natural way of curing
and if you want a natural
cure use Homeopathy.
-When will we hear your interpretation of
paragraph 49, 50 to 291? Just a question.
-Repeat...That will happen before the next
course. I do not know. I have no idea.
It just came to my mind while in the open
course, it was last year I think, I have
promised to write commentaries on the
Organon but I said I will never be able to
do it, I must speak out
and do the commentaries.
Maybe in this way I can complete the
commentaries on the Organon and
many years ago I said the last
book I wanted to write will be
the meaning and the
origin of diseases.
I want to write a book explaining the
meaning and the origin of diseases
for which I have some ideas but I don't
know if I will have enough time to do it.
This is not something I can speak out. I
have to sit down and organize my thinking
before I do it. With
this it's easy.
I believe there is a reason for us being
sick and I have to explain the parameters
and the reasons and also what is
and where it leads. Diseases.
It's a difficult subject but maybe
if I have time I will do it.
-You talked of the stimulation of the vital
force by the remedy and the occurrence
of an aggravation. Why don't we see the
aggravation in Group A and in Group D?
-There is an aggravation but it is mild.
Once the disease is not deep,
the aggravation is mild.
-So there is but you can't perceive it.
Because the symptoms are too high in
group A and the symptoms
too mild in Group D or...?
-No, the symptoms are not having
behind them substance in group A.
Symptoms are superficial.
Not really deep.
So therefore you may give a remedy and
the aggravation is hardly perceptible.
But as we go lower and lower the
aggravation becomes more obvious.
In level 5 aggravation is more obvious,
level 6 more aggravation, 7 you may have
aggravations.
Aggravation are strong because the
pathology becomes deeper and deeper.
In the last ones, there is no force
and there is no aggravation,
there is only amelioration.
The organism is too weak.
It's like pushing somebody to start running
and you push him and he goes a few steps
away and stops. Not running. Because
the vital force is almost finished.
So there is a lot of suffering in these
levels but no power of the defense mechanism
to bring about a reaction.
Sometimes after a few remedies you may,
in some cases, bring the organism into
a state where the immune system becomes
stronger and stronger and at a certain
moment it shows an aggravation.
That will be very good after the aggravation.
That may be after 5 years of treatment.
And there comes the aggravation
and it's very good, if it comes.
-Hello, I would like to know
your opinion about the pill.
-The woman pill?
-Yes, because if we are treating someone
with Homeopathy, the body is going
the natural way. Do you consider the pill
as something negative because it's like
a hormonal treatment? What should
we advise to our patients?
Some other natural
contraceptives?
-This matter is not simple. I
will discuss a little bit.
There are cases in which the
woman who takes the pill says
"I used to have PMS and now after having
the pill there are no more problems".
In such a case, the pill contains the exact
amount of hormones which the organism
needs as a supplement. It's
like insulin in diabetes...
In this case the pill may be Ok.
I don't know on the long run.
But in the case where the woman feels
good and takes the pill in order
not to become pregnant, that is not good.
Definitely there is a disturbance.
Whether the woman who had the PMS and
does not have it now this is a good thing
or not, I say I do not know, I am not sure.
But it is not as bad as the other woman
who is normal and has menses with no
problem and takes the pill in order
to prevent becoming pregnant. That is really
bad and will have an effect eventually.
Therefore the best thing to
do is not to stop the pill...
What is the most
logical thing to do?
The most logical thing that you have to
do, if you know the pill makes you sick.
Become pregnant? No, because you
don't want to become pregnant.
You just tell your man please have
a condom. This is the most simple.
Why a woman should destroy her health
instead of the man using the condom?
I did not hear that from anybody. It's very
simple. These things should be discussed.
I'll tell you why this does not come
to your mind. Shall I tell you?
Why were you not able to answer this
simple question? Shall I tell you?
I shall not tell you. I want
to say goodbye. We meet again.
I don't know if somebody stays over
for the other things but anyhow those
who go away, I wish you a very nice journey
and I hope you enjoyed the Organon.