Your age is 31 year old and what is your main problem?
- My main problem is numbness and weakness of hands.
- And you have been treated homeopathically?
- For a long time. A lot remedies.
- How many years?
- For about 8-10 years.
- And the main problem was the original problem. For which you went to treatment.
- No.
- So the first time you went for treatment for what reason?
- It all started about 10 years ago. With infection. It looked like tonsillitis with high fever.
- How high?
- 38.9C. I cannot remember.
- And you were 20 years old, by that time, 21.
-Yes 21.
- And you were in school? What were you doing?
- I was studying. I was a student.
- Student of what?
- I studied technology. It's a kind of technical subject.
- And this was the first time you got an infection or it was usual you got infections?
- I used to have infections, a lot of times. But this one was different.
- Was it too heavy or too strong?
- I didn't recuperate well.
- But did you take antibiotics?
- Yes.
- During that time? For how long? Do you remember?
- For this particular infection, it was just standard 10 days.
- And do you know the type? Penicillin type?
- I can't remember.
- Ok. Let me understand now.
Before you had infections as well and every time you took antibiotics?
- No, I had different kind of painkillers.
-  And for which you took what?
- Sometimes nothing, sometimes some aspirin but I quite often I had tonsillitis,
or not quite often, about once a year or something.
- With high fever or medium fever?
- Yes always high fever.
- The last time the fever was the highest or not so high? The problem was more serious?
- The fever was more or less the same.
But from the previous tonsillitis I was recuperated after the antibiotics quite well.
I had not problem after.
- But this time it was different.
- What was different? What happened after the antibiotics you felt...
- By the way I remember one thing. Before this final tonsillitis I had some kind of flu.
It looked like common influenza but not with high fever.
And then after a week or two after that the tonsillitis came.
And I wasn't lying down in bed with the flu.
- And then you took antibiotics and then you felt weak or what...?
- First of all the pain of the throat didn't go away with the antibiotics
and it was very intense for one month and then it somehow eliminated
but it was there for about one year or two.
- You were seeing by a doctor or you just treated yourself?
- No, I was seeing a doctor, a general practitioner at that time.
- This case was not infectious mononucleosis?
- I don't know.
- The doctor he saw you he looked at your tonsils?
-Yes.
- And there was pus?
- I can't remember what she said but she said it was tonsillitis.
- With the severe pain?
- I used to have always serious pains.
This one was different, I remember details,
because I got pain in the throat before I got the fevers, I was normally functioning,
I had energy but I had pain in the throat as if I had tonsillitis.
I had never had something like this before.
- So for days you had pain in the tonsils?
- Yes 3 or 4 days
- As if there was an abscess there you felt?
- As if in my common tonsillitis I used to have before.
It was the same pain during swallowing.
- It was one side or both?
- I can't remember now.
If I had tonsillitis at that time it was usually more prominent in one side.
- And then when the fever came you went to the doctor.
He looked at your tonsils?
- Yes.
- And he said you have tonsillitis, take this. How many minutes did he examine?
- I don't know, maybe 5.
- And he did not ask you a general blood examination?
- No.
- Did you have a blood examination later on?
- Yes.
- And how was? Did you have the results?
- I can't remember.
- In the blood examinations there are some cells that are called monocytes.
Do you remember if this was increased?
- I don't think so.
- You don't think.
- The only thing that was found in my blood was much later on
because I developed chronic problems and I went to the doctor.
They took the blood and they found EB virus antibodies. Epstein- Barr.
But they said it's quite common and it's nothing. Also chlamydia antibodies as far as I remember.
But this was examined much later about 1-2 years later.
After the antibiotics I didn't feel energy, I didn't feel in good condition.
- You felt weak?
-Yes.
- With headache, with bad mood?
- Yes like slight headaches but I can't remember my mood by that time.
I was generally weak, I felt that the body didn't recuperate quite well.
I was tired and then I had this pain still but I didn't have fever.
- So later on did they put a diagnosis? Did they tell you what you are suffering from?
- No. But it was developing it was not the end.
I was just living my life, continued living and didn't pay much attention to it.
Because it was just some general fatigue.
- They did not say chronic fatigue syndrome.
- No they did not and I was actually 14 days at the hospital diagnosed all around
and they did also some tests they wanted to confirm the chronic fatigue syndrome
but they did not. What is important I think that 2 months after this tonsillitis
I developed chronic [?] , fever 37.1C constantly.
First it was about 6 in the evening, one hour a day.
- 6 to 7.
- Then it was 2 hours a day, then it was 3 hours a day, then it was all afternoon
and then after one year of this it was whole day.
- Did you have tubercular test?
- Yes, in the hospital later on.
I was done Mantoux test and it was borderline.
I was examined with x-ray of lungs and nothing was found.
Then I started of course being more and more tired and generally exhausted.
That was the problem for which I came to my first homeopath.
- And since then you have received how many remedies, have you counted?
- I haven't counted because I don't know. Some of them he didn't tell me and I cannot remember.
- Some of the remedies are here...
- The first homeopath didn't give me so many remedies.
-In Czech?
- Always in Czech.
- Ars, Sil, Ruta, Gels, Caust, Fl-ac, Ph-ac, Abrot, Nux-v, Bar-c and a few others
and then Psor, Phos, Ars, Sulph, Syph, Lyc and yourself you took what remedy finally?
- I took Psor, Ars, Phos. And I think these three I took myself.
- And also Cham.
- It was for acute tooth pain.
- Nat-m also
- Yes but I didn't take it myself.
- It was given to you?
- Yes, it was given to me.
Then I took Acon, Phos again, Pic-ac and Nux-v.
These I had to take because...
- From the 24 hours which is the worst hours to you?
You wake up in the morning?
- Do you mean now?
- The last months.
- The last months generally I think in the morning I have the most energy.
Till the evening it goes down.
- The more you get tired the more you lose energy.
- That is the situation.
- What time you go to bed?
- 22.00-23.00.
- Are you married?
- No.
- Divorced?
- No. I have a girlfriend.
- You have been infected with venereal or something? Venereal type of disease?
- I don't think so, I don't have no idea.
- There was no discharge from the urethra?
- No, never.
- There was no inflammation there?
- Never.
- And your weight was always like this?
- No. I lost weight the last 5 years or something.
After the treatment of some homeopaths I lost weight.
- How much?
- About 10 kilos.
- Because you did not have enough appetite or just you were losing...?
- First of all I was on a diet. I still am.
- Why?
- Because first of all I had some digestive troubles
and the second thing I found out that at the time I had these fevers,
this low fever constant, that diet makes me well.
I have more energy then I was generally better when I was on a diet.
- If you are vegetarian?
- I'm not a vegetarian.
- If you're careful with your diet...
- Yes, I am careful.
- Which means, you have to eat what?
- Basically not much fat, nothing fried,
basically nothing that does bad to liver or gallbladder suffering people...
This makes me good.
- Do you have any glands swollen?
- In the past I had, now not so much.
- In the past? How long ago?
- At the time I got this infection 10 years ago and maybe 2-3 years later.
- You have swollen glands, sublingual...Only.  Not glands somewhere else.
-No, as far as I know.
- Your stool is normal or you have diarrheic stool?
- Now, normal.
- It was diarrheic?
-No, one time it was more constipation. One time.
- One time, never diarrhea.
- When I started eating olive oil I started having a little bit loose stool but not diarrhea.
- You like olive oil?
- Yes but I eat it mainly because it is healthy. Later on I liked also the taste.
- Do you know what condylomata are? Did you have any condylomata?
- No.
- Never?
- Never. I started with my sexual life late.
- How late?
- Well, actually about 2 years ago.
- You did not have any contact previously?
- Not a sexual contact.
- And since when you developed this numbness in your hands?
- It was after I was treated for the fevers by the first homeopath.
First of all it started with weakness of the muscles.
I was a professional guitarist.
- You have trembling...?
- A little bit I have trembling.
- Can you stretch?
- Yes a little bit I think so.
- Lift it a little bit.
-For quite many years I think.
- You feel the trembling yourself, right?
- Yes but of course now I am excited. I am a bit nervous.
- And when you are nervous you tremble...
- Not in the absolute ease because I've never been in such situation.
Not very difficult but not absolutely relaxed.
- I see. So you never took Tub?
- No.
- Bac?
- Do you have grinding of the teeth during sleep?
- I am not aware of it, I don't know but my girlfriend hasn't told me.
- But your dentist would have seen it if you were grinding your teeth.
You never had problems with your...
- I have a lot of problems with my teeth since I was a child.
- With carries?
- Yes carries and abscesses and I have an extra teeth, supernumerary.
Which has to be taken out. I had nines here.
- You had one extra teeth.
- No, 5-6.
- 5 extra teeth?
- Yes when I was a child I had two here they were taken away
and then I have one here and I have two ninth teeth here. The one was taken away.
- Your father is alive?
- Yes.
- How old is he?
- He is 56.
- He has problem with his nervous system?
- No.
- Walks nicely?
- He's quite healthy.
- He can run?
- Yes. He is a sportsman.
He plays sports twice or three times a week. Football and everything. He is very vital.
- Your mother? Is she alive?
- Yes.
- She has a problem?
- Yes she has some problems.
- What is..?
- She has in her uterus some kind of benign tumors. This is the last problem she has.
- Otherwise her mental state is ok or she is hysterical?
- Wow! I wouldn't say she is emotionally absolutely balanced but...
- Is she reacting in a hysterical way?
- Maybe when she was arguing with my father. Sometimes she can be hysterical.
Yes, she can be hysterical actually. But between us this situation...
- You are more attached to your mother?
- Definitely. Since childhood.
- You have a brother or sister?
- Brother.
- Is he having any problems?
- Yes but I would say functional things.
He's got some nausea, constant and chronic nausea but nothing serious as far as I know.
- You say you do not eat fat.
- I eat fat. But only...
- Do you like fat?
- In small or normal amount I like.
- When you used to eat meat.
- I eat meat now.
- You like?
- Not particularly.
- Which type of meat you like the best?
- Maybe chicken. I am not sure.
- You have a pain in the right hypochondria?
- Yes, quite often.
- Since when?
- For about 5 years.
- Why? Do you know a reason? You have been examined to see if the gallbladder is functioning?
- No, nothing was found. No stones or something like it.
- Lazy gallbladder, they told you?
- I was not diagnosed. I've been to doctors.
- But they say nothing, they can find nothing.
And the pain is... can you show me the place.
- Yes.
- And this pain extends to the back sometimes?
- Not, really but sometimes it gets to both sides.
- At the same time?
- Yes , at the same time.
Especially when it gets irritated, when I eat something more it hurts on both sides.
- Mostly when you eat something like eggs, or milky products or meat or fat?
- Mostly when I eat a lot of fat or if I eat a lot of chocolate,
something which I don't eat normally. But now I eat chocolate quite a lot. One time I was very hard.
I was very fastidious in my diet.
- Very fastidious for your food.
- Yes.
- But it seems to me that you like fat, actually.
Pork you eat?
- Sometimes, not very much.
Especially for the last 2 years I don't have much desire for fatty meat
or for pork but I don't remember being keen on fat ever.
- About meat which is smoked?
- Not particularly.
- You can eat it.
- I can.
But now I don't eat it because I am very fastidious in my diet.
But I didn't like eating it, it was not my best.
- You eat salami?
- Normal, I like them...
- What do you like to eat best?
- I've always liked cheese, tomato, stuff like Italian cuisine, pasta...
but it could be also meat with tomato pasta I like very much at one time.
I like it now as well. And sweets I like.
- How much salt you use?
- Quite a lot. My girlfriend says I use a lot of salt.
- You always used to use a lot of it?
- I don't remember because I started perceiving these things since I started Homeopathy.
- But you don't remember as a child eating salt?
- No I don't think I did this.
- Strange fear of death you have before going to sleep.
- Not as a child, as a teenager.
- Not now.
- No.
- Do you have any fear now? Fear of the dark?
- I don't feel very well in the dark. Especially when I am alone.
When I am alone in the house but it is not a big fear but I don't feel at ease.
In the dark and alone...
-You prefer to have somebody always.
- Not because of the fear but I like company.
- You feel better with company.
- Yes.
- Because of anxiety about your health.
- No, I would say the opposite. When I'm alone if feel generally worse. Especially my mood is worse.
- So when you have company, it fixes your mood.
- I wouldn't say it like this, I'm not sure about it. Definitely I'm better with company.
- Any other fear?
- For the past few years I was very anxious about myself, in general.
- About your health?
- Yes.
And for example when I have a remedy I have fear the remedy will be antidoted, very apprehensive.
Fear about catching some disease.
I know I am a little bit underweight, so I know if a get some gastrointestinal disease
I could have some problems, not now but 5 years ago my weight was even lower.
- Do you have fear of catching AIDS?
- Also, all kinds of diseases.
- You have fear of all infectious diseases?
- Many of them, I don't know if for all of them but quite a lot.
- For salt, how many times would you underline your desire?
- 2 or 3.
- 2 or 3. Strong.
- Because I don't use much spices, for example pepper... I have a pain in the hypochondria after it.
Salt sort of supplies some taste to food. But I like salty food.
- Do you like cats, dogs?
- Yes.
When I was a child I was very much afraid of dogs.
- Big dogs or even small dogs?
- Even the small I think.
- Cats?
- No. I don't remember.
- Can you pet a cat?
- Yes sure, definitely, no problem.
And now the dogs also. We have a dog with my girlfriend.
-In the sea, when you bath, you feel good?
- Yes, I like the sea.
- Or you feel worse?
- No, I feel the same or good. I love the sea.
-Did you have any time Med.?
- No. I don't think.
- But you don't know the remedies they gave you.
You went to a homeopath that had the custom to give 3 remedies daily for 2-3 months?
- Every day.
- At that time you took a lot of remedies but you don't know the type.
- I can't remember all of them because they were so many of them. This was my 3rd homeopath.
- The general appetite which you have according to you is normal,
that means you eat a normal amount of food?
- I would say that I eat quite a lot.
Some people have told me how it is possible that I eat so much, big amounts and I am so thin.
So I have appetite. I don't eat fatty food. I eat diet, healthy but big amounts.
- In general you feel cold or hot or normal?
- For the last 3-4 years I felt very cold but for the last month
since I got this last remedy (Nux-v., Pic-ac...) I feel warm again. But I felt cold for many years.
In the beginning when I had these fevers I had flushes of heat and I felt hot.
Later on I lost weight and I started feeling cold. Originally I had flushes of heat.
- You have some eczema in your hands?
- Yes.
The eczema developed together with the numbness.
- Where is the eczema? Can you show me?
- Here.
- You mean more dryness? There is itching?
- I went to a dermatologist and she said it's an eczema.
It's not itching so much, it's red, it's not now I have it only in winter.
In the summer I don't have it a lot. Only in cold months.
- Do you have any difficulty in breathing? You have to sigh like this?
- I am not aware.
- How is your sexual desire?
- Quite high, not low, normal.
It depends on how tired I am, how much I work. I don't know what can you say it's normal.
- Each one has his own...for you...
- For me it's normal.
I wouldn't say I'm a slave of my... no, not at all.
Shall I confess one thing to you?
- Yes.
- Many times during in a homeopathic consultation like this I tend to laugh involuntarily,
now it's the same. I am excited and I have the tendency to laugh. I don't know why.
- This happens when you are in other serious conditions? It may happen to you.
- Once it happened in funeral, I didn't feel very good.
- How's your memory?
- Not very good.
- You tend to forget?
- I have to concentrate very much on doing some mental work
and actually one month ago I developed a kind of peculiar state
when I studied quite a lot for about a year very intensively I developed a headache with nausea
and with numbness in the whole half of the body. Leg and hand and half of the face.
- Had you taken Causticum during that time?
- No, 4 days I took Bell, Acon and finally Nux-v which did something. And I also ended studying.
But the memory is not good. I have to strain to remember.
- To remember what you have to do, to remember what you read?
- In reading actually I have problems paying attention.
When I read a few lines I go to the beginning again because I didn't pay attention.
Sometimes this happens quite lately that when I want to say a word,
I'm searching for some word and...
- You cannot find the word.
- I can but 2 words come and I cannot decide which one to use.
And finally I use some kind of hybrid of the 2. Half and half. It's a quite late symptom.
- When has this happened?
- One or two years.
And I am concerning my memory for the last few months especially I was very absentminded.
I will give an example to be clear.
When I study I watch a seminar from the e-learning I watch the video...
When I'm watching, after a few minutes I start doing something else.
I start searching something on the Internet as if the mind was saying
"No more please, I'm overloaded". I have this feeling.
- If I understand well when you study suddenly your mind goes away
and then you start something else and you feel you had enough of this, you cannot control...
- I force myself to go back to the original subject.
- You had otitis a few times.
- As a child.
- But the fever which you had the 39C fever was 10 years the last time with this big fever.
-No. But I had this big fever 39C about a year or half a year ago when I took Psor. I had 39C fever.
- For what? Tonsils?
- No, I had some kind of general of flu.
It was a cold and general fatigue, general malaise, influenza.
I've never suffered with real influenza and this was let's say a strong cold.
But it was mainly fever.
I didn't have strong coryza, I didn't have strong cough but the fever was 39C for 2 days.
- You took Psor today and it was in 2 days...
- No it was in 3 weeks after.
- During these 3 weeks you felt better? In general, more energy?
- I don't know, I cannot tell for 100%.
I maybe I wrote somewhere but I cut can't find it now... I have information only about fever
and I had swollen here...
- Here you report you said Psor you took 4 doses
and immediately felt a mental/emotional amelioration.
- Yes that's when I took it for the first time. It was about 3 years ago.
- "I felt very well and relaxed during the first day. Hear problems ceased after few hours
and 10 days later I got a cold with coryza and fever 37.5C." Not 39C.
- That was the first time I took Psor. Then I took it later on myself. And it was 39.
- Psor. Fistula in gum appeared.
- After this fever.
- A single dose 3 weeks later an acute with high fever up to 39C one day. 37.6C...
Recovered slowly without any remedies. Then stand still repeated...
But you don't write how you felt, in general. Fistula in gum appeared one month later.
Frequent eructations, extreme thirst, frequent urination, sensation of fullness after eating
then intense pain in the hypochondria, both sides, chilliness,
after few days repeated Psor, no change. And then you took Phos. Repeated Phos.
And you have premature ejaculation.
- I was trying to put down some clear symptoms. Objective.
- Ok, we go inside.
I think that for those medical doctors present this was a good example case
how we make a diagnosis in homeopathy and irrespective of the laboratory tests.
In order to understand what's going on in a human organism.
So what's going on in his organism? What happens? What is the problem?
The first thing that I would like for you to remember in this case is what I have said
I think in the morning concerning...
I am confused I don't know if I told you or yesterday to the previous class, but anyhow...
I will repeat that a severe acute condition
if suppressed maybe be transferred to a sub-acute inflammation.
And all chronic conditions according to my understanding
are sub-acute chronic inflammation conditions. All of them.
Whether it is schizophrenia, whether it is an autoimmune disease
or whether it is any degenerative disease is of a sub-acute inflammatory condition.
In his case strangely enough the sub-acute appears also in fever. He has a high fever
which is suppressed, why it is suppressed, because of wrong treatment
because they did not understand what he was suffering from.
The doctor who examined him did not realize that most probably he had an abscess in the tonsil
and that's why he was feeling pain for days
and then eventually the high fever there was an abscess in the tonsils which developed
in what is called acute infectious mononucleosis.
Which is quite a serious condition and it has to be treated with care,
there are no medicines for that, usually they give cortisone I think
and the usual 10 days antibiotics which make things worse, suppressed the fever
and then the organism gave up and he starting having an effort every day
to recover through this inflammation.
Because the inflammation is always for a good reason. You cannot suppress an inflammation.
An inflammation is the way the organism is recuperating itself, it's coming back to normal.
It's only through an inflammation.
Whether there is a fever manifesting in the physical body it is a different thing.
When there is a high fever the organism shows it has power,
the immune system is in a good condition.
Actually as far as levels of health are concerned this is a man
who had frequent acutes with high fever so his condition could be considered
before this episode as level what...? Which level?
Frequent acutes are level 6 and we have that an organism who is easily brining up acute problems,
otitis, cystitis, bronchitis, whatever treated each time with antibiotics there is a time
when the acutes subside and there is a manifestation
of a chronic sub-inflammatory condition.
This is the rule which has never been observed in medicine.
But it is a fact and this is exactly what I was talking about.
So level 6 he was, frequent acutes treated badly he went with a sub-inflammatory condition
into level 7. Started a chronic degenerative process.
So for me for 10 years he is in this condition.
Last year he got a fever after Psor. So he got out of level 7 to level 6. Is this?
No, it's not. I'll tell you why. Psor was a remedy close enough to the condition.
For a time being gave some energy to his body and his body managed for 1 day to get 39.
And the subsided back to level 7.
Otherwise you would have seen first of all not 1 day only but several days of fever
then you would see after 2 months again another acute and another acute to come to level 6
where we have frequent acutes. We did not see that.
Therefore we come to the conclusion that the remedies have been given so far
were all wrong except of Psor which was not totally wrong but it was a close remedy.
Otherwise his condition has not been helped so far by homeopathy. 10 years of homeopathy...
lots of remedies... but maybe never the correct remedy was given.
So this is unless you know the theory you can go on and give remedies after remedies
and what happens...
Confusion more confusion... But the confusion for his organism is not so dramatic.
Because he says I felt weak and I still feel weak. Now I have some numbness also.
So the condition in which he is now the syndrome
if we want to speak with terms of conventional medicine we would say
that this is a post viral syndrome.
The chronic fatigue syndrome, they call it post viral syndrome.
That means they have noticed that once a person had a fever and they gave antibiotics
they realize that this persons goes into chronic fatigue syndrome.
This is a big diagnosis. Usually in such a case Epstein- Barr antibodies are found.
This is condition used to be called benign encephalomyelitis, then Epstein- Barr,
then post viral syndrome and then forgot about post viral syndrome quickly
and named it chronic fatigue syndrome, just like that. How come chronic fatigue syndrome?
It doesn't come just like that, by itself. Something you have done to this organism.
Why the infectious mononucleosis had such a severe effect?
It is because his organism coming from mother and father has a weak immune system.
Why the immune system is weak?
Most probably because of the condition of the mother.
The condition of the mother is emotionally very weak.
So the mixture of mother and father they bring out an organism which is not strong,
not powerful to fight and very easy staphylococcal infections, quite frequent...
The pathology as it appears is as I said what they call chronic fatigue syndrome
with one difference in his case;
the type of pathology, you see they say another story,
the chronic fatigue syndrome imitates all possible syndromes, whatever.
It can imitate mental pathology, neurological pathology, all kinds of pathologies.
What can you make out of that?
That means we don't have a standard picture of the chronic fatigue symptom.
We have several symptomatologies put together, one person with this, totality of symptoms,
another with this, another with this...
The main line which runs through all these cases is the fatigue which is on the nervous,
on the muscular system. This is the common factor actually.
And then in his case he has a hectic fever with good appetite but losing weight.
So if we want to treat such a case we have to go to the basis of the pathology.
The basis of the pathology is such that imitates actually which disease?
Which is the disease that people may eat but lose weight with hectic fever? Tuberculosis.
Does he have tuberculosis? When I asked him he said he had the Mantoux and is borderline.
May be yes, or may be not. We're not talking about active tuberculosis.
But we are talking about a predisposition in his organism
which brings along from his ancestors the tubercular miasm.
Which under the stress of antibiotics
and the wrong treatment has manifested now as an imitation of tuberculosis.
So there is in his ancestry the tubercular miasm most probably
he does not know whether his grandfather, grandmother had tuberculosis.
Your mother or grandmother?
She had tuberculosis? She died from tuberculosis? Ok, I will repeat.
The grand-grandmother had tuberculosis but it is not certain that his grandmother was born before
or after the tuberculosis. Correct? He thinks it was after. But it does not matter.
When somebody who is prepared to have tuberculosis,
it's the miasm which comes. That's the one.
There is not only this problem, there is another problem with ancestry.
Which is the next problem? Most probably we realize that by what?
What is very peculiar is his case?
He was better in the sea? Not exactly very much better. Tell me and I will repeat...
- The time that you asked him if mother was hysterical or she had emotional problems...
- How I got it...You ask too much. It is through looking. Fear of taking virus.
It's not very peculiar. Yes that's it. The dental pathology.
What he gave as information 9 extra teeth which are coming through this. 5 ok.
5 is more than enough. 5 extra teeth which came in an irregular way.
Which we know that such a condition is due to syphilis.
Not that he has syphilis himself or his father but a syphilitic miasm that comes through ancestors.
So therefore from his case we come to the conclusion
that when he was born he was bringing with him 2 miasms, the tubercular and the also the syphilitic.
We have reasons to substantiate this.
Now we examined the case and we have to make a decision of the remedy which he has to take.
And what is the remedy? I'll show you something. How many symptoms you put? 19.
Ok. Show me 19 symptoms.
Desire for company, concentration difficult, fear of contagion, memory weakness...
teeth irregular, swelling of cervical glands. When I asked for cervical glands was why?
Because of... Why did I ask him whether he has swollen glands? Because of tuberculosis? No.
I was thinking something else but doesn't matter.
Hectic fever, eruptions in winter, ailments after influenza, great appetite with emaciation,
desires sea, salt, sweets, tonsillitis recurrent, weakness fever during etc..
And the remedy is, show them, Tuberculinum. Show the columns.
I'll show you something I tried to confirm the Tub. I could not really confirm it.
First of all because there was no disgust with cats and dogs and fat desire was not really strong.
And the lungs... there were no problems here really so I did not like Tub.
What you will give him? You don't know. You are the yogi? Bacillinum? Congratulations.
Bac. You see it's very interesting, on the 2nd column, you see Bac is coming
yet if you have to explain why the symptoms are very few. But I will tell you something.
Tub has how many symptoms? 12 symptoms. And Bac has only 3. And yet I would prefer to give Bac.
The reason is when you cannot confirm Tub give Bac.
Who was here on the little boy problems from Russia?
Lots of remedies had been given. Had a similar condition. The boy was doing very well on Bac.
Of course this is not the reason. The reason is the 2 remedies are quite similar.
The general picture is the same but the Bac is does not necessarily
have the fear of cats and dogs and the desire for fat.
So therefore I would prefer Bac 200CH one dose and we'll see what happens.
Did you agree?
- May I ask you what didn't you take into consideration the anxiety about health?
- We take it into account, yes, why not? If you want anxiety about health, put anxiety about health.
He has great anxiety about health. I'll tell you something with this case.
Do not think that after Bac everything will be gone but it is the first remedy
that will lift the organism, the immune system and then we'll give some energy to the body
and eventually he will develop the next remedy which will be most probably...
fear of the dark...Phos which was given repeatedly and did not act.
After Bac it will act.
This is why I said it is so important when you start a case to start correctly.
Otherwise you will confuse the case and you will not find it a way out.