Sleeplessness was the original problem, from slightest noise impossible to sleep,
waking from slightest noise, it takes 3-4 hours to fall asleep
and then you had fear of being alone in the night "probably from being frightened
when I was a little boy, I saw a man standing with a knife in the doorway..."
- It could be a delusion.
- Loves animals, bad memory, fear of snakes and heights, did not like school,
he was a bad boy.
Medical history; as a child he had a lot of ear infections treated with antibiotics,
have had all the children diseases, never takes chemical drugs.
You never took marijuana?
- Long time ago. Not much.
- High fever, last time was in December. Never severe acutes.
And the first remedy I prescribed was coff 10M and sleeplessness continued for some time...
- Yes but the first nights I slept good after coff. But then it went up and down.
- And how is it now?
- Much better.
I still have it but not so often. I am still sensitive to noise, when I'm about to sleep.
- And there was another remedy I prescribed to you
when you started having problems with your knee.
- I think you gave me physostigma.
- Yes but for what reason?
- I can't remember.
- Very nice...
- But you gave me bry also for an injury in my thumb and I got numb.
- A bad injury?
- I have still pain.
But the pain was better after bry but now... You gave me nat-m also
when I was here in the first follow up.
- Then you wrote me that your thumb was better, still painful
but the biggest problem for you was your ex-girlfriend has made it clear
that "she has moved on without me"
- We separated.
- "And that is really destroying me and I'm crying all the time."
You look very hard man but...
- I'm not.
- "I'm alone."
- I never cry in front of people.
- "I really feel miserable, I'm thinking about her all the time.
I know it's normal to feel bad when something like this happens
but this is really really bad right now.
So, is there something I can do?" so what can I do, I send you a remedy?
- You gave me nat-m every day for 10 days.
- And what happened? You forgot.
- Completely. No it was much better.
- So how is the situation now?
- With the girlfriend?
- She left. You have another girlfriend?
- Yes.
- I can see it.
- But my main problem now is I'm more prone to injuries with my muscles. And also my allergy.
- You have another injury?
- Lots of them.
- You are driving a motorbike?
- No. I'm training in martial arts. And I think I'm more prone to injuries than anybody else.
- You know the Indians, what they say?
It's your karma.
- Ok. I hope not.
- Ok, you have to be more careful than others. Did you injure yourself?
Because I can see your body is more strong now in general. Is that correct?
- Maybe.
- You are doing martial arts still in spite of the fact you injured yourself?
- Yes.
- Do you know why you are injuring yourself more than others?
- Maybe because I am better on my emotional plane than the physical plane.
- Do you have pains now because of these injuries?
- Yes.
- Where?
- In my arms and sprinkle in my foot and toe and rib.
Strained muscle here, also small pain in my knees, a little stiff joints.
- You are injured when you are fighting with somebody?
- Yes but not only fighting, also when we make some kicks. I can easily strain a muscle.
When I got injured in my arms I didn't train for three weeks but there was no effect.
But then you gave me a rhus-t 200CH for this and my knee was very good.
But the arms did not have an effect. But then I took rhus-t 200CH every day for 5 days
and that was much better but not completely good. So I start training again.
- So you are a picture of health actually.
- I have a good diet.
- Very good diet, healthy life.
- Yes, I have a lot of stress for the moment
because when I split up with my girlfriend I had to sell the house
because it was too expensive to live in and we are going to lose in euros
maybe 150.000 when we sell the house.
It's a lot of money and right now the market is bad so no one is buying.
It costs a lot to hold the house every month. So it's a little bit stress.
- But except of homeopathy do you do something else?
- Yes.
- And you are having a girlfriend or many girlfriends?
- I have one girlfriend.
- Only one at the moment. And you are happy with her?
- Yes. I have some questions but it's ok.
- You eat a healthy diet you say.
- Most of the time.
- You eat fruits?
- Yes, I like fruits, mostly bananas.
It's easy to eat. I eat 3 bananas a day sometimes.
- Not other fruits? Only bananas? I see you are not interested very much in fruits.
- I eat fruit. I don't have an aversion.
- Are you sighing?
- Maybe sometimes. I also have a new grief.
I had to put my dog to sleep, before 2 months ago; to take her away. She is dead.
- Your dog. She was sick.
- Yes. That was also a grief.
- You were connected with your dog.
- Yes. I had 2 dogs I had to put away in 9 months.
- With distemper?
- No, some other problems.
- You are easily offended?
- Maybe it depends. Maybe I can be.
But it depends on what they are saying. I think I'm also very obstinate.
- If somebody says something that hurts you how long this may last inside you?
- I don't think so long. I forgive very easily.
I had my ganglion, it was doing better after rhus-t but it has been bigger now.
- Cold, hot, you tolerate both?
- I tolerate not cold, not hot. But mostly cold, I don't like too hot either.
- But you cannot tolerate the cold.
- The heat is because I don't like to perspire.
- When you perspire where do you perspire?
- Under my arms.
- Not in the face.
- No, maybe in my forehead.
- What do you like to eat? Do you like to eat something special?
- I like sweets very much, especially chocolate.
- What else?
- Salt. Anything spicy.
- You put extra salt in your food?
- Yes, always. I would have taken more if I knew it's not good for me.
- You restrict yourself. But after nat-m it was not reduced?
- No.
- You like lemon?
- I like it on French fries and maybe fish but not very much.
- Eggs?
- I eat eggs, 2 eggs a day, soft boiled.
- Your feet in bed are usually cold or normal? Do you have to put on socks?
- If I'm cold I put socks on but normally not.
- Sweden up to what degree the temperature can go down.
- Minus 20 degree.
In my house it's cold, maybe 17-18 degrees when it's winter
and then I have socks on because it's too cold.
- 17-18 is low. You are not calc. Calc needs 23-24 degrees.
- But I need more, it's too cold.
- You keep it low because of expenses.
- Yes.
- You are not perspiring around your neck.
- No. My fear of high places is better.
- The fear of being alone in the night?
- Still there but I think it's better also.
- Fear of snakes?
- I don't like snakes.
- There is fear. In bed there is restlessness or you sleep more...
- It's always restless before I go to sleep. I change position.
- But when I sleep I don't think I'm restless.
I'm also a little bit restless when I'm sitting. I have to change positions.
I have some symptoms like the one we talked about just before.
I cannot urinate in front of others. It's impossible.
I can urinate if I got to the toilet and there are other people around
but if I am standing in public toilets with people beside me, it's impossible.
- What potency I gave you? 200CH?
- 10M.
- Nat-m?
- Yes, 10M when I was here. But the latest was 200CH.
- Because of the separation.
- Yes.
- Do you think that you need a remedy?
- Yes. I also want to get rid of the allergy.
- In spring time.
- In the summer.
Mostly in the eyes and I always get coryza when it's cold. And lacrimation also from wind.
- There is any salivation during sleep?
- No.
- Sexually you feel ok?
- Yes.
- Are you able to express emotions with your girlfriend?
- I don't like to weep. I cry when I am alone most of the time but when...
- But expressing emotions say "I love you" and this kind of things.
- Yes, I can do that.
- If you stay under the sun, you can tolerate it?
- I think so. It's the perspiration I don't like from the sun also.
- From which pharmacy you get the remedies?
- Helios. England.
- What was the effect of 10M in comparison with 200CH later? Which was more effective?
- The 10M. The 200CH was more acute.
- Ok I'll give you the remedy.
Why he gets injuries more than others? Who can tell? She can tell.
You're an athlete? No.
-  I think emotionally he's not well yet and he has to prove something
and then when he practices, he practices with a lot of ego proving something,
doing more and then he has these injuries. I have seen this...
- But why he has injuries? You approach very much with what you say. Very tight.
He's quite tight still in general, he's not loose enough
when he fights to fall in a placid way.
He falls and he is tight and this tightness manifests in the muscles still,
so it is a deep thing which I doubt if we can touch it with a remedy.
It's a thing that comes from very young age,
most probably is his character to be rather tight.
But he has 2 symptoms still, on which we can justify to try once again;
which are the 2 symptoms?
- In the presence of others he cannot urinate...
- And the other? Desires salt. And there is a third one which is not mentioned there
but I know it, where nat-m is bothered by perspiration, they don't like to perspire.
I've said in the M.M. but I don't see it there.
Still if you make the "solve" still with symptoms nat-m is coming first.
So we can be justified though in this state usually you leave alone,
you say "Continue your life" but because he says that still the desire for salt is so strong,
still he has this timidity in urinating which is characteristic of nat-m
and he has also the aggravation, he does not like the perspiration, will give him nat-m 50M
and we'll see what happens.
Maybe it will take a few years and a few things in your life which make you more loose.
Your life has been such that you are on guard all the time, something may happen.
So you are tight. Something may happen, let it happen.
So who agrees with this prescription? Thank you I have some supporters.
You can ask some questions.
- The first dose was nat-m 10M. I don't understand why you gave nat-m 200CH.
- Because I could not remember what I have given him already.
I received all these e-mails and I don-t have the whole picture of the case.
If I had to go and read right through what I've done before... Forget it.
I would be needing 26 hours a day.
- You have given nat-m 10M to him and since then he told you he is doing better.
The symptoms which we have; he cannot urinate in the presence of others, desires salt,
and he wants to cry alone in a room... All these are symptoms of nat-m.
You see nat-m is working on him and still...
- It needs to go deeper. Go on a higher potency, that's all we can do.
He needs still nat-m to stimulate him.
That means if we stimulate we expect that he will react because the keynotes are still there.
But if somebody feels good, in spite of the fact he may still have some keynotes we can wait.
We can say "wait..." then many  go away without further dose.
- What is your opinion about repeating the same remedy in the same potency?
- If it is needed. If had a headache I would say take "Ok, take nat-m".
Now I am hesitating because I see him in a good condition in general.
Otherwise if he had a real problem I would say yes take it.
But he has no real problem. He's quite healthy. But maybe 50M if it is potentized properly...
This is a big problem with potencies.
50M means 50000 times you put the 99 drops and one of the previous shake it 20 times,
empty it, refill it, shake 20 times...
If you do it really it will take 15 days with a computer, with a robot to do 50M.
So I'm not sure if they are doing it properly. And Korsakoff is not correct for me.
Because they inject with force water on the bottle still it works
but I don't know how it works, really, I cannot explain that. I am more classic.
But I am using from several companies, using sometimes 2-3 companies together
and there are 2-3 companies of Greece they produce also
but it's not what I want as the perfect remedy and the effect when I use this,
I have some of these remedies produced in Italy the effect was really impressive.
And where somebody like him... You see he got 10M and he had some effect but not deep enough.
If he had good potentized remedy the effect would be different.
Question, yes.
- When it is that you are sure what was the remedy which you prescribe?
When you asked this man "Is it easy for you to forgive?"
and I was expecting him to say no and on the contrary you stumbled, I mean I did,
when he said "I forgive easily".
What is your general analysis of the case that you have 3 general symptoms
that go to the wrong way and the core of nat-m has to me the resentment and he is not,
or he says he is not? What's your attitude in general in patients...?
- You're asking me if I believed him? Or not? That's one.
- This is what he said.
- But the fact that he said that that he can forgive for me
this is something of no importance anymore. That means I don't have a symptom to prescribe.
It's normal. It's a normal reaction of a healthy man.
In spite of the fact he looks quite sensitive and offended easily
and you expect he would offended he said "I go over it easily".
So that means this area in the brain is healthy.
I don't expect always to have all the symptoms of a remedy. Mental, emotional etc...
You can have a person with keynote symptoms of a remedy and a healthy mind
where he would respond...
- ... in nat-m you have to have resentment or hate...
- You don't have to have as long as you have... You see 3-4 keynotes of nat-m are enough.
Is he offended easily?
For nat-m there is some pathology on the mental emotional level which is very severe,
with depression, they don't want to talk to anybody etc.
If the person says "I don't have that" it does not take me away from the remedy
if I have the keynote symptoms of the physical body.
So he has the general idea of tightness I describe it as "tightness" I cannot find a better word,
he feels tight that's why when he falls down, he falls down and he's tight. He's not loose.
People are learning to fall down from the motorbike by becoming loose and let it happen.
This he cannot do it yet. This is so far the pathology which I see on an emotional level.
But if I take into consideration his life, you have not seen his case,
who has seen his original case?
You remember, some dramatic things happened in his early life.
So if you see that you justify this tightness, this carefulness.
- I want to ask you another question.
- Yes.
Was it expected what I said by you? I don't think.
- Yes. I was sure that you were going to say that.
The thing is I dismiss my patient when the mental symptom does not go inside with the generals.
I see that you don't give much importance to dreams.
You don't ask much about dreams and illusions.
- I don't ask everybody. That is true.
But if something triggers my mind I will ask about dreams.
If I want to confirm some things. Especially when the person is not talking a lot.
Then I have to search an area which is a subconscious area. Then I ask.
But a general idea with me taking a case is I take a case as long I need to prescribe.
I don't go further. I am not inquisitive. I got enough information, I can prescribe, stop.
I don't go and ask and make psychoanalysis and think like that.
- I agree that he was very tense. You can see his jaws were going up and down all the time
but since he responded so well to rhus-t
don't you think that there is also underlying some inflammatory disease...
- This rhus-t was an acute for the injury. The rhus-t could not deal with more than that but...
- But usually when people are on rhus-t they often inflammatory conditions in...
- Yes. He had injuries and rhus-t covered the acute, that means the injuries.
Not the tightness, not what we are discussing now.
- So you don't think he also has an inflammation in joints and muscles...
- Maybe but not very much. I don't consider it as much.
- I wanted to ask you about what the lady before said that there is no hate, he can forgive.
I perceived the case, he was more hurt and he can forgive on the surface
but deep inside he is still hurt by so many things and it is like a curtain
which he draws in front... The fear of being injured or hurt comes through,
what you said, with the tension he can fall loosely. He injures himself.
-  You can explain it in this way. But for me I would never prescribe for that.
I would prescribe if I knew he cannot urinate in front of others,
if he has desire for salt, if he's bothered by perspiration. Then I would prescribe.
If he had only that I would not prescribe.
- Yes but he doesn't have to say it he is fearful of being hurt.
- True but what he said is "If I am hurt I go over it quickly" where nat-m
if he is hurt it will take 2 years before he can to get rid of it.
They go and think all the time about this "why he told me that..."
He does not seem to have that. Also when he wrote to me that his girlfriend left him
he described it in such a way that I could not see the real nat-m picture,
but still... I had no other option. But the nat-m will cry but alone and not a lot.
He said "I'm crying day and night". That's not nat-m.
The typical nat-m they try to control, they try not to become ridiculous because of that issue.
The end of the class, thank you.